<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 21:02:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Should a Debut Novel &#8220;Play it Safe?&#8221;</title>
		<link>http://outwherethebusesdontrun.com/2013/01/29/should-a-debut-novel-play-it-safe/</link>
		<comments>http://outwherethebusesdontrun.com/2013/01/29/should-a-debut-novel-play-it-safe/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 21:31:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Gus Sanchez</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[authors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chuck palahniuk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ernest cline]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[joseph heller]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[novels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[out where the buses don't run;]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[playing it safe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[work in progress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zadie smith]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://outwherethebusesdontrun.com/?p=527</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Before I kick off this post, first, an apology: you&#8217;ll pardon my lack of blog posts recently, as I&#8217;m slowly recovering from the GODDAMNED FLU. Jesus H. Christ on a shit-stained cracker, I never get sick! Suddenly, Friday night, I&#8217;m overcome with a thumping migrane and body aches. By Saturday morning, I&#8217;m in agony, so [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=527&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Before I kick off this post, first, an apology: you&#8217;ll pardon my lack of blog posts recently, as I&#8217;m slowly recovering from the GODDAMNED FLU. Jesus H. Christ on a shit-stained cracker, I never get sick! Suddenly, Friday night, I&#8217;m overcome with a thumping migrane and body aches. By Saturday morning, I&#8217;m in agony, so it&#8217;s off to the Urgent Care I go. A week&#8217;s worth of Tamiflu and Hydrocodone (which is quite delicious, by the way, and habit-forming&#8230;hmm&#8230;) notwithstanding, Saturday night was brutal. I was in the kind of physical discomfort that made resting absolutely impossible. Oh, and I got to hug the toilet, which is also a rarity. I&#8217;ve pounded booze until I&#8217;ve drunk myself sober, and hardly ever puked, but the flu make me do the barf dance.</p>
<p>Great. Nothing like puking in front of your daughter, who thinks this is HILARIOUS. That little shit. I reminded her later of when she got sick and spent the entire day puking. That shut her up.</p>
<p>So it&#8217;s now Thursday, I&#8217;ve exhausted my Tamiflu, but I still have some Hydrocodone left over. My head is stopped up, and I still feel sluggish. I haven&#8217;t had a chance to go for a 2-3 mile run lately, or to the gym, so I&#8217;m feeling doughy, but I don&#8217;t dare go to the gym feeling the way I feel. Worse yet, I don&#8217;t even feel like writing. Nothing. Not even a blog. Well, until right now, I suppose.</p>
<p>Ten days have passed, my throat is still scratchy, I finally made it to the gym this morning, only to wrestle furiously with an elliptical machine; I won, but barely.</p>
<p>In addition to the flu, I&#8217;ve reprised my role as <a href="http://outwherethebusesdontrun.com/2012/11/12/confessions-of-a-collegiate-ringer/">a collegiate ringer</a>. One of my wife&#8217;s classes involves her reading a rather horrible novel; essentially, it&#8217;s Socratic didactic disguised as a novel. Great. Nothing more I love than being lectured to. So I took it upon myself to read the novel over the weekend, only to work myself up into a teeth-gnashing frenzy over how fucking irresponsible and outright <em>wrong</em> the whole didactic was. But I finished her assignments for the week, with a few more coming in the following weeks.</p>
<p>Speaking of which, that novel, which I won&#8217;t reveal its title just yet, has now entered my list of my All-Time Top 5 Most Hated Novels Ever. A blog post on this to come very soon.</p>
<p>Oh, and J.J. Abrams will direct the new <em>Star Wars</em> film. I want to be all excited about this, but I&#8217;m withhold any expected frenzy until May 2015, when the seventh chapter comes to the screen.</p>
<p>Now, without further ado&#8230;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>A few weeks ago, I was at a local writer&#8217;s critique group I attend every second Saturday of each month. A lively discussion took place regarding one of the participant&#8217;s submitted pieces. I felt his writing, though promising, needed a lot of work. Too many run-on sentences, and his story seemed to threaten to get away from him. Like a lot of young adult writers, his story is part of a multi-part story; his submitted short selection was the prologue and opening chapter to the first novel.</p>
<p>My suggestion to him, one which I voiced loudly, was to make the story more ambitious. I felt he was restraining himself a bit too much.</p>
<p>One participant argued otherwise. There&#8217;s an adage in the publishing world, she said, that both agents and publishers will repeat with writers: your first and second novels should play it safe. Save the really ambitious stuff for the third novel. Agents find it easier to sell novels that play it safe. A few participants in the group nodded their heads, although it was hard to say if they agreed, or were just nodding for the sheer hell of it all.</p>
<p>I let her commentary pass, without a comment of my own. After all, I&#8217;m not a published writer, so I have no frame of reference to retort with. There are rules every writer must abide by. The classic &#8220;show, don&#8217;t tell,&#8221; is probably the one cardinal rule no writer dare violate. The greatest lesson any writer should know is what the rules to writing actually are. Know the rules, and you&#8217;ll play the game correctly.</p>
<p>With that being said, there&#8217;s something to be said about breaking the rules. The greatest art has often been created when the artist thumbs their nose at the rules, and creates a new set of rules. Actually, let&#8217;s take that one step down a bit. Good art, even if it&#8217;s not great, should make every attempt to break the rules. And this rule that your debut novel should be something you should play safe, as a writer, is one rule I think needs to be broken more frequently.</p>
<p>I&#8217;d be hard-pressed to tell you exactly how many debut novels I&#8217;ve read, but I find that while so many are well-written and possessing of a literary voice that&#8217;s clearly going places, often times that debut just seems unmemorable. Not to say it&#8217;s a bad book. Far from it. But I get a feeling sometimes that after I&#8217;ve read a debut novel, I&#8217;ll likely not think much about it ever again. Which leads me recently to wonder if someone, an agent, an editor, another writer, suggested to this writer that they play it safe with their debut novel. The better the chances to get their novel published, right? So be it, I suppose.</p>
<p><img class="alignleft" alt="" src="http://d.gr-assets.com/books/1333576871l/9969571.jpg" width="250" height="380" /></p>
<p>Then I finished reading <a href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/9969571-ready-player-one"><em>Ready Player One</em></a> by Ernest Cline recently, and was reminded again of what a debut novel should read like: an opening, forceful statement of intent from a new novelist, one that brims with so much promise, and whose debut novel is filled with the idea that &#8220;playing it safe&#8221; is a fool&#8217;s errand. Clearly, Ernest Cline skipped class the day that lesson was taught, and thank the gods for that, because had Ernest Cline played it safe, <em>Ready Player One</em> would simply be another run-of-the-mill sci-fi tale. By not playing it safe, Ernest Cline has weaved a hilarious, heart-racing, smile-inducing pop-culture thrill ride, a love letter to nerd culture and 80s-era nostalgia, and a game inside a story that&#8217;s hard to put down. If you&#8217;ve read this novel, then you know what I&#8217;m talking about.</p>
<p>In other words, this is one hell of a debut novel because it goes for something far greater than the sum of its parts. It dares to be far more ambitious than it should be, and it works.</p>
<p>I thought of some of my favorite debut novels: <em>Fight Club</em>, by Chuck Palahniuk, <em>White Teeth</em>, by Zadie Smith, <em>The Curious Incident of the Dog in the Night-Time</em>, by Mark Haddon, and <em>Catch-22</em>, by Joseph Heller. What if Chuck Palahniuk&#8217;s agent told him to play it safe, and lose the whole plot twist about Tyler Durden and the narrator being the same person? Certainly Palahniuk&#8217;s ruminations on commercialism, masculinity, and materialism wouldn&#8217;t have had the same heft and anarchic glee to them. What if Joseph Heller&#8217;s agent told him, &#8220;Forget it, you need to make Yossarian less crazy and more likeable?&#8221;</p>
<p>It&#8217;s possible these conversations took place. Clearly, if they did, these authors dug their heels.</p>
<p>Mind you, I&#8217;m not dumping on agents for dispensing this advice. Sometimes an author not playing it safe is an author being self-indulgent, and a good agent needs to call bullshit sometimes. But sometimes this advice can be misguided. I&#8217;m not saying the rule of &#8220;playing it safe&#8221; is wrong, but it&#8217;s a rule worth breaking when writing your first novel.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/527/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/527/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=527&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://outwherethebusesdontrun.com/2013/01/29/should-a-debut-novel-play-it-safe/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>43</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/68e38965e394afdc04d40d0aa6f57a9c?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">dabi71</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://d.gr-assets.com/books/1333576871l/9969571.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>For the Love of Playing on the High-Voltage Electrical Transformer Box</title>
		<link>http://thesurfingpizza.com/2013/01/25/for-the-love-of-playing-on-the-high-voltage-electrical-transformer-box-in-the-front-yard/</link>
		<comments>http://thesurfingpizza.com/2013/01/25/for-the-love-of-playing-on-the-high-voltage-electrical-transformer-box-in-the-front-yard/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2013 20:20:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>The Pizza</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Things I Like]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thesurfingpizza.com/?p=9290</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Playing on the high voltage electrical transformer was one of the most fun things you could do as a kid. It was like a jungle gym with a warm comforting electric voltage. It was like playing with matches and running with scissors at the same time. It was like smoking. It was like drinking. It [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=9290&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://iwantpizza.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/elecboxbefore.jpg?w=720" alt="ElecBoxBefore"   class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-9425" /></p>
<p>Playing on the high voltage electrical transformer was one of the most fun things you could do as a kid. It was like a jungle gym with a warm comforting electric voltage. It was like playing with matches and running with scissors at the same time. It was like smoking. It was like drinking. It was like DRUGS. </p>
<p>The thing had a siren song I could not resist. Or maybe that was just the sound of the cancerous grounding hum. My parents had many rules, most of which I followed. Don&#8217;t talk to strangers? Fine. Don&#8217;t play with matches? Done. But don&#8217;t play on the high-voltage electrical transformer box that could electrocute you to death? Sorry, no can do. </p>
<p>Besides, if it was really so dangerous, there would have been an after-school special about it. Or a special filmstrip shown in class. A cartoon all-stars program. At the very least, a piddly PSA at the end of GI Joe. I trusted television for all of my most important information.</p>
<p>I openly defied the sticker on the side of the transformer than read WARNING DO NOT TOUCH. I mocked it. A picture of silhouetted man being shocked to death meant nothing to the ice cold water running in my veins. I was a daredevil. A rebel. A fearless dragon. The only thing that scared me was quicksand. Well&#8212;and that episode of <em>Punky Brewster</em> where Cherie got trapped in the refrigerator and almost suffocated. God, that was traumatizing.</p>
<p>Okay, fine, and jellyfish. They&#8217;re translucent blobs with tentacles. And Brussels Sprouts. They&#8217;re mini-cabbages. SCARY. </p>
<p>The transformer was fun for lots of reasons. Reason #1: it was called a transformer. I was always waiting for that thing to turn in Optimus Prime. Reason #2: It was a moon base for my action figures. Reason #3: I could do extreme stunts off of it. Like jumping and well&#8212;only jumping. But I could jump all the way to the sidewalk without touching the grass. And that arbitrary invisible line was like the Olympic finish line.</p>
<p>I was like Rocky always training for the big fight. I practiced my jumps on the staircase in the house, always trying to jump from the next step up. I usually chickened out around the fourth or fifth step, but with enough training, my goal in life was to jump down an entire flight of stairs. </p>
<p>I never did make it, and maybe that&#8217;s a shame. I could always start trying again, but I like my knees. I think they used to be made of Kevlar, but now they&#8217;re just made of ligaments and flesh. I was bionic, once. I&#8217;m human now. But I&#8217;m a fearless dragon forever.</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://thesurfingpizza.com/category/things-i-like/'>Things I Like</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/9290/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/9290/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=9290&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thesurfingpizza.com/2013/01/25/for-the-love-of-playing-on-the-high-voltage-electrical-transformer-box-in-the-front-yard/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>30</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c63ffec6073142d5338465c140aa5055?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The Pizza</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://iwantpizza.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/elecboxbefore.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ElecBoxBefore</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Curtain Call for &#8220;The United Kingdom&#8221;?</title>
		<link>http://daliennation.wordpress.com/2013/01/29/curtain-call-for-the-united-kingdom/</link>
		<comments>http://daliennation.wordpress.com/2013/01/29/curtain-call-for-the-united-kingdom/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 15:59:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lyncath</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Current Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Britain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[British Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Current Affairs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[International Politics.]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scotland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[World History]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://daliennation.wordpress.com/?p=991</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[We&#8217;re living through an interesting and potentially groundbreaking peroid of history at the moment with &#8220;The Arab Spring&#8221;, the very first African-American  President of the United States taking and retaining office, the economic balance of power shifting eastwards, and seeing the biggest challenge to Capitalism since the Bolshevik Revolution and &#8220;The Great Depression&#8221; of the [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=991&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We&#8217;re living through an interesting and potentially groundbreaking peroid of history at the moment with &#8220;The Arab Spring&#8221;, the very first African-American  President of the United States taking and retaining office, the economic balance of power shifting eastwards, and seeing the biggest challenge to Capitalism since the Bolshevik Revolution and &#8220;The Great Depression&#8221; of the 1930&#8242;s.</p>
<p>However, if you live in the United Kingdom there is another potentially historic development arriving in 2014: Scottish Independence. If you&#8217;ve not been following the news or do not live in the UK I&#8217;ll give a rundown of what I&#8217;m about to address. All of the nations which currently make up &#8220;The United Kingdom&#8221; were not always part of it; Ireland, Wales, England and Scotland to be exact. Scotland has been part of the UK for just over three centuries, since the 1st of May 1707 to be precise when the Acts of Union merged the Scottish Parliament with the Westminster British Parliament. With it&#8217;s foundations secured Britain went forth and forged the greatest empire known to man, an empire which stretched the width of the globe and brought many nations under it&#8217;s influence&#8230; <em>&#8220;The sun never sets on the British Empire&#8221;</em> was a term which was not too far from reality when it was coined.<br />
Despite being immensely prosperous for the British Empire the imperial model was an unsustainable system, financially and socially, and sure enough nation after nation began either demanding autonomy or outright independence from the British Crown. Although the American War of Independence (1775 &#8211; 1783) had shaken the foundations of the British Empire the real killer blows came with the Boer Wars (1880 &#8211; 1881 &amp; 1899 &#8211; 1902), World War One (1914 &#8211; 1918), and World War Two (1939 &#8211; 1945). In addition to almost bankrupting Britain these wars had also proven that Britain could no longer guarantee the safety of it&#8217;s colonies, the Japanese bombing of Darwin being a good example, and in the aftermath of World War Two many of these colonies began seeking new partnerships such as the ANZUS <em>(Australia, New Zealand, United States Security Treaty)</em> Treaty of 1951. Despite it&#8217;s worldwide empire fast falling to pieces Britain could be safe in the knowledge that it still had Scotland, Wales, and Northern Ireland (Republic of Ireland was recognized in 1922) to maintain the title of &#8220;United Kingdom&#8221;.</p>
<p>Now even that appears to be in question as the Scottish Parliament has recently taken the extraordinary step of deciding to hold a referendum on whether or not Scotland should remain part of the UK. If the vote in favor of &#8216;Devolution&#8217;* passes in November 2014 that would mean with immediate effect that Scotland will become it&#8217;s own state completely independent from British politics. That would only leave England with Northern Ireland, which is experiencing ongoing tensions with it&#8217;s republican neighbor, and Wales, who&#8217;s future in the UK also seems in question.<br />
* <em>Devolution essentially means the transfer of powers from the UK parliament in London to assemblies in Cardiff and Belfast, and the Scottish Parliament in Edinburgh.</em></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://daliennation.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/devolution.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-992" alt="Devolution" src="http://daliennation.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/devolution.jpg?w=267&#038;h=322" width="267" height="322" /></a></p>
<p>What this essentially means is that &#8220;The United Kingdom&#8221; would lose it&#8217;s second biggest member leaving England, Wales, and Northern Ireland as the remainder of what was once a global empire. The world has seen the death of the British Empire <em>(if you&#8217;re one of those patriotic zealots who believes Britain still has an empire you&#8217;re delusional)</em> and I genuinely think we&#8217;re about to see the death of the United Kingdom. If Scotland leaves the UK what does that mean for Wales? Even more so what does that mean for Northern Ireland, will it join it&#8217;s republican neighbor?</p>
<p><a href="http://daliennation.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/uk-scotland.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-998" alt="UK Scotland" src="http://daliennation.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/uk-scotland.png?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>Sceptics have said that without support from England Scotland would fail to keep itself afloat, pointing to the recent Euro bailout of The Republic of Ireland as a fear-inducing example. However, consider this&#8230; Scotland is not part of the Euro currency and has shown little inclination of ever joining it. It has a considerable advantage that many sceptics overlook when addressing this issue, the size of it&#8217;s population. As of 2012 England has a staggering population of roughly 60,000,000 people whilst Scotland has a mere 5,000,000. Nay-sayers will eagerly point out the potential costs Scotland will face without support from Westminster but the fact remains that Scotland has a tiny population to care for compared to England and that any public services bill would be minute compared to the ever-rising English bill. Scotland has the means to care for itself outside of finance, something that England is now learning the hard way <em>(thanks for that Maggie Thatcher&#8230;). </em>It is already rearing it&#8217;s own livestock, cultivating it&#8217;s own land, and has access to North Sea oil which can help sustain it&#8217;s economy for the time being.</p>
<p>English critics of the 2014 referendum generally sound like parents who are desperately clinging onto their children and who don&#8217;t want them leaving the nest. I think that a more suitable analogy is that of overly-protective grandparents taking care of their grandchildren in a similar manner, except they are stuck in a time warp and cannot get over the fact that the British Empire is dead-and-buried.</p>
<p>Can Scotland stand by itself come 2014?<br />
Who knows.<br />
We won&#8217;t know until we let them try though, it&#8217;s time to let Scotland decide it&#8217;s own future.</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://daliennation.wordpress.com/category/current-events/'>Current Events</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/991/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/991/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=991&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://daliennation.wordpress.com/2013/01/29/curtain-call-for-the-united-kingdom/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://daliennation.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/end-of-uk.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://daliennation.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/end-of-uk.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">End of UK</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a132c8adf73448587aae24ea3b9e7efe?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">dale100889</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://daliennation.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/devolution.jpg?w=445" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Devolution</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://daliennation.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/uk-scotland.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">UK Scotland</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Moral Dilemma of Financial Doping</title>
		<link>http://welshgull.wordpress.com/2013/01/29/the-moral-dilemma-of-financial-doping/</link>
		<comments>http://welshgull.wordpress.com/2013/01/29/the-moral-dilemma-of-financial-doping/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 21:40:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>James</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Club Football]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Football]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://welshgull.wordpress.com/?p=1121</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Money, it&#8217;s a hit Don&#8217;t give me that Do goody good bullshit For many months I&#8217;ve been wrangling internally over one of the big questions of 21st century football &#8211; when is it OK to spend more than everyone else? On the one hand, I should loathe financial doping and everything it stands for &#8211; [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1121&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;"><em>Money, it&#8217;s a hit<br />
Don&#8217;t give me that<br />
Do goody good bullshit</em></p>
<p>For many months I&#8217;ve been wrangling internally over one of the big questions of 21st century football &#8211; when is it OK to spend more than everyone else?</p>
<p>On the one hand, I should loathe financial doping and everything it stands for &#8211; outside owners buying a club and then spending way beyond its means in order to make the task of winning things that much easier. It&#8217;s artificially enhancing performance &#8211; hence &#8220;financial doping&#8221;. It&#8217;s not fair on those that don&#8217;t have the money trying to do it the &#8220;right&#8221; way.</p>
<p>But what is the &#8220;right&#8221; way? Who&#8217;s to say the Middle Eastern-owned clubs spending billions every year on a squad their clubs should not be able to sustain without financial assistance are &#8220;wrong&#8221; to do that? This is the other side of the coin. Alongside this is the fact that we all love a club that spends money, buys the best players and tries to turn them into a superteam. Real Madrid have done it for years and no one has ever criticised them for it. And I&#8217;m sure that anyone who has ever played Football Manager has at some point picked a team with loads of money to try and build our own perfect squad &#8211; at the very least, we always try to make signings as soon as we take over, don&#8217;t we?</p>
<p>I certainly look on in admiration at Pars Saint-Germain&#8217;s purchases over the last couple of years &#8211; Zlatan, Lavezzi, Thiago Silva, Lucas Moura, Sirigu, Motta. What a team that could be, especially if their Qatari owners keep handing managers the cash to buy some more superstars. For the neutral, it&#8217;s great fun.</p>
<p>But that&#8217;s the other thing &#8211; it&#8217;s all well and good thinking this way when you&#8217;re a neutral, but if you&#8217;re facing financially-doped teams, is it a different matter? Remember, it&#8217;s not only the big teams. As a Torquay fan, I&#8217;ve witnessed the rises of the likes of Crawley Town and Fleetwood Town, surging through the Conference and League Two with squads their small attendances should not be able to sustain, because of sugar-daddy owners &#8211; in Rushden &amp; Diamonds&#8217; case, it didn&#8217;t last and the club was liquidated.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s immensely frustrating as a fan of a club that prides itself on having never been in administration and very rarely in any sort of financial trouble &#8211; I take pride in that, but I&#8217;m also frustrated because it&#8217;s almost too stifling, when you know that other clubs around you are spending beyond their means and being successful in the process, like Swindon Town last year; sometimes I feel Torquay should live a little and spend some money on some good players, instead of just getting by on the bare minimum.</p>
<p>So do I apply this thinking to the higher leagues? Does this mean I have to support the new Financial Fair Play regulations which UEFA says will stop financial doping? It should, if I wasn&#8217;t a hypocrite. But I am a hypocrite. Financial doping is the only way the European football landscape has changed in recent years &#8211; the rises of Chelsea, Manchester City and PSG. FFP will mean the status quo will last forever &#8211; and anyone outside of it will be sitting ducks; if they&#8217;re lucky enough to produce any good players, they&#8217;ll be picked off by the big teams.</p>
<p>And what of the risks? They say clubs like Chelsea and Man City are screwed if their owners abandon them. But hang on, let&#8217;s look at Malaga &#8211; their Middle Eastern sugar-daddy owners decided to stop funding in the summer and it looked as if the club was doomed. And yet they&#8217;re through to the knockout stages of the Champions League and are sitting 4th in La Liga. Doomed? They&#8217;re in better shape than ever. You may suggest Portsmouth, but their troubles were because of an owner promising money and then not giving it to them, which could happen anywhere &#8211; that&#8217;s not a problem of financial doping; a problem of financial doping would be an owner like Abramovich spending loads of money and then pulling the plug overnight, as happened at Malaga. There may be risks but they haven&#8217;t shown themselves yet &#8211; has no one considered the possibility that these sugar-daddy owners might actually be in it for the long term?</p>
<p>For me, Man City are at the centre of this debate &#8211; not necessarily for what they have got out of it (a great squad, fantastic training facilities and their name on the Premier League trophy) but for what they haven&#8217;t, i.e. a record in Europe that is anything but terrible considering the money spent. Roberto Mancini should not be a manager someone would entrust with spending a lot of money on building a good squad of players &#8211; he has billions to spend on a football squad, with literally endless possibilities, and yet Man City regularly start Gareth Barry and James Milner. Think of all the great midfielders in the world he could have brought in instead of them. It&#8217;s no wonder they have failed two years in a row in the Champions League.</p>
<p>From this, you could draw two different conclusions. One is that anyone can win things with lots of money, as proven by Man City&#8217;s Premier League title win. If you take this conclusion, then you probably think that spending lots of money isn&#8217;t a good thing. But the other perspective is that it&#8217;s a lot more difficult to win things with lots of money than you might think, as proven by the gap between the Manchester clubs last year at the end of the season, and Man City&#8217;s failures in Europe.</p>
<p>It might look on the surface to be &#8220;easy&#8221;, or &#8220;buying a trophy&#8221;, but if money was that much of a leg-up on its own, they would have done much better in every competition. And they wouldn&#8217;t be drawing with a dreadful QPR team as they have done tonight. Don&#8217;t dislike Man City just because they&#8217;ve spent loads of money, but feel free to dislike the way they&#8217;ve spent loads of money and yet still underachieve &#8211; blame them for incompetency, not greed.</p>
<p>The fact is that superteams don&#8217;t always succeed. Real Madrid&#8217;s history has been littered with expensive failures and Thomas Gravesen. PSG are only just scraping to the Ligue 1 title with Zlatan, Thiago Silva and co, and were beaten to it last year by a Montpellier side built on a shoestring, with John Utaka as a key player. Bayern&#8217;s last few seasons have been up and down, having been beaten by a far less expensive Borussia Dortmund team. Inter failed in Europe until Mancini was given the boot; Jose Mourinho, the master of big-spending, promptly took them to the first ever Italian Treble. The manager is even more important than the squad.</p>
<p>So is financial doping right? Probably not, in the sense that it&#8217;s not great to spend your way into a massive loss and not worry about it. But does it guarantee success? No way. And does it make football a hell of a lot more interesting, especially when in the hands of an average manager who has been promoted way above their station? Absolutely. If Mourinho doesn&#8217;t go to Man City in the summer, be grateful. Spending millions only works when it&#8217;s in the right hands. Otherwise you might as well just flush those millions down the toilet.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1121/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1121/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1121&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://welshgull.wordpress.com/2013/01/29/the-moral-dilemma-of-financial-doping/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/6a503de8cfcf99f4a99e277f16d05c23?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">JB-F1</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Train Travels #33: Decoration</title>
		<link>http://gingerfightback.com/2013/01/28/train-travels-33-decoration/</link>
		<comments>http://gingerfightback.com/2013/01/28/train-travels-33-decoration/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2013 19:31:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>gingerfightback</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[ginger, humor, nonsense]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Authors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Britain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Decorating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Short Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[star trek]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://gingerfightback.com/?p=5313</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#160; &#160; It was my Father&#8217;s opinion that a whistling worker was a happy chap. His assumption extended to a belief that a whistling worker, fulfilled and sated with his day&#8217;s toil, enjoyed evenings around the hearth with loved ones, chomping on hearty, nourishing fare and discussing the events of the day in tedious detail. [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=5313&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://gingerfightback.com/2013/01/28/train-travels-33-decoration/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f0a344ff53d9dedb79e74518c7882c04?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gingerfightback</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gingerfightback.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/fresco_rescue.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">fresco_rescue</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8220;A Letter to the Girl I Harassed&#8221;</title>
		<link>http://rosiesays.com/2013/01/29/a-letter-to-the-girl-i-harassed/</link>
		<comments>http://rosiesays.com/2013/01/29/a-letter-to-the-girl-i-harassed/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 20:57:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Rosie Says</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gender]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sex]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gender]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[letter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[letters to the editor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pick-up]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sexual harassment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[street harassment]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rosiesays.com/?p=9847</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Whoo boy, and the ride never ends. A few days ago, I received a letter from a guy who wanted to respond to my street harassment piece with his own explanation of this pattern of male behavior. I find the letter to be quite disturbing and a little scary, but mostly it makes me sad. [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=9847&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_9861" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 285px"><a href="http://rosiesaysblog.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/predator.jpeg"><img class="size-full wp-image-9861" alt="Predator or Prey? Really?" src="http://rosiesaysblog.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/predator.jpeg?w=720"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Predator or Prey? Really?</p></div>
<p>Whoo boy, and the ride never ends. A few days ago, I received a letter from a guy who wanted to respond to <a href="http://www.rolereboot.org/culture-and-politics/details/2012-12-a-letter-to-the-guy-who-harrassed-me-outside-the-bar" target="_blank">my street harassment piece</a> with his own explanation of this pattern of male behavior. I find the letter to be quite disturbing and a little scary, but mostly it makes me sad.</p>
<p>I believe the writer is sincerely trying to participate in the conversation about street harassment, and for that I am truly appreciative. I&#8217;ve received enough junky hate mail on this subject to know what straight-up misplaced aggression looks like, and this isn&#8217;t it. He has granted me permission to republish in full and I have not edited his letter at all.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s his caveat that he included: <em>&#8220;I do not think that the letter offers a good or healthy perspective, however, I suspect that a portion of guys can relate to it, because at some point in their lives they have felt some of the nasty things that the letter describes. Also, such nastiness needs to be expressed, even if its not PC, because how else can we talk about what&#8217;s going on?&#8221;</em></p>
<p>*    *    *     *    *</p>
<p><strong>To the Girl Whom I Harassed At the Bar</strong></p>
<p>It&#8217;s a drizzly Friday in Chicago and I&#8217;m loitering outside a bar after midnight. My friends and I would like a hookup, but we don&#8217;t have enough guts to talk to any girls. Sure, we can joke and snicker at them. Being assholes is kind of our strategy, because it gives us the upper hand.</p>
<p>We&#8217;re chilling on the sidewalk when two young women walk out of a bar. They&#8217;re not dressed up, but they&#8217;re still pretty. I notice they&#8217;re having a good time. My friends are I are bored. So I go up to the ladies and say something about their “tacos.” My friends all laugh. I laugh too. I feel pretty good, except that part of me doesn&#8217;t feel good. It&#8217;s an odd feeling. I don&#8217;t understand. It&#8217;s just another mixed up moment in my life.</p>
<p>Here is something you should know about me. I intentionally hurt people sometimes to make myself feel better.</p>
<p>Being in the presence of a woman can be anguish. It&#8217;s loneliness (and sometimes horniness), and all that other Freudian bullshit rolled up into mundane moments. Just walking down the street can make me feel helpless when I pass a woman sometimes. I can&#8217;t shake it. If I could shake it, I would. Trust me. It&#8217;s no fun. But this is the hand I&#8217;m dealt, so I roll with it.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s no one&#8217;s fault that I want to connect to someone sometimes and can&#8217;t.</p>
<p>You ask when will someone make a gender-swapping plug-in for real life? Well if you want to gender swap, then here&#8217;s my world. I live in a zero-sum culture. There is no harmony of the sexes; it&#8217;s a battle of the sexes. Who will be overcome by desire first? Who will have their daily routine interrupted by unwanted sexual tension first? If I were a saint, I would rise above the bullshit and say no one has to suffer. But I&#8217;m no saint.</p>
<p>You might say I that have a problem, that I&#8217;m wounded. Maybe you pity me. Pity doesn&#8217;t help me though.</p>
<p>Do I want to be this guy. Hell no! But who knows another way to become a man? Who can show me how to connect with a woman and respect myself? Not the women, since half of them are ignoring me, and the other half don&#8217;t respect themselves when I diss them. The men, at least the men I know, don&#8217;t know nothing. They just watch pornos and get pussy-whipped.</p>
<p>Love is a zero sum game.</p>
<p>Sometime, when you&#8217;re ready for a change, consider this question. If you find yourself in a vicious game, would you rather be the predator or the prey?</p>
<p>*    *    *     *    *</p>
<p>Yikes. Wow. Oof. Kapow. I don&#8217;t really know what to do with this, exactly. A big part of me is afraid that this writer&#8217;s perspective is all too common. I&#8217;ve heard this kind of language, &#8220;zero sum game,&#8221; &#8220;predator or prey,&#8221; etc from other young men before and it&#8217;s usually in the service of justifying unquestionably mean-spirited, manipulative, Douche-with-a-capital-D behavior. Some of this is straight out of the pick-up artist handbook, especially the idea that if a tactic works (on the women who &#8220;don&#8217;t respect themselves&#8221;) it&#8217;s acceptable to use.</p>
<p>The most consistent feedback I&#8217;ve received for the original street harassment piece is the overwhelming need for empathy, literally the capacity to recognize emotions that other people are feeling and try to vicariously experience them as well. When I reread the letter with that in mind, I lose a lot of the gut reaction rage that this letter inspired in me.</p>
<p>Without minimizing the overwhelming perfect storm of body hating, slut-shaming, victim-blaming, mixed messaging media bullshittery that women face on a daily basis, I <em>do </em>think there&#8217;s a void for young men about what modern masculinity really means. This is a conversation we&#8217;ve sorta kinda maybe a little bit started in this country, but for guys like this writer, already in their twenties, there are few role models of &#8220;manliness&#8221; that don&#8217;t involve killing the bad guy and getting the girl.</p>
<p>Is that an excuse? No. Treat women like humans and not opponents to be triumphed over and you might have more success with them. Don&#8217;t make taco jokes; say hello and smile. Approach with no expectation of anything more than a pleasant exchange with a fellow person just doing their best.</p>
<p>And this is not unidirectional. Ladies (in this imaginary all-hetero world I&#8217;m writing in at the moment), don&#8217;t be jerks to guys that try to talk to you (assuming they are civil), whether you&#8217;re interested or not. You can politely move on without rolling your eyes, turning away, sighing in disgust, or being a generally uninterested pretentious douchface.</p>
<p>People, be nice to each other. Niceness is a awesome. Niceness doesn&#8217;t mean I want to bone you, and it doesn&#8217;t mean you deserve a date or a drink or anything of the sort. It means that shit is hard out there, son, and a little kindness goes a long way.</p>
<p><strong>Related Post:</strong><a href="http://www.xojane.com/sex/you-can-get-laid-without-being-a-jerk" target="_blank"> You don&#8217;t have to be a jerk to get laid. </a></p>
<p><strong>Related Post:</strong> <a href="http://rosiesays.com/2013/01/20/two-letters/" target="_blank">Two letters.</a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/9847/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/9847/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=9847&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://rosiesays.com/2013/01/29/a-letter-to-the-girl-i-harassed/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>42</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/38b7a1ee2b23af1d0fc4de64313885e6?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">rosiesaysblog</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://rosiesaysblog.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/predator.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Predator or Prey? Really?</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Franchise Films and Why Wong Kar Wai Should Direct the Next Star Wars Film</title>
		<link>http://biblioklept.org/2013/01/25/franchise-films-alternate-worlds-and-why-wong-kar-wai-should-direct-the-next-star-wars-film/</link>
		<comments>http://biblioklept.org/2013/01/25/franchise-films-alternate-worlds-and-why-wong-kar-wai-should-direct-the-next-star-wars-film/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2013 21:02:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Edwin Turner</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Literature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Abram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David Lynch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dune]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fantasy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[godfather films]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hollywood studio system]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[J. J. Abrams]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[John Carter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sci-Fi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spider-Man]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Star Trek]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Star Wars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[star wars franchise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wong Kar Wai]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://biblioklept.org/?p=24512</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[News that J.J. Abrams will direct the seventh Star Wars film almost broke the internet yesterday. It&#8217;s easy to see why anyone who nerds out over franchise properties would take interest. After all, Abrams helmed the 2009 big-screen reboot of Star Trek, a film that shook the camp and cheese from the franchise&#8217;s previous films, replacing it [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=24512&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="size-full wp-image-24518 aligncenter" alt="STAR WARS 3 hartter" src="http://biblioklept.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/star-wars-3-hartter.jpg?w=720"   /></p>
<p>News that <a href="http://www.avclub.com/articles/today-in-star-wars-rumors-jj-abrams-is-directing-s,91573/" target="_blank">J.J. Abrams will direct the seventh Star Wars film</a> almost broke the internet yesterday. It&#8217;s easy to see why anyone who nerds out over franchise properties would take interest. After all, Abrams helmed the 2009 big-screen reboot of <em>Star Trek</em>, a film that shook the camp and cheese from the franchise&#8217;s previous films, replacing it with hip humor, thrilling action, and lots and lots of lens flare. Abrams&#8217;s sequel, <em>Star Trek Into Darkness</em> is perhaps the most anticipated franchise film of the year. <i><br />
</i></p>
<p>I won&#8217;t speculate whether an Abrams Star Wars film will be successful or not&#8212;you probably wouldn&#8217;t want me to, because I hold the extreme minority opinion that Lucas&#8217;s <em>Revenge of the Sith</em> is a deeply profound and moving work of cinema art&#8212;but I do think that the choice to hand the next big film in the Star Wars franchise over to Abrams represents the worst in corporate thinking. This goes beyond the playground logic of Abrams swiping all the marbles&#8212;<em>he gets both the &#8220;Star&#8221; franchises!&#8212;</em>what it really points to is the bland, safe commercial mindset that guides the corporations who own these franchises. J.J. Abrams is a safe bet. I can more or less already imagine the movie he&#8217;ll make.</p>
<p><em>Star Wars: A New Hope</em> came out in 1977, perhaps at the exact moment that the innovations of the &#8220;<a href="http://www.digitalhistory.uh.edu/historyonline/hollywood_1960s.cfm" target="_blank">New Hollywood</a>&#8221; movement crested (before <a href="http://www.avclub.com/articles/my-year-of-flops-case-file-81-heavens-gate,10347/" target="_blank"><em>Heaven&#8217;s Gate </em></a>crashed the whole damn thing in 1980). The films of this decade&#8212;<em>Badlands</em>, <em>The Godfather</em> <em></em>films, <em>Bonnie &amp; Clyde</em>, <em>Chinatown</em>, <em>Nashville</em>, <em>Dr. Strangelove</em>, etc.&#8212;helped to redefine film as art; they also captured and illustrated a zeitgeist that&#8217;s almost impossible to define. And while plenty of filmmakers today continue in this spirit, their films are often pushed into the margins. The Hollywood studio system is tangled up in big budget spectacle. I have no problem with this, but at the same time I think that there&#8217;s something sad in it all&#8212;in the bland safety of having Abrams turn out <em></em>Star Wars <em>and </em>Star Trek films&#8212;it all points to a beige homogeneity.</p>
<p>The problem I&#8217;m talking about is neatly summed up by Gus Van Sant in a 2008 interview with <em>The Believer</em>:</p>
<blockquote><p>So, there were some projects I never really could get going, and one of them was <em>Psycho</em>. It was a project that I suggested earlier in the ’90s. It was the first time that I was able to actually do what I suggested. And the reason that I suggested <em>Psycho</em> to them was partly the artistic appropriation side, but it was also partly because I had been in the business long enough that I was aware of certain executives’ desires. The most interesting films that studios want to be making are sequels. They would rather make sequels than make the originals, which is always a kind of a funny Catch-22.</p>
<p>They have to make <em>Bourne Identity</em> before they make <em>Bourne Ultimatum</em>. They don’t really want to make <em>Bourne Identity</em> because it’s a trial thing. But they really want to make <em>Bourne Ultimatum</em>. So it was an idea I had—you know, why don’t you guys just start remaking your hits.</p></blockquote>
<p>Lately it seems that the studios trip over themselves to reboot their franchises&#8212;the latest <em>Spider-Man </em>film (the one you probably forgot existed) being a choice example of corporate venality. In a way, it&#8217;s fascinating that Sam Raimi, something of an outsider director, was allowed to do the first <em>Spider-Man</em> films at all. Of course, now and then a franchise film (or potential franchise film) winds up in the hands of an auteur&#8212;take <em>Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban</em>, for example. Alfonso Cuarón&#8217;s third entry in the franchise can stand on its own (it certainly saved the franchise from the tepid visions of Chris Columbus). Even stranger, take Paul Verhoeven&#8217;s films <i>RoboCop</i> and <em>Starship Troopers. </em>These films were brilliant subversive satires, and what did Hollywood do to the movies that came after them? These franchises devolved into flavorless, flawed, run of the mill muck.</p>
<p>Of course, entertainment conglomerates have good (economic) reasons to &#8220;protect&#8221; their product. David Lynch&#8217;s <em>Dune</em> remains one of the great cautionary tales in recent cinema history. What could have reinvigorated &#8220;New Hollywood&#8221; instead proved a disastrous flop.<i> </i> <em>Dune </em>never panned out as the blockbuster franchise that it could have been; instead, it gets to hang out in a strange limbo, greeting newer arrivals like Chris Weitz&#8217;s atrocious<i> </i>adaptation of <em>The Golden Compass</em> and Andrew Stanton&#8217;s underrated <em>John Carter from Mars</em>. It&#8217;s actually sort of surreal that we even <em>got</em> a <em>Dune</em> film by David Lynch, complete with Kyle MacLachlan, Brad Dourif, Jack Nance, and fucking Sting.</p>
<p>What&#8217;s even <em>weirder</em> is that <a href="http://biblioklept.org/2011/01/26/alejandro-jodorowsky-on-david-lynchs-dune-and-other-matters/" target="_blank">Alejandro Jodorowsky tried to adapt <em>Dune</em></a><em>,</em> working with artists H.R. Geiger and Moebius. (Jodorowsky also planned to involve Orson Welles, Mick Jagger, and  Karlheinz Stockhausen among others in the film). What a Jodorowsky <em>Dune</em> film might have looked like is a constant source of frustrated fun for film buffs.</p>
<p>But what about a Star Wars film by Jodorowsky? What might that look like?</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-24535" alt="the star wars hartter" src="http://biblioklept.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the-star-wars-hartter.jpg?w=720"   /></p>
<p><a href="http://hartter.blogspot.com/2009/11/misc.html" target="_blank">Sean Hartter imagines such prospects in his marvelous posters for films from an alternative universe</a>. Hartter&#8217;s posters&#8212;most of which include not just cast and director but also specific studios, producers, and soundtrack composers and musicians&#8212;conjure up wonderful <em>could-have-beens. </em>They posit the kind of daring spirit and experimentalism I&#8217;d like to see more of from Hollywood franchises.</p>
<p>Most Hollywood franchises revere the illusion of stability in the property&#8212;the idea of a constancy of character throughout film to film. Even a franchise like the James Bond films, with its ever-rotating leads, tries to create the guise of a stable aesthetic along with narrative continuity. I would love to see something closer to the Alien franchise, the only line of films I can think of where each film bears the distinctive mark of its respective filmmaker; even if I don&#8217;t think Fincher&#8217;s <em>Alien 3</em> is a particularly good film, at least it feels and looks and sounds like a Fincher film and not a weak approximation of a Cameron blockbuster or a stock repetition of Scott&#8217;s space horror (and Jeunet&#8217;s <em>Resurrection</em>&#8212;how weird is that one!).</p>
<p>But back to Bond for a moment&#8212;wouldn&#8217;t it be great to see Wes Anderson do James Bond, but as a <i>Wes Anderson film</i>? Or Werner Herzog? Or Cronenberg? What would Jane Campion do with Bond? (I&#8217;m tempted to add Jim Jarmusch, but he already made an excellent James Bond film called <em>The Limits of Control</em>). I&#8217;d love to see a range of auteur versions of the franchise. (Similarly, I&#8217;ve recently been fascinated by the way certain cult artists render major corporate franchise characters, <a href="http://biblioklept.org/2013/01/06/iron-man-dave-sim/" target="_blank">like Dave Sim doing Iron Man</a>, or <a href="http://biblioklept.org/2012/11/25/spider-man-moebius/" target="_blank">Moebius doing Spider-Man</a>, or <a href="http://biblioklept.org/2013/01/19/wonder-woman-jaime-hernandez-3/" target="_blank">Jaime Hernandez doing Wonder Woman</a>). Obviously this fantasy will never happen&#8212;the auteur would have to have complete control&#8212;a Coen brothers&#8217; Bond film would have to be first and foremost a <em>Coen brothers film</em>, not a 007 film&#8212;but hey, just like with Hartter&#8217;s posters, it&#8217;s fun to pretend.</p>
<p>Imagine a year of James Bond movies, one a month, featuring different directors, actors, studios, production designs. 007 films from Spike Lee, Tarantino, Almodavar, Lynne Ramsay, Lynch, Wong Kar Wai.</p>
<p>What would a Wong Kar Wai James Bond film look like?</p>
<p>What would a Wong Kar Wai Star Wars film look like?</p>
<p>I don&#8217;t know. I imagine it would be beautiful and moody and at times impressionistic. I imagine its narrative would tend toward obliqueness. I imagine it might infuriate die-hard fans (I imagine this last part with a big grin). I imagine that it would easily be the most <em>human</em> Star Wars film.</p>
<p>But beyond that, it&#8217;s hard to imagine what a Wong Kar Wai Star Wars film might look and sound and feel like because his films are powerful and moving and evoke the kind of imaginative capacity that marks great art, great <i>original and originating art</i>. Put another way, I can&#8217;t really imagine what a Wong Kar Wai Star Wars film would look like&#8212;which is precisely why I&#8217;d love to see one.</p>
<br /> Tagged: <a href='http://biblioklept.org/tag/abram/'>Abram</a>, <a href='http://biblioklept.org/tag/art/'>Art</a>, <a href='http://biblioklept.org/tag/david-lynch/'>David Lynch</a>, <a href='http://biblioklept.org/tag/dune/'>Dune</a>, <a href='http://biblioklept.org/tag/fantasy/'>Fantasy</a>, <a href='http://biblioklept.org/tag/film/'>Film</a>, <a href='http://biblioklept.org/tag/godfather-films/'>godfather films</a>, <a href='http://biblioklept.org/tag/hollywood-studio-system/'>hollywood studio system</a>, <a href='http://biblioklept.org/tag/j-j-abrams/'>J. J. Abrams</a>, <a href='http://biblioklept.org/tag/john-carter/'>John Carter</a>, <a href='http://biblioklept.org/tag/reviews/'>Reviews</a>, <a href='http://biblioklept.org/tag/sci-fi/'>Sci-Fi</a>, <a href='http://biblioklept.org/tag/spider-man/'>Spider-Man</a>, <a href='http://biblioklept.org/tag/star-trek/'>Star Trek</a>, <a href='http://biblioklept.org/tag/star-wars/'>Star Wars</a>, <a href='http://biblioklept.org/tag/star-wars-franchise/'>star wars franchise</a>, <a href='http://biblioklept.org/tag/wong-kar-wai/'>Wong Kar Wai</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/24512/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/24512/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/24512/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/24512/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/24512/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/24512/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/24512/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/24512/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/24512/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/24512/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/24512/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/24512/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/24512/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/24512/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=24512&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://biblioklept.org/2013/01/25/franchise-films-alternate-worlds-and-why-wong-kar-wai-should-direct-the-next-star-wars-film/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>28</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/629afe3593777a908b53b84b771a7f17?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">biblioklepted</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://biblioklept.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/star-wars-3-hartter.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">STAR WARS 3 hartter</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://biblioklept.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the-star-wars-hartter.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">the star wars hartter</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Let Zero Dark Thirty Be Multi-Faceted</title>
		<link>http://thesmokefilledroomblog.com/2013/01/28/let-zero-dark-thirty-be-multi-faceted/</link>
		<comments>http://thesmokefilledroomblog.com/2013/01/28/let-zero-dark-thirty-be-multi-faceted/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2013 14:15:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Chris Clary</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Conflict]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pakistan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Violence]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thesmokefilledroomblog.com/?p=1289</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Zero Dark Thirty is stuck in a proxy fight over torture. One’s view of the movie seems to be a referendum on whether you think the torture portrayed in the film was essential to the information that ultimately led to the raid in Abbottabad. But perhaps I’m naïve to think that a theme of the [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1289&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Zero Dark Thirty is stuck in a proxy fight over torture. One’s view of the movie seems to be a referendum on whether you think the torture portrayed in the film was essential to the information that ultimately led to the raid in Abbottabad. But perhaps I’m naïve to think that a theme of the film is that people are people and violence is violence. (Bear with me, even as you say to yourself, tautology is tautology.)</p>
<p>The opening torture sequence is often lumped in with “24,” but I think it is different from similar scenes in that TV series for three reasons. First, the movie’s protagonist is deeply troubled by the torture, even as she continues her participation in it. Jack Bauer never doubted the necessity of his actions or showed any qualms. Maya (Jessica Chastain) does. Even her mentor, Dan (Jason Clark), seems wounded by his involvement in such acts as the movie progresses. Second, the tortured prisoner is not shown doing any concrete harm prior to the torture. Yes, the immediately prior scene involves 9/11, but the prisoner undergoing “enhanced interrogation” has a somewhat distant link to that trauma—a “money man,” related to a more important planner, not important in his own right. Third, and relatedly, Reda Ketab portrays the tortured prisoner with impressive humanity. Torture in movies sometimes feels like vengeance; here the audience’s sympathies lie with the tortured man. Why are the CIA agents doing this? Why do they continue? And the vindication of the torture is diffuse at best. It is unclear if the information was revealed because of the torture, or just because of the sleep deprivation. Ketab’s character, Ammar, does not reveal his information to avoid more pain or more simulated drowning. His revelation is disconnected physically and temporally from his pain. He is, in essence, tricked into revealing his information, and that information has no real effect on finding bin Laden until years later. At which point, numerous other individuals have separately provided that same information. It seems quite likely that the torture was unnecessary; the information would have come anyway. I can think of no episode of “24” with a similar equifinality with regard to torture.</p>
<p>Which brings me back to this theme of people being people and violence being violence. It seems a message of the movie is that 9/11 led the United States to do considerable harm in its efforts to both retaliate for the harm done and also prevent future harm. One might think the harm was justified, but it doesn’t erase pain inflicted by the United States. The film doesn’t shy away from demonstrating that U.S. efforts are not always “clean.” The movie shows that violence is still violence, and not pretty. While mentally I knew that there were others in the compound when the raid took place, it is different to know this than it is to see their deaths portrayed. There were wives and children in the compound. The movie goes out of its way to show that the children likely saw their parents being killed in front of them, and wives saw their husbands dying. The raiding team is shown as troubled by these aspects, even as they continue.</p>
<p>The conservative columnist George Will occasionally will argue that individuals have to make a determination for themselves as to whether it is possible to “economize violence,” to employ violence now in an effort to prevent greater violence in the future. But even if it is morally valid to employ violence for prevention or retribution, it doesn’t sanitize the violence. Violence damages people—both the victims and the perpetrators. I feel as if Zero Dark Thirty broadcasts that message, but no one is listening because they are too busy re-litigating torture controversies. The people killed and tortured in this movie are portrayed as people, even if their screen time is brief. The violence undertaken for U.S. interests is not elided or ignored by the director. Only bin Laden himself is never shown, and in a way denied personhood by Bigelow and Boal.</p>
<p>And how does the movie end? With a weeping Maya having accomplished her goal. She does not know what she is going to do or where she is supposed to go. The quest for bin Laden has destroyed her as a social creature, has taken her humanity. It is tough for me to square the images of Zero Dark Thirty with a conclusion that it glamorizes the hunt for bin Laden or vindicates decisions taken by the Bush administration. The movie shows U.S. choices as complicated and painful. By showing images of episodes too often described only as text in a CNN chyron, it forces us to “see” the choices our government makes. The next time you are reading of a drone strike in Pakistan or a raid in Yemen, visualize what the scene of violence actually looked like. The decision might still be morally valid, perhaps even morally praiseworthy, but the action almost certainly was not pretty or glamorous. People are people. Violence is violence.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1289/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1289/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1289&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thesmokefilledroomblog.com/2013/01/28/let-zero-dark-thirty-be-multi-faceted/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/cc5d1c5bc68752c5d6a522e9ad70e827?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">chrisclary</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Photos from the Aftermath of Tahrir Clashes</title>
		<link>http://asenseofbelonging.org/2013/01/29/photos-from-the-aftermath-of-tahrir-clashes/</link>
		<comments>http://asenseofbelonging.org/2013/01/29/photos-from-the-aftermath-of-tahrir-clashes/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 15:05:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>jnjcasper</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Current Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jayson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Egypt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Helwan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ismaïlia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Maadi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Port Said]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Suez Canal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tahrir Square]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://asenseofbelonging.org/?p=3800</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Egypt has just witnessed some of the fiercest clashes in the revolutionary era, as many protestors appear radicalized. There are still peaceful demonstrations, to be sure, but even these appear to be violently resisted by police. It is hard to blame the police, though, as the lines are blurred. I missed out on the latest [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3800&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_3801" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://asenseofbelonging.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/cornish-tree.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-3801" alt="Cornish Tree" src="http://asenseofbelonging.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/cornish-tree.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">An uprooted tree on the Nile Cornish, just outside of Tahrir Square. Muslim rules of war forbid the wanton destruction of nature.</p></div>
<p>Egypt has just witnessed some of the fiercest clashes in the revolutionary era, as many protestors appear radicalized. There are still peaceful demonstrations, to be sure, but even these appear to be violently resisted by police. It is hard to blame the police, though, as the lines are blurred.</p>
<p>I missed out on the latest battles. I spent January 25 in Helwan, a city to the south of Cairo at the end of the Metro line. The Muslim Brotherhood was conducting an outreach campaign to counter-program the message of demonstrations and unrest offered in Tahrir. I planned to take the Metro downtown to see these protestors, but on the way the car stopped and sat for five minutes &#8211; at the very stop nearest our home in Maadi.</p>
<p>Demonstrators in Tahrir had cut the tracks, causing a backup. Rather than waiting what could be an hour or more, based on previous examples, I left and went home, seeking to catch up on the news of the day, and perhaps go down after a bit.</p>
<p>A minute later, before I was able to exit the station, the Metro started up again. Perhaps it was propitious I had left.</p>
<p>These pictures taken this morning are from my first visit back to Tahrir. The worst clashes occurred in the Suez Canal cities of Port Said, Ismailia, and Suez, where a state of emergency has been declared. It is hard to know precisely what happened anywhere &#8211; the consequence of sitting home and following news updates and Twitter bylines. But the pictures to follow give a disturbing indication of where Egypt stands at the moment.</p>
<p>Is this the last gasp of resistance to a new order, or a sign of worse things yet to come? Please pray for Egypt, either way.</p>
<div id="attachment_3802" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://asenseofbelonging.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/rock-pile.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-3802" alt="The worst clashes took place on the Nile Cornish. This rock pile is on the road leading there from Tahrir, where protestors would retreat to reload in the volleys against the police." src="http://asenseofbelonging.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/rock-pile.jpg?w=300&#038;h=224" width="300" height="224" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The worst clashes took place on the Nile Cornish. This rock pile is on the road leading there from Tahrir, where protestors would retreat to reload for their volleys against the police.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_3803" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://asenseofbelonging.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/semiramses-door.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-3803" alt="At one point during the fighting, armed criminals broke in to the Semiramsis Hotel, smashing this door. According to reports, protestors intervened and beat them off." src="http://asenseofbelonging.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/semiramses-door.jpg?w=300&#038;h=224" width="300" height="224" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">At one point during the fighting, armed criminals broke in to the Semiramsis Hotel, smashing this door. According to reports, protestors intervened and beat them off.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_3804" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://asenseofbelonging.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/cornish-cleanup.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-3804" alt="Outside on the Cornish clean up crews were hard at work collecting the debris, preparing the road for traffic" src="http://asenseofbelonging.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/cornish-cleanup.jpg?w=300&#038;h=224" width="300" height="224" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Outside on the Cornish clean up crews were hard at work collecting the debris, preparing the road for traffic.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_3805" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://asenseofbelonging.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/tahrir-roadblock.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-3805" alt="Traffic into Tahrir, however, was blocked by these makeshift barricades." src="http://asenseofbelonging.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/tahrir-roadblock.jpg?w=300&#038;h=224" width="300" height="224" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Traffic into Tahrir, however, was blocked by these makeshift barricades.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_3806" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://asenseofbelonging.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/bridge-blocking.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-3806" alt="And on the bridge across the Nile leading into Tahrir, group of protestors were trying to block traffic, as they had over the previous few days. This attempt petered out after about five minutes." src="http://asenseofbelonging.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/bridge-blocking.jpg?w=300&#038;h=224" width="300" height="224" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">And on the bridge across the Nile leading into Tahrir, group of protestors were trying to block traffic, as they had over the previous few days. This attempt petered out after about five minutes.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_3807" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://asenseofbelonging.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/cornish-cameraman.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-3807" alt="Meanwhile, camera crews were already in place, awaiting the next round of violence." src="http://asenseofbelonging.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/cornish-cameraman.jpg?w=300&#038;h=224" width="300" height="224" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Meanwhile, camera crews were already in place, awaiting the next round of violence.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_3808" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://asenseofbelonging.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/burned-out-police-van.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-3808" alt="Back in Tahrir, things were calm, as protestors celebrated their previous night's capture off a police van." src="http://asenseofbelonging.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/burned-out-police-van.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Back in Tahrir, things were calm, as protestors celebrated their previous night&#8217;s capture off a police van.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_3809" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://asenseofbelonging.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/tahrir-pizza-hut.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-3809" alt="Even the local Pizza Hut was open for business - sort of." src="http://asenseofbelonging.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/tahrir-pizza-hut.jpg?w=300&#038;h=224" width="300" height="224" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Even the local Pizza Hut was open for business &#8211; sort of.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_3810" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://asenseofbelonging.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/tahrir-museum.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-3810" alt="Protestors opened their very own Tahrir Museum in the center circle of the roundabout." src="http://asenseofbelonging.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/tahrir-museum.jpg?w=300&#038;h=224" width="300" height="224" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Protestors opened their very own Revolution Museum in the center circle of the Tahrir roundabout.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_3811" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 234px"><a href="http://asenseofbelonging.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/omar-makram-statue-e1359470952523.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-3811" alt="The celebrated statue of Omar Makram had a new round of graffiti." src="http://asenseofbelonging.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/omar-makram-statue-e1359470952523.jpg?w=224&#038;h=300" width="224" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The celebrated statue of Omar Makram had a new round of graffiti.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_3813" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://asenseofbelonging.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/tahrir-mural.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-3813" alt="And the walls were updated with the pictures of the latest martyrs and targets of political rejection. Here, the Muslim Brotherhood's General Guide hovers behind a split image of Mubarak and former army General Tantawi." src="http://asenseofbelonging.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/tahrir-mural.jpg?w=300&#038;h=224" width="300" height="224" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">And the walls were updated with the pictures of the latest martyrs and targets of political rejection. Here, the Muslim Brotherhood&#8217;s General Guide hovers behind a split image of Mubarak and former army head General Tantawi. A plaque has been affixed bearing a verse from the Quran.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_3814" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 234px"><a href="http://asenseofbelonging.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/tahrir-flag-e1359471308149.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-3814" alt="But at some point since my last visit a huge Egyptian flag had been draped on the side of this building. Perhaps it can be read as a sign of hope." src="http://asenseofbelonging.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/tahrir-flag-e1359471308149.jpg?w=224&#038;h=300" width="224" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">But at some point since my last visit a huge Egyptian flag had been draped on the side of this building. Perhaps it can be read as a sign of hope.</p></div>
<p><strong>Related Posts: </strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://asenseofbelonging.org/2013/01/24/family-in-tahrir/" target="_blank">Family in Tahrir</a> &#8211; January 24, 2013</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://asenseofbelonging.wordpress.com/2011/05/16/thoughts-and-photos-from-friday-protest-national-unity-and-palestinian-solidarity/" target="_blank">Thoughts and Pictures from Friday Protest for National Unity and Palestinian Solidarity</a> &#8211; May 16, 2011</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://asenseofbelonging.wordpress.com/2011/04/16/observations-and-photos-post-revolution/" target="_blank">Observations and Photos, post-Revolution</a> &#8211; April 20, 2011</li>
</ul>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3800/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3800/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3800&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://asenseofbelonging.org/2013/01/29/photos-from-the-aftermath-of-tahrir-clashes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>25</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://asenseofbelonging.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/cornish-tree.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://asenseofbelonging.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/cornish-tree.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Cornish Tree</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a3488c32ae2d8d6bc5c682d743cdea06?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jnjcasper</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://asenseofbelonging.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/cornish-tree.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Cornish Tree</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://asenseofbelonging.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/rock-pile.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The worst clashes took place on the Nile Cornish. This rock pile is on the road leading there from Tahrir, where protestors would retreat to reload in the volleys against the police.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://asenseofbelonging.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/semiramses-door.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">At one point during the fighting, armed criminals broke in to the Semiramsis Hotel, smashing this door. According to reports, protestors intervened and beat them off.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://asenseofbelonging.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/cornish-cleanup.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Outside on the Cornish clean up crews were hard at work collecting the debris, preparing the road for traffic</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://asenseofbelonging.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/tahrir-roadblock.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Traffic into Tahrir, however, was blocked by these makeshift barricades.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://asenseofbelonging.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/bridge-blocking.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">And on the bridge across the Nile leading into Tahrir, group of protestors were trying to block traffic, as they had over the previous few days. This attempt petered out after about five minutes.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://asenseofbelonging.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/cornish-cameraman.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Meanwhile, camera crews were already in place, awaiting the next round of violence.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://asenseofbelonging.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/burned-out-police-van.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Back in Tahrir, things were calm, as protestors celebrated their previous night&#039;s capture off a police van.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://asenseofbelonging.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/tahrir-pizza-hut.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Even the local Pizza Hut was open for business - sort of.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://asenseofbelonging.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/tahrir-museum.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Protestors opened their very own Tahrir Museum in the center circle of the roundabout.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://asenseofbelonging.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/omar-makram-statue-e1359470952523.jpg?w=224" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The celebrated statue of Omar Makram had a new round of graffiti.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://asenseofbelonging.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/tahrir-mural.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">And the walls were updated with the pictures of the latest martyrs and targets of political rejection. Here, the Muslim Brotherhood&#039;s General Guide hovers behind a split image of Mubarak and former army General Tantawi.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://asenseofbelonging.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/tahrir-flag-e1359471308149.jpg?w=224" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">But at some point since my last visit a huge Egyptian flag had been draped on the side of this building. Perhaps it can be read as a sign of hope.</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>DIY: How to Make Handmade Postcards</title>
		<link>http://pradaforbreakfast.wordpress.com/2013/01/06/diy-how-to-make-handmade-postcards/</link>
		<comments>http://pradaforbreakfast.wordpress.com/2013/01/06/diy-how-to-make-handmade-postcards/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2013 08:01:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Prada For Breakfast</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[homemade]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how-to]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cardstock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[do it yourself]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[handmade]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[magazines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mail]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[postcard]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://pradaforbreakfast.wordpress.com/?p=1470</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Snail mail is one of my favorite things to receive. There&#8217;s nothing like opening your mailbox and (after sorting through all the junk catalogues and bills) finding a letter from one of your best friends, or even a Christmas card from distant relatives. There&#8217;s a quality to handwritten mail (and postcards, short as they may [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1470&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://pradaforbreakfast.wordpress.com/2013/01/06/diy-how-to-make-handmade-postcards/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>60</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/40d4274bf7fe849d0a844a7ed65799e5?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">HALIE</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://pradaforbreakfast.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/header.jpg?w=560" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">header</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://pradaforbreakfast.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/1-supplies.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">1-supplies</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://pradaforbreakfast.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/step2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">step2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://pradaforbreakfast.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/step3.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">step3</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://pradaforbreakfast.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/step5.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">step5</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://pradaforbreakfast.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/designs.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">designs</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://pradaforbreakfast.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/poetry.jpg?w=560" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">poetry</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://pradaforbreakfast.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/ne.jpg?w=560" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ne</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://pradaforbreakfast.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/butterfly.jpg?w=560" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">butterfly</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://pradaforbreakfast.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/butterfly-process.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">butterfly-process</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://pradaforbreakfast.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/fortune.jpg?w=560" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">fortune</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://pradaforbreakfast.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/dye1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">dye1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://pradaforbreakfast.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/fortune-back.jpg?w=560" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">fortune-back</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://pradaforbreakfast.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/ny.jpg?w=560" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ny</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://pradaforbreakfast.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/newspaper.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">newspaper</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://pradaforbreakfast.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/cairo.jpg?w=560" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cairo</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://pradaforbreakfast.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/paris.jpg?w=560" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">paris</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://pradaforbreakfast.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/parisprocess.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">parisprocess</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://pradaforbreakfast.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/paris-back.jpg?w=560" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">paris-back</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://pradaforbreakfast.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/writing.jpg?w=560" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">writing</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
