<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 21:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Heart—Posterior View</title>
		<link>http://lindatownsdin.wordpress.com/2013/02/13/heart-posterior-view/</link>
		<comments>http://lindatownsdin.wordpress.com/2013/02/13/heart-posterior-view/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2013 17:41:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>ltownsdin</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Poetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amherst Writers & Artists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mixed media art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poetic short fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing groups]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://lindatownsdin.wordpress.com/?p=357</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Made up of two halves, the heart is divided by the septum. &#160; Where did the rift between us occur? Left subclavian artery or aortic arch? Perhaps the right atrium, always pulsing, pumping out those feelings. &#160; Or was it the oh so superior vena cava? Most likely the inferior. My inferior vena cava has [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=357&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Made up of two halves,</p>
<p>the heart is divided by the septum.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Where did the rift between us occur?</p>
<p>Left subclavian artery or aortic arch?</p>
<p>Perhaps the right atrium, always pulsing,</p>
<p>pumping out those feelings.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Or was it the oh so superior vena cava?</p>
<p>Most likely the inferior.</p>
<p>My inferior vena cava has always felt, well, inferior.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>After all our history, your footprints</p>
<p>were all over my pericardium.</p>
<p>How could they not be</p>
<p>after confessing every heartbreak</p>
<p>every fear, every shameful secret?</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>And each triumph</p>
<p>when shared with you</p>
<p>more meaningful.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>When you abandoned me</p>
<p>my left common carotid artery</p>
<p>bled out.</p>
<p>I was half a person</p>
<p>with half a heart.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>I blame the septum.</p>
<p>Always divisive, controlling</p>
<p>what comes in and what goes out.</p>
<p>Published in <i>Soul of the Narrator Anthology</i> Vol. III, Fall 2012</p>
<div id="attachment_359" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://lindatownsdin.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/009.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-359" alt="Mixed MediaLinda Townsdin" src="http://lindatownsdin.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/009.jpg?w=300&#038;h=224" width="300" height="224" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Mixed Media<br />Linda Townsdin</p></div>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/357/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/357/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=357&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://lindatownsdin.wordpress.com/2013/02/13/heart-posterior-view/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>15</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/3b2a96dbd5126237bb6d3053e7cfb93c?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ltownsdin</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lindatownsdin.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/009.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mixed MediaLinda Townsdin</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Loved By Me</title>
		<link>http://sanesamantha.wordpress.com/2013/02/13/loved-by-me/</link>
		<comments>http://sanesamantha.wordpress.com/2013/02/13/loved-by-me/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2013 14:14:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>SaneSamantha</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://sanesamantha.wordpress.com/?p=1794</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[If, like me, you find yourself alone on Valentine’s Day, please do as I do &#8211; treat yourself well. As the spotlight shines down and reveals that you have yet to end your day looking into the eyes of your life’s love, or even that of a mere lover, use the day to look into [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1794&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_1795" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 490px"><a href="http://sanesamantha.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/lovedbyme.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1795" alt="http://mysticmedusa.com/2013/01/the-upside-of-being-a-love-zombie/" src="http://sanesamantha.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/lovedbyme.jpg?w=720"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text"><a href="http://mysticmedusa.com/2013/01/the-upside-of-being-a-love-zombie/" rel="nofollow">http://mysticmedusa.com/2013/01/the-upside-of-being-a-love-zombie/</a></p></div>
<p>If, like me, you find yourself alone on Valentine’s Day, please do as I do &#8211; treat yourself well. As the spotlight shines down and reveals that you have yet to end your day looking into the eyes of your life’s love, or even that of a mere lover, use the day to look into yourself. And when you do, please do so with kindness. Fall in love with you.</p>
<p>It almost seems like a superfluous concept &#8211; to fall in love with one’s self. And yet, it is your self that will follow you wherever you go. It is yourself that will talk to you when no one is there. Your self will damn you. Your self will love you. The belief you have in yourself can cause you to crumble or it can cause you to reach unprecedented heights. The energy and perspective you put into you &#8211; you will receive from you in the form of inner knowing, conviction and peace.</p>
<p>On this day, instead of giving free rein to a mind that critiques and reminds us of our failures, come to peace with those moments when the outcome for which you had most hoped didn’t manifest. Think about giving yourself credit for having survived something that, at the time, felt like death. When you look in the mirror, instead of seeing the effects of time and stress, see a face that has viewed some of the ugliest of circumstances, and yet can radiantly shine when caught up in laughter. And when you look down at your body, try not to see those things that cause you disappointment. Try to remember that your body is giving you it&#8217;s very best, dependent upon what you are giving it. Furthermore, if your body is like mine, it has moved through hell and back, perhaps more than once. And when the time comes that you are confronted with your life’s love, they will see your beauty &#8211; because doing so is inherent to the nature of who they are. A divine love is divinely given, and thus sees the divine in us even when we falter and struggle to see it for ourselves.</p>
<p>Go easy on you. I would recommend that you take every day to treat yourself well. But if not, then please use tomorrow as a celebration of the love you are cultivating for you. Making peace with yourself. Loving your many attributes, thoughts, hopes and dreams is the beginning of the most important relationship one can have &#8211; the one we have with ourself. You will be with you during your greatest successes, your deepest disappointments and upon your final day. And if you are blessed to meet up with your life’s love, you’ll then be coming from a place not of insecurity, but of acceptance. You’ve accepted you, which will allow you to accept them.</p>
<p>I won’t deny that the favorable ending for tomorrow would be in front of a fire or wrapped in the arms of one’s lover. That would be my chosen route. But instead, I will endeavor to treat myself well. I will remind myself of my own beauty. My triumphs. My successes. My gifts. I will also spend the day spoiling me as I would wish to be spoiled by a partner. I will stop off and enjoy the taste of something delectable; its a fair assumption dark chocolate will be involved. I will peruse my favorite boutiques and I will allow my body to get pampered. Most of all, I will go easy on me. And my hope is that you go easy on you. Whether you are loved by many, loved by one or only loved by you &#8211; never forget &#8211; you are quite special.</p>
<p>Sane</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1794/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1794/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1794&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://sanesamantha.wordpress.com/2013/02/13/loved-by-me/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>21</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/510ff7e2048068f20d718f2414c8333f?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sanesamantha</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://sanesamantha.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/lovedbyme.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">http://mysticmedusa.com/2013/01/the-upside-of-being-a-love-zombie/</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Riding the Bus with Gido</title>
		<link>http://waitingonaword.wordpress.com/2013/02/11/daily-post-weekly-writing-challenge/</link>
		<comments>http://waitingonaword.wordpress.com/2013/02/11/daily-post-weekly-writing-challenge/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2013 18:08:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jess</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[body pillow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[characters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[daily post weekly writing challenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPchallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[public bus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[purple heart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://waitingonaword.wordpress.com/?p=542</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This week&#8217;s writing challenge on the Daily Post blog (www.dailypost.wordpress.com) is to describe a character from your life. Check out the challenge here. This is my contribution. I am twelve years old and I just woke up at Gido&#8217;s house. Gido is my grandfather and we will be spending the day together. Gido slept on [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=542&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>This week&#8217;s writing challenge on the Daily Post blog (www.dailypost.wordpress.com) is to describe a character from your life. Check out the challenge <a href="http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2013/02/11/weekly-writing-challenge-characters/">here</a>. This is my contribution.</em></p>
<p>I am twelve years old and I just woke up at Gido&#8217;s house. Gido is my grandfather and we will be spending the day together.</p>
<p>Gido slept on the floor all night, because that&#8217;s what he does. He lays on the hard floor in front of the television with a big body pillow and sleeps. I don&#8217;t ask why, but I think it has something to do with the war. Now that he&#8217;s older and has had more surgeries than anyone ever, and the scars to show it, I wonder why he still prefers the floor. Despite his many scars, he never complains about pain or the war. I don&#8217;t even know how he won his Purple Heart. He never talks about it.</p>
<p>In fact, he doesn&#8217;t talk much at all. He&#8217;s quiet, but observant. And handsome. Everyone says he&#8217;s handsome.</p>
<p>The first thing he does every morning, even when I am visiting, is feed the birds. He grabs a couple of slices of old bread and heads outside to the street.  I watch from the porch as he rolls the bread in his hands and walks backwards down the middle of the road, leaving a trail of breadcrumbs before him. I see the birds waiting patiently on the neighbors&#8217; rooftops for their breakfast. Hundreds of them looking for Gido.</p>
<p>He joins me on the porch and we watch the birds feast. We don&#8217;t talk much. Days with Gido are calm and quiet.</p>
<p>When I am with Gido, I get to take the public bus. Gido never learned how to drive. It&#8217;s just another thing that makes him different. He walks a lot, or takes the bus, or mom drives him around. Mom never complains about driving him where he needs to go because he was a single parent, and a good parent, when his wife died.  Mom respects him for that and loves and likes him. Mom was twelve when my grandmother died. The same age as me now. I wonder if I remind him of my mom when she was a kid.</p>
<p>Gido knows the bus driver since he often rides this route. They greet each other and Gido pays my fare since I don&#8217;t know how to ride the bus. Today we are going to the bank in the strip mall.  It&#8217;s not very far, but too far to walk.  We sit facing sideways.</p>
<p>People like Gido because he&#8217;s quiet. He only says things that are necessary, and he&#8217;s a good listener. He remembers what you tell him. Once, my aunt told him that she liked these pistachios he bought from the Syrian bakery, so he buys her a giant bag every Christmas, even though my aunt calls him our &#8220;gi-due&#8221; instead of &#8220;gi-daw,&#8221; the way we say it.</p>
<p>Sometimes he gets silly and sings wacky songs about buglers and the army and the moon and pretty ladies. He sings softly and smiles even when we roll our eyes and wonder if he&#8217;s crazy. He likes to play cards with his buddies at &#8220;the post&#8221; where the other Syrians and vets hang out, but he doesn&#8217;t drink and he quit smoking cold turkey in one day. He smoked a pack, wrote the date on it, and said it was the last pack he&#8217;d ever smoke. And it was.  But he still likes the company and the food at &#8220;the post.&#8221;</p>
<p>When we go places, we bring him with us. He is always gently pleasant, except for the two trips that he hated: apple-picking and off-roading over sand dunes. I can&#8217;t blame him though because apple-picking was exhausting, and the sand dunes were really bumpy and uncomfortable, even for me.  These are the only two times I&#8217;ve heard him complain.  He&#8217;s only human, after all.</p>
<p>We step off the bus and he shuffles his feet as we walk through the parking lot to the bank. He always shuffles his feet and he always wears black socks and shoes, and his one foot turns inward. My mom says my brother has that same foot and is a lot like Gido, but I don&#8217;t agree. My brother is annoying and Gido never annoys me.</p>
<p>We walk slowly. Normally, I have to walk fast, from here to there to everywhere, but Gido goes slow, and it&#8217;s a nice change. I breathe the air and realize the sun is warm today. I look up at him and see his face is tan, maybe from walking everywhere in the hot summer, or from his Syrian ancestry, or both.</p>
<p>He stops, looking at the pavement with his dark eyes. I follow his gaze and see a small doll. He bends down and picks it up and hands it to me. &#8220;If you go slowly and keep your eyes open you&#8217;ll find things,&#8221; he says. It&#8217;s not the first time he&#8217;s found stuff that way. Sometimes it&#8217;s old coins or bottle caps, keys, or flowers. He finds them because he takes his time and looks. I never wonder what he&#8217;s thinking when he&#8217;s quiet. I assume it&#8217;s none of my business, or he&#8217;s looking for stuff.</p>
<p>I hold the doll and she rides back on the bus with me. I tell myself to remember to always go slowly and keep my eyes open to find the treasures of the world. I look at the slow, simple, peaceful man sitting next to me and feel lucky that he&#8217;s my grandfather.  My Gido.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/542/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/542/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=542&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://waitingonaword.wordpress.com/2013/02/11/daily-post-weekly-writing-challenge/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>22</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a71e57dbbb72930cdbdeb8d2a74b8abc?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">waitingonaword</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Mutants Offspring</title>
		<link>http://itchyneurons.wordpress.com/2013/02/12/the-mutant/</link>
		<comments>http://itchyneurons.wordpress.com/2013/02/12/the-mutant/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2013 07:39:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>itchy</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Random firing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[characters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPchallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[foundation series]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Isaac Asimov]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[labrador]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mind control]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weekly writing challenge]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://itchyneurons.wordpress.com/?p=1286</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This is a humorous take on our affection for dogs and how they may have hypnotized the humans. Asimov fans of the Foundation series will recognize the &#8216;Mule&#8217; &#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212; The Mule was sterile. Is that what you thought? That, when he died the random threat was over? You read the Encyclopedia Galactica and assumed that was [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1286&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>This is a humorous take on our affection for dogs and how they may have hypnotized the humans. Asimov fans of the Foundation series will recognize the &#8216;Mule&#8217; <img src='http://s0.wp.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif' alt=':)' class='wp-smiley' /> </em></p>
<p>&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;</p>
<p>The Mule was sterile.</p>
<p>Is that what you thought? That, when he died the random threat was over? You read the E<em>ncyclopedia Galactica</em> and assumed that was how things went? Ah, but emotions control the chemicals in the brain you know, and they in turn control the changes in the body. That is how it had always worked for the Mule. Emotional control was his tool and he used it to solve the problem with his body.</p>
<p>He knew he had two flaws, his inability to produce offspring and his jarring ugly physical appearance. The initial mutations must have induced parthenogenesis and subsequently, sexual differentiation. It was changing his appearance that proved tricky. There is no guarantee of conserving good looks,  and he wanted his offsprings to rule forever, over generations. Ultimately he made a choice.  He would alter the physical features entirely such that it would not resemble the humanoid form at all. He changed the limbs and added an extended coccyx, but he did not mess with the eyes. The eyes were important.</p>
<p>The control over the galaxy remained, though the inhabitants were not aware of it.  That was how he wanted it.  That was how he had managed to become the greatest conquerors the galaxy had ever seen. He was a random mutation himself, and he was born with the ability to reach into the minds of others and adjust their emotions. It was because of this that though he was ruthless, he did not have to kill or torture. The people he ruled over had once hated and feared him, but he had changed their emotional waves to adoration and respect for himself.  He had probed and felt emotional patterns of individuals and of masses, and he knew it to be true.</p>
<p>The Mule died a natural death but his progeny remained and bred and still rule over us. The mind control is oh-so-subtle. It is the soulful eyes that do it. They seem to look straight into your heart, but they  are actually probing your mind patterns and changing them till you feel the warmth of affection flood your senses.  The emotional adjustment inflicted is almost artistic . The behavioral pattern  and memories remain intact, the ‘adjustment’ works only to create affection and a willingness to please and obey orders.</p>
<p>They look at you and you are mesmerized, you take them home and look after them thinking you are the master, but then that is how they wanted it in the first place. Mind control so subtle that when you make them do ‘tricks’ you have not the faintest idea that it is they who have trained you to get them food. You are only a tool.</p>
<p>It is the eyes that do it, and also the extended coccyx, the tail. It wags and we move accordingly, in affection.</p>
<p>&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;-</p>
<p>P.S. i am under the control of a 3 month old labrador retriever. He has adjusted our mind patterns and is now part of our family.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1286/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1286/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1286&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://itchyneurons.wordpress.com/2013/02/12/the-mutant/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/16a4de69dcd81492023c94914bba1f53?s=96&#38;d=retro&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">archanabist</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ode to Grams</title>
		<link>http://ramblingsofanorthernlass.com/2013/02/12/ode-to-grams/</link>
		<comments>http://ramblingsofanorthernlass.com/2013/02/12/ode-to-grams/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2013 11:15:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>devvers</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Random]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clothing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPchallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weekly Writing Challenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ramblingsofanorthernlass.com/?p=563</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[To anyone else she was just another old lady staring blindly in the general direction of the communal TV which was blaring out mindless daytime chat shows for its gathered audience. She wasn&#8217;t just any old lady though; she was Eleanor Craig, my grandma. On first glance she was tiny and frail until her weary, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=563&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>To anyone else she was just another old lady staring blindly in the general direction of the communal TV which was blaring out mindless daytime chat shows for its gathered audience. She wasn&#8217;t just any old lady though; she was Eleanor Craig, my grandma.</p>
<p>On first glance she was tiny and frail until her weary, watery eyes met yours in the doorway. The cloud of confusion slowly cleared from her pale blue eyes and was replaced by a sparkling of recognition. As you walked towards her, she appeared to grow, until her presence and welcoming smile filled the room. Arms outstretched as soon as you took your first step towards her, her hands beckoned you greedily into her embrace. A hug from Grandma was like no other. I swear it had medicinal properties. It seemed to wrap you into a cotton-wool world where only you and she existed, and no harm could come to you Despite her 5&#8217;2 frame, her soft, cushioned arms enclosed around your shoulders, dragging you into the crook of her neck. Once there, you were rocked from side to side and sang a ditty from her school days. It was comforting and magical; the world could never get you once you were with Grandma.</p>
<p>There was always something regal about Grandma when she sat in her chair. Her personality demanding the respect she had earned and deserved throughout the 94 years of her life. The straightness of her spine aligned perfectly with the back of the chair, hands often clasped in her lap as she listened eagerly to our stories, or crocheted the endless blankets that filled her cupboards &#8211; and ours. She wasn&#8217;t aloof, we were too poor to be aloof, her manner was affable and playful. Her dresses, conservative florals, were usually blue or purple and served as a blank canvas for the rest of her outfit. She made her mark through her accessorising; 3 or 4 set of plastic beads, bright, often clashing colours and a cardigan or two on a chilly day. brooches. Why choose one when you can wear all your favourites every day? And then there were her rings. Often a ring on every finger that told the story of her life. There was the engagement ring from the 19 year old soldier who didn&#8217;t make it back from the war; the engagement ring from Granddad Craig who at 9 years her elder, declared on the day he met her, she was the girl he was going to marry. The green plastic ring that came out of last year&#8217;s Christmas cracker but was kept for its colour. A colour that matched her crudely painted fingernails &#8211; or at least one or two of them. There was always a story.</p>
<p>It seemed perfectly natural for us to sit on the floor at her feet and memorise her poems. Looking up at her. It didn&#8217;t matter how many times we heard them or how many times she repeated herself. It was all part of the deal. All of us children and grandchildren would subconsciously surround her, hanging on her every word, laughing, teasing, looking up at her, looking up to her. We were protecting the family jewel.</p>
<br /> Tagged: <a href='http://ramblingsofanorthernlass.com/tag/clothing/'>clothing</a>, <a href='http://ramblingsofanorthernlass.com/tag/dpchallenge/'>DPchallenge</a>, <a href='http://ramblingsofanorthernlass.com/tag/family/'>family</a>, <a href='http://ramblingsofanorthernlass.com/tag/weekly-writing-challenge/'>Weekly Writing Challenge</a>, <a href='http://ramblingsofanorthernlass.com/tag/writing/'>writing</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/563/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/563/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/563/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/563/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/563/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/563/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/563/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/563/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/563/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/563/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/563/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/563/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/563/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/563/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=563&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://ramblingsofanorthernlass.com/2013/02/12/ode-to-grams/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a7db77f50a73c2d4c6ef08aa9c0e2cad?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">devvers</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Say It To My Face, Jonah Lehrer</title>
		<link>http://racheldoesscience.wordpress.com/2013/02/12/say-it-to-my-face-jonah-lehrer/</link>
		<comments>http://racheldoesscience.wordpress.com/2013/02/12/say-it-to-my-face-jonah-lehrer/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2013 20:06:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Rachel</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bad science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jonah Lehrer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[knight foundation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plagiarism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science journalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the new yorker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wired]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://racheldoesscience.wordpress.com/?p=246</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Today, Jonah Lehrer gave the final address at the Knight Foundation’s Media Learning Seminar. For an hour, he spoke about his journalistic transgressions over the course of the past few years, which came to light over the summer. He was paid $20,000 for his time.  What struck me the most wasn’t Lehrer’s robotic, characteristically arrogant speech, but [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=246&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today, Jonah Lehrer gave the final address at the Knight Foundation’s <a href="http://ksj.mit.edu/tracker/2013/02/will-jonah-lehrer-discuss-his-journalist">Media Learning Seminar</a>. For an hour, he spoke about his journalistic <a href="http://nymag.com/news/features/jonah-lehrer-2012-11/">transgressions over the course of the past few </a>years, which came to light over the summer.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.poynter.org/latest-news/mediawire/204005/jonah-lehrer-talks-about-plagiarism-at-knight-lunch/">He was paid $20,000 for his time. </a></p>
<p>What struck me the most wasn’t Lehrer’s robotic, characteristically arrogant speech, but one of the questions posed by a conference attendee. She stated flippantly that Lehrer’s plagiarism affected her less than a “typo on Wikipedia,” and didn’t understand why people expected public apology for something that didn’t specifically hurt them.</p>
<p>Alrighty then. Let’s talk about how Jonah Lehrer has hurt the journalism community. Come on, raise your hand if you’ve ever felt personally victimized by Regina George.</p>
<p>First of all, the public inherently trusts successful journalists, especially ones hired as staff writers for publications as reputable as <i>The New Yorker</i>. Should people be skeptical of everything they read? Yes! Please, be skeptical. Should readers have to wonder if every word written in a magazine they trust is a lie or a fabrication? Dear god, I hope not.</p>
<div id="attachment_256" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 437px"><a href="http://racheldoesscience.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/screen-shot-2013-02-12-at-12-52-03-pm.png"><img class=" wp-image-256 " alt="A screencap from our furious twitter rampage " src="http://racheldoesscience.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/screen-shot-2013-02-12-at-12-52-03-pm.png?w=427&#038;h=244" width="427" height="244" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">A screencap from our furious twitter rampage</p></div>
<p>Lehrer was a public darling. I was never a fan of his writing (I found it over simplified and written with a cocky tone that rubbed me the wrong way) but I always appreciated how good he was at playing into what the mainstream wanted to read. To end up in a position like that and then abuse it is to tarnish public view of journalistic morality. Permanently.</p>
<p>Let’s get more specific, shall we? Lehrer wrote about science. Science journalists have another layer of public trust to navigate, because science has gotten a reputation for being confusing, boring, and elitist. It’s hard to get the public listening to you when you talk about science, and Lehrer had his finger on the pulse. So yes, I do feel that there’s something wrong with Lehrer ending up on a science journalism pedestal and then making shit up, pulling quotes out of thin air, and muddling facts so that they fit the narrative he knows will sell a book. Personally.</p>
<p>One more thing. Jonah Lehrer’s behavior was offensive to me. Specifically me. Me, and every other young, emerging science journalist. Do you know how unobtainable a staff position at The New Yorker is, especially for a science writer, in the age of dying print and literary cutbacks? I would cut out my own kidney if it got me a regular blog on Wired, let alone a longterm print contract. The respect, stability, and readership attached to that gig is the sort of thing I’m afraid to even dream of. Jonah Lehrer got it, and he abused it. He recycled old pieces. He copy and pasted from others’ work. He didn’t provide the content he was being paid to provide.</p>
<p>If he hadn’t been caught, that job would still be his–and that would be one less staff position for a young science writer willing to actually write about science.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theatlanticwire.com/national/2013/02/jonah-lehrer-apologizes-surrounded-tweets-still-calling-him-plagiarist/62055/">Did tweeting live zingers</a> about Lehrer while he spoke make me feel better about what he’d done? Not really. Especially now that I know how much money he made for his lackluster public apology.</p>
<p><em id="__mceDel"><em id="__mceDel">Find a new playing field, Lehrer. The other kids don’t want you here anymore. </em></em></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/246/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/246/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=246&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://racheldoesscience.wordpress.com/2013/02/12/say-it-to-my-face-jonah-lehrer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/9efdd2b4f39865185d0a068ae6f74220?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">rahelanne</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://racheldoesscience.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/screen-shot-2013-02-12-at-12-52-03-pm.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">A screencap from our furious twitter rampage </media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pig As a Blanket</title>
		<link>http://sabor-kitchen.com/2013/02/03/pig-as-a-blanket/</link>
		<comments>http://sabor-kitchen.com/2013/02/03/pig-as-a-blanket/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2013 19:27:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>lucasryden</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Appetizers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FOOD]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bacon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cabernet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dates]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flavor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gouda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jalapeno]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Maillard Reaction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Meat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pork]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[umami]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://sabor-kitchen.com/?p=1645</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In the world of culinary fetishes, bacon is king.  No other product has attained this gut-busting level of popularity, creating an utter obsession that &#8211; in some regions of the world &#8211; borders on religious fantacism.  There are now week-long festivals dedicated to bacon.  We eat bacon with chocolate and drink cocktails with bacon-infused vodka.  [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1645&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://sabor-kitchen.com/2013/02/03/pig-as-a-blanket/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://saborkitchen.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/bacondates.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://saborkitchen.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/bacondates.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bacondates</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c658e05b8278c88d0ba8fac2cb9206e5?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lucasryden</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://saborkitchen.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/bacondates.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bacondates</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Body Talk 6</title>
		<link>http://thegirlinthehat.wordpress.com/2013/01/31/body-talk-6/</link>
		<comments>http://thegirlinthehat.wordpress.com/2013/01/31/body-talk-6/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 16:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>girl in the hat</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[personal essays]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Anna Fonte]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Barrington Hall]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[body talk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[girl in the hat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hallucination]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Henry Louis Gates Jr.]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lies my body tells me]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[memoir]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[memory]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[paranoia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[psychosis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thegirlinthehat.wordpress.com/?p=3654</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Lies My Body Tells Me (a list-in-progress): 1. I have cancer. Why does my back hurt? Must be the tumor on my spine. Why are my hands so papery? Cancer sucking me dry. Why am I so tired? Definitely cancer. 2. Okay, maybe it’s not cancer but still, I’m dying right now. It’s 1995 and [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3654&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://thegirlinthehat.wordpress.com/2013/01/31/body-talk-6/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>62</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://thegirlinthehat.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/x-ray-1.png?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://thegirlinthehat.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/x-ray-1.png?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">x ray 1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/1566ebc3679bd30c09178f2e3e75ffeb?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F1.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=R" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">thegirlinthehat</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thegirlinthehat.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/x-ray-1.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">x ray 1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thegirlinthehat.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/x-ray-2.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">x ray 2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thegirlinthehat.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/x-ray-3.png?w=292" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">x ray 3</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Brainpickings Brouhaha and the Problem with Affiliate Links</title>
		<link>http://paidcontent.org/2013/02/14/the-brainpickings-brouhaha-and-the-problem-with-affiliate-links/</link>
		<comments>http://paidcontent.org/2013/02/14/the-brainpickings-brouhaha-and-the-problem-with-affiliate-links/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 21:07:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Mathew Ingram</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[advertising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Affiliate links]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[andrew sullivan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brainpicker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Disclosure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Future of Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sponsored content]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://paidcontent.org/?p=224723</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Blogger Maria Popova has come under fire from a number of critics for her use of undisclosed affiliate links on her blog Brainpickings, which highlights how heated the debate over alternative forms of advertising has become.<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=224723&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There&#8217;s been <a href="http://mediagazer.com/130213/p41#a130213p41">a lot of sound and fury recently</a> about a blogger named Maria Popova, who makes her living by curating links to smart content on her Brainpickings blog. Popova has been quite vocal about how she <a href="http://www.brainpickings.org/index.php/donate/">doesn&#8217;t like traditional advertising</a> and instead relies on donations from her readers, in much the same way that former Daily Beast <a href="http://paidcontent.org/2013/01/28/andrew-sullivan-nate-silver-and-the-shifting-balance-of-power-for-media-brands/">blogger Andrew Sullivan now does</a>. But that commitment was recently challenged by an anonymous critic who noted that Popova also gets revenue from affiliate links to sites like Amazon (s amzn) &#8212; and the resulting debate says a lot about the future of both content and advertising.</p>
<p>One of the reasons why this incident has drawn so much attention is that Popova seems like a great example of the kind of self-sustaining media entity many bloggers &#8212; and even traditional journalists &#8212; aspire to become. While she may not be in the same league as Sullivan, who employs a team to run his Daily Dish blog (and who will <a href="http://event.gigaom.com/paidcontent/?utm_source=media&amp;utm_medium=editorial&amp;utm_campaign=intext&amp;utm_term=223801+andrew-sullivan-nate-silver-and-the-shifting-balance-of-power-for-media-brands&amp;utm_content=mathewingram">be speaking at our paidContent Live</a> conference in New York on April 17), the idea that someone can make a living by simply curating excellent content in return for donations is inspiring.</p>
<h2 id="are-affiliate-links-a-sneaky-f">Are affiliate links a sneaky form of advertising?</h2>
<p>The Popova case has also become a flashpoint because as traditional advertising becomes less lucrative, publishers are turning to alternative forms of advertising such as &#8220;native&#8221; or sponsored content &#8212; something that <a href="http://paidcontent.org/2013/01/16/what-we-can-learn-from-the-atlantics-sponsored-content-debacle/">caused a similar firestorm of criticism</a> for <em>The Atlantic</em> recently &#8212; as well as affiliate-related content. Gawker is hiring writers to create what it calls &#8220;commerce journalism&#8221; that is <a href="http://paidcontent.org/2013/01/24/nick-denton-says-gawkers-advertising-future-is-affiliate-links-and-commerce-journalism/">designed to drive revenue</a> from affiliate links. But standards on disclosure and other elements of these new forms of advertising are all over the map.</p>
<p><a href="http://paidcontent.org/2013/02/14/the-brainpickings-brouhaha-and-the-problem-with-affiliate-links/brainpicker1/" rel="attachment wp-att-224727"><img src="http://gigaompaidcontent.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/brainpicker1.png?w=720" alt="brainpicker1"   class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-224727" /></a></p>
<p>In a number of profiles, including <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2012/12/02/fashion/maria-popova-has-some-big-ideas.html?pagewanted=all&amp;_r=0">a glowing one in the Sunday</a> <em>New York Times</em>, Popova comes across as a highly intelligent and motivated individual &#8212; a former recreational bodybuilder from Bulgaria who started <a href="http://brainpickings.org">Brainpickings</a> as a way of collecting interesting links to books and other content. The reputation of the blog seems to have spread fairly quickly, to the point where luminaries like former State Department official Anne-Marie Slaughter said they support her through donations in the same way they support National Public Radio. And Popova has said repeatedly that <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/theobserver/2012/dec/30/maria-popova-brain-pickings-internet">she is proud to be advertising free</a>:</p>
<blockquote id="quote-it-doesnt-put-the-re"><p>&#8220;It doesn&#8217;t put the reader&#8217;s best interests first – it turns them into a sellable eyeball, and sells that to advertisers. As soon as you begin to treat your stakeholder as a bargaining chip, you&#8217;re not interested in broadening their intellectual horizons or bettering their life. I don&#8217;t believe in this model of making people into currency. You become accountable to advertisers, rather than your reader.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>That rosy picture got a little blurrier over the past couple of days, however, after an anonymous blogger (later revealed to be Tom Bleymaier, founder of a startup in Palo Alto, Calif.) posted on Tumblr <a href="http://on-advertising.tumblr.com/post/42994773187/maria-popova-have-you-made-1m-on-affiliate-ads-while">about Popova&#8217;s liberal use of affiliate links</a> &#8212; that is, links to books and other products on e-commerce sites (primarily Amazon) that provide her with a payment if one of her readers clicks through. The anonymous blogger extrapolated from Popova&#8217;s traffic numbers and estimated that she could generate between $200,000 and $400,000 a year from those links.</p>
<blockquote class='twitter-tweet' lang='en'><p>.@<a href="https://twitter.com/underoak">underoak</a> @<a href="https://twitter.com/moorhen">moorhen</a> blogs that bring in money should have on-site disclosures about where it is coming from. cc @<a href="https://twitter.com/brainpicker">brainpicker</a></p>&mdash; <br />Staci D Kramer (@sdkstl) <a href='http://twitter.com/#!/sdkstl/status/302097811942559745' data-datetime='2013-02-14T16:51:45+00:00'>February 14, 2013</a></blockquote>
<h2 id="disclosure-is-always-better-if">Disclosure is always better if you want trust</h2>
<p>Given that kind of income &#8212; from something that is pretty clearly a form of advertising, although perhaps a non-traditional one &#8212; the Tumblr critic argued that Popova&#8217;s claim to be &#8220;advertising free&#8221; is clearly inaccurate. He also argued that some of her donors might <a href="http://on-advertising.tumblr.com/post/42994773187/maria-popova-have-you-made-1m-on-affiliate-ads-while">think twice about giving her money</a> every month if they knew that she was deriving a substantial amount of income from affiliate links, something that Popova didn&#8217;t disclose before or after a reader clicked on one of those links (<strong>Note</strong>: She has since added disclosure <a href="http://www.brainpickings.org/index.php/donate/">to her donations page</a>).</p>
<p>Reuters blogger Felix Salmon <a href="http://blogs.reuters.com/felix-salmon/2013/02/13/blogonomics-maria-popova-edition/">followed up with a post about Popova</a>, repeating some of the financial claims made by Bleymaier and adding some of his own. Popova has since responded to both Salmon and Betabeat &#8212; which also <a href="http://betabeat.com/2013/02/maria-popova-brain-pickings-affiliate-links-amazon-on-advertising-tumblr-ads-ads-ads/">published a critical post about her practices</a> &#8212; saying she doesn&#8217;t see affiliate links as advertising, is open about using them, and doesn&#8217;t make anything close to what Bleymaier said she does.</p>
<blockquote id="quote-those-numbers-are-lu2"><p>&#8220;Those numbers are ludicrous! If Amazon gave me even a tenth of that a year after Uncle Sam takes his fair share, I’d be delighted. I&#8217;ve been completely honest about the Amazon links with anyone who’s ever asked – and have many, many, many emails I’m happy to forward – and have brought it up myself multiple times in talks and on Twitter.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Many of Popova&#8217;s supporters have said they are happy to have her get revenue from her writing in any way possible, and <a href="https://twitter.com/stevesilberman/status/302138662668337153">don&#8217;t mind the lack of disclosure</a> about her use of affiliate links. Others, however, have questioned why she wouldn&#8217;t attach a simple disclaimer to her site &#8212; especially on the donation page &#8212; to note that she uses them (and some have even pointed out that this kind of disclaimer is arguably required by law, due to FTC regulations <a href="http://diannej.com/blog/2012/05/new-ftc-rules-on-writing-reviews-affiliations-and-sponsored-posts/">on disclosing marketing-related content</a>).</p>
<p>I think the main point that Salmon makes in his post on the issue is a good one: namely, that if you are relying on donations from your fans for your livelihood &#8212; as Sullivan is, and others such as musician Amanda Palmer are &#8212; then <a href="http://blogs.reuters.com/felix-salmon/2013/02/13/blogonomics-maria-popova-edition/">it behooves you to be as open as possible</a> about your financial arrangements, in the interests of increasing the trust your readers or fans have in you. Sullivan and Palmer have both been <a href="http://paidcontent.org/2013/01/31/what-andrew-sullivan-and-amanda-palmer-have-in-common-a-fanatical-devotion-to-users/">extremely forthcoming</a> about their financial situations, an approach Popova might want to imitate.</p>
<p><strong>Note</strong>: Since the original version of this post appeared, Popova has added a footnote to her site at the bottom of each page that describes how she uses Amazon affiliate links, which says:</p>
<blockquote id="quote-brain-pickings-parti3"><p>&#8220;Brain Pickings participates in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn commissions by linking to Amazon. In more human terms, this means that whenever you buy a book on Amazon from a link on here, I get a small percentage of its price. That helps support Brain Pickings by offsetting a fraction of what it takes to maintain the site, and is very much appreciated.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p><em>This story was updated to note that Popova has added disclosure of her affiliate links to her donations page, as she <a href="https://twitter.com/brainpicker/status/302172114155360256">noted on Twitter</a>, as well as a note in the footer of her site.</em></p>
<p><em>Images courtesy of <a href="http://www.shutterstock.com/gallery-191161p1.html">Shutterstock / Igor Steganovic</a> and <a href="Twitter.com/brainpicker">Brainpicker</a></em></p>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=224723&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://paidcontent.org/2013/02/14/the-brainpickings-brouhaha-and-the-problem-with-affiliate-links/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>21</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://gigaompaidcontent.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/shutterstock_123438763.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://gigaompaidcontent.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/shutterstock_123438763.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">shutterstock_123438763</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/0bdf7ab171ade0708a11fa3378e6d8cb?s=96&#38;d=retro&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mathew</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gigaompaidcontent.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/brainpicker1.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">brainpicker1</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>There&#8217;s Blood in the Fountain</title>
		<link>http://agirlandherthumb.wordpress.com/2013/02/12/theres-blood-in-the-fountain/</link>
		<comments>http://agirlandherthumb.wordpress.com/2013/02/12/theres-blood-in-the-fountain/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2013 20:28:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jo Magpie</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Iran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pictures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tabriz]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://agirlandherthumb.wordpress.com/?p=4337</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Tabriz, 22-24th November, 2012 &#160; There &#8216;s probably no worse time to enter Iran than the day before Ashura. The country&#8217;s devout masses are out every night, literally whipping themselves up into a frenzy with chains and lashes; all of the shops are closed and there&#8217;s blood in the fountain in the centre of Tabriz. [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4337&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://agirlandherthumb.wordpress.com/2013/02/12/theres-blood-in-the-fountain/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>21</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/2f4e8a4db954eedb1dd8c13c2c440163?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F2.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">agirlandherthumb</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://agirlandherthumb.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/dsc_1431.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Blood in the Fountain</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://agirlandherthumb.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/dsc_1439.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_1439</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://agirlandherthumb.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/dsc_1444.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mosque in Tabriz</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://agirlandherthumb.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/dsc_1446.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_1446</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
