<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2013 20:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Back to the Front</title>
		<link>http://tragicocomedia.com/2013/02/04/back-to-the-front/</link>
		<comments>http://tragicocomedia.com/2013/02/04/back-to-the-front/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2013 02:52:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Professor Rollmops</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Memoir]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travelogues]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tragicocomedia.com/?p=2891</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This piece was written just prior to my arrival in India on December 24, 2012, but remained incomplete. After a quick edit and polish, I present it here in its original tense, despite just having returned from India. I got the shakes just before leaving Singapore. It was two and a half years since my [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2891&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>This piece was written just prior to my arrival in India on December 24, 2012, but remained incomplete. After a quick edit and polish, I present it here in its original tense, despite just having returned from India.</em></p>
<p>I got the shakes just before leaving Singapore. It was two and a half years since my last visit to India and I had forgotten how hardcore it can be. On the whole, India is a pretty safe place to travel – it’s not exactly a warzone and whilst violence and crime certainly occur, most foreigners get away with being ripped off a few times and suffering some health issues. Yet, travelling in India takes a lot of effort and can be at times quite harrowing. It is not, despite its reputation as a centre for meditation and religious retreat, a very relaxing country.</p>
<p><a href="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/9935-jodphur-bw.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2897" title="Everybody wants you in their photograph" alt="Jodphur B&amp;W" src="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/9935-jodphur-bw.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>I’ve written several stories about my first trip to India and some of the various experiences I had there. Some fictionalised, others as memoir, and it is not an easy place to which to do justice. It can be breathtaking and amazing, restful and beautiful, yet it can also be utterly exhausting and very frustrating. It also has its attendant, inherent difficulties – such as the heat and dust, the discomfort, the chaos, the noise, the touts, the lying and cheating that goes hand in hand with incredible hospitality, and the inconvenience of not being able to drink the tap water in a country that is often unrelentingly hot and humid.</p>
<p><a href="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/7984-taj-from-agra-fort.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2893" title="The Taj from Agra Fort" alt="Taj from Agra Fort" src="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/7984-taj-from-agra-fort.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>In my first few days in India in March 2010 I struggled to make sense of the place and learn to negotiate it. Rather like being thrown in at the deep end, I learned to swim soon enough, yet not before having a number of difficult and challenging experiences and getting sick. The illness in itself wasn&#8217;t so bad &#8211; stomach cramps and diarrhoea &#8211; but after a few days it made me feel very weak. For two days in Pushkar I did almost nothing but lie in my hotel room and read, with occasional ventures outside.</p>
<p><a href="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/1218-bikaner.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2898" title="Woman in muddy street in Bikaner" alt="Bikaner" src="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/1218-bikaner.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>After four days, travelling further into Rajasthan, I arrived in Udaipur dehydrated and exhausted. The weakness of not eating much for three days made me paranoid and, sitting alone in my hotel room watching the cricket that night I got the crazy idea that I might genuinely die. I force-fed myself a vegetable biriani and fruit salad and the following morning went straight to the chemist to get some antibiotics. Within twelve hours of taking them, the illness vanished and I cursed myself for not having done so sooner. Take my advice – most gastric illness in India is bacterial and over-the-counter antibiotics are readily available at any medical shop.</p>
<p><a href="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/9031-udaipur.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2894" title="Not a bad place to fear death" alt="Udaipur" src="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/9031-udaipur.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>As soon as I got better, that first trip in India really got underway. With my strength returned, I was able to put in the hard yards and see and do the things I wanted to. The more I saw of India, the more I loved it – but this love came with serious reservations about why I felt the way I did. It was all very well to see charm and romance and the exotic, yet alongside that was terrible poverty, failing infrastructure, appalling hygiene in public places, rubbish dumped and burned everywhere on the streets, including plastics and excrement, and such a harrowing welter of noise pollution, overcrowding and almost non-stop inquisitions from people I passed that it was equally depressing and demoralising. It was, of course, a photographers&#8217; paradise, but my joy at the subject matter was tainted by a feeling of intrusion and exploitation and terms like “poverty porn” lingered in my mind. I tried very hard on that trip to remain friendly and positive. For the first few weeks I answered every query, shook hands with a hundred strangers and stopped for the ubiquitous “just one photo, sir”, but after a time India’s constant assault forced me to retreat inside myself. I turned to my headphones and sunglasses and started ignoring people.</p>
<p><a href="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/5925-onkar.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2902" title="Onkar! a very nice tea man in McLeod Ganj" alt="Onkar!" src="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/5925-onkar.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>A better solution, however, came when I arrived in Darjeeling. Perhaps it was the prevalence of Buddhism, the cool calm of the mountains or just the friendly, peaceful nature of the Ghorka people, but in Darjeeling people left me alone. When people did greet me or make an inquiry, it was not merely preliminary to an attempted transaction.</p>
<p><a href="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/3986-darjeeling.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2899" title="Darjeeling, chilled" alt="Darjeeling" src="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/3986-darjeeling.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>In the rest of India there seems to be an automatic reflex whereupon, seeing a tourist, if staring is insufficient, then belting out the question “which country?” is the next step. This was sometimes done in the nicest possible way, but often it was thrown at me with such urgency that it felt impolite. What really surprised me was how often the inquirers accepted the answer without further ado, at times seeming almost uninterested, which left me wondering why they had needed to ask in the first place. It was like being a display, which, to be fair, was probably not much different from how people felt when I was photographing them – though I do try to shoot as surreptitiously as possible.</p>
<p>The solution, it seemed, to avoiding the hustle of India, was to be in the mountains, which wasn&#8217;t exactly India after all. Once I’d discovered the relative calm of the mountains, I did my best to stay there.</p>
<p><a href="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/5641-amritsar.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2900" title="The Golden Temple, Amritsar" alt="Amritsar" src="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/5641-amritsar.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>From Darjeeling I flew across to Amritsar where I lasted one day before taking a bus across Punjab into the mountains around Dharamsala.</p>
<p><a href="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/6949-vashisht.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2903" title="Mountains around Vashisht" alt="Vashisht" src="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/6949-vashisht.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>I was so reluctant to return to the heat, dust and general hubbub hat I stayed another three weeks in Himachal Pradesh before finally venturing down again via Shimla.</p>
<p><a href="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/5830-mcleod-ganj.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2901" title="Twin Rainbows, McLeod Ganj" alt="McLeod Ganj" src="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/5830-mcleod-ganj.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>By the end of that journey, just shy of two months, I felt like an old veteran after a long campaign. Yet my energy was also pretty well spent and I had fallen into a state of relative dissipation. Tired and world-weary, I wandered around Varanasi in a daze, wiped out by heat and hash. I made sure I took the photographs I wanted to get, yet the subject that had so fascinated me for the first two months – namely India – had become a little less appealing.</p>
<p><a href="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/9129-varanasi.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2895" title="So many people, Varanasi" alt="Varanasi" src="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/9129-varanasi.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>I could no longer stomach the scent of excrement, urine and decomposition. I had no more patience for beggars, priests, touts or even genuinely curious Indians. I literally just wanted to shoot the place and avoid any interactions. When anyone spoke to me I shook my head, pointed to the headphones, raised my hands as though to say, “Sorry, dude, I can’t hear you,” and walked away. It was not how I wanted to be at all, and I hid out in my hotel room at times, simply indulging in privacy and regretting the feelings of displeasure I had with the world at large. I guess introverts should travel in Scandinavia instead.</p>
<p><a href="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/9412-varanasi.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2896" title="Man with tea, Varanasi" alt="Varanasi" src="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/9412-varanasi.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>It was for these reasons that, just prior to my flight into Thiruvananthapuram for a second visit to India, I started to have reservations about where I was going. I should be looking forward to the challenge, but perhaps I am too effete and western for the grit and grime of it all.  Still, despite the above introduction, my last trip was one of the greatest experiences of my life and I came away from it feeling very inspired. This time is also bound to be different for a number of reasons. Firstly, I&#8217;ll be starting in the south instead of the north and travelling in regions I&#8217;ve not visited before. Secondly, I&#8217;m not travelling alone this time around. V is coming with me, or I with her if you will, and the dynamic will be very different indeed. It will certainly be a lot easier with someone to share the highs and lows, and I hope it will be more enjoyable as a consequence. Hopefully I will come away both appreciating what I have discovered anew and having been reminded of what is important and good in life. I also hope to shoot a hell of a lot of good photographs. Wish me luck.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2891/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2891/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2891&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tragicocomedia.com/2013/02/04/back-to-the-front/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/131f1980849d4768f8e3ee6882a5b019?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Professor Rollmops</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/9935-jodphur-bw.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Everybody wants you in their photograph</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/7984-taj-from-agra-fort.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The Taj from Agra Fort</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/1218-bikaner.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Woman in muddy street in Bikaner</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/9031-udaipur.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Not a bad place to fear death</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/5925-onkar.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Onkar! a very nice tea man in McLeod Ganj</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/3986-darjeeling.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Darjeeling, chilled</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/5641-amritsar.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The Golden Temple, Amritsar</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/6949-vashisht.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mountains around Vashisht</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/5830-mcleod-ganj.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Twin Rainbows, McLeod Ganj</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/9129-varanasi.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">So many people, Varanasi</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/9412-varanasi.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Man with tea, Varanasi</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Land Before Hype</title>
		<link>http://mostlybrightideas.wordpress.com/2013/02/01/the-land-before-hype/</link>
		<comments>http://mostlybrightideas.wordpress.com/2013/02/01/the-land-before-hype/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 16:59:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bronxboy55</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Still Human After All These Years]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[baseball]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[basketball]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commercials]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[football]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Super Bowl]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[World Series]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yankees]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mostlybrightideas.wordpress.com/?p=5345</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It’s that time again: Super Bowl week. I know this, not because I follow football in even the slightest way, but because I’ve noticed the potato chip and Coca-Cola displays at the grocery store. Built like shrines to the gods, these stockpiles of snacks will be inhaled by a hundred million people in six hours. [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=5345&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It’s that time again: Super Bowl week. I know this, not because I follow football in even the slightest way, but because I’ve noticed the potato chip and Coca-Cola displays at the grocery store. Built like shrines to the gods, these stockpiles of snacks will be inhaled by a hundred million people in six hours. This is just enough time to complete the pre-game and post-game shows, four fifteen-minute quarters of actual football competition, a forty-five-minute halftime extravaganza, and a lot of expensive commercials created to get you to eat potato chips and drink Coca-Cola.</p>
<div id="attachment_5346" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 366px"><a href="http://mostlybrightideas.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/electric.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-5346" alt="Electric" src="http://mostlybrightideas.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/electric.jpg?w=356&#038;h=198" width="356" height="198" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">From <a href="http://www.kshs.org" rel="nofollow">http://www.kshs.org</a></p></div>
<p>I don’t have many positive memories related to the sport. When I was about eleven, my best friend got one of those electric football games that had plastic players and a metal field that would vibrate when you flipped the switch. We’d line up our teams with great care, and then sit there for a long time listening to this thing buzz and staring at our little men as they wandered around in all directions, quivering like mad and eventually getting stuck against a side wall or clustering in bunches in the corner like tiny bumper cars. It was, I imagine, not much different from putting on show tunes and watching termites attempt to perform <i>Guys and Dolls</i>. Every now and then my friend would announce that he’d gotten a first down, a development that always escaped my attention but that he never failed to see. Touchdowns and field goals would follow, along with other assorted scoring opportunities based on obscure rules that I was pretty sure he was making up on the spot.<a href="http://mostlybrightideas.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/football.png"><img class="alignright  wp-image-5349" style="margin-top:8px;margin-bottom:8px;" alt="Football" src="http://mostlybrightideas.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/football.png?w=416&#038;h=300" width="416" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>Sometimes, when the older boys had a thirst for human blood, we played real football on an empty lot riddled with small rocks and shards of broken glass. We had only the ball, and no other equipment whatsoever. Helmets were for sissies, we decided, and complaining of pain after being slammed to the ground and crushed under a pile of snarling teenagers would just mean you’d be picked last the next time we played. If we didn’t call it the Stupid Bowl, we should have. We were a bunch of morons.</p>
<p>I preferred baseball. For one thing, in other sports the opposing team spent most of its time trying to take something away from you, inflicting physical harm and verbal abuse in the process. It was too much like real life. Football, for example, was nothing more than the offense bulling its way through, while the defense did whatever it could to knock you down and get you to fumble the ball.</p>
<p>Basketball was the same, except you wore shorts and were required to dribble and avoid committing a three-second violation. No one ever explained the three-second rule to me, or how the referees could possibly keep track of where everyone was and for how long. I got called on it a lot in gym class, usually because I had to stop and re-tie my sneakers in the middle of play.</p>
<p><a href="http://mostlybrightideas.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/soccer.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5351" alt="Soccer" src="http://mostlybrightideas.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/soccer.png?w=720"   /></a>In both hockey and soccer, there was an infraction referred to as <i>off-sides</i>. Again, I’ve never been able to understand this rule, beyond the simple conclusion that it’s designed to keep you from wanting to score a goal too much. The result, often, was an unbearably long game that ended in a tie. Frequently, a <i>scoreless</i> tie. This was like going to a restaurant, ordering a meal, waiting for your dinner to be served, then leaving without eating anything.</p>
<p>I found myself playing lacrosse once, and like hockey, its bizarre regulations included something called a <i>crease</i>, which I think is an invisible fourth dimension that players either must stay inside of or avoid entering at all costs. I’m still not sure.</p>
<p>These sports seemed to have a common element: they all had commentators and coaches who rattled on and on about intricate strategies and match-ups, deep explanations of what worked and didn’t work, how they needed to go back to the fundamentals, and what they intended to accomplish next game or next season. The only thing I ever saw was a bunch of lunatics chasing after a loose ball or puck, unsure of where it was headed and knocking each other around to relieve their frustration.<a href="http://mostlybrightideas.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/baseball.png"><img class="alignright  wp-image-5352" style="margin-top:10px;margin-bottom:10px;" alt="Baseball" src="http://mostlybrightideas.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/baseball.png?w=342&#038;h=352" width="342" height="352" /></a></p>
<p>But baseball was different. Baseball involved thinking, rather than reptilian-brain reflex responses. There was time to plan ahead. And there was room for real strategy, because there were just so many things that could happen, and each thing had a correct reaction.</p>
<p>My younger brother and I played baseball every chance we got. We played in the street, using flattened beer cans and manhole covers for bases. We played on concrete playgrounds, and on any available stretch of grass. We pitched to a rectangle we’d drawn with yellow chalk on a brick wall. In the winter, we played in the house, arranging the living room furniture like an infield and using a rolled-up sock for a ball.</p>
<p>We watched professional games on television. And once or twice a year, our father took us to see the Yankees or the Mets play in person. One summer, we went to the Mayor’s Trophy Game, an annual fundraiser in which the Yankees and Mets played <i>against</i> each other. My brain nearly exploded with excitement, but I’d also been backed into the corner of team loyalty, and chose to focus instead on eating as many hot dogs as I could. This was in the early 1960s, when you could sit in a box seat for three dollars, or the bleachers for seventy-five cents. When players had names like Ernie and Vic, Roberto and Duke, Sandy and Moose, and the very best of them made less than a hundred thousand dollars.</p>
<p>Of course, I had no idea about players’ salaries when I was a kid. I doubt I’d ever even considered the fact that they were paid at all. Baseball was a game, not a job, and I’d have paid <i>them</i> just for a chance to step onto that field and touch the bases. I dreamed of someday getting a close look at the three monuments in centerfield at Yankee Stadium, vertical granite slabs that looked exactly like the headstones I’d seen when visiting my grandparents’ graves at the cemetery in Queens. I wasn’t certain, but I thought the players might have been buried right there in the outfield.</p>
<p>At one game, Mickey Mantle hit a five-hundred-foot shot over the black screen in dead center. I may have seen it, but more likely I was looking around for a food vendor. Still, I was there. I remember standing and cheering about something; it had to be either the home run or the guy selling Dixie Cups – cardboard containers filled with half vanilla and half chocolate ice cream that you ate with a flat wooden spoon.</p>
<p>World Series games were played in the afternoons back then, in the first week of October, when you could tell the inning by how close the shadows were to the pitcher’s mound. There were two leagues, as there are now, but each had just ten teams. The best record at the end of the season got you into the World Series. No playoffs or division championships. No slipping into a side entrance off Wild Card Alley. You either won the pennant or you didn’t. It was pure, and it was fair. I remember running home from school to catch the last couple of innings. And sometimes, on days when I loved the world more than anything, the nuns would turn on the television and let us watch the game right there in our classroom.</p>
<p>The Super Bowl had not yet been born. The highlights of the year were Easter, summer vacation, the World Series, my birthday, and Christmas. It was the anticipation of each event that helped sustain me from one to the next. People say it was a simpler time, and I guess it was. Potato chips came in two flavors, and there was Coca-Cola and whatever it was other people drank. There was vanilla and chocolate, the Yankees and the Mets, baseball and all those strange, inferior sports.</p>
<p style="padding-bottom:30px;">And there was time to think.</p>
<hr />
<p style="padding-top:30px;"><span style="color:#0000ff;"><em>On second thought, <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qmXacL0Uny0">he</a> explains it better.</em></span></p>
<p style="padding-bottom:34px;">
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5345/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5345/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=5345&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://mostlybrightideas.wordpress.com/2013/02/01/the-land-before-hype/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>64</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/985f77a6e63f66b1719d766801a886e7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bronxboy55</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mostlybrightideas.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/electric.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Electric</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mostlybrightideas.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/football.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Football</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mostlybrightideas.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/soccer.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Soccer</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mostlybrightideas.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/baseball.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Baseball</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fire and Ice: The Rise of the Snow Weber</title>
		<link>http://patronsofthepit.wordpress.com/2013/02/02/fire-and-ice-the-rise-of-the-snow-weber/</link>
		<comments>http://patronsofthepit.wordpress.com/2013/02/02/fire-and-ice-the-rise-of-the-snow-weber/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2013 14:25:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Patrons of the Pit</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[barbecue]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[barbeque]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bbq]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[camping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cooking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[extreme]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faithful remnant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fire and Ice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fishing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[foodie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[huntung]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outdoors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robert Frost]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[snow weber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[winter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[winter grilling]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://patronsofthepit.wordpress.com/?p=933</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Over a steaming cup of tea, I glance out the window at the pit, watching spindrift swirl off the house in a fashion suitable maybe, for the weathered,  icy,  flanks of Everest. The mercury gauge read a sporty 5 degrees F, but the weather man said it felt more like minus 15, and I guess [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=933&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Over a steaming cup of tea</strong>, I glance out the window at the pit, watching spindrift swirl off the house in a fashion suitable maybe, for the weathered,  icy,  flanks of Everest. The mercury gauge read a sporty 5 degrees F, but the weather man said it felt more like minus 15, and I guess believed him. You kind of have to believe him I concluded, when it feels like your parking brake is engaged when you back down the driveway in the morning, only it isn&#8217;t  Yeah, it was cold out there alright. A vintage January day in Minnesota. The kind of day where you put on two or three shirts in the morning, and then you go about the business of getting dressed. I curled my toes in my warm socks, fingers cradling the hot, porcelain cup , and after a dash of consideration, I decided to do the only sensible thing I could think of &#8211; to go outside naturally, and ignite the Snow Weber!</p>
<p><a href="http://patronsofthepit.wordpress.com/2013/02/02/fire-and-ice-the-rise-of-the-snow-weber/afterfocus_1359675847092_edit0/" rel="attachment wp-att-928"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-928" alt="afterfocus_1359675847092_edit0" src="http://patronsofthepit.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/afterfocus_1359675847092_edit0.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<div id="mp0_ctr">
<div id="mp0_msgPartBody">
<div id="mpf0_readMsgBodyContainer">
<div id="mpf0_MsgContainer">
<div>The Snow Weber, that’s what I’m calling it at least, is the tactile end result of our latest BBQ brain thrust. A frozen monument if you will, erected in a semi-stately homage, symbolic to all the keepers of the grill out there, who do not, and will not, save for a trip somewhere with a blue tag on their big toe,  take the winter off.  The faithful remnant possessing the macaroni to lay meat to flame whence the jaws of winter hath conspired against them. Carry the flame proudly brethren, for this is our story. A tale of fire and ice.</div>
<div></div>
<div><a href="http://patronsofthepit.wordpress.com/2013/02/02/fire-and-ice-the-rise-of-the-snow-weber/afterfocus_1359694383277_edit0/" rel="attachment wp-att-932"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-932" alt="afterfocus_1359694383277_edit0" src="http://patronsofthepit.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/afterfocus_1359694383277_edit0.jpg?w=720"   /></a></div>
<p>Robert Frost postulates in his poem the virtues of world destruction either by the fire or by ice, figuring either, if we had to, would be pretty nice.  I wonder tho if he ever grilled in winter, or knew that the two forces could harmonize together for the betterment of his tummy. Because they can. And so it was, with pork chops in hand, I stepped out onto the wind-swept patio, and at once my left eye lid seared tight from the keen northern wind. I love it! Tenderly I placed the two chops on the hot grate, and admired them there for a spell.  The previous owners of which I&#8217;m sure knew each other back on their farm. Perhaps routinely getting together for morning slop, to discuss their lives, their hopes, and their dreams. Maybe they even aspired to make it on to this blog one day. Hmm. I shook off the thought, and dusted the chops with some <a href="http://louisianafishfry.elsstore.com/view/product/?id=18723&amp;cid=2062">Louisiana Fish Fry Cajun Seasoning</a> instead.</p>
<p><a href="http://patronsofthepit.wordpress.com/2013/02/02/fire-and-ice-the-rise-of-the-snow-weber/afterfocus_1359693630086_edit0/" rel="attachment wp-att-931"><img class="size-full wp-image-931 aligncenter" alt="           " src="http://patronsofthepit.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/afterfocus_1359693630086_edit0.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>After a while, and maybe even longer than that, I felt the compulsion to put the lid on, and go think about my life. Nothing quite so fine as repairing out in the yard with a 15 below cross-wind, whilst two pork chops sizzle on the snow grill. Glory! The art of winter grilling, if your wondering, is not to fight it. But to embrace it. To make the proverbial glass of lemon aid out of it. To meet it on it&#8217;s terms and not your own. That, and a degree of lunacy doesn&#8217;t hurt none either.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div></div>
<div>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://patronsofthepit.wordpress.com/2013/02/02/fire-and-ice-the-rise-of-the-snow-weber/20130131_172504_edit0/" rel="attachment wp-att-929"><img class="size-full wp-image-929 aligncenter" alt="" src="http://patronsofthepit.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/20130131_172504_edit0.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
</div>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>And supper is served, courtesy of, and inspired by:</strong></p>
<h3 style="text-align:center;">Fire and Ice</h3>
<p style="text-align:center;"><em>Some say the world will end in fire,</em><br />
<em>Some say in ice.</em><br />
<em>From what I&#8217;ve tasted of desire</em><br />
<em>I hold with those who favor fire.</em><br />
<em>But if it had to perish twice,</em><br />
<em>I think I know enough of hate</em><br />
<em>To say that for destruction ice</em><br />
<em>Is also great</em><br />
<em>And would suffice</em>.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">-Robert Frost</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/933/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/933/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=933&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://patronsofthepit.wordpress.com/2013/02/02/fire-and-ice-the-rise-of-the-snow-weber/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>29</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://patronsofthepit.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/afterfocus_1359675847092_edit0.jpg?w=112" />
		<media:content url="http://patronsofthepit.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/afterfocus_1359675847092_edit0.jpg?w=112" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Fire and Ice</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/b358cc0808635b00957805d083fe96e8?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">patronsofthepit</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://patronsofthepit.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/afterfocus_1359675847092_edit0.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">afterfocus_1359675847092_edit0</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://patronsofthepit.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/afterfocus_1359694383277_edit0.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">afterfocus_1359694383277_edit0</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://patronsofthepit.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/afterfocus_1359693630086_edit0.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">           </media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://patronsofthepit.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/20130131_172504_edit0.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Are They Really So Different?</title>
		<link>http://thenorth666.wordpress.com/2013/01/28/thought-of-the-week-are-they-really-so-different/</link>
		<comments>http://thenorth666.wordpress.com/2013/01/28/thought-of-the-week-are-they-really-so-different/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 02:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Satis</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Thought of the Week]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Behaviors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Calvin and Hobbes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kids]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pluto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thenorth666.wordpress.com/?p=2082</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s a funny business, living with a child. It&#8217;s a little bit like living with a mooching flatmate who is quite a bit smarter than you. (And shorter, which sort of makes up for it.) You see, when you&#8217;re talking about children in the hypothetical (as in, &#8220;we might want kids some day&#8221;, or &#8220;aren&#8217;t your [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2082&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://thenorth666.wordpress.com/2013/01/28/thought-of-the-week-are-they-really-so-different/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>23</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://thenorth666.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/dsc_0181.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://thenorth666.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/dsc_0181.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0181</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/d88970831fd574590dd147783c59dc8b?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F1.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">thenorth666</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thenorth666.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/dsc_0181.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">A child and a grownup…but which is which?</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thenorth666.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/pluto-a.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">-Pluto-a</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thenorth666.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/daysarejustpacked.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">daysarejustpacked</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple\&#8217;s Nine Definitions Since 1995</title>
		<link>http://alex4d.wordpress.com/2013/02/05/apple-is/</link>
		<comments>http://alex4d.wordpress.com/2013/02/05/apple-is/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2013 16:10:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Alex</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://alex4d.wordpress.com/?p=4004</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Looking back, it&#8217;s interesting to see how the way Apple has described itself has changed over the years. Luckily for us, press releases usually include a definition of the company issuing them. I&#8217;ve been back through Apple&#8217;s site and used The Wayback Machine at Archive.org to research the evolution of the way Apple sees itself. [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4004&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Looking back, it&#8217;s interesting to see how the way Apple has described itself has changed over the years. Luckily for us, press releases usually include a definition of the company issuing them. I&#8217;ve been back through Apple&#8217;s site and used <a href="http://Archive.org/web/web.php" target="_blank">The Wayback Machine at Archive.org</a> to research the evolution of the way Apple sees itself.</p>
<h4>April 1995 &#8211; A standard mid-nineties computer company</h4>
<p>The only distinction being a mention of &#8216;personal digital assistants&#8217;:</p>
<blockquote><p>Apple Computer, Inc., a recognized pioneer and innovator in the information industry, creates powerful solutions based on easy to use personal computers, servers peripherals, software, online services and personal digital assistants. Headquartered in Cupertino, California, Apple Computer, Inc. (NASDAQ: AAPL) develops, manufactures, licenses, and markets products, technologies, and services for the business, education, consumer, scientific &amp; engineering and government markets in over 140 countries.</p></blockquote>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://web.archive.org/web/19990922045328/http://product.info.apple.com/pr/press.releases/1995/q3/950403.pr.rel.education2.html"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-4013" alt="press-release-1995" src="http://alex4d.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/press-release-1995.jpg?w=308&#038;h=442" width="308" height="442" /></a></p>
<p><span id="more-4004"></span></p>
<h4><strong>January 1996 &#8211; Apple&#8217;s only asset?</strong></h4>
<p>In 1996, Apple decided to define QuickTime as one of its major assets:</p>
<blockquote><p>Apple Computer, Inc., a recognized innovator in the information industry<span style="color:#000000;"> <em>and leader in multimedia technologies</em></span>, creates powerful solutions based on easy-to-use personal computers, servers, peripherals, software, online services, and personal digital assistants. Headquartered in Cupertino, California, Apple (NASDAQ: AAPL) develops, manufactures, licenses and markets solutions, products, technologies and services for business, education, consumer, entertainment, scientific &amp; engineering and government customers in over 140 countries.</p></blockquote>
<h4><strong>April 1997 &#8211; The Newton declines</strong></h4>
<p>As less complex PDAs started to gain market share, &#8216;online services, and personal digital assistants&#8217; became &#8216;handheld computers and Internet content<em>&#8216;:<br />
</em></p>
<blockquote><p>Apple Computer, Inc., a recognized innovator in the information industry and leader in multimedia technologies, creates powerful solutions based on easy-to-use personal computers, servers, peripherals, software, <em><span style="color:#000000;">handheld computers and Internet content</span>.</em> Headquartered in Cupertino, California, Apple develops, manufactures, licenses and markets solutions, products, technologies and services for business, education, consumer, entertainment, scientific and engineering and government customers in more than 140 countries.</p></blockquote>
<h4><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size:14px;font-weight:bold;line-height:14px;"><strong>September 1997 &#8211; Steve Jobs changes everything</strong></span></h4>
<p>10 months after Steve Jobs returned to Apple, four days before <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20010816130723/http://product.info.apple.com/pr/press.releases/1997/q4/970916.pr.rel.jobs.html" target="_blank">his appointment as Interim CEO</a>, the definition <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20010816130723/http://product.info.apple.com/pr/press.releases/1997/q4/970912.pr.rel.quicktime.html" target="_blank">almost completely changed</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>Apple Computer<span style="color:#000000;">, Inc. ignited the personal computer revolution in the 1970s with the Apple II, and reinvented the personal computer in the 1980s with the Macintosh. Apple is now recommitted to its original mission-to bring the best personal computing products and support to students, educators, designers, scientists, engineers, businesspersons and consumers in over 140 countries around the world.</span></p></blockquote>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20010816130723/http://product.info.apple.com/pr/press.releases/1997/q4/970912.pr.rel.quicktime.html"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-4014" alt="press-release-1997" src="http://alex4d.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/press-release-1997.jpg?w=206&#038;h=270" width="206" height="270" /></a></p>
<h4><strong>July 2004 &#8211; &#8216;Original mission&#8217; achieved</strong></h4>
<p>It took almost seven years for the definition to <a href="http://www.apple.com/pr/library/2004/07/07Apple-iPod-mini-International-Availability-Set-for-July-24.html" target="_blank">change again</a>. Steve&#8217;s 1997 mission achieved, the definition includes specific products and what they do.</p>
<blockquote><p>Apple ignited the personal computer revolution in the 1970s with the Apple II and reinvented the personal computer in the 1980s with the Macintosh. <em><span style="color:#000000;">Today, Apple continues to lead the industry in innovation with its award-winning desktop and notebook computers, OS X operating system, and iLife and professional applications. Apple is also spearheading the digital music revolution with its iPod portable music players and iTunes online music store.</span><br />
</em></p></blockquote>
<h4><strong>March 2007 &#8211; Next market disruption announced</strong></h4>
<p>Almost three years later, the distinction between desktop and notebook computers was dropped and <a href="http://www.apple.com/pr/library/2007/03/21Apple-TV-Now-Shipping.html" target="_blank">the iPhone was included</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>Apple ignited the personal computer revolution in the 1970s with the Apple II and reinvented the personal computer in the 1980s with the Macintosh. Today, Apple continues to lead the industry in innovation with its award-winning computers, OS X operating system and iLife and professional applications. Apple is also spearheading the digital media revolution with its iPod portable music and video players and iTunes online store,<em><span style="color:#000000;"> and will enter the mobile phone market this year with its revolutionary iPhone.</span><br />
</em></p></blockquote>
<h4><strong>April 2010 &#8211; Three revolutions joined by a fourth</strong></h4>
<p>A small <a href="http://www.apple.com/pr/library/2010/04/05Apple-Sells-Over-300-000-iPads-First-Day.html" target="_blank">addition for the iPad</a>, Apple&#8217;s fourth market revolution<a href="http://www.apple.com/pr/library/2010/04/05Apple-Sells-Over-300-000-iPads-First-Day.html" target="_blank"><br />
</a></p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Apple ignited the personal computer revolution with the Apple II, then reinvented the personal computer with the Macintosh. Apple continues to lead the industry with its award-winning computers, OS X operating system, and iLife, iWork and professional applications. Apple leads the digital music revolution with its iPods and iTunes online store, has reinvented the mobile phone with its revolutionary iPhone and App Store,<em><span style="color:#000000;"> and has recently introduced its magical iPad which is defining the future of mobile media and computing devices.&#8221;</span><br />
</em></p></blockquote>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://www.apple.com/pr/library/2010/04/05Apple-Sells-Over-300-000-iPads-First-Day.html"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-4015" alt="press-release-2010" src="http://alex4d.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/press-release-2010.jpg?w=327&#038;h=254" width="327" height="254" /></a></p>
<h4><strong>June 2010 &#8211; Computers, yes, also…</strong></h4>
<p>The Apple II is dropped and the amount of text on the Mac <a href="http://www.apple.com/pr/library/2010/06/28iPhone-4-Sales-Top-1-7-Million.html" target="_blank">is reduced</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p><span style="color:#000000;"><em>Apple designs Macs, the best personal computers in the world, along with</em></span> OS X, iLife, iWork, and professional software. Apple leads the digital music revolution with its iPods and iTunes online store. Apple reinvented the mobile phone with its revolutionary iPhone and App Store, and has recently introduced its magical iPad which is defining the future of mobile media and computing devices.</p></blockquote>
<h4>January 2012 &#8211; iPad mission achieved</h4>
<p><span class="Apple-style-span" style="color:#000000;font-size:12px;line-height:18px;">The current definition </span><span class="Apple-style-span" style="color:#000000;font-size:12px;line-height:18px;"><a href="http://www.apple.com/pr/library/2012/01/19Apple-Unveils-All-New-iTunes-U-App-for-iPad-iPhone-iPod-touch.html" target="_blank">is a year old</a></span><span class="Apple-style-span" style="color:#000000;font-size:12px;line-height:18px;">:</span></p>
<blockquote><p>Apple designs Macs, the best personal computers in the world, along with OS X, iLife, iWork and professional software. Apple leads the digital music revolution with its iPods and iTunes online store. Apple has reinvented the mobile phone with its revolutionary iPhone and App Store, and is defining the future of mobile media and computing devices with iPad.</p></blockquote>
<h4>January 2013 &#8211; Something MacPro users will love?</h4>
<p>Writing as a long-term user of Apple&#8217;s professional software, I find it interesting that despite predictions of Apple abandoning pro users, pro software has been part of the way Apple identifies itself since July 2004. However given that iLife and iWork haven&#8217;t changed very often over the last few years, they&#8217;ll either be updated soon, or dropped from Apple&#8217;s corporate definition.</p>
<p>Given that an email from Tim Cook reassured that later this year Apple will introduce a product that MacPro users will love, how could that redefine Apple? Here&#8217;s a possible definition from me:</p>
<blockquote><p>Apple leads the digital music revolution with its iPods and iTunes online store. Apple reinvented the mobile phone with its revolutionary iPhone and App Store, and is defining the future of mobile media and computing devices with iPad. <span style="color:#000000;"><em>Apple helps people organise their lives with iLife, iWork and iCloud. Apple makes Macs, OS X and professional software: the best content creation tools in the world.</em></span></p></blockquote>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4004/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4004/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4004&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://alex4d.wordpress.com/2013/02/05/apple-is/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>25</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/9957eee2771a6071c439194f4d97fe99?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Aladar</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://alex4d.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/press-release-1995.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">press-release-1995</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://alex4d.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/press-release-1997.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">press-release-1997</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://alex4d.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/press-release-2010.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">press-release-2010</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Beating the Drum for Metaphor</title>
		<link>http://blog.lexiconbranding.com/2013/01/30/beating-the-drum-for-metaphor/</link>
		<comments>http://blog.lexiconbranding.com/2013/01/30/beating-the-drum-for-metaphor/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2013 11:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lexicon® Blog</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Brand Name Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brand Naming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Branding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate naming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Linguistics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Naming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trademarks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David Placek]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ithkuil]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[language]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lexicon Branding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[metaphor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Will Leben]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://lexiconblog.com/?p=286</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[An engaging recent New Yorker article* describes the constructed language Ithkuil, which aims to be “maximally precise” by “eliminating the ambiguity, vagueness, illogic, redundancy, polysemy (multiple meanings) and overall arbitrariness that [are] seemingly ubiquitous in natural human language.” Our first response was that the creator of this constructed language had likely not seen our recent [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=286&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:left;">An engaging recent <em>New Yorker</em> article* describes the constructed language Ithkuil, which aims to be “maximally precise” by “eliminating the ambiguity, vagueness, illogic, redundancy, polysemy (multiple meanings) and overall arbitrariness that [are] seemingly ubiquitous in natural human language.”</p>
<p>Our first response was that the creator of this constructed language had likely not seen <a title="the Unbearable Lightness of Meaning" href="http://lexiconblog.com/2013/01/03/the-unbearable-lightness-of-meaning/" target="_blank">our recent blog post</a> about connotation vs. denotation in brand names. The post notes that connotation is often more important than denotation in brand names. An example is <em>gazelle</em>. For the many who have never actually seen one of these animals, the literal meaning may be a bit blurry, yet to them the gazelle is still likely to connote swiftness and grace.</p>
<p>Our second reaction to Ithkuil was to ask why, as its creator noted, overall arbitrariness is so widespread in human language. The answer’s pretty easy if we picture what occurs in ordinary conversation: as communicators, we incline more toward verbal artistry than toward explicit programming. We <strong>launch</strong> plans as if they were rockets, <strong>face</strong> problems as if they were adversaries, and <strong>target</strong> opportunities as if&#8211;well, no need to flog a metaphorical horse.</p>
<p>Consider what language would be like without metaphor. Rather than launching plans, we’d simply make them, or start them. Metaphor is so intrinsic to the way we use words, it’s even difficult to find literal verbs to substitute for <em>face</em> in “face problems” or <em>target</em> in “target opportunities.” It’s much easier to find other metaphors: <em>attack problems</em>, <em>meet problems head on</em>, <em>embrace change</em>, <em>aim for opportunities</em>…</p>
<p>That gives good reason to suppose that even if a precise language&#8211;be it Ithkuil or C++&#8211;should ever be spoken, it wouldn’t take a day for a ninja band of metaphors to start creeping in.</p>
<p>No wonder, then, that metaphor should be a staple of brand names. Metaphor helps us to see something new in everyday objects. It enables brands like <strong>Tide</strong>, <strong>BlackBerry</strong>, and <strong>Volt</strong> to stand out from the competition by endowing them with a unique, attractive message.</p>
<p>Metaphors do lose their force over time. Our verb <em>reveal</em> goes back to a Latin verb meaning ‘pull back the veil,’ yet that image no longer pops up when we encounter the word. Metaphor weakening explains how we get unwitting blends of metaphor like:</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align:left;">Over all, many experts conclude, advanced climate research in the United States is fragmented among an alphabet soup of agencies, strained by inadequate computing power and starved for the basic measurements of real-world conditions that are needed to improve simulations.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;padding-left:360px;"><em>New York Times</em>, June 11, 2001</p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align:left;">The images in brand names subside over time as well. While the newcomer <strong>Volt</strong> immediately brings to mind an electric charge, the <strong>BlackBerry</strong>, introduced in 1999, now offers models&#8211;the Porsche and the Pearl&#8211;in colors other than black. <strong>Tide</strong>, introduced in 1946, hardly conjures the image of waves in the sea anymore.</p>
<p>But in branding, that’s OK, because a brand name’s heaviest lifting happens up front, when the name is new. A colorful name attracts attention, ties a unique message to a product, and is more likely to spread virally (if you’ll pardon the metaphor) when it’s first introduced.</p>
<p>Therefore, for those – like the inventor of Ithkuil – that wish to make language more efficient, we recommend metaphor, which in a single word can turn a caterpillar into a butterfly.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">— Will Leben, Chair of Linguistics</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">
* Joshua Foer, <a href="http://www.newyorker.com/reporting/2012/12/24/121224fa_fact_foer" target="_blank">“Utopian for Beginners: An Amateur Linguist Loses Control of the Language He Invented.”</a> The New Yorker, December 24 &amp; 31, 2012.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/286/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/286/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=286&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://blog.lexiconbranding.com/2013/01/30/beating-the-drum-for-metaphor/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>20</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/bb7241ca6a25c3359d36324be21b773d?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lexiconblog</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>An Undelivered Letter to My Loved One</title>
		<link>http://imthatkay.wordpress.com/2013/02/01/an-undelivered-letter-to-my-loved-one/</link>
		<comments>http://imthatkay.wordpress.com/2013/02/01/an-undelivered-letter-to-my-loved-one/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2013 04:26:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>imthatkay</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Opinion/Personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Random]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Anniversary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crying]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Death]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[deceased]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Letter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Memories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tears]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Undelivered]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://imthatkay.wordpress.com/?p=921</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[To you, I don&#8217;t know whether to feel relieved, sad, or guilty.  Right now, I feel a little of all three.  But mostly guilty.  I was dreading the day, watching the calendar as it crept up.  But then I got so caught up that it came and went and I hardly noticed.  I didn&#8217;t even [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=921&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>To you,</p>
<p>I don&#8217;t know whether to feel relieved, sad, or guilty.  Right now, I feel a little of all three.  But mostly guilty.  I was dreading the day, watching the calendar as it crept up.  But then I got so caught up that it came and went and I hardly noticed.  I didn&#8217;t even realize until just now that I had missed it. And now I battle this gang of emotions and the only thing I knew to do was this: to write it out.  To write it to you.</p>
<p><span id="more-921"></span></p>
<p>The fact that you will never receive this letter does not hinder my writing it.  It doesn&#8217;t make me feel liberated, as I wish more than anything that you could.  I thought of writing to you often and just putting all the notes into a jar and saving them up until it was full and I could bring it to you, but I know I can&#8217;t.  The road to you has been all but demolished, so much so that I am afraid to even try it.  And besides, I know even if I did, it would not be you that I&#8217;d be finding there.</p>
<p>There were two things I never got to do.  One you knew: to keep open communication via instant messaging that you had set up and talked with me about.  I got so busy with school and friends that I forgot to search your email.  I forgot to find you.  One you did not know.  It was a cheap painting that I had been working on of wolves.  It was an advanced paint by number, if you will, and honestly it looked like shit.  I felt compelled to finish it and worked fervently for several days, but then I broke. The paint had dried up, the colors weren&#8217;t matching anymore, and my shaking hands couldn&#8217;t catch the details.</p>
<p>For a while, I couldn&#8217;t watch a <a class="zem_slink" title="Sterling Jewelers" href="http://www.sterlingjewelers.com/" target="_blank" rel="homepage">Kay Jewelers</a>&#8216; commercial without crying.  For a month I went to class in a fog and otherwise slept.  I couldn&#8217;t talk about it.  I couldn&#8217;t talk about you.  It took years to get through a story about you without my voice breaking.  And now here I sit, grieving the fact that I went through the anniversary without shedding one tear, without even realizing it was that day.</p>
<p>Maybe it&#8217;s a good thing.  I did finally get to a point in which I could talk about you and not have to excuse myself afterward so I could dab my eyes in private.  Maybe this is another step towards acceptance and a healthy moving on.  But that creates another emotion: fear.  I fear this process.  I don&#8217;t want that to go away.  I want that hurt, just a little, because it reminds me of how important you were.</p>
<p>I know that the pain easing does not mean I don&#8217;t care as much as I used to.  I know it&#8217;s supposed to get easier with more time.  But I also know that I don&#8217;t want to forget those little things that make it so painful in the first place.  I don&#8217;t want to cry, but I do.  Not yesterday.  Not on the anniversary anymore.  Not on your birthday anymore.  Not on holidays anymore. And that&#8217;s when I realize that I will never forget the little things, no matter what, because all those little things were what made you so important.  There are certain songs that will always remind me of you and your guitar on the front porch.  There are certain movies that will always make me think of <a class="zem_slink" title="Christmas Eve" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Christmas_Eve" target="_blank" rel="wikipedia">Christmas Eve</a> and you opening your gifts and knowing exactly what they were before the paper was even off. There are certain symbols and pictures and objects that will remind me of your connections to our heritage and your tattoo.  There are still those times that I can hear your voice as clear as if you were sitting next to me – and even still those times that I expect to hear that voice answer the phone.  And those are the things that will never go away.  And I will cry, always, because no matter how long it is, I will miss you.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter" alt="" src="http://www.thecheapplace.com/image/cache/data/Product-images/ivamis/P3117-Tribal-Feathers-Patch-190x190.jpg" width="190" height="190" /></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/921/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/921/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=921&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://imthatkay.wordpress.com/2013/02/01/an-undelivered-letter-to-my-loved-one/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>64</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/bebb79ac72e55dabadbb6a70ec05b54f?s=96&#38;d=wavatar&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">imthatkay</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://www.thecheapplace.com/image/cache/data/Product-images/ivamis/P3117-Tribal-Feathers-Patch-190x190.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Six Nations Rugby: The Super Bowl\&#8217;s Antithesis</title>
		<link>http://mariannebevis2.wordpress.com/2013/02/02/six-nations-rugby-the-super-bowls-antithesis/</link>
		<comments>http://mariannebevis2.wordpress.com/2013/02/02/six-nations-rugby-the-super-bowls-antithesis/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2013 16:05:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>clarabellabevis</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[American football]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rugby union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Six Nations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Super Bowl]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mariannebevis2.wordpress.com/?p=32</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[You might be forgiven—were you American—for believing that the entire sporting world pauses on its axis in awe as the brouhaha that is Super Bowl sweeps towards NFL Championship Sunday. And in fairness, the reach of the biggest sporting event in the United States has a huge international audience. A global audience of more than [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=32&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://mariannebevis2.wordpress.com/2013/02/02/six-nations-rugby-the-super-bowls-antithesis/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>37</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/82e031beb89e49052f8e856ffea1c880?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">clarabellabevis</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mariannebevis2.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/super-bowl1-e1359820866230.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">super bowl</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Public Art and the Case of Henry Moore\&#8217;s Outdoor Sculpture</title>
		<link>http://chelseapierce.wordpress.com/2013/02/01/cultural-stewardship-public-art-and-the-case-of-henry-moores-outdoor-sculpture/</link>
		<comments>http://chelseapierce.wordpress.com/2013/02/01/cultural-stewardship-public-art-and-the-case-of-henry-moores-outdoor-sculpture/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 22:09:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>chelseapierce</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[museums]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Henry Moore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[london]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[public art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sale]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sculpture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UK]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://chelseapierce.wordpress.com/?p=377</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Figure 1. Moore’s Draped Seated Woman. From The Guardian.  A recent article in the Guardian newspaper has raised questions regarding the democratization of art and institutional responsibilities in the stewardship of public cultural patrimony. In regards to public art, it is often difficult to determine who is responsible for its care and maintenance. In light [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=377&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone" alt="" src="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2012/11/7/1352318511537/Henry-Moores-sculpture-Dr-008.jpg" width="460" height="276" /></p>
<p>Figure 1. Moore’s <i>Draped Seated Woman</i><i>. </i>From<i> The Guardian. </i></p>
<p>A recent article in the <i>Guardian</i> newspaper has raised questions regarding the democratization of art and institutional responsibilities in the stewardship of public cultural patrimony. In regards to public art, it is often difficult to determine who is responsible for its care and maintenance. In light of the global economic recession, it is clear that the cultural sector is in desperate need of funding. Difficult decisions have been made to maintain budgets such as a London council’s proposal to sell a statue by Henry Moore. What must be determined is how far cultural institutions’ responsibilities extend as stewards of public art, and furthermore, who in the public has the right to lay claim.</p>
<p>In the case of a Henry Moore sculpture, which is located outdoors for public access, many problems have surfaced regarding the future of its care. Arguments have ensued from the council and members of the public over maintaining the statue&#8217;s current location and the artist&#8217;s original intent. This case—while not directly involving a museum—still pertains to museums’ and other cultural institutions’ responsibilities to their public regarding the ownership and care of art, and also demonstrates elitism within the cultural sector. Therefore, I will present the case as follows to serve as a precedent for future dilemmas over selling a piece of long-standing material culture for shortsighted revenue and determine how future cases can be mediated through the multi-vocality of stakeholders.</p>
<p>In summary, this case pertains to an article detailing the potential sale of Henry Moore’s <i>Draped Seated Woman</i><a title="" href="#_ftn1"><b>[1]</b></a><i>,</i> located outdoors within a “socially deprived” area of East London<a title="" href="#_ftn2">[2]</a>. East London Council has proposed the sale of the sculpture after a £100 million cut to their budget. The £20 million estimate for the statue’s worth in consideration with additional savings in maintenance and insurance costs has propelled the council to take such actions. Additionally, the council maintains that the sculpture’s current location makes it susceptible to graffiti and other damage.</p>
<p>However, members of the “cultural elite,”<a title="" href="#_ftn3">[3]</a> such as film director Danny Boyle and Tate Gallery Director Sir Nicholas Serota have made arguments in a letter to the council for the sculpture’s retention with the support of the artist’s daughter, Mary Moore. Boyle and Serota argue that the £20 million estimate is inflated, as the price would be an all-time high for a Moore sculpture. They appraise the sculpture at £5 million, which would not significantly improve the council’s budget. Furthermore, Serota and Boyle contend that the sale of the sculpture contradicts the artist’s original intent, using Mary Moore’s testimony to corroborate such claims. The article describes Moore as a “life-long socialist”<a title="" href="#_ftn4">[4]</a> who accepted a much lower price for his work than collectors would have offered under the agreement that the sculpture would remain in an area of low socio-economic status for the residents’ own enrichment. Mary Moore purports that her father believed in the importance of art in everyday life and would want it to remain in a public space. Boyle proposes a solution for the statue to be moved to an outdoor Olympic Park facility in East London, where the sculpture would remain in sight, thus protecting it from potential damage, yet allowing the work to still be accessible to the public.</p>
<p>In order to mediate these arguments, several factors must be considered such as cultural institutions’ roles in proper stewardship. This involves a discourse on ethics: Is it ethical to sell objects of cultural patrimony for revenue? Furthermore, who has the right to make such decisions? The news article’s description of Boyle and Serota as “cultural elite” raises questions of authority as well as cultural paternalism. Lastly, in concern of ethics, how far do cultural institutions’ adherence to artists’ original intent extend?</p>
<p>Tristram Besterman’s article <i>Museum Ethics</i> provides a workable definition of ethics that can be used in this case study. Besterman states, “ethics is an expression of social responsibility” and explains that “ethics defines the relationship of the museum with people, not with things.”<a title="" href="#_ftn5">[5]</a> Therefore, in this definition, the council’s ethical role is to identify the stakeholders of the sculpture and address each party’s opinions and requests. Obviously, the residents of East London are the primary stakeholders, as the sculpture is a part of their daily lives and is located within their tax-paying district. Secondly, the “cultural elite,” represented by Serota and Boyle, are stakeholders as well. Demonstrated by their public claims, they are concerned parties and have proposed counterarguments and solutions. Also, Mary Moore represents the artist as a stakeholder and upholds what she believes to be her father’s original intention for the sculpture. Lastly, the East London Council is also a stakeholder, as it is the present steward of the sculpture and has been charged with the sculpture’s maintenance and care.</p>
<p>Besterman goes on to explain that within museums, “collections are part of the public realm” and that it is the stewards’ role to ensure that the collections remain accessible to the public.<a title="" href="#_ftn6">[6]</a>  While the Henry Moore sculpture does not exist within a museum, it is part of a collection of public art and monuments. Ian Leith of the Public Monuments and Sculpture Association, a non-profit organization that raises awareness of the value of public art, believes that the Henry Moore sculpture in question belongs to “the greatest national gallery of all—which is outdoors—and it&#8217;s completely undefined.”<a title="" href="#_ftn7">[7]</a> Consequently, these same questions of ethical stewardship within museums apply to the Henry Moore sculpture and should be treated in a similar way.</p>
<p>Clearly, the main issue in this argument is money, or the lack thereof, which is an issue that museums face today. Detailed in a more recent article pertaining to the Henry Moore sale, are other sales of public art in the United Kingdom such as the Bolton Council’s sale of several works of art by artists such as Picasso and John Everett Millais. Gloucester City Council, Newcastle City Council and Leicestershire County Council have also made similar sales of their public art collections.<a title="" href="#_ftn8">[8]</a> Besterman explains how many museums in the United States “trade-up” or sell some of their objects as sources for revenue, but that this practice is frowned upon in the UK.<a title="" href="#_ftn9">[9]</a> Therefore it is interesting to see that the stance on sales for public art differ from sales of museum assets.</p>
<p>I feel the underlying problem here is that public art is not valued in the same way as art within museums is, nor is there a clear steward to advocate for the collection of public art in consideration of the public’s interests. There seems to be a need for a museum-like institution to take charge of public art and manage the collection in an institutional manner. Vera Zolberg’s article <i>An Elite Experience for Everyone </i>explains how museums have to justify their purpose to the public and their need for public funding by providing statistics in attendance.<a title="" href="#_ftn10">[10]</a> How can a collection of public art justify its purpose? By evaluating the stakeholders’ claims to <i>Draped Seated Woman</i>, perhaps the public’s claim to such works and the status of public art can be negotiated and serve in future cases.</p>
<p>Boyle and Serota seem to be arguing for the residents of East London, whose opinions have not been addressed in the articles surrounding this case. As their voices and opinions have not been heard, it is difficult to determine their stance on the sale of the sculpture. Is it ethical for Boyle and Serota, members of the “cultural elite,” to make assumptions for the voiceless residents of East London? Their arguments for the retention of the sculpture imply more than simple altruism. Their stance and positions of authority allude to issues of elitism in museums, a topic that has received much attention in the last 50 years. Stephen Weil explains how museums have portrayed their institutions as “philanthropic,” “charitable,” and “benevolent.” <a title="" href="#_ftn11">[11]</a> These words imply that museums come from higher ground than that of their public and that their role is to extend their knowledge downwards to the masses through actions of “social enterprise”<a title="" href="#_ftn12">[12]</a>. The inferred authority of the museum stems back to the origins of museums and digresses from our topic, yet it is important to keep in mind that museums and by extension museum professionals and other cultural sector leaders maintain a level of authority.</p>
<p>Nonetheless, Boyle and Serota’s arguments maintain the notion that members of the elite can determine what is appropriate for the public. This draws on Zolberg’s discourse on “cultural literacy,” or the summary of Pierre Bourdieu’s ideas that differing groups of people hold different levels of cultural capital. This capital is based on their <i>habitus</i> or cultural baggage, based on socio-political and economic status.<a title="" href="#_ftn13">[13]</a> In short, peoples’ cultural knowledge or appreciation is determined by their social and economic backgrounds. As members of the elite typically hold more cultural capital, it is assumed to be their right and role to determine what is best for those of smaller cultural capital.</p>
<p>Returning to the case at hand, the <i>Guardian</i> article makes clear the site of the sculpture is in a “socially deprived” area.<a title="" href="#_ftn14">[14]</a> Thus, Boyle and Serota argue that the retention of the sculpture’s location is crucial to the residents’ cultural enrichment and appreciation. Mary Moore supplements these claims with her testimony of her father’s agreement on the location as crucial to promoting the democratization of art. But is it the cultural elite or artist’s daughter’s place to make such determinations? The East London Council (ELC) would argue it is not. Speaking more for the residents than Serota and Boyle, the ELC seems to be making difficult decisions for the good of the residents. In identifying their shortage of money, the sale of the sculpture could be perceived as a way to lift the financial burden and perhaps maintain some benefits that would be otherwise cut if the statue stays in place. But the ELC is not just thinking of the money; the council obviously feels that for the residents, the Henry Moore holds no cultural capital, hence the vandalism and thefts of such public monuments. A recent article details the council’s final decision to ignore the advisement of Boyle and Serota and place the sculpture at auction.<a title="" href="#_ftn15">[15]</a> As the fate of this sculpture seems decided, I feel responsible to provide alternative solutions for future propositions.</p>
<p>Returning to my previous thoughts on the perceived lack of value for public art, I feel that some form of a non-profit similar to the Public Monuments and Sculpture Association should take stewardship of the outdoor collection. In doing so, new acquisitions can be thoughtfully assessed with regards to expenses and the sales of public works could be avoided. A more defined budget would also be set in place for the maintenance and protection of the works. Also, a museum-like institution would assumedly adhere to a similar code of ethics, and thus decisions regarding stakeholders can be mediated properly. It is important that the public gets a say in the future of its patrimony, and as museums are shifting their missions more towards public needs, more voices are being heard. Therefore, a non-profit acting as stewards of public art would consider the public’s needs more effectively, and hopefully in the future, public art will be withheld from the budgetary chopping block.</p>
<div>
<hr align="left" size="1" width="33%" />
<div>
<p><a title="" href="#_ftnref1">[1]</a> See Figure 1</p>
<p><a title="" href="#_ftnref2">[2]</a> (Alberge 2012)</p>
</div>
<div>
<p><a title="" href="#_ftnref3">[3]</a> Ibid.</p>
</div>
<div>
<p><a title="" href="#_ftnref4">[4]</a> Ibid.</p>
</div>
<div>
<p><a title="" href="#_ftnref5">[5]</a> (Besterman 2008)</p>
</div>
<div>
<p><a title="" href="#_ftnref6">[6]</a> (Besterman 2008)</p>
</div>
<div>
<p><a title="" href="#_ftnref7">[7]</a> (Alberge 2012)</p>
</div>
<div>
<p><a title="" href="#_ftnref8">[8]</a> (Hill 2012)</p>
</div>
<div>
<p><a title="" href="#_ftnref9">[9]</a> (Besterman 2008)</p>
</div>
<div>
<p><a title="" href="#_ftnref10">[10]</a> (Zolberg 1994)</p>
</div>
<div>
<p><a title="" href="#_ftnref11">[11]</a> (Weil 1999)</p>
</div>
<div>
<p><a title="" href="#_ftnref12">[12]</a> Ibid.</p>
</div>
<div>
<p><a title="" href="#_ftnref13">[13]</a> (Zolberg 1994)</p>
</div>
<div>
<p><a title="" href="#_ftnref14">[14]</a> (Alberge 2012)</p>
</div>
<div>
<p><a title="" href="#_ftnref15">[15]</a> (Hill 2012)</p>
<h1 align="center">Works Cited</h1>
<p>Alberge, Dayla. “Britain&#8217;s Cultural Elite Battles to Halt Sale of Henry Moore Sculpture<i>.</i>” Prod. <i>The Guardian</i>. London, November 3, 2012.</p>
<p>Besterman, Tristram. &#8220;Museum Ethics.&#8221; In <i>A Companion to Museum Studies</i>, by Sharon Macdonald, 431-441. Chichester: Wiley, 2008.</p>
<p>Hill, Amelia. “Henry Moore sculpture Decision Raises Fears for Public Art.&#8221; <i>The Guardian.</i> London, November 7, 2012.</p>
<p>Weil, Stephen. &#8220;From Being About Something to Being for Somebody.&#8221; In <i>Reinventing the Museum</i>, by Gail Anderson, 170-188. Lanham: AltaMira Press, 1999.</p>
<p>Zolberg, Vera. &#8220;An Elite Experience for Everyone.&#8221; In <i>Museum Culture: Histories, Discourses, Spectacles</i>, by D. Sherman and I. Rogoff, 49-63. Minneapolis: University of Minnesota Press, 1994.</p>
</div>
</div>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/377/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/377/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=377&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://chelseapierce.wordpress.com/2013/02/01/cultural-stewardship-public-art-and-the-case-of-henry-moores-outdoor-sculpture/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>28</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/30b0c6e2fe30538c9129edef79a71822?s=96&#38;d=identicon" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">chelseapierce</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2012/11/7/1352318511537/Henry-Moores-sculpture-Dr-008.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Newspaper Stories Are Too Long, Except When They’re Too Short</title>
		<link>http://stevebuttry.wordpress.com/2013/01/29/newspaper-stories-are-too-long-except-when-theyre-too-short/</link>
		<comments>http://stevebuttry.wordpress.com/2013/01/29/newspaper-stories-are-too-long-except-when-theyre-too-short/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 14:35:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Steve Buttry</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alan Mutter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brady Dennis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gene Weingarten]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Grantland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jim Gannon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joe McGuff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Longreads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York Times]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Roy Wenzl]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Atlantic]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://stevebuttry.wordpress.com/?p=10799</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Alan Mutter makes a point that I&#8217;ve been hearing editors make most of my career: Most newspaper stories are too long. I&#8217;m sure he&#8217;s right. But some newspaper stories are too short. And story length is way down the list of problems facing the newspaper business. I remember when I was at the Des Moines [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=10799&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Alan Mutter makes a point that I&#8217;ve been hearing editors make most of my career: <a title="Most newspaper stories are too long" href="http://newsosaur.blogspot.ca/2013/01/most-newspaper-stories-are-still-too.html">Most newspaper stories are too long</a>.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m sure he&#8217;s right. But some newspaper stories are too short. And story length is way down the list of problems facing the newspaper business.</p>
<p>I remember when I was at the Des Moines Register, <a title="James P. Gannon" href="http://spectator.org/people/james-p-gannon/all">Jim Gannon</a>, who I believe was executive editor at the time, decreed that no story could be longer than he was tall. He was 5&#8217;10&#8243;, as I recall, so a story couldn&#8217;t be longer than 70 inches. 70 inches! Register reporters were writing so long that Gannon&#8217;s idea of introducing some discipline was to limit stories to 70 inches (and newspaper columns were wider then than they are today).<span id="more-10799"></span></p>
<p>When I was at the Kansas City Times, Editor <a title="Joe McGuff" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joe_McGuff">Joe McGuff</a> tried to hold stories to no more than 35 inches. But, he assured us (when President Ronald Reagan was in the news for defying Libyan dictator <a title="Muammar Gaddafi" href="http://topics.nytimes.com/top/reference/timestopics/people/q/muammar_el_qaddafi/index.html?8qa">Muammar Gaddafi</a>&#8216;s &#8220;Line of Death&#8221; in the <a title="Gulf of Sidra" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gulf_of_Sidra">Gulf of Sidra</a>) the limit was not a line of death; reporters could exceed it if they made the case to McGuff and got permission for a particular story.</p>
<p>At various times, editors have restricted jumps from page one, either forbidding them entirely or limiting them to one or two stories a day.</p>
<p>I support Mutter, Gannon, McGuff and lots of editors past and present in their quest to introduce more discipline in journalists&#8217; writing. I freely acknowledge that many of my blog posts run too long, without the limited space of print and without editors to help me trim an extraneous word here and a redundant paragraph there.</p>
<p>But frankly, the problem and the challenge (whether in my blog or in a newspaper or on a news website) is not how long the story is, but whether it&#8217;s worth the length. I can&#8217;t recall ever getting more reader response than I did from two stories that were 70 inches (about the <a title="Lessons in narrative journalism from the rescue of the twins" href="http://stevebuttry.wordpress.com/2011/01/17/lessons-in-narrative-journalism-from-the-rescue-of-the-twins/">rescue of twins who nearly froze</a>) and 200 inches long (about <a title="The Homecoming" href="http://www.scribd.com/doc/57824432/The-Homecoming">four people</a> in a <a title="The Homecoming" href="http://stevebuttry.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/homecoming.jpg">famous photograph of a World War II homecoming</a>). Those stories didn&#8217;t work because readers want long stories. They connected with readers because they were two of the best stories of my career and people enjoy reading <em>good </em>stories however long they are.</p>
<p>Good stories don&#8217;t have to be long. I&#8217;m not sure either the twins story or the homecoming story were as good as <a title="Roy Wenzl" href="http://www.goodreads.com/author/show/518382.Roy_Wenzl">Roy Wenzl</a>&#8216;s <a title="Baby's birth broke the speed limit" href="http://www.niemanstoryboard.org/2005/04/21/babys-birth-broke-the-speed-limit/">mystery child story</a> or <a title="Brady Dennis" href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/brady-dennis/2011/02/25/ABMgsCJ_page.html">Brady Dennis</a>&#8216; &#8220;<a title="After the sky fell" href="http://www.sptimes.com/2005/01/28/Tampabay/After_the_sky_fell.shtml">After the sky fell</a>&#8221; story, neither of which would top 20 inches in most newspapers. The length of a story isn&#8217;t what matters; it&#8217;s how well the story connects with readers.</p>
<p><a title="Longreads" href="http://longreads.com/">Longreads</a> and <a title="Grantland" href="http://www.grantland.com/">Grantland</a> are carving out their digital niches based on their faith in people&#8217;s interest in long, well-written stories. <a title="The Atlantic" href="http://www.theatlantic.com/">The Atlantic</a> doesn&#8217;t shy from presenting long stories that are worth the time to read. I&#8217;m confident that journalists and news organizations will continue writing good, long stories at the same time as newspapers fill their precious dwindling space with too many long stories that don&#8217;t merit the space.</p>
<p>I absolutely support Mutter&#8217;s call to tell stories with tables, charts, infographics and other tools when those are more appropriate storytelling tools than strings of paragraphs. The New York Times <a title="Snowfall" href="http://www.nytimes.com/projects/2012/snow-fall">Snowfall</a> project engaged readers successfully by using words and multimedia tools effectively. So did Gene Weingarten&#8217;s Pulitzer Prize-winning <a title="Pearls Before Breakfast" href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-dyn/content/article/2007/04/04/AR2007040401721.html">Pearls Before Breakfast</a>, which deftly inserted video clips into the text of a long narrative.</p>
<p>We have lots of data about how well stories connect. We know which stories readers are most likely to share with their friends and which they read for long times and which they skim quickly. We should learn from that data and try to write the types of stories that people are going to want to read and share. That&#8217;s way more important than worrying about how long or short a story is.</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://stevebuttry.wordpress.com/category/writing-2/'>Writing</a> Tagged: <a href='http://stevebuttry.wordpress.com/tag/alan-mutter/'>Alan Mutter</a>, <a href='http://stevebuttry.wordpress.com/tag/brady-dennis/'>Brady Dennis</a>, <a href='http://stevebuttry.wordpress.com/tag/gene-weingarten/'>Gene Weingarten</a>, <a href='http://stevebuttry.wordpress.com/tag/grantland/'>Grantland</a>, <a href='http://stevebuttry.wordpress.com/tag/jim-gannon/'>Jim Gannon</a>, <a href='http://stevebuttry.wordpress.com/tag/joe-mcguff/'>Joe McGuff</a>, <a href='http://stevebuttry.wordpress.com/tag/longreads/'>Longreads</a>, <a href='http://stevebuttry.wordpress.com/tag/new-york-times/'>New York Times</a>, <a href='http://stevebuttry.wordpress.com/tag/roy-wenzl/'>Roy Wenzl</a>, <a href='http://stevebuttry.wordpress.com/tag/the-atlantic/'>The Atlantic</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/10799/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/10799/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=10799&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://stevebuttry.wordpress.com/2013/01/29/newspaper-stories-are-too-long-except-when-theyre-too-short/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>45</slash:comments>
		<georss:point>0.000000 0.000000</georss:point>
		<geo:lat>0.000000</geo:lat>
		<geo:long>0.000000</geo:long>
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/103c45b1efe7ffb01b96e614207363b0?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">stevebuttry</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
