<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2013 20:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Somalia is Not India: The Importance of Cultural Competency</title>
		<link>http://breakboundaries.wordpress.com/2013/01/10/somalia-is-not-india-the-importance-of-cultural-competency/</link>
		<comments>http://breakboundaries.wordpress.com/2013/01/10/somalia-is-not-india-the-importance-of-cultural-competency/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2013 19:18:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>breakboundaries</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[social justice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[civil rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[refugees]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://breakboundaries.wordpress.com/?p=570</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I have started reading the book The Spirit Catches You and You Fall Down, a story of a Hmong child and her encounters with the American medical system. As I read about the loyal social worker and her above and beyond commitment to Lia Lee&#8217;s family, I can&#8217;t help but think about my own experiences with [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=570&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://breakboundaries.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_3300.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-571 aligncenter" alt="Spirit Catches You" src="http://breakboundaries.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_3300.jpg?w=400&#038;h=400" width="400" height="400" /></a></p>
<p>I have started reading the book <em>The Spirit Catches You and You Fall Down</em>, a story of a Hmong child and her encounters with the American medical system. As I read about the loyal social worker and her above and beyond commitment to Lia Lee&#8217;s family, I can&#8217;t help but think about my own experiences with a refugee.</p>
<p>For confidentiality reasons, I&#8217;ll call him Nadif, which means &#8220;between seasons&#8221; because in many ways, Nadif was always in a liminal stage. He escaped his war-torn country of Somalia through a sponsorship, along with his sister. Little is known about his mother and father &#8212; whenever I&#8217;ve asked him, he would go on a tangent about a blind man and suddenly start speaking both French and English.</p>
<p>Nadif was intelligent: he was trilingual (he spoke English, Somali, and French fluently), he had dreams of becoming a water engineer in Somalia and he followed American politics religiously (although he said he&#8217;d vote for Mitt Romney, not realizing what that means to the welfare he was receiving).</p>
<p>He became a client in our program sometime in the early 2000s, following a psychiatric hospitalization, aggressive behavior landing him in jail and then being diagnosed and put on psychiatric medications. Although he had been in the mental health system for several years, it wasn&#8217;t until he was transferred to my caseload that I realized he ought to be diagnosed with PTSD and not schizophrenia. I had no idea he was from Somalia until his green card fell out of his chart, with &#8220;country of origin: Somalia&#8221; written on it.</p>
<p>He had always been adamant about becoming a citizen. He knew the process full well, having applied and been waiting for someone to walk him through the process. His previous case manager, though both compassionate and sensitive to Nadif&#8217;s needs, wasn&#8217;t able to spend the time Nadif sought to reach this dream of his, hence transferring Nadif to my caseload. I decided that &#8220;taking medications regularly&#8221; wasn&#8217;t as big of a priority to us as &#8220;become an American citizen.&#8221;</p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 410px"><img alt="" src="http://www.unhcr.org/thumb1/50052c9d6.jpg" width="400" height="303" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Somali refugees source: <a href="http://www.unhcr.org" rel="nofollow">http://www.unhcr.org</a></p></div>
<p>The mental health system has told Nadif repeatedly that he must take his medications and has gone as far as belittle him like a child for missing medications or refusing to take them. I don&#8217;t know about you, but I&#8217;ve never taken psychiatric medications and I know I would hate to take them since the list of side effects is endless. I don&#8217;t blame him for not wanting to take his medications, just like Lia Lee&#8217;s family struggled to find the benefits of giving their baby seizure medications.</p>
<p>I still remember someone in the office saying, about Nadif, &#8220;That Indian guy?&#8221; which really left me shaking my head. Nadif doesn&#8217;t even look Indian, on top of the fact that his last name is Arabic, which again is NOT INDIAN. How ignorant could we be to assume that he is something he was not! On top of that mishap, his chart indicated that he was Muslim; however, through my many conversations with Nadif, I discovered he attended church and had become Christian through the woman who sponsored him to the States. He talked about Jesus Christ with such awe, but often struggled with the thought that Jesus was white (don&#8217;t get me started) and equated his injustices with the fact that he himself is black.</p>
<p>My favorite memory with Nadif was after our gruesomely long process of getting him prepared for his citizenship test. With the help of a pro-bono attorney who specializes in assisting immigrants and refugees with obtaining their citizenship, we were able to get Nadif all the way up to his citizenship test. In that large and crowded waiting room, I sat with Nadif as he kept reading and re-reading his citizenship study packet (do you know who your senator is or what the Bill of Rights says? Nadif does).</p>
<p>He passed with flying colors and with the utmost confidence. We were told because of his criminal background (around the time of his first &#8220;psychotic&#8221; breakdown) that even though he passed, they would have to screen his results but that we should anticipate a notice in the mail for his oath ceremony. I am pretty sure I cried tears of joy. I know Nadif did. We walked out of that office and he tried to grab my cheeks, saying, <strong>&#8220;My little sister! Thank you! I love you!&#8221;</strong></p>
<p>Because I had to leave my agency to focus on graduate school, I don&#8217;t know if he ever received his letter about his oath ceremony. Through my old coworkers, it sounds like he may not have and might be back at square one, struggling to get enough cash for cigarettes and sodas. I don&#8217;t know if maybe he was hospitalized again and quickly treated as yet another zombie, walking the halls of inpatient psychiatric care.</p>
<p>The lessons we learn from <em>The Spirit Catches You and You Fall Down</em> is applicable not just to doctors and social workers; as human beings, we need to constantly learn about other cultures and increase our cultural competency. I chose to not pressure him to &#8220;do as he&#8217;s told&#8221; and focus on his dreams and his goals. Why did he want to become an American citizen so bad when he already had a green card? Because he wanted to be able to vote, because he followed our political process so closely, because he didn&#8217;t want the threat of deportation looming over his head if ever he was found guilty of God-knows-what, because he was done with Africa and because he thought America was the land of opportunity.</p>
<p>Refugees are seeking refuge. Refuge is defined as a place of protection from danger, a shelter and a place of safety. I can&#8217;t say that Nadif felt any safer or protected from danger here in America. Granted, he has food and shelter and a bit of money thanks to welfare, but what baffles me the most is one of the last things Nadif said to me before I left the agency.</p>
<p><strong>&#8220;I am going to go back to Africa. White man is god in America.&#8221;</strong></p>
<p>My hope is this: that American institutions &#8212; schools, medical offices, mental health agencies, social service organizations, even coffee shops and retail stores &#8212; will be filled with much more culturally competent people, who seek to meet newcomers where they are at, be driven to understand where people come from, and be committed to embracing the diversity that makes up this country.</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://breakboundaries.wordpress.com/category/civil-rights/'>civil rights</a>, <a href='http://breakboundaries.wordpress.com/category/culture/'>culture</a>, <a href='http://breakboundaries.wordpress.com/category/personal/'>personal</a>, <a href='http://breakboundaries.wordpress.com/category/refugees/'>refugees</a>, <a href='http://breakboundaries.wordpress.com/category/social-justice/'>social justice</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/570/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/570/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=570&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://breakboundaries.wordpress.com/2013/01/10/somalia-is-not-india-the-importance-of-cultural-competency/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/df636111d13281a8a9591dcd41ffb901?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Peggy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://breakboundaries.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_3300.jpg?w=545" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Spirit Catches You</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://www.unhcr.org/thumb1/50052c9d6.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The web responds to the death of hacker-activist Aaron Swartz</title>
		<link>http://gigaom.com/2013/01/12/the-web-responds-to-the-death-of-hacker-activist-aaron-swartz/</link>
		<comments>http://gigaom.com/2013/01/12/the-web-responds-to-the-death-of-hacker-activist-aaron-swartz/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2013 16:40:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Mathew Ingram</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Aaron Swartz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Freedom of information]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hacking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[JSTOR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Justice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[suicide]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://gigaom.com/?p=601342</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Aaron Swartz, an early Reddit staffer and founder of the open-web activist group Demand Progress, committed suicide on Friday at the age of 26, touching off an outpouring of grief and memorials from a wide range of friends and colleagues.<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=601342&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The open web and freedom of information in general lost one of their most passionate proponents yesterday, with the death of early Reddit staffer and Demand Progress founder Aaron Swartz, <a href="http://tech.mit.edu/V132/N61/swartz.html">who committed suicide on Friday</a>, according to a family member. He was facing federal charges for hacking into the JSTOR academic database and <a href="http://gigaom.com/2011/07/19/aaron-swartz-hacked-mit-library/">downloading millions of research papers</a>, but had also reportedly suffered from depression. He was 26 years old.</p>
<p>As the news of his death <a href="http://www.techmeme.com/130112/p3#a130112p3">spread throughout the web and social networks</a> like Twitter, there was an outpouring of grief and sorrow from some of his friends and those he had worked with on a number of projects &#8212; including the early development of the RSS syndication standard, the web.py software framework, the Creative Commons movement and the W3C web standards committee.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ve collected some of those comments and responses here (there&#8217;s also <a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/16fjjm/aaron_shwartz_reddit_cofounder_rip/">a Reddit thread</a> and a <a href="http://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=5046845">Hacker News thread</a> about his death, and Alex Howard of O&#8217;Reilly has collected <a href="http://storify.com/digiphile/the-internet-mourns-the-death-of-aaron-swartz">some tweets and links</a> in a Storify post):</p>
<p>Sir Tim Berners-Lee, the creator of the web, <a href="https://twitter.com/timberners_lee/status/290140454211698689">posted a message after he learned</a> of the news, saying: &#8220;Aaron dead. World wanderers, we have lost a wise elder. Hackers for right, we are one down. Parents all, we have lost a child. Let us weep.&#8221;</p>
<blockquote class='twitter-tweet' lang='en'><p>Heartbroken about @<a href="https://twitter.com/aaronsw">aaronsw</a>, so brilliant, idealistic, soulful.  Here&#039;s where I first met him. <a href="http://www.thedailybeast.com/newsweek/2004/12/12/what-your-college-kid-is-really-up-to.html"> thedailybeast.com/newsweek/2004/…</a></p>&mdash; <br />Steven Levy (@StevenLevy) <a href='http://twitter.com/#!/StevenLevy/status/290113079642034177' data-datetime='2013-01-12T15:08:42+00:00'>January 12, 2013</a></blockquote>
<blockquote class='twitter-tweet' lang='en'><p>Shocked and saddened to hear about the suicide of Aaron Swartz, whom I first met when he was 14. @<a href="https://twitter.com/doctorow">doctorow</a>&#039;s eulogy <a href="http://bit.ly/VSk8Td"> bit.ly/VSk8Td</a></p>&mdash; <br />Tim O&#039;Reilly (@timoreilly) <a href='http://twitter.com/#!/timoreilly/status/290131206396313600' data-datetime='2013-01-12T16:20:44+00:00'>January 12, 2013</a></blockquote>
<p>Cory Doctorow, author and BoingBoing co-founder, <a href="http://boingboing.net/2013/01/12/rip-aaron-swartz.html">posted a long and heart-felt tribute</a> to Swartz and a discussion of his struggles with depression, saying:</p>
<blockquote id="quote-aaron-accomplished-s"><p>&#8220;Aaron accomplished some incredible things in his life. He was one of the early builders of Reddit (someone always turns up to point out that he was technically not a co-founder, but he was close enough as makes no damn), got bought by Wired/Conde Nast, engineered his own dismissal and got cashed out, and then became a full-time, uncompromising, reckless and delightful shit-disturber&#8230; we have all lost someone today who had more work to do, and who made the world a better place when he did it.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Matt Haughey, the founder of Metafilter, <a href="http://www.metafilter.com/123777/Open-access-open-internet-closed-book#4772018">posted a comment on his site about Aaron</a>, whom he met while he was working on the Creative Commons project with Larry Lessig &#8212; and how at one programming event, Swartz had to come with his father because he was only 15:</p>
<blockquote id="quote-aaron-im-so-sorry-to2"><p>&#8220;Aaron, I&#8217;m so sorry to see you go. You were an amazing person who did incredible work that helps us all out and I really wish you stayed for many more decades so you could continue making society a better place to be. I&#8217;ll really miss you.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Brewster Kahle, founder of the Internet Archive, <a href="http://blog.archive.org/2013/01/12/aaron-swartz-hero-of-the-open-world-rip/">posted a memorial entitled</a> &#8220;Aaron Swartz, hero of the open world, dies&#8221; &#8212; and recalled working with the young man on Kahle&#8217;s Open Library project, which he helped to code:</p>
<blockquote id="quote-aaron-was-steadfast-3"><p>&#8220;Aaron was steadfast in his dedication to building a better and open world. Selfless.   Willing to cause change. He is among the best spirits of the Internet generation. I am crushed by his loss, but will continue to be enlightened by his work and dedication. May a hero and founder of our open world rest in peace.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>In 2007, Swartz wrote <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20070809020323/http://paste.lisp.org/display/40875">what many took to be a suicide note</a> (thanks to Nik Cubrilovic for the link) after he had been fired by Conde Nast (which acquired Reddit in 2006), a note that eventually led Reddit founder Alexis Ohanian to call the police and break into Swartz&#8217;s apartment. The young programmer <a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/1octb/reddit_cofounder_aaron_swartz_discusses_how_he/c1oe1d">later explained that</a> he wrote it while he was in pain due to a medical issue, but some friends took it as a sign that he was struggling with emotional problems as well.</p>
<blockquote class='twitter-tweet' lang='en'><p>RIP Aaron Swartz. What a terrible, tragic waste. <a href="http://boingboing.net/2013/01/12/rip-aaron-swartz.html"> boingboing.net/2013/01/12/rip…</a></p>&mdash; <br />Timothy B. Lee (@binarybits) <a href='http://twitter.com/#!/binarybits/status/290111220491644928' data-datetime='2013-01-12T15:01:19+00:00'>January 12, 2013</a></blockquote>
<blockquote class='twitter-tweet' lang='en'><p>Aaron Swartz was one of my favorite people, and I&#039;m crying. <a href="http://j.mp/UdKWvB"> j.mp/UdKWvB</a></p>&mdash; <br />Adrian Holovaty (@adrianholovaty) <a href='http://twitter.com/#!/adrianholovaty/status/290102876888502272' data-datetime='2013-01-12T14:28:10+00:00'>January 12, 2013</a></blockquote>
<p>In 2007, Philipp Lenssen of the blog Google Blogoscoped <a href="http://blogoscoped.com/archive/2007-05-07-n78.html">posted a long interview with Swartz</a> about his development as a programmer, his work with Reddit and Creative Commons, getting fired by Conde Nast and a number of other topics:</p>
<blockquote id="quote-seriously-though-the4"><p>&#8220;Seriously, though, the Web is what we make of it. We have a powerful, widely-deployed, largely uncontrolled communication network. It’s up to us to decide where to go next.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>John Gruber of the Apple blog Daring Fireball <a href="http://daringfireball.net/linked/2013/01/12/aaronsw">also posted a tribute</a>, saying: &#8220;Aaron was a friend and a brilliant mind&#8230; he had an enormous intellect — again, a brilliant mind — but also an enormous capacity for empathy. He was a great person. I’m dumbfounded and heartbroken.&#8221;</p>
<blockquote class='twitter-tweet' lang='en'><p>wow so sad @<a href="https://twitter.com/aaronsw">aaronsw</a>. he was definitely fighting the good fight.</p>&mdash; <br />from the future (@nk) <a href='http://twitter.com/#!/nk/status/290033584591499264' data-datetime='2013-01-12T09:52:49+00:00'>January 12, 2013</a></blockquote>
<p>Swartz was also involved in the fight against SOPA, the draconian anti-piracy law that Congress tried to pass last year &#8212; this is a video of him discussing the campaign against the bill, which was later shelved:</p>
<span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='560' height='315' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/Fgh2dFngFsg?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span>
<p>Many of those who mourned Swartz&#8217;s passing wondered whether he knew how respected and loved he was by those who were close to him:</p>
<blockquote class='twitter-tweet' lang='en'><p>Angry about @<a href="https://twitter.com/aaronsw">aaronsw</a>&#039;s suicide. So much love for him on the Internet today, did he know?</p>&mdash; <br />Nelson Minar (@nelson) <a href='http://twitter.com/#!/nelson/status/290109762669002752' data-datetime='2013-01-12T14:55:32+00:00'>January 12, 2013</a></blockquote>
<p>Some of Swartz&#8217;s supporters in his fight against the federal charges related to his JSTOR hacking <a href="https://twitter.com/declanm/status/290032735479808000">questioned whether the threat of jail time</a> might have accelerated his depression, but others said he didn&#8217;t seem that troubled by it. As we wrote last year, Swartz &#8212; who had <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2009/02/13/us/13records.html">hacked into a federal database</a> in 2009 and download thousands of documents but never been prosecuted for it &#8212; gained access to a computer at Harvard and ran a program that <a href="http://gigaom.com/2011/07/19/aaron-swartz-hacked-mit-library/">downloaded a huge proportion of the research papers</a> JSTOR sells to universities and other institutions.</p>
<blockquote class='twitter-tweet' lang='en'><p>Fuck. The world seems emptier knowing Aaron&#039;s not in it. Hounded to death by the DOJ after the &quot;victims&quot; dropped charges. All is sadness.</p>&mdash; <br />Nat Torkington (@gnat) <a href='http://twitter.com/#!/gnat/status/290026251232636929' data-datetime='2013-01-12T09:23:41+00:00'>January 12, 2013</a></blockquote>
<p>Larry Lessig, who worked with Swartz on Creative Commons and other projects, has written a post saying what his young friend did with the JSTOR archive was wrong &#8212; although the principle may have been right &#8212; but that <a href="http://lessig.tumblr.com/post/40347463044/prosecutor-as-bully">the government&#8217;s case against him was reprehensible</a> and over-reaching in the extreme: &#8220;Here is where we need a better sense of justice, and shame. For the outrageousness in this story is not just Aaron. It is also the absurdity of the prosecutor’s behavior. From the beginning, the government worked as hard as it could to characterize what Aaron did in the most extreme and absurd way.&#8221;</p>
<blockquote class='twitter-tweet' lang='en'><p>The best tribute to <a href="http://twitter.com/search?q=%23Aaron" title="#Aaron">#Aaron</a> Swartz would be to keep this JSTOR torrent alive. Lasting legacy of a great prodigy - <a href="https://thepiratebay.se/torrent/6554331/Papers_from_Philosophical_Transactions_of_the_Royal_Society__fro"> thepiratebay.se/torrent/655433…</a></p>&mdash; <br />Suhail Kazi (@kazisuhail) <a href='http://twitter.com/#!/kazisuhail/status/290087983686754305' data-datetime='2013-01-12T13:28:59+00:00'>January 12, 2013</a></blockquote>
<blockquote class='twitter-tweet' lang='en'><p>@<a href="https://twitter.com/jdrch">jdrch</a> We don&#039;t know what Aaron was thinking. We do know that, two months from now, he was facing up to 50+ years for &quot;hacking.&quot; @<a href="https://twitter.com/JPBarlow">JPBarlow</a></p>&mdash; <br />Declan McCullagh (@declanm) <a href='http://twitter.com/#!/declanm/status/290032735479808000' data-datetime='2013-01-12T09:49:27+00:00'>January 12, 2013</a></blockquote>
<p>According to those who knew him, Swartz believed that it was wrong to charge so much for access to these papers, many of which were produced by academics for free, and in some cases with government funding (Maria Bustillos has <a href="http://www.theawl.com/2011/08/was-aaron-swartz-stealing">a great overview of the case</a> here). And even though JSTOR said it didn&#8217;t want to proceed with a case against him (and <a href="http://lj.libraryjournal.com/2013/01/academic-libraries/many-jstor-journal-archives-now-free-to-public/">has since opened up its database</a> &#8212; at least a little) the Department of Justice continued with its case, and Swartz faced a potential 35 years in prison.</p>
<blockquote class='twitter-tweet' lang='en'><p>Just heard about @<a href="https://twitter.com/aaronsw">aaronsw</a>: <a href="http://bit.ly/13oQE2B"> bit.ly/13oQE2B</a> Rends my heart. Horrible news for all who loved him, and the Net he loved as well.</p>&mdash; <br />Doc Searls (@dsearls) <a href='http://twitter.com/#!/dsearls/status/290147727814316033' data-datetime='2013-01-12T17:26:23+00:00'>January 12, 2013</a></blockquote>
<p>Bradley Horowitz of Google, and formerly of Yahoo, <a href="https://plus.google.com/113116318008017777871/posts/TirBnLBey8e">remembered talking with Swartz</a> about his plans to use Hangouts for journalistic purposes around the Occupy Wall Street movement:</p>
<blockquote id="quote-i-was-really-heart-b5"><p>&#8220;I was really heart-broken by this news&#8230; Thank you Aaron, for all you contributed to the world, and inspiring so many.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<blockquote class='twitter-tweet' lang='en'><p>This world needs people as brave and brilliant as Aaron Swartz. It just does not tolerate them well.</p>&mdash; <br />Siva Vaidhyanathan (@sivavaid) <a href='http://twitter.com/#!/sivavaid/status/290137149225959424' data-datetime='2013-01-12T16:44:21+00:00'>January 12, 2013</a></blockquote>
<p>In <a href="http://bloggingheads.tv/videos/1602?in=01:17&amp;out=04:06">this video conversation from 2008</a>, Swartz talked about how he got started as a programmer with Economist blogger Will Wilkinson:</p>
<p class="protected-embed-fallback">This embed is invalid</p><!-- blog has no permission to use protected embeds -->
<p>Swartz had prepared a webpage in the event that he <a href="http://www.aaronsw.com/2002/continuity">was &#8220;hit by a truck&#8221;</a> as he put it:</p>
<blockquote id="quote-i-ask-that-the-conte6"><p>&#8220;I ask that the contents of all my hard drives be made publicly available from aaronsw.com&#8230; please update the footer of this page with a link. Also email the relevant lists and set up an autoresponder for my email address to email people who write to me. Feel free to publish things people say about me on the site. Oh, and BTW, I&#8217;ll miss you all.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>This is a photo of the teenaged Aaron Swartz meeting Creative Commons founder and copyright activist Larry Lessig (<a href="http://www.aaronsw.com/weblog/000291">photo by Richard Gibson</a>)</p>
<p><a href="http://gigaom2.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/larryandme.png"><img src="http://gigaom2.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/larryandme.png?w=590" alt="larryandme"   class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-601349" /></a></p>
<p>Web pioneer and Harvard fellow Doc Searls <a href="http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/doc/2013/01/12/losing-aaron-swartz/">wrote a memorial post for Swartz</a>, along with a picture of him at a conference with Dave Winer &#8212; a conference Swartz had to be driven to by his mom, since he was only 15 &#8212; and said: &#8220;We haven’t just lost a good man, but the better world he was helping to make.&#8221;</p>
<p>Alex Macgillivray, general counsel at Twitter and former Google lawyer, said:</p>
<blockquote class='twitter-tweet' lang='en'><p>. @<a href="https://twitter.com/aaronsw">aaronsw</a> made the internet better in so many ways. We are all worse off for his passing. So. Sad. <a href="http://t.co/ynBGkhdx" rel="nofollow">http://t.co/ynBGkhdx</a></p>&mdash; <br />Alex Macgillivray (@amac) <a href='http://twitter.com/#!/amac/status/290154983591129088' data-datetime='2013-01-12T17:55:13+00:00'>January 12, 2013</a></blockquote>
<blockquote class='twitter-tweet' lang='en'><p>Remembering just some of @<a href="https://twitter.com/aaronsw">aaronsw</a>&#039;s life of service to an open Internet. Cannot express my sadness. <a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/16fjjm/aaron_shwartz_reddit_cofounder_rip/c7vmyea"> reddit.com/r/pics/comment…</a></p>&mdash; <br />David Weinberger (@dweinberger) <a href='http://twitter.com/#!/dweinberger/status/290140928310657024' data-datetime='2013-01-12T16:59:22+00:00'>January 12, 2013</a></blockquote>
<p>A comment on the discussion thread on the Y Combinator site Hacker News that <a href="http://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=5047398">appeared to be from Swartz&#8217;s mother</a> said:</p>
<blockquote id="quote-thank-you-all-for-yo7"><p>&#8220;Thank you all for your kind words and thoughts. Aaron has been depressed about his case/upcoming trial, but we had no idea what he was going through was this painful. Aaron was a terrific young man. He contributed a lot to the world in his short life and I regret the loss of all the things he had yet to accomplish. As you can imagine, we all miss him dearly. The grief is unfathomable.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<blockquote class='twitter-tweet' lang='en'><p>Heartbreaking news that my dear friend Aaron Swartz has died at 26. Imaginative, smart about everything, and, best of all, different.</p>&mdash; <br />Edward Tufte (@EdwardTufte) <a href='http://twitter.com/#!/EdwardTufte/status/290167154677006337' data-datetime='2013-01-12T18:43:35+00:00'>January 12, 2013</a></blockquote>
<p>The website <a href="http://public.resource.org">public.resource.org</a> &#8212; founded by freedom-of-information activist Carl Malamud, who worked with Swartz after with his earlier hack of the federal PACER archive &#8212; has gone dark as a tribute, with text that reads in part &#8220;Aaron Swartz made our world more free. Thank you Aaron for what you gave us.&#8221;</p>
<p><em>Post and thumbnail images <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/deed.en">courtesy</a> of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Aaron_Swartz_profile.jpg">Fred Benenson</a> and <a href="http://www.reportagebygettyimages.com/mario-tama/">Getty Images/Mario Tama</a></em></p>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=601342&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://gigaom.com/2013/01/12/the-web-responds-to-the-death-of-hacker-activist-aaron-swartz/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://gigaom2.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/aaron_swartz_profile1.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://gigaom2.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/aaron_swartz_profile1.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Aaron Swartz</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/0bdf7ab171ade0708a11fa3378e6d8cb?s=96&#38;d=retro&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mathew</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gigaom2.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/larryandme.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">larryandme</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Man Crush of the Year</title>
		<link>http://boywiththethorninhisside.wordpress.com/2013/01/08/man-crush-of-the-year-eddie-redmayne/</link>
		<comments>http://boywiththethorninhisside.wordpress.com/2013/01/08/man-crush-of-the-year-eddie-redmayne/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2013 18:14:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Nathan Beesley</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[fashion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[actor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[birdsong]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burberry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eddie redmayne]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[esquire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gq]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[les mis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[les miserable]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[man crush]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[men's fashion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sebastian faulks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sebastien falks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[style]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://boywiththethorninhisside.wordpress.com/?p=432</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Despite my pristinely made bedding, zealously strict grooming routine and severely bloated wardrobe, I am actually a happily heterosexual guy with a healthy fondness for all things female. This even extends to, though very rarely, actually entering relations with the fairer sex. I tend to take a somewhat uncompromising stance with regard to my sexuality [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=432&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://boywiththethorninhisside.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/eddie_redmayne_0.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-433" alt="eddie_redmayne_0" src="http://boywiththethorninhisside.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/eddie_redmayne_0.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>Despite my pristinely made bedding, zealously strict grooming routine and severely bloated wardrobe, I am actually a happily heterosexual guy with a healthy fondness for all things female. This even extends to, though very rarely, actually entering relations with the fairer sex.</p>
<p>I tend to take a somewhat uncompromising stance with regard to my sexuality (unlike the rest of my family and friends, I never thought I was gay) and this can create difficulties when one is trying to express ones respect for an attractive role model of the male persuasion.</p>
<p>Luckily, the growing number of English colloquial idioms has provided us with the perfect solution, namely the expression ‘man crush’. This expression allows even the most Neanderthal of homophobes to express their affection for anyone from Joey Essex to Boris Johnson, (although if you have a man crush on either of the aforementioned characters, I would seek immediate medical advice).</p>
<p>The New Year seems like an appropriate time to look back and assess which guy has left the deepest impression on me and, as far as I’m concerned, there is only one contender.</p>
<p>I first came across Burberry darling Eddie Redmayne in the television adaptation of Sebastian Falk’s <i>Birdsong</i>, a book which holds the record for bring me to tears at least twice. I was immediately struck by his impeccable attire, which radiated personal style even when he was donning military uniform. Anyone who can look dapper running into a hail of German machine gun fire is sure to be an idol of mine.</p>
<p>I was made more conscious of him by my favourite style publications, including <i>GQ</i>, who featured him on their list of 50-dressed men. It was Redmayne who later influenced me in quiffing my hair, though I’m still working on replicating his tousled, boyish take on the classic style.</p>
<p><a href="http://boywiththethorninhisside.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/eddie_redmayne.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-434" alt="eddie_redmayne" src="http://boywiththethorninhisside.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/eddie_redmayne.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>Redmayne’s personal style is everything I aspire to. He takes minimalist, versatile pieces of tailoring and mixes these separates to create something truly inspired and refined. There’s always a healthy dose of Sprezzatura, or ‘artful dishevelment’, in everything he does. In a world where men button things up to the extreme, Redmayne takes the opposite approach. Blazer collars are popped, pocket squares are stuffed in, casual henleys and knits are layered effortlessly under sharp, crisp suiting. You just get the sense that Redmayne has just thrown on what he’s wearing, but there’s clearly a strong thought process behind creating this impression.</p>
<p>Jessica Punter, the style and grooming editor for <i>GQ</i>, puts it better than I ever could:</p>
<blockquote><p>‘Baby-faced charm, artfully dishevelled hair and a killer suit. It’s a really simple formula, but boy, does it work’.</p></blockquote>
<p>Boy, does it indeed.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/432/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/432/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=432&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://boywiththethorninhisside.wordpress.com/2013/01/08/man-crush-of-the-year-eddie-redmayne/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/75c6fa19c29352064b65301cd27ac996?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">boywiththethorninhisside</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://boywiththethorninhisside.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/eddie_redmayne_0.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">eddie_redmayne_0</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://boywiththethorninhisside.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/eddie_redmayne.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">eddie_redmayne</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gun Control &#8211; Or People Control?</title>
		<link>http://embeddedinamerica.wordpress.com/2013/01/10/gun-control-or-people-control/</link>
		<comments>http://embeddedinamerica.wordpress.com/2013/01/10/gun-control-or-people-control/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2013 18:49:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>The Prophet</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Guns]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Heritage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gun control]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mexico]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[second amendment]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://embeddedinamerica.wordpress.com/?p=378</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Let&#8217;s face it, an armed society is going to have shootings. Any quick internet search will turn up shootings in every country in which guns are present. This is simply fact. At the same time, there are armed countries &#8211; like Canada &#8211; where shootings are rare. Canadians are armed, no doubt, it&#8217;s just they [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=378&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Let&#8217;s face it, an armed society is going to have shootings. Any quick internet search will turn up shootings in every country in which guns are present. This is simply fact. At the same time, there are armed countries &#8211; like Canada &#8211; where shootings are rare. Canadians are armed, no doubt, it&#8217;s just they don&#8217;t use their arms on their neighbors or their schools or family members. At least, not like us Americans do. The Swiss are armed too &#8211; literally millions of Swiss men have &#8211; get this &#8211; fully automatic weapons in their homes. In fact, nearly every Swiss man does. Same&#8217;s true of a few other northern European countries.</p>
<p>With notable exceptions, these countries experience few shootings.</p>
<p>So what is it about Americans and America that ends up with armed (legal or otherwise) citizens shooting each other?</p>
<p>There&#8217;s two questions posed in the title: Gun Control or People Control? If we are truly egalitarian and say there are no differences between say, us and the Swiss, then what makes it so that the Swiss can remain armed (with the most horrific of arms, the fully-automatic rifle) and yet not shoot each other? Because, if there is no difference, then gun laws won&#8217;t work. Period. The opposite side of that is that Mexico has very strict gun laws, outlawing most private ownership. So law-abiding Mexicans are without arms. You might argue that point and say &#8220;as far as we know&#8221; or some other disclaimer but then I&#8217;d point out the &#8216;law-abiding&#8217; part of the statement. Mexicans are dying, especially in terms of ratios, at record rates to gunfire.</p>
<p>So we have two opposites: heavily armed Swiss that rarely shoot each other and an unarmed populace of Mexicans regularly dying at the hands of illegally armed criminals. If guns are the problem &#8211; why this disparity? Shouldn&#8217;t the Swiss be shooting each other just every other hour?</p>
<p>Gun laws have not worked to keep guns out of the hands of criminals &#8211; whether in America or Mexico.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s true that in America, a good percentage of gun deaths are by those who legally owned guns. Gun laws restricting ownership would then, it would seem, curtail those shootings. At least, the <em>mass</em> shootings. After all, the crimes of passion would probably occur with a knife, club, baggy. Those headline-grabbing shootings, though, they might be limited. So, what gun laws that would most likely affect everyone would do is reduce the number of legally-owned guns that are used in mass shootings. Fair statement?</p>
<p>I can hear ya! No, you gun haters say, it would restrict the number of guns, which in turn would reduce the number of shootings, like from stolen guns. So the gun laws that would affect all gun owners would do is reduce mass shootings by those who legally owned the guns and those who stole legally owned guns. Now are we in agreement?</p>
<p>Even if that&#8217;s true, and I&#8217;ll concede it&#8217;s logical (I don&#8217;t know that logic will necessarily equal true, but let&#8217;s say it does), it doesn&#8217;t fix the problem of the illegal gun shootings.</p>
<p>First, I think we have to address what we want. Because if we do that, we&#8217;re going to see that we are trying to eliminate a very few events (however awful) by affecting a huge number of people. The many will suffer for the few. Heh, sounds like America.</p>
<p>What we want is the mass shootings to stop &#8211; right? Gun control people just said, no, we want all shootings to stop. OK, how? How do we do that? Mexico outlaws almost all gun ownership and I think very few would think that&#8217;s what is going to happen here, no matter how much they want that. So we aren&#8217;t going to eliminate all shootings.</p>
<p>The possible paths are:</p>
<ol>
<li>Nothing changes &#8211; no new restrictions.</li>
<li>The &#8216;assault weapons&#8217; ban is reinstated.</li>
<li>All semi-automatic guns are restricted.</li>
<li>All semi-auto and handguns are restricted.</li>
<li>All guns are restricted.</li>
</ol>
<p>The scenarios are:</p>
<ol>
<li>America &#8211; 275million guns. Convicted felons can&#8217;t own any. Regular Joes can&#8217;t own fully automatic weapons. Most gun ownership has some restrictions on it in every state.</li>
<li>Sweden &#8211; 4million automatic assault weapons plus hunting weapons in the hands of the public.</li>
<li>Mexico &#8211; no legally owned private weapons.</li>
<li>Canada &#8211; much like America with limited access to &#8216;assault weapons&#8217;.</li>
</ol>
<p>So, under 1/1, nothing changes. We live with the fact that, like with any object that can hurt or kill lots of people, under the right (or wrong) circumstances, they will do exactly that.</p>
<p>Under 2/1, we go back to where we were in the Clinton era. Columbine occurred under his watch. So did a rash of school shootings.</p>
<p>The rest, we don&#8217;t know the effects.</p>
<p>The real problem is being obscured and for good reasons. If you were our leaders, how would you frame the real problem? If you came out and said, &#8216;look, we have weapons in our country and we shoot each other. A lot. Canada has weapons, Sweden has weapons and neither country shoot each other much. Mexico has outlawed weapons and we all know what happens there. So maybe it&#8217;s not a gun problem but a people problem. What&#8217;s wrong with our people?&#8217;</p>
<p>Because that&#8217;s the real question. And the answer is the real problem.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/378/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/378/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=378&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://embeddedinamerica.wordpress.com/2013/01/10/gun-control-or-people-control/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>21</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/98a2a05aa9d7cc119e2787344c0f864b?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">norcalal</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>No More Excuses: Time To Be a Hijabi</title>
		<link>http://meditationsofamuslimah.wordpress.com/2013/01/09/no-more-excuses-time-to-be-a-hijabi/</link>
		<comments>http://meditationsofamuslimah.wordpress.com/2013/01/09/no-more-excuses-time-to-be-a-hijabi/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2013 17:30:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Meditating Muslimah</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Islam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[being a hijabi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[choosing to cover]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hijabi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[islam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Muslimah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wearing hijab]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://meditationsofamuslimah.wordpress.com/?p=89</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I have been Muslim for about two and a half years now. About 6 months after that, I began dressing more modestly, wearing long sleeves, looser fitting clothes, etc. I knew then that I would eventually want to/ need to wear a hijab, but wasn&#8217;t ready for that. I&#8217;ve been seriously considering wearing a hijab [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=89&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://meditationsofamuslimah.wordpress.com/2013/01/09/no-more-excuses-time-to-be-a-hijabi/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>26</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/74fa25d2f44ea4a4cd915500361bf49c?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">meditatingmuslimah</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://meditationsofamuslimah.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/hijab.jpg?w=640" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">http://www.bing.com/images/search?q=hijab&#38;FORM=BILH#view=detail&#38;id=1ACC5394D61F116309DEAA3223FF7967C33F7593&#38;selectedIndex=31</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Super Brown</title>
		<link>http://graysonqueen.wordpress.com/2013/01/09/brown/</link>
		<comments>http://graysonqueen.wordpress.com/2013/01/09/brown/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2013 04:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>graysonqueen</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[sci-fi/fantasy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[batman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brown skin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[captain america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Comic book]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comic books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[costumes for brown people]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flash]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Green Lantern]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Luke Cage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marvel Comic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spider-man]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Super Hero]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Superhero]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://graysonqueen.wordpress.com/?p=829</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In the beginning, America was a mostly Caucasian dominated society.  From this world comic books were born and, with them, the legendary superheroes we know to this day&#8211;  Superman, Captain America, Batman, Ironman, Flash, Spider-man and on and on.  Men (and a few woman on occasion, because it was also a male-dominated society) drawn in the image of [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=829&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the beginning, America was a mostly Caucasian dominated society.  From this world comic books were born and, with them, the legendary superheroes we know to this day&#8211;  Superman, Captain America, Batman, Ironman, Flash, Spider-man and on and on.  Men (and a few woman on occasion, because it was also a male-dominated society) drawn in the image of their creators: Caucasian.</p>
<p>But that&#8217;s just the way things were.  An artist/creator can&#8217;t be faulted for writing what they know.  And on the times they reached outside that box, they created &#8216;ethnic&#8217; characters that were such stereotypes that they were almost racist.</p>
<p><a href="http://graysonqueen.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/apachechief.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-843" alt="Apachechief" src="http://graysonqueen.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/apachechief.jpg?w=300&#038;h=228" width="300" height="228" /></a><a href="http://graysonqueen.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/luke_cage.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-845" alt="Luke_Cage" src="http://graysonqueen.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/luke_cage.jpg?w=202&#038;h=300" width="202" height="300" /></a>Things have changed as the world becomes interconnected.  There are several African and African American superheroes and villains; a few Asian ones (Asia being any of those countries out near China, but it doesn&#8217;t mater as long as they know some kind of martial art or carry a sword), there are a few Hispanic ones (though I can&#8217;t think of them straight away and I&#8217;m sure some were rebooted out of existence), and I&#8217;m sure there&#8217;s an villain from India (just the one).  Meanwhile Canada and Europe have their own superhero teams galore, despite being some of the smaller percentages of the global population.</p>
<p>Statistically speaking, assuming super powers are gained by random chance; China and India should have a much greater representation in the super-powered community (Followed by the USA, Indonesia and Brazil.  Although now that I&#8217;m seeing this, it might explain why all superheroes are attractive. Imagine a bunch of Brazilian models flying around and saving the day.)</p>
<p>Now you might be thinking I&#8217;m mad or angry or something, but I&#8217;m not.  I&#8217;m really only pointing out a curiosity   As an artist I think  it would be more appalling to force people to create ethnic characters just for the sake of diversity.  If it doesn&#8217;t fit in the story, don&#8217;t do it. But on the other hand&#8230; it <em>can</em> fit in the story.  There are opportunities to have ethnic secondary characters and to run into someone who isn&#8217;t an English-speaking Westerner.</p>
<p>The problem is we are to afraid to let go of the old characters, the ones who no longer fit the current social constructs and have become outdated.  There is no room for new characters and new comics if the old ones are taking up most of the shelf space.  Will the major players be brave enough to move forward.  Will Peter Parker stay dead?  Will the reboots go on forever?  Yes.  Because they are still making money.  Sometimes it&#8217;s a little sad for me to see.  Often as I&#8217;m reading an issue I get angry that this big long soap opera/sitcom will never change.  Sure they&#8217;re trying, the new Green Lantern and a gay wedding, but does that matter when they have to do a retcon to fix everything back to square one?</p>
<p>What is more frustrating is that I find myself falling into the same habits.  My main characters are Caucasian,  they&#8217;re American and they&#8217;re men.  For my recent book I had to make a very specific attempt to integrate ethnicity into my novel.  Is that because I&#8217;m inundated with ethnically-slanted entertainment media?  I&#8217;m sure I could turn that question into a mile long debate.  The only thing that matters to me, a brown person and artist, is that I recognize the box I put over my head and work to fix it.  Because what I want in the next few years is a Halloween where I can dress as something without feeling awkward about being the &#8220;brown version&#8221;.</p>
<p>So I humbly offer this awesome spider based super hero for the taking.</p>
<p><a href="http://graysonqueen.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/brown.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-846" alt="brown recluse" src="http://graysonqueen.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/brown.jpg?w=300&#038;h=289" width="300" height="289" /></a></p>
<h1 style="text-align:center;">The Brown Recluse!</h1>
<p>P.S.  I know there are plenty of ways to explain off why Western, first world nations have a higher percentage of superheroes, but that&#8217;s not the point.</p>
<br /> Tagged: <a href='http://graysonqueen.wordpress.com/tag/batman/'>batman</a>, <a href='http://graysonqueen.wordpress.com/tag/brown-skin/'>brown skin</a>, <a href='http://graysonqueen.wordpress.com/tag/captain-america/'>captain america</a>, <a href='http://graysonqueen.wordpress.com/tag/comic/'>comic</a>, <a href='http://graysonqueen.wordpress.com/tag/comic-book/'>Comic book</a>, <a href='http://graysonqueen.wordpress.com/tag/comic-books/'>comic books</a>, <a href='http://graysonqueen.wordpress.com/tag/costumes-for-brown-people/'>costumes for brown people</a>, <a href='http://graysonqueen.wordpress.com/tag/flash/'>Flash</a>, <a href='http://graysonqueen.wordpress.com/tag/green-lantern/'>Green Lantern</a>, <a href='http://graysonqueen.wordpress.com/tag/luke-cage/'>Luke Cage</a>, <a href='http://graysonqueen.wordpress.com/tag/marvel-comic/'>Marvel Comic</a>, <a href='http://graysonqueen.wordpress.com/tag/spider-man/'>spider-man</a>, <a href='http://graysonqueen.wordpress.com/tag/super-hero/'>Super Hero</a>, <a href='http://graysonqueen.wordpress.com/tag/superhero/'>Superhero</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/829/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/829/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/829/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/829/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/829/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/829/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/829/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/829/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/829/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/829/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/829/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/829/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/829/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/829/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=829&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://graysonqueen.wordpress.com/2013/01/09/brown/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>79</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/ecb9c3d194e055d02edf6dfe48af5db3?s=96&#38;d=retro&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">graysonqueen</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://graysonqueen.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/apachechief.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Apachechief</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://graysonqueen.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/luke_cage.jpg?w=202" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Luke_Cage</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://graysonqueen.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/brown.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">brown recluse</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>American Vignettes (I): Totalitarian Undercurrents</title>
		<link>http://thedisorderofthings.com/2013/01/09/american-vignettes-i-totalitarian-undercurrents/</link>
		<comments>http://thedisorderofthings.com/2013/01/09/american-vignettes-i-totalitarian-undercurrents/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2013 21:29:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Joe</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Biopolitics & The Biopolitical]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ethics!]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hegemony & Ideology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[US Politics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thedisorderofthings.com/?p=6851</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The airport is a totalitarian space; sometimes the truth is hyperbolic. You re-enter the United States, land of your birth, as part of the stream of arriving passengers. It is an everyday experience. You leave the airplane slowly, on stiff limbs, trickling with the mass of travellers into Newark airport. The imperatives are issued as [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=6851&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:justify;">The airport is a totalitarian space; sometimes the truth is hyperbolic.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">You re-enter the United States, land of your birth, as part of the stream of arriving passengers. It is an everyday experience. You leave the airplane slowly, on stiff limbs, trickling with the mass of travellers into Newark airport.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">The imperatives are issued as soon as you enter the terminal building. No smoking. No cell phones. Stand in line. Fill in your declaration form. Foreigner here. Citizen there. Wait behind the red line till you are called. The armed immigration officer checks your papers, holding the power to pronounce your worthiness to enter this sanctified space.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><a href="http://thedisorderofthings.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/customsborderprotectionscreentravelersutu1g4paaaax.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-6853" alt="Border Control" src="http://thedisorderofthings.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/customsborderprotectionscreentravelersutu1g4paaaax.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">With the imperatives come the questions. Where are you coming from? Where are you going? As if the answers are clear. As if these are simple questions. The man with the gun, holding your passport, asks, “Where are you flying next?” But he already knows and he answers for you, “Chicago, on Friday.” This is a test.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">“What were you doing in London?” You answer but the officer is not interested, he looks at you with an unarticulated accusation, why would you leave your homeland? Your suspect status is confirmed when he asks, “How long are you staying?” Until you please the armed man with your answers everyone is a foreigner no matter where they were born.<span id="more-6851"></span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">With the questions comes the paperwork. Stamps in the passport. Scribbles on the customs forms. Tags on your luggage. Everyone leaves a trail as they move through the world and every trail must be made legible.  Even your fingertips are traced on the scanner. Before you arrived and presented yourself for inspection the trail began, unseen by you.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><a href="http://thedisorderofthings.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/large_newark-liberty-airport-passport-kiosk.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-6854" alt="Scanner" src="http://thedisorderofthings.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/large_newark-liberty-airport-passport-kiosk.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Your credit history, your financial information is passed between corporation and government when you buy your ticket. All of your earlier passings over these secured borders have been logged. Your purchases, your card numbers, your preferences, are pumped into the river of information rushing through the air, making it flow a little faster.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">And this work of legibility renders us computable by the armed men, by their computers, by the networks of machines that monitor us. To be made safe is to be rendered predictable, absolutely knowable. To be made safe today is to be made ultimately vulnerable.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Once outside the terminal the undercurrent of control continues to carry you along. Waiting for the airport train you realise the imperatives are still echoing as robot voices issue yet more commands. Watch your bags. Be suspicious. Get on the train quickly and make room for others. Stand back from the doors. Do not smoke. It is a strange choice to give the work of public morality over to robots without acknowledging the abdication. As the work of production and service is given over to machines, so to is the work of maintaining order.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">The imperatives, the questions, the paper work – the apparatus of order always carries a veiled threat. Every reminder is a warning, a prelude to a punishment to come. The airport is a hub for the transfer of populations, a site of vulnerability and power, such that the elements of control stand out in high contrast – hence the need for the elements of comfort to be exaggerated: fancy restaurants, high-end shops, the whole buzzing scene meant to reassure.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><a href="http://thedisorderofthings.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0329.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-6858" alt="IMG_0329" src="http://thedisorderofthings.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0329.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>But the discordance of that space cannot be ignored and its resonance stays with you, makes you aware of the undercurrent that pushes at you long after you’ve left the terminal, demanding your obedience quietly, constantly.</p>
<p>You leave the airport behind, getting on the train that will take you to the city. The mechanized voices still clamour; the calculated conscience impels you to move quickly, informs you of the next stop, reminds you of your final destination, and to be alert to the dangerous edges in this fast moving machine driven world.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">After you leave the airport, riding the trains and buses of America’s great cities – New York, Chicago – you encounter a world of gates, fences, bulletproof windows, and cages. Little prisons that separate the women and men who monitor the safety of society from the rest of us, so that they can ensure that fares are paid, rules are followed, forms are filled in, and that the great social machine ticks along as it should. And around you everyone seems to be moving through the parts of this machine with ease – compliant with a tense smile.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">In the spaces away from the centres of control, away from the social body’s steel organs and electrified arteries, the sound of imperatives fades – you feel some control returned. But it also seems these spaces are closing up, tightening, and being invaded – you feel paranoid even having such thoughts. Maybe you are.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><a href="http://thedisorderofthings.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0337.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-6859" alt="IMG_0337" src="http://thedisorderofthings.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0337.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Yet, the world around you is being made more uniform. The neighbourhood bars, the little storefronts and the local factories you remember from childhood trips through Chicago are slowly being replaced with identical corporate units. Manhattan makes you uncomfortable with its cleanliness, its order, as if the madness of those streets promised in the pages of Kerouac and scenes of Scorsese is now tended like a garden in a California theme park.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">And wading in that expanding uniformity you feel the undercurrent pushing you once again. Streets are monitored by cameras, corporate security agents, police policing the image of the city, and all of us – armed with suspicion. As you stop on the streets, watch, and you can see the invisible barriers that hem us in. You suddenly feel less paranoid. And you feel the source of your true vulnerability in this world of safety and order.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">And then you must return to one of the centres of the social order: to their airports, needing to ride the fast current of the social machine once more. You return to the securitised space of the airport, a vital organ of the social body, which depends on the movement of women and men like other lesser beasts depend upon the movement of blood.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-6861" alt="TSA screener" src="http://thedisorderofthings.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/gty_tsa_screeners_lax_jrs_120425_wmain.jpg?w=590"   /></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">To re-enter this space you must be made clean. You produce your ticket, your proof of payment &#8211; your offering. You hand over your identity papers. You produce yourself as obedient and legible to the human eyes of the social body. They relieve you of your baggage so that your things can be screened for contraband. Your possessions disappear into the guts of their security machine, out of view until you are ejected back out into the unruly world on the other side of your journey.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">And then you move to the antechamber of the security machine, to be cleansed. You again present yourself, your papers, obedient, ready to receive orders. You disrobe, you stand exposed before the others waiting, you stand exposed to the eyes and hands of those who operate the security machine that guards the social body. You then pass through the centre of that machine – to be approved or spit out – waiting as its x-ray eye scans you, looking past your own self-presentation, seeing you as a body that cannot hide, which holds up its hands in supplication.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Once you have been judged safe, you collect yourself, your papers, your clothing. The airport is made secure by demanding you give up your personal security. It is the perfection of the collectivist imperative for safety. But even within this space the imperatives ring out. So many uniformed hands of the security machine crisscross this space. There’s beeping and sirens and announcements, the humming of machines so loud you stop thinking.</p>
<p><em id="__mceDel"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-6862" alt="Wave Scanners" src="http://thedisorderofthings.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/wavescanners.jpg?w=590"   /></em></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">There are lines and there is waiting. And there is patience, endless patience – patience that, especially when threatened by frustration and embarrassment, is held in place by the horrible threat of  the security machine crashing upon you. You are safe because you are powerless; you are patient because you are afraid. In this space there is obedience, endless obedience.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">You wonder how such an order was built. You wonder why we consent. But this moment is only the abscess that forms over the infection. In a world where we pursue the feeling of security to the point of total vulnerability we have no right to be surprised when we consent to, participate in, and are then subjected to the brutality of control.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">The airport is a totalitarian space. It is a distorted but true reflection. America is a civilization always overflowing with violence ready to be directed at whatever the social body deems dangerous. We lovers of obedience and control make anything possible here.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/6851/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/6851/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=6851&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thedisorderofthings.com/2013/01/09/american-vignettes-i-totalitarian-undercurrents/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>47</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/86da5f3d6c8b902198b1cdc25ac08c3d?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">joedyson</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thedisorderofthings.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/customsborderprotectionscreentravelersutu1g4paaaax.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Border Control</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thedisorderofthings.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/large_newark-liberty-airport-passport-kiosk.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Scanner</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thedisorderofthings.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0329.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0329</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thedisorderofthings.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0337.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0337</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thedisorderofthings.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/gty_tsa_screeners_lax_jrs_120425_wmain.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">TSA screener</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thedisorderofthings.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/wavescanners.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Wave Scanners</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rape Is Not Just India\&#8217;s Problem</title>
		<link>http://britishasianmum.com/2013/01/09/rape-is-not-just-indias-problem/</link>
		<comments>http://britishasianmum.com/2013/01/09/rape-is-not-just-indias-problem/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2013 20:33:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>britishasianmum</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Indian Sub-Continent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News and Current Affairs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Popular culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asians]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[criminal justice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Delhi rape]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Indian rape]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[men]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rape]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rape victims]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://britishasianmum.com/?p=191</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Picture the scene. A woman in a bar. Dressed up for a night out, drinking and having fun. A group of men at the other side spot her. She leaves her drink on the table with her friend and goes to the toilet. She comes back and finishes the drink. Gradually she becomes more and [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=191&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Picture the scene. A woman in a bar. Dressed up for a night out, drinking and having fun. A group of men at the other side spot her. She leaves her drink on the table with her friend and goes to the toilet. She comes back and finishes the drink. Gradually she becomes more and more giddy, as if going under an anaesthetic.</p>
<p>She wakes up in hospital with sharp stabbing pains in her groin and pelvic area. Her legs and arms are covered in bruises. Her left eye is so badly swollen she can barely see out of it. She has no recollection of the night before, what happened to her or how she ended up in hospital.</p>
<p>It transpires that her drink had been spiked. She was taken outside and gang raped by the group of men that had spotted her in the bar. Once they had finished raping her, she was left outside a club, unconscious. The club bouncers found her and called an ambulance. Through the help of the club&#8217;s CCTV, authorities were able to piece together what happened to her.</p>
<p>This account is the true story of an ex-work colleague of mine, and the horrifying ordeal that happened to her in the summer of 2008. The fact is, rape happens to women everyday, all over the world.  The brutal gang- rape and murder of a 23 year old medical student in Delhi last month has got the whole world talking about rape. It has shone the light on a country where a rape is reported every twenty minutes. It has also highlighted the fact that India&#8217;s criminal justice system has abysmally failed its women in bringing rapists to justice (<a title="one comment I read by an Indian woman" href="http://blogs.telegraph.co.uk/news/brendanoneill2/100196384/the-delhi-rape-is-being-used-to-demonise-indian-men/">one comment I read by an Indian woman</a> who had herself been raped claimed that you were lucky if the police didn&#8217;t rape you themselves).</p>
<p>But more specifically, the global media are pointing the finger at India and Indian men; and the treatment of women in the Asian sub-continent. This horrible crime is being hailed as indicative of &#8216;how depraved&#8217; Indian men are. Indeed, most news articles, blogs and opinion pieces that I&#8217;ve read are screaming that Indian men are somehow more savage, more monstrous, even <a title="&quot;hyena-like&quot;" href="http://www.thetimes.co.uk/tto/opinion/columnists/article3643810.ece">&#8220;hyena-like&#8221; </a> than their Western counterparts and that&#8217;s why they did this.</p>
<p>Come on, lets not fool ourselves into thinking that rape is someone else&#8217;s problem. We in the West cannot afford to talk about this incident as if it were isolated to the Third World and its men. It&#8217;s not just Asian men that rape their women, its men from many walks of life and from many different societies and cultures.</p>
<p>Now I&#8217;m not defending the double standards that Asian women suffer. It makes my blood boil to see so many of my sisters, at best,  considered the property of a man (our father&#8217;s first, then husband&#8217;s) and at worst, second-class citizens. Misogyny<em> is</em> rife amongst our men.  But that is a separate (by no means smaller) issue. The woman in Delhi was treated as a piece of meat, a piece of rubbish to be tortured then thrown away, but this is no different to what happened to my colleague- (who, incidentally is English).</p>
<div id="attachment_194" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 185px"><a href="http://britishasianmum.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/candle-lit-vigil-delhi.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-194" alt="Protesters hold candles during a rally in New Delhi late Saturday following the death of a woman gang-raped on a bus." src="http://britishasianmum.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/candle-lit-vigil-delhi.jpg?w=590"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Protesters hold candles during a rally in New Delhi late Saturday following the death of a woman gang-raped on a bus.</p></div>
<p>She too was raped and left unconscious on the floor while her rapists went off into the night. Thankfully she didn&#8217;t die. But what happened to her is just as indicative of an attitude towards women that seems to have been shared by men on opposite sides of the planet.</p>
<p>So come on, lets wake up and talk about rape for the universal issue that it is. Yes as Asians we need to deal with some attitudes that are systemic to our culture. But so too does the rest of &#8216;man&#8217;-kind.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/191/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/191/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=191&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://britishasianmum.com/2013/01/09/rape-is-not-just-indias-problem/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>94</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://britishasianmum.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-delhi-rape-protest.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://britishasianmum.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-delhi-rape-protest.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">INDIA-KASHMIR-CRIME-RAPE-PROTEST</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/73a066f1f0180fa69f90dd7dbb214be6?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">britishasianmum</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://britishasianmum.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/candle-lit-vigil-delhi.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Protesters hold candles during a rally in New Delhi late Saturday following the death of a woman gang-raped on a bus.</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Map It Out!</title>
		<link>http://3rdculturechildren.com/2013/01/11/weekly-writing-challenge-map-it-out/</link>
		<comments>http://3rdculturechildren.com/2013/01/11/weekly-writing-challenge-map-it-out/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2013 16:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>3rdCultureChildren</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[expat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FAMILY]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[foreign service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TRAVEL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPchallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[map it out]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[maps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[postaday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weekly writing challenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing challenge]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://3rdculturechildren.com/?p=15079</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[[Backstory, inspiration from WP] "As bloggers, we scan through photos and descriptive tales from our fellow writers who share their travels with us... Maps symbolize the places we’ve been, the places we want to go, and the places we’ll end up, even if we don’t know it yet... "

That said, I'm taking up on the challenge, and 'mapping out' the places in my life. Just the important, 'life event' moves. A couple years back when I began blogging, I decided to name this blog, representing/expressing what my [now 3] kids are: the product of their mom's and dad's hybrid/joined cultures. Moving is part of our lives, and was part of mine way before met the so-called husband. Maps are a frequent guest at my posts, and this time, responding to the challenge, I'm 'mapping out my life', the moves I've endured as a nomad child back in Brazil, the ones leading me to a new path as an expat, mother and 'trailing spouse'... ♥<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=15079&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_15098" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 526px"><a href="http://3rdculturechildren.com/2013/01/08/weekly-writing-challenge-map-it-out/screen-shot-2013-01-08-at-5-01-18-pm/" rel="attachment wp-att-15098"><img class=" wp-image-15098 " title="moves as an expat..." alt="" src="http://3rdculturechildren.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/screen-shot-2013-01-08-at-5-01-18-pm.png?w=516&#038;h=286" width="516" height="286" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Moving as an expat&#8230;</p></div>
<p><em><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size:14px;line-height:21px;">[Backstory, <a href="http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2013/01/07/writing-challenge-map-it-out/">inspiration from WP</a>] &#8220;As bloggers, we scan through photos and descriptive tales from our fellow writers who share their travels with us&#8230; Maps symbolize the places we’ve been, the places we want to go, and the places we’ll end up, even if we don’t know it yet&#8230;&#8221;</span></em></p>
<h4><em>That said, I&#8217;m taking up on the challenge, and &#8216;mapping out&#8217; the places in my life. Just the important, &#8216;life event&#8217; moves. A couple years back when I began blogging, I decided to name this blog, representing/expressing what my [now 3] kids are: the product of their mom&#8217;s and dad&#8217;s hybrid/joined cultures. <strong>Moving is part of our lives</strong>, and was part of mine way before meeting the so-called &#8216;best-half&#8217;. Maps are a frequent guest at my posts, and this time, responding to the challenge, I&#8217;m &#8216;mapping out my life&#8217;, the moves I&#8217;ve endured as a nomad child back in <a class="zem_slink" title="Brazil" href="http://maps.google.com/maps?ll=-15.75,-47.95&amp;spn=10.0,10.0&amp;q=-15.75,-47.95 (Brazil)&amp;t=h" target="_blank" rel="geolocation">Brazil</a>, the ones leading me to a new path as an expat, mother and &#8216;<a class="zem_slink" title="Trailing spouse" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Trailing_spouse" target="_blank" rel="wikipedia">trailing spouse</a>&#8216;&#8230; ♥</em></h4>
<h4><strong>The beginning: &#8216;this child is born&#8217;, in a small Japanese colony, in Southeastern Brazil:</strong></h4>
<div class="googlemaps"><iframe width="300" height="300" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" src="https://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;source=s_q&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=&amp;q=Itaguaí - Rio de Janeiro, Brazil&amp;aq=0&amp;oq=itagua&amp;sll=37.0625,-95.677068&amp;sspn=34.808514,78.925781&amp;t=h&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;hnear=Itaguaí - Rio de Janeiro, Brazil&amp;ll=-22.593726,-43.59375&amp;spn=141.149296,210.9375&amp;z=1&amp;iwloc=A&amp;output=embed"></iframe><br /><small><a href="https://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;source=s_q&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=&amp;q=Itaguaí - Rio de Janeiro, Brazil&amp;aq=0&amp;oq=itagua&amp;sll=37.0625,-95.677068&amp;sspn=34.808514,78.925781&amp;t=h&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;hnear=Itaguaí - Rio de Janeiro, Brazil&amp;ll=-22.593726,-43.59375&amp;spn=141.149296,210.9375&amp;z=1&amp;iwloc=A&amp;source=embed" style="text-align:left">View Larger Map</a></small></div>
<div id="attachment_15135" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 655px"><a href="http://3rdculturechildren.com/2013/01/11/weekly-writing-challenge-map-it-out/screen-shot-2013-01-11-at-8-51-39-am/" rel="attachment wp-att-15135"><img class="size-full wp-image-15135" alt="Itaguaí, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil" src="http://3rdculturechildren.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/screen-shot-2013-01-11-at-8-51-39-am.png?w=590"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Itaguaí, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil</p></div>
<h4></h4>
<h4><strong><span class="Apple-style-span" style="color:#444444;font-family:Arial, 'Trebuchet MS', sans-serif;">The original family moves to the nation&#8217;s capital, for a fantastic couple of decades of friendships, schooling, learning, growing, language, cultural and life experiences:</span></strong></h4>
<div class="googlemaps"><iframe width="425" height="350" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" src="https://maps.google.com/maps?f=d&amp;source=s_d&amp;saddr=Itaguaí - Rio de Janeiro, Brazil&amp;daddr=Brasilia - Distrito Federal, Brazil&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=FZUVo_4dOANk_Sn9V2_RhfibADHUJJXWXlZ4Yw;Fcw2D_8drqgk_SmjkVvkGD1akzF_XdgLYtPoJA&amp;aq=0&amp;oq=brasilia&amp;sll=-22.866539,-43.777224&amp;sspn=0.632683,1.233215&amp;t=h&amp;mra=ls&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;ll=-19.642588,-45.351562&amp;spn=55.873612,74.707031&amp;z=3&amp;output=embed"></iframe><br /><small><a href="https://maps.google.com/maps?f=d&amp;source=s_d&amp;saddr=Itaguaí - Rio de Janeiro, Brazil&amp;daddr=Brasilia - Distrito Federal, Brazil&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=FZUVo_4dOANk_Sn9V2_RhfibADHUJJXWXlZ4Yw;Fcw2D_8drqgk_SmjkVvkGD1akzF_XdgLYtPoJA&amp;aq=0&amp;oq=brasilia&amp;sll=-22.866539,-43.777224&amp;sspn=0.632683,1.233215&amp;t=h&amp;mra=ls&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;ll=-19.642588,-45.351562&amp;spn=55.873612,74.707031&amp;z=3&amp;source=embed" style="text-align:left">View Larger Map</a></small></div>
<h4></h4>
<h4><strong>Professional opportunities keep leading that <em>grown child</em> to keep moving up&#8230; and North!</strong></h4>
<div class="googlemaps"><iframe width="425" height="350" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" src="https://maps.google.com/maps?f=d&amp;source=s_d&amp;saddr=Itaguaí - Rio de Janeiro, Brazil&amp;daddr=Brasilia - Distrito Federal, Brazil to:Fortaleza - Ceara, Brazil&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=FZUVo_4dOANk_Sn9V2_RhfibADHUJJXWXlZ4Yw;Fcw2D_8drqgk_SmjkVvkGD1akzF_XdgLYtPoJA;FQZDx_8d3d-z_Sk_eExGP0zHBzHKN2sMCsZhRg&amp;aq=0&amp;oq=Fortale&amp;sll=17.36146,-80.097123&amp;sspn=77.751109,157.851563&amp;t=h&amp;mra=ls&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;ll=-13.410994,-43.242187&amp;spn=57.419688,74.707031&amp;z=3&amp;output=embed"></iframe><br /><small><a href="https://maps.google.com/maps?f=d&amp;source=s_d&amp;saddr=Itaguaí - Rio de Janeiro, Brazil&amp;daddr=Brasilia - Distrito Federal, Brazil to:Fortaleza - Ceara, Brazil&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=FZUVo_4dOANk_Sn9V2_RhfibADHUJJXWXlZ4Yw;Fcw2D_8drqgk_SmjkVvkGD1akzF_XdgLYtPoJA;FQZDx_8d3d-z_Sk_eExGP0zHBzHKN2sMCsZhRg&amp;aq=0&amp;oq=Fortale&amp;sll=17.36146,-80.097123&amp;sspn=77.751109,157.851563&amp;t=h&amp;mra=ls&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;ll=-13.410994,-43.242187&amp;spn=57.419688,74.707031&amp;z=3&amp;source=embed" style="text-align:left">View Larger Map</a></small></div>
<h4></h4>
<h4><em>Life presents itself in very strange ways.</em>.. and sometimes, love, personal life &amp; work seem to agree with each other&#8230; a few fortunate moments, that one must take advantage of&#8230; and move on! Again, keep moving up&#8230; and North! <strong>The new home, now officially an expat, the &#8220;D&#8221; city indicated by the map &#8211; working as a foreign research fellow, in <a class="zem_slink" title="Davis, California" href="http://maps.google.com/maps?ll=38.5538888889,-121.738055556&amp;spn=0.1,0.1&amp;q=38.5538888889,-121.738055556 (Davis%2C%20California)&amp;t=h" target="_blank" rel="geolocation">Davis, CA</a>.</strong></h4>
<div class="googlemaps"><iframe width="425" height="350" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" src="https://maps.google.com/maps?f=d&amp;source=s_d&amp;saddr=Itaguaí - Rio de Janeiro, Brazil&amp;daddr=Brasilia - Distrito Federal, Brazil to:Fortaleza - Ceara, Brazil to:Davis, CA, United States&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=FZUVo_4dOANk_Sn9V2_RhfibADHUJJXWXlZ4Yw;Fcw2D_8drqgk_SmjkVvkGD1akzF_XdgLYtPoJA;FQZDx_8d3d-z_Sk_eExGP0zHBzHKN2sMCsZhRg;FQomTAIdG2O--Ck_VJWUmSmFgDH_j-JuGz8Bww&amp;aq=0&amp;oq=Davis&amp;sll=7.751987,-80.097123&amp;sspn=79.845041,157.851563&amp;t=h&amp;doflg=ptm&amp;mra=luc&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;ll=7.710992,-80.15625&amp;spn=153.125254,298.828125&amp;z=1&amp;output=embed"></iframe><br /><small><a href="https://maps.google.com/maps?f=d&amp;source=s_d&amp;saddr=Itaguaí - Rio de Janeiro, Brazil&amp;daddr=Brasilia - Distrito Federal, Brazil to:Fortaleza - Ceara, Brazil to:Davis, CA, United States&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=FZUVo_4dOANk_Sn9V2_RhfibADHUJJXWXlZ4Yw;Fcw2D_8drqgk_SmjkVvkGD1akzF_XdgLYtPoJA;FQZDx_8d3d-z_Sk_eExGP0zHBzHKN2sMCsZhRg;FQomTAIdG2O--Ck_VJWUmSmFgDH_j-JuGz8Bww&amp;aq=0&amp;oq=Davis&amp;sll=7.751987,-80.097123&amp;sspn=79.845041,157.851563&amp;t=h&amp;doflg=ptm&amp;mra=luc&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;ll=7.710992,-80.15625&amp;spn=153.125254,298.828125&amp;z=1&amp;source=embed" style="text-align:left">View Larger Map</a></small></div>
<h4></h4>
<h4>One day, we all come to the realization that it&#8217;s necessary to say &#8216;YES&#8217; to a lifetime commitment&#8230; and so I did! <strong>And the acceptance brought me to a new address, some 2,800 miles away, to new work opportunities, to <em>a new life as a spouse</em>:</strong></h4>
<div class="googlemaps"><iframe width="425" height="350" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" src="https://maps.google.com/maps?f=d&amp;source=s_d&amp;saddr=Davis, CA, United States&amp;daddr=Washington, DC, United States&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=FQomTAIdG2O--Ck_VJWUmSmFgDH_j-JuGz8Bww;FQh-UQIdsoRo-ylb5PZa3sa3iTEqXYjUIkVSwg&amp;aq=0&amp;oq=Washington, &amp;sll=7.885147,-80.15625&amp;sspn=79.821565,157.851563&amp;t=h&amp;mra=ls&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;ll=40.178873,-99.140625&amp;spn=89.274076,149.414063&amp;z=2&amp;output=embed"></iframe><br /><small><a href="https://maps.google.com/maps?f=d&amp;source=s_d&amp;saddr=Davis, CA, United States&amp;daddr=Washington, DC, United States&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=FQomTAIdG2O--Ck_VJWUmSmFgDH_j-JuGz8Bww;FQh-UQIdsoRo-ylb5PZa3sa3iTEqXYjUIkVSwg&amp;aq=0&amp;oq=Washington, &amp;sll=7.885147,-80.15625&amp;sspn=79.821565,157.851563&amp;t=h&amp;mra=ls&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;ll=40.178873,-99.140625&amp;spn=89.274076,149.414063&amp;z=2&amp;source=embed" style="text-align:left">View Larger Map</a></small></div>
<h4></h4>
<h4><em>What happens when a &#8216;nomad child&#8217; marries another &#8216;nomad spirit&#8217;?</em></h4>
<h4>Well, <em>they move</em>, together with their first &#8216;<em>world citizen</em>&#8216;! <strong>This time, as a &#8216;trailing spouse&#8217; and a mom, I&#8217;m going back South&#8230; to <a class="zem_slink" title="Southern Africa" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Southern_Africa" target="_blank" rel="wikipedia">Southern Africa</a>&#8230;</strong></h4>
<div class="googlemaps"><iframe width="425" height="350" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" src="https://maps.google.com/maps?f=d&amp;source=s_d&amp;saddr=Washington, DC, United States&amp;daddr=Maputo, Maputo City, Mozambique&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=FQh-UQIdsoRo-ylb5PZa3sa3iTEqXYjUIkVSwg;FbXHc_4dpS7xASlV2ma2I5fmHjFCtGuaV39JQg&amp;aq=0&amp;oq=Maputo&amp;sll=6.468506,-44.545789&amp;sspn=79.994794,157.851563&amp;t=m&amp;mra=ls&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;ll=6.315299,-44.296875&amp;spn=153.202767,298.828125&amp;z=1&amp;output=embed"></iframe><br /><small><a href="https://maps.google.com/maps?f=d&amp;source=s_d&amp;saddr=Washington, DC, United States&amp;daddr=Maputo, Maputo City, Mozambique&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=FQh-UQIdsoRo-ylb5PZa3sa3iTEqXYjUIkVSwg;FbXHc_4dpS7xASlV2ma2I5fmHjFCtGuaV39JQg&amp;aq=0&amp;oq=Maputo&amp;sll=6.468506,-44.545789&amp;sspn=79.994794,157.851563&amp;t=m&amp;mra=ls&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;ll=6.315299,-44.296875&amp;spn=153.202767,298.828125&amp;z=1&amp;source=embed" style="text-align:left">View Larger Map</a></small></div>
<h4></h4>
<h4><b>It came time to welcome our second child&#8230; so then we moved to a neighboring country, for a little while&#8230;</b></h4>
<h4><strong> </strong> <strong></strong> <div class="googlemaps"><iframe width="425" height="350" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" src="https://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;source=s_q&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=&amp;q=Pretoria, Gauteng, South Africa&amp;aq=0&amp;oq=pretoria&amp;sll=-22.866539,-43.777224&amp;sspn=0.632683,1.233215&amp;t=h&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;hnear=Pretoria, Gauteng, South Africa&amp;ll=-25.799891,28.300781&amp;spn=27.489471,37.353516&amp;z=4&amp;iwloc=A&amp;output=embed"></iframe><br /><small><a href="https://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;source=s_q&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=&amp;q=Pretoria, Gauteng, South Africa&amp;aq=0&amp;oq=pretoria&amp;sll=-22.866539,-43.777224&amp;sspn=0.632683,1.233215&amp;t=h&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;hnear=Pretoria, Gauteng, South Africa&amp;ll=-25.799891,28.300781&amp;spn=27.489471,37.353516&amp;z=4&amp;iwloc=A&amp;source=embed" style="text-align:left">View Larger Map</a></small></div></h4>
<h4></h4>
<h4>We were done with our work in Africa, and had to return to our original home. Back in <a class="zem_slink" title="Washington, D.C." href="http://maps.google.com/maps?ll=38.8951111111,-77.0366666667&amp;spn=0.1,0.1&amp;q=38.8951111111,-77.0366666667 (Washington%2C%20D.C.)&amp;t=h" target="_blank" rel="geolocation">Washington DC</a>, before heading out to our next adventure&#8230; <strong>From &#8220;A&#8221; to &#8220;B&#8221;, landing in &#8220;C&#8221;, and welcoming our third child into the world [of traveling!]:</strong></h4>
<div class="googlemaps"><iframe width="425" height="350" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" src="https://maps.google.com/maps?f=d&amp;source=s_d&amp;saddr=Maputo, Maputo City, Mozambique&amp;daddr=Washington, DC, United States to:Recife - Pernambuco, Brazil&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=&amp;aq=0&amp;oq=Recife&amp;sll=15.45368,-55.898437&amp;sspn=78.284573,157.851563&amp;t=h&amp;mra=ls&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;ll=15.284185,-55.546875&amp;spn=152.419423,298.828125&amp;z=1&amp;output=embed"></iframe><br /><small><a href="https://maps.google.com/maps?f=d&amp;source=s_d&amp;saddr=Maputo, Maputo City, Mozambique&amp;daddr=Washington, DC, United States to:Recife - Pernambuco, Brazil&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=&amp;aq=0&amp;oq=Recife&amp;sll=15.45368,-55.898437&amp;sspn=78.284573,157.851563&amp;t=h&amp;mra=ls&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;ll=15.284185,-55.546875&amp;spn=152.419423,298.828125&amp;z=1&amp;source=embed" style="text-align:left">View Larger Map</a></small></div>
<h4></h4>
<h4>But since we&#8217;ve got &#8216;<em>itchy souls</em>&#8216;, common to world travelers, we may not stop&#8230; We&#8217;re always moving, and <strong>as a result of work, lifestyle and adventurous minds, we find ourselves in a different place, the beautiful country of Bolivia&#8230; <em>for now!</em></strong> <img src='http://s1.wp.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_surprised.gif' alt=':o' class='wp-smiley' />  Thanks for following us, and&#8230; <em><strong>what about you? What is YOUR JOURNEY?</strong> </em>Feel free to <strong>leave a link at the comments section</strong> for others to &#8216;live thru your experiences&#8217;!! <img src='http://s1.wp.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_surprised.gif' alt=':o' class='wp-smiley' /> </h4>
<div class="googlemaps"><iframe width="425" height="350" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" src="https://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;source=s_q&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=&amp;q=La Paz, La Paz Department, Bolivia&amp;aq=0&amp;oq=la paz&amp;sll=-12.33432,-51.5126&amp;sspn=21.346399,39.462891&amp;t=h&amp;doflg=ptk&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;hnear=Our Lady of Peace, La Paz Dept, Bolivia&amp;ll=-16.636192,-68.027344&amp;spn=14.700164,18.676758&amp;z=5&amp;output=embed"></iframe><br /><small><a href="https://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;source=s_q&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=&amp;q=La Paz, La Paz Department, Bolivia&amp;aq=0&amp;oq=la paz&amp;sll=-12.33432,-51.5126&amp;sspn=21.346399,39.462891&amp;t=h&amp;doflg=ptk&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;hnear=Our Lady of Peace, La Paz Dept, Bolivia&amp;ll=-16.636192,-68.027344&amp;spn=14.700164,18.676758&amp;z=5&amp;source=embed" style="text-align:left">View Larger Map</a></small></div>
<p>Related: <a href="http://fisefton.wordpress.com/2013/01/11/writing-challenge-map-it/" rel="external nofollow">Writing Challenge: Map It | Fi&#8217;s Mutterings &amp; Mumblings</a></p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://3rdculturechildren.com/category/expat/'>expat</a>, <a href='http://3rdculturechildren.com/category/family/'>FAMILY</a>, <a href='http://3rdculturechildren.com/category/foreign-service/'>foreign service</a>, <a href='http://3rdculturechildren.com/category/travel/'>TRAVEL</a> Tagged: <a href='http://3rdculturechildren.com/tag/dpchallenge/'>DPchallenge</a>, <a href='http://3rdculturechildren.com/tag/map-it-out/'>map it out</a>, <a href='http://3rdculturechildren.com/tag/maps/'>maps</a>, <a href='http://3rdculturechildren.com/tag/postaday/'>postaday</a>, <a href='http://3rdculturechildren.com/tag/weekly-writing-challenge/'>weekly writing challenge</a>, <a href='http://3rdculturechildren.com/tag/writing-challenge/'>writing challenge</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/15079/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/15079/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=15079&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://3rdculturechildren.com/2013/01/11/weekly-writing-challenge-map-it-out/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>90</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/07acd0951ea3f4c6ab5e94276685a702?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F0.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">3rdculturechildren</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://3rdculturechildren.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/screen-shot-2013-01-08-at-5-01-18-pm.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">moves as an expat...</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://3rdculturechildren.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/screen-shot-2013-01-11-at-8-51-39-am.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Itaguaí, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Slow Motion, Black and White Movie</title>
		<link>http://aquashift.wordpress.com/2013/01/07/writing-challenge-map-it-out-the-slow-motion-black-and-white-movie/</link>
		<comments>http://aquashift.wordpress.com/2013/01/07/writing-challenge-map-it-out-the-slow-motion-black-and-white-movie/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2013 00:18:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Aquashift</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[challenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPchallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[East]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eastern Culture. East]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[idea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[location]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surreal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surrealism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Varanasi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wordpress]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://aquashift.wordpress.com/?p=78</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This is India? Perusing it&#8217;s highways and streets from google maps, one would not find much remarkable about it.  There is nothing special that sticks out to compel one to look closer or think  a little more deeply about what the land and people are like.  All one can see at first glance are those squiggly [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=78&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://aquashift.wordpress.com/2013/01/07/writing-challenge-map-it-out-the-slow-motion-black-and-white-movie/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/eccb676efc1fab56a09a862af5330a9b?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">aquashift</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
