<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2013 21:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>School Masterpiece</title>
		<link>http://ellenkydd.wordpress.com/2013/03/12/84/</link>
		<comments>http://ellenkydd.wordpress.com/2013/03/12/84/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 20:13:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>ellenkydd</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[childhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[freedom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nostalgia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[restriction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[school]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ellenkydd.wordpress.com/2013/03/12/84/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[When you are child, you dream, you ponder, you create. Without a care in the world, you splash a drab of paint here with a few sequins scattered there, entirely absorbed in the art of your creation. You follow your intuition, your irrationality, your movement; not an ounce of second thought can hinder your masterpiece. [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=84&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When you are child, you dream, you ponder, you create. Without a care in the world, you splash a drab of paint here with a few sequins scattered there, entirely absorbed in the art of your creation. You follow your intuition, your irrationality, your movement; not an ounce of second thought can hinder your masterpiece. You pin your work up in the hallway, full of pride, knowing that <i>every</i>body can see it there.</p>
<p>When September comes around, you are taken into a world filled with other young people, equally curious but each entirely different. There are lots of other fresh minds, full of innovation, buzzing and wild. You start the term sharing ideas, sharing words and creation. You sing in groups, seeing who can fill their lungs with the most air, who can reach the highest pitch. In the role play area, you metamorphose into an entirely new character, rather like the hungry caterpillar you just read about. When in it’s time to go to the dining room, you skip along in your slightly scuffed shoes, hand-in-hand with your bestest friend. Not a worry in the world will sway you from what you are up to.</p>
<p>Then you enter <i>big </i>school. You are scooped into a class with new faces, new names and a new type of uniform. This time, you have to wear a bright red tie to match the fiery colour of the school logo, a dragon. Sitting at your desk, you drift into a daydream, the dragon dancing around your head, breathing its fumes down your spine. Your teacher drops down in front of you, asking you to ‘have another go’ at your art. Apparently the sky cannot possibly be green, or the donkey orange.</p>
<p>The terms begin to gain speed: Christmas, then Easter, then the joyous summer holidays. You take home work to complete, more and more as the months collect. Numbers, words, nature… All these spheres of thoughts collected and categorised into long complicated names. Mathematics, English literature, Biology. Now you are slightly older, you are told to sit for hours at a time in silence, independently working on each subject. No peaking at anybody else, no eye contact: you are being tested for <i>your </i>ability.</p>
<p>You’ve always had a passion for colour, shapes and words. You’ve always traced the clouds with your imagination as they float past the classroom window. But now you must concentrate on the paragraphs lay before you. You must learn these facts, absorb them, apply them. You must spend several hours analysing their meaning, depicting each sentence until its original meaning has shifted somewhat. And when you write about your findings, you cannot offer your own opinion as itself; it must conform to the <i>learning objectives</i>. If you do not display the expected response, you cannot be thinking in the right way.</p>
<p>You mature into a young adult, imitating the several others around you in lesson. Following the rules of learning that will train you into the right way of doing things, the right pattern of thinking. This is the way forward in life. At some points, you are still able to recall your inner child, projecting it if possible. You now paint with a variety of brushes. You now have more opportunity than ever to create your masterpiece, free and unlimited. A swish of this broad brush, a touch of that intricate brush and a few dabs of an <i>artist’s </i>sponge. You have every colour, every shade; your palette is wider than ever.</p>
<p>But you are too self-critical. You know that line is crooked, those colours do not complement each other, those patterns look absurd together. You spend hour upon hour perfecting each subtle graduation in the stormy sky, each stroke of rain falling at the correct angle onto the horses below. One day you will create your masterpiece.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/84/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/84/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=84&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://ellenkydd.wordpress.com/2013/03/12/84/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c50fc47ac6bf703407d679faa31b04f1?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ellenkydd</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Impressions of SXSW from Far Away, Getting Farther</title>
		<link>http://topicsofcapricorn.wordpress.com/2013/03/12/impressions-of-sxsw-from-far-away-getting-farther/</link>
		<comments>http://topicsofcapricorn.wordpress.com/2013/03/12/impressions-of-sxsw-from-far-away-getting-farther/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 13:46:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>topicalstormb</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[biographical]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Non-fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[art v. commerce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hatred for the time you live in]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nostalgia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-loathing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[south by southwest]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://topicsofcapricorn.wordpress.com/?p=630</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A long time ago, I really liked music. Actually that&#8217;s still true today. I like music more than I like almost everything. Yesterday I told Julie (who is someone I probably like more than music) that if I had to choose between Andy Warhol&#8217;s work and the song &#8220;Roadrunner&#8221; by the Modern Lovers, I would [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=630&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://topicsofcapricorn.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screen-shot-2013-03-11-at-7-25-21-pm.png"><img class="size-full wp-image alignright" id="i-629" alt="Image" src="http://topicsofcapricorn.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screen-shot-2013-03-11-at-7-25-21-pm.png?w=356&#038;h=526" width="356" height="526" /></a><strong>A long time ago, I really liked music</strong>.</p>
<p>Actually that&#8217;s still true today. I like music more than I like almost everything. Yesterday I told Julie (who is someone I probably like more than music) that if I had to choose between Andy Warhol&#8217;s work and the song &#8220;Roadrunner&#8221; by the Modern Lovers, I would kiss those screen prints and Brillo Boxes goodbye in a second. That&#8217;s a pretty tricky thought experiment though, because the way most people tell the history of the Modern Lovers involves Andy Warhol somehow. This is an oversimplification, since the Velvets were around before Warhol and did their best work without him around, although who&#8217;s to say where the influence starts or stops?</p>
<p>Anyway, I have nothing against Andy Warhol; I just chose him off-handedly because he&#8217;s obviously important. But Roadrunner, man. Great song.</p>
<p><strong>So South By Southwest is going on</strong>.</p>
<p>And when I was a teenager in Omaha, the old-timers were already mourning what SXSW had become. In the days before the early 2000s, I guess it was a place for unsigned bands to be discovered by labels. By the time I heard about sxsw, it was mostly the labels putting on showcases and it was so expensive to go and stay in Austin that week, that unsigned bands just wouldn&#8217;t go.</p>
<p>Still, Nigel and I dreamed of going to sxsw, but the cost and distance to Austin always exceeded our grasp.</p>
<p><strong>I write for a tech website</strong> so I got a smart phone and joined Twitter and started following people who do the same sort of stuff. Many of them are writing from SXSW. Many of them are from Brooklyn. All I&#8217;ve heard about from sxsw is about people going to viral marketing conferences and where people have been spotted wearing Google Glass and TED talk this and bullshit that.</p>
<p>Brooklyn, and New York more broadly, is a place I fell in love with via music. It is also a very strong brand.</p>
<p><em></em><strong>Did you know </strong></p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;the idea that art and commerce are at odds is a remnant of an old culture war: dogma presented as forward-thinking but really just protecting<a title="When the NYT tells you something is outmoded..." href="dogma presented as forward-thinking but really just protecting an outmoded status quo" target="_blank"> an outmoded status quo</a>.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Of course you already knew that. How long has it been since you took the phrase &#8220;sell-out&#8221; seriously? If you aren&#8217;t commodifying everything you do, putting ads in front of your youtube videos and monitoring your page views, you&#8217;re just an idiot and someone else is making that money. No band is going to turn down an opportunity for their song to be used in a commercial.</p>
<div class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 410px"><img alt="" src="http://www.art247.com/images/large/BRIDGEMAN/XIR157492.jpg" width="400" height="265" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Pope Julius dictates art because he pays Michelangelo.</p></div>
<p><strong>And you know</strong> art has always been at the behest of commerce. Why did everyone paint stuff for the church? Because the church paid them. Lucky painters did paintings of rich families. Even the Impressionists needed their patrons and they still were all poor and covered in lice.</p>
<p>And those examples are just painters! The more expensive and new arts&#8211;like film&#8211;don&#8217;t even have an illusion of being made with hands free of commerce. Some of the most seminal and revered films&#8211;<em>Battleship Potemkin</em>, <em>Triumph of the Will</em>&#8211;are openly propaganda. Every Hollywood movie opens with a corporate logo.</p>
<p><strong>I haven&#8217;t sought out music coverage from SXSW</strong>, because I just don&#8217;t listen to that much contemporary indie rock, or much contemporary music of any stripe. SXSW doesn&#8217;t really have much to do with indie rock anyway.</p>
<p>I guess I see most indie rock as the form of the pop song played on guitars instead of via computer, and sung by a person with a pretty normal sounding voice rather than a computer-aided super voice.</p>
<p>And indie rock has a lot of pretense of &#8220;art,&#8221; but if it&#8217;s all commerce, does indie v. major label matter much? And how is using the same formula for a pop song&#8211;same line-up of two guitars, bass and drums, that has been used since Buddy Holly&#8211;innovative or impressive?</p>
<p>So I&#8217;ve been listening to American Primative guitarists and jazz music and Penguin Café Orchestra and space-age big band, and operettas and none of them are at SXSW, so for all I know it hasn&#8217;t changed, but I have.</p>
<p><strong>Everything is technology</strong> of course. Last night, talking to Julie, I talked about how the acoustic guitar&#8211;even mine&#8211;is made in a factory (in Nazareth, PA), and the frets are a technological development, as is the bridge and the interface is the strings. It&#8217;s on a spectrum with Google Glass. Maybe it isn&#8217;t a spectrum. Maybe they just share a category. I mean, anything could share a category, depending how you categorize.</p>
<p>So it isn&#8217;t with any pretense of authenticity or superiority that I ignore most EDM or whatever. I just look at a computer screen all damn day, and I don&#8217;t want to make music while looking at my computer screen, and frankly, seeing a musician making music on their computer live is a comically depressing, post-modern display. But there&#8217;s no denying that it&#8217;s very <em>now</em>.</p>
<p><strong>I sold off</strong> the Stratocaster a few days ago. The slow winter months tend to result in my selling something of value. Last year it was my amp, which was too big and loud anyway. This year it was the Strat. I liked the way that guitar played, maybe even more than the Telecaster that I kept and will probably have to sell next year, but the Tele has more sentimental value. It&#8217;s just a product that I used, when you get down to it.</p>
<p><strong>Even the SXSW</strong> that old timers pined for&#8211;unsigned bands trying to become signed bands&#8211;is commerce based. Everything is. <img class="alignright" alt="" src="http://www.oberlin.edu/amam/images/warhol_ft.jpg" width="275" height="209" /></p>
<p>The fact that everyone clamors to get into conferences given by someone who made millions of dollars running a web-based company probably isn&#8217;t categorically different from clamoring to see someone who made millions of dollars playing two-chord songs to teenagers.</p>
<p>Isn&#8217;t that sort of Andy Warhol&#8217;s point with the Brillo Boxes? Look for art in consumer design, because those are the same thing.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not like the bastards won. There was no one else fighting.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not like the counter-culture is being co-opted by the business guys, because there isn&#8217;t a counter-culture. There is only aesthetics. It&#8217;s not like an indie rock festival is categorically different from a tech conference.</p>
<p><strong>It&#8217;s all how you categorize</strong> things, right? You can&#8217;t really afford to be so naïve.</p>
<p><strong>Still</strong>.</p>
<span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='420' height='315' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/QHv8Rok9UfA?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span>
<p>I don&#8217;t feel so bad with the radio on. It helps me from being lonely late at night.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/630/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/630/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=630&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://topicsofcapricorn.wordpress.com/2013/03/12/impressions-of-sxsw-from-far-away-getting-farther/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/ef50ce989be223c1a222aa456c479a8e?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">topicalstormb</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://topicsofcapricorn.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screen-shot-2013-03-11-at-7-25-21-pm.png?w=356" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://www.art247.com/images/large/BRIDGEMAN/XIR157492.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://www.oberlin.edu/amam/images/warhol_ft.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Freelancing Author, or Will I Ever Be Paid Again?</title>
		<link>http://thatsoundscool.wordpress.com/2013/03/12/fumbling-for-the-truth-the-freelancing-author-or-will-i-ever-be-paid-again/</link>
		<comments>http://thatsoundscool.wordpress.com/2013/03/12/fumbling-for-the-truth-the-freelancing-author-or-will-i-ever-be-paid-again/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 15:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Aaron Riccio</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Criticism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Readings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Binghamton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fumbling for the Truth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nate Thayer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Show Business Weekly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Show Showdown]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ta-Nehisi Coates]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Atlantic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Theater Talk]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thatsoundscool.wordpress.com/?p=168</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;m not sure what the big deal is.  Nate Thayer was respectfully asked by Olga Khazan, the Global Editor for The Atlantic, to repurpose an article he wrote for NK News about &#8220;basketball diplomacy,&#8221; for the benefit of her readers. Nate Thayer, needing a paycheck more than exposure, respectfully declined. And then, perhaps deciding that if [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=168&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m not sure what the big deal is.  Nate Thayer was respectfully asked by Olga Khazan, the Global Editor for <em>The Atlantic</em>, to repurpose <a href="http://www.nknews.org/2013/03/slam-dunk-diplomacy/">an article he wrote for NK News about &#8220;basketball diplomacy,&#8221;</a> for the benefit of her readers. Nate Thayer, needing a paycheck more than exposure, respectfully declined. And then, perhaps deciding that if he was going to work for free, he might as well get that exposure in a different way, he chose to <a href="http://natethayer.wordpress.com/2013/03/04/a-day-in-the-life-of-a-freelance-journalist-2013/">adapt his experience into a blog post about the sorry state of unpaid journalism</a>. Publishing the editor&#8217;s e-mail address seemed unnecessary, I suppose, but hardly vindictive so much as childish: &#8220;You offered me exposure to your readers, I return the favor to you via mine.&#8221; And then his comments were <a href="http://nymag.com/daily/intelligencer/2013/03/nate-thayer-vs-the-atlantic-writing-for-free.html">picked up by </a><em><a href="http://nymag.com/daily/intelligencer/2013/03/nate-thayer-vs-the-atlantic-writing-for-free.html">New York</a>, </em>which got him being a bit more profane and officially on-the-record. Recursively, the whole thing wound up back at <em>The Atlantic</em>, in <a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/national/archive/2013/03/lucrative-work-for-free-opportunity/273846/">a half-defensive blog post by Ta-Nehisi Coates</a> that seemed intent on contextualizing Thayer in the worst possible light. Which might not have been such a terrible thing, what with <a href="http://jeremyduns.blogspot.se/2013/03/nate-thayer-is-plagiarist.html">another blog accusing Thayer of plagiarizing his entire article</a>. The whole thing&#8217;s spit-balled around the blogosphere long enough for even me, The Lowest Man on the Totem Pole, to chime in about it . . . so let&#8217;s get back to the actual point: that writers are increasingly asked to exchange their services&#8211;whether to create entirely new content or to adapt previously published work&#8211;for nothing more than the opportunity to reach a larger, or different, audience. Monetizing that would, one assumes, be left up to the writer . . . though if <em>The Atlantic </em>finds itself requesting free articles in order to boost their own ad revenue, I don&#8217;t imagine that&#8217;s a winning strategy.</p>
<p>But rather than write about things I don&#8217;t have the full story on, I&#8217;ll share some experiences of my own. I graduated from Binghamton University in 2005 and took the experiences I&#8217;d gotten from running the entertainment section of our school&#8217;s newspaper (<em>Pipe Dream</em>) and working within the theater department (and its scrappy community brethren) to find work writing freelance theater reviews for <em>Show Business Weekly </em>and for a new blog founded by the PBS show <em>Theater Talk</em>, <em><a href="http://newtheatercorps.blogspot.com/">New Theater Corps</a>, </em>which had gathered sixteen young would-be critics. At first, I was happy simply to have validation: that outside of college, professionals thought enough of my work to still publish it (and to support my unsustainable habit of regularly going to the theater without having a paying job). How could I not forever be grateful to Susan Haskins for the opportunities that she provided me&#8211;to make my first, extremely nervous television appearance and, later, to take over editing the site (which actually <em>did </em>pay). None of this made me feel as if I&#8217;d been taken advantage of, or misled, and the work that I was doing there helped me to get some paying freelance work with David Cote at <em>Time Out New York; </em>I&#8217;d like to think that if I were better at networking (or even sending out my resume), I could have continued to find paying outlets. Enough to sustain myself? Probably not (and I&#8217;d personally rather read Helen Shaw&#8217;s writing than my own), but at least there was a path available, if I could afford to walk it. Hell, <a href="http://theater.nytimes.com/2007/02/25/theater/25laro.html?_r=0">as one of the original members of the <em>Show Showdown, </em>I even got a write-up in the <em>Times </em>herself</a>, and that traffic gave us a foundation for reaching out to more publicists and covering more shows, especially ones that other publications weren&#8217;t ready, willing, or able to get to.</p>
<p>But then the economy started to slide. The grant that sustained the work I was doing for <em>New Theater Corps </em>dried up, I stopped receiving assignments from <em>Time Out New York </em>(save for an unpaid request to help with their Fringe Binge, which I gladly accepted), and after nearly two years of writing for <em>Show Business Weekly</em>, when I&#8217;d informed them that I&#8217;d like to start getting paid <em>something </em>for my work, or to perhaps get some paid copy-editing or proofreading work thrown my way (which is what I do for an actual living), I basically never heard from them again. I liked the editor that I worked with&#8211;<strong>I think every blogger should have access to an editor; perhaps we could edit one another&#8217;s work</strong>&#8211;and I&#8217;d like to think that I was somewhat helpful to the people I worked with at <em>New Theater Corps</em>, but let me tell you, I&#8217;m sure they had the same experience: save for some reference letters that I wrote, they&#8217;ve never heard from me again. I haven&#8217;t sent any opportunities their way, though I&#8217;d like to think that if I&#8217;d gotten into a position to do so, I would have. Still, small comfort to them that I&#8217;d been exactly where they were, writing and rewriting without pay; in fact, the very fact that I was where I was <em>now </em>all but guaranteed that they <em>wouldn&#8217;t </em>be paid, since I wasn&#8217;t going anywhere.</p>
<p>And then my full-time job, the one that actually paid, imploded&#8211;taking an entire 150-plus-person department with it&#8211;and I found myself unable to even get <em>interviews </em>for internships in the field that I&#8217;d spent six years writing about. I&#8217;m not saying I&#8217;m better than the people who did wind up getting those positions; I&#8217;m saying that there were suddenly so many of us, all struggling to find a position. I remember when <em>The Sun </em>folded and I realized that if I was serious about it, I&#8217;d be competing with people like Eric Grode. Around this time I started missing performances that I&#8217;d booked, or worse, attending and failing to write the promised review; how was that supposed to help? By punishing people who, even when I was being paid nothing, were probably making even less (given that some companies spend <em>their own money</em> to make a dream production come true)? I knew what I wanted to do, and it wasn&#8217;t even that I couldn&#8217;t get paid to do it&#8211;it was that I suddenly couldn&#8217;t even get <em>not </em>paid to do it. (I&#8217;ve since discovered a new means of self-motivating, and that&#8217;s largely come from being more discerning in the assignments that I take, whether they&#8217;re something that I&#8217;d probably already be doing, like television or video games, or if they&#8217;re shows That Sound Cool. Whether anything career-oriented comes of my writing is beside the point now&#8211;though one always hopes for the best&#8211;I&#8217;m just personally happy to be providing exposure to subjects that I find interesting.)</p>
<p>So when someone like Thayer, whether you respect the guy or not, announces that he&#8217;s being treated the same way as the rest of us, that <strong>the freelancer is essentially an ink-stained Sisyphus, rolling words uphill (is that not what writing feels like?) and then being crushed back down by financial burdens</strong>, it makes one pause. Perhaps the Atlantic isn&#8217;t greedy, perhaps they&#8217;re struggling under the same market conditions as the rest of us (but at a different order of magnitude), and they really can&#8217;t afford to pay for content, not when bloggers like me are quoting and repurposing their paid content. (I feel a little better in knowing that I at least pay for a yearly subscription, that I&#8217;m at least <em>less </em>a part of the freeloading, paywall-skipping problem.) And it&#8217;s not as if they don&#8217;t pay <em>any </em>authors&#8211;and more than fairly, when they do&#8211;so much as that most people can&#8217;t afford to work on constant spec, hoping for the moment at which an <em>Atlantic</em>-type publication will swoop in, recognize their portfolio, and shower money upon them.</p>
<p>That said, here are two possibilities to alleviate this situation:</p>
<ol>
<li><span style="line-height:13px;"><span style="line-height:13px;"><span style="line-height:13px;">Create a &#8220;path to staff&#8221;; like a tenure track, or an unpaid internship, this would essentially be some sort of contract that would guarantee (in the sense that anything in the tenuous &#8220;publishing&#8221; world can be guaranteed) future, paid work in exchange for unpaid (and less-edited, hopefully less-strenuous) work in the present. I&#8217;m phrasing that poorly, but the implication from Ta-Nehisi Coates&#8217;s blog post is that his unpaid work led to him eventually being hired as a staff writer for <em>The Atlantic</em>, and even if that&#8217;s never put in writing, a simple good-faith understanding would provide that reassuring light at the end of the tunnel, a sign that the struggling author is not going insane (you know, from publishing over and over again without ever being paid but expecting a different outcome). At the very least, there have to be <em>some </em>perks that <em>The Atlantic </em>(and other large publications) could offer to their toiling, literally freelancers, whether that&#8217;s through exclusive first-looks at job postings or through some sort of social network in which you have more than good faith than an editor you&#8217;ve given free product to is going to be advocating on your behalf. What about sharing access to JSTOR or other research tools that you have the money to license, but which your average struggling, unpaid author could really use in improving the quality of future work?
<p></span></span></span></li>
<li>Stop simply offering &#8220;exposure&#8221; and come up with a way of monetizing that for authors. Doesn&#8217;t YouTube offer a very small percentage of ad revenue to the videos that most drive traffic? If that fails, or your site doesn&#8217;t actually generate income on its own (not without the print component, or through brand awareness/relevance), you might consider simply being transparent about it&#8211;revealing <em>why </em>you don&#8217;t have the money to pay your writers might make them feel more empathetic and less ripped off. All things considered, why not implement a &#8220;tip&#8221; button beside the various tools to retweet or post on Facebook? If the numbers of eyes that you offer the unpaid author are really that spectacular, and the content they&#8217;re writing is actually worth publishing and reading, perhaps you might shame readers into paying a bare minimum, much like the Humble Indie Bundle basically gives games away (for exposure), but at such a volume that money is actually made. I wouldn&#8217;t expect my readers to pay a dollar a word (especially at the rate I&#8217;m ranting), but what about a thousandth of a penny? <strong>If you had the <em>Atlantic</em>&#8216;s supposed 13 million readers, and one percent of them gave one-thousandth of a penny per word (so basically a cent and a half from each person in that elite 1%), this essay would&#8217;ve made more than $2,000.</strong> That&#8217;s the sort of monetized exposure I could get behind. Sure, it&#8217;d lead to pandering, with authors attempting to write to those most likely to donate, but that&#8217;s what you&#8217;d have the rest of the <em>paid </em>writers for: to focus on the articles that <em>need </em>to be written, regardless of our low-attention spans and fetishization of celebrity culture.</li>
</ol>
<p>As I&#8217;ve said, the purpose of these &#8220;Fumbling for the Truth&#8221; posts isn&#8217;t accuracy or even answers: it&#8217;s simply a ball-rolling hope that this time&#8211;this time!&#8211;the boulder of words will make it over the hill, pick up momentum, and reach the intended goal: more sustainable wages for writers. Until then, I guess there&#8217;s always Kickstarter. (So long as my idea focuses on a forbidden love triangle between a socially awkward vampire, a teenage mummy and his wizardly cat, and an angel with a bondage fetish.)</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/168/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/168/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=168&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thatsoundscool.wordpress.com/2013/03/12/fumbling-for-the-truth-the-freelancing-author-or-will-i-ever-be-paid-again/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/19efbd0104cbaffa5782aef5b7104019?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">illogicaljoker</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Meat, With a Side Of</title>
		<link>http://exploringmyculture.wordpress.com/2013/03/12/meat-with-a-side-of/</link>
		<comments>http://exploringmyculture.wordpress.com/2013/03/12/meat-with-a-side-of/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 21:51:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Creative Metaphor</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[American Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nutrition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal exploration]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://exploringmyculture.wordpress.com/?p=55</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The American culture pushes meat as the main course in a meal, almost every meal.  There are very few meals where the meat is considered the side dish, and mostly these are breakfasts (such as pancakes and bacon) but when we talk about what a meal is or what we ate, we almost always list [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=55&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The American culture pushes meat as the main course in a meal, almost every meal.  There are very few meals where the meat is considered the side dish, and mostly these are breakfasts (such as pancakes and bacon) but when we talk about what a meal is or what we ate, we almost always list the meat first, as the main dish, and everything else is &#8220;with a side of&#8221;.</p>
<p>Hamburger and fries.  Steak and potatoes.  Chicken noodle soup.   The meat is almost always listed first, even when it isn&#8217;t the majority of the meal!  Pork fried rice.   Clam chowder.  Heck, sometimes it&#8217;s even meat with a side of meat!  Steak and eggs, bacon-wrapped pork, steak and prawns.</p>
<p>When was the last time you read that someone had a salad with a side of steak?  Asparagus with salmon?  Vegetable casserole with chicken?</p>
<p>The reason I bring this up is that I&#8217;ve been learning just how language shapes our thoughts, like how mindsets shaped the language to begin with.  When we think of food as a meat-based affair, we are set up to misrepresent portions on our plate.  While protein is important for the body, it actually shouldn&#8217;t be the main course, and it certainly doesn&#8217;t have to be animal protein.  I&#8217;m not a vegetarian, but I do accept that our society puts far too much weight (ha, pun) on meat not just in every meal, but *as* every meal.</p>
<p>Being tight on money, meat was one of the sacrifices my diet had to make.  I eat eggs regularly, and beans, and sometimes tofu, and occasionally chicken if it&#8217;s on sale, but beef and fish are generally beyond my budget.  I have a little extra these days and enjoy spending it on fish more often, but not daily and certainly not several times per day.</p>
<p>It struck me how ingrained this idea of meat being the meal and vegetables the side when someone asked what I had for lunch.</p>
<p>My lunch consisted of half of a red bell pepper, a third of a cucumber &#8211; sliced, two stalks of celery, five radishes, two cherry tomatoes, a sprig of parsley, all fresh.  It also consisted of 2 oz of salmon, a piece of pita bread, and a dab of salsa.</p>
<p>The vegetables consisted of about 3 cups total volume.  The salmon was maybe 1/4 cup, with a 5&#8243; round piece of bread.  The vegetables far outweighed and out measured the fish and bread, and yet when I started to reply with what I ate for lunch, I automatically said &#8220;Salmon with a side of&#8230;&#8221; but no, wait, that wasn&#8217;t right!  I had a tray of fresh cut vegetables with a side of salmon and pita bread!</p>
<p>At this point you&#8217;re probably rolling your eyes and sighing &#8220;why are you getting so hung up on semantics?&#8221;  Part of trying to change my health and lower my weight is recognizing the way we are meant to eat.  I&#8217;ve met people who acknowledge that they should eat more vegetables, but don&#8217;t know how to fit them in.  One person noted that after a burger, there isn&#8217;t much room left to eat a big salad.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s why semantics are important, I think.  We have the mindset that the focus of our meal is the meat, and the rest should be sort of tucked in around the edges, but only if we have room.  Instead, we should be creating our meals around vegetables, using them as the focus and the main course, and using meat more as a seasoning and less as an entree.</p>
<p>Rethinking the way you approach food can be a bit overwhelming, and certainly takes time to retrain your thinking.  When deciding what to have for dinner, think first about what vegetables you have on hand or what&#8217;s fresh and available in stores.  Then think of what whole grains and proteins you can mix in.</p>
<p>One trick some cultures use is to take small amounts of meat and slice them very thin or into small pieces.  This distributes them evenly throughout the dish and sometimes you don&#8217;t even know you&#8217;ve really eaten far less meat.  Stir fry, stew, and casseroles are great way to use this technique, using very thin slices of beef or well chopped chicken, you can get a little bit of meat in most bites without edging out vegetables as the main ingredient.  You can extend ground beef by mixing it with beans for sloppy joes, meatloaf and tacos.</p>
<p>Besides just the benefit of adjusting our ratios of vegetables, grains and meats, we can also help our budgets because meat is more expensive than vegetables.  Less money out at the grocery store means more money for other things.</p>
<p>If we start thinking about vegetables as our main food source, and meat as the side dish and more for flavor, I think we can go a long way in re-imagining how we relate to food and how food relates to our health.  And it starts with small, conscious steps toward changing how we think about and relate to food.</p>
<p>My goal for the next month is consciously ask myself &#8220;what did I eat?&#8221; and practice answering with &#8220;vegetables, and a side of&#8230;&#8221; instead of &#8220;meat, with a side of&#8230;&#8221; Because that both reflects what I&#8217;m actually eating most of the time, and helps keep me oriented towards vegetables as the main source of nutrition in my diet.  As I lessen my automatic response to focus on meat and grains as what I think of first when it comes to what I eat, the actions of preparing vegetables first and meat and grains secondary will follow.  Thought proceeds action, so I&#8217;m going to keep healthy eating as part of the conscious thought during meal planning.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/55/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/55/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=55&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://exploringmyculture.wordpress.com/2013/03/12/meat-with-a-side-of/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>16</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/dc27359cc37ab540db9a66654ebe3083?s=96&#38;d=monsterid&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">creativemetaphor</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Luckiest Man on the Face of the Earth</title>
		<link>http://fieldnotesfromfatherhood.com/2013/03/12/the-luckiest-man-on-the-face-of-the-earth/</link>
		<comments>http://fieldnotesfromfatherhood.com/2013/03/12/the-luckiest-man-on-the-face-of-the-earth/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 01:30:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>mmtread</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[being grateful]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consumerism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[privilege]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[raising grateful kids]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fieldnotesfromfatherhood.com/?p=3746</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[My oldest son squirms and mopes in his economy class seat, flouncing like a 1920&#8242;s film starlet and sighing deeply enough to drive a small wind turbine. He&#8217;s bored. He&#8217;s been on this stinking plane for almost an hour, and he wants off. Some perspective: We&#8217;re on the second of two 1 1/2-hour hopscotch flights [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3746&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://fieldnotesfromfatherhood.com/2013/03/12/the-luckiest-man-on-the-face-of-the-earth/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>29</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tripswithtots.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/iwant1-e1363036114340.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tripswithtots.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/iwant1-e1363036114340.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">iwant</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/130e38577e9de89053bd99fab77c85af?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mmtread</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tripswithtots.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/eric-lewis-i-m-just-grateful-we-were-able-to-turn-our-pants-into-shorts-new-yorker-cartoon.jpg?w=470" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">eric-lewis-i-m-just-grateful-we-were-able-to-turn-our-pants-into-shorts-new-yorker-cartoon</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Recent Ancient Tradition of Ogoh Ogoh</title>
		<link>http://middlesavagery.wordpress.com/2013/03/11/the-recent-ancient-tradition-of-ogoh-ogoh/</link>
		<comments>http://middlesavagery.wordpress.com/2013/03/11/the-recent-ancient-tradition-of-ogoh-ogoh/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 03:06:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>colleenmorgan</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[anthropology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bali]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ogoh ogoh]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://middlesavagery.wordpress.com/?p=1539</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#160; Bali is quiet today. It is Nyepi, the first day of the New Year, and it is a day of mandatory rest and meditation. We are not allowed outside our flat&#8211;if we are caught on the street we&#8217;ll be firmly escorted back inside. We must stay very quiet and not indulge in any way, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1539&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://middlesavagery.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/photo-24.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1541" alt="photo (24)" src="http://middlesavagery.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/photo-24.jpg?w=500&#038;h=500" width="500" height="500" /></a></p>
<p>Bali is quiet today. It is <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nyepi">Nyepi</a>, the first day of the New Year, and it is a day of mandatory rest and meditation. We are not allowed outside our flat&#8211;if we are caught on the street we&#8217;ll be firmly escorted back inside. We must stay very quiet and not indulge in any way, or we&#8217;ll catch the attention of demons that are currently flying over Bali. If we are quiet enough they&#8217;ll shove on and not stop to wreak havoc. There are no flights in or out of Bali today. Silence.</p>
<p><a href="http://middlesavagery.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/photo-25.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1540" alt="photo (25)" src="http://middlesavagery.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/photo-25.jpg?w=500&#038;h=669" width="500" height="669" /></a></p>
<p>Yesterday, however, was a glorious racket as Ogoh Ogoh were paraded down the street at sunset, twirled around and &#8220;confused&#8221; at intersections, then burned down at the seaside. Over the past week we&#8217;ve been peeping inside of temples to look at the in-progress Ogoh Ogoh as they were carefully built over metal frames. As we stood watching while the young single women of the neighborhood encircled the crossroads, holding torches toward the center, and the young single men of the neighborhood paraded into the center, playing drums and melodic reong&#8211;pot-shaped gongs, the ceremony felt timeless, foreign, yet had a spiritual resonance as well. It was invented in the 1980s.</p>
<p>I was ambivalent when I heard of the recent manufacture of the Ogoh Ogoh parade&#8211;it seemed typical of the kind of trap you can fall into with Orientalist thinking. <em>Bali is so mystical, the people are so nice, they value spirituality, aren&#8217;t their ancient ceremonies so quaint and romantic?</em> Still, I love a good procession and it reminded me of the <a href="https://middlesavagery.wordpress.com/2010/11/03/dia-de-los-muertos-in-the-mission/">Day of the Dead</a>, another parade that celebrates the liminal and otherworldly.</p>
<p><a href="http://middlesavagery.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/photo-23.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1542" alt="photo (23)" src="http://middlesavagery.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/photo-23.jpg?w=500&#038;h=500" width="500" height="500" /></a></p>
<p>The materiality of Ogoh Ogoh is interesting; though some Ogoh Ogoh are very small, they rapidly become very elaborate, with an emphasis on the grotesque. Many go to great lengths to make the Ogoh Ogoh appear to be flying, with very little attaching the demon to the underlying bamboo structure that young men use to carry it. There are lights installed to light up their faces, and some have heavy metal music blaring from their bases. Many Ogoh Ogoh have pendulous, veiny breasts representing Rangda the demon queen. Some are painted, some are meticulously airbrushed, and I have heard that some of them are sold instead of burned at the end of the night.</p>
<p><a href="http://middlesavagery.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/photo-22.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1543" alt="photo (22)" src="http://middlesavagery.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/photo-22.jpg?w=500&#038;h=500" width="500" height="500" /></a></p>
<p>The Ogoh Ogoh and their young male handlers process to the beach, where they gleefully tear off the heads of their creations, then set fire to the demons that they carried through the streets. The Ogoh Ogoh were once made of paper mache, but now they are mostly polystyrene and the great gouts of black smoke made it impossible to breathe. The crowds dispersed before the fire had gone out.</p>
<p><a href="http://middlesavagery.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/photo-21.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1544" alt="photo (21)" src="http://middlesavagery.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/photo-21.jpg?w=500&#038;h=500" width="500" height="500" /></a></p>
<p>And today, Bali is quiet.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1539/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1539/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1539&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://middlesavagery.wordpress.com/2013/03/11/the-recent-ancient-tradition-of-ogoh-ogoh/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/0e521641c1a8847f163433322e6130fb?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">colleenmorgan</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://middlesavagery.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/photo-24.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">photo (24)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://middlesavagery.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/photo-25.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">photo (25)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://middlesavagery.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/photo-23.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">photo (23)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://middlesavagery.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/photo-22.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">photo (22)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://middlesavagery.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/photo-21.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">photo (21)</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Journey Begins?</title>
		<link>http://mymeanderingtrail.com/2013/03/12/the-journey-begins/</link>
		<comments>http://mymeanderingtrail.com/2013/03/12/the-journey-begins/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 09:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jordana</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Mental Preparation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[appalachian trail]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hiking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reflection]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mymeanderingtrail.com/?p=2156</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Planning an Appalachian Trail thru-hike has been one of the most stressful and exciting things I’ve done in a long time. Sure, there are life’s day-to-day anxieties that sometimes bog me down as well as the grander “What’s the answer to life, the universe, and everything?” thoughts (spoiler: it’s 42). But on August 30, 2012, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2156&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Planning an Appalachian Trail thru-hike has been one of the most stressful and exciting things I’ve done in a long time. Sure, there are life’s day-to-day anxieties that sometimes bog me down as well as the grander “What’s the answer to life, the universe, and everything?” thoughts (spoiler: it’s 42). But on August 30, 2012, I decided &#8211; out loud, to the whole blogging universe (or my one follower at the time, at least) &#8211; that I was going to hike along the Appalachian mountain chain from Georgia to Maine.</p>
<p>Little did I know what I’d gotten myself into. I thought, “I’ll just figure out how it works, buy a bunch of gear, and start walking.” It seemed simple enough. I’d gone hiking in the woods many times. And I have plenty of experience car camping. It couldn’t be that different, right? What I didn’t realize at the time is that I had just started my journey.</p>
<div id="attachment_2157" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 160px"><a href="http://mymeanderingtrail.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/at-map.jpg"><img class="size-thumbnail wp-image-2157" alt="This is getting to heavy. We should break it up with a light picture. This'll work." src="http://mymeanderingtrail.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/at-map.jpg?w=150&#038;h=97" width="150" height="97" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">This is getting too heavy. We should break it up with a light picture. This&#8217;ll work.</p></div>
<p>By academic measures, I have always been a fine student, at least by current standards. If a teacher tells me a hard fact or a rule that governs, I can memorize it and spit it back. That’s pretty much what the SAT (standardized test accepted by most American colleges) measures, right? Calculations, multiple choice, even essays &#8211; they all generally test a student’s ability to convey &#8211; either information, a process, or a way of thinking. Got it. No problem.</p>
<p>So reflecting on the past six months, I’d probably have to admit that I was ready to walk into an outdoor store or search online and have someone give me step-by-step instructions on how to hike the A.T. Obviously I’m being farcical, but every step of the way, with every decision, I’ve thought, “Do I need this piece of gear or not? Why won’t someone tell me?!”  “Should I do mail drops? Ah! So many conflicting opinions!” “What’s the right answer? I just want to know the right answer!”</p>
<p>And I’ve lost count of the number of times that I’ve flip flopped on decisions big and small. I’m cutting off all my hair. No, I’m not! I’m not bringing a stove. OK, actually yes, I am. I’m selling all my furniture. Or maybe I’ll store it at my mom’s house. Oh no, these hiking boots aren’t waterproof. Wait, waterproof boots don’t dry as quickly once they get wet? I need to lighten my pack weight. Oh my, this super heavy Gregory Deva feels like the Cadillac of packs. And the list goes on.</p>
<p>I feel like with many aspects of life, one can get on the train. You may not know the destination, but at least you know the train’s riding on a fairly steady track. When I went to college, deep down I knew that I would graduate. Yeah, OK, I took a year off to serve in AmeriCorps, but I knew the general path. When I started working (after serving a second year in AmeriCorps), it didn’t take long to get the general gist either. Go to an office for eight hours a day, five days a week; get a paycheck every couple of weeks; repeat. More or less predictable.</p>
<p>Preparing for my A.T. thru-hike has been anything but predictable. I’ve been awash in a sea of research (the internet is a wonderful and terrible thing), underwater and at times not knowing which way is up. Sustaining the focus and enthusiasm for so many months has been exhausting. And, ya know what? I haven’t been so excited to do anything in my entire adult life. I have no idea where I’ll be on Day 92 of my trek, nonetheless on Day 7, and I couldn’t be happier to find out.</p>
<div id="attachment_2158" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 160px"><a href="http://mymeanderingtrail.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/kiss-butt-goodbye.jpg"><img class="size-thumbnail wp-image-2158" alt="Actually, that last picture was a little overwhelming. This one's better. Think about it. No, don't think about it." src="http://mymeanderingtrail.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/kiss-butt-goodbye.jpg?w=150&#038;h=132" width="150" height="132" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Actually, that last picture was a little overwhelming. This one&#8217;s better. Think about it. No, don&#8217;t think about it.</p></div>
<p>I’ve already faced the fear of leaving my job, signing away the lease to my apartment, getting off the train. What’s there left to fear? Hours upon hours of solitude (or conversely <em>really</em> getting to know fellow hikers)? Aggressive bears? Thunderstorms? Yeah, those things may eventually become frightening, but they’re also part of what makes hiking the A.T. so alluring, so appealing, so exhilarating!</p>
<p>With a little bit of luck I’ll make it to Mount Katahdin in Maine, but I truly believe that my journey can’t begin the day I step foot on Springer Mountain. Instead, it already started on August 30, 2012 when I announced that I’m going to thru-hike the Appalachian Trail. In reality, I’m already halfway to my goal.</p>
<p>So, without further ado&#8230;</p>
<span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='640' height='390' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/f4hsC0nRvZM?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span>
<p>(Don&#8217;t read into the lyrics too much. Just focus on the &#8220;jet plane&#8221; part.)</p>
<p>I&#8217;m headed to Atlanta. See y&#8217;all on the flip side.</p>
<p>Meandering on,</p>
<p>Jordana</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2156/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2156/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2156&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://mymeanderingtrail.com/2013/03/12/the-journey-begins/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>18</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://mymeanderingtrail.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/at-map.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://mymeanderingtrail.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/at-map.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">AT map</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/50c71e12b5e3e6c94406f659145b1dcd?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mymeanderingtrail</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mymeanderingtrail.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/kiss-butt-goodbye.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Actually, that last picture was a little overwhelming. This one&#039;s better. Think about it. No, don&#039;t think about it.</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Whatever &#8220;It&#8221; Is, Do It!</title>
		<link>http://somethingfathappened.wordpress.com/2013/03/11/whatever-it-is-do-it/</link>
		<comments>http://somethingfathappened.wordpress.com/2013/03/11/whatever-it-is-do-it/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 20:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Maggie O'C</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Friendship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Miracles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Never too late]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Never too soon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Power of Prayer]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://somethingfathappened.wordpress.com/?p=3632</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Last week I read an article that Valerie Harper, Rhoda from my all time favorite show The Mary Tyler Moore Show, has been diagnosed with incurable brain cancer. She could have a seizure and die tomorrow. She could live a few months or a few years, she and her doctor don&#8217;t know. They do know [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3632&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last week I read an article that Valerie Harper, Rhoda from my all time favorite show <em>The Mary Tyler Moore Show</em>, has been diagnosed with incurable brain cancer. She could have a seizure and die tomorrow. She could live a few months or a few years, she and her doctor don&#8217;t know. They do know that right now there is no cure for this cancer of the membrane surrounding the brain.</p>
<div id="attachment_3634" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://somethingfathappened.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/rhoda.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-3634" alt="Look how pretty Rhoda is! Big brown eyes, I loved her." src="http://somethingfathappened.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/rhoda.jpg?w=300&#038;h=186" width="300" height="186" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Look how pretty Rhoda is! Big brown eyes, I loved her.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_3635" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://somethingfathappened.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/rhodasmom.png"><img class="size-medium wp-image-3635" alt="Unfortunately, most people sooner associated me with Rhoda's mom." src="http://somethingfathappened.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/rhodasmom.png?w=300&#038;h=300" width="300" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Unfortunately, most people sooner associated me with Rhoda&#8217;s mom.</p></div>
<p>That news got me to thinking, what would I do? What do you do with a three-months-to-live diagnosis?</p>
<p>Then on Friday, I got this email from my Muffincake pal Kitty:</p>
<blockquote>
<div>Ladies</div>
<div>My father was hit by a Baltimore City bus this AM on his way to a dentist appointment. He is in emergency surgery in the shock trauma unit of Univ of MD. He has a broken pelvis, ribs, leg and forehead. His left leg was deskinned. He should be out of surgery in a few hours then into ICU. He will be in the hospital for a few weeks.</div>
</blockquote>
<p>Kitty&#8217;s dad was a perfectly fit 81-year-old man who played tennis a couple of times a week and was planning to spend a month in Italy with his wife this spring until he was hit by a bus Friday morning. Just walking to a dentist appointment. One step different, one more turn of the head, a different parking space&#8230;and life would be different today.</p>
<p>As it is, he has already gone through two surgeries and everyone is praying he is stable enough for another one this week. He has been given more than 15 units of blood. He has broken every bone in his face. There has been internal bleeding. He may lose his leg. He&#8217;s in a medically-induced coma which they bring him out of regularly to make sure he is not suffering any neurological damage which thanks be to God, he is not. His three kids are there in the hospital with him. Kitty&#8217;s mom, the love of his life and wife of 50+ years, is there with him.</p>
<div id="attachment_3642" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://somethingfathappened.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/billbone.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-3642" alt="Kitty's Dad and Mom" src="http://somethingfathappened.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/billbone.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Kitty&#8217;s Dad and Mom</p></div>
<p>I haven&#8217;t seen Kitty&#8217;s dad in years but back in college, I went on vacation with her family. I had Easter and Thanksgiving with them. I have seen him at different events through the years. Kitty&#8217;s dad is a gentleman. Like the kind of gentleman they don&#8217;t make anymore. He is a self-made man. He is mellow, urbane, intelligent, athletic, well-read and well-educated. He has a sharp wit which catches you when you least expect it. He is a measured man who doesn&#8217;t, or at least rarely, gets angry&#8230;instead he solves the problem. He has always been one of my favorite friend dads. Kitty is her father&#8217;s daughter. And she is one of my best friends. This is devastating. Shocking. Traumatic. Baffling. What? How can this be?</p>
<p>So, no one is getting out of here alive. Here are two stories of lives well-lived and now those lives are in jeopardy. What do you think?</p>
<p>It makes me think that you never know when the piano is going to fall out of the sky, so whatever it is you want to do, need to do&#8230;what are you waiting for?</p>
<p>My mother died at 68 and I learned then, life is short &#8212; don&#8217;t delay! Stop making excuses for why you can&#8217;t do something, for why something won&#8217;t work or why it might work some day. Right now today is the day, the time to tell someone, everyone, anyone that you love them. Tell a friend that they hurt your feelings (thank you Trisha). Apologize, you don&#8217;t need to wait a day or two&#8230;if you know you&#8217;re wrong, just say you&#8217;re sorry right now.<br />
You can&#8217;t afford to get married? Don&#8217;t have a wedding, just get married if that&#8217;s what you want. You need to get divorced but continue thinking, &#8220;things will get better&#8221;. If you know in your gut what you should do, do it.</p>
<p>I wish I had a dog (I have a dog but let&#8217;s say someone wishes they had a dog.) Go get a dog! There are thousands of cats and dogs waiting for someone to bring them home and give them a home where they are loved and fed and cared for. Get a dogwalker, get two cats so they will have a pal. Whatever you have to offer is better than living on death row or in a shelter.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://www.petfinder.com/pet-search?location=97219&amp;animal_type=Dog&amp;pet_breed=&amp;pet_age=&amp;pet_gender=&amp;startsearch=Go"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-3637" alt="petfinder" src="http://somethingfathappened.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/petfinder.jpg?w=300&#038;h=117" width="300" height="117" /></a></p>
<p>Lose weight (Maggie, I&#8217;m looking at me). Go for a walk. Move. Don&#8217;t eat that wheel of brie. You have control over whether you do these things or not.</p>
<p>Read <em>War and Peace</em> (I mean if that&#8217;s what you want to do, I can&#8217;t help it if you are a masochist). Go to the movies. Make a movie, you have a phone don&#8217;t you? Paint a picture, write a song or a poem or a blog, sculpt a sculpture.</p>
<p>Help someone, volunteer, point out the spinach in the stranger&#8217;s tooth. Be understanding when you could be angry. Laugh. Surprise yourself. Surprise someone else.</p>
<p>Be who you are, whoever that is. Don&#8217;t hide. Live honestly. Tell the truth, then you will never have to remember what you said (Mark Twain, I think).</p>
<p>Get a job. Quit a job. Find what you love to do and try to get paid for it.</p>
<p>Travel, even if it&#8217;s just diverting onto a road you have never been on.</p>
<p>Remind yourself that you are never too young (unless by law you are) and you are never too old.</p>
<p>And not least of all things, realize the beauty of the greater world, of the universe, of the heavens. Recognize that all of this is bigger than yourself.</p>
<p><strong><em>Pray. Please pray for my friend&#8217;s Dad. All the skills and all the training of nurses and doctors; and all the drugs and machinery in hospitals are sometimes not enough. Please pray, to who or whatever you pray to, that Kitty&#8217;s Dad gets a miracle.</em></strong></p>
<p>(Kitty&#8217;s dad pulled off his own miracle yesterday getting me to Mass at 7:30 in the morning&#8230;anything is possible&#8230;there is no need to wait).</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3632/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3632/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3632&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://somethingfathappened.wordpress.com/2013/03/11/whatever-it-is-do-it/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>95</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/0e9c3ecee26e0de3bf7268d6b038a472?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jetmag26</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://somethingfathappened.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/rhoda.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Look how pretty Rhoda is! Big brown eyes, I loved her.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://somethingfathappened.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/rhodasmom.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Unfortunately, most people sooner associated me with Rhoda&#039;s mom.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://somethingfathappened.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/billbone.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Kitty&#039;s Dad and Mom</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://somethingfathappened.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/petfinder.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">petfinder</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Grokking Expatriates In Sci-Fi*</title>
		<link>http://stevenglassman.de/2013/03/11/grokking-expatriates-in-sci-fi/</link>
		<comments>http://stevenglassman.de/2013/03/11/grokking-expatriates-in-sci-fi/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 05:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Steven</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Anywhere Else]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[capes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comic books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture shock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[expatriates]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fantasy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fish out of water]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[geekstuff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[heroes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sci-fi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[space travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[third culture kids]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[time travel]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://stevenglassman.de/?p=1926</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I was having a conversation with Spring about Doctor Who, as we often do, and it occurred to me that The Doctor is actually an expatriate. That&#8217;s really what this blog is about-  I started to write here originally just to tell my family and close friends what I was up to during my time [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1926&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I was having a conversation with <a href="http://www.timey-wimey.com/" target="_blank">Spring</a> about <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/b006q2x0" target="_blank">Doctor Who</a>, as we often do, and it occurred to me that The Doctor is actually an expatriate.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s really what this blog is about-  I started to write here originally just to tell my family and close friends what I was up to during my time in Germany.  Over time, however, my blog evolved into more than that-  I talk about life as an expat, and I talk about things that are different from life back in the US, different from the life I knew before last year.</p>
<p>Every third or fourth time I use the word expatriate, or expat for short, someone asks me what it means.  An expatriate is just somebody who lives outside of their native country, whether that be temporary or permanent.  The original meaning of the word referred to people who were permanently exiled or who had renounced their homes, but the word is used much  more generically now to describe anyone living outside their home country.</p>
<p><a href="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/doctorwho.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-2181" alt="Doctor Who" src="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/doctorwho.jpg?w=300&#038;h=187" width="300" height="187" /></a>If you broaden the definition slightly of expatriate from country to planet, you can posit that the Doctor is actually an expat.   His homeworld is Gallifrey, a planet that is lost forever in time, but he spends an awful lot of time on Earth, hanging out with humans and generally getting involved with the culture.  That, my friends, is what an expatriate does.  Most of us don&#8217;t spend quite as much time running as the Doctor,  though, with the possible exception of <a href="http://noapathyallowed.com/" target="_blank">Mandi</a>.</p>
<p>Talking about the Doctor as an expatriate got me thinking about all the other expats scattered throughout geeky pop culture, and there are hundreds upon hundreds of them.  Since I&#8217;m a huge list-making nerd, this naturally led to me making a list of some of my favorite sci-fi and fantasy expats from movies, television, comics, and books.  There are far too many to include in one sitting, but these are some of my favorites.  I separate most of them into one of four basic categories: <strong>Last Of My Kind</strong>,<strong> </strong><strong>Stranded</strong>, <strong>Out Of Time</strong>, and <strong>Expat By Choice</strong>.</p>
<p>The Doctor falls into the <strong>Last Of My Kind</strong> grouping.</p>
<p><a href="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/jonnjonnz.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-2188" alt="jonnjonnz" src="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/jonnjonnz.jpg?w=163&#038;h=300" width="163" height="300" /></a>Another memorable example of the last of his kind is J&#8217;onn J&#8217;onnz, the Martian Manhunter.  J&#8217;onn has taken on the human secret identity of John Jones, and he works as a police detective.  Here we encounter a major genre caveat:  Almost all comic book characters have had their story told and retold so many times that there are numerous versions, numerous origins, and numerous backstories.  J&#8217;onn was not always the last of his kind, and certain versions of him have other martians around.  In current continuity, there are green martians and white martians- J&#8217;onn is a green.  In most of the versions though, J&#8217;onn spends much of his non-crimefighting time observing and trying to understand humanity.</p>
<p><a href="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/bigblue.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-2178" alt="bigblue" src="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/bigblue.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" width="300" height="225" /></a>Continuing on in comics, we have perhaps one of the most famous expatriates of all time:  Kal-El of Krypton. Sent to earth by his father to escape a dying planet, baby Kal is adopted by Jonathan and Martha Kent, and is raised as their son, Clark Kent.  The story of Superman is so well known in our shared popular culture that even people who don&#8217;t read comics tend to have at least some knowledge of the story.  One interesting question where Superman is concerned, however:  In most versions of his story, Kal-El really knows very little of the cultural heritage of Krypton.  He was raised on Earth, as an Earth child.  Does this mean he&#8217;s not really an expatriate?</p>
<p>I could go on and on about expats in comics, since many of the comic book heroes are living outside their home countries.   As my friend <a href="http://frankfradella.com/" target="_blank">Frank Fradella</a> put it when I bounced the idea for this post off of him, &#8220;&#8230;and geez&#8230; the entire &#8220;new&#8221; X-Men were expats. Storm, Colossus, Banshee, Sunfire, Nightcrawler.&#8221;  Frank is right-  if I keep listing comic book expats, we&#8217;ll never get around to other fun characters.  Let&#8217;s move on to the <strong>Stranded</strong> expats.</p>
<p>While most expat stories in the sci-fi/fantasy genre tend to be fish out of water stories, it&#8217;s a pretty common trope to have people stuck somewhere, trying to get home.  Heck, that&#8217;s the entire premise of Star Trek: Voyager.  I don&#8217;t count them as expatriates, though, because they&#8217;re living in a community of their own kind (i.e. on board Voyager) and they&#8217;re not really integrating into the society around them as much as they&#8217;re just passing  through.  Star Trek: Voyager is the sci-fi equivalent of an American Army base in Germany- just passing through, folks.</p>
<p><a href="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/farscape.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-2182" alt="farscape" src="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/farscape.jpg?w=300&#038;h=206" width="300" height="206" /></a>Often, however, the characters who fit this category are <em>stuck</em>.  They want to go home, but don&#8217;t know a way.  Like John Crichton in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Farscape" target="_blank">Farscape</a>.  John is an astronaut and test pilot.  In the first episode of the series, he&#8217;s flying his module, Farscape One, and he is pulled into a suddenly appearing wormhole.  When he exits the other side, he&#8217;s in the middle of a battle between the Peacekeepers, a human-looking species called the Sebacean, and a group of escaped prisoners of various alien species aboard Moya, a living ship.  He&#8217;s pulled onboard Moya, and the rest of the series is a combination of his adventures with that group and his attempts to get home.</p>
<p><a href="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/flashgordon.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-2183" alt="flashgordon" src="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/flashgordon.jpg?w=198&#038;h=300" width="198" height="300" /></a><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flash_gordon" target="_blank">Flash Gordon</a>&#8216;s story is not all that different than John Crichton, although in the wonderfully campy 1980 movie version, he&#8217;s not an astronaut, he&#8217;s a professional football player. (The original 1930s version had him as a polo player.)   During a series of pretty ludicrous events, he gets launched into space, and crash-lands on Mongo, before getting into a series of adventures with the various peoples of that world.  Flash adapts amazingly well, and ultimately winds up saving the various different nations of Mongo from their evil overlord, Ming The Merciless.  There have been other versions of Flash&#8217;s story, but the 1980 version is my favorite, partially because of the amazing <a href="http://www.queenonline.com/" target="_blank">Queen</a> rock-score for the film, but mostly for the amazing cast, including Timothy Dalton as Prince Barin, Max von Sydow as Ming, and the amazing Brian Blessed as Prince Vultan:</p>
<p><a href="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/diiiiive.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-2288" alt="Gordon's alive?" src="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/diiiiive.jpg?w=404&#038;h=500" width="404" height="500" /></a></p>
<p>Moving on, then.  The television series Land Of The Lost counts as a <strong>Stranded</strong> <strong></strong>expat story, because the Marshall family (father Rick, children Will and Holly) accidentally moves through a dimensional portal and spends the rest of their time dodging dinosaurs and Sleestaks (humanoid reptilian bad guys) and trying to get back home.  I have no particular fondness for this series, but I like saying &#8220;Sleestak.&#8221;</p>
<p>Another great expatriate character who is stuck away from his home is Oscar Zoroaster Phadrig Isaac Norman Henkel Emmannuel Ambroise Diggs, known to most as the Wizard of Oz.  As with comics, there are many different versions of this character.  In some versions, he&#8217;s fairly benificent.  In the original book version, he really just wanted to go home.  In the musical <a href="http://www.wickedthemusical.com/" target="_blank">Wicked</a>, (my favorite version, incidentally,) he&#8217;s actually kind of a dick.</p>
<p><a href="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/kevinflynn.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-2189" alt="kevinflynn" src="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/kevinflynn.jpg?w=150&#038;h=99" width="150" height="99" /></a>In another of my all time favorites, the TRON series, Kevin Flynn has a rather interesting version of being stuck in another place. Since 1989, Flynn has been living in the Grid, a fictional virtual reality world.  We don&#8217;t really see much of Flynn&#8217;s life on the Grid, because the movie follows his son, Sam Flynn.  Still, it&#8217;s evident from what you do see that he has established a remarkable life for himself there.</p>
<p><a href="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/fordprefect.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-2184" alt="fordprefect" src="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/fordprefect.jpg?w=300&#038;h=181" width="300" height="181" /></a>Up until this point, all of my <strong>Stranded</strong> examples have been humans.  However, one of my favorite expatriate characters isn&#8217;t human at all.  He is, in fact, from a small planet somewhere in the vicinity of Betelgeuse.   Ford Prefect, from the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hitchhiker%27s_guide_to_the_galaxy" target="_blank">Hitchhiker&#8217;s Guide To The Galaxy</a> series, has been in many formats-  books, television shows, radio shows, a movie, comic books, trading cards-  the version pictured to the right is the movie Ford, played by Mos Def.  I prefer the book and radio show versions of Ford, but it was much easier to find a picture of the movie version.   Ford is a roving researcher for the titular Hitchhiker&#8217;s Guide.  He came to Earth to research it for the book, and got stuck for fifteen years.</p>
<p>We can go in with the <strong>Stranded</strong> examples for pages and pages, but I think it&#8217;s Time to move onto the <strong>Out Of Time</strong> category.  (See what I did there?)  These are characters who wind up stuck outside of their own time, like <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Booster_gold" target="_blank">Booster Gold</a>.  I said I wouldn&#8217;t do any more comic book heroes in this list, though.</p>
<p><a href="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/fry.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-2185" alt="fry" src="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/fry.jpg?w=300&#038;h=223" width="300" height="223" /></a>I didn&#8217;t say anything about cartoons, though.  Take Philip J. Fry, in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Futurama" target="_blank">Futurama</a> for example.  In the pilot episode of the series, Fry is a pizza delivery man who gets accidentally (ish) frozen in a cryogenic tube for one thousand years.  He wakes up in the future, and starts working as a delivery boy (naturally) at Planet Express, a delivery company owned as a side-business by Fry&#8217;s distant, distant, very distant nephew, Professor Hubert J. Farnsworth.  A quick side-note about Futurama-  this show is insanely smart at times.  From the earliest episodes, the creators plotted out certain things that get threaded throughout the series.  For example, in the future world of Futurama, owls have become vermin and pests, not unlike city rats of the present day.  Don&#8217;t believe me?  Watch the show again from the beginning, and watch for owls.</p>
<p><a href="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/buckrogers.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-2179" alt="Bidi-bidi-bidi." src="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/buckrogers.jpg?w=210&#038;h=300" width="210" height="300" /></a>Getting back to our expats<strong> </strong>in time, we have <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Buck_rogers" target="_blank">Buck Rogers</a>.  Buck is another old character who has been in movies, television shows, comics, and even video games.  The version most people know about is the 1979-1981 television show Buck Rogers, in which he&#8217;s a shuttle pilot who accidentally gets frozen for roughly 500 years. Once revived, he joins the Earth Defense Directorate, finds love, and gains a pet ambuquad named Twiki, a little robot who seems to have been designed to cash in on the popularity of C3PO and R2-D2 from the newly released film Star Wars.</p>
<p>I can&#8217;t believe it never occurred to me before right now as I write this sentence that Buck Rogers + Flash Gordon = Farscape.  Hmm.</p>
<p><a href="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/johnspartan.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-2187" alt="Enhance your calm, John Spartan!" src="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/johnspartan.jpg?w=300&#038;h=197" width="300" height="197" /></a>As with all my other examples of expats stuck out of time, John Spartan of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Demolition_man" target="_blank">Demolition Man</a> was crygenically frozen.  Whatever happened to a good old time machine?  John Spartan is a cop, sent to CryoPrison in 1996.  They wake him up about forty years later to stop another escaped cryoprisoner, the dastardly Simon Phoenix.  You can tell that Simon is the bad guy because his hair is an unnatural yellow-white color.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s move on to the <strong>Expat By Choice</strong> category.  I could reference Wonder Woman&#8217;s decision to leave Themyscira, but dang it, I said no more comic book heroes.</p>
<p><a href="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/chewbacca.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-2180" alt="chewbacca" src="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/chewbacca.jpg?w=169&#038;h=300" width="169" height="300" /></a>In the Star Wars universe, Chewbacca could loosely be considered an expat.  He isn&#8217;t hanging out on Kashyyyk with the other Wookiees.  However, expanded universe canon states that he fled his home-world when the Empire enslaved the rest of the Wookiees to get construction of the Death Star back on schedule.  This means that technically, Chewie is more of a refugee than an expatriate.  Additionally, since he travels with his friend and business partner Han Solo to fulfill his life-debt (long story), Chewbacca isn&#8217;t really embracing the culture of any specific new place.</p>
<p>While I would love to say that <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Babylon_5" target="_blank">Babylon 5</a> is full of expatriate characters, it really only has two:  Sinclair and Sheridan.  Both of them go to live on Minbar at different points in the series.   The rest don&#8217;t quite match the definition of expatriate because the different species on board Babylon 5 all have their own groupings.  You rarely see a Pak&#8217;mara hanging out with the Gaim, for example, and you would never see a Drazi living on the Vorlon homeworld.  It just isn&#8217;t done.   Babylon 5 is a merchant outpost and a travel hub, and although it&#8217;s referred to as a city in space in the opening credits, it really isn&#8217;t.  B5 is run primarily by EarthForce, and it has no predominant single culture.</p>
<p><a href="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/spock.jpg"><img class="alignleft  wp-image-2191" alt="spock" src="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/spock.jpg?w=210&#038;h=170" width="210" height="170" /></a>Similarly, Star Trek is full of characters who seem to fit the role of expat at first, but perhaps aren&#8217;t textbook examples.  We have characters like Quark on Deep Space Nine, and Worf on board the Enterprise (and later, Deep Space Nine.)  Quark is a merchant, and since the station is a trading post, he&#8217;s not really adopting the culture of a new home-world.  As for Worf, he has Kal-El&#8217;s problem.  Worf may have been born a Klingon, but he was adopted by and raised by humans.  His primary culture is the one that he&#8217;s most commonly in touch with.  Worf isn&#8217;t an expatriate at all.  He falls into a slightly different category though, and I&#8217;ll touch on that a little bit later on.  Lastly, from my Star Trek examples, there&#8217;s Spock.  Spock was raised on Vulcan, but one of his parents was human.  He chooses to live in Starfleet, which is mostly populated by humans.  Even later in his timeline, when he becomes an Ambassador, he mostly sticks around Earth until his eventual trip to Romulus for reunification efforts between the Vulcans and Romulans.</p>
<p><a href="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/tealc.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-2192" alt="teal'c" src="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/tealc.jpg?w=200&#038;h=300" width="200" height="300" /></a>Now that we&#8217;ve covered Star Wars and Star Trek, I would be remiss to leave out the third Star* franchise, Stargate.  Teal&#8217;c is another character that <em>looks</em> human, but isn&#8217;t quite human.  He is a Jaffa, which is a genetically modified human with an abdominal pouch so that he can serve as an incubator for a larval Goa&#8217;uld symbiote.  It&#8217;s not as icky as it sounds, because the symbiote grants its host Jaffa enhanced strength, health, and longevity as well as rapid healing.  The Jaffa are also an enslaved race at the beginning of the series, serving as military forces to the System Lords, who are the initial run of bad guys in the show.  I&#8217;m vastly oversimplifying the sequence of events here, but Teal&#8217;c defects to the SG1 team and goes back to Earth in the pilot episode of the series.    He becomes a valuable member of the team, and he even tries to live outside of Stargate Command in a regular apartment at one point in the series.  Naturally, he wears a hat to cover up the gold embossed tattoo on his forehead whenever he&#8217;s out in public.</p>
<p><a href="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/spikegiles.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-2190" alt="spikegiles" src="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/spikegiles.jpg?w=300&#038;h=293" width="300" height="293" /></a>Meanwhile, back in Sunnydale, we have a couple of Brits living in America.  One of them is Giles, a Watcher, and the other is Spike, a vampire.  (I won&#8217;t get into Liam&#8230; sorry, Angelus here, because his Irish accent was just too horrific for words.)  The expats in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Buffy_the_Vampire_Slayer_%28TV_series%29" target="_blank">Buffy The Vampire Slayer</a> tend to be much more like the textbook definition of expatriate.  Giles is sent to Sunnydale by the Watcher&#8217;s Council, and that&#8217;s not all that different than me being sent to Germany for my job.  As for Spike, I suppose when you&#8217;ve lived for a hundred years or more, it makes sense to try to live somewhere different.</p>
<p><a href="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/travelinmatt.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-2193" alt="travelinmatt" src="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/travelinmatt.jpg?w=201&#038;h=300" width="201" height="300" /></a>Also in the Expat By Choice category is Uncle Traveling Matt, a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fraggle_rock" target="_blank">Fraggle</a> who spends most of his time exploring &#8220;Outer Space,&#8221; his term for the normal human world the rest of us inhabit.  Matthew is the quintessential exploring expatriate, constantly evaluating the culture and norms around him, even if his observations are more Jane Goodall than Terry Gilliam.  (For those of you that know me well, you know I couldn&#8217;t do a list like this without including at least one Muppet.)</p>
<p>A few paragraphs back, I mentioned that Worf isn&#8217;t an expatriate, and that he falls into a different category than the rest of this list.  That category is <strong>Third-Culture Kids</strong>. A <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Third_culture_kid" target="_blank">third-culture kid</a>, or trans-culture kid, in the real world is usually the child of an expatriate.  For example, an American couple has a child while living in Germany.  The child is American-born, but German by culture.  When the family relocates back to the country of their passports, the child has to deal with this cultural divide.  Third-Culture Kids are often multilingual, and are very often accomplished.  However, adjusting to their passport country after years of living in other cultures can be incredibly difficult and can take a great deal of time.  This is Worf in a nutshell, although he didn&#8217;t reintegrate with Klingon culture until very late in his life.</p>
<p><a href="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/valentinemichaelsmith.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-2194" alt="valentinemichaelsmith" src="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/valentinemichaelsmith.jpg?w=195&#038;h=300" width="195" height="300" /></a>My favorite literary Third-Culture Kid would have to be Valentine Michael Smith, the man from Mars, in Heinlein&#8217;s amazing novel, <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Stranger-Strange-Land-Robert-Heinlein/dp/0441788386/" target="_blank">Stranger In A Strange Land</a>.  Mike to his friends, Smith is the biological child of Mary Jane Lyle Smith and Captain Michael Brant of the <em>Envoy<strong></strong></em><strong>, </strong>the first ship to travel to Mars.  The fate of the Envoy crew is unknown for twenty years, and when another ship finally arrives to investigate, they find that Mike is the <em>Envoy&#8217;s</em> only survivor<em>.  </em>Since Mike was raised by Martians, he went the first twenty years of his life never seeing any other human, and he spoke and thought in Martian at the beginning of the story.  Michael Smith is an incredibly intelligent character, and it didn&#8217;t take him long to pick up most of the language, but the first two thirds of the novel deal with his adaptation to a completely alien culture- that of Earth- in a very detailed and fascinating way.</p>
<p><strong>These are some of my favorite expatriates from Sci-Fi, Fantasy, and Comic Book culture. What are some of your favorites?</strong></p>
<p>*Don&#8217;t know what Grokking means?  I guess you should read Stranger In A Strange Land, then.  I&#8217;m off to <a href="http://www.megaconvention.com/" target="_blank">MegaCon in Orlando</a> this weekend, so you can tell me what you thought of it after I get back.</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://stevenglassman.de/category/anywhere-else/'>Anywhere Else</a> Tagged: <a href='http://stevenglassman.de/tag/capes/'>capes</a>, <a href='http://stevenglassman.de/tag/comic-books/'>comic books</a>, <a href='http://stevenglassman.de/tag/comics/'>comics</a>, <a href='http://stevenglassman.de/tag/culture-shock/'>culture shock</a>, <a href='http://stevenglassman.de/tag/expatriates/'>expatriates</a>, <a href='http://stevenglassman.de/tag/fantasy/'>fantasy</a>, <a href='http://stevenglassman.de/tag/fish-out-of-water/'>fish out of water</a>, <a href='http://stevenglassman.de/tag/geekstuff/'>geekstuff</a>, <a href='http://stevenglassman.de/tag/heroes/'>heroes</a>, <a href='http://stevenglassman.de/tag/movies/'>movies</a>, <a href='http://stevenglassman.de/tag/sci-fi/'>sci-fi</a>, <a href='http://stevenglassman.de/tag/space-travel/'>space travel</a>, <a href='http://stevenglassman.de/tag/television/'>television</a>, <a href='http://stevenglassman.de/tag/third-culture-kids/'>third culture kids</a>, <a href='http://stevenglassman.de/tag/time-travel/'>time travel</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1926/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1926/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1926&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://stevenglassman.de/2013/03/11/grokking-expatriates-in-sci-fi/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>57</slash:comments>
		<georss:point>49.016864 12.097408</georss:point>
		<geo:lat>49.016864</geo:lat>
		<geo:long>12.097408</geo:long>
		<media:thumbnail url="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/11doctors-50th.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/11doctors-50th.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">11doctors-50th</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/900f42e4bfbb683759d7a757d9582c87?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">stevenglassman</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/doctorwho.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Doctor Who</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/jonnjonnz.jpg?w=163" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jonnjonnz</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/bigblue.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bigblue</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/farscape.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">farscape</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/flashgordon.jpg?w=198" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">flashgordon</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/diiiiive.jpg?w=404" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Gordon&#039;s alive?</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/kevinflynn.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">kevinflynn</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/fordprefect.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">fordprefect</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/fry.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">fry</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/buckrogers.jpg?w=210" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Bidi-bidi-bidi.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/johnspartan.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Enhance your calm, John Spartan!</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/chewbacca.jpg?w=169" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">chewbacca</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/spock.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">spock</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/tealc.jpg?w=200" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">teal&#039;c</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/spikegiles.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">spikegiles</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/travelinmatt.jpg?w=201" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">travelinmatt</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://stevenglassman.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/valentinemichaelsmith.jpg?w=195" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">valentinemichaelsmith</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>On Occupying in a Midwest College Town</title>
		<link>http://thirdcoastconspiracy.wordpress.com/2013/03/02/the-university-as-a-site-of-struggle-on-occupying-in-a-college-town/</link>
		<comments>http://thirdcoastconspiracy.wordpress.com/2013/03/02/the-university-as-a-site-of-struggle-on-occupying-in-a-college-town/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2013 23:08:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>thirdcoastconspiracy</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Midwest]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thirdcoastconspiracy.wordpress.com/?p=45</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A short reflection on the meaning of democracy and our experience at Occupy organizing at a large “public” university in Michigan. The three of us first began organizing together under the aegis of Occupy in 2011 at the university where we work (though we were also involved in other regional/local Occupies). While the GAs on [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=45&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>A short reflection on the meaning of democracy and our experience at Occupy organizing at a large “public” university in Michigan.</em></p>
<p><img style="border:0 none;" alt="Photo: , License: N/A" src="http://metrotimes.com/polopoly_fs/1.1219856.1318968048%21/image/652713208.jpg_gen/derivatives/landscape_335/652713208.jpg" width="360" height="224" /></p>
<p>The three of us first began organizing together under the aegis of Occupy in 2011 at the university where we work (though we were also involved in other regional/local Occupies). While the GAs on our campus initially drew more than a hundred students, our numbers quickly began to decline and we ultimately turned into a sort of affinity group that, while consistently active, became a closed space with little potential for movement building. Looking back, we remain convinced that universities are an under organized space in anticapitalist struggles but that the dominant organizing models, in particular their emphasis on <i>democracy</i>, require some fundamental rethinking. In what follows, we detail our experience with the GA and sketch out some of the reasons why it failed to serve as the organizing space that we had initially hoped for.</p>
<p>The GAs were one of the most visible and emblematic features of Occupy and were frequently celebrated as consensus-based decision-making bodies both based on and dedicated to principles of <i>radical democracy</i>. GAs helped to introduce thousands of participants to numerous practices that, while well known to anarchist organizers and professional activists (facilitation, stack, consensus, committees/working groups, etc.), were unfamiliar to many newcomers. Compared with the dismal charade of “politics” characteristic of the electoral system, the experience of “real democracy” was in many ways captivating. It created widely circulable images of protestors and offered a tangible way to imagine what they were seeking when they themselves refused to issue precise demands. These practices were quickly drawn into the everyday language of Occupy, most often in the form of “prefigurative” politics.</p>
<p>While GAs in New York, for example, seemed to draw large numbers over long periods of time, the GAs on our campus quickly became an exhausting and draining burden. First and foremost, they were really, really long. Open conversations often take a long time and at times can end up doing little more than going over the same ground. At the same time, since we weren’t actually occupying a space on campus, participants weren’t already gathered in the same place for an indefinite period of time—folks had other places to be, struggling to find enough time to study and work to pay to study. Second, as numbers dropped at the meetings, the bureaucratic structures of the GA began to seem a little ridiculous. When there are only 20 people in a room, there simply is not a need for such a formalized structure. Given that our meeting size varied so much, planning appropriately was a problem. Third, in part because we were not holding space, our meetings tended to be unfocused. Too much time was spent discussing demands and formulating principles, and not enough on planning actions. It was frustrating to attend a three-hour GA whose purpose could not be synthesized and which often had no product. Ultimately the long, drawn out, romantically declarative GA felt like a fetishistic performance of what we imagined politics to be.</p>
<p>We see these problems as arising not from inefficient or otherwise flawed procedures that impede the GA’s democratic function but rather from the obsession with democracy itself. Neither “better facilitation” nor “bigger GAs” would have changed the political valence of the Occupy model or, for that matter, the objective conditions of struggle on our campus. Democracy is synonymous with a liberal politics in which politics as such is defined as speech and individual rights take precedence over collective missions. Below we offer a series of hypotheses about how the GA conceived of politics and democracy and lay out some questions that, we think, might help us develop new ways to organize.</p>
<p><b>Democracy and the GA</b></p>
<p>Hypothesis 1: GAs are based on the notion that <i>speech is equivalent to democracy and, as a consequence, politics</i>. The structures of democracy that are embedded in the GA form (participation is showing via hand signals or voicing your opinion about a given topic, the human mic and repetition of speech, and so on) will always tend, despite strong disavowals to the contrary, toward a form of politics as speech. The GA absorbs direct action into itself, coordinating and distributing speech acts that come to stand in for the anarchist politics from which the GA emerges. So people talk about how Occupy has “already won” because it “changed the national conversation” about inequality. The premise is that speaking aloud comes to supersede and in a way replace structural change. Talking has to lead to action—the two are intertwined and there must be space for both, but mere denunciation is not enough. In our Occupy, which was not holding space, we spent far more time talking than doing. Meetings can be great, and can generate the social bonds that form the basis of solidarity, but without direct action that potential solidarity withers and dies before it can be tested, strengthened, and deployed.</p>
<p>Furthermore, many of our direct actions—such as interrupting a regents’ meeting or a speech at the Business school with a mic check—in fact took the form of vocal denunciations, of political speech. The most common reaction to the mic checks seemed to be mild irritation. Other than short delays, our speech had few material consequences. In fact, it could be argued that our actions served to improve the university’s image as a “site of free speech.” After we disrupted a regents’ meeting, the president of our university published an open letter to President Obama the next day beseeching him to address the issue student debt. Shortly after that, he appeared on campus for some photo ops. Tuition still increased 2.8% for in-state students and 3.5% for out-of-state students the following year.</p>
<p>Hypothesis 2: Given the dominance of the notion of politics as speech, <i>the GA has a problematic tendency to become the primary site of subjectivization</i>. In its presumptively prefigurative model, the forms of democracy it enables and proliferates come to stand as the embodiment of a coming “democratic” community. But the GA is a horrible site for introducing people to a movement, changing their minds, convincing them to get involved—don’t you want your life to be more like an unending series of 3-hour long meetings? In sites like ours where there is not already a significant level of radicalization (more than 10-20 students and faculty) finding ways of building a group of people to undertake actions and protest is critical. Equally important is having multiple points of entry and forms of involvement. What this means is that the structure of governance (a GA, a meeting, a spokescouncil) ceases to be the place we bring people to try to convince them that they should care more deeply about student debt, go on strike, or occupy a building.</p>
<p>Hypothesis 3: The GA is a weak organizing model <i>because it doesn’t think of itself as an organizing model</i>. This creates a problematic overlap between the “form of governance” and the “structure of movement.” These have to be separated. Take the following three cases. In Occupy Oakland, there was initially a dialectic between subjectivization in the streets and containment in the GA, but once this dialectic broke down (coming to favour the GA over the streets) there was no other structure supporting the movement. In Occupy Wall Street, there was a shift from the GA (form of governance) to a dual model with both a GA and a spokescouncil as a parallel organizational structure. Here, the separation between structure and governance is too pronounced and results in a form of shadow governance—the spokescouncil wields the real power and the GAs turn into performance art. In the Occupy at our university, this overlap between governance and structure led to the group’s transformation into an affinity group. Sensing the hollowness of the GA as an organizing model, we shifted to friendship, which is a firmer organizing structure, but which had high barriers to entry and few points for subjectivization.</p>
<p>Hypothesis 4: <i>The most powerful GAs are tied to actions</i> or called to determine if a group of people is willing to undertake a large-scale action (“large-scale” being a scalar term, depending on where and how many you are). If we stop thinking of the GA as either an organizational structure or as a site of subjectivization, we can then ask ourselves what it is they do well. In our opinion, the GA works best under two conditions: 1) it involves a decision on an action (in other words, it operates not as mechanism of containment but rather in a dialectic with direct action), and 2) the decision and process of making the decision has a profound effect of supernumerary collectivity (even if it is marked by intense disagreements with other participants). This does not require perpetual repetition or a reconvening as a general meeting structure, but is more of a collective beginning for a very tangible, visible struggle. It does not rely on a notion of politics as speech, but rather links speech and action.</p>
<p><img id="tumblr_lightbox_center_image" alt="" src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m2jls34R861rq2zyfo2_1280.jpg" width="358" height="275" /></p>
<p><b>Next Steps for Campus Organizing</b></p>
<p>While over the last few years we have seen significant examples of police violence and repression on campuses across the country (especially in California and New York), university administrations more often engage protesters in less direct ways which are highly effective in generating burnout. The denial of confrontation, which while possibly dangerous is at the same time useful for mobilization, ultimately leaves us inaudible. Coupled with the bureaucracy of endless meetings, the administrative response exhausts enthusiasm for movement building. Changing the university requires bringing a halt to the “business” of its everyday operations, something that will actually require the university to publicly confront protestors. For this to happen on our campus, we will need to build support for more militant direct actions.</p>
<p>One of the challenges to organizing on campus is getting undergraduate students—many of whom are being buried under mountains of student debt—to realize that their degree will probably not result in the comfortable middle class lifestyle that they’ve been told awaits them after graduation. This runs counter to their day-to-day experiences in which they do not yet find themselves in the uncomfortable position of not being able to pay back their loans. In a way, we are asking students to anticipate their own future failure. We need to think through the temporality of what people are being asked to act on and how that impacts participation. This requires a longer term relationship with students that may even extend beyond the time it takes them to graduate. Community involvement needs to include alumni and a more intergenerational approach to thinking the figure of “the student.”</p>
<p>With regards to graduate students and faculty, we need to dispel the notion that your scholarship can be your activism. Participation in university-based activism means material risk for individuals whose careers are tied to the institution in such an intimate way. Many of our colleagues, while championing anticapitalist, antiracist, and feminist politics in their work, routinely fail to participate in an open struggle to change the structures that govern our lives. While our writing and research can feed, nurture, and illuminate our struggles (and vice versa), the two should not be conflated. As scholars, we need to put our bodies where our theory is.</p>
<p>Given the current state of student debt, a vicious administrative class, and the prevalence of idealism and creativity, we believe that university campuses are logical and essential sites of struggle. That being said, the university is a trap—only university-based struggles that aim at generalization, at escaping the university and becoming part of wider social condition of refusal (as in Quebec), will have a shot at avoiding either recuperation or reformism. For us, this implies a two part, long-term organizing problem: first, organizing enough students to form a powerful bloc capable of acting on the terrain of the university, and second, organizing the communities that surround us.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/45/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/45/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=45&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thirdcoastconspiracy.wordpress.com/2013/03/02/the-university-as-a-site-of-struggle-on-occupying-in-a-college-town/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/b8c5f314581ccd9c60c782b83ecfd771?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">thirdcoastconspiracy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://metrotimes.com/polopoly_fs/1.1219856.1318968048%21/image/652713208.jpg_gen/derivatives/landscape_335/652713208.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Photo: , License: N/A</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://24.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m2jls34R861rq2zyfo2_1280.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
