<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2012 01:02:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>The Age of Technology (There\&#8217;s No Going Back)</title>
		<link>http://theoverberg.wordpress.com/2012/08/21/the-age-of-technology-theres-no-going-back/</link>
		<comments>http://theoverberg.wordpress.com/2012/08/21/the-age-of-technology-theres-no-going-back/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2012 11:45:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>theoverberg.com</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Humour & Fun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the overberg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[peace of mind]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[website]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[businesses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smartphone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[old]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://theoverberg.wordpress.com/?p=202</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[“He was dragged, kicking and screaming into the age of technology!” This is how my children describe my progress in the electronic business and “social” world – when asked (and sometimes when they&#8217;re not) they paint this picture of a reluctant, stuck-in-the-mud traditionalist, battling to overcome the vagaries of what the world has descended into. [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=202&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:justify;">“He was dragged, kicking and screaming into the age of technology!” This is how my children describe my progress in the electronic business and “social” world – when asked (and sometimes when they&#8217;re not) they paint this picture of a reluctant, stuck-in-the-mud traditionalist, battling to overcome the vagaries of what the world has descended into.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Well that&#8217;s not strictly true. In terms of how fast technology is presently racing <a href="http://smarthdlapps.com/ind_it.php#&amp;panel1-1" target="_blank"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-207" title="Technology" src="http://theoverberg.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/technology.jpg?w=300&h=229" alt="" width="300" height="229" /></a>ahead I might take a few more days to grasp concepts and applications on an Android handset than a fourteen year old might, but I HAVE always been at the forefront of cutting edge technology – just at a more sedate pace!</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">I was the ONLY teacher in the town to own a pocket calculator back in 1974. I proudly bore my purchase (R9,99 from GAME in <a href="http://www.durbanexperience.co.za/Pages/default.aspx" target="_blank">Durban</a>) back to the rural town of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kadoma,_Zimbabwe" target="_blank">Gatooma</a> and while my colleagues manually calculated averages, percentages and added long columns of marks, I tore through the figures as fast as my fingers would allow. I even scored some “free drinks” by loaning out the instrument when deadlines loomed!</p>
<p>I learned how to set the clock on our first video machine in 1982 AND was able to tune it to the TV in order to record TJ Hooker, Night Rider and Dallas. It was also at that time I acquired a fax machine and was able to “hook it” up to the telephone. Not many households could boast THAT array of hardware. I was constantly being asked to help neighbours decipher the instructions as they blankly tried to make sense of the manual that came with the new item.</p>
<p>My children were proud of our “386” with the orange monochrome screen that was carefully positioned on the desk in the study – we were able to type letters AND do sums on a “spreadsheet”!</p>
<p>Over the years the 386 became a 486, then a Pentium and the screen had Windows with pretty colours and icons. I learned how to use WordPerfect and MS Word and Lotus. I had to come to terms with the ever changing Windows versions from 1 through NT, 95, 98, ME, XP, Vista and now 7 … what a ride!</p>
<p>I learned some of these things myself, but it was easier when the pace wasn&#8217;t as frenetic as it is today – thanks goodness <a title="Francois Harris - gotaclick.com" href="http://www.gotaclick.com/" target="_blank">I have a son in this field</a> (he wrote his first simple DOS programme in Grade 1) who continues to teach me some of the finer points along the way.</p>
<p>What I&#8217;m “kicking and screaming” about today is the speed at which everything is changing! No sooner do I get my brand new <a href="http://www.htc.com/africa/" target="_blank">HTC phone</a> than I am told it&#8217;s “old technology” &#8211; what more must I need it to do? I can send and receive my emails, I can update my <a title="Facebook Page for theoverberg.com " href="http://www.facebook.com/theoverberg" target="_blank">Facebook profile</a>, I can “Check In” to Foursquare and to <a title="Rob Harris LinkedIn profile" href="http://www.linkedin.com/profile/edit?trk=tab_pro" target="_blank">LinkedIn</a>, upload to YouTube, surf the net using my DataBundle, pinpoint my exact location in Google Maps, use the built in GPS to tell me where to go, I can read the news, get stock updates, view live TV (on certain channels), I can “locate” my phone if it is lost or stolen and even remotely disable it, I can listen to the radio or MP3&#8242;s, I can take and view photographs or videos and share them with friends, I can Tweet, Peep, Talk and WhatsApp … I can even make and receive phone calls!</p>
<p>Why do I need more modern technology? Maybe I&#8217;m just getting old – anybody want to buy an old phone?</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/202/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/202/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=202&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://theoverberg.wordpress.com/2012/08/21/the-age-of-technology-theres-no-going-back/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/42b4a918e285a08f874fce85026b083c?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">theoverberg</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theoverberg.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/technology.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Technology</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>An Ode to McSweeney’s</title>
		<link>http://dlmayfield.wordpress.com/2012/08/21/an-ode-to-mcsweeneys/</link>
		<comments>http://dlmayfield.wordpress.com/2012/08/21/an-ode-to-mcsweeneys/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2012 13:19:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>D.L. Mayfield</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kingdom of God]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[assimilate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christian art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christian tattoos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mcsweeneys column contest]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dlmayfield.wordpress.com/?p=505</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[My last column at McSweeney&#8217;s is up here. Nearly ten years ago, I submitted my first piece to a oddly named literary website, Timothy McSweeney&#8217;s Internet Tendency. Drawn by the allure of Mr. Dave Eggers, I stayed for the spare, funny, and biting writing that graced this weird little corner of the internet. When I [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=505&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>My last column at McSweeney&#8217;s is up <a href="http://www.mcsweeneys.net/articles/the-year-of-jubilee" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<p>Nearly ten years ago, I submitted my first piece to a oddly named literary website, Timothy McSweeney&#8217;s Internet Tendency. Drawn by the allure of Mr. Dave Eggers, I stayed for the spare, funny, and biting writing that graced this weird little corner of the internet. When I submitted my piece I had just dropped out of my Pentecostal Bible college; I was suffering what I didn&#8217;t know then to be anxiety attacks. I had packed up my dorm room and lived in my sister&#8217;s apartment, crowded with other roommates, where I sat at her PC and banged out a an emotional essay on How I Still Loved Jesus but Didn&#8217;t Love Christians Very Much at All. It was all very dramatic, as I remember. I sent it off, still in my pajamas, working up the nerve to think about what I was going to do next in my life. I waited. I went to the Santa Monica pier and got a tattoo, a small heart with a &#8220;J&#8221; in it, my own inconsequential and obvious way of declaring that Jesus was indeed still in my heart. I eventually got on a train and went to be with my parents in Portland, 33 hours of supposed morose reflection, my depression lifting the closer I got the gray skies of my future, the place that would become my home for the next 9 years.</p>
<p>I got a very nice e-mail back from the site, from the then-editor Mr. Eli Horowitz. I don&#8217;t remember it exactly, but it was very polished and polite, explaining that they didn&#8217;t really publish personal essays, but he did wish me the best of luck. I took it on the chin, and went on with rebuilding my young life. Through the years, I was a regular reader of McSweeney&#8217;s, devoured all the humor books they published (I remember going to Powell&#8217;s with my crazy southern friend, him reading the lists in exaggerated drawls, us busting up with laughter; I remember buying the books for my then-boyfriend K, hoping and hoping that he found them funny so I could marry him&#8211;luckily, he did). I especially loved the columns they published, the outsider perspectives from massage therapists, skateboarders, transvestites, escorts, teenagers. I lived in such a narrow world, and these narratives opened up my doors, put a personal, thoughtful spin on alternative ways of living life.</p>
<p>Last year, I entered the contest. Can I be all evangelical and tell you that God told me to? That he told me exactly what angle to play, how to write it? I&#8217;m sorry, but that is the story. And then I got in, I was picked to be one of the lucky few. I had a platform, I had a space to tell my stories, and the stories of my friends and neighbors. When I got the news, I sat quiet, still, and stunned. It had always been a dream of mine, a list of the top 3 things I dreamed about (the other two were, strangely, writing an essay about love for the NYT and being interviewed by Terry Gross on Fresh Air).</p>
<p>I got some criticism with the first column, some deserved, some not so much. I changed my perspective on a few things, stopped projecting so much onto others and instead jumped headfirst into examining the murkier aspects: faith, doubt, and always failure, failure, failure. People like to read about it, evidently. I wish Christians understood this more.</p>
<p>I love McSweeney&#8217;s. I love the site, comment-and-ad-free, a writer&#8217;s dream. I love the editors, who were encouraging when I was freaking out, told me when I wasn&#8217;t being very funny, said nice things all the time. I love the readers, who (for the most part) wrote me when they didn&#8217;t have to, talked of their worlds being opened a little wider as well. I love that people gave me, an outsider, a chance to think my thoughts, in public.</p>
<p>When friends found out I was doing this writing thing, almost none of them knew what McSweeney&#8217;s was (a common response: Oh, you&#8217;re a writer? You should do the church bulletins!). It further cemented in my mind the way the Christian world is distrustful of the secular, how we have retreated and created our own publishing companies, blogs, bookstores. And as many other, more articulate people have noted, this retreat into our own ghettos has not been kind to us. It has robbed the art and it has robbed the artists. After writing for McSweeney&#8217;s, I know I can&#8217;t go back to writing platitudes and easy moral stories. I was pushed to ask questions, to be honest, to be vulnerable. And this should be expected of all of us, those who are writing stories, those of us who are living great stories.</p>
<p>And so, I thank you, kind folks of McSweeney&#8217;s, for doing what you do. May the next batch of columns be grand, the perspectives wide and varied and funny and honest. I know I will be reading.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/505/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/505/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=505&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://dlmayfield.wordpress.com/2012/08/21/an-ode-to-mcsweeneys/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/8c3dac616267f103002c639468869a26?s=96&#38;d=retro&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">krispindanielle</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Poet’s Day, Mathematically Speaking</title>
		<link>http://sciencelens.wordpress.com/2012/08/21/poets-day/</link>
		<comments>http://sciencelens.wordpress.com/2012/08/21/poets-day/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2012 23:41:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sciencelens</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Special days]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[literature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mathematics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[postaday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://sciencelens.wordpress.com/?p=908</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Today is Poet&#8217;s Day, a day to celebrate the sensitive souls who, through the ages, shared their deepest thoughts through verse and rhyme. I have to admit to being more of a &#8216;prose person&#8217; than a &#8216;poetry person&#8217;, but that by no means implies that I don&#8217;t have the greatest respect and admiration for a [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=908&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today is <strong><em>Poet&#8217;s Day</em></strong>, a day to celebrate the sensitive souls who, through the ages, shared their deepest thoughts through verse and rhyme. I have to admit to being more of a <em>&#8216;prose person&#8217;</em> than a <em>&#8216;poetry person&#8217;</em>, but that by no means implies that I don&#8217;t have the greatest respect and admiration for a good poem &#8211; it&#8217;s simply not my very favourite literary form.</p>
<p>Of course there&#8217;s a close relation between poetry and mathematics &#8211; a subject that is close to my heart. It was Einstein who said: <em>&#8220;Pure mathematics is, in its way, the poetry of logical ideas.&#8221;</em></p>
<p>Mathematics in general seem to play an important role in poetry. Not only is there mathematics in the structure and rhythm of poetry, but many poems have also been written that contain overt mathematical themes. In a 2010 article entitled <em>&#8220;<a href="http://www.math.uconn.edu/~glaz/My_Articles/PoetryInspiredByMathematics.Bridges10.pdf" target="_blank">Poetry Inspired by Mathematics</a>&#8220;</em>, Sara Glaz from the University of Connecticut, discusses some examples of such poems. More examples can be found in an earlier article from 2006 by JoAnne Growney, <em>&#8220;<a href="http://mathdl.maa.org/images/upload_library/4/vol6/Growney/MathPoetry.html" target="_blank">Mathematics in Poetry</a>&#8220;</em>. In the latter article, Growney elegantly states, <em>&#8220;As mathematicians smile with delight at an elegant proof, others may be enchanted by the grace of a poem. An idea or an image expressed in just the right language&#8211;so that it could not be said better&#8211;is a treasure to which readers return.&#8221;</em></p>
<div id="attachment_909" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 539px"><a href="http://sciencelens.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/fibonacci_shell.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-909" title="fibonacci_shell" src="http://sciencelens.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/fibonacci_shell.jpg" alt="" width="529" height="529" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The wonderful Fibonacci number sequence not only pops out in nature, but now claims its place in the world of the poet as well.<br />(© All Rights Reserved)</p></div>
<p>An interesting new poetic form which I&#8217;ve discovered while doing some background reading for today, is the so-called <em><strong>&#8220;Fibonacci poetry&#8221;</strong></em>, which is based on the Fibonacci number sequence. Fibonacci numbers are a sequence, starting with 0 and 1, where each subsequent number is the sum of the previous two, i.e. 0,1,1,2,3,5,8,13,21,34,&#8230;</p>
<p>Fibonacci numbers occur often in nature, as I&#8217;ve discussed in an <a href="http://sciencelens.wordpress.com/2012/05/18/fascination-for-plants-day-3-2/" target="_blank">earlier blog post</a>.</p>
<p>In poetry, the number sequence can refer to the numbers of letters, syllables or words in successive lines of the poem. These poems, known as <em>&#8216;Fibs&#8217;</em>, are six lines long, typically starting with a single letter/syllable/word in the first line. They can, however, theoretically start with any number of letters/syllables/words in the Fibonacci sequence.</p>
<p>Even though this form, originally introduced by Gregory K in a <a href="http://gottabook.blogspot.co.nz/2006/04/fib.html" target="_blank">blog post</a> on the GottaBook blog, appears to still be more popular among mathematicians than among poets, it has managed to garner a <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2006/04/14/books/14fibo.html" target="_blank">mention</a> in the New York Times Books section. Their example, based on syllables, neatly illustrate the concept:</p>
<p><em>Blogs </em><br />
<em>spread </em><br />
<em>gossip </em><br />
<em>and rumor </em><br />
<em>But how about a </em><br />
<em>Rare, geeky form of poetry?</em></p>
<p>I like the idea, I really do &#8211; very cool indeed! So, without further ado, herewith my own humble Fib for the day:</p>
<p><em>Words</em><br />
<em>and</em><br />
<em>numbers</em><br />
<em>sequences</em><br />
<em>not just in nature</em><br />
<em>but warming the hearts of poets too.</em></p>
<p><em><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-style:normal;">(uhm, assuming <em>&#8216;poets&#8217;</em> is a single syllable word, of course&#8230;)</span></em></p>
<p>Happy Poet&#8217;s Day, everyone!  And please do share some Fibs, if you&#8217;re that way inclined!</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://sciencelens.wordpress.com/category/special-days/'>Special days</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/908/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/908/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=908&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://sciencelens.wordpress.com/2012/08/21/poets-day/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/d251e6d0bf748e4721f610570566e044?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sciencelens</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://sciencelens.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/fibonacci_shell.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">fibonacci_shell</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Art Journal Tricks: Sgraffito With Acrylics</title>
		<link>http://smallestforest.net/2012/08/13/httpwp-mepeep9-sw/</link>
		<comments>http://smallestforest.net/2012/08/13/httpwp-mepeep9-sw/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2012 11:59:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>smallestforest</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[My Bag of Tricks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[paint]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[process]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sketchbooks and journaling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tutorials]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[acrylic mediums]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Acrylic paint]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[art journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Paint]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[painting technique]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scraperboard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scratch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sgraffito]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technique]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://smallestforest.net/?p=3380</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This technique is pretty much like scraperboard work...or those oil pastel drawings you made in primary school art class...with the advantage of being fully smudge-proof and waterproof once dry, because you only use acrylic paints...which makes it a great technique for the art journal.<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3380&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;"><a title="art journal page: squid music by Smallest Forest, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/book_wallah/7772694108/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8427/7772694108_91d4100d9b_z.jpg" alt="art journal page: squid music" width="640" height="427" /></a></p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align:center;"><em><a class="zem_slink" title="Sgraffito" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sgraffito" rel="wikipedia" target="_blank">sgraffito</a></em> |sgraˈfiːtəʊ|<br />
noun ( pl. -ti |-ti|)<br />
literally &#8216;scratched away&#8217;; a form of decoration made by scratching through a surface to reveal a lower layer of a contrasting color, typically done in plaster or stucco on walls, or in slip on ceramics before firing.</p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align:center;">This technique is pretty much like scraperboard work&#8230;or those oil pastel drawings you made in primary school art class that you covered with a thick black poster paint, and then scraped back to reveal the colors&#8230;with the advantage of being fully smudge and waterproof once dry, because you only use acrylic paints, which makes it a great technique for the art journal.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a title="Untitled by Smallest Forest, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/book_wallah/7772692502/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8421/7772692502_bf3dc8d5bc_z.jpg" alt="Untitled" width="640" height="480" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">Start by painting your page with the background colors. You can paint it solidly in one color of acrylics, as I hurriedly did today for this post, or you can execute an actual design—shapes, letters, whatever—in blocks of solid color.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><em>N.B. Remember that when you cover the background with another color to start the sgraffito, the background color will only be seen in the lines you have scratched out. So if you want a pink lily, for example, with fine black lines, you would paint a black lily, first, and then cover it all up with a very opaque pink, and then scratch lines to reveal the black underneath.<br />
</em>◦◦◦◦◦◦◦◦◦◦◦◦◦◦◦</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a title="Untitled by Smallest Forest, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/book_wallah/7772692250/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8288/7772692250_d897fe1e69_z.jpg" alt="Untitled" width="640" height="427" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">When the acrylic is dry, give the page a single coat of gloss or semi-gloss acrylic medium. This seals one color from the next, keeping the layers of different colors from sticking to each other, and so keeps the colors and lines distinct.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a title="Untitled by Smallest Forest, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/book_wallah/7772692728/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8446/7772692728_2016abb829_z.jpg" alt="Untitled" width="640" height="426" /></a><br />
Let the coat dry.<br />
◦◦◦◦◦◦◦◦◦◦◦◦</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a title="Untitled by Smallest Forest, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/book_wallah/7772692880/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8308/7772692880_b8091112dd_z.jpg" alt="Untitled" width="640" height="427" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">Take the color of your next layer, and mix it with retarder medium. Don&#8217;t use any water, just the medium, and try to use a paint to medium ratio of 2:1&#8230;too much retarder medium and your paint will take forever to dry. Also, it will sit in a wet puddle that is no good for scratching because every time you draw a line through it the wet paint will simply flow in to fill the line again. You want the paint smooth but not runny.<br />
◦◦◦◦◦◦◦◦◦◦◦◦</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a title="Untitled by Smallest Forest, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/book_wallah/7772693162/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8295/7772693162_c1a22a6690_z.jpg" alt="Untitled" width="640" height="427" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">Fill in the shape, or letters, or whatever that you&#8217;ve drawn. Don&#8217;t do the whole page at once&#8230;remember that even with retarder, the thin film of paint will start to dry, and if the shape is so big that it takes you a long time to scratch your designs into it, parts of it may be dry before you get to them. Scratching only really works if the paint is still wet. I work on patches the size of a playing card, scrape my lines into it, then paint the next patch, scrape into that, and so on.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">I didn&#8217;t have a design planned,so I just kind of doodled this rather underwhelming shape: yet another tentacled creature&#8230;every time I try to paint something spontaneously I end up with tentacles. Damn limited imagination. Anyway.<br />
◦◦◦◦◦◦◦◦◦◦◦◦</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a title="Untitled by Smallest Forest, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/book_wallah/7772693354/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8288/7772693354_c4c98a0492_z.jpg" alt="Untitled" width="640" height="427" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">Experiment with scratching tools. From top to bottom are a thin brass rod, a sculpting tool with a soft rubber cone on the tip (I think polymer clay artists use these things?), and the wrong end of a thin paintbrush. Personally I find the rubber-tipped tool too yielding&#8230;the very end of the cone tends to wiggle, but you may like that. I prefer the metal rod and the paintbrush&#8230;firm sticks that draw consistent lines, each of a definite weight. Find what you like.<br />
◦◦◦◦◦◦◦◦◦◦◦◦</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a title="s'graffito by Smallest Forest, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/book_wallah/7772693606/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8300/7772693606_de32b7cbc8_z.jpg" alt="s'graffito" width="640" height="427" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">Keep a wad of tissue in your other hand, and start scratching your design into the wet paint. Every inch or so, wipe the tip of your tool off on the tissue paper, as a glob of wet paint will collect there. The term &#8220;scratching&#8221; here isn&#8217;t quite accurate&#8230;it implies more force than necessary. There&#8217;s no need to bear down or tear the paint and paper beneath. If the paint hasn&#8217;t dried yet, it&#8217;s like drawing in butter. If the paint has dried, you can still revive it with a tiny dab of retarder from a small brush. Spread that dab of retarder around the dry area, wait a few seconds, and try again.<br />
◦◦◦◦◦◦◦◦◦◦◦◦<br />
<a title="s'graffito by Smallest Forest, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/book_wallah/7772693812/"><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8431/7772693812_92c52248f1_z.jpg" alt="s'graffito" width="640" height="426" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">The rounded tip of a paintbrush makes good dots&#8230;hold the brush vertically and rotate the handle between your fingers, rather than try and &#8216;gouge&#8217; the dot out from one direction. It makes nice round dimples (albeit small ones)<br />
◦◦◦◦◦◦◦◦◦◦◦◦</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a title="art journal page: squid music by Smallest Forest, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/book_wallah/7772694334/"><img class="aligncenter" style="border:0 none;" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8281/7772694334_4c92753aae_z.jpg" alt="art journal page: squid music" width="560" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">If you have made your paint too wet and runny—with either water or retarder—you will know it right away, because the paint will form wet patches, and scratching into it will not leave behind a clean path, but the liquid paint will creep back into the lines you scratched, which is what happened in this toxic green speech bubble I painted next. Wait a bit for the paint to dry a little bit or, if you used too much retarder and it looks like the paint won&#8217;t dry for hours, blot it up with paper towel, maybe a slightly moistened one (the acrylic gloss medium will protect the background layer) and paint the shape in again with the right consistency of paint.<br />
◦◦◦◦◦◦◦◦◦◦◦◦<br />
And that&#8217;s it. Nothing special, really, but it produces a nice effect of its own, distinct from painting fine lines onto a background with a brush or mapping pen. It was often used by the old masters in their oil paintings to hint at, without actually detailing, the intricate lines of lacework or leafy shrubbery. It allows your drawn line to variegate from color to color, too&#8230;just paint the background with rainbows or whatever, before covering up and scratching through.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">I wish I&#8217;d given more thought to what I was going to draw for this post&#8230;this tentacled thing has turned out pretty fugly. Hopefully you see the potential of the technique without being pot off by Squid Ugly, here. <img src='http://s1.wp.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif' alt=';)' class='wp-smiley' /><br />
◦◦◦◦◦◦◦◦◦◦◦◦<br />
<a href="http://smallestforest.net/category/sketchbooks-and-journaling/my-bag-of-tricks/"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-2971" title="For all posts on art journaling tricks, click here." src="http://smallestforest.files.wordpress.com/2012/03/big-fat-bag-of-tricks.jpg?w=442&h=217" alt="For all posts on art journaling techniques, click here." width="442" height="217" /></a></p>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3380&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://smallestforest.net/2012/08/13/httpwp-mepeep9-sw/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
		<georss:point>-12.449029 130.855172</georss:point>
		<geo:lat>-12.449029</geo:lat>
		<geo:long>130.855172</geo:long>
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/1df113b333e83df8ddd627ec069faeb0?s=96&#38;d=monsterid&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">smallestforest</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8427/7772694108_91d4100d9b_z.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">art journal page: squid music</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8421/7772692502_bf3dc8d5bc_z.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Untitled</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8288/7772692250_d897fe1e69_z.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Untitled</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8446/7772692728_2016abb829_z.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Untitled</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8308/7772692880_b8091112dd_z.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Untitled</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8295/7772693162_c1a22a6690_z.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Untitled</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8288/7772693354_c4c98a0492_z.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Untitled</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8300/7772693606_de32b7cbc8_z.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">s&#039;graffito</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8431/7772693812_92c52248f1_z.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">s&#039;graffito</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8281/7772694334_4c92753aae_z.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">art journal page: squid music</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://smallestforest.files.wordpress.com/2012/03/big-fat-bag-of-tricks.jpg?w=611" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">For all posts on art journaling tricks, click here.</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Kiss Isn’t An Emoticon: The Myth of Digital Love</title>
		<link>http://margaretdoyle.wordpress.com/2012/07/30/a-kiss-isnt-an-emoticon-the-myth-of-digital-love/</link>
		<comments>http://margaretdoyle.wordpress.com/2012/07/30/a-kiss-isnt-an-emoticon-the-myth-of-digital-love/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2012 07:29:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>margaretdoyle</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Non-fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Germany]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hannover]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transmedia]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://margaretdoyle.wordpress.com/?p=2893</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I had two long distant relationships this year, one in DC, one in Hannover, Germany. I work in the digital space for a living so it was no problem for me to seamlessly shift from IRL (in real life) to digital life. I do it all day long. My German boyfriend was barely past opening [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2893&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://margaretdoyle.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/img_2620.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-2910" title="Brewed in Percolator" src="http://margaretdoyle.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/img_2620.jpg?w=300&h=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" /></a>I had two long distant relationships this year, one in DC, one in Hannover, Germany. I work in the digital space for a living so it was no problem for me to seamlessly shift from IRL (in real life) to digital life. I do it all day long. My German boyfriend was barely past opening email when I met him but managed, in the space of a short time, to direct message on Twitter, open a Dropbox account, begin skyping at all hours, and even made videos and opened a YouTube account. We hacked the tools to make them work for us and our time distance. Sometimes I&#8217;d wake to a dozen love tweets just as he might be going to bed. There was a kind of pause effect that I liked about digital love; it gave me time to think, to process words as a reader. I loved the idea that someone was sending small blips of poetry to me across an ocean as I slept. I adored waking to them, as though each day greeted me with possibility and sweetness, albeit in the glowing light of an iPhone in the early morning dark.</p>
<p>But the problem with digital relationships is that you effortlessly enter a world of fiction.</p>
<p>Even as I write this, there are thousands of calls being made between people full of hope, commitment, and a steely determination that <em>their</em> digital connection is as good as their connection in real life.</p>
<p>It isn&#8217;t.</p>
<p>Don&#8217;t kid yourself. While our cross-media relationships hold incredible power&#8211;they <em>do</em> communicate our powerful emotions in words, photographs, and video but the subtleties get lost in cyber space: The small twitch of a finger, anxiously drumming a leg, a poker-like tell of inner conflict that is entirely missed as the face smiles in a pixelated mess of <em>I love you&#8217;s</em>, no really, <em>I do&#8217;s</em>.</p>
<p>There are no soft shoulders, no forgiving spaces to lean into on a couch, no hesitant moments in a kitchen before a meal where love can heal and eat in peace together. Instead, words can slam into you at 140 characters like a semi doing 90 miles an hour straight into a brick wall. Direct messages are direct alright.</p>
<p>It is also easier to lie and obfuscate in digital communications. One can get carried away with the fictionalized world of the social objects created to imagine a storyworld between you and your loved one. Pictures, video links, mp3 files, Dropbox playlists, Pins, and memos, even couriered packages all begin to shape and form the world you share. Connection, that is, <em>wi-fi</em>, takes on a life or death dependency. And it seems real, it <em>seems</em> like the best possible world, it is never boring or tedious; it is in fact often <em>better than the real thing</em>. No breath is exchanged however, not a single touch is explored truthfully.</p>
<p>Doubt is easily buried in emoticons.</p>
<p>As our globe shrinks to a <img src='http://s0.wp.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif' alt=':)' class='wp-smiley' /> :):):):):) and a <em>lmao</em> or a bleakly typed &#8216;<em>are you there</em>?&#8217;, we should not confuse digital love with IRL love. In fact, I think dating sites should really come with a warning, like a pack of cigarettes: &#8220;Nothing you see, hear, feel, or read is real. Proceed with caution into this fictionalized world.&#8221;</p>
<p>Don&#8217;t get me wrong, I love r<a href="http://aliceproject4.wordpress.com/2009/10/28/down-the-rabbit-hole-what-does-it-mean/" target="_blank">abbit holes</a>, I really do love escaping into imaginary worlds. And that is the danger. I&#8217;m so easily drawn into fiction over reality that the slippery slope ends up in a lot of digital debris and very little to show for my journey. Good fiction should <em>transform</em> you, take you on a journey, and leave you having learned from the storyworld something that you could not have learned had you not entered it. But digital relationships aren&#8217;t always authored by a good writer and entering into any old story world is a risk.</p>
<p>Smell and taste and laughter and tactile moments cannot be replaced by digital communications no matter how advanced we are; the smell of just washed hair, the texture of hands holding one another, the visceral experience of sitting across from another person and feeling their truth without having to say a word, without, in fact, a single electrical outlet around for a 1000 miles.</p>
<p>Ironically, the more digital I make my life, the more I savour my IRL experiences. The exquisite pleasure of sitting with my old friends, my iPhone off, wine in hand, hearing familiar laughter, clinking of steak knives on plates, the smell of coals below a dripping grill, late afternoon sun warming my back, the lightness of just being in one place, analog style, with only my five senses to record the experience.</p>
<p>Be wary if you think you can port your relationship into and across digital media: There needs to be a time when the circus puts pegs down into the earth, the tent is raised, and real stories get told and real people sit with one another and share them. For me, without the IRL component, no relationship can be truly alive and experienced. Besides, I am pretty sure a kiss still wants to be a kiss and not an emoticon&#8230;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2893/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2893/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2893&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://margaretdoyle.wordpress.com/2012/07/30/a-kiss-isnt-an-emoticon-the-myth-of-digital-love/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>55</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/8445169ea6ff0d4d3a0fdf0a10760a65?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">margaretdoyle</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://margaretdoyle.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/img_2620.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Brewed in Percolator</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>We&#8217;re All Out!</title>
		<link>http://javaj240.wordpress.com/2012/08/20/were-all-out/</link>
		<comments>http://javaj240.wordpress.com/2012/08/20/were-all-out/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2012 22:59:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>javaj240</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Restaurant Server Rant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bullshit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prime rib]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[restaurant server rant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sundays]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://javaj240.wordpress.com/?p=468</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Here&#8217;s a tip: When you come out to dinner and are told that we are out of an item, rest assured that we are out of the item. Please don&#8217;t send your server in the back to check again for you. We are out of it for everyone, not just you. It&#8217;s actually not personal, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=468&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://javaj240.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/primerib.png"><img src="http://javaj240.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/primerib.png" alt="" title="primerib" width="225" height="225" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-474" /></a></p>
<p><strong>Here&#8217;s a tip:</strong><br />
When you come out to dinner and are told that we are out of an item, rest assured that we are out of the item. Please don&#8217;t send your server in the back to check again for you. We are out of it for everyone, not just you. It&#8217;s actually not personal, so don&#8217;t take it that way. And don&#8217;t take it out on your server. They don&#8217;t order the supplies. </p>
<p><strong>Here&#8217;s another tip:</strong><br />
Prime rib requires four to six hours to cook. We cook what we think we will sell. We won&#8217;t resell it tomorrow. When we run out, we run out. Believe it or not, Sunday is a big prime rib day. Don&#8217;t waltz in an hour before we close on a Sunday and expect us to have prime rib. If, by some stroke of luck, we actually do have prime rib at that time, we will probably not have a rare piece. Get here earlier. Or have something else. And stop whining about it. We&#8217;ll see if we can&#8217;t get you the numbers of the one-hundred guests who had prime rib today. Give one of them a buzz. Yell at them for taking your piece. I&#8217;m sure they&#8217;ll be delighted to hear from you. </p>
<p><strong>And another one:</strong><br />
Our special menu is very popular. More than likely we will exhaust our supply of at least one part of it by the end of the weekend. Don&#8217;t ask what you can substitute. You can&#8217;t substitute anything. That&#8217;s why it&#8217;s a &#8220;special&#8221; menu. Be happy we run out of things. That means that we rotate our stock frequently. You should regularly eat at establishments that run out of things. That&#8217;s actually a good sign. Quit your bellyaching and order already.</p>
<p><strong>What the heck, here&#8217;s one more for you:</strong><br />
Stop being so dramatic. Stop using words like crestfallen. This mopey behavior is not going to change anything. Don&#8217;t ask what is going to be done for you because you feel inconvenienced. On the inconvenience scale, not getting to eat a slow-cooked slab of fatty meat with a Caesar salad is relatively minor. It probably falls somewhere between a good toe stubbing and taking your neighbor to the airport. The fact that we ran out of prime rib and your salad choices were reduced by one should not ruin your night. Nor should it ruin mine. Get the hangdog look off your face and be grateful that you have ridiculous things like this to be upset about. Not far from here there are, no doubt, children living in cardboard boxes. </p>
<p><strong>Finally:</strong><br />
You were already told that you would not be compensated for your &#8220;terrible&#8221; experience. Twice. No, you cannot (wink, wink, elbow nudge) &#8220;have&#8221; a slice of cake and a cup of coffee. Frankly, you&#8217;re already a little worked up. Sugar and caffeine might just exacerbate your mood. Perhaps you should consider a nice, warm glass of milk. But not here. Because we&#8217;re all out of milk.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/468/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/468/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=468&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://javaj240.wordpress.com/2012/08/20/were-all-out/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>40</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/526726815989c03bd896ecebb496719e?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">javaj240</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://javaj240.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/primerib.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">primerib</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>E-Books and the Personal Library</title>
		<link>http://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2012/08/20/e-books-and-the-personal-library/</link>
		<comments>http://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2012/08/20/e-books-and-the-personal-library/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2012 09:30:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Joseph Esposito</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Authors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nostalgia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[World of Tomorrow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GoodReads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kerouac]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LibraryThing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[literary classics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=27155</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Moving from the West Coast to the East prompts some thoughts on personal libraries and e-books, as it no longer makes economic sense to carry a lifetime of books around with us. But maybe economic sense isn't the only sense bibliophiles possess . . . <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=27155&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2012/08/20/e-books-and-the-personal-library/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>64</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a3370c4268c26e1ebe2b796b9ecfb356?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F1.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jesposito</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/0/03/Bookshelves.jpg/300px-Bookshelves.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">English: A whole lotta books in my personal li...</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://img.zemanta.com/zemified_e.png?x-id=a059c3fa-4a27-482c-a068-90434c4b7b69" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Enhanced by Zemanta</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dear Fox: Any Day Now, Okay?</title>
		<link>http://cheekybride.wordpress.com/2012/08/20/dear-fox/</link>
		<comments>http://cheekybride.wordpress.com/2012/08/20/dear-fox/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2012 01:11:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>The Cheeky Bride</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Babies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[39 Weeks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[babies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[letter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pregnancy]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cheekybride.wordpress.com/?p=1369</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This will probably be the last letter I write to you while you&#8217;re still baking, as I&#8217;m about a week away from your due date and I&#8217;m praying in every religion that you don&#8217;t decide to make a late appearance.  However, I must remember you ARE your father&#8217;s child, so you very well could come [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1369&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This will probably be the last letter I write to you while you&#8217;re still baking, as I&#8217;m about a week away from your due date and I&#8217;m praying in every religion that you don&#8217;t decide to make a late appearance.  However, I must remember you ARE your father&#8217;s child, so you very well could come on your <em>own damn time</em>, thankyouverymuch.  Sigh.</p>
<p>I don&#8217;t sleep anymore and while I&#8217;ve carried you low throughout this entire pregnancy, you&#8217;ve all of a sudden gotten wise to the fact that you&#8217;ve been missing out on the precious real estate below my rib cage and have moved on up to check it out.  You&#8217;re heading in the wrong direction.  Just an FYI.</p>
<p>I have tried everything from walking to sex to learning to use a weed whacker to try and jar you loose, youngin&#8217;, but you seem pretty content to  prove all the wives tales false.  Your father drew the limit on letting me mow the lawn yesterday.  But that castor oil myth looks more and more tempting by the day.</p>
<p>These last couple weeks have been a big time of reflection for me and things are starting to finally feel a little more real.  In less than 2 weeks I will get to meet you.  It seems like yesterday I stared down at a pregnancy test with two lines and squealed loudly through our empty apartment.  Your dad was hanging out with friends and I couldn&#8217;t wait for him to get home.  I taped the pee stick to our refrigerator for him to find.  Which, looking back, might not have been the most sanitary route to go.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s been quite a journey ever since.  And now as I near the end I think a lot about how labor will go and how life will be with a newborn.  But most of all I think about what you&#8217;ll look like and who you will be.  Whose eyes you&#8217;ll have.  If your hair will be curly and blonde like mine or if you&#8217;ll have your dad&#8217;s darker complexion.  Will you be a little neurotic nutcase like your mom or a mellow little fellow like your dad?  Will you be a mama&#8217;s boy or will you live up to a name like Fox and be the kind of child we&#8217;re pulling off the ceiling fan and buttering his head to get it unstuck from the banisters?</p>
<p>I try to imagine the first moment I see you.  Will I cry?  Will your father cry?  Will my worries that you&#8217;re healthy and happy start from the moment I hold you in my arms?  Will I look at your dad and realize that we have so much love for each other that you&#8217;re our beautiful result?</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve gotten a little sappy on you, I know.  But I just want you to know how much you&#8217;re loved now, already.  Regardless of all the bladder pinching and rib kicking.  The acid reflux and achy hips.  You are so worth it already and I can&#8217;t wait until the day we meet and start our own beautiful journey.</p>
<p>Love,</p>
<p>Your Mom</p>
<div id="attachment_1370" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 520px"><a href="http://cheekybride.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc00250.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1370" title="39 Weeks Pregnant Belly" src="http://cheekybride.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc00250.jpg" alt="39 Weeks Pregnant Belly" width="510" height="602" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">You&#8217;re huge, kiddo!</p></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1369/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1369/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1369&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://cheekybride.wordpress.com/2012/08/20/dear-fox/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>35</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/363c7b5e0edc695834afe9a6f198f3d4?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The Cheeky Bride</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cheekybride.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc00250.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">39 Weeks Pregnant Belly</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Morello Rages Against Ryan&#8230;So What?</title>
		<link>http://dcspillman.wordpress.com/2012/08/20/morello-rages-against-ryan-so-what/</link>
		<comments>http://dcspillman.wordpress.com/2012/08/20/morello-rages-against-ryan-so-what/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2012 01:58:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Spill Man</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Election]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dcspillman.wordpress.com/?p=1199</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It seems that forces were aligned to legitimize my claim from last week that the media, and the public at large, are less concerned with real issues, and more focused on some of the most pointless triviality that dominates our lives these days.  Since Friday, much of my Facebook News Feed and my Twitter page [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1199&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_1200" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 577px"><a href="http://dcspillman.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/ryan-morello.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-1200 " title="Ryan Morello" src="http://dcspillman.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/ryan-morello.jpg?w=567&h=382" alt="" width="567" height="382" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Photo By Mary Altaffer/AP</p></div>
<p>It seems that forces were aligned to legitimize my claim from last week that the media, and the public at large, are less concerned with real issues, and more focused on some of the most pointless triviality that dominates our lives these days.  Since Friday, much of my Facebook News Feed and my Twitter page was dominated by references to <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/08/17/tom-morello-paul-ryan-rage-against-the-machine_n_1795607.html?utm_hp_ref=elections-2012">comments made</a> by guitarist Tom Morello.</p>
<p>Morello is the lead guitarist for Rage Against the Machine, a band cited by GOP VP nominee Paul Ryan as one of his favorites.  Apparently, Mr. Morello is not as big of fan of Ryan as Ryan is of RATM.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><em>In a blistering op-ed published Thursday night on Rolling Stone&#8217;s website, Tom Morello blasts Mitt Romney&#8217;s new VP choice as &#8220;the embodiment of the machine our music rages against.&#8221;</em></p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><em>In painting Ryan as antithetical to progress, Morello compares the Congressman&#8217;s appreciation of RATM to Charles Manson&#8217;s love for The Beatles and New Jersey Gov. Chris Christie&#8217;s liking for Bruce Springsteen.</em></p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><em>At the heart of Morello&#8217;s distaste for Ryan is &#8220;his guiding vision of shifting revenue more radically to the one percent.&#8221; He goes on to say Ryan has plenty of &#8220;rage,&#8221; but claims its &#8220;A rage against women, a rage against immigrants, a rage against workers, a rage against gays, a rage against the poor, a rage against the environment.&#8221;</em></p>
<p>I am not posting this to critique Morello&#8217;s political views.  He is entitled to believe what he believes.  My concern here is how much weight people (especially the media) are giving his opinions.  In my humble opinion, Morello is one of the most talented guitarists to grace the music scene in the last 20 years.  He takes sounds and styles that most people would not have considered, and uses them to make interesting and entertaining melodies.  The man can make music using feedback from an amplifier.  Astounding.</p>
<p>Due mainly to Morello&#8217;s talent, I was a big RTM fan in high school and into college.  I was also impressed with the way the band chose to intertwine their music and their activism.  That being said, I generally could not care less what the band&#8217;s political ideologies are.  I am a music fan for the music itself.  I firmly believe that many of my favorite musicians would probably disagree with my political views.  But that is fine.  I don&#8217;t like them because of their political leanings.  I like them because of their talent.</p>
<p>So, does it surprise me that Morello does not like Ryan?  Not at all.  Based on what I know about him, I wouldn&#8217;t think he would be a big fan of a fiscal and social conservative.  Do I care?  Not particularly.  What I do care about is the fact that people, including some friends of mine, seem to think that Morello&#8217;s indictment of Ryan&#8217;s policies is worth their time and attention.  Why?  As a musician, what makes his political viewpoint worthwhile?  I felt the same way when the media went crazy over the comments that Hank Williams Jr. made on Fox News last fall.  The guy is a singer.  Who cares what his political views are?</p>
<p>I am not saying that Morello should not voice his opinion.  He is a public figure who has access to a microphone and a fan base.  Go for it.  Be heard.  That said, I hope people that listen to him do so with a firm grasp on reality.  He may be an amazing guitarist.  He may even be an educated voter/activist.  But it doesn&#8217;t mean he is right when he talks about Ryan or his policies.  He is not an economist.  He doesn&#8217;t have a PhD in political science.  He is a musician.</p>
<p>I am a lawyer.  When I speak about politics, people should keep in mind that I am not an economist, I am not a political science professor, and I am not a paid political pundit.  I may have lived in DC for a decade and immersed myself in the culture, but it does not mean I am some sort of expert on the issues.  Everything I say should be taken with a grain of salt.  Same goes for Morello.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1199/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1199/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1199&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://dcspillman.wordpress.com/2012/08/20/morello-rages-against-ryan-so-what/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>59</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/0a4bd38b761dc329ca4678a09c88ceea?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">spillmanslaw</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dcspillman.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/ryan-morello.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ryan Morello</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Who Were John and Jessie?</title>
		<link>http://gypsy4evermore.wordpress.com/2012/08/18/john-and-jessie/</link>
		<comments>http://gypsy4evermore.wordpress.com/2012/08/18/john-and-jessie/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2012 16:40:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>gypsy4evermore</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[grief]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[war]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[friends]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[loss]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lost lives]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ripples that come from death]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[veterans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vietnam Wall]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[waste]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://gypsy4evermore.wordpress.com/2012/08/18/john-and-jessie/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Who are John and Jessie? Pretty good question. Very good question. And the answer is, I don’t know. Here’s what I do know. Both were men, most likely youngish and fit. Both were American. Both traveled outside the United States and both were killed in Vietnam. How do I know this? Well John was the [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=97&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Who are John and Jessie? Pretty good question. Very good question. And the answer is, I don’t know. Here’s what I do know. Both were men, most likely youngish and fit. Both were American. Both traveled outside the United States and both were killed in Vietnam. How do I know this? Well John was the first American killed in that conflict and Jessie was the last. Still, how do I know this? Well, the traveling Vietnam wall came to my home town and I visited it last night since I’d never seen the wall at night. And there was John and there was Jessie. The first and the last. Forever etched and forever cut short.</p>
<p>Whenever I see a memorial like that, with the names carved quietly into stone (or hard plastic in this case) I can’t help but imagine the screaming anger and justified indignation behind each name. They were birthed, grew, barely scratched the surface of their lives before whoops, time for war and time to die. There is so much weight and domino effect behind those names. And not just those names, but the uncarved names of the myriads of people who died in violence and war and battle and pillage. Those who do not get a memorial and even the name, cause and time period of their quickened death has been forgotten. So many stolen chances.</p>
<p>Looking at that wall, and trying to see people instead of letters, I can’t help but grin a little and remember that yes, they died, but they were still people. Goofs, assholes, honorable, douche bags, intellects, nerds, athletes, orphans, geniuses, jokers, introverts, artists, romantics, pessimists, farmers, economists, joyful souls and dour spirits. I look at those names and hear the staccato pronunciation in the voice of a Drill Sergeant and the laughing tease as friends take and misshape a name into a dirty joke or dry insult. So many lives hurtled unwillingly toward that wall. Splat into death and cultural immortality.</p>
<p>There are so many meanings and interpretations and soul searching to be done at a place like that. The usual thoughts arise such as “It’s not fair.” “What a waste.” “Those poor parents.” “No more complaining about getting old since I get to do it!” “Better not waste my life since they lost theirs.” And other and sundry such thinkings. All that is of substance, but that was not the primary thought on my brain as I knelt in the grass and watched the flame from the torch reflect off that dark wall. Nope, my thought was a selfish, bitter tasting longing. “I want one! I want a wall!”</p>
<p>These men who died, I honor them. Deeply. Yet none of those names belong to faces I knew.</p>
<p>It is called the healing wall. I want a healing wall. Or if not a wall then something to see and know and trace my fingers across the names that contain the heartbeats and laughter and fights and panic and jokes and shared long boring days and impulsive snowball fights and de-pantsings, and pranks and fear and disgust and sweat and long hard days of work and…and the lives! Their lives! Something to see and touch again. Something more than the remembered empty boots and dangling dog tags. Something tangible. Something I can stare at and rage at and, God help me please, weep at.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/97/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/97/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=97&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://gypsy4evermore.wordpress.com/2012/08/18/john-and-jessie/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>16</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/2a5999d4c2c4f32fc2b55d5083968a58?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gypsy4evermore</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>