<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2012 00:02:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>A Tale of Two Festival Marketers</title>
		<link>http://kathryncoduto.wordpress.com/2012/08/01/a-tale-of-two-festival-marketers/</link>
		<comments>http://kathryncoduto.wordpress.com/2012/08/01/a-tale-of-two-festival-marketers/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 18:28:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Katy Coduto</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Publicity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Advertising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[catalpa nyc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jeep]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[samsung]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[catalpa festival]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sponsorships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music festival]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://kathryncoduto.wordpress.com/?p=146</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As you might have read in one of my earlier posts, I went to NYC&#8217;s Catalpa Festival this past weekend. While there is a great deal of debate over whether or not Catalpa can survive as NYC&#8217;s &#8220;destination festival&#8221; and become one on par with Chicago&#8217;s Lollapalooza or Indio&#8217;s Coachella, there is one thing that [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=146&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As you might have read in one of my earlier posts, I went to NYC&#8217;s Catalpa Festival this past weekend. While there is a great deal of debate over whether or not Catalpa can survive as NYC&#8217;s &#8220;destination festival&#8221; and become one on par with Chicago&#8217;s Lollapalooza or Indio&#8217;s Coachella, there is one thing that Catalpa nailed: sponsorships. <span id="more-146"></span></p>
<p>Catalpa had so many sponsors in so many capacities that it was hard not to be bombarded with advertising during every moment of the festival. Jeep had its own side stage; Absolut vodka had an art lounge; Got2b hair products had a &#8220;confessional&#8221; booth; Heinekin was just about the only beer you could find within a mile radius. Their signs were splashed everywhere, and their logos covered every piece of paper Catalpa handed out. Everyone, it seemed, wanted to be on the Catalpa bandwagon. Catalpa&#8217;s festival goers were the ultimate audience.</p>
<div id="attachment_149" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 250px"><a href="http://kathryncoduto.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/screen-shot-2012-08-01-at-1-41-28-pm1.png"><img class=" wp-image-149 " title="Screen shot 2012-08-01 at 1.41.28 PM" src="http://kathryncoduto.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/screen-shot-2012-08-01-at-1-41-28-pm1.png?w=240&h=238" alt="" width="240" height="238" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The clouds started rolling in at Catalpa early Saturday morning. Midtown Manhattan served as the festival&#8217;s backdrop. (Photo by Katy Coduto)</p></div>
<p>What many of the sponsors weren&#8217;t prepared for was terrible weather, which especially plagued the festival on Saturday. It rained throughout most of the afternoon, including a deluge around 4:15 that turned the entire festival space into a mud pit and left many a festival attendee soaked through.</p>
<p>Jeep was prepared for the rain. They had a massive tent set up next to their side stage, and the tent was an impressive stunt even in nice weather. It featured two Jeeps stacked on stereos, television screens demonstrating different Jeeps, couches and chairs where festival goers could relax, and a bar near the back. Two messages were present in the Jeep tent: First, Jeeps are awesome vehicles that you should drive because, well, here&#8217;s a demonstration. Second, Jeep cares about your comfort at this festival. Jeep basically reminded attendees that while they were there for you to test their new products, they also wanted to be more than just another car to you.</p>
<p>They completely delivered on this when the rain started. Jeep let as many people as possible jam into their tent to avoid the rain. No one got kicked or pushed out. Even at its most crowded, the Jeep tent let more people in. And the volunteers in the tent made the most of their captive audience. They blasted music, and they went around to shivering individuals and talked to them about test driving Jeeps. However, they weren&#8217;t overly persistent. When I told them I wasn&#8217;t interested, they just let me be. Didn&#8217;t ask me to leave, didn&#8217;t try to get me to drive anymore. Jeep had it figured out.</p>
<div id="attachment_151" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 246px"><a href="http://kathryncoduto.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/screen-shot-2012-08-01-at-1-40-36-pm1.png"><img class=" wp-image-151 " title="Screen shot 2012-08-01 at 1.40.36 PM" src="http://kathryncoduto.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/screen-shot-2012-08-01-at-1-40-36-pm1.png?w=236&h=240" alt="" width="236" height="240" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">British band (and one of my personal favorites) The Big Pink perform on the Jeep Stage. Other acts on this stage included A$AP Rocky, Umphrey&#8217;s McGee and the Dirty Heads. (Photo by Katy Coduto)</p></div>
<p>On the other side of this, though, is Samsung, who had an apparatus set up in the middle of Catalpa in support of their Galaxy 3. First of all, Samsung had a semi-lounge set up around their apparatus. The lounge featured chairs and umbrellas, which were dismantled when the rain started. Everything else was contained in a trailer that was composed of 100% metal (or so I was told by one of the guys working in the trailer-thing).</p>
<p>The minute the rain started, all hell broke loose in the Samsung world. I actually tried to take cover first in the Samsung area, but I just couldn&#8217;t take it. First of all, the sales rep was an annoying, sexist pervert who decided he needed to hit on every girl in his captive audience. While hitting on us, disregarding any and all male partners, he also tried to push the Samsung phones. Okay. No. Then, a man who maybe was this guy&#8217;s boss or maybe not, came stomping into the trailer and informed us we needed to leave because, if lightning hit the trailer, it was going to explode.</p>
<p>Now, I&#8217;m not saying I don&#8217;t believe that if lightning strikes metal it&#8217;s going to be a disaster. It&#8217;s probably going to be a dreary situation. But this guy was one of the rudest, most unfortunate people I ran into all weekend. He didn&#8217;t ask us to leave; he didn&#8217;t calmly explain that he was concerned about the safety of the trailer. He literally told us we needed to leave the potential explosive ASAP because he was just not having any of that mess on his hands. HE HAD PHONES TO PROTECT, OKAY?!</p>
<p>But he really didn&#8217;t handle the situation well, especially when faced with nearly fifty people looking for shelter. Telling people they&#8217;re going to die in your trailer isn&#8217;t exactly encouraging. And, as an electronics retailer, shouldn&#8217;t Samsung know better than to create a 100% metal trailer that&#8217;s going to sit outside in the middle of an open field where storms might happen to come by? (If that was even true?)</p>
<p>After this weekend, I&#8217;m ready to buy a Jeep (or at least consider it). However, I also know why I own an iPhone and not a Samsung. Apple, in all of my interactions with the company in any capacity, has always maintained a degree of professionalism that I respect and even admire. Samsung had a captive audience and blew their chance with an undertrained salesman and a manager who was more concerned about his phones than his consumers. There&#8217;s a right way to do sponsorships and a wrong way, especially at a music festival in the rain.</p>
<p>Jeep nailed it. Samsung ultimately failed.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/146/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/146/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=146&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://kathryncoduto.wordpress.com/2012/08/01/a-tale-of-two-festival-marketers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://kathryncoduto.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/catalpa-day-2.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://kathryncoduto.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/catalpa-day-2.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">catalpa-day-2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/0d3e37d11e781e67785cb88e6867d19b?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">kcoduto</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://kathryncoduto.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/screen-shot-2012-08-01-at-1-41-28-pm1.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen shot 2012-08-01 at 1.41.28 PM</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://kathryncoduto.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/screen-shot-2012-08-01-at-1-40-36-pm1.png?w=295" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen shot 2012-08-01 at 1.40.36 PM</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Meatless vs. More Meat Mondays</title>
		<link>http://curranttable.wordpress.com/2012/08/01/meatless-vs-more-meat-mondays/</link>
		<comments>http://curranttable.wordpress.com/2012/08/01/meatless-vs-more-meat-mondays/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 18:15:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Currant Table</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aquaculture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beef]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Grassley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Industrial Agriculture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[joel salatin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[local food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Meat Industry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Meatless Mondays]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[organic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[responsible food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sustainability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainable agriculture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UBCA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[USDA]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://curranttable.wordpress.com/?p=145</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Now that we are back in action here at Currant Table, it feels good to have a forum in which we can highlight the positive changes (Prop 37 on this fall’s ballot) and call into questions those that set us back. In the case of the recent scuffle between the USDA and the NBCA (National [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=145&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Now that we are back in action here at Currant Table, it feels good to have a forum in which we can highlight the positive changes (Prop 37 on this fall’s ballot) and call into questions those that set us back. In the case of the recent scuffle between the USDA and the NBCA (National Cattleman’s Beef Association) . . . . set us WAY BACK.</p>
<p>In quick summary, at the end of July, the USDA announced that they were in support of ‘Meatless Monday’s’, a movement that strives to improve the health of Americans and the environment by cutting meat out of our diets for one day a week. May I note here that there are still 6 MORE days in the week where a participant could subsist entirely on meat if they so choose? In response, the president of the NBCA, J.D. Alexander, released a statement accusing the USDA of not supporting the beef industry, and calling Meatless Mondays ‘an animal rights extremist campaign to ultimately end meat consumption.’ He also claimed “This is truly an awakening statement by USDA, which strongly indicates that USDA does not understand the efforts being made in rural America to produce food and fiber for a growing global population in a very sustainable way,”</p>
<p>If you just laughed out loud . . . don’t worry, so did I. There is NOTHING sustainable about the way we farm beef industrially in the United Sates. And, call me crazy, but announcing that you ‘support’ Meatless Monday, does not in fact mean that you hate meat, or believe that people should stop consuming it. I understand the perceived conflict of interest on the part of the NBCA, however, could it not also be seen as the USDA supporting the one other facets of industrial agriculture for one day? ‘Support Tomato Farmer Mondays!’</p>
<p>I could go back and forth, and come up with my own snarky unfounded assertions to match those of Alexander, but I won’t. As annoyed as I was by the official NBCA statement, they do have a right to a government who protects their interests as much as the next person.</p>
<p>However, we kick this confrontation up a notch when those in DC get involved, and call for the over consumption of meat on the following Monday. The two following tweets are from Senator Chuck Grassley (Iowa) and Congressman Steve King (Iowa).<a href="http://curranttable.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/screen-shot-2012-08-01-at-1-25-08-pm.png"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-147" title="Screen shot 2012-08-01 at 1.25.08 PM" src="http://curranttable.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/screen-shot-2012-08-01-at-1-25-08-pm.png?w=300&h=112" alt="" width="300" height="112" /></a><a href="http://curranttable.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/screen-shot-2012-08-01-at-1-24-48-pm.png"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-146" title="Screen shot 2012-08-01 at 1.24.48 PM" src="http://curranttable.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/screen-shot-2012-08-01-at-1-24-48-pm.png?w=300&h=112" alt="" width="300" height="112" /></a></p>
<p>Grassley’s office, with a handful of other co-conspirators then went so far as to call for a celebration of Meat Mondays.</p>
<p><a href="http://curranttable.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/screen-shot-2012-08-01-at-1-30-32-pm.png"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-148" title="Screen shot 2012-08-01 at 1.30.32 PM" src="http://curranttable.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/screen-shot-2012-08-01-at-1-30-32-pm.png?w=300&h=277" alt="" width="300" height="277" /></a></p>
<p>This photo was posted to the facebook page of junior senator John Cornyn, and depicts the lunch purchased from a local BBQ restaurant in DC. A staffer said that the lunch included  a total of 52 orders of barbecue beef sandwiches, brisket, sausage and ribs, as well as sides of cornbread and macaroni and cheese. Do you all remember those annoying boys in middle school who, when faced with someone else’s effort to, say ‘Save the Whales’ would wear an ‘I hate Whales’ t-shirt? I do, and it is even more obnoxious when adult men engage in the same behavior, and order more meat than an entire office could consume (WASTEFUL) just to make a rather asinine point.</p>
<p>From a food standpoint, since that is what we, here at Currant Table are all about, Meatless Mondays provide a day for American’s to think outside the box of ‘meat/vegetable/carb’ dinners, and get creative while improving their health and the health of the environment. It SHOULD be supported by government offices, because the government is supposed to have our best interests at heart (right?).  I personally know sustainable meat farmers (poultry, beef, pork etc . . .) who engage in Meatless Mondays themselves, without having their entire business crash down around their ears. So it begs the question, what is the NBCA so concerned about? It can’t possibly be that one day a week a fraction of Americans choose not to eat any type of meat (again, 6 more days in the week) so it must be something else.</p>
<p>Could it be that they are starting to feel the squeeze, albeit just a pinch at this point, caused by those of us fighting the fight in the name of accurate information?  We stated in an earlier post, that there is a LOT of it flying around, and that sometimes it is tough to make heads or tails of what you are reading. But in this case it is fairly straightforward:</p>
<p>-Meatless Monday’s are intended to improve the heart health of Americans and help stave off the obesity epidemic.</p>
<p>-Meatless Monday’s are intended to reduce the carbon footprint of an individual, reduce water usage and reduce fossil fuel usage.</p>
<p>-Meatless Monday’s are not intended to turn everyone into vegetarians.</p>
<p>-The NBCA is afraid of Meatless Mondays</p>
<p>In response to the negative outpouring of statements, and actions, only a fraction of which I have mentioned, the USDA recanted their endorsement of Meatless Mondays. This is yet another example of the uphill battle that those of us who believe that we deserve better food are facing.  I know how we at Current Table feel about this, but how do you all feel?</p>
<p>We endorse Meatless Mondays, and encourage all of you reading to visit their site for delicious menu ideas, and information about how you can promote it in your community!</p>
<p>You heard me . . . . Currant Table supports Meatless Mondays! Come and get us NBCA <img src='http://s0.wp.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif' alt=':)' class='wp-smiley' /> </p>
<p>Meatless Monday: <a href="http://www.meatlessmonday.com/">http://www.meatlessmonday.com</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.beefusa.org/newsreleases1.aspx?newsid=2560">http://www.beefusa.org/newsreleases1.aspx?newsid=2560</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/07/30/meatless-monday-chuck-grassley_n_1720505.html#slide=more241780">http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/07/30/meatless-monday-chuck-grassley_n_1720505.html#slide=more241780</a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/145/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/145/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=145&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://curranttable.wordpress.com/2012/08/01/meatless-vs-more-meat-mondays/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://curranttable.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/screen-shot-2012-08-01-at-2-13-51-pm.png?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://curranttable.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/screen-shot-2012-08-01-at-2-13-51-pm.png?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen shot 2012-08-01 at 2.13.51 PM</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/b4342aa46e9599e7680ef68b4025ec57?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">curranttable</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://curranttable.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/screen-shot-2012-08-01-at-1-25-08-pm.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen shot 2012-08-01 at 1.25.08 PM</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://curranttable.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/screen-shot-2012-08-01-at-1-24-48-pm.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen shot 2012-08-01 at 1.24.48 PM</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://curranttable.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/screen-shot-2012-08-01-at-1-30-32-pm.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen shot 2012-08-01 at 1.30.32 PM</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Painted Hills</title>
		<link>http://peacheserratica.wordpress.com/2012/08/01/the-painted-hills-14/</link>
		<comments>http://peacheserratica.wordpress.com/2012/08/01/the-painted-hills-14/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 20:25:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>peacheserratica</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Places]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Roadtripping]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://peacheserratica.wordpress.com/2012/08/01/the-painted-hills-14/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Yesterday I was feeling antsy so I decided to drive to the Painted Hills, a small park in the deserts of central Oregon that features some beautiful geology. It&#8217;s about a 4-5 hour drive from Portland, depending on traffic, but well worth the trip, especially if you&#8217;re a fan of deserts and history. My GPS [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=711&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://peacheserratica.wordpress.com/2012/08/01/the-painted-hills-14/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>32</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/53f6a8301ac4a606958af328a0ce33c0?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">peacheserratica</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peacheserratica.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/255344_4358972660849_282956594_n.jpg?w=487" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peacheserratica.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/386979_4359232667349_1652713742_n.jpg?w=487" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peacheserratica.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/painted1b.jpg?w=487" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peacheserratica.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/painted1c.jpg?w=487" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peacheserratica.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/painted3.jpg?w=487" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peacheserratica.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/painted5.jpg?w=487" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peacheserratica.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/painted6.jpg?w=487" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peacheserratica.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/painted8.jpg?w=487" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peacheserratica.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/painted10.jpg?w=487" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peacheserratica.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/painted11.jpg?w=487" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peacheserratica.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/painted17.jpg?w=487" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peacheserratica.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/painted18.jpg?w=487" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peacheserratica.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/painted21.jpg?w=487" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>I Can Do Dad All By Myself</title>
		<link>http://dadandburied.com/2012/08/01/i-can-do-dad-all-by-myself/</link>
		<comments>http://dadandburied.com/2012/08/01/i-can-do-dad-all-by-myself/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 16:51:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dad and Buried</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Shut Up]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advertising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BloggerFather]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dad bloggers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dad blogs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fatherhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new millenium]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Norelco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[olympics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parenting]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dadandburied.com/?p=4366</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As I promised in my post earlier this week, today I&#8217;m tackling the mom-centric ads being broadcast during the Olympics. These particular ads are from Procter &#38; Gamble, and they celebrate the role of moms in the lives of aspiring and actual Olympic athletes. A lot of dads out there are outraged or at least [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4366&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As I promised in <a title="An Olympic-Sized Commitment" href="http://dadandburied.com/2012/07/30/an-olympic-sized-commitment/">my post earlier this week</a>, today I&#8217;m tackling the mom-centric ads being broadcast during the Olympics.</p>
<p>These particular ads are from Procter &amp; Gamble, and they celebrate the role of moms in the lives of aspiring and actual Olympic athletes. A lot of dads out there <a href="http://www.brucesallan.com/2012/08/01/pg-procter-gamble-ignore-dads-olympics-commercials/">are outraged</a> or at least a little annoyed at the way the ads focus on moms to the exclusion of fathers. Procter &amp; Gamble isn&#8217;t the first brand to ignore dads and they won&#8217;t be the last, just as this is neither the first nor the last time the online community of fathers has gotten excited about what they feel is a total disregard for the role they play in their kids lives.</p>
<p>To which I say: who gives a shit?</p>
<p><span id="more-4366"></span></p>
<p>Here is the ad that sparked the latest round of protests from the online Dad community:</p>
<span style="text-align:center; display: block;"><a href="http://dadandburied.com/2012/08/01/i-can-do-dad-all-by-myself/"><img src="http://img.youtube.com/vi/GhwHhDu8pL4/2.jpg" alt="" /></a></span>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://www.nycdadsgroup.com/2012/07/dear-proctor-gamble-thank-you-mom-but.html">Here is one of the responses to it.</a></p>
<p>I get it. I understand that it&#8217;s a little annoying for a good father&#8217;s role as a parent to be completely ignored. It&#8217;s not the &#8217;50s anymore, when men went to work and women raised the kids. These days (I think it&#8217;s the &#8217;90s or something by now &#8211; time stopped for me in college) things have changed. The odds are that either Mom or Dad even HAS a job are pretty slim. They&#8217;re most likely unemployed and living at Grandma and Grandpa&#8217;s house, doing their best to not kill each other, treading water until one of them finds a new job.</p>
<p>And yet despite all that, they&#8217;re both taking part in the parenting, and the old roles aren&#8217;t so easily defined anymore. That&#8217;s a good thing.</p>
<p>But &#8211; understandably &#8211; it&#8217;s taking some time to see this new paradigm, the new Millenium&#8217;s redefinition of parenting, represented in the media. When we do see it, it&#8217;s in the form of some <a href="http://www.nbc.com/guys-with-kids/">insipid TV show</a> or <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1586265/">terrible movie</a>. Advertising in particular seems to be running behind. And a lot of Dad bloggers are SICK OF IT! This strikes me as an extremely silly thing to be upset about.</p>
<p><a href="http://es.simpsons.wikia.com/wiki/Archivo:Angry_dad.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-4417" title="Angry_dad" src="http://dadandburied.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/angry_dad.jpg?w=300&h=225" alt="Angry Dad, Simpsons" width="300" height="225" /></a></p>
<p>Anyone looking to the advertising industry to lead the way in changing perceptions is looking in the wrong place. Most brands want to sell, and unless they&#8217;re blatantly going for attention, odds are they&#8217;re going to sell by focusing on the lowest common denominator; the easy stereotype; the safe play. And the safe play here is to market their products to moms.</p>
<p>Yes, Dads have a bigger role in parenting than they did in previous years (though I&#8217;m sure they are plenty of Dads from the &#8217;90s, &#8217;80s and &#8217;70s who won&#8217;t take kindly to their role being discounted so generally), but we&#8217;re still a smaller piece of the pie. That&#8217;s just the way it is. The number of Stay At Home Dads has doubled since 2001&#8230;to make up 3.4% of all Stay At Home parents. (Obviously SAHDs aren&#8217;t the only dads who parent, I&#8217;m just sayin&#8217;.)</p>
<p>But again, the numbers aren&#8217;t the point. Many of my fellow dads feel slighted by advertising campaigns and the culture in general. I get it, but I think it&#8217;s silly. What do I care what Procter &amp; Gamble thinks of my role as a parent? I don&#8217;t need their validation. So long as my son knows I&#8217;m there, and my wife gives me some goddamn credit for once, I&#8217;m all good. It just seems like a waste of time &#8211; like most of the <a title="Time Magazine: Parent Porn" href="http://dadandburied.com/2012/05/10/time-magazine-parent-porn/">Mommy Wars</a> and <a title="I Am Parent, Hear Me Roar" href="http://dadandburied.com/2012/05/14/i-am-parent-hear-me-roar/">Parenting Wars</a> and etc. &#8211; to worry about that kind of stuff.</p>
<div id="attachment_4422" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://www.squidoo.com/love-letters-to-my-kids"><img class="size-medium wp-image-4422" title="letter to Mom and dad i guess" src="http://dadandburied.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/letter-to-mom-and-dad-i-guess.jpeg?w=300&h=217" alt="" width="300" height="217" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Image © MamaBush</p></div>
<p>Sure, I guess it would be nice if P&amp;G&#8217;s campaign about Dads supporting their Olympian kids got more play &#8211; and <a href="http://news.pg.com/blog/company-strategy/heres-dad">one does exist</a> &#8211; but whatever (I&#8217;ve already made <a title="An Olympic-Sized Commitment" href="http://dadandburied.com/2012/07/30/an-olympic-sized-commitment/">my stance on my son&#8217;s Olympic dreams</a> quite clear). The stereotype is that Mom takes care of the kids and Dad brings home the bacon, and even if in most homes it&#8217;s much more of a 50/50 split these days, the stereotype was pretty true for quite a while. And the last place we&#8217;re gonna see stereotypes end is in advertising.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s no skin off my back if you continue to write blog posts like <a href="http://www.bloggerfather.com/2012/06/philips-norelco-iv-lost-hope.html">this one</a>, by the popular and respected <a href="http://www.bloggerfather.com/">Blogger Father</a>, who led an uproar about Norelco&#8217;s &#8220;made for moms&#8221; advertising and actually effected some change. They got wind of his protest and changed it to &#8220;made for parents,&#8221; though they didn&#8217;t actually change much else in the language, which says the clippers are &#8220;made for women&#8217;s hands.&#8221; How rude. Not only do I clip their kids&#8217; hair, my wife has enormous man-hands. So screw you, Norelco!</p>
<p>Gandhi said &#8220;Be the change you want to see in the world,&#8221; not &#8220;blog about the change you don&#8217;t see until Madison Avenue throws you a bone.&#8221; I&#8217;m glad <a>Blogger Father</a> actually got <em>something</em> done; I&#8217;m just not interested in joining the picket line.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m not gonna be the jerk that says something like: maybe you dads should spend less time railing against what advertisers think of you and more time parenting your kids, because that&#8217;s obnoxious and condescending and not what&#8217;s happening here. These are dedicated dads who are tired of getting short shrift in the good parent department. But if they merely keep up the good work, even if they don&#8217;t get the recognition they deserve, they can at least be secure in the fact that they&#8217;re kids will know that Dads aren&#8217;t just window dressing, and they&#8217;ll grow up with a healthier perspective on the role of both parents in raising children.</p>
<p>But go ahead and keep writing your posts, I guess. I just won&#8217;t be reading them.</p>
<p>BECAUSE I&#8217;LL BE TOO BUSY RAISING MY SON. And also writing posts about<a title="Top 10 Reasons Why I Hate My Son*" href="http://dadandburied.com/2012/07/27/top-10-reasons-i-hate-my-son/"> why I hate him.</a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4366/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4366/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4366&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://dadandburied.com/2012/08/01/i-can-do-dad-all-by-myself/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>15</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://dadandburied.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/greatest-weekend-dad-ever-family-ecard-someecards.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://dadandburied.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/greatest-weekend-dad-ever-family-ecard-someecards.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">greatest-weekend-dad-ever-family-ecard-someecards</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/9f48496f83072567d6b6c35b64f0f6c4?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">julesy999</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dadandburied.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/angry_dad.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Angry_dad</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dadandburied.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/letter-to-mom-and-dad-i-guess.jpeg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">letter to Mom and dad i guess</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>split identities</title>
		<link>http://mindmelodies.wordpress.com/2012/08/01/split-identities/</link>
		<comments>http://mindmelodies.wordpress.com/2012/08/01/split-identities/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 18:53:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>cc334</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chinese american]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cultural identity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[olympics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mindmelodies.wordpress.com/?p=185</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As I was watching an intense swimming round in the Olympics the other day with my family, my mom suddenly asked me: &#8220;Which country are you rooting for?&#8221; I looked at her, confused for a minute, and replied: &#8220;Uh&#8230;USA of course. Who else?&#8221;  To which she said: &#8220;Oh, what about the Chinese?&#8221; I suppose I shouldn&#8217;t [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=185&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As I was watching an intense swimming round in the Olympics the other day with my family, my mom suddenly asked me: &#8220;Which country are you rooting for?&#8221; I looked at her, confused for a minute, and replied: &#8220;Uh&#8230;USA of course. Who else?&#8221;  To which she said: &#8220;Oh, what about the Chinese?&#8221;</p>
<p>I suppose I shouldn&#8217;t have been surprised that my mom was cheering when the Chinese swimmer won gold, but I never before realized that I have never questioned which country I &#8220;belonged&#8221; to. So easily, I identify as American, although I am of 100% Chinese descent. I mean, I look 100% Chinese, I technically <em>am</em> 100% Chinese, and I check the &#8220;Asian/Pacific Islanders&#8221; box on forms, but I still see myself as an American at heart and in my mindset.  I guess it&#8217;s just another one of those labels with which society tends to organize people; it&#8217;s easier to look than to understand.</p>
<p>While writing this post, I&#8217;ve found it difficult to express this feeling of &#8220;split identities&#8221; (it&#8217;s taken me about 30 minutes just to formulate the last 2 paragraphs), because I don&#8217;t think I quite understand yet. The conversation with my mom somehow inspired me to think about this though, so I&#8217;m just putting out observations and trying to come to as many conclusions as I can. Bear with me. <img src='http://s0.wp.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif' alt=':)' class='wp-smiley' /> </p>
<p>I know that although I see myself as an American through and through, I&#8217;m still quite not sure what that means. What are those fundamental ideals that make me American? We have long celebrated our notions of freedom and equality here in the States, but I think that viewing those values as uniquely &#8220;American&#8221; is a bit outdated by now.  Many other countries have the same luxuries we have, and we must also consider how much &#8220;freedom&#8221; is too much, and when that will begin affecting our social well-being (the classic freedom vs. security issue).  Regardless, I do know that I&#8217;m proud to be both American and Chinese, because I still cherish and keep close my Chinese heritage, yet I feel loyal to my home country. I am certain that my way of looking at life and future experiences will be heavily influenced by my Chinese upbringing though, so being Chinese still plays a huge role in my life.</p>
<p>Another observation I have is that whenever I visit China, I don&#8217;t feel quite at home. And as a child, it used to bother me a lot, because I saw how happy my parents were because it was home to them. And what made it more difficult was that I <em>looked</em> like I should belong.  And now that I think about it, I realize that what defines the US is truly the &#8220;melting pot,&#8221; so to speak. Here, although the majority is still Caucasian, I don&#8217;t feel like misplaced just based on what race I&#8217;m perceived to be.  I don&#8217;t see race as a fundamental difference here, but that may be due to my rather privileged and sheltered upbringing.</p>
<p>And it&#8217;s interesting, because my best friend is half Asian, half Caucasian, but she identifies much more with her Asian side.  I find her philosophies, emotional thinking, even her artwork (she&#8217;s an amazing artist) distinctively belonging to a more eastern culture.  And she says that when she&#8217;s in Taiwan, she feels at home and peaceful, which is starkly different than my experiences.  I&#8217;m not sure why that is, but I feel that both of us are quite lucky to be able to have such a strong sense of self that we&#8217;re able to craft our own &#8220;cultural identity&#8221; by using more than just race as an influence.</p>
<p>- C</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/185/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/185/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=185&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://mindmelodies.wordpress.com/2012/08/01/split-identities/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>20</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/e123f1aefde038cc00789dccdad1738d?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cc334</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Girl Cheese Sammich</title>
		<link>http://makemeasammich.org/2012/07/31/girl-cheese-sammich/</link>
		<comments>http://makemeasammich.org/2012/07/31/girl-cheese-sammich/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2012 17:16:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Rosie</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Introduction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sammiches!]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cheese]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[french fries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grilled cheese]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Long Beach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Los Angeles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[National Grilled Cheese Sandwich Month]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[National Sandwich Month]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pool]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pool shark]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pork rinds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sammiches]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://makemeasammich.org/?p=487</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As we say goodbye to National Grilled Cheese Sandwich month and hello to National Sammich Month, I want to take the opportunity to tell you briefly about my personal relationship with grilled cheese sandwiches. You see, when I was a tiny, little girl&#8230;so tiny that the world was still a place of only beauty and wonder [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=487&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://makemeasammich.org/2012/07/31/girl-cheese-sammich/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>46</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/08d32088b4cbea4649532b22b4e3cef2?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">makemeasammichrosie</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://girlempowered.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/grilledcheesead.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">GrilledCheeseAd</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://girlempowered.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/tinymo.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tinymo</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>We Are Star People!</title>
		<link>http://whybecausescience.wordpress.com/2012/08/01/we-are-star-people/</link>
		<comments>http://whybecausescience.wordpress.com/2012/08/01/we-are-star-people/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 06:53:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Thea Beckman</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Astronomy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chemistry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Physics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science and Society]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Albert Einstein]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[astronomy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Big Bang theory]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[origin of the universe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://whybecausescience.wordpress.com/?p=185</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[No, that is not a Bob Sinclair song. It is a revelation of divine proportions. Only, THIS concept, which is grounded in the soils of the Big Bang Theory, bears more gravity than Creationism. A lot more. What Exactly ARE Stars? Stars are tiny, tiny little fireflies trapped against a velvet blanket of night. Bet [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=185&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>No, that is not a Bob Sinclair song. It is a revelation of divine proportions. Only, THIS concept, which is grounded in the soils of the Big Bang Theory, bears more gravity than Creationism.</p>
<p>A lot more.</p>
<p><strong>What Exactly ARE Stars?</strong></p>
<p><a href="http://whybecausescience.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/orion.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-186" title="We are star people" src="http://whybecausescience.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/orion.jpg" alt="" width="540" height="480" /></a></p>
<p>Stars are tiny, tiny little fireflies trapped against a velvet blanket of night.</p>
<p>Bet they didn’t teach you THAT in AST101!</p>
<p>Let’s humour the astronomers though&#8230; stars are aggregations of mass bound together by gravity. Immense gravity. Let’s take a look at our own Earth. The deeper you dig, the hotter it gets. Why do you think that is? The incredible amount of pressure exerted by the millions upon billions of tonnes of soil, rock and Kim Kardashian’s bum on the Earth’s core have actually rendered it so hot that it has become a giant oozy ball of molten magma.</p>
<p>If the Earth was bigger, MUCH bigger; bigger even than Jupiter, the pressure exerted on the core of the planet would be so immense that it would initiate spontaneous nuclear reactions. Yes: atomic bomb-sized explosions. But instead of the singular blast that wiped out Hiroshima and instantly incinerated 70,000 people, these reactions would be continuous, with the prodigious amounts of heat generated by one nuclear explosion feeding several others in a chain reaction of fire and brimstone that would make Lucifer green with envy.</p>
<div id="attachment_187" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 594px"><a href="http://whybecausescience.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/sol17.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-187" title="The Sun" src="http://whybecausescience.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/sol17.jpg" alt="" width="584" height="389" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text"><em>Image: A sexy close-up of our Sun.</em></p></div>
<p>And this is a star! Stars are giant accumulations of mass, just like a planet really. The key difference is that they are far more massive than planets. And because of the incredible gravity, heat and pressure exerted on the core of the star, it initiates spontaneous and unending nuclear reactions, generating all that delicious light and heat we feel when we walk outside into the sun.</p>
<p><strong>Here’s a fun fact:</strong> While our planet TOTALLY bombed out on its stellar exam, Jupiter only failed by a margin. Jupiter and Saturn, the gas giants in our solar system, could have been stars if they were a little heavier. But alas. Can you imagine though? Three suns? Finland would be stoked!</p>
<p><strong>In the Beginning&#8230;</strong></p>
<p>Alright, so you know what stars are. And that a summer vacation on the Sun wouldn’t be all the tourist brochures paint it to be. But how does this explain where we come from?</p>
<p>When the universe was formed, a couple of seconds after the cataclysmic boom started the ball rolling, there was hydrogen and helium and trace amounts of lithium and beryllium. The first thing you need to know is that protons, which are positively charged particles, occupy mass. So, the more protons an atom has, the heavier it will be.</p>
<p>Hydrogen, with only one proton, is the lightest element in the universe. Helium is the next in line to the throne with only two protons. Lithium is next with three and then beryllium with four protons and so on and so forth. Here, we come full circle. At the formation of the universe, there was hydrogen, helium and trace amounts of lithium and beryllium (and yes, God, there was light. Lots of it.)</p>
<p>But there weren’t any other elements, certainly not the heavier ones we know are necessary for life, like carbon and oxygen. Where did these come from?</p>
<p><strong>Albert Einstein Drops an A-Bomb (Metaphorically Speaking)</strong></p>
<div id="attachment_188" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 594px"><a href="http://whybecausescience.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/h31_01.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-188" title="Hiroshima" src="http://whybecausescience.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/h31_01.jpg" alt="" width="584" height="354" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text"><em>Image: The devastation of Hiroshima after &#8220;Little Boy&#8221;, the atom bomb, was dropped on 6th August 1945.</em></p></div>
<p>On August 6th 1945, a 4,000 kg bomb sadistically dubbed ‘Little Boy’ was dropped on a city in southwest Honshu, Japan. Of the bomb’s 4,000 kg (8,900 lbs) mass, only 64 kg (141 lbs) consisted of uranium, a notoriously radioactive element coveted by numerous comic book villains. But get this&#8230;</p>
<p>Of the 64 kg of uranium, only 0.7 kg (1.5 lbs) actually underwent fission. And of the 700 grams of super critical uranium, only 0.6 grams of matter got converted into pure energy. It was this energy – not ANYTHING ELSE – that instantly disintegrated 70,000 people, flattened the city and, as a result of injury and radiation, claimed a further 70,000 lives.</p>
<p>Think about that: 600 milligrams &#8211; 0.6 grams of matter - when converted directly into energy just about punched a hole in the Earth. How? How it is possible for this tiny amount of mass to liberate enough energy to level an entire city in Japan? And how does this bring us closer to understanding where we come from and that ridiculous tree-hugging heading about being &#8220;star people?!&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>Because E = mc^2. That’s why.</strong></p>
<p><a href="http://whybecausescience.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/einstein-laughing.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-189" title="Albert Einstein laughing" src="http://whybecausescience.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/einstein-laughing.jpg" alt="" width="400" height="240" /></a></p>
<p>It doesn’t take very much matter to create explosions that, even at a distance of 150 million kilometres, could leave you looking like a boiled lobster. Just ask anyone who has ever fallen asleep on a beach before.</p>
<p>Einstein’s famous equation explains this. The mass of matter (m) multiplied by the square of the speed of light (c^2) equals the amount of energy (E) contained by that mass. In the case of the atom bomb that was dropped on Hiroshima almost exactly 67 years ago today, the mass that was converted into energy only weighed 0.6 g. But use Einstein’s equation to calculate the corresponding amount of energy and you’re effectively multiplying this by 90,000,000,000,000,000 m/s (the speed of light squared.)</p>
<p>The answer equals 540,000,000,000,000,000 Joules.</p>
<p>Holy CRAP that’s a lot!</p>
<div id="attachment_191" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 460px"><a href="http://whybecausescience.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/1_-atomic.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-191" title="Atomic bomb explosion" src="http://whybecausescience.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/1_-atomic.jpg" alt="" width="450" height="338" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text"><em>Petrifed broccoli. Or an atomic bomb explosion. I can&#8217;t remember which. What were we talking about again?</em></p></div>
<p>This brings us back to stars. In the very bowels of a star, where these incredible nuclear reactions are taking place, hydrogen atoms are combined to form a single helium atom. But if you look closely at the atomic mass of these elements – their weight really – you’ll see that this equation doesn’t work out precisely. For every four hydrogen atoms mashed together to form one atom of helium, there is tiny amount of excess mass and it is this that gets converted into pure energy via Albert Einstein’s famous equation.</p>
<p>This is the energy that we see as light, feel as heat and, if we were within earshot of a star, would hear as sound too. Unfortunately space is a vacuum and sound doesn’t travel in a vacuum. So there goes that idea.</p>
<p><strong>Honey, We’re Outta Gas!</strong></p>
<p>Forget what happens in a single fusion reaction. Our star, the sun, is a main sequence star (middle-aged) that fuses 620,000,000 metric tonnes of hydrogen EVERY second! The equivalent amount of energy just boggles the mind and the zeros required to write that number down would occupy an entire typed page.</p>
<p>Now what happens? Well, the amount of hydrogen contained in a star is finite. Eventually a star will run out of fuel. Via the hydrogen fusion reactions we discussed, a star accumulates vast oceans of helium throughout its lifetime, which it will start to burn when it runs out of hydrogen. And via the same kind of fusion reaction, the immense heat and pressure in a star will mash together atoms of helium to form heavier elements, such as carbon, oxygen and iron.</p>
<p>Eventually, however, a star will burn out and when it does, it implodes upon itself. Then, depending upon its size, it goes supernova, which is science speak for “shit hitting the fan.” The dying star, in one last melodramatic gesture of sheer awesomeness, explodes outwards, sending a shower of heavy elements into the cosmos.</p>
<div id="attachment_193" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 594px"><a href="http://whybecausescience.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/3cd0a6aa-1af6-43f3-b01e-4f154bb05861_thumb.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-193" title="Super nova explosion" src="http://whybecausescience.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/3cd0a6aa-1af6-43f3-b01e-4f154bb05861_thumb.jpg" alt="" width="584" height="580" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text"><em>Supernova: Ka-BOOM!!</em></p></div>
<p><strong>Class Dismissed: Your Take Home Message</strong></p>
<p>Hydrogen, oxygen, carbon, calcium and magnesium and so on&#8230; these are the elements from which we are made. All of these elements were forged in the hearts of stars over the millennia.</p>
<p>This is why we are star people: literally created from the guts of exploded stars.</p>
<p>Your homework is to watch this video. If it doesn’t make you smile or at least tap your foot, then you were born without a limbic system:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8g4d-rnhuSg&amp;feature=player_embedded">http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8g4d-rnhuSg&amp;feature=player_embedded</a></p>
<p>Now take it away Neil!</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/185/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/185/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=185&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://whybecausescience.wordpress.com/2012/08/01/we-are-star-people/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>24</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/7de46b3fe19d0b58dd627403cd6f5a84?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">theabeckman</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://whybecausescience.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/orion.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">We are star people</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://whybecausescience.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/sol17.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The Sun</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://whybecausescience.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/h31_01.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Hiroshima</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://whybecausescience.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/einstein-laughing.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Albert Einstein laughing</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://whybecausescience.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/1_-atomic.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Atomic bomb explosion</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://whybecausescience.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/3cd0a6aa-1af6-43f3-b01e-4f154bb05861_thumb.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Super nova explosion</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>All about Tears!!!</title>
		<link>http://reflectionslav.wordpress.com/2012/08/01/all-about-tears/</link>
		<comments>http://reflectionslav.wordpress.com/2012/08/01/all-about-tears/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 15:15:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>reflectionslav</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Reflections]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crying]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emotional feelings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emotional tears]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lachrymal glands]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lifestyle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[miscellaneous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[People]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[random]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tears]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://reflectionslav.wordpress.com/?p=1011</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I was reading this touching story from one of the forwarded mails and I suddenly realize that there are tears running down my cheeks. I was telling myself to control… it would be so embarrassing to cry that way in office sitting at my desk. But they don’t stop at all and I had to [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1011&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a title="Visit blogadda.com to discover Indian blogs" href="http://www.blogadda.com"> <img src="http://www.blogadda.com/images/blogadda.png" alt="Visit blogadda.com to discover Indian blogs" width="80" height="15" border="0" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://reflectionslav.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/baby.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-1018" title="baby" src="http://reflectionslav.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/baby.jpg?w=275&h=183" alt="" width="275" height="183" /></a></p>
<p>I was reading this touching story from one of the forwarded mails and I suddenly realize that there are tears running down my cheeks. I was telling myself to control… it would be so embarrassing to cry that way in office sitting at my desk. But they don’t stop at all and I had to run to the washroom to clean my already reddened face.</p>
<p>It happened to me many times, when I really wanted to put a brave face and not cry at all, but my brain and eyes betray me. It was then, I decided to do a bit of research on net, that why some people cry more than others.</p>
<p>Interestingly, the actual reason why tears are more in some people than others is not yet established. Nevertheless, here are my findings :-p</p>
<p>Tears are secretions from the lachrymal glands that clean and lubricate the eyes. The lachrymal glands secrete lachrymal fluid, which flows through the main excretory ducts into the space between the eyeball and lids. When the eyes blink, the lachrymal fluid is spread across the surface of the eye and flows through the lachrymal canaliculi at the inner corner of the eyelids entering finally into the nasal cavity. An excess of tears can thus cause the nose to run.</p>
<p>There are three types of tears –</p>
<p>Basal Tears : normal continuous lachrymal secretions to lubricate the eye and clear it from any dust particles.</p>
<p>Reflex Tears : This is due to the irritation of the eyes due to foreign particles or exposure to irritable agents or during cough/yawning.</p>
<p>Emotional Tears : These are due to strong emotional feelings like stress, anger, fear, sadness, happiness. In humans, emotional tears can be accompanied by reddening of the face and sobbing — cough-like, convulsive breathing, sometimes involving spasms of the whole upper body.</p>
<p>Emotional tears can sometimes be useful to alleviate stress. That is the reason why people cry even when they are alone, when there is no one else to receive the communication. This explains why we feel refreshed after a good cry <img src='http://s0.wp.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif' alt=':)' class='wp-smiley' /> . The hormones released with tears(emotional) have a different chemicals compared to normal basal/reflex tears. They contain leucine encephalin (a natural painkiller) which helps in relieving stress.</p>
<p>There are statements that negate this theory too. However scientists say that there needs to be a strong emotional stimulus for tears to come. Hence they say that the theory about “crocodile tears” (or manipulative crying) is false. It is said that no one can fake crying. They have to conjure strong emotional feelings to produce tears.</p>
<p>Emotional tears are supposedly triggered by nerves running from the limbic system &#8211; the part of the brain that controls emotion &#8211; to the brain stem at the top of the spinal cord, and from there to the lachrymal glands. It makes sense that many brain systems are involved because both laughing and crying require understanding an emotional context. Also with both, a cluster of physiological responses occur: The muscles of the face are engaged, heart and respiration rates rise, even the voice changes tone.</p>
<p>But what sets off those triggers for some people more readily than others is not known yet. Effect of the society and the surroundings however seems to have an effect on it. For example, it is long determined that men are stronger than women and men who cry are treated as weak beings. Hence men are not at liberty to heal their emotional wounds by crying their worries out. It is said that this is the reason why men take a long time to handle stressful situations, as they may need to work very long and hard to access the grief behind anger.</p>
<p>Having said all this, is there a way to control tears? Psychologists say it is best not to control them and let them out. Because it involves a lot of emotional build-up before you actually cry and it may be harmful to your health to resist from letting it out.</p>
<p>Having said that, crying for days together can be harmful too as it has the danger of the person going into depression. In this situation, it is best to divert yourself by keeping your mind busy with some interesting tasks and thinking happy thoughts. It is all about manipulating your brain. Act as if you are happy and your innocent brain believes you <img src='http://s0.wp.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif' alt=':)' class='wp-smiley' /> </p>
<p>Before I end this post, wanted to quote this beautiful statement :</p>
<p>“perhaps our eyes need to be washed by our tears once in a while, so that we can see Life with a clearer view again.”</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1011/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1011/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1011&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://reflectionslav.wordpress.com/2012/08/01/all-about-tears/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>31</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/5fa344071f42978309ba6155a20d13e5?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">reflectionslav</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://www.blogadda.com/images/blogadda.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Visit blogadda.com to discover Indian blogs</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://reflectionslav.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/baby.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">baby</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>it is always the words that undress you</title>
		<link>http://thekingdomofeternalnight.wordpress.com/2012/08/01/it-is-always-the-words-that-undress-you/</link>
		<comments>http://thekingdomofeternalnight.wordpress.com/2012/08/01/it-is-always-the-words-that-undress-you/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 16:27:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Miss Rosen</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Death]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Faith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Inspiration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York State of Mind]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Signs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thoughts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thekingdomofeternalnight.wordpress.com/?p=1747</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1747&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/545617_451331958211914_13574795_n1.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-1802" title="545617_451331958211914_13574795_n" src="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/545617_451331958211914_13574795_n1.jpg?w=438&h=289" alt="" width="438" height="289" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_lkyb4c0zej1qa16ugo1_400.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-1749" title="tumblr_lkyb4c0Zej1qa16ugo1_400" src="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_lkyb4c0zej1qa16ugo1_400.jpg?w=441&h=71" alt="" width="441" height="71" /></a><a href="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_ly7reelmek1rnjqlqo1_1280.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-1753" title="tumblr_ly7reelmeK1rnjqlqo1_1280" src="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_ly7reelmek1rnjqlqo1_1280.jpg?w=434&h=64" alt="" width="434" height="64" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_lqkhu00tlt1qexl81o1_500.png"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-1751" title="tumblr_lqkhu00tLT1qexl81o1_500" src="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_lqkhu00tlt1qexl81o1_500.png?w=429&h=308" alt="" width="429" height="308" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_lw9rs4kjv21qbdm4ko1_500-1.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-1752" title="tumblr_lw9rs4kjV21qbdm4ko1_500-1" src="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_lw9rs4kjv21qbdm4ko1_500-1.jpg?w=435&h=39" alt="" width="435" height="39" /></a><a href="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_m051cks0pc1r0j1wwo1_1280.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-1754" title="tumblr_m051cks0Pc1r0j1wwo1_1280" src="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_m051cks0pc1r0j1wwo1_1280.jpg?w=435&h=52" alt="" width="435" height="52" /></a><a href="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_m2ui0biepl1r0fx0po1_12801.gif"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-1756" title="tumblr_m2ui0bIEPL1r0fx0po1_1280" src="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_m2ui0biepl1r0fx0po1_12801.gif?w=440&h=80" alt="" width="440" height="80" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_m4ag3qxl9n1r4ivkvo1_1280.png"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-1757" title="tumblr_m4ag3qXl9n1r4ivkvo1_1280" src="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_m4ag3qxl9n1r4ivkvo1_1280.png?w=438&h=270" alt="" width="438" height="270" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_m0yl8zskmg1qc2qk9o1_500.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-1758" title="tumblr_m0yl8zskmG1qc2qk9o1_500" src="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_m0yl8zskmg1qc2qk9o1_500.jpg?w=441&h=291" alt="" width="441" height="291" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_m0omcni5m91qm0r99o1_1280.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-1759" title="tumblr_m0omcnI5M91qm0r99o1_1280" src="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_m0omcni5m91qm0r99o1_1280.jpg?w=439&h=68" alt="" width="439" height="68" /></a><a href="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_m0jx4oappr1r2fr72o1_500.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-1760" title="tumblr_m0jx4oAppr1r2fr72o1_500" src="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_m0jx4oappr1r2fr72o1_500.jpg?w=437&h=247" alt="" width="437" height="247" /></a><a href="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_m0lcnrjtot1qbb77eo1_500.png"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-1772" title="tumblr_m0lcnrjTOT1qbb77eo1_500" src="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_m0lcnrjtot1qbb77eo1_500.png?w=429&h=100" alt="" width="429" height="100" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_lykqpjoyp71qdok4ro1_500.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-1761" title="tumblr_lykqpjOYp71qdok4ro1_500" src="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_lykqpjoyp71qdok4ro1_500.jpg?w=435&h=84" alt="" width="435" height="84" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_lyokbehxfs1qdxmsmo1_500.png"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-1764" title="tumblr_lyokbehxFs1qdxmsmo1_500" src="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_lyokbehxfs1qdxmsmo1_500.png?w=419&h=293" alt="" width="419" height="293" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_m2nc43fynz1r0fx0po1_1280.gif"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-1770" title="tumblr_m2nc43FYnZ1r0fx0po1_1280" src="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_m2nc43fynz1r0fx0po1_1280.gif?w=417&h=75" alt="" width="417" height="75" /></a><a href="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_m2i6zu5wo21r0fx0po1_500.gif"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-1769" title="tumblr_m2i6zu5Wo21r0fx0po1_500" src="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_m2i6zu5wo21r0fx0po1_500.gif?w=420&h=38" alt="" width="420" height="38" /></a><a href="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_lzg6v7lfxe1qm0r99.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-1777" title="tumblr_lzg6v7lFXe1qm0r99" src="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_lzg6v7lfxe1qm0r99.jpg?w=420&h=46" alt="" width="420" height="46" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_m15yyz6mv11r3j7kto1_500.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-1775" title="tumblr_m15yyz6MV11r3j7kto1_500" src="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_m15yyz6mv11r3j7kto1_500.jpg?w=418&h=277" alt="" width="418" height="277" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_m0zw8c6i801qi5ntfo1_500.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-1778" title="tumblr_m0zw8c6i801qi5ntfo1_500" src="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_m0zw8c6i801qi5ntfo1_500.jpg?w=425&h=618" alt="" width="425" height="618" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_lxi2dshjm41qz6f9yo1_500.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-1784" title="tumblr_lxi2dshJM41qz6f9yo1_500" src="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_lxi2dshjm41qz6f9yo1_500.jpg?w=417&h=294" alt="" width="417" height="294" /></a><a href="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_lwuve110yp1r09idxo1_500.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-1783" title="tumblr_lwuve110yp1r09idxo1_500" src="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_lwuve110yp1r09idxo1_500.jpg?w=420&h=61" alt="" width="420" height="61" /></a><a href="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_lxi0hlls071r0fx0po1_500.png"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-1780" title="tumblr_lxi0hlls071r0fx0po1_500" src="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_lxi0hlls071r0fx0po1_500.png?w=421&h=82" alt="" width="421" height="82" /></a><a href="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_lyirhxmpv21qm0r99o1_500.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-1785" title="tumblr_lyirhxmpv21qm0r99o1_500" src="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_lyirhxmpv21qm0r99o1_500.jpg?w=419&h=54" alt="" width="419" height="54" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_m3m8ffei3b1qd1ycjo1_5001.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-1794" title="tumblr_m3m8ffei3b1qd1ycjo1_500" src="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_m3m8ffei3b1qd1ycjo1_5001.jpg?w=418&h=398" alt="" width="418" height="398" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_lv0zp9h0t21qie3w6o1_500.png"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-1781" title="tumblr_lv0zp9h0t21qie3w6o1_500" src="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_lv0zp9h0t21qie3w6o1_500.png?w=421&h=43" alt="" width="421" height="43" /></a></p>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1747&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thekingdomofeternalnight.wordpress.com/2012/08/01/it-is-always-the-words-that-undress-you/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>54</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/1f53642e5938826c9506f069eb86d54d?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">missrosen</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/545617_451331958211914_13574795_n1.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">545617_451331958211914_13574795_n</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_lkyb4c0zej1qa16ugo1_400.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tumblr_lkyb4c0Zej1qa16ugo1_400</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_ly7reelmek1rnjqlqo1_1280.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tumblr_ly7reelmeK1rnjqlqo1_1280</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_lqkhu00tlt1qexl81o1_500.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tumblr_lqkhu00tLT1qexl81o1_500</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_lw9rs4kjv21qbdm4ko1_500-1.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tumblr_lw9rs4kjV21qbdm4ko1_500-1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_m051cks0pc1r0j1wwo1_1280.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tumblr_m051cks0Pc1r0j1wwo1_1280</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_m2ui0biepl1r0fx0po1_12801.gif?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tumblr_m2ui0bIEPL1r0fx0po1_1280</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_m4ag3qxl9n1r4ivkvo1_1280.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tumblr_m4ag3qXl9n1r4ivkvo1_1280</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_m0yl8zskmg1qc2qk9o1_500.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tumblr_m0yl8zskmG1qc2qk9o1_500</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_m0omcni5m91qm0r99o1_1280.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tumblr_m0omcnI5M91qm0r99o1_1280</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_m0jx4oappr1r2fr72o1_500.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tumblr_m0jx4oAppr1r2fr72o1_500</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_m0lcnrjtot1qbb77eo1_500.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tumblr_m0lcnrjTOT1qbb77eo1_500</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_lykqpjoyp71qdok4ro1_500.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tumblr_lykqpjOYp71qdok4ro1_500</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_lyokbehxfs1qdxmsmo1_500.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tumblr_lyokbehxFs1qdxmsmo1_500</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_m2nc43fynz1r0fx0po1_1280.gif?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tumblr_m2nc43FYnZ1r0fx0po1_1280</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_m2i6zu5wo21r0fx0po1_500.gif?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tumblr_m2i6zu5Wo21r0fx0po1_500</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_lzg6v7lfxe1qm0r99.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tumblr_lzg6v7lFXe1qm0r99</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_m15yyz6mv11r3j7kto1_500.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tumblr_m15yyz6MV11r3j7kto1_500</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_m0zw8c6i801qi5ntfo1_500.jpg?w=206" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tumblr_m0zw8c6i801qi5ntfo1_500</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_lxi2dshjm41qz6f9yo1_500.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tumblr_lxi2dshJM41qz6f9yo1_500</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_lwuve110yp1r09idxo1_500.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tumblr_lwuve110yp1r09idxo1_500</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_lxi0hlls071r0fx0po1_500.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tumblr_lxi0hlls071r0fx0po1_500</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_lyirhxmpv21qm0r99o1_500.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tumblr_lyirhxmpv21qm0r99o1_500</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_m3m8ffei3b1qd1ycjo1_5001.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tumblr_m3m8ffei3b1qd1ycjo1_500</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thekingdomofeternalnight.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tumblr_lv0zp9h0t21qie3w6o1_500.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tumblr_lv0zp9h0t21qie3w6o1_500</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bailey&#8217;s &amp; White Chocolate Truffles</title>
		<link>http://piewithsparkles.wordpress.com/2012/08/01/baileys-white-chocolate-truffles/</link>
		<comments>http://piewithsparkles.wordpress.com/2012/08/01/baileys-white-chocolate-truffles/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 17:15:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Emily</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Candy/Chocolate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bailey's]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[baking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chocolate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[truffles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[white chocolate]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://piewithsparkles.wordpress.com/?p=1461</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This post is the second of two about truffles. Like I said in last week&#8217;s post, I first started experimenting with truffles for a New Year’s Eve party, where my theme was decadence. Not many things resonate decadence to me as much as truffles. Besides the Dark Chocolate Raspberry Truffles, my other go-to truffle is the [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1461&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This post is the second of two about truffles. Like I said in last week&#8217;s post, I first started experimenting with truffles for a New Year’s Eve party, where my theme was decadence. Not many things resonate decadence to me as much as truffles. Besides the <a title="Dark Chocolate Raspberry Truffles" href="http://piewithsparkles.wordpress.com/2012/07/27/dark-chocolate-raspberry-truffles/">Dark Chocolate Raspberry Truffles</a>, my other go-to truffle is the Bailey&#8217;s and White Chocolate Truffle, another recipe adapted from the Barefoot Contessa.</p>
<p>These truffles are slightly more complicated than the chocolate ones and will require a bit more patience and effort. But, like anything I do, the result is totally worth the effort! The truffles start with a very basic high-quality white chocolate (purchase the best you can find because the quality <em>will</em> make a difference), infused with a good amount of Bailey&#8217;s Irish Cream Liqueur, and coated with a thin layer of dark chocolate. The result is a firm chocolate shell that, when cracked open, reveals a rich and creamy white chocolate center with a good punch of Bailey&#8217;s.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://piewithsparkles.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/487114_10101679247830818_842913741_n.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1499" title="Bailey's &amp; White Chocolate Truffles" src="http://piewithsparkles.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/487114_10101679247830818_842913741_n.jpg" alt="" width="540" height="540" /></a></p>
<p>Click below for the recipe! Have a question? Feel free to ask in the comments below! And thanks for reading! <img src="http://s0.wp.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif?m=1129645325g" alt=":)" /></p>
<p><span style="text-decoration:underline;"><strong>UPDATE</strong></span><strong>: </strong>This post was chosen by WordPress to be featured today on their &#8216;Freshly Pressed&#8217; page, where they highlight the &#8220;best&#8221; of the day&#8217;s blog posts and bloggers. This has led to a <em>huge</em> spike in blog traffic, as well as likes, comments, and new followers! I am humbled and extremely grateful for the attention and recognition. I write this, slightly in shock of how much positive feedback I&#8217;m receiving&#8230; Thank you all SO MUCH!! And please, keep following the blog. I have a ton of new things coming down the pipeline, including a simple rhubarb crisp, whiskey caramel sauce, and lychee ice cream. Thanks again for reading and sharing in my love of baking! <img src='http://s0.wp.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif' alt=':D' class='wp-smiley' /> </p>
<p><span id="more-1461"></span></p>
<p><span style="text-decoration:underline;"><strong>Bailey’s White Chocolate Truffles</strong></span></p>
<p>Yield: 25 truffles</p>
<p>Begin by assembling your ingredients.</p>
<p><a href="http://piewithsparkles.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/img_4363.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1462" title="Bailey's &amp; White Chocolate Truffles ingredients" src="http://piewithsparkles.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/img_4363.jpg" alt="" width="540" height="405" /></a></p>
<p>You are going to need:</p>
<ul>
<li>1 pound (16 ounces) good-quality white chocolate (like Ghirardelli, Lindt, etc.)</li>
<li>8 ounces bittersweet chocolate or other dark chocolate (around 60% cacao)</li>
<li>1/4 cup heavy cream</li>
<li>1/4 cup Irish cream liqueur, such as Bailey’s</li>
<li>1 teaspoon vanilla</li>
</ul>
<p>You are also going to need:</p>
<ul>
<li>Double boiler or heat-proof bowl set over simmering water</li>
<li>Whisk</li>
<li>Cookie sheet lined with wax paper or parchment paper</li>
<li>Cookie scoop</li>
<li>Chocolate-dipping tool, such as <a href="http://www.wilton.com/store/site/product.cfm?id=FC217680-0A2F-8907-7779D5292CE56626&amp;fid=D2EB979F-AC4A-8D89-B342AEC8C5748221">these</a> (particularly the &#8220;fork&#8221; tool)</li>
</ul>
<p>First, roughly cut or break up the white chocolate in to a double boiler. Over simmering, not boiling water, melt the chocolate.</p>
<p><a href="http://piewithsparkles.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/img_4365.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1463" title="Melt white chocolate" src="http://piewithsparkles.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/img_4365.jpg" alt="" width="540" height="405" /></a></p>
<p>Once melted, add the heavy cream, liqueur, and vanilla. Stir to combine.</p>
<p><a href="http://piewithsparkles.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/img_4368.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1465" title="Melted chocolate mixture" src="http://piewithsparkles.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/img_4368.jpg" alt="" width="540" height="405" /></a></p>
<p>Remove the chocolate mixture from the heat. Let cool slightly, and then cover and refrigerate overnight.</p>
<p><a href="http://piewithsparkles.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/img_4369.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1466" title="Let truffle mixture cool" src="http://piewithsparkles.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/img_4369.jpg" alt="" width="540" height="405" /></a></p>
<p>The next day, remove the chocolate from the refrigerator. In a double boiler over simmering water, melt the bittersweet chocolate. Be careful not to overheat, or else the chocolate will seize and be unusable.</p>
<p><a href="http://piewithsparkles.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/img_4422-e1343840234373.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1469" title="Melted chocolate coating" src="http://piewithsparkles.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/img_4422-e1343840234373.jpg" alt="" width="540" height="405" /></a></p>
<p>Once the chocolate is melted, remove it from the heat.</p>
<p>Use the cookie scoop to portion out scoops of the white chocolate. Roll in to small balls, and place on a cookie sheet lined with wax paper or parchment paper. (This is the step where you want your chocolate to be pretty cold. The heat from your hands will melt the chocolate, and a solid ball will not form if the chocolate is too warm.)</p>
<p><a href="http://piewithsparkles.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/img_4421.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1468" title="Rolled truffles" src="http://piewithsparkles.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/img_4421.jpg" alt="" width="540" height="405" /></a></p>
<p>Place the cookie sheet in the freezer for approximately 15 minutes to make sure the truffles are fully cold.</p>
<p>Remove the truffles from the freezer. Using the chocolate dipping tool, coat the truffles in a layer of the melted bittersweet chocolate. Place the coated truffles on the cookie sheet.</p>
<p><a href="http://piewithsparkles.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/img_4423.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1470" title="Chocolate coating" src="http://piewithsparkles.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/img_4423.jpg" alt="" width="540" height="405" /></a></p>
<p>Return the cookie sheet to the freezer for approximately 15 minutes to harden the chocolate coating.</p>
<p><a href="http://piewithsparkles.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/img_4426.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1471" title="Chocolate coated truffles" src="http://piewithsparkles.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/img_4426.jpg" alt="" width="540" height="405" /></a></p>
<p>To store, place the truffles in an airtight container. Keep in the refrigerator for up to one week. Remove from the refrigerator and let warm to room temperature before serving.</p>
<p>Enjoy! <img src='http://s0.wp.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif' alt=':D' class='wp-smiley' /> </p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1461/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1461/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1461&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://piewithsparkles.wordpress.com/2012/08/01/baileys-white-chocolate-truffles/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>46</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/4679ee984c41ef119e21df612c28c82a?s=96&#38;d=retro&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">piewithsparkles</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://piewithsparkles.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/487114_10101679247830818_842913741_n.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Bailey&#039;s &#38; White Chocolate Truffles</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://s0.wp.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif?m=1129645325g" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">:)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://piewithsparkles.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/img_4363.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Bailey&#039;s &#38; White Chocolate Truffles ingredients</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://piewithsparkles.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/img_4365.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Melt white chocolate</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://piewithsparkles.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/img_4368.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Melted chocolate mixture</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://piewithsparkles.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/img_4369.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Let truffle mixture cool</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://piewithsparkles.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/img_4422-e1343840234373.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Melted chocolate coating</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://piewithsparkles.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/img_4421.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Rolled truffles</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://piewithsparkles.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/img_4423.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Chocolate coating</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://piewithsparkles.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/img_4426.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Chocolate coated truffles</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>