<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 22:13:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>In-N-Out Merger</title>
		<link>http://thenewprint.com/2013/03/14/in-n-out-merger/</link>
		<comments>http://thenewprint.com/2013/03/14/in-n-out-merger/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2013 21:58:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>SlickRickSchwartz</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ideology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Minding the Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[perception]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[privacy]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thenewprint.com/?p=2676</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Does it feel like things are finally starting to turn a corner when it comes to online data privacy? It seems like a lot more people are starting to care about privacy, at least as an issue, if not as a personal ethic. Sure, some people are starting to use Facebook&#8217;s privacy settings, but because [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2676&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Does it feel like things are finally starting to turn a corner when it comes to online data privacy? It seems like a lot more people are starting to care about privacy, at least as an issue, if not as a personal ethic. Sure, some <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/larry-magid/facebook-users-becoming-m_b_1299643.html">people are starting to use Facebook&#8217;s privacy settings</a>, but because <a href="http://bits.blogs.nytimes.com/2012/12/12/facebook-changes-privacy-settings-again/">those things change all the damn time</a>, it&#8217;s hard to tell whether that will make much of a lasting difference.</p>
<div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/larry-magid/facebook-users-becoming-m_b_1299643.html"><img alt="" src="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2012-02-24-pew.jpg" width="500" height="289" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Percent of social networking users who have taken these steps to protect their privacy (Source: Pew Internet &amp; American Life Project)</p></div>
<div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 532px"><a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/larry-magid/facebook-users-becoming-m_b_1299643.html"><img class=" " alt="" src="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2012-02-24-priv2.jpg" width="522" height="240" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Privacy settings: Teens Vs. Adults (Source: Pew Internet &amp; American Life Project)</p></div>
<p>I&#8217;m also not convinced that people are seeing the writing on the wall when it comes to online privacy or the retention of their own civil liberties. People have never seemed to care that <a href="http://www.propublica.org/article/everything-we-know-about-what-data-brokers-know-about-you">data is used to sell them stuff they &#8220;already want,&#8221; or that current and prospective health insurers are getting all sorts of data on what you Google</a>. Nor do they care that their reading list&#8211;something the Founders would have considered sacrosanct&#8211;has been accessible by government since the PATRIOT ACT.</p>
<blockquote>
<blockquote><p>Want to buy a list of people who <a href="http://lists.epsilon.com/market?page=research/datacard&amp;id=313339">read romance novels</a>? <a href="http://www.epsilon.com/pdf/TotalSourcePlus_Overview_0211.pdf">Epsilon</a> can sell you that, as well as a list of people who donate to <a href="http://lists.epsilon.com/market?page=research/datacard&amp;id=259613">international aid charities</a>. &#8230;</p>
<p>A subsidiary of credit reporting company Equifax even <a href="http://redtape.nbcnews.com/_news/2013/01/30/16762661-exclusive-your-employer-may-share-your-salary-and-equifax-might-sell-that-data?lite">collects detailed salary and paystub information</a> for roughly <a href="http://www.theworknumber.com/Employees/Why/index.asp">38 percent</a> of employed Americans. &#8230;</p>
<p>Datalogix &#8230; which collects information from <a href="http://www.ft.com/intl/cms/s/0/6cc4cf0a-0584-11e2-9ebd-00144feabdc0.html#axzz2M3rUaJjK">store loyalty cards</a>, says it has information on more than $1 trillion in consumer spending &#8220;<a href="http://www.datalogix.com/industries/retail/">across 1400+ leading brands</a>.&#8221; It doesn&#8217;t say which ones. &#8230;</p>
<p>Data companies can capture information about your &#8220;interests&#8221; in certain health conditions based on what you buy — or what you search for online. Datalogix has lists of people classified as <a href="http://www.datalogix.com/health-related-segments/">&#8220;allergy sufferers&#8221; and &#8220;dieters.&#8221;</a> Acxiom sells data on whether an individual has an &#8220;online search propensity&#8221; for a certain &#8220;ailment or prescription.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
</blockquote>
<p>People don&#8217;t seem to care about whether their information is up for grabs because they don&#8217;t understand how easily comprehended and quantified they are. Everyone thinks he or she is immune from easy prediction, but with the rise of big data, prediction is getting scarily smart. For example, <a href="https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2013/03/facebook-likes-reveal-sensitive-personal-information">analyzing Facebook &#8220;likes&#8221; is enough to predict a lot about your personality</a> that you probably wouldn&#8217;t tell a stranger, let alone some amoral marketing firm trying to figure out ways to extract money from you.</p>
<blockquote><p>The researchers used a pool of 58,000 volunteers in the United States. Based on “Likes” alone, they were able to predict whether a user was African-American or white 95% of the time, male or female 93% of the time.</p>
<p>They were able to gauge sexual orientation 88% of the time for men and 75% of the time for women. They were also able to predict political leaning (Republican versus Democrat) 85% of the time. On a more personal level, the researchers were able to predict whether your parents divorced when you were a kid 60% of the time.</p>
<p>The study also could make reasonably accurate guesses about whether you were a drug user, drinker, or smoker, as well as a host of other attributes, including emotional stability, satisfaction with life, and extraversion.</p></blockquote>
<p>And in many cases, it&#8217;s not even a question of prediction; it&#8217;s simply data analysis because people live enough of their lives on the web for there to be sufficient data to determine all of those characteristics.</p>
<p>On a small side note, this <em>attitude</em> has had serious implications. Except for Rand Paul and a few others who have been written off as right-wing loonies (and not without some justification), no one really seems to be talking about the near-omnipotence of government vis-a-viz individual civil liberties and freedom from <em>state</em> monitoring, as long as lip service is paid to the correct constitutional priority. Didn&#8217;t liberals care about civil liberties at some point? Wouldn&#8217;t they be crowing about the horrendous abuse of executive power if Bush was still in office, <a href="http://www.motherjones.com/politics/2013/03/drones-explained">authorizing drone strikes</a> or signing off on memos that allow for unilateral targeting and assassination of <a href="http://www.motherjones.com/mojo/2013/03/obama-admin-says-it-can-use-lethal-force-against-americans-us-soil">anyone it designates an enemy combatant</a>? People have been placated in this permanent surveillance state by having Obama institutionalize the violations that began under Bush. In that way, greater damage has been done to civil liberties in the failure to restore them than the initial infringement could ever do.</p>
<p>Government&#8217;s hunger for data also fuels its passive allowance of private companies to do its collection and data mining for it. Sure, government is constrained by the Fourth Amendment, but Facebook, Google, Apple, and the like aren&#8217;t. And <a href="http://www.sfgate.com/technology/article/Subpoenas-of-Google-show-law-s-failings-4222199.php">they do respond to subpoenas</a>.</p>
<blockquote><p>Other than certain kinds of protected data — including medical records and data used for credit reports — consumers have no legal right to control or even monitor how information about them is bought and sold. As the FTC notes, &#8220;There are <a href="http://www.ftc.gov/opa/2012/12/databrokers.shtm">no current laws</a> requiring data brokers to maintain the privacy of consumer data unless they use that data for credit, employment, insurance, housing, or other similar purposes.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>In terms of online privacy, though, I think it&#8217;s that people are starting to get <em>possessive</em> about their data, and it&#8217;s because it&#8217;s becoming increasingly easy to care about privacy as it is to not care about it. Of course, the additional effort means that most people will stay in-by-default than opted-out. But there are ways to start to default to an opt-out. For example, there are <a href="http://www.cnn.com/2013/02/28/tech/web/online-privacy-policies">user-side solutions</a> like &#8220;<a href="https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2011/01/mozilla-leads-the-way-on-do-not-track">Do Not Track</a>&#8220;:</p>
<blockquote><p>The customer demand for stronger data controls led to the introduction of the &#8220;do not track&#8221; feature. &#8220;Do not track&#8221; is a setting that can be now found on all the major browsers: Firefox, Internet Explorer, Chrome and Safari. When turned on, it asks sites not to track that person&#8217;s online activities. A Microsoft survey found that 75% of people were concerned about online tracking and thought the setting should be turned on by default.</p></blockquote>
<p>And then, there are the more <a href="https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2013/02/howto-opt-out-databrokers-showing-your-targeted-advertisements-facebook">forcible opt-out solutions</a>, that can opt-out your data from being further used and abused. Sure, it&#8217;s more effort, but those who care enough can take the steps to opt-out. That scheme stands in stark contrast to the state of civil liberties, where an opt-out gives rise to automatic suspicion.</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://thenewprint.com/category/ideology/'>Ideology</a>, <a href='http://thenewprint.com/category/minding-the-media/'>Minding the Media</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2676/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2676/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2676&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thenewprint.com/2013/03/14/in-n-out-merger/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f6e691415a5a38f5194c9480fe3dd8e1?s=96&#38;d=&#38;r=X" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">slickricks</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2012-02-24-pew.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://images.huffingtonpost.com/2012-02-24-priv2.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Drake &#8211; The Voice of a Generation</title>
		<link>http://onthepursuitofawesomeness.wordpress.com/2013/03/06/drake-the-voice-of-a-generation/</link>
		<comments>http://onthepursuitofawesomeness.wordpress.com/2013/03/06/drake-the-voice-of-a-generation/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2013 12:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>gmass927</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[essay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[generation y]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hip hop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[longreads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[millennial generation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[millennials]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rap]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onthepursuitofawesomeness.wordpress.com/?p=24</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve always thought of Jay-Z as this generation’s Frank Sinatra.  It&#8217;s an easy connection to make.  He’s the biggest recording artist in the world.  He has his own Rat Pack (Roc-a-Fella).  He’s widely regarded as one of the coolest people on Earth.  He has his own New York City anthem.  He makes no bones about being tied [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=24&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;"><img class="aligncenter" alt="" src="http://www.dose.ca/5713466.bin?size=dose462" width="627" height="462" /></p>
<p>I&#8217;ve always thought of Jay-Z as this generation’s Frank Sinatra.  It&#8217;s an easy connection to make.  He’s the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Billboard_200#Most_number-one_albums.5B8.5D" target="_blank">biggest recording artist in the world</a>.  He has his own Rat Pack (Roc-a-Fella).  He’s widely regarded as one of the coolest people on Earth.  He has his own <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0UjsXo9l6I8" target="_blank">New York City anthem</a>.  He makes no bones about being tied to organized crime.   Jay-Z, himself, even makes the comparisons quite often (DOA, Empire State of Mind, Pray, Threat, Hola Hovito).</p>
<p>But, while they have numerous similarities, Jay-Z is not this generation&#8217;s Frank Sinatra.  I once heard a music critic say, (and I’m paraphrasing here because I can’t remember exactly how he put it) what made Frank Sinatra so unique was his ability to speak for an entire generation and to concisely sum up what that generation was feeling and going through at the time.  That’s where Jay and Frank diverge.  Jay-Z doesn&#8217;t speak for the masses.  Early Jay may have spoken for a small part of the population growing up in the projects during the reign of Reaganomics (see: Reasonable Doubt – Vol 3), but a more recent Jay is absolutely unrelatable (see: any verse on Watch the Throne).  Now this doesn&#8217;t necessarily make his music any less enjoyable, but it does disqualify him from the “voice of a generation” conversation.</p>
<p>The voice of this generation – the Millennial Generation – is Drake.  And yes, I am serious.</p>
<p>I know that sounds silly.  I know he’s not the most skilled rapper.  I know he has a whiny, somewhat irritating, voice.  I know he wears goofy sweaters.  I know liking Drake hasn&#8217;t been cool in two years.  I know he’s a cornball.  I know he&#8217;s 26 and still stuck in a hookah phase (<em>sooo</em> High School).  And I know a lot of people will dismiss this as me just being a Drake fanboy, but despite all that being true, he’s still the voice of a generation.</p>
<p><i>Take Care</i> came out 16 months ago.  It’s still on Spotify’s top ten most listened to albums (only two non-2012 albums are in the top 15).  Considering that a super majority of Spotify users fall into the Millennial Generation, this is significant.</p>
<p><em>“Do you think we choose the times into which we are born? Or do we fit the times we are born into?”</em> That’s a line from <i>Lincoln </i>(the movie).  But it also uniquely fits the Drake motif.  The Millennial Generation (Drake included) grew up with AOL, ditched their walkmans for iPods and pioneered social networking.  Napster popularized the <del>illegal</del> free mp3 in 1999.  Apple released the first iPod in 2001.  Today, CDs are irrelevant and free music (legally or illegally) litters the internet.  Without these innovations (or as record companies might call them, “disruptions”) Drake could not exist.</p>
<p>In January 2006, Drake was not Drake.  Drake was Aubrey Graham.  And Aubrey Graham was Jimmy from Degrassi (a wheelchair bound high schooler in a sappy Canadian teen soap opera).  In February 2006, Aubrey Graham released <i>Room for Improvement,</i> a <i>free</i> mixtape distributed through the <i>internet.  </i>Drake was born.  He wasn&#8217;t the Drake we know now, he didn&#8217;t sing and he kind of came off as a Pharrell/Lupe wannabe.  The industry ignored it.  In 2007, he released <i>Comeback Season, </i>again a free mixtape distributed through the internet.  Still raw, he started showing glimpses of what he would become.  His popularity grew and thanks in large part to an internet fan base, he became the first unsigned Canadian rapper to have a music video featured on BET.  The underground hype was swelling and the industry started paying attention, including, the most popular rapper in the game circa 2008, Lil’ Wayne.  Then in 2009 Drake exploded.  Still unsigned, Drake released <i>So Far Gone, </i>another free mixtape distributed through the internet.  And right around then, Drake became the voice of a Generation.  A bidding war ensued, Wayne signed him to Young Money and now it’s an industry necessity that any rap album released needs an obligatory Drake feature if the artist owns any desires of commercial viability.</p>
<p>A half white, middle class, Jewish, former child star from the suburbs of Canada with not a shred of street-cred became the biggest name in rap.  Let that marinate for a second.  In no other generation could this have been possible.  Imagine, if you will, that it’s 1994 and Eddie from Family Matters is Jewish and Canadian <i>and</i> a rapper.  Is there any possible scenario you can conceive where Suge Knight signs him to Death Row or Puffy signs him to Bad Boy?  And before you bring up Will Smith, remember, he was an established rapper before <i>The Fresh Prince of Bel-Air</i>.  The only reason Drake’s accession is possible is because of the generation we live in.  Drake ignored the record labels and their “rules” and spoke directly to a generation (thanks to the internet this was possible) and his fellow Millennials responded, forcing an industry obsessed with gangster mentalities to throw out its conventions and glom to a cornball from Canada.</p>
<p><em>“That&#8217;s because we&#8217;re uncool. And while women will always be a problem for us, most of the great art in the world is about that very same problem. Good-looking people don&#8217;t have any spine<span style="color:#ff0000;">¹</span>.  Their art never lasts. They get the girls, but we&#8217;re smarter … Yeah, great art is about conflict and pain and guilt and longing and love disguised as sex, and sex disguised as love&#8230; and let&#8217;s face it, you got a big head start.” </em> That’s a line from <i>Almost Famous</i> and it describes a massive part of Drake’s appeal.  I&#8217;ve been to a Drake concert, I&#8217;ve talked to Drake fans and believe me not even the most hardened Drake fans think Drake is cool.  He’s uncool.  He <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mlr2xjSRxMA" target="_blank">falls on stage</a>.  His fashion sense is best described as <a href="http://www.nypost.com/rw/nypost/2012/04/24/pulse/web_photos/drake--300x300.jpg">tacky</a>.  And he probably cries during sex.  Don’t be fooled by the fact that he somehow tricked Rihanna into sleeping with him.  That was an anomaly.  Listen to any Drake album, they’re filled with these “love disguised as sex, and sex disguised as love” themes.  Alishia, Bria, Nebby, Jade, Cece, Maliah, Rihanna, and a million unnamed strippers all broke Drake’s heart or he broke theirs or “he fucked her once and never fucked again” (but then got into a Champagne bottle throwing fight over her (?)).</p>
<p>We live in what’s been called “<a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/01/13/fashion/the-end-of-courtship.html?_r=0&amp;adxnnl=1&amp;pagewanted=all&amp;adxnnlx=1362253824-wBA5pmc49xBHSmGvUvB+7w" target="_blank">the hook up generation</a>.”  The NY Times describes it as the “rise of the ‘hookup culture’ among young people, characterized by spontaneous, commitment-free (and often, alcohol-fueled) romantic flings.”  No one speaks to this generation more than Drake.  He scatters bars like, “We live in a generation of not being in love, and not being together,” “I can tell it wasn’t love, I just thought you’d fuck with me,” or “I won’t say no names, after a while they all seem the same.”  Lines that reveal his knowledge of the reality he lives, the realty any twenty-something lives in, the acceptance of sex without love, but none of these lines come off as loose boasts about sleeping with as many women as possible like other rappers, there’s more depth to them.  There is always a sub context in these verses.  That something is missing from these random hook ups, an emptiness, a longing, that while it may be fun, sex cannot replace love.</p>
<p>The twenty something generation lives in a Facebook world.  We&#8217;ve even been called a generation of &#8220;<a href="http://www.foxnews.com/opinion/2013/01/08/are-raising-generation-deluded-narcissists/" target="_blank">deluded narcissists</a>.&#8221;  We post pictures of our late night exploits on Instagram, broadcast all our achievements and boast on Twitter, shout out friends and take veiled shots at exes on Facebook and complain about the hardships of growing up on our blogs.  Our online avatars quite literally mirror a Drake album.  While there is no stat for it, I am willing to bet Drake is the most quoted artist on Facebook or Twitter.  Hell, #YOLO became a national epidemic.  The first bars of “Up All Night” are effectively Instagram imagery.  He’s constantly representing his “team” on tracks like “Crew Love” and “Show Me a Good Time.”  His verse on “No Lie” is a not-so veiled shot at Rihanna.  And nearly half of all his material is laced with complaints on his emerging fame and responsibilities (see: The Ride).  Last month Drake released the first single off his new album and I fully expect 21 year old college seniors everywhere to proudly exclaim, without a hint of irony, that, “they started from the bottom now they’re here” when they graduate in May, get a $15/hr job as a receptionist and move into their cramped Washington Heights apartment.  Drake has become the mouth piece of a world that strives to communicate in 140 characters or less.</p>
<p>One of the biggest stories from the 2012 Presidential Election was the changing demographics of America.  The pundits have dubbed it, the &#8220;<a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/11/06/barack-obama-reelection_n_2085819.html" target="_blank">rise of a New America</a>.”  America has become more diverse.  Browner.  Younger.  More tolerant.  Fragmented.  As a half white, half black, Jewish, quasi-feminine rapper who grew up in Canada, spent his summers in Memphis and enjoys hanging out with Lil’ Wayne and Justin Bieber in his free time, I doubt Drake will ever experience a Lena Dunham<span style="color:#ff0000;">²</span> “&#8230; but it doesn&#8217;t represent me” type backlash.    While not a U.S. citizen, his mish-mash of backgrounds perfectly represents the “New America.”  Drake is oddly like no one else and everyone else at the same time.</p>
<p>Now, in a few years I may look back at this and shake my head. Drake may be dismissed as a fad like the pet rock or Jnco jeans, because in hip-hop you need at least one &#8220;classic&#8221; album on your résumé to be deemed great.  And Drake doesn&#8217;t have one<span style="color:#ff0000;">³</span>.  Without a classic album, rappers are cast aside with the likes of Nelly or Ja Rule as just a weird phase rap went through way back when<span style="color:#ff0000;"><sup>4</sup></span>.  Most rappers’ &#8220;classic&#8221; albums are their first, think <i>Illmatic, Reasonable Doubt, Doggystyle</i>.  Some come later, most notably the <i>Marshall Mather LP</i>, but they all have at least one.  I could argue that <i>So Far Gone</i> <em><strong>would have</strong></em> been a classic album, if it <em><strong>would have</strong></em> been an album instead of a mixtape, but, then again, the Queen of England<strong><em> would have</em></strong> been the King if she <b><i>would have</i></b> been born with balls.  The point is, &#8220;would&#8217;ves&#8221; don&#8217;t count.</p>
<p>The Greatest Generation lived through the Great Depression, won WWII and built America into a super power.  They got Frank.  The Baby Boomers protested Vietnam, fought for civil rights and changed the world.  They got Dylan.  Generation X wore a ton of flannel   They got Kurt.  And us &#8211; we got Drake.  Deal with it.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">****************************************************************************************</p>
<h5><em><span style="color:#ff0000;"><sup>1</sup></span> (cough-Chris Brown-cough)<br />
</em><em><span style="color:#ff0000;"><sup>2</sup></span> She&#8217;s also in the “voice of a generation” conversation.</em><br />
<em><span style="color:#ff0000;"><sup>3</sup></span> And if <a href="http://pitchfork.com/news/49550-theres-a-drakeriff-raff-collaboration-on-the-way/" target="_blank">this</a> pans out, &#8220;Nothing was the Same&#8221; won’t be either.</em><br />
<em><span style="color:#ff0000;"><sup>4  </sup></span>No matter what people say, &#8220;The Carter 3&#8243; is not a classic.   And Lil’ Wayne has already began his descension into Ja and Cornell territory.</em></h5>
<h5></h5>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/24/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/24/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/24/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/24/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/24/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/24/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/24/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/24/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/24/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/24/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/24/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/24/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/24/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/24/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=24&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://onthepursuitofawesomeness.wordpress.com/2013/03/06/drake-the-voice-of-a-generation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/82c8a9e1d44943d1f1f05281fe9b45bf?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gmass927</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://www.dose.ca/5713466.bin?size=dose462" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Keywords: &#8220;Longform,&#8221; &#8220;Print,&#8221; &#8220;Journalism,&#8221; &#8220;Thayer&#8221; &#8220;Pay&#8221;, &#8220;Whither?&#8221;</title>
		<link>http://williamhogeland.wordpress.com/2013/03/08/longform-print-journalism-pay-whither/</link>
		<comments>http://williamhogeland.wordpress.com/2013/03/08/longform-print-journalism-pay-whither/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 21:49:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>William Hogeland</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alana Newhouse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David Grann]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David Samuels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Evan Ratliff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[longform]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Max Linsky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Michael Washburn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Atavist]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://williamhogeland.wordpress.com/?p=2830</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The writer Michael Washburn put together a good panel the other night, at CUNY Graduate Center, on the future &#8212; or not &#8212; of what&#8217;s now called longform journalism. The idea being that in the age of the tweet, we have to call it something (we used to just call it journalism). &#8220;People don&#8217;t read [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2830&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://williamhogeland.wordpress.com/2013/03/08/longform-print-journalism-pay-whither/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/d59463e633a969f3aaa62e7ad50a37f4?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=X" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">williamhogeland</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Wheels Are in Motion</title>
		<link>http://mihirkamat.wordpress.com/2013/03/12/the-wheels-are-in-motion/</link>
		<comments>http://mihirkamat.wordpress.com/2013/03/12/the-wheels-are-in-motion/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 21:46:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>mihirkamat</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Poetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[action]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPchallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inspiration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Poems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[postaday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[postaweek]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thoughts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wheels]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mihirkamat.wordpress.com/?p=1175</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Its quiet outside Maybe too quiet The mind is restless It won&#8217;t go to sleep It seeks answers To a million questions Solutions to problems Searching, waiting, and watching. The heart joins in Beating slowly, in a deep rhythm Music that pushes the mind Forward on its unknown quest Yet there is something missing; The [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1175&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div style="text-align:justify;margin-bottom:10px;">
<p><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8381/8550225494_066d17bbd2_z.jpg" style="margin-top:10px;margin-bottom:20px;" /></p>
<p>Its quiet outside<br />
Maybe too quiet<br />
The mind is restless<br />
It won&#8217;t go to sleep</p>
<p>It seeks answers<br />
To a million questions<br />
Solutions to problems<br />
Searching, waiting, and watching.</p>
<p>The heart joins in<br />
Beating slowly, in a deep rhythm<br />
Music that pushes the mind<br />
Forward on its unknown quest</p>
<p>Yet there is something missing;<br />
The mind knows it is alone<br />
But longs for something more<br />
Than just the ordinary</p>
<p>The body can&#8217;t take it anymore<br />
It craves for a piece of the action<br />
It twists and turns<br />
Spinning out of control</p>
<p>The wheels are in motion<br />
The quietness all gone now<br />
The fire burns brightly within<br />
A spark is all it took.</p>
</div>
<div style="margin-top:40px;margin-bottom:10px;">
<font style="color:#424242;">&copy; 2013 Mihir Kamat</font>
</div>
<div style="color:#424242;">Inspired by this week&#8217;s <a href="http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2013/03/11/weekly-writing-challenge-abstraction/">writing challenge.</a></div>
<div>Image copyright of Mihir Kamat.</div>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://mihirkamat.wordpress.com/category/poetry/'>Poetry</a> Tagged: <a href='http://mihirkamat.wordpress.com/tag/action/'>action</a>, <a href='http://mihirkamat.wordpress.com/tag/dpchallenge/'>DPchallenge</a>, <a href='http://mihirkamat.wordpress.com/tag/inspiration/'>inspiration</a>, <a href='http://mihirkamat.wordpress.com/tag/poems/'>Poems</a>, <a href='http://mihirkamat.wordpress.com/tag/poetry/'>Poetry</a>, <a href='http://mihirkamat.wordpress.com/tag/postaday/'>postaday</a>, <a href='http://mihirkamat.wordpress.com/tag/postaweek/'>postaweek</a>, <a href='http://mihirkamat.wordpress.com/tag/thoughts/'>Thoughts</a>, <a href='http://mihirkamat.wordpress.com/tag/wheels/'>wheels</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1175/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1175/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1175&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://mihirkamat.wordpress.com/2013/03/12/the-wheels-are-in-motion/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://mihirkamat.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/wheels1.png?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://mihirkamat.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/wheels1.png?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">wheels</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/93942377fd97057b14518a0d2c76fff4?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F0.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mihirkamat</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8381/8550225494_066d17bbd2_z.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Weekly Writing Challenge: Abstraction</title>
		<link>http://storiesbyfrances.wordpress.com/2013/03/12/weekly-writing-challenge-abstraction/</link>
		<comments>http://storiesbyfrances.wordpress.com/2013/03/12/weekly-writing-challenge-abstraction/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 18:37:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>storiesbyfrances</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Short Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[abstraction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[counting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[disorder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPchallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[numbers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[numeral perspective]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[postaday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[steps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://storiesbyfrances.wordpress.com/?p=1407</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Two steps from my bed to my desk. Three steps from my bed to my TV. Two steps from my bed to the balcony door. One step from my bed to my wardrobe. I can reach everything in my one-room apartment with no more than five steps. It´s five steps to reach my book shelf. [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1407&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://storiesbyfrances.wordpress.com/2013/03/12/weekly-writing-challenge-abstraction/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>16</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/cc18c7999600206f44f05406aa3d80f0?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">storiesbyfrances</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://storiesbyfrances.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/25-e1363109699462.jpg?w=1000" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Close-up</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://s0.wp.com/i/badges/freshly-pressed-circle.png?m=1345187675g" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Where the Muni Buses Sleep at Night</title>
		<link>http://snottingblack.com/2013/03/05/where-the-muni-busses-sleep-at-night/</link>
		<comments>http://snottingblack.com/2013/03/05/where-the-muni-busses-sleep-at-night/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2013 15:46:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>edrevets</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[San Francisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creative fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creative writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lolz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[san francisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[san francisco public transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing about san francisco]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://snottingblack.com/?p=3109</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Muni buses are the red blood cells of San Francisco, which makes the people the oxygen. The Mission is probably the city&#8217;s belly, and downtown is its the liver, but Oakland is also in the running. To most people, the buses are ordinary vehicles of public transit, purely utilitarian pieces of equipment with no other [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3109&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://snottingblack.com/2013/03/05/where-the-muni-busses-sleep-at-night/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/9759d1ea082fcbaae8cc9b4a3fb8eb36?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">edrevets</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://edrevets.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/muni_bus_san_francisco.jpg?w=225" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Muni busses at night</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Homesick.</title>
		<link>http://thesirenstale.wordpress.com/2013/03/13/homesick/</link>
		<comments>http://thesirenstale.wordpress.com/2013/03/13/homesick/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2013 19:27:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>The Siren's Tale</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[being homesick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[career]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[childhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[home]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[homesick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[homesickness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[memoir]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[psychology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[work]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thesirenstale.wordpress.com/?p=1255</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As far back as I can remember, I&#8217;ve carried a constant feeling of homesickness every time I am away from my dwelling. While the feeling has manifested itself differently over the years, it&#8217;s always there. That gnawing discomfort that sits in the base of your stomach, tugging at your heart-strings with no mercy. It all [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1255&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://thesirenstale.wordpress.com/2013/03/13/homesick/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>71</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://thesirenstale.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/nicole_kidman_crying.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://thesirenstale.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/nicole_kidman_crying.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">crying in car</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/77b9eb2e6922a756c187133f6a1960da?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F1.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">thesirenstale</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thesirenstale.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/homesick1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">homesick heart</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thesirenstale.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/school-refusal.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">school refusal</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thesirenstale.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/lala.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">go home on weekends</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thesirenstale.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/nicole_kidman_crying.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">crying in car</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>That Cursed Ruby Box</title>
		<link>http://victoriadougherty.wordpress.com/2013/03/13/that-cursed-ruby-box/</link>
		<comments>http://victoriadougherty.wordpress.com/2013/03/13/that-cursed-ruby-box/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2013 06:53:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>victoriadougherty</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[faith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cold war]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Communist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Czech Republic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Grimm's fairytales]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pepperidge Farm Cookies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prague]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://victoriadougherty.wordpress.com/?p=463</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In the family I grew up in, love was often misplaced, nearly always badly botched, but nevertheless there – taking us from day to day. As a unit, we had every kind of bad luck you can imagine – Nazis, Communists, deaths big and small, petty humiliations and feature film-worthy fiascos. It’s luck so bad [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=463&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the family I grew up in, love was often misplaced, nearly always badly botched, but nevertheless there – taking us from day to day.  As a unit, we had every kind of bad luck you can imagine – Nazis, Communists, deaths big and small, petty humiliations and feature film-worthy fiascos.  It’s luck so bad my mom actually calls it a curse.  She believes that curse started germinating right around 1938 – when Hitler rolled into Prague.  My mom curses that day.</p>
<p>But I’m an American.  The only member of my family actually born here and raised with the corresponding happy-go-lucky spirit that all of us Americans share to some extent – even the grumpiest of us, the most self-loathing.  I guess that’s why my family’s story – from my point of view – didn’t begin with “the curse.”  It began with a gold box with a big plastic ruby on it.</p>
<p>My grandparents had a tiny closet in their bedroom when I was growing up – maybe half the size of a shower stall.  It was a place I liked to go when nobody was home because I feared I would get in big-ass trouble if I was caught snooping around in it.  Not because my grandfather kept dirty magazines there (I wished), but because it was where my brother, Viktor, was kept.</p>
<p>His ashes sat in a dark bronzed metal container on the middle shelf of a metal framed display case, surrounded by things that had meant something to him in his short life – a blue teddy bear roughly the size of a man’s hand, for instance.  He was also surrounded by things that meant something to my mother – a yellow vase filled with dried flowers, a small, iron crucifix.  I was intrigued by the trinkets and tchotchkes.  They seemed to burn with hidden meanings and when no one was around, I would take the tchotchkes down from the case and look at them.  </p>
<p>One afternoon sometime after school, my grandmother finally “caught” me.  I started explaining and before I knew it I was telling her all about how I’d come up there because I wanted to add something to my brother’s shrine.  I was just looking around for a good place to put it, since there was already so much stuff up there, I told her.</p>
<p>“What do you want to put there?” she asked.</p>
<p>“My ruby box.”</p>
<p>A little gold box with a fake ruby on its lid – I used it, quite literally, to hold my fantasies.  Maybe it contained a simple bag of wishes on one day, or a hidden message the next.  Anyway, I did not want to put my ruby box up there.</p>
<p>“Are you sure?” my grandmother asked.  She knew I really liked that box.</p>
<p>“Mm hmm,” I said, praying she’d drop it.</p>
<p>“Ok, then,” she said.  “Go get it.”</p>
<p>I went to the bedroom she kept for me in her house and took my ruby box out of my underwear drawer.  I put the box right in front of the container with my brother’s ashes.</p>
<p>My grandmother then kissed me and brought me downstairs for some Pepperidge Farm cookies.</p>
<p>I still really wanted my box back – especially when I remembered that I’d left a faux pearl ring in its belly.  My only consolation was the tiny tickle of virtuousness I felt about having given up my ruby box for the brother I’d never met.  And I guess I also hoped that in a weird way, my gift would forge a connection between me and my mom and my surviving brother that hadn’t existed before, and really wouldn’t until years later when I nearly lost one of my own children.  My mom and my oldest brother had gone through Viktor’s death together – and in the old country.  They shared that bond.  I was born a year after Viktor died, and in Chicago.  And despite the shrine in my grandmother’s closet, my brother was hardly ever mentioned and you knew better than to bring him up.</p>
<p>And now he had my ruby box.  With my ring in it.  Over the days, that thought began to drive my eight year-old mind crazy.</p>
<p>I started sneaking up to the little closet again.  I’d pick up my box, open it, put the pearl ring on my finger, then take it off and put the box back.  I was terrified that if I actually took the box back into my possession that I’d get cursed somehow.  After all, what kind of jerk takes a present back from her dead brother?  So, I’d pick it up; put it back. Pick it up; put it back.   This went on for a couple of years.</p>
<p>But over time, the box lost its meaning to me and I stopped obsessing about it.  I can’t say I forgot about it entirely, but I definitely put it out of my mind for about thirty years.  It only came up again because I was going through a pretty horrible time myself after my youngest daughter was born.  She was born with cancer and spent the first few months of her existence taking toxic doses of chemo and fighting for her life.  </p>
<p>My mom and I got really close then and Viktor stopped being a taboo subject.  I’d become a full member of our tribe – the secret initiation being basically a catastrophic curse of an event that had been commonplace for the other members of my family, but had eluded me because I’d lived a very privileged, middle-class American life free of dictators, gulags, political prisons and the resulting havoc they can wreak.</p>
<p>“I remember when you gave Viktor your box,” my mother said, out of the blue.  I’d had no idea that she even knew about it, let alone remembered such a thing.</p>
<p>“I didn’t want to,” I told her, and she smiled and said I could take it back if it was that important to me. </p>
<p>“Neh,” I said.  “He can keep it.”  We both laughed.</p>
<p>Maybe that box was the beginning of my part of our curse.  Maybe I should rue the day I ever placed it in my brother&#8217;s shrine, tossing my lot in with the rest of my family.  But I don&#8217;t.  Because along with the heartache, and the begging, the sleepless nights and the maddening loss of control that came with my part of the curse, there also appeared a few tiny cells of magic. </p>
<p>Grimm’s fairytales have long told us as much.  A curse is an enchantment.  It does, after all, take more than a few historical events to transform a run of bad luck into a true curse.  It takes something special – like fairy dust or spittle from a gargoyle, if I believed in such things – for a mere awful event to enter the realm of the supernatural.  The way it might take a golden box with a plastic ruby to make a family out of a broken band of immigrants.  </p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/463/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/463/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=463&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://victoriadougherty.wordpress.com/2013/03/13/that-cursed-ruby-box/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>44</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://victoriadougherty.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/raven-family.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://victoriadougherty.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/raven-family.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">raven family</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/69dd44894da56740eb04112bed55cb7b?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">victoriadougherty</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Girl With The Bowl Cut Hair</title>
		<link>http://mikecalahan.wordpress.com/2013/02/14/girl-with-the-bowl-cut-hair/</link>
		<comments>http://mikecalahan.wordpress.com/2013/02/14/girl-with-the-bowl-cut-hair/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 17:55:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>calahan</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Childhood = 100 Years Ago]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[childhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life lessons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[puppy love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[valentine's]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mikecalahan.wordpress.com/?p=1829</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The place: Mrs. Dell&#8217;s 6th grade classroom, Idlewild Elementary, Tacoma, WA. *** As Valentine’s Day crept up on us like a pink disease, Mrs. Dell read aloud stories of love. Every one of the girls in class were attentive as Mrs. Dell read about love won, love lost, mythical love (both Greek and Roman). We [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1829&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://mikecalahan.wordpress.com/2013/02/14/girl-with-the-bowl-cut-hair/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>137</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/81a9c6be718db54f848e85686d375d47?s=96&#38;d=wavatar&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">calakutha</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mikecalahan.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/freshly-pressed-logo.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">freshly-pressed-logo</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mikecalahan.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/bc26651381725d40_large-e1360812467446.jpeg?w=615" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bc26651381725d40_large</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mikecalahan.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/89615b70c3dce706_large-e1360810634377.jpeg?w=690" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">89615b70c3dce706_large</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mikecalahan.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/e88aadfc80e1b693_large-e1360809828526.jpeg?w=542" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">e88aadfc80e1b693_large</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mikecalahan.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/edf70f77a393db29_large.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">edf70f77a393db29_large</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mikecalahan.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/76b48cc2305087fd_large.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">76b48cc2305087fd_large</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mikecalahan.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/21e738de55ec17a7_large-e1360805789378.jpeg?w=690" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">21e738de55ec17a7_large</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mikecalahan.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/5ec4e360f8a14ea1_large-e1360814822303.jpeg?w=690" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">5ec4e360f8a14ea1_large</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mikecalahan.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/8ed315a1f7f96b3c_large.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Fear I and Fear II go head to head. </media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mikecalahan.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/8006a0056088c230_large-e1360805022231.jpeg?w=690" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">8006a0056088c230_large</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mikecalahan.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/06da4c7eeffddfbe_large.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">&#34;One-two-three-four, Mike is a dumb bore! Five-six-seven-eight, we see Mike and we hate!&#34;</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mikecalahan.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/6e468e7c420350ab_large-e1360815683596.jpeg?w=578" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">6e468e7c420350ab_large</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Bottomless Glass of Evgeny Morozov</title>
		<link>http://analogandantisocial.com/2013/03/04/the-bottomless-glass-of-evgeny-morozov/</link>
		<comments>http://analogandantisocial.com/2013/03/04/the-bottomless-glass-of-evgeny-morozov/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2013 04:27:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>epalaveeva</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Commentary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media commentary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brain Pickings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Evgeny Morozov]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York Times]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pinterest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://analogandantisocial.com/?p=141</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Eastern Europeans have a natural (or, as we will argue, historically necessitated) proclivity to be negative and I fit that stereotype pretty well. I am not a glass-half-full person. “Tell me what you are doing, and I will tell you what is wrong with it” is a pretty accurate description of my attitude. So, you [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=141&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Eastern Europeans have a natural (or, as we will argue, historically necessitated) proclivity to be negative and I fit that stereotype pretty well. I am not a glass-half-full person. “Tell me what you are doing, and I will tell you what is wrong with it” is a pretty accurate description of my attitude. So, you can’t blame me, if I get fixated on someone whose glass is so empty that it makes mine look like it’s overflowing.</p>
<p>Meet <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Evgeny_Morozov">Evgeny Morozov</a> – a fellow Eastern European and “a writer and researcher, who studies political and social implications of technology.” It is an amazing field to dedicate your career to. On one hand, technology changes so quickly that, by the time you have discovered a phenomenon to study (music sharing via Napster, anyone?), it is gone. At the same time, our understanding of individual and group psychology and behavior is growing exponentially. One would imagine that the combination of these two factors would provide a researcher with plentiful opportunities to observe, investigate, develop and test hypotheses, build and tear down assumptions.</p>
<p>And then you have Morozov. He does not exactly <i>study</i> and <i>research </i>technology, he speculates about its impact. All of us in the tech world do a lot of that, but his bias is so strong that to describe him as a researcher is as accurate as to say that the <a href="http://www.afa.net/">American Family Association</a> is about family. Judge for yourself:</p>
<ul>
<li>In his latest <i>New York Times</i> piece, <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/03/03/opinion/sunday/the-perils-of-perfection.html?pagewanted=1&amp;pagewanted=all">The Perils of Perfection</a>, he argues that we should not use technology to fix our imperfections unless we are confident that the technology solutions Silicon Valley comes up with have pure intent. On the surface, that makes sense. And then you think about, where medicine would be right now, if we took the same approach with pharmaceutical research. Should we ignore progress, if it is driven by the desire for business success?</li>
<li>Earlier in 2012, he lamented about the <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2012/02/05/opinion/sunday/the-death-of-the-cyberflaneur.html?pagewanted=all">Death of Cyberflaneurism</a>, that ancient art of browsing the Internet for useless information. I guess, sites like <a href="http://www.brainpickings.org/">Brain Pickings</a>, which does an amazing job of finding interesting information; <a href="http://getprismatic.com">Prismatic</a> that curates news content for you, or even <a href="http://www.facebook.com">Facebook</a> (let alone <a href="http://www.pinterest.com">Pinterest</a>), where friends share a lot of useless stuff, make the art too easy.</li>
<li>And then there is his recurring column, Future Tense, on <a href="http://www.slate.com/authors.evgeny_morozov.html">Slate.com</a>. If someone reads his posts a hundred years from now, they would conclude that the Internet is killing us.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="http://analogandantisocial.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/fanatic.jpg"><img class=" wp-image alignright" id="i-285" alt="Image" src="http://analogandantisocial.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/fanatic.jpg?w=351&#038;h=196" width="351" height="196" /></a>To be fair, Morozov does have a nose for the silliness and over-the-top enthusiasm of technologists. His ridicule of pointless services that Tweet after you die, products that “erase” the homeless from your view, or forums (TED) that make a communist parade seem propaganda-free, are absolutely on target. Yet, when I read his pieces, I can’t help but think of agent Nelson Van Alden, <a href="http://www.hbo.com/boardwalk-empire/index.html">Boardwalk Empire</a>’s puritanical government official, whose obsession seems a tad unhealthy. Does Morozov denounce technology because he likes it too much?</p>
<p>In one of his pieces, Morozov quotes Polish philosopher Leszek Kolakowski, who argued that being inconsistent is the only way to avoid becoming a doctrinaire ideologue. Morozov writes with admiration:</p>
<blockquote><p>“For Kolakowski, absolute consistency is identical to fanaticism.”</p></blockquote>
<p>Smart man, that Kolakowski.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/141/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/141/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=141&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://analogandantisocial.com/2013/03/04/the-bottomless-glass-of-evgeny-morozov/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/1fb0e0847039efc1ea13a1fa54eeaf6a?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F1.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">epalaveeva</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://analogandantisocial.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/fanatic.jpg?w=487" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
