<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2011 20:52:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Nokia: Culture will out</title>
		<link>http://speedbird.wordpress.com/2011/02/19/nokia-culture-will-out/</link>
		<comments>http://speedbird.wordpress.com/2011/02/19/nokia-culture-will-out/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2011 20:07:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>AG</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Clean living under difficult circumstances]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The meta stuff]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://speedbird.wordpress.com/?p=999</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[OK, you got me. You knew I couldn&#8217;t go for very long without having some kind of outlet for random thoughts and personal opinions. To paraphrase Forest Whitaker in The Crying Game — and boy, does that date me — expressing same is in my nature. So forgive me if I go back on my [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=999&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://speedbird.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/nokia_blues.jpg"><img src="http://speedbird.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/nokia_blues.jpg?w=460&#038;h=345" alt="Stuck inside of Espoo with them Nokia blues again" title="nokia_blues" width="460" height="345" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1000" /></a></p>
<p>OK, you got me.</p>
<p>You knew I couldn&#8217;t go for very long without having some kind of outlet for random thoughts and personal opinions. To paraphrase Forest Whitaker in <em>The Crying Game</em> — and boy, does <em>that</em> date me — expressing same is in my nature.</p>
<p>So forgive me if I go back on my word a little, and use this space to comment briefly on the contrast between what have already become the daily and weekly rhythms of work in <a href="http://urbanscale.org/">my own practice</a>, and what I saw during two years at Nokia. I guess I&#8217;m moved to do this both because writing helps me organize my own complicated thoughts on the situation that company finds itself in, and ideally because it might help clarify things for others. My hope is that everything that follows will prove especially useful to you if you&#8217;re on the verge of joining a large, global organization — or leaving one.</p>
<p>Executive summary: Despite the omnipresent burden of responsibility, and the inherent risk of failure, there&#8217;s an excitement and pleasure in working on one&#8217;s own behalf that was for the most part missing entirely from my Nokian experience. The word I keep coming back to, in my head, is &#8220;unbound,&#8221; and it&#8217;s an unbelievably lovely and liberating sensation.</p>
<p>My experience with <a href="http://urbanscale.org/2011/02/15/project-perry/">a project we&#8217;re working on</a>, even at this very early stage, might serve as a small illustration of why the entrepreneurial life has already been so rewarding, and incidentally, why I wouldn&#8217;t look for innovation from large organizations. At any rate, it&#8217;s as good a way as any to comment, hopefully constructively, on Nokia&#8217;s recent and ongoing troubles.</p>
<p><strong>Most obviously: our size lets us move <em>fast</em></strong>. We&#8217;ve taken this from first notion to Illustrator sketch to technical validation to &#8220;Patent Pending&#8221; in mere weeks, and not very many of them. This is in distinct contrast to my experience in Espoo, where anybody wanting to launch anything at all had to secure layers (upon layers) of buy-in from people who — in many but certainly not all cases, and with all due respect — are not properly equipped to evaluate the merits of the propositions they&#8217;re being presented with. I&#8217;m hesitant to generalize. Honestly, I am. But my personal experience suggests that rather than acting as the incubator/force multiplier/accelerator it ought to have, Nokia&#8217;s corporate culture served as a brake on all kinds of innovative thought.</p>
<p><strong>We&#8217;re better-equipped to detect and respond to actual user needs</strong>. Nokia&#8217;s problem is not, and has never been, that it lacks for creative, thoughtful, talented people, or the resources to turn their ideas into shipping product. It&#8217;s that the company is fundamentally, and has <em>always</em> been, organized to trade in commodities. Whether those commodities were stands of timber, reams of paper, reels of cable, pairs of boots, or cheap televisions for deployment in hotel chains, much the same basic logic applied: acquire, or manufacture, great quantities of a physical product for the lowest achievable cost, and sell for whatever the market will bear.</p>
<p>Nokia&#8217;s engineers were and are brilliant at this. I am so far from an expert on the topic it&#8217;s not even funny, but I&#8217;d feel comfortable wagering that there is still no organization on the planet more capable at designing the guts of a phone, the various antennae and radios-on-a-chip that allow a handset to communicate with a network. Nor are there many who can compete with Nokia on the ability to optimize a supply chain and bring in a given <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bill_of_materials">bill of materials</a> at a given (and generally astonishingly low) cost.</p>
<p>These are precisely the skills you need if you&#8217;re interested in dominating a global market in commodity communication devices, as Nokia did for the fourteen years of the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jorma_Ollila">Jorma Ollila</a> era. But the company utterly failed to anticipate, understand or organize itself to deal with the critical thing that happened at the cusp of the Ollila-Kalasvuo transition. This was that you could no longer think of mobile phones as <em>communication devices</em>. You had to conceive of them as <em>interface objects</em> through which users would experience content and command functionality that ultimately lived on the network. (That grandeur and disproprotionate benefit would accrue to those who did understand this shift was underlined by Apple&#8217;s launch of its astonishingly successful iPhone in late June of 2007, just over a year after Kallasvuo ascended to the CEOship.)</p>
<p>Individuals at Nokia, of course, did understand this — many of them. Indeed, the entire Insight &amp; Foresight unit produced material throughout the immediate pre-iPhone period that was as visionary with respect to the emerging paradigm as anything I&#8217;ve seen, just as, throughout my tenure, the Design Strategic Projects team under Phil Lindberg continued to generate ideas that for the most part took the full measure of so-called 4G/<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/LTE_Advanced">LTE</a> networks and cloud-based interaction.</p>
<p>But whether as teams or individuals, the parties trying — energetically, and in good faith — to help the company avail itself of this insight were ignored. Compensated competitively, paid lip service to (if not actually fawned over, or rubbed as if for totemic good luck) in presentations to the Group Executive Board&#8230;but comprehensively overruled when it came time to set policy or direction. I&#8217;m tempted to say that considerations of user experience were  bypassed at a structural level.</p>
<p>And this is the crux of it. As it happens, the value-engineering mindset that&#8217;s so crucial to profitability as a commodity trader is <em>fatal</em> as a purveyor of experiences. Of course you still want to produce your offering for the lowest achievable cost — but that cost is bound up in intangible, nondeterministic dimensions of design, in ways that are only partially-at-best quantifiable. It&#8217;s just not particularly wise to allow engineers to make decisions about things like product and service nomenclature, interface typography and the graphic design of icons: they&#8217;re, I daresay, not even neurocognitively equipped to do so. And yet this is what happened when I was at Nokia and, I would imagine, is happening still.</p>
<p>Again, please understand that I say this with enormous respect for my engineer friends, who manage without thinking twice to achieve a very great number of things for which <em>I</em> am not neurocognitively equipped. My point is merely that, at Nokia, engineering has been allowed to displace what is properly the company&#8217;s <em>design</em> prerogative almost entirely.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ll give an example. Nokia spent many years, and a great deal of money, doing research and development of a technology called <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Near_field_communication">NFC</a>, or &#8220;near field communication.&#8221; NFC really does have the potential to transform all kinds of everyday interactions; it&#8217;s essentially a flavor of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Radio-frequency_identification">RFID</a> that allows signals to pass between objects that are brought within close (touch or tap) proximity with one another. It&#8217;s the gimmick underlying the phone you&#8217;ll buy next year, with which, if you live in the developed world, you&#8217;ll almost certainly conduct the lion&#8217;s share of your daily monetary transactions.</p>
<p>When I arrived at Nokia, the folks down the road at <a href="http://research.nokia.com/">NRC</a> were very proud of something they&#8217;d ginned up: an NFC-equipped, but otherwise entirely conventional,  vending machine. At last!, I thought, here&#8217;s a concrete step toward the future of everyday transactions. And in what was, from my perspective, the very best kind of context: that of an interaction so banal and unremarkable that it undermined any conceivable charge of utopian handwaving. Whatever frisson of futurism you derive from the encounter quickly subsides beneath the threshold of the ordinary, which — per all my gurus, from <a href="http://www.jnd.org/">Don Norman</a> to <a href="http://www.jaspermorrison.com/html/index.html">Jasper Morrison</a> and <a href="http://www.metropolismag.com/story/20070518/without-thought">Naoto Fukasawa</a> — is exactly as it should be.</p>
<p>Except that, as realized by Nokia, this is precisely what failed to happen. I experienced, in fact, neither a frisson of elegant futurism <em>nor</em> a blasé presentiment of everyday life at midcentury. I was given an NFC phone, and told to tap it against the item I wanted from the vending machine. This is what happened next: the vending machine <em>teeped</em>, and the phone <em>teeped</em>, and six or seven seconds later a notification popped up on its screen. It was an incoming text message, which had been sent by the vending machine at the moment I tapped my phone against it. I had to respond &#8220;Y&#8221; to this text to complete the transaction. The experience was clumsy and joyless and not in any conceivable way an improvement over pumping coins into the soda machine just the way I did quarters into <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Defender_(video_game)">Defender</a> at the age of twelve.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not that the NFC-based, phone-to-object interaction didn&#8217;t work. Of course it did: it had been <em>engineered</em> perfectly. But what it hadn&#8217;t been was <em>designed</em>. Those responsible for imagining the interaction apparently wanted to protect users against the (edge case!) contingency of someone making off with their phones and running up a huge vending-machine tab. They failed to understand that, for low-value transactions like this, at least, <em>the touch gesture is a useful proxy for consent</em> — and that if someone&#8217;s got physical possession of my phone, I&#8217;m likely to have bigger problems than whether or not they order a few cans of Coke with it. A designer committed to the user and the quality of that user&#8217;s experience gets this in a way only the rarest engineer seems to. Designers are also, by training and predilection, inclined to design for the usual, where engineers are taught a kind of rigor that compels them to account for, <em>and overweight</em>, low-probability events.</p>
<p>Bottom line: the &#8220;magic&#8221; of an NFC-based transaction, the &#8220;surprise and delight&#8221; our esteemed colleagues in Marketing so often demand we wrest out of technological interactions, was foreclosed from the beginning. All of the potential lightness and elegance that would make this not merely a <em>possible</em> way of doing things but a <em>better</em> way was ruled out, by an organization committed to the virtues of engineering rather than those of design.</p>
<p>Is it entirely fair to expect what was, after all, a product of a research lab to exhibit much in the way of polish at the level of interaction? Ordinarily, I&#8217;d say no, of course not. But for the fact, that is, that certain highly-placed people in the Nokia mainforce were aware of the NFC vending machine project, delighted with it as-is, and perceived little if any fault with it. It may certainly have needed some &#8220;fine tuning,&#8221; I was told on more than one occasion&#8230;but otherwise stood proudly ready for the day the mass market was provisioned with NFC-capable phones, and could make use of it.</p>
<p>I have to conclude that it&#8217;s this inability to even perceive the clear makings of an unacceptably bad user experience, let alone address them as profound obstacles to success in the marketplace, that leads to <a href="http://speedbird.wordpress.com/2007/01/24/on-nokia-ui-and-ux-blunders-and-the-raising-of-the-bar/">situations like this</a>.</p>
<p>Another, blunter way of putting it: there&#8217;s nobody with any taste in the decision-making echelons at Nokia. And this is especially unfortunate and ironic, given that elegant, simple Finnish <a href="http://www.harrikoskinen.com/">design</a> <a href="http://www.iittala.com/web/Iittalaweb.nsf/en/home">has</a> <a href="http://www.marimekko.com/">tutored</a> <a href="http://www.artek.fi/">generations</a> in what taste means. My whole tenure in Espoo was soured by the nagging counterfactual, &#8220;What if Nokia had embraced and extended the finest traditions of its own national design culture, in its approach to the global mass market?&#8221;</p>
<p>Something tells me that Stephen Elop, whether or not he turns out to be a Trojan horse for Redmond, will be comprehensively unable to help in this department.</p>
<p><strong>We&#8217;re happy if our product is viable enough that it reaches an audience, and contributes in any way to making those lives easier. It doesn&#8217;t have to be a blockbuster</strong>. This raises a related issue, which is that Espoo is only and solely interested in <em>scale</em>. In Nokian terms, this generally means &#8220;on the order of tens of millions of users.&#8221; On the surface, this is defensible, but it means the company doesn&#8217;t really have many innovation pathways open to it. It certainly can&#8217;t tolerate the kind of lowercase experiments that other institutions benefit from, whether these are inherently viable businesses generating high-multiple ROIs that are, however, small in absolute terms, or probes like Twitter that enjoy no clear business model at their outset, but later find scale and thereby produce value.</p>
<p>In concrete terms, this means that projects like <a href="http://sportstracker.nokia.com/nts">Nokia Sports Tracker</a> — one of the best things I saw during my time in Espoo, and in my opinion actually superior to the Nike+ iPod offering — are abandoned, orphaned, starved of the oxygen they need. This despite what I would have thought was the obvious fact that it&#8217;s projects like these that lend your brand an aura of futurity, build consumer enthusiasm and loyalty, and generally make your company more attractive as a place for people to work. In other words, they pay for themselves many times over and in many ways, whether or not they generate revenue. If nothing else, they cut down on headhunter bills; a company that fully and whole-heartedly supports homegrown initiatives like Sports Tracker is a place where bright developers will want to play.</p>
<p>Although I had nothing a&#8217;tall to do with Sports Tracker, it&#8217;s extra-galling to me personally that Nokia killed the project more or less in the same breath that it embraced the frankly ludicrous fantasies peddled by acting head of Services and Developer Experience Tero Ojanperä (&#8220;responsible for the company&#8217;s portfolio of location, messaging, entertainment and context-based services&#8221;). I find it so galling because the company had, in its sweaty little hands, a truly pioneering service that showcased its devices and their onboard sensors at their best, leveraged locational technology, was fun to use and nice to look at, and, if you&#8217;ll forgive a little jargon, demonstrably &#8220;drove user engagement.&#8221; And it literally threw this all away, apparently preferring to indulge itself as an institution in, among other things, the fantasy of being a glittering media brand.</p>
<p>I always thought of Sports Tracker as something I would be proud to have designed myself. Now, though, in my role as managing director, I understand that I would be equally proud had I anything to do with creating the kind of environment in which folks like <a href="http://www.sports-tracker.com">the creators of Sports Tracker</a> might thrive. That&#8217;s why it&#8217;s inexplicable to me that Nokia&#8217;s mid-upper echelons took a pass on what was obviously a service with a bright future — I mean, if success indisputably has many parents, didn&#8217;t they want a win they could claim credit for?</p>
<p>I have a great deal more to say on the topic, if you can believe it, but I&#8217;ve already gone on pretty long, and likely stressed your interest and/or patience to the breaking point. Quickly, therefore, and I say this to everyone who&#8217;s ever whiled away their hours in the corporate breakrooms of the world, boring their coworkers with dream-architectures of world domination and largely ungrounded assertions that <em>everything could be so much better if only x and y and z</em>: I wish I&#8217;d done this years ago. Gone out on my own, that is.</p>
<p>You own your mistakes and failures, certainly, in a way that a large organization can trivially buffer you against, but so too your joys. Yeah, it&#8217;s brisk out here&#8230;but so, so exciting, and there is <em>at the very least</em> a 1:1 ratio between the effort you exert on a day-to-day basis and what is seen to come of it. Say that about any big shop you care to name, I dare you.</p>
<p>As for Nokia, their fate is their own, too. Given the highly questionable judgment displayed by the organization and its senior management over many years, I&#8217;d say they&#8217;ve finally gotten what was coming to them — but for the fact that &#8220;they,&#8221; in this context, unavoidably includes many who have been doing their absolute best, under truly thankless conditions, for far, far too long. It&#8217;s to you that I&#8217;m going to raise my glass tonight, and you know very well who you are.</p>
<p>It also includes just about the entire Finnish people, for whom Nokia has long been a particularly significant benefactor, and for whom I retain a great (if frequently enough puzzled) fondness. These people are blameless — or if not blameless, certainly don&#8217;t deserve to be held culpable for the blunders of a few. To me, their experience is a sobering reminder of the responsibility for the welfare of others one takes on in deciding to start any kind of venture at all that extends beyond the shores of the self. And if, in the end, that&#8217;s all I wind up taking away from my time in Espoo, I guess that&#8217;s not such a bad deal at all.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/999/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/999/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/999/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/999/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/999/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/999/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/999/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/999/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/999/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/999/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/999/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/999/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/999/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/999/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=999&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://speedbird.wordpress.com/2011/02/19/nokia-culture-will-out/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>66</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">AG</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://speedbird.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/nokia_blues.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">nokia_blues</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>You Sure Are A Lot Uglier In Person</title>
		<link>http://markarmstrongillustration.com/2011/02/17/you-sure-are-a-lot-uglier-in-person/</link>
		<comments>http://markarmstrongillustration.com/2011/02/17/you-sure-are-a-lot-uglier-in-person/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2011 00:42:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Mark Armstrong</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[magazine assignment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cartoon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[illustration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rough sketches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[funny]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[court]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lawyer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lawsuit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[matchmaking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[judge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jury]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IHOP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pancakes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kitty litter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dennis Kucinich]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sandwich]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://markarmstrongillustration.wordpress.com/?p=2107</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[You're nobody till somebody sues you: the latest lawsuit humor for Inside Counsel Magazine.<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=2107&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://markarmstrongillustration.com/2011/02/17/you-sure-are-a-lot-uglier-in-person/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/982e79091ae00071cca9be80120ee62b?s=96&#38;d=&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mrstrongest</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://markarmstrongillustration.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/baddate-final.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">BadDate.final</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://markarmstrongillustration.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/ruff1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ruff1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://markarmstrongillustration.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/ruff2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ruff2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://markarmstrongillustration.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/ruff3.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ruff3</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://markarmstrongillustration.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/ruff4.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ruff4</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Confessions of a (Not So) Supermom</title>
		<link>http://saltandnectar.wordpress.com/2011/02/21/confessions-of-a-not-so-supermom/</link>
		<comments>http://saltandnectar.wordpress.com/2011/02/21/confessions-of-a-not-so-supermom/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2011 08:22:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>saltandnectar</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Motherhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Work/Life Balance]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://saltandnectar.wordpress.com/?p=379</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[When you’re at the park pushing a swing, shopping for diapers at Target, or simply walking down the street with baby in tow, do you ever find yourself staring at one of those mothers and wonder what you’re missing? C’mon, you know what I’m talking about.  I’m talking about the Supermom.  She runs 10 miles, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=379&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When you’re at the park pushing a swing, shopping for diapers at Target, or simply walking down the street with baby in tow, do you ever find yourself staring at <em>one of those</em> mothers and wonder what you’re missing? C’mon, you know what I’m talking about.  I’m talking about the <a href="http://www.happyworker.com/supermom" target="_blank">Supermom</a>.  She runs 10 miles, does downward dog, and answers 50 e-mails before the sun and Little Johnny rise.  She has perfectly coiffed hair, a body that rivals Heidi Klum, and doesn’t need <span style="text-decoration:line-through;">botulism</span> Botox to look beautiful. She’s CEO of everything, only prepares scrumptious organic meals, and has children that emit sunshine. Okay, so I exaggerate. The woman isn’t <em>that</em> perfect, but she sure seems to epitomize this otherworldly, unattainable ideal of motherhood. And alas, I still find myself staring at this mythical heroine through the shield of my aviator sunglasses wondering how she balances it all (or at least fakes it to make it).</p>
<p>While I never expected to be like June Cleaver, I did imagine that I’d glide through motherhood like Claire Huxtable: smart, witty, rational mommy lawyer bringing home the bacon and managing family life with style and grace.  Of course it was possible to be this version of a Supermom, especially because I’d previously kicked the butt of all multitasking villains and earned my cape as Superwoman sans baby. I worked in a high-powered career, shopped at the farmers’ market for dinner, squeezed in yoga and friends, remodeled my bathroom, made cupcakes, and still had time for an episode of <em>True Blood</em> all before going to bed. Jeez, how hard could it be?</p>
<p>Daydream music comes to a screeching halt. Bubble bursts. Cue reality.</p>
<p>At the end of my real life episode as a work-at-home mom, I seriously feel and look more like Miranda Hobbes than Charlotte York. I am tired, slightly overworked, struggling with what we all struggle with—balance, imperfectly dressed, ready to collapse on the couch and enjoy Thai takeout, happy to be home, and struck by the daily realization that I didn’t get anything done. You raise your eyebrow and ask, “How can you feel all of the above if you didn’t get anything done? What the hell did you do all day?”  I know, I know. It sounds crazy. But I can tell you that I am not the only new mom afflicted by this phenomenon, where one who used to be a multitasking maven now can barely manage to check off a few items if any from her “to do” list.</p>
<p>My dear friend and I recently commiserated about this very issue. She, like me, reaches the end of her active day as a mom feeling exhausted, as if she tackled a week’s worth of errands and chores but in reality only made it to the Post Office.  Maybe we were naïve to think that we’d emerge for the new parent sleep-deprived daze capable and ready to do it all, but we never thought in a million years that it would be so challenging to muster the energy to balance mommyhood with all the “other stuff,” especially when we were no longer beholden to the law firm.  As we confessed that our type-A personalities were having some difficulty coming to terms with the baby toys littering the living room floor, the dishes left undone, the pile of laundry reaching Everest-sized proportions, and our inability to make real meals unless you count Luna Bars, we also shared the secret that it was positively freeing not to be burdened with multitasking and the self-imposed pressure to be “productive.”</p>
<p>After we ended our Skype chat, I kept thinking about how good it felt to openly reveal that we are happier individuals/women/mothers/wives/friends/you name it when everything isn’t perfect. So, I’ll also confess to you why I’m a (not so) Supermom:</p>
<ul>
<li>I hate that my son wakes up at 5:30 AM because I am not ready to play before the sun rises, so I bring him to bed with me in an attempt to lure him back to sleep for a just a little while longer. I pretend to keep sleeping even when he crawls on my head.</li>
<li>I wash my hair every other day, never blow dry it, and always wear it in a French twist, ponytail, or braid. Personal grooming takes too much energy.</li>
<li>I look like the living corpse of Sarah because I never have time to put on concealer or any other makeup for that matter. Again, see bullet point above.</li>
<li>I pretend to look pulled together by accessorizing my outfits with a brightly patterned scarf and flashy stud earrings. Hopefully, no one will notice that I’ve worn the same pair of jeans three days in a row.</li>
<li>I feed my son frozen waffles, instant oatmeal, and vegetable puffs on an almost daily basis because they’re quick and easy. Hey, at least they’re organic.</li>
<li>I gave up cleaning the kitchen floor after every meal and ignore the food crumbs and sticky tile until it becomes too unsightly.</li>
<li>I have stopped apologizing for the water-stained quartz countertops, dishes in the sink, mail on the dining table, and shoes collecting by our door.  Because I’m not a candidate for the television shows about hoarders, I’ve stopped worrying about my mess.</li>
<li>I buy cookies and cupcakes at the bakery, and I rely on Trader Joe’s to get me through a dinner party.  Yes, it’s true, I used the store’s delicious flash frozen mashed potatoes at Thanksgiving. Martha would not approve.</li>
<li>Sixteen months later and I have not lost all the baby weight. Instead, I wear a lot of black or use Spanx.</li>
<li>Once my son goes to bed, I watch <em>Glee</em> and fantasize about being a pop star instead of attending to my “to do” list. A girl&#8217;s gotta dream, right?</li>
</ul>
<p>The list definitely goes on.</p>
<p>And while there is still a small part of me that occasionally aspires to be Supermom, I feel relieved that I can hang up my cape along with my star-studded hot pants and high heels and don’t have to pretend to be something I’m not (I certainly don’t want to fake it to make it).  So, productivity be damned! Everything is perfect whether or not I clean the kitchen because I am free — I am free to live in the moment, free to focus my energy on what matters and spend my time with my son, and free to just be.</p>
<p>Thanks E for reminding me of this.</p>
<p><em>~ The Other Sarah</em></p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://saltandnectar.wordpress.com/category/motherhood/'>Motherhood</a>, <a href='http://saltandnectar.wordpress.com/category/worklife-balance/'>Work/Life Balance</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/379/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/379/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/379/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/379/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/379/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/379/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/379/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/379/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/379/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/379/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/379/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/379/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/379/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/379/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=379&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://saltandnectar.wordpress.com/2011/02/21/confessions-of-a-not-so-supermom/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>77</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/2e2812b1632a4fdc4e217d860b32ee21?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">saltandnectar</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Between The Earthquakes In Christchurch</title>
		<link>http://giftsofthejourney.wordpress.com/2011/02/22/between-the-earthquakes-in-christchurch/</link>
		<comments>http://giftsofthejourney.wordpress.com/2011/02/22/between-the-earthquakes-in-christchurch/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2011 11:55:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Elizabeth Harper</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health & Wellness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Memories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Unexplainable]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christchurch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ChristChurch Cathedral]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Earthquake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elizabeth Harper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fortuna Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gifts Of The Journey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New Zealand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tales Of Pioneer Women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tete-A-Tete]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vanessa Hardy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Warren Chilton]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://giftsofthejourney.wordpress.com/?p=8433</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Waking this morning to the news of another earthquake in Christchurch, I searched the internet and was sad to see the loss of lives during this most recent quake. When John and I were in Christchurch two months ago there were still many signs of the previous earthquake in September. Our hotel was right around [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=8433&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_8434" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://giftsofthejourney.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/20101214-9129.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-8434" title="20101214-9129" src="http://giftsofthejourney.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/20101214-9129.jpg?w=500&#038;h=385" alt="" width="500" height="385" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">John Winchurch In Christchurch, New Zealand</p></div>
<p>Waking this morning to the news of another earthquake in Christchurch, I searched the internet and was sad to see the loss of lives during this most recent quake. When John and I were in Christchurch two months ago there were still many signs of the previous earthquake in September. Our hotel was right around the corner from the cathedral that was hit so hard yesterday in the center of Christchurch. Pictures of the 110 year old <strong><a href="http://www.christchurchcathedral.co.nz/" target="_blank"><span style="color:#800000;">ChristChurch cathedral </span></a></strong>are everywhere showing the collapsed spire and roof damage and I wanted to share with you what it looked like when we were there in December, only nine days before Christmas.</p>
<p><a href="http://giftsofthejourney.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/20101214-9156.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-8435" title="20101214-9156" src="http://giftsofthejourney.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/20101214-9156.jpg?w=500&#038;h=375" alt="" width="500" height="375" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">I loved the angels which I imagine were up for the Christmas season.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://giftsofthejourney.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/20101214-9176.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-8441" title="20101214-9176" src="http://giftsofthejourney.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/20101214-9176.jpg?w=400&#038;h=354" alt="" width="400" height="354" /></a><a href="http://giftsofthejourney.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/20101214-9177.jpg"></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://giftsofthejourney.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/20101214-9177.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-8442" title="20101214-9177" src="http://giftsofthejourney.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/20101214-9177.jpg?w=320&#038;h=363" alt="" width="320" height="363" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://giftsofthejourney.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/20101214-9174.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-8444" title="20101214-9174" src="http://giftsofthejourney.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/20101214-9174.jpg?w=320&#038;h=427" alt="" width="320" height="427" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://giftsofthejourney.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/20101214-9158.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-8436" title="20101214-9158" src="http://giftsofthejourney.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/20101214-9158.jpg?w=500&#038;h=386" alt="" width="500" height="386" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://giftsofthejourney.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/20101214-9160.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-8437" title="20101214-9160" src="http://giftsofthejourney.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/20101214-9160.jpg?w=500&#038;h=648" alt="" width="500" height="648" /></a></p>
<p>Also near our hotel was this older building which housed several shops where I enjoyed meeting the owners and making a few purchases. I hope the people I met survived the earthquake.</p>
<p><a href="http://giftsofthejourney.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/20101216-9369.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-8439" title="20101216-9369" src="http://giftsofthejourney.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/20101216-9369.jpg?w=500&#038;h=386" alt="" width="500" height="386" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://giftsofthejourney.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/20101214-9180.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-8438" title="20101214-9180" src="http://giftsofthejourney.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/20101214-9180.jpg?w=500&#038;h=375" alt="" width="500" height="375" /></a></p>
<p>I searched for them online, but could not find an email link to one in particular. Vanessa Hardy has a wonderful shop in the green building above and I wish I could find a way to see if she and her shop, Tete-a-Tete made it safely through the quake. I had hoped to write about her earlier, but I have not time to write about my New Zealand experience since we returned so it is only now that I am taking a minute to tell you about her. I bought one of my favorite new (to me) scarves in her shop and we shared our stories about how we met our lovely men. I stayed so long that I had a chance to meet her sweetie, Warren Chilton when he arrived just before closing time.</p>
<p><a href="http://giftsofthejourney.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/img_0281.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-8440" title="IMG_0281" src="http://giftsofthejourney.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/img_0281.jpg?w=500&#038;h=386" alt="" width="500" height="386" /></a></p>
<p>I also bought the book above in a bookstore on site, <strong><a href="http://www.fortunabooks.com/index.htmlhttp://" target="_blank"><span style="color:#800000;">Fortuna Books</span></a><span style="color:#800000;">.</span></strong> It feels like a strange coincidence that I happened to be reading that book last night when I went to sleep.</p>
<p>Judging by the time difference, I was reading about pioneer women in New Zealand when Christchurch was breaking up. I pulled it off the bookshelf late last night choosing it over the three or four books already on my bedside table. I had been reading a book of short stories by Tobis Wolf, but last night felt like reading this one instead.</p>
<p>Strange, but true &#8230; it feels kind of woo-woo to me now, but John would say it was just chance.</p>
<p>I sent an email off to the bookstore owner and hope to hear all is well in the building since I can&#8217;t find a way to check on Vanessa. If one of my New Zealand readers hears any news, I would appreciate knowing that Vanessa and those around her in the other shops in the Green building made it safely through the earthquake.</p>
<div id="attachment_8449" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 410px"><a href="http://giftsofthejourney.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/20101214-9133.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-8449 " title="20101214-9133" src="http://giftsofthejourney.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/20101214-9133.jpg?w=400&#038;h=519" alt="" width="400" height="519" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">ChristChurch Cathedral - Christchurch, New Zealand</p></div>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://giftsofthejourney.wordpress.com/category/books/'>Books</a>, <a href='http://giftsofthejourney.wordpress.com/category/health-wellness/'>Health &amp; Wellness</a>, <a href='http://giftsofthejourney.wordpress.com/category/memories/'>Memories</a>, <a href='http://giftsofthejourney.wordpress.com/category/photography/'>Photography</a>, <a href='http://giftsofthejourney.wordpress.com/category/travel/'>Travel</a>, <a href='http://giftsofthejourney.wordpress.com/category/unexplainable/'>Unexplainable</a> Tagged: <a href='http://giftsofthejourney.wordpress.com/tag/christchurch/'>Christchurch</a>, <a href='http://giftsofthejourney.wordpress.com/tag/christchurch-cathedral/'>ChristChurch Cathedral</a>, <a href='http://giftsofthejourney.wordpress.com/tag/earthquake/'>Earthquake</a>, <a href='http://giftsofthejourney.wordpress.com/tag/elizabeth-harper/'>Elizabeth Harper</a>, <a href='http://giftsofthejourney.wordpress.com/tag/fortuna-books/'>Fortuna Books</a>, <a href='http://giftsofthejourney.wordpress.com/tag/gifts-of-the-journey/'>Gifts Of The Journey</a>, <a href='http://giftsofthejourney.wordpress.com/tag/new-zealand/'>New Zealand</a>, <a href='http://giftsofthejourney.wordpress.com/tag/tales-of-pioneer-women/'>Tales Of Pioneer Women</a>, <a href='http://giftsofthejourney.wordpress.com/tag/tete-a-tete/'>Tete-A-Tete</a>, <a href='http://giftsofthejourney.wordpress.com/tag/vanessa-hardy/'>Vanessa Hardy</a>, <a href='http://giftsofthejourney.wordpress.com/tag/warren-chilton/'>Warren Chilton</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/8433/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/8433/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/8433/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/8433/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/8433/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/8433/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/8433/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/8433/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/8433/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/8433/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/8433/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/8433/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/8433/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/8433/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=8433&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://giftsofthejourney.wordpress.com/2011/02/22/between-the-earthquakes-in-christchurch/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>32</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/fac150842bd4817fe9cd80eca1c1d477?s=96&#38;d=identicon" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">E</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://giftsofthejourney.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/20101214-9129.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">20101214-9129</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://giftsofthejourney.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/20101214-9156.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">20101214-9156</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://giftsofthejourney.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/20101214-9176.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">20101214-9176</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://giftsofthejourney.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/20101214-9177.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">20101214-9177</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://giftsofthejourney.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/20101214-9174.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">20101214-9174</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://giftsofthejourney.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/20101214-9158.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">20101214-9158</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://giftsofthejourney.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/20101214-9160.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">20101214-9160</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://giftsofthejourney.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/20101216-9369.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">20101216-9369</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://giftsofthejourney.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/20101214-9180.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">20101214-9180</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://giftsofthejourney.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/img_0281.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0281</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://giftsofthejourney.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/20101214-9133.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">20101214-9133</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Not enough excellent art?  O rly?</title>
		<link>http://chavisory.wordpress.com/2011/02/22/not-enough-excellent-art-o-rly/</link>
		<comments>http://chavisory.wordpress.com/2011/02/22/not-enough-excellent-art-o-rly/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2011 05:14:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>chavisory</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Performing arts]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://chavisory.wordpress.com/?p=411</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This opinion piece (What Is Wrong With the Arts?) from the Huffington Post made the rounds of Facebook last week among my theater friends, mostly garnering at least some degree of agreement with the thesis that, contrary to much common knowledge about what&#8217;s hurting our arts culture, the arts are suffering the most because there&#8217;s [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=411&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This opinion piece (<a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/michael-kaiser/what-is-wrong-with-the-ar_b_822757.html">What Is Wrong With the Arts?</a>) from the Huffington Post made the rounds of Facebook last week among my theater friends, mostly garnering at least some degree of agreement with the thesis that, contrary to much common knowledge about what&#8217;s hurting our arts culture, the arts are suffering the most because there&#8217;s not enough really good art being made.</p>
<p>But I wasn&#8217;t on the side of the author (Kennedy Center president Michael Kaiser) until fairly deep into his article; in fact, I started out fairly upset at what he seemed to be charging, when he says that &#8220;the arts are in trouble because there is simply not enough excellent art being created,&#8221; and goes on to list a large handful of iconic choreographers, conductors and composers of the 1950&#8242;s and &#8217;60&#8242;s, and that &#8220;the classical arts have simply not kept up&#8221; with the kind of creativity and innovation going into television, movies, and rock music.</p>
<p>(Though I <em>may</em> be inclined to agree with him about rock music, given the intelligence and loveliness of some of the rock music I&#8217;ve heard in the past couple years.)</p>
<p>Young artists today just aren&#8217;t up to it, he seems to be saying.</p>
<p>And I don&#8217;t believe him, because I see astonishing art almost every day.  There&#8217;s almost not a week of my working life that goes by in which I don&#8217;t feel privileged and blessed and astonished to be seeing what I&#8217;m seeing.</p>
<p>But by the end of the piece, he&#8217;s saying something different, when he writes:</p>
<blockquote><p><em>But the institutional nature of our arts ecology, a relatively recent  phenomenon, means that groups of people are now more responsible for  arts making than the individual.  Boards, managers and producing  consortia are overly-involved.</em></p>
<p><em>And these groups are misbehaving. They are overly-conservative,  subject to &#8220;group think&#8221; and so worried about budgets that they forget  that bad art hurts budgets far more than risk-taking does.</em></p></blockquote>
<p>Now he&#8217;s not indicting artists at all, but producing and funding organizations.  He&#8217;s confused the creation of art with <em>production</em> on a high level.  And isn&#8217;t that exactly what he&#8217;s complaining about, when he bemoans the substitution of celebrity for excellence, of ever bigger and more expensive spectacle for insight?  Isn&#8217;t THAT the problem?  He&#8217;s got artists and what they do confused with institutions and what they do.  And he&#8217;s right about the behavior of the institutions.  It&#8217;s not that excellent art isn&#8217;t being made, it&#8217;s that it isn&#8217;t being chosen for support by institutions and canonization the way it was in the decades he&#8217;s nostalgic for.  But I promise you, it is being made.<em></em></p>
<p>It&#8217;s just that I&#8217;m not going to the Kennedy Center or Lincoln Center  or Broadway to see it (and that&#8217;s a whole &#8216;nother discussion about the cost of art to working people, including actual artists), but places like La Mama ETC, and Manhattan  Theatre Source, and the Fringe Festival (yes, as much as we all love to complain about the Fringe Festival).  It&#8217;s being done by groups like New York  Theater Experiment and Company XIV.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s often being done in the low, low budget shadows.</p>
<p>One of the most daring,  emotionally riveting and heartstoppingly good pieces of theater I&#8217;ve  ever seen to this day was called <em>The Warzone is My Bed</em>, and it was done  at La Mama with no sets but one wall and a bed.  And I have no idea what, if anything, happened to it after the end of its 2007 showcase run.</p>
<p>I think about the projects I&#8217;ve worked for which have brought me to both tears and elation, night after night as I sat and ran the cues.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s not enough excellent art being chosen for financial support and further production and distribution.  That doesn&#8217;t mean that no one&#8217;s making it.  It means no one&#8217;s paying attention.  Or that the people who are don&#8217;t have the financial means to bring it to a wider market.  Or that the people with the financial means are making bad judgments about what&#8217;s good art.  Or that we all lack faith (maybe justifiably, given the box office success of <em>No Strings Attached</em> and <em>Jackass 3D</em>) in the willingness of the wider citizenry to pay for daring, challenging performing arts.</p>
<p>But in any of those cases, if we were to actually, substantially, visibly support the most talented and insightful of individual young artists, I bet we wouldn&#8217;t be complaining about not having enough good art.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/411/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/411/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/411/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/411/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/411/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/411/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/411/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/411/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/411/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/411/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/411/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/411/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/411/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/411/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=411&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://chavisory.wordpress.com/2011/02/22/not-enough-excellent-art-o-rly/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>27</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/b100351d8f72708d2aa3f573cb61a9af?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">chavisory</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>I Will Check My Phone At Dinner And You Will Deal With It</title>
		<link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/02/21/phones-at-dinner/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2011/02/21/phones-at-dinner/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2011 05:21:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>MG Siegler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=277330</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img class="alignright size-full wp-image-277342" title="din" src="http://tctechcrunch.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/din.png" alt="" />The next time you go out to dinner, look around. Depending on the restaurant, there will be anywhere from a few people with their heads buried in their phones, to a <em>ton</em> of people in that position. If you don't see any, keep watching, you will.

This topic of discussion came up this past weekend when I took a trip outside of the Bay Area bubble to go visit my parents. My mother has the stance that I can only assume most mothers do: you shouldn't check your phone at the dinner table. So naturally, to comply with her request, every few minutes I would check my phone <em>under</em> the table.<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=277330&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-277342" title="din" src="http://tctechcrunch.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/din.png?w=330&#038;h=260" alt="" width="330" height="260" />The next time you go out to dinner, look around. Depending on the restaurant, there will be anywhere from a few people with their heads buried in their phones, to a <em>ton</em> of people in that position. If you don&#8217;t see any, keep watching, you will.</p>
<p>This topic of discussion came up this past weekend when I took a trip outside of the Bay Area bubble to go visit my parents. My mother has the stance that I can only assume most mothers do: you shouldn&#8217;t check your phone at the dinner table. So naturally, to comply with her request, every few minutes I would check my phone <em>under</em> the table.</p>
<p>I&#8217;d pretend to read the menu or fix my napkin to just be slyly looking straight down at my device beneath her line of sight — you know the drill. And while I was doing that, I would look around. Sure enough, there were a half dozen other people at the tables around me doing the same thing.</p>
<p>Love it or hate it, this is becoming the norm. And when it fully becomes the norm, there will no longer be the same stigma attached to checking your phone at a restaurant. Naturally, my mother refuses to believe this will happen, but it&#8217;s happening already. Go out to dinner with people in their 20s or 30s. Or worse, go out to dinner with teenagers.</p>
<p>When I go out to dinner with my peers these days, it&#8217;s not considered weird at all to pull out your phone. In fact, the situation has sort of reversed itself: you feel awkward if everyone else is using their phones and you&#8217;re not. It happens. A lot.</p>
<p>Obviously, at a fancy restaurant this behavior is less prevalent than at a bar. But it&#8217;s still increasingly happening all around you.</p>
<p>And it has made going to dinner <em>so much better</em>.</p>
<p>I shouldn&#8217;t have to state the obvious, but I will: using your phone in this context does not mean <em>talking</em> on the phone. That is still very frowned upon in restaurants for a very good reason: it&#8217;s annoying. A person talking on their phone is making noise, a person using their phone (as in surfing the web, sending texts, using apps, etc) is often doing the exact opposite.</p>
<p>Of course, the stigma around using the phone at the table stems from the same idea: it&#8217;s considered rude. But again, it&#8217;s not rude as in annoying, it&#8217;s rude as in you&#8217;re ignoring those around you. It challenges the social norm that when you go out to dinner with people, you&#8217;re supposed to have conversations with them.</p>
<p>That itself is a bit odd since it&#8217;s also considered rude to talk and eat at the same time, but I digress&#8230;</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s the thing: the common misconception that my parents and others have about using the phone during dinner is that it&#8217;s antisocial. But increasingly, it makes dinner even <em>more</em> social.</p>
<p>In the situations where I go out to dinner with my peers, use of the phone often augments the conversations being had. Don&#8217;t know who won game 3 of the 1995 World Series? Don&#8217;t know who directed that movie you all saw? It&#8217;s all right there in your pocket.</p>
<p>But even more fascinating is when the topic of conversation now often revolves around the phones themselves — or more specifically, what is on them. <a href="http://twitter.com">Tweets</a>, <a href="http://instagr.am">Instagrams</a>, <a href="http://belugapods.com">Belugas</a>, etc. These all now spark new conversations or tidbits of personal connection.</p>
<p>And then there are the shared experiences of doing things like checking-in or Foodspotting. One person at a table doing it often trigger everyone else to as well.</p>
<p>Forgive me, but it&#8217;s Dinner 2.0. And again, I&#8217;m having more fun at these dinners than I ever have.</p>
<p>Is part of it antisocial? Sure. Can it lead to distractions if you read a work-related email that you need to respond to? Of course. But this is the way the world works now. We&#8217;re always connected and always on call. And some of us prefer it that way.</p>
<p>What&#8217;s annoying to me isn&#8217;t someone using their phone at the table, it&#8217;s the people who really believe I shouldn&#8217;t be allowed to use my phone. Why? So I can repress the desire I have to check the phone while failing to engage in a conversation so I can be able to quickly excuse myself to go to the bathroom to check the phone?</p>
<p>My mother&#8217;s answer: yes.</p>
<p>Makes sense. It&#8217;s exactly why things are changing. Get with the program, or get out of the way.</p>
<p>What&#8217;s more likely? In ten years, everyone goes to a restaurant and talks to one another without pulling out their phones at the table — or in ten years, the table is <em>designed</em> in a way to enable you to more easily use your phones? That&#8217;s an easy one.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/277330/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/277330/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/277330/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/277330/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/277330/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/277330/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/277330/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/277330/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/277330/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/277330/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/277330/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/277330/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/277330/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/277330/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=277330&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2011/02/21/phones-at-dinner/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/710187cd963df0f92d11ddb31e6ae3db?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">MG</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tctechcrunch.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/din.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">din</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hopping hilltop towns in Tuscany</title>
		<link>http://randomthoughtsfrommidlife.wordpress.com/2011/02/21/hopping-hilltop-towns-in-tuscany/</link>
		<comments>http://randomthoughtsfrommidlife.wordpress.com/2011/02/21/hopping-hilltop-towns-in-tuscany/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2011 16:51:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>CMSmith</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Postcards]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Italy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Monteriggioni]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[postaday2011]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tuscany]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Volterra]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://randomthoughtsfrommidlife.wordpress.com/?p=347</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The second day of our trip we visited two small hill towns, Volterra and Monteriggioni, in the morning and Siena in the afternoon. Many of the Tuscan hill towns can be traced to Etruscan times. Others originated with the fall of Rome when lowland people fled to the hills and built walled communities, fortified against [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=347&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_348" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 600px"><a href="http://randomthoughtsfrommidlife.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/volterra_roofs1000.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-348" title="_Volterra_roofs1000" src="http://randomthoughtsfrommidlife.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/volterra_roofs1000.jpg?w=590&#038;h=391" alt="View of rooftops as we approach Volterra on foot." width="590" height="391" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">View of rooftops as we approach Volterra on foot. The antennas were a surprise.</p></div>
<p>The second day of our trip we visited two small hill towns, Volterra and Monteriggioni, in the morning and Siena in the afternoon. Many of the Tuscan hill towns can be traced to Etruscan times. Others originated with the fall of Rome when lowland people fled to the hills and built walled communities, fortified against barbarian invasions.</p>
<div class="mceTemp mceIEcenter" style="text-align:center;">
<dl class="wp-caption  aligncenter">
<dt class="wp-caption-dt"><a href="http://randomthoughtsfrommidlife.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/volterra-roman-theatre1000.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-356" title="Volterra-roman-theatre1000" src="http://randomthoughtsfrommidlife.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/volterra-roman-theatre1000.jpg?w=590&#038;h=393" alt="Roman theatre ruins in Volterra, Italy" width="590" height="393" /></a></dt>
<dd class="wp-caption-dd">Roman theatre ruins in Volterra, Italy</dd>
</dl>
</div>
<p>Volterra was one of the most important Etruscan cities. It was eventually absorbed by Rome and then fell to the Florentines. We were excited to see our first Roman ruins here. The ruins of the Roman Theatre in Volterra are among the best preserved Roman ruins in Italy.</p>
<div id="attachment_355" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 423px"><a href="http://randomthoughtsfrommidlife.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/volterra-roman-close1000.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-355 " title="Volterra-Roman-close1000" src="http://randomthoughtsfrommidlife.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/volterra-roman-close1000.jpg?w=413&#038;h=622" alt="A close-up view from a walled walkway of the Volterra Roman theatre ruins." width="413" height="622" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">A close-up view from a walled walkway of the Volterra Roman theatre ruins. </p></div>
<p>The stage wall of the theatre was standard Roman design with three levels from which the actors appeared—the bottom for the human characters, the middle for heroes, and the top for the gods. Only parts from two levels remain.</p>
<div id="attachment_357" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 423px"><a href="http://randomthoughtsfrommidlife.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/volterra-townhall1000.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-357 " title="Volterra-townhall1000" src="http://randomthoughtsfrommidlife.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/volterra-townhall1000.jpg?w=413&#038;h=622" alt="Palazzo dei Priori, Volterra's City Hall." width="413" height="622" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Palazzo dei Priori, Volterra&#039;s City Hall.</p></div>
<p>Volterra’s City Hall, the Palazzo dei Priori, claims to be the oldest of any Tuscan city-state. Towns like Volterra were truly city-states, independent of the pope and emperor and relatively democratic. (<em>Steves)</em></p>
<div id="attachment_358" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 600px"><a href="http://randomthoughtsfrommidlife.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/volterra-church1000.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-358" title="Volterra-church1000" src="http://randomthoughtsfrommidlife.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/volterra-church1000.jpg?w=590&#038;h=391" alt="A partial view of the ornate columns and coffered ceiling inside Volterra's cathedral." width="590" height="391" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">A partial view of the ornate columns and coffered ceiling inside Volterra&#039;s cathedral.</p></div>
<p>It took over two centuries to build Volterra’s cathedral begun in 1200. As you might expect, Catholic churches were prominent, elaborate, and in abundance throughout the region.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">&nbsp;</p>
<div id="attachment_353" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 600px"><a href="http://randomthoughtsfrommidlife.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/volterra-candles1000.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-353 " title="Volterra-candles1000" src="http://randomthoughtsfrommidlife.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/volterra-candles1000.jpg?w=590&#038;h=391" alt="Candles for Dad Grote and Annie." width="590" height="391" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Candles for Dad Grote and Annie.</p></div>
<p>I lit two candles in every church we visited that allowed it—one for my father-in-law who died the previous year, and one for my disabled sister Annie, a year younger than me, who died the month before we left for Italy.</p>
<p>I couldn’t leave Volterra without purchasing a small decorative lidded box made from the alabaster for which  they are famous.  We made a quick  stop for pizza Margherita, and then on to Monteriggioni.</p>
<div id="attachment_351" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 423px"><a href="http://randomthoughtsfrommidlife.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/monter-fort1000.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-351 " title="Monter-fort1000" src="http://randomthoughtsfrommidlife.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/monter-fort1000.jpg?w=413&#038;h=619" alt="Part of the fortifications in the wall surrounding Monteriggioni." width="413" height="619" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Part of the fortifications in the wall surrounding Monteriggioni.</p></div>
<p>Monteriggioni was built in 1203 and soon became a garrison town guarding the northern borders of Siena’s territory from the Florentine armies.</p>
<div id="attachment_352" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 600px"><a href="http://randomthoughtsfrommidlife.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/monter-piazza1000.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-352" title="Monter-piazza1000" src="http://randomthoughtsfrommidlife.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/monter-piazza1000.jpg?w=590&#038;h=391" alt="Monteriggioni's piazza." width="590" height="391" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Monteriggioni&#039;s piazza.</p></div>
<p>It is a very small town consisting of a large piazza where we stopped for refreshments, a Romanesque church, a few houses, restaurants and shops. A small street there is named for Dante who referred to Monteriggioni in his <em>Inferno.</em></p>
<p><em> </em></p>
<div id="attachment_350" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 600px"><em><em><a href="http://randomthoughtsfrommidlife.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/monter-church-1000.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-350" title="Monter-church-1000" src="http://randomthoughtsfrommidlife.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/monter-church-1000.jpg?w=590&#038;h=391" alt="The church in Monteriggioni." width="590" height="391" /></a></em></em><p class="wp-caption-text">The church in Monteriggioni.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_349" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 600px"><em><em><a href="http://randomthoughtsfrommidlife.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/monter-candles1000.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-349" title="Monter-candles1000" src="http://randomthoughtsfrommidlife.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/monter-candles1000.jpg?w=590&#038;h=391" alt="Candles in Monteriggioni for Dad Grote and Annie." width="590" height="391" /></a></em></em><p class="wp-caption-text">Candles in Monteriggioni for Dad Grote and Annie.</p></div>
<p>On to Siena. . .</p>
<p>Photos by Christine M. Grote and <a href="http://grotemonster.tumblr.com/">Mark Joseph Grote</a><br />
Copyright © 2011 by Christine M. Grote</p>
<p>See more links to posts about Italy on my <a href="http://randomthoughtsfrommidlife.wordpress.com/places-ive-been/">&#8220;Places I&#8217;ve Been&#8221;</a> page.</p>
<p>Sources:<br />
DK Eyewitness travel — Florence &amp; Tuscany, DK Publishing, NY, 2007<br />
DK Eyewitness Top 10 Travel Guides, Top 10 Tuscany, DK Publishing, NY, 2005<br />
Frommer’s Florence, Tuscany &amp; Umbria, 6<sup>th</sup> ed., by John Moretti, Wiley Publishing,NJ, 2008<br />
Rick Steves&#8217; Florence &amp; Tuscany 2009</p>
<p><em> </em></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/347/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/347/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/347/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/347/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/347/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/347/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/347/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/347/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/347/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/347/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/347/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/347/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/347/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/347/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=347&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://randomthoughtsfrommidlife.wordpress.com/2011/02/21/hopping-hilltop-towns-in-tuscany/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>30</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/b37a72b06ba47a8035118d00460018f3?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">christinemgrote</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://randomthoughtsfrommidlife.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/volterra_roofs1000.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">_Volterra_roofs1000</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://randomthoughtsfrommidlife.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/volterra-roman-theatre1000.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Volterra-roman-theatre1000</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://randomthoughtsfrommidlife.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/volterra-roman-close1000.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Volterra-Roman-close1000</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://randomthoughtsfrommidlife.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/volterra-townhall1000.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Volterra-townhall1000</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://randomthoughtsfrommidlife.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/volterra-church1000.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Volterra-church1000</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://randomthoughtsfrommidlife.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/volterra-candles1000.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Volterra-candles1000</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://randomthoughtsfrommidlife.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/monter-fort1000.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Monter-fort1000</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://randomthoughtsfrommidlife.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/monter-piazza1000.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Monter-piazza1000</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://randomthoughtsfrommidlife.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/monter-church-1000.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Monter-church-1000</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://randomthoughtsfrommidlife.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/monter-candles1000.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Monter-candles1000</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Tuesday tree: the forest floor</title>
		<link>http://dancingbeastie.wordpress.com/2011/02/22/the-tuesday-tree-the-forest-floor/</link>
		<comments>http://dancingbeastie.wordpress.com/2011/02/22/the-tuesday-tree-the-forest-floor/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2011 13:08:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>dancingbeastie</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[castle history]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oak]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[simple pleasures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sweet chestnut]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trees]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[walking the dogs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wildlife]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dancingbeastie.wordpress.com/?p=2040</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[One of the most entrancing things about woodland is that it is such an extraordinarily rich environment. While it might seem natural, walking under tall trees, to look up, there is just as much to be seen under your feet. Every step brings fresh details to notice. Having served my time of tramping along grey [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=2040&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One of the most entrancing things about woodland is that it is such an extraordinarily <em>rich</em> environment. While it might seem natural, walking under tall trees, to look up, there is just as much to be seen under your feet. Every step brings fresh details to notice. Having served my time of tramping along grey city streets, all concrete, grime and chewing gum, I never fail to be aware of the sensory pleasure of walking in the woods. Climb up this crumbling wall with me, into this favourite patch of mixed woodland, and see what I mean.</p>
<p><a href="http://dancingbeastie.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/101_4321.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2041" title="101_4321" src="http://dancingbeastie.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/101_4321.jpg?w=600&#038;h=450" alt="" width="600" height="450" /></a></p>
<p>Just up here&#8230;</p>
<p><a href="http://dancingbeastie.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/101_4322.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2045" title="101_4322" src="http://dancingbeastie.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/101_4322.jpg?w=600&#038;h=450" alt="" width="600" height="450" /></a></p>
<p>This is a woodland that was planted as a place of leisure and enjoyment by a laird of the castle perhaps a hundred and sixty years ago. It contains native and long-established British trees such as oak and beech, pine and sweet chestnut, holly and yew; but it is, strictly speaking, more of a garden than a wild forest, in that it is an &#8216;engineered&#8217; landscape. Thus it has tumble-down paths running through it, half-buried under the leaf litter; while some of the trees within it are imports such as Douglas fir and North American oaks. Though it looks untended now, we continue to cut back the rampant rhododendrons and to fill in the gaps with saplings as trees fall victim to old age or gales. I love its semi-wild state. Rabbits and hedgehogs find shelter amongst the tree-roots here; red and grey squirrels scuttle up the trunks; roe deer melt away like ghosts among the shadows or bound through the trees and away across the far fields. Once we saw a pole-cat here. On summer days, we hear the drumming of a greater spotted woodpecker in these woods, while on winter nights the quavering hoots of brown owls give dimension to the dark.</p>
<p><a href="http://dancingbeastie.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/101_4326.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2042" title="101_4326" src="http://dancingbeastie.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/101_4326.jpg?w=600&#038;h=450" alt="" width="600" height="450" /></a></p>
<p>At this time of year, the woods are rather stark and open with all the deciduous leaves gone from the branches. Or <em>almost</em> all, I should say: here and there, a stiff brown oak or beech leaf clings on through the worst of winter.</p>
<p><a href="http://dancingbeastie.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/101_4318.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2046" title="101_4318" src="http://dancingbeastie.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/101_4318.jpg?w=600&#038;h=486" alt="" width="600" height="486" /></a></p>
<p>Where have the others gone? Well, countless numbers of leaves are still underfoot, making a carpet as thick and springy in places as summer heather.</p>
<p><a href="http://dancingbeastie.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/101_4332.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2047" title="101_4332" src="http://dancingbeastie.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/101_4332.jpg?w=600&#038;h=450" alt="" width="600" height="450" /></a></p>
<p>Elsewhere in the wood, where the leaf litter is a little sparser, there are other things to be spotted at one&#8217;s feet. Here, amongst the oak leaves, are the sea-urchin-like spiny balls of sweet chestnuts. The tiny tear-drop shaped nuts scattered near them, however, are beech nuts, I think. The kernels of the chestnuts are a little bigger, though they do not grow big enough here for humans to eat. With more beechnuts and chestnuts than they can eat, no wonder the squirrels are busy here in the autumn.</p>
<p><a href="http://dancingbeastie.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/101_4328.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2048" title="101_4328" src="http://dancingbeastie.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/101_4328.jpg?w=600&#038;h=450" alt="" width="600" height="450" /></a></p>
<p>There are at least two kinds of oak growing in this wood. The pleasing scalloped outline of leaves of the native oak, <em>Quercus robur</em>, is instantly recognisable. But here amongst those is a larger, spikier leaf: an oak, I&#8217;m sure, but not a native. I don&#8217;t know &#8211; there is no-one now on the estate whom I could ask &#8211; but I think this is the leaf of the North American Nuttall oak (<em>Quercus nutallii</em>). If anyone knows better, I&#8217;d love to be told.</p>
<p><a href="http://dancingbeastie.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/101_4289.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2049" title="101_4289" src="http://dancingbeastie.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/101_4289.jpg?w=600&#038;h=450" alt="" width="600" height="450" /></a></p>
<p>In another step, you can find more shapes, equally distinctive. Here is a piece of lichen, like a branch of pale coral.</p>
<p><a href="http://dancingbeastie.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/101_4324.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2051" title="101_4324" src="http://dancingbeastie.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/101_4324.jpg?w=600&#038;h=450" alt="" width="600" height="450" /></a>In that picture, you can also see an empty beech husk (top), a cone from a Douglas fir with its characteristic flame-like wisps, a tiny spark of green moss and, oh look, rabbit poo! (bottom left)</p>
<p>And here is more evidence of non-human inhabitants: a pheasant feather lying amongst the other detritus of the woods.</p>
<p><a href="http://dancingbeastie.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/101_4325.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2052" title="101_4325" src="http://dancingbeastie.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/101_4325.jpg?w=600&#038;h=449" alt="" width="600" height="449" /></a></p>
<p>There is always something new to notice, on every walk. I hope you have enjoyed your brief foray with me &#8211; rabbit droppings and all &#8211; but I must leave you now. It&#8217;s high time I took my patiently waiting dogs out &#8211; for a walk in the woods.</p>
<p>For some views of this wood in May, see <a title="an evening walk" href="http://dancingbeastie.wordpress.com/2010/05/09/an-evening-walk/">An evening walk</a> and <a title="In the enchanted wood" href="http://dancingbeastie.wordpress.com/2010/05/25/in-the-enchanted-wood/">In the enchanted wood</a>.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2040/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2040/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2040/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2040/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2040/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2040/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2040/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2040/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2040/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2040/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2040/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2040/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2040/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2040/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=2040&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://dancingbeastie.wordpress.com/2011/02/22/the-tuesday-tree-the-forest-floor/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>46</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/f166f96ecf733519b9b7fc326194b0cd?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">dancingbeastie</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dancingbeastie.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/101_4321.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">101_4321</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dancingbeastie.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/101_4322.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">101_4322</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dancingbeastie.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/101_4326.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">101_4326</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dancingbeastie.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/101_4318.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">101_4318</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dancingbeastie.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/101_4332.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">101_4332</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dancingbeastie.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/101_4328.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">101_4328</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dancingbeastie.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/101_4289.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">101_4289</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dancingbeastie.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/101_4324.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">101_4324</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dancingbeastie.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/101_4325.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">101_4325</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Weekly Photo Challenge: Refuge</title>
		<link>http://butterflybound.wordpress.com/2011/02/19/weekly-photo-challenge-refuge/</link>
		<comments>http://butterflybound.wordpress.com/2011/02/19/weekly-photo-challenge-refuge/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2011 01:48:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>butterflybound</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Postaweek2011]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stuff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boracay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[postaweek2011]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Refuge]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://butterflybound.wordpress.com/?p=1894</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Boracay, May 2009. Photos taken with a Canon Digital IXUS 750 grateful slice:  the beach and the glorious sun that never lets us down Filed under: Photography, Postaweek2011, Stuff Tagged: beach, boracay, photography, postaweek2011, Refuge<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=1894&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_1895" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 500px"><a href="http://butterflybound.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/p5091110.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1895" title="CANON DIGITAL CAMERA" src="http://butterflybound.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/p5091110.jpg?w=490&#038;h=367" alt="" width="490" height="367" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Purple Haze</p></div>
<div id="attachment_1896" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 500px"><a href="http://butterflybound.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/img_2360.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1896" title="IMG_2360" src="http://butterflybound.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/img_2360.jpg?w=490&#038;h=367" alt="" width="490" height="367" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Yellow Orange</p></div>
<div id="attachment_1897" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 500px"><a href="http://butterflybound.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/img_2347.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1897" title="IMG_2347" src="http://butterflybound.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/img_2347.jpg?w=490&#038;h=367" alt="" width="490" height="367" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Blue Blue my world is Blue</p></div>
<div id="attachment_1901" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 500px"><a href="http://butterflybound.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/img_2371.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1901" title="IMG_2371" src="http://butterflybound.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/img_2371.jpg?w=490&#038;h=367" alt="" width="490" height="367" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Hues that Heal </p></div>
<p>Boracay, May 2009.</p>
<p>Photos taken with a Canon Digital IXUS 750</p>
<p>grateful slice:  the beach and the glorious sun that never lets us down</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://butterflybound.wordpress.com/category/photography/'>Photography</a>, <a href='http://butterflybound.wordpress.com/category/postaweek2011-2/'>Postaweek2011</a>, <a href='http://butterflybound.wordpress.com/category/stuff/'>Stuff</a> Tagged: <a href='http://butterflybound.wordpress.com/tag/beach/'>beach</a>, <a href='http://butterflybound.wordpress.com/tag/boracay/'>boracay</a>, <a href='http://butterflybound.wordpress.com/tag/photography-2/'>photography</a>, <a href='http://butterflybound.wordpress.com/tag/postaweek2011/'>postaweek2011</a>, <a href='http://butterflybound.wordpress.com/tag/refuge/'>Refuge</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1894/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1894/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1894/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1894/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1894/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1894/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1894/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1894/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1894/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1894/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1894/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1894/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1894/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1894/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=1894&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://butterflybound.wordpress.com/2011/02/19/weekly-photo-challenge-refuge/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/eace12ba8cb828e2f8d65028b8102c28?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">X</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://butterflybound.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/p5091110.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">CANON DIGITAL CAMERA</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://butterflybound.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/img_2360.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_2360</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://butterflybound.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/img_2347.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_2347</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://butterflybound.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/img_2371.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_2371</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What the Groundswell Means for Small Business:  Takeaways from Groundswell:  Winning in a World Transformed by Social Technologies</title>
		<link>http://debbiekenny.wordpress.com/2011/02/21/what-the-groundswell-means-for-small-business-takeaways-from-groundswell-winning-in-a-world-transformed-by-social-technologies/</link>
		<comments>http://debbiekenny.wordpress.com/2011/02/21/what-the-groundswell-means-for-small-business-takeaways-from-groundswell-winning-in-a-world-transformed-by-social-technologies/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2011 02:43:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Debbie Kenny</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Business & Entrepreneurship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Planning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Takeaways]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Charlene Li]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Groundswell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Josh Bernoff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Small Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social Media]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://debbiekenny.wordpress.com/?p=237</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve just turned the last page of the book Groundswell:  Winning in a World Transformed by Social Technologies by Charlene Li and Josh Bernoff, and I am seeing dollar signs flashing before my eyes. These are not the dollar signs that I can picture growing at the top of the income statement as my clients and [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=237&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="size-medium wp-image-242 alignleft" title="groundswell_cover" src="http://debbiekenny.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/groundwell_cover.png?w=180&#038;h=210" alt="cover of the book &quot;groundswell:  winning in a world transformed by social technology&quot;" width="180" height="210" /></p>
<p>I&#8217;ve just turned the last page of the book <em><a onclick="return mugicPopWin(this,event);" oncontextmenu="mugicRightClick(this);" class="zem_slink" title="Groundswell: Winning in a World Transformed by Social Technologies" rel="amazon" href="http://www.amazon.com/Groundswell-Winning-Transformed-Social-Technologies/dp/1422125009%3FSubscriptionId%3D0G81C5DAZ03ZR9WH9X82%26tag%3Dzemanta-20%26linkCode%3Dxm2%26camp%3D2025%26creative%3D165953%26creativeASIN%3D1422125009">Groundswell:  Winning in a World Transformed by Social Technologies</a></em> by Charlene Li and Josh Bernoff, and I am seeing dollar signs flashing before my eyes.</p>
<p>These are not the dollar signs that I can picture growing at the top of the income statement as my clients and I take advantage of the new opportunities created by social media.   Nor are they the dollar signs that some executives fear will come from lost sales and degraded brand reputation if they enable employees and customers to freely share potentially damaging ideas and experiences with the cyber community.  Rather, these are dollar signs that I am associating with major new expenses most small companies could never afford.</p>
<p>Don’t get me wrong.  I think the groundswell of social technology use, and the book, provide a wealth of opportunities for small businesses.  It’s just that the case studies, examples, and ROI analyses presented by the authors all have first year starting costs between $180,000 and $705,000.  While the results may be impressive, this level of investment is simply out of reach for many small organizations with limited time and financial resources.</p>
<p>But don’t worry.  There are lots of ways to take advantage of the groundswell for little or no upfront investment–if you are willing to think creatively and participate in the communities other people have already built.</p>
<h2>Creating a Groundswell Strategy</h2>
<p><em>Groundswell</em> starts with a wakeup call for business leaders who may have missed the fact that a rapid, grass-roots rise of social interactions on the internet is changing how customers perceive your brand, buy your products, and interact with your company.</p>
<p>The book provides social technology neophytes with an overview of various “groundswell technologies” such as blogs, wikis, bookmarking and tagging sites, social networks, forums, ratings, reviews, RSS feeds, and widgets.</p>
<p>It introduces an interesting and useful data tool called the “<a title="Social Technographic Profile Tool" href="http://www.forrester.com/empowered/tool_consumer.html" target="_blank">Social Technographic Profile</a>” and shows how you can use this metric to understand what percentage of online adults in your target market are Creators, Critics, Collectors, Joiners, Spectators, and Inactives.</p>
<p>It also defines a 4-step POST process that you can use to consider People, Objectives, Strategy, and Technology when you are deciding how to tap into the groundswell and use its power to benefit your organization.</p>
<h2>Defining a Groundswell Objective</h2>
<p>Perhaps the most useful part of <em>Groundswell </em>for small businesses is the continued emphasis on the need to start small and define a single objective for your social media program.  Your objective should align with the social media involvement of your target audience.  The authors identify 5 objectives:  Listening, Talking, Energizing, Supporting, and Embracing.</p>
<p><strong>Listening</strong>:  For small businesses unfamiliar with social technologies, listening is a great place to start.  As the authors point out, if you were at a cocktail party you wouldn’t just walk up to a group of people and start talking.  First you would work your way over to the group, listen to what they have to say, and then start adding your own comments to the conversation.  It’s the same with your social media strategy.  Find the places your target market are going online to talk about you, your products, or topics related to the problems you solve.  Then go there too, and hear what people are saying.  As you get better at listening, you may find a wealth of ideas that can help you improve your products and the overall experience you offer to your customers.</p>
<p><strong>Talking</strong>:  Once you’ve listened for a while, you may find that you are ready to join the conversation and start talking.  You can do this by posting comments on other people’s blogs, contributing ideas to social networking sites, answering questions on sites like <a title="Ask.com" href="http://www.ask.com" target="_blank">Ask.com</a> or <a href="http://www.linkedin.com/answers" target="_blank">LinkedIn</a>, and starting your own blog.  All of these activities can be free except, of course, for the time it takes you to do them.</p>
<p><strong>Energizing</strong>:  If you have a strong base of loyal customers or supporters, you can focus your groundswell initiative on energizing these advocates.  Find ways to enable and encourage them to post, comment, answer questions, and write reviews about your products or services.  Word of mouth recommendations and advice from your customers can go a lot further than anything you do on your own.</p>
<p><strong>Supporting</strong>:  There are many people in the groundswell who enjoy helping and supporting others.  The more you can help these people help your other customers, the more everyone will feel supported, and the less you will have to do to answer and respond to user questions.</p>
<p><strong>Embracing</strong>:  Small companies may actually have an advantage when it comes to embracing the groundswell and integrating your customers into the way your business works.  It’s hard for big companies to quickly change course, upend processes, and rethink the way they do business.  But you can adapt more quickly.  Find ways to use the groundswell to involve your customers in your decision-making processes, and implement their best ideas as quickly as you can.</p>
<h2>Engaging with Your Customers</h2>
<p>All of these objectives can lead to inexpensive and productive strategies for engaging with your customers and finding new ways to meet their needs.  Many small organizations have continued to ignore the groundswell because they feel they just don’t have the time or expertise to keep up a blog or monitor social sites for relevant content.</p>
<p>Without a clear objective and strategy for joining the conversation it’s easier to rely on old marketing techniques that have served you well in the past.  But relying on these old strategies alone will inevitably leave you far behind your competitors as they figure out how to use the groundswell to gain market share.  If you’re still ignoring this reality, it’s time to take a look around you and join the conversation.</p>
<p>ⱷⱷⱷⱷⱷⱷⱷⱷⱷⱷⱷⱷⱷⱷⱷⱷⱷⱷⱷⱷⱷⱷⱷⱷⱷⱷⱷⱷⱷⱷⱷⱷⱷⱷⱷ</p>
<h2>Your Thoughts?</h2>
<p>Are you ready to embrace the groundswell and join the conversation?  If not, what’s stopping you?  If you are, what do you see as the greatest opportunities for your organization?  Please share your thoughts.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/237/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/237/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/237/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/237/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/237/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/237/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/237/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/237/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/237/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/237/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/237/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/237/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/237/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/237/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=237&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://debbiekenny.wordpress.com/2011/02/21/what-the-groundswell-means-for-small-business-takeaways-from-groundswell-winning-in-a-world-transformed-by-social-technologies/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c4f01ab617233000b6ca0bb44d3b29e9?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">debbiekenny</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://debbiekenny.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/groundwell_cover.png?w=257" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">groundswell_cover</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>