<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2013 20:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Even You Can Be Nominated for an Academy Award!</title>
		<link>http://lilyincanada.wordpress.com/2013/01/10/even-you-can-be-nominated-for-an-academy-award/</link>
		<comments>http://lilyincanada.wordpress.com/2013/01/10/even-you-can-be-nominated-for-an-academy-award/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2013 19:09:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lily</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anne hathaway]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[academy award nominations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best actor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best actress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oscars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[looking ugly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[going crazy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mental disabilities]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[holocaust]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[daniel day lewis]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://lilyincanada.wordpress.com/?p=1943</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I’ve determined that every Best Actor and Actress has something in common. They pick roles that will shock people. They pick roles that are challenging. They pick roles that will make people love them because, deep down, they hate themselves so much. The least we can do is award them with some kind of trophy [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1943&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I’ve determined that every Best Actor and Actress has something in common. They pick roles that will shock people. They pick roles that are challenging. They pick roles that will make people love them because, deep down, they hate themselves so much. The least we can do is award them with some kind of trophy for all their hard work on top of their enormous salaries. We’re just the little people, after all.</p>
<p>If you want to go through all of the mess of going on auditions and getting discovered, go right ahead. That’s the hard stuff. If you want to find a role that will win you an Oscar, then you’ve come to the right place. Here are some tricks of the trade I&#8217;ve picked up from being an avid movie watcher:</p>
<p><b>Make yourself fugly</b>. No one wants to be on the big screen and look awful, right? Well, if you do, The Academy will most likely consider you “brave” and nominate you for one thing or another. For example, look at Anne Hathaway’s choice this year. She could’ve opted for a different role, but she chose the shave-your-head-snot-dripping-crying role. I can’t get over her bravery.</p>
<div id="attachment_1945" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 526px"><a href="http://lilyincanada.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/anne-hathaway-les-miserables-fantine.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1945" alt="Ew ew ew." src="http://lilyincanada.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/anne-hathaway-les-miserables-fantine.jpg?w=720"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Ew ew ew.</p></div>
<p>Others that have won or been nominated for awards by making themselves gross are: John Hurt (<i>The Elephant Man</i>), Mickey Rourke (<i>The Wrestler</i>), Charlize Theron (<i>Monster</i>), Gabourey Sidibe (<i>Precious</i>).</p>
<p>Side note: I realize that Mr. Rourke and Ms. Sidibe already looked like that before their roles, but still. They’re on the list.</p>
<p><b>Go insane</b>. Crazy characters are always fun to watch. There’s nothing better than a good old fashioned break-down. I believe that in order to play someone who goes off the deep end, you’ve had to have experience of it yourself. Just keep that in mind.</p>
<p>Examples of expert crazies: Vivien Leigh (<i>A Streetcar Named Desire),</i> Bette Davis (<i>Whatever Happened to Baby Jane?</i>), Ellen Burstyn (<i>Requiem for a Dream</i>), Natalie Portman (<i>Black Swan</i>).</p>
<p>Hey all girls! Whadda know?!</p>
<p><b>The old switcheroo</b>. To show The Academy what an amazing skill set you have, try portraying the other sex. This should prove difficult even for the best of them. If you go through with it though, you’ll no doubt be awarded for your talent. I mean, even Gwyneth Paltrow won for dressing up as a guy in <i>Shakespeare in Love</i>. Is that really Oscar quality? No. But she dressed up as a boy so it’s fine.</p>
<div id="attachment_1946" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 501px"><a href="http://lilyincanada.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/shakespeareinlove3.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1946" alt="So convincing. " src="http://lilyincanada.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/shakespeareinlove3.jpg?w=720"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">So convincing.</p></div>
<p>Other examples of people that can play<em></em> the opposite gender well are: Hillary Swank (<i>Boys Don’t Cry</i>), Dustin Hoffman (<i>Tootsie</i>), Jaye Davidson (<i>The Crying Game</i>).</p>
<p><b>Mental disability fall-back</b>. This type of role is tried and true. It’s basically a guarantee that you will win an award for playing someone “special”. It’s also a guarantee that someone is going to comment on this post and tell me that I’m being offensive. I’m just being brave, okay?!</p>
<p>Examples of people that were itching for an Oscar: Billy Bob Thornton (<i>Sling Blade</i>), Dustin Hoffman (<i>Rain Man</i>), Tom Hanks (<i>Forrest Gump</i>), Sean Penn (<i>I Am Sam</i>).</p>
<p>Oh look, all men. This type of role seems to come easy to them.</p>
<p><b>Holocaust roles</b>. Everyone knows how disturbing the Holocaust was, yet for some reason we like to keep reliving it by watching movies about it. For those of us who didn’t get a chance to actually be there, it’s a great way to see what really happened, right?</p>
<p>Examples of these challenging and brave roles: Roberto Benigni (<i>Life is Beautiful</i>) Liam Neeson (<i>Schindler’s List</i>), Adrien Brody (<i>The Pianist</i>).</p>
<p>If all else fails, try to morph into Daniel Day Lewis.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1943/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1943/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1943&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://lilyincanada.wordpress.com/2013/01/10/even-you-can-be-nominated-for-an-academy-award/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>38</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/215ec1caa359b1e7b68dc032d49d71b5?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F2.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lilyincanada</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lilyincanada.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/anne-hathaway-les-miserables-fantine.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ew ew ew.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lilyincanada.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/shakespeareinlove3.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">So convincing. </media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Middle Schoolers Intuitively Grasp Economics</title>
		<link>http://mattdickenson.com/2013/01/07/middle-schoolers-intuitively-grasp-economics/</link>
		<comments>http://mattdickenson.com/2013/01/07/middle-schoolers-intuitively-grasp-economics/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2013 14:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>You Study Politics, Right?</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[behavior]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[free markets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[micro-institutions everywhere]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mattdickenson.com/?p=1928</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Planet Money&#8217;s Dec. 25 podcast was another episode that was too good not to blog. They perform a classroom experiment related to gift-giving: randomly distributing ten different treats to a classroom of seventh-graders. Each student received one snack, which ranged in desirability from raisins and Fig Newtons to Three Musketeers and Sour Patch Kids. Upon [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1928&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Planet Money&#8217;s <a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/money/2012/12/25/167976196/episode-238-making-christmas-more-joyful-and-more-efficient">Dec. 25 podcast</a> was <a href="http://mattdickenson.com/2012/11/28/the-politics-and-economics-of-drug-dealing-part-ii/">another episode</a> that was too good not to blog. They perform a classroom experiment related to gift-giving: randomly distributing ten different treats to a classroom of seventh-graders. Each student received one snack, which ranged in desirability from raisins and Fig Newtons to Three Musketeers and Sour Patch Kids.</p>
<p>Upon initially receiving their gifts, the kids gave an estimate of how much they liked what they received on a scale from 1 to 10. The total utility of the class at this stage of the experiment was 50. It took about 11.8 seconds for one of the middle schoolers to suggest that they could all be better off by trading. After one minute of swapping, the class&#8217;s utility went up to 82.</p>
<p>Economists are used to this sort of thing, but take a minute to appreciate how significant this is. The students&#8217; assessment of how well off they were went up <em>60 percent</em> in only 60 seconds. That&#8217;s without the addition of any other resources except time, and a free market. Without any more &#8220;stuff,&#8221; they still achieved more happiness.</p>
<p>This reminded me of two economics lessons related to trade. The first reminder was of R.A. Radford&#8217;s classic article, &#8220;The Economic Organization of a P.O.W. Camp.&#8221; Radford discusses how soldiers would trade items from their Red Cross packets (gifts, of a sort) to achieve greater total utility. There was so much utility left on the table in the initial allocation that a middleman&#8211;a chaplain, if I recall correctly&#8211;was able to facilitate the trades and turn his own packet into two as a reward for his efforts. (See <a href="http://www.econtalk.org/archives/2008/10/munger_on_middl.html">this podcast</a> for a discussion of the paper.)</p>
<p>The second reminder was of a very similar classroom experiment. Marc Bellemare runs a <a href="http://marcfbellemare.com/wordpress/2012/09/the-trading-game/">trading game</a> at the beginning of his microeconomics course. It has the same setup as above: a random initial allocation of goods (in this case, inexpensive toys and trinkets), pre-trade measure of aggregate utility, a short trading period (five minutes), and a post-trade utility increase. Last fall his students experienced similar gains to the middle schoolers discussed above:</p>
<blockquote><p>When I ran the Trading Game last week, my class’ “aggregate welfare” went from 128 to about 180, if I recall correctly, and you could just see that it had become obvious to students that (in this context of well enforced property rights) trade not only left no one worse off, but it increased aggregate welfare.</p></blockquote>
<p>One final, interesting aspect gets brought up in the Planet Money podcast but not resolved: several of the students seem rather displeased with what they get, even though it was a <em>gift</em>. They are certainly no worse off but it does seem odd to assign a value of 0 (i.e. no different than their pre-gift utility) after receiving something that they did not have to work for. The Planet Money hosts seem to think that the kids should be happier.</p>
<p>It seems to me that the kids are grasping another subtle economic concept&#8211;<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Opportunity_cost">opportunity cost</a>. Even though they had no candy initially and had done nothing to earn it, the experiment publicly gave everyone an opportunity for a gift and they could see what their fellow students received. The kids may have assigned some value to their expected gift (the average of those around them, say) before they received anything. If what they got was worth less to them than what they expected, they were disappointed because they had lost the opportunity for something better. (Keep in mind that at that stage of the experiment they did not know that trading would occur.) The takeaway from this last comment is that the experiment actually includes an additional treatment because participants can see what others receive, and that changes their expectations.</p>
<p>For a tongue-in-cheek discussion of how additional choices can reduce utility, see the video below:</p>
<span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='640' height='390' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/VVp8UGjECt4?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;start=80&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1928/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1928/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1928&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://mattdickenson.com/2013/01/07/middle-schoolers-intuitively-grasp-economics/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/21acab710c6e17104c2af7bf8390a9d5?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F2.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">yspr</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Zeus Announces Contest to Name New God</title>
		<link>http://moviewriternyu.wordpress.com/2013/01/08/zeus-announces-contest-to-name-new-god/</link>
		<comments>http://moviewriternyu.wordpress.com/2013/01/08/zeus-announces-contest-to-name-new-god/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2013 01:41:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>moviewriternyu</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Philosophy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Greek Gods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Modern Philosophers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mount Olympus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[satire humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zeus]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://moviewriternyu.wordpress.com/?p=928</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This Modern Philosopher received the thrill of a lifetime today when he got to put on his formal toga and take a trip to Mount Olympus for an announcement from Zeus. Not only does the &#8220;Father of the Gods&#8221; rarely ever make a public appearance, but he also never allows mortals to set foot on [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=928&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://moviewriternyu.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/zeus.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-929" alt="zeus" src="http://moviewriternyu.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/zeus.jpg?w=293&#038;h=300" width="293" height="300" /></a>This Modern Philosopher received the thrill of a lifetime today when he got to put on his formal toga and take a trip to Mount Olympus for an announcement from Zeus.</p>
<p>Not only does the &#8220;Father of the Gods&#8221; rarely ever make a public appearance, but he also never allows mortals to set foot on his home turf.   So, I knew this had to be a big deal when Hermes arrived to pick me up and fly me back to the mountaintop.</p>
<p>The members of the media invited to the news conference were given no advanced warning as to what it was about, but no one really seemed to care.  We got to walk around Mount Olympus!</p>
<p>So what did Zeus want?  He&#8217;s upset that Greek Mythology has essentially vanished from cultural significance, and inspired by the Norse God Thor&#8217;s recent surge in popularity via the movies, decided that it was time to use the world of entertainment to re-introduce the Gods of Olympus to the masses.</p>
<p>&#8220;I am pleased to announce a contest to name the newest Greek God,&#8221; Zeus told those of us lucky enough to be there for the big moment.  &#8220;I have decided that it&#8217;s time to introduce a new God into the ranks, and he shall be the God of Social Media.  You get to decide on the name.  Please post your suggestions on our Facebook page, text them to 444-ZEUS, email them to BigZ@gmail.com, or tweet them to @Zeus_is_Loose.&#8221;</p>
<p>Zeus and a panel of celebrity judges will review all the entries and pick a winner.  In the event that more than one person suggests the winning name, all those who submitted it will have the opportunity to complete Herculean tasks until a winner emerges.</p>
<p>The winner will meet the new God, receive $1M in gold, get to select one enemy for Zeus to either smite or turn into a farm animal, and spend three weeks in the Greek Isles on an all expenses paid dream vacation for two.</p>
<p>How could you not be excited about this?  I&#8217;ve already submitted seven names and my fingers are crossed.</p>
<p>What do you think, Modern Philosophers?  What would you name The Greek God of Social Media?  Are you planning on entering the contest?  Do you think Greek Mythology should become hip again?  Which Greek God is your favorite?</p>
<p>Time to send the formal toga to the dry cleaners and do a little more brain storming on potential entries.  I look forward to hearing your Deep Thoughts on this one&#8230;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/928/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/928/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=928&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://moviewriternyu.wordpress.com/2013/01/08/zeus-announces-contest-to-name-new-god/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>67</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/ad04237121d3d9cb48ae905d2d305008?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">moviewriternyu</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://moviewriternyu.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/zeus.jpg?w=293" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">zeus</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>I Can Smile at the Old Days.  I Was Beautiful Then.  And a Better Mom.</title>
		<link>http://whatimeant2say.wordpress.com/2013/01/09/i-can-smile-at-the-old-days-i-was-beautiful-then-and-a-better-mom/</link>
		<comments>http://whatimeant2say.wordpress.com/2013/01/09/i-can-smile-at-the-old-days-i-was-beautiful-then-and-a-better-mom/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2013 23:45:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>whatimeant2say</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Memory Loss]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[class picture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[memories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[motherhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parenthood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photo]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://whatimeant2say.wordpress.com/?p=2779</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[When I was younger, I could remember anything, whether it had happened or not. ~ Mark Twain It&#8217;s picture day tomorrow.  Dimples is 10.  This is her last year in elementary school.  Her last class picture with less than 200 people in it.  I get it.  I should buy the picture.  However, she brought home [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2779&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3 style="text-align:center;">When I was younger, I could remember anything, whether it had happened or not. ~ Mark Twain</h3>
<p>It&#8217;s picture day tomorrow.  Dimples is 10.  This is her last year in elementary school.  Her last class picture with less than 200 people in it.  I get it.  I should buy the picture.  However, she brought home <em>four</em> order forms.</p>
<p>&#8220;What&#8217;s this?&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;For clubs.  We have to do a separate order form for each club.&#8221;</p>
<p>There are four clubs taking pictures.  Dimples is in three of them, in case you have not done the math.</p>
<p>Each picture costs approximately $500.</p>
<p>Just kidding.  But, they are relatively expensive.  Especially for someone who just had to pay to recover data from her not-dead-yet hard drive.</p>
<p>&#8220;So, I&#8217;m just wondering.  Do you know where <em>last year&#8217;s</em> class picture is?&#8221; I asked.</p>
<p>&#8220;Oh, we didn&#8217;t get one last year,&#8221; she quickly responded.</p>
<p>&#8220;Yes, we did.  What about the one for the year before that?&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Oh, we haven&#8217;t bought any for the last couple of years.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Yes, we have.  I&#8217;ve bought one every year.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Well, where are they?&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;That&#8217;s what I asked <em>you</em>.  But since you obviously don&#8217;t know, I will tell you.  They are in a file drawer.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Well, why are they <em>there</em>?&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Because every year, you toss them at me, and I stick them in the drawer.  And you never think about it again.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;But we should hang them up!&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Really?  This is what we should display on our walls?  Photos in which 5 years from now we will be able to identify 1/28th of the people represented?&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Well, we should put them somewhere.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;I&#8217;m not hanging them in the hallway, and I&#8217;m not paying for 4 more pictures to stick in my drawer.&#8221;  <em>Even though I just lost your whole lifetime of pictures when my hard drive bit the dust.  But let&#8217;s not dwell on the past.  Or the complete absence of it.</em></p>
<p>&#8220;Fine.&#8221;</p>
<p>Later on, she informed me that she was willing to deal.  One club picture and the class picture.</p>
<p>I think there&#8217;s enough room in the drawer for them.</p>
<div id="attachment_2783" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 490px"><a href="http://whatimeant2say.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/large_69614623.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-2783" alt="large_69614623" src="http://whatimeant2say.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/large_69614623.jpg?w=720"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">In a couple of years, I could probably pass this off as her class picture. She won&#8217;t know the difference, right?<br />photo credit: <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/hseikaly/69614623/">hseikaly</a> via <a href="http://photopin.com">photopin</a> <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/2.0/">cc</a></p></div>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2779/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2779/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2779&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://whatimeant2say.wordpress.com/2013/01/09/i-can-smile-at-the-old-days-i-was-beautiful-then-and-a-better-mom/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>43</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/df3763e720ee07d4bdf01a6226c4456c?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">whatimeant2say</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://whatimeant2say.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/large_69614623.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">large_69614623</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Somalia is Not India: The Importance of Cultural Competency</title>
		<link>http://breakboundaries.wordpress.com/2013/01/10/somalia-is-not-india-the-importance-of-cultural-competency/</link>
		<comments>http://breakboundaries.wordpress.com/2013/01/10/somalia-is-not-india-the-importance-of-cultural-competency/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2013 19:18:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>breakboundaries</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[civil rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[refugees]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social justice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://breakboundaries.wordpress.com/?p=570</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I have started reading the book The Spirit Catches You and You Fall Down, a story of a Hmong child and her encounters with the American medical system. As I read about the loyal social worker and her above and beyond commitment to Lia Lee&#8217;s family, I can&#8217;t help but think about my own experiences with [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=570&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://breakboundaries.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_3300.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-571 aligncenter" alt="Spirit Catches You" src="http://breakboundaries.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_3300.jpg?w=400&#038;h=400" width="400" height="400" /></a></p>
<p>I have started reading the book <em>The Spirit Catches You and You Fall Down</em>, a story of a Hmong child and her encounters with the American medical system. As I read about the loyal social worker and her above and beyond commitment to Lia Lee&#8217;s family, I can&#8217;t help but think about my own experiences with a refugee.</p>
<p>For confidentiality reasons, I&#8217;ll call him Nadif, which means &#8220;between seasons&#8221; because in many ways, Nadif was always in a liminal stage. He escaped his war-torn country of Somalia through a sponsorship, along with his sister. Little is known about his mother and father &#8212; whenever I&#8217;ve asked him, he would go on a tangent about a blind man and suddenly start speaking both French and English.</p>
<p>Nadif was intelligent: he was trilingual (he spoke English, Somali, and French fluently), he had dreams of becoming a water engineer in Somalia and he followed American politics religiously (although he said he&#8217;d vote for Mitt Romney, not realizing what that means to the welfare he was receiving).</p>
<p>He became a client in our program sometime in the early 2000s, following a psychiatric hospitalization, aggressive behavior landing him in jail and then being diagnosed and put on psychiatric medications. Although he had been in the mental health system for several years, it wasn&#8217;t until he was transferred to my caseload that I realized he ought to be diagnosed with PTSD and not schizophrenia. I had no idea he was from Somalia until his green card fell out of his chart, with &#8220;country of origin: Somalia&#8221; written on it.</p>
<p>He had always been adamant about becoming a citizen. He knew the process full well, having applied and been waiting for someone to walk him through the process. His previous case manager, though both compassionate and sensitive to Nadif&#8217;s needs, wasn&#8217;t able to spend the time Nadif sought to reach this dream of his, hence transferring Nadif to my caseload. I decided that &#8220;taking medications regularly&#8221; wasn&#8217;t as big of a priority to us as &#8220;become an American citizen.&#8221;</p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 410px"><img alt="" src="http://www.unhcr.org/thumb1/50052c9d6.jpg" width="400" height="303" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Somali refugees source: <a href="http://www.unhcr.org" rel="nofollow">http://www.unhcr.org</a></p></div>
<p>The mental health system has told Nadif repeatedly that he must take his medications and has gone as far as belittle him like a child for missing medications or refusing to take them. I don&#8217;t know about you, but I&#8217;ve never taken psychiatric medications and I know I would hate to take them since the list of side effects is endless. I don&#8217;t blame him for not wanting to take his medications, just like Lia Lee&#8217;s family struggled to find the benefits of giving their baby seizure medications.</p>
<p>I still remember someone in the office saying, about Nadif, &#8220;That Indian guy?&#8221; which really left me shaking my head. Nadif doesn&#8217;t even look Indian, on top of the fact that his last name is Arabic, which again is NOT INDIAN. How ignorant could we be to assume that he is something he was not! On top of that mishap, his chart indicated that he was Muslim; however, through my many conversations with Nadif, I discovered he attended church and had become Christian through the woman who sponsored him to the States. He talked about Jesus Christ with such awe, but often struggled with the thought that Jesus was white (don&#8217;t get me started) and equated his injustices with the fact that he himself is black.</p>
<p>My favorite memory with Nadif was after our gruesomely long process of getting him prepared for his citizenship test. With the help of a pro-bono attorney who specializes in assisting immigrants and refugees with obtaining their citizenship, we were able to get Nadif all the way up to his citizenship test. In that large and crowded waiting room, I sat with Nadif as he kept reading and re-reading his citizenship study packet (do you know who your senator is or what the Bill of Rights says? Nadif does).</p>
<p>He passed with flying colors and with the utmost confidence. We were told because of his criminal background (around the time of his first &#8220;psychotic&#8221; breakdown) that even though he passed, they would have to screen his results but that we should anticipate a notice in the mail for his oath ceremony. I am pretty sure I cried tears of joy. I know Nadif did. We walked out of that office and he tried to grab my cheeks, saying, <strong>&#8220;My little sister! Thank you! I love you!&#8221;</strong></p>
<p>Because I had to leave my agency to focus on graduate school, I don&#8217;t know if he ever received his letter about his oath ceremony. Through my old coworkers, it sounds like he may not have and might be back at square one, struggling to get enough cash for cigarettes and sodas. I don&#8217;t know if maybe he was hospitalized again and quickly treated as yet another zombie, walking the halls of inpatient psychiatric care.</p>
<p>The lessons we learn from <em>The Spirit Catches You and You Fall Down</em> is applicable not just to doctors and social workers; as human beings, we need to constantly learn about other cultures and increase our cultural competency. I chose to not pressure him to &#8220;do as he&#8217;s told&#8221; and focus on his dreams and his goals. Why did he want to become an American citizen so bad when he already had a green card? Because he wanted to be able to vote, because he followed our political process so closely, because he didn&#8217;t want the threat of deportation looming over his head if ever he was found guilty of God-knows-what, because he was done with Africa and because he thought America was the land of opportunity.</p>
<p>Refugees are seeking refuge. Refuge is defined as a place of protection from danger, a shelter and a place of safety. I can&#8217;t say that Nadif felt any safer or protected from danger here in America. Granted, he has food and shelter and a bit of money thanks to welfare, but what baffles me the most is one of the last things Nadif said to me before I left the agency.</p>
<p><strong>&#8220;I am going to go back to Africa. White man is god in America.&#8221;</strong></p>
<p>My hope is this: that American institutions &#8212; schools, medical offices, mental health agencies, social service organizations, even coffee shops and retail stores &#8212; will be filled with much more culturally competent people, who seek to meet newcomers where they are at, be driven to understand where people come from, and be committed to embracing the diversity that makes up this country.</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://breakboundaries.wordpress.com/category/civil-rights/'>civil rights</a>, <a href='http://breakboundaries.wordpress.com/category/culture/'>culture</a>, <a href='http://breakboundaries.wordpress.com/category/personal/'>personal</a>, <a href='http://breakboundaries.wordpress.com/category/refugees/'>refugees</a>, <a href='http://breakboundaries.wordpress.com/category/social-justice/'>social justice</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/570/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/570/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=570&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://breakboundaries.wordpress.com/2013/01/10/somalia-is-not-india-the-importance-of-cultural-competency/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>69</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/df636111d13281a8a9591dcd41ffb901?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Peggy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://breakboundaries.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_3300.jpg?w=545" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Spirit Catches You</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://www.unhcr.org/thumb1/50052c9d6.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The web responds to the death of hacker-activist Aaron Swartz</title>
		<link>http://gigaom.com/2013/01/12/the-web-responds-to-the-death-of-hacker-activist-aaron-swartz/</link>
		<comments>http://gigaom.com/2013/01/12/the-web-responds-to-the-death-of-hacker-activist-aaron-swartz/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2013 16:40:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Mathew Ingram</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Aaron Swartz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Freedom of information]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hacking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[JSTOR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Justice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[suicide]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://gigaom.com/?p=601342</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Aaron Swartz, an early Reddit staffer and founder of the open-web activist group Demand Progress, committed suicide on Friday at the age of 26, touching off an outpouring of grief and memorials from a wide range of friends and colleagues.<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=601342&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The open web and freedom of information in general lost one of their most passionate proponents yesterday, with the death of early Reddit staffer and Demand Progress founder Aaron Swartz, <a href="http://tech.mit.edu/V132/N61/swartz.html">who committed suicide on Friday</a>, according to a family member. He was facing federal charges for hacking into the JSTOR academic database and <a href="http://gigaom.com/2011/07/19/aaron-swartz-hacked-mit-library/">downloading millions of research papers</a>, but had also reportedly suffered from depression. He was 26 years old.</p>
<p>As the news of his death <a href="http://www.techmeme.com/130112/p3#a130112p3">spread throughout the web and social networks</a> like Twitter, there was an outpouring of grief and sorrow from some of his friends and those he had worked with on a number of projects &#8212; including the early development of the RSS syndication standard, the web.py software framework, the Creative Commons movement and the W3C web standards committee.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ve collected some of those comments and responses here (there&#8217;s also <a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/16fjjm/aaron_shwartz_reddit_cofounder_rip/">a Reddit thread</a> and a <a href="http://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=5046845">Hacker News thread</a> about his death, and Alex Howard of O&#8217;Reilly has collected <a href="http://storify.com/digiphile/the-internet-mourns-the-death-of-aaron-swartz">some tweets and links</a> in a Storify post):</p>
<p><strong>Update:</strong> Swartz&#8217;s family and his partner have <a href="http://rememberaaronsw.tumblr.com/post/40372208044/official-statement-from-the-family-and-partner-of-aaron">released a statement about his death</a>, in which they point the finger of blame directly at the U.S. Attorney&#8217;s office and say their prosecution played a role in Aaron&#8217;s suicide. The statement says:</p>
<blockquote id="quote-aaron%e2%80%99s-deat"><p>&#8220;Aaron’s death is not simply a personal tragedy. It is the product of a criminal justice system rife with intimidation and prosecutorial overreach. Decisions made by officials in the Massachusetts U.S. Attorney’s office and at MIT contributed to his death.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Sir Tim Berners-Lee, the creator of the web, <a href="https://twitter.com/timberners_lee/status/290140454211698689">posted a message after he learned</a> of the news, saying: &#8220;Aaron dead. World wanderers, we have lost a wise elder. Hackers for right, we are one down. Parents all, we have lost a child. Let us weep.&#8221;</p>
<blockquote class='twitter-tweet' lang='en'><p>Heartbroken about @<a href="https://twitter.com/aaronsw">aaronsw</a>, so brilliant, idealistic, soulful.  Here&#039;s where I first met him. <a href="http://www.thedailybeast.com/newsweek/2004/12/12/what-your-college-kid-is-really-up-to.html"> thedailybeast.com/newsweek/2004/…</a></p>&mdash; <br />Steven Levy (@StevenLevy) <a href='http://twitter.com/#!/StevenLevy/status/290113079642034177' data-datetime='2013-01-12T15:08:42+00:00'>January 12, 2013</a></blockquote>
<blockquote class='twitter-tweet' lang='en'><p>Shocked and saddened to hear about the suicide of Aaron Swartz, whom I first met when he was 14. @<a href="https://twitter.com/doctorow">doctorow</a>&#039;s eulogy <a href="http://bit.ly/VSk8Td"> bit.ly/VSk8Td</a></p>&mdash; <br />Tim O&#039;Reilly (@timoreilly) <a href='http://twitter.com/#!/timoreilly/status/290131206396313600' data-datetime='2013-01-12T16:20:44+00:00'>January 12, 2013</a></blockquote>
<p>Cory Doctorow, author and BoingBoing co-founder, <a href="http://boingboing.net/2013/01/12/rip-aaron-swartz.html">posted a long and heart-felt tribute</a> to Swartz and a discussion of his struggles with depression, saying:</p>
<blockquote id="quote-aaron-accomplished-s2"><p>&#8220;Aaron accomplished some incredible things in his life. He was one of the early builders of Reddit (someone always turns up to point out that he was technically not a co-founder, but he was close enough as makes no damn), got bought by Wired/Conde Nast, engineered his own dismissal and got cashed out, and then became a full-time, uncompromising, reckless and delightful shit-disturber&#8230; we have all lost someone today who had more work to do, and who made the world a better place when he did it.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Matt Haughey, the founder of Metafilter, <a href="http://www.metafilter.com/123777/Open-access-open-internet-closed-book#4772018">posted a comment on his site about Aaron</a>, whom he met while he was working on the Creative Commons project with Larry Lessig &#8212; and how at one programming event, Swartz had to come with his father because he was only 15:</p>
<blockquote id="quote-aaron-im-so-sorry-to3"><p>&#8220;Aaron, I&#8217;m so sorry to see you go. You were an amazing person who did incredible work that helps us all out and I really wish you stayed for many more decades so you could continue making society a better place to be. I&#8217;ll really miss you.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Brewster Kahle, founder of the Internet Archive, <a href="http://blog.archive.org/2013/01/12/aaron-swartz-hero-of-the-open-world-rip/">posted a memorial entitled</a> &#8220;Aaron Swartz, hero of the open world, dies&#8221; &#8212; and recalled working with the young man on Kahle&#8217;s Open Library project, which he helped to code:</p>
<blockquote id="quote-aaron-was-steadfast-4"><p>&#8220;Aaron was steadfast in his dedication to building a better and open world. Selfless.   Willing to cause change. He is among the best spirits of the Internet generation. I am crushed by his loss, but will continue to be enlightened by his work and dedication. May a hero and founder of our open world rest in peace.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>In 2007, Swartz wrote <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20070809020323/http://paste.lisp.org/display/40875">what many took to be a suicide note</a> (thanks to Nik Cubrilovic for the link) after he had been fired by Conde Nast (which acquired Reddit in 2006), a note that eventually led Reddit founder Alexis Ohanian to call the police and break into Swartz&#8217;s apartment. The young programmer <a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/reddit.com/comments/1octb/reddit_cofounder_aaron_swartz_discusses_how_he/c1oe1d">later explained that</a> he wrote it while he was in pain due to a medical issue, but some friends took it as a sign that he was struggling with emotional problems as well.</p>
<blockquote class='twitter-tweet' lang='en'><p>RIP Aaron Swartz. What a terrible, tragic waste. <a href="http://boingboing.net/2013/01/12/rip-aaron-swartz.html"> boingboing.net/2013/01/12/rip…</a></p>&mdash; <br />Timothy B. Lee (@binarybits) <a href='http://twitter.com/#!/binarybits/status/290111220491644928' data-datetime='2013-01-12T15:01:19+00:00'>January 12, 2013</a></blockquote>
<blockquote class='twitter-tweet' lang='en'><p>Aaron Swartz was one of my favorite people, and I&#039;m crying. <a href="http://j.mp/UdKWvB"> j.mp/UdKWvB</a></p>&mdash; <br />Adrian Holovaty (@adrianholovaty) <a href='http://twitter.com/#!/adrianholovaty/status/290102876888502272' data-datetime='2013-01-12T14:28:10+00:00'>January 12, 2013</a></blockquote>
<p>In 2007, Philipp Lenssen of the blog Google Blogoscoped <a href="http://blogoscoped.com/archive/2007-05-07-n78.html">posted a long interview with Swartz</a> about his development as a programmer, his work with Reddit and Creative Commons, getting fired by Conde Nast and a number of other topics:</p>
<blockquote id="quote-seriously-though-the5"><p>&#8220;Seriously, though, the Web is what we make of it. We have a powerful, widely-deployed, largely uncontrolled communication network. It’s up to us to decide where to go next.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>John Gruber of the Apple blog Daring Fireball <a href="http://daringfireball.net/linked/2013/01/12/aaronsw">also posted a tribute</a>, saying: &#8220;Aaron was a friend and a brilliant mind&#8230; he had an enormous intellect — again, a brilliant mind — but also an enormous capacity for empathy. He was a great person. I’m dumbfounded and heartbroken.&#8221;</p>
<blockquote class='twitter-tweet' lang='en'><p>wow so sad @<a href="https://twitter.com/aaronsw">aaronsw</a>. he was definitely fighting the good fight.</p>&mdash; <br />from the future (@nk) <a href='http://twitter.com/#!/nk/status/290033584591499264' data-datetime='2013-01-12T09:52:49+00:00'>January 12, 2013</a></blockquote>
<p>Swartz was also involved in the fight against SOPA, the draconian anti-piracy law that Congress tried to pass last year &#8212; this is a video of him discussing the campaign against the bill, which was later shelved:</p>
<span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='560' height='315' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/Fgh2dFngFsg?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span>
<p>Many of those who mourned Swartz&#8217;s passing wondered whether he knew how respected and loved he was by those who were close to him:</p>
<blockquote class='twitter-tweet' lang='en'><p>Angry about @<a href="https://twitter.com/aaronsw">aaronsw</a>&#039;s suicide. So much love for him on the Internet today, did he know?</p>&mdash; <br />Nelson Minar (@nelson) <a href='http://twitter.com/#!/nelson/status/290109762669002752' data-datetime='2013-01-12T14:55:32+00:00'>January 12, 2013</a></blockquote>
<p>Some of Swartz&#8217;s supporters in his fight against the federal charges related to his JSTOR hacking <a href="https://twitter.com/declanm/status/290032735479808000">questioned whether the threat of jail time</a> might have accelerated his depression, but others said he didn&#8217;t seem that troubled by it. As we wrote last year, Swartz &#8212; who had <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2009/02/13/us/13records.html">hacked into a federal database</a> in 2009 and download thousands of documents but never been prosecuted for it &#8212; gained access to a computer at Harvard and ran a program that <a href="http://gigaom.com/2011/07/19/aaron-swartz-hacked-mit-library/">downloaded a huge proportion of the research papers</a> JSTOR sells to universities and other institutions.</p>
<blockquote class='twitter-tweet' lang='en'><p>Fuck. The world seems emptier knowing Aaron&#039;s not in it. Hounded to death by the DOJ after the &quot;victims&quot; dropped charges. All is sadness.</p>&mdash; <br />Nat Torkington (@gnat) <a href='http://twitter.com/#!/gnat/status/290026251232636929' data-datetime='2013-01-12T09:23:41+00:00'>January 12, 2013</a></blockquote>
<p>Larry Lessig, who worked with Swartz on Creative Commons and other projects, has written a post saying what his young friend did with the JSTOR archive was wrong &#8212; although the principle may have been right &#8212; but that <a href="http://lessig.tumblr.com/post/40347463044/prosecutor-as-bully">the government&#8217;s case against him was reprehensible</a> and over-reaching in the extreme: &#8220;Here is where we need a better sense of justice, and shame. For the outrageousness in this story is not just Aaron. It is also the absurdity of the prosecutor’s behavior. From the beginning, the government worked as hard as it could to characterize what Aaron did in the most extreme and absurd way.&#8221;</p>
<blockquote class='twitter-tweet' lang='en'><p>The best tribute to <a href="http://twitter.com/search?q=%23Aaron" title="#Aaron">#Aaron</a> Swartz would be to keep this JSTOR torrent alive. Lasting legacy of a great prodigy - <a href="https://thepiratebay.se/torrent/6554331/Papers_from_Philosophical_Transactions_of_the_Royal_Society__fro"> thepiratebay.se/torrent/655433…</a></p>&mdash; <br />Suhail Kazi (@kazisuhail) <a href='http://twitter.com/#!/kazisuhail/status/290087983686754305' data-datetime='2013-01-12T13:28:59+00:00'>January 12, 2013</a></blockquote>
<blockquote class='twitter-tweet' lang='en'><p>@<a href="https://twitter.com/jdrch">jdrch</a> We don&#039;t know what Aaron was thinking. We do know that, two months from now, he was facing up to 50+ years for &quot;hacking.&quot; @<a href="https://twitter.com/JPBarlow">JPBarlow</a></p>&mdash; <br />Declan McCullagh (@declanm) <a href='http://twitter.com/#!/declanm/status/290032735479808000' data-datetime='2013-01-12T09:49:27+00:00'>January 12, 2013</a></blockquote>
<p>According to those who knew him, Swartz believed that it was wrong to charge so much for access to these papers, many of which were produced by academics for free, and in some cases with government funding (Maria Bustillos has <a href="http://www.theawl.com/2011/08/was-aaron-swartz-stealing">a great overview of the case</a> here). And even though JSTOR said it didn&#8217;t want to proceed with a case against him (and <a href="http://lj.libraryjournal.com/2013/01/academic-libraries/many-jstor-journal-archives-now-free-to-public/">has since opened up its database</a> &#8212; at least a little) the Department of Justice continued with its case, and Swartz faced a potential 35 years in prison.</p>
<blockquote class='twitter-tweet' lang='en'><p>Just heard about @<a href="https://twitter.com/aaronsw">aaronsw</a>: <a href="http://bit.ly/13oQE2B"> bit.ly/13oQE2B</a> Rends my heart. Horrible news for all who loved him, and the Net he loved as well.</p>&mdash; <br />Doc Searls (@dsearls) <a href='http://twitter.com/#!/dsearls/status/290147727814316033' data-datetime='2013-01-12T17:26:23+00:00'>January 12, 2013</a></blockquote>
<p>Bradley Horowitz of Google, and formerly of Yahoo, <a href="https://plus.google.com/113116318008017777871/posts/TirBnLBey8e">remembered talking with Swartz</a> about his plans to use Hangouts for journalistic purposes around the Occupy Wall Street movement:</p>
<blockquote id="quote-i-was-really-heart-b6"><p>&#8220;I was really heart-broken by this news&#8230; Thank you Aaron, for all you contributed to the world, and inspiring so many.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<blockquote class='twitter-tweet' lang='en'><p>This world needs people as brave and brilliant as Aaron Swartz. It just does not tolerate them well.</p>&mdash; <br />Siva Vaidhyanathan (@sivavaid) <a href='http://twitter.com/#!/sivavaid/status/290137149225959424' data-datetime='2013-01-12T16:44:21+00:00'>January 12, 2013</a></blockquote>
<p>In <a href="http://bloggingheads.tv/videos/1602?in=01:17&amp;out=04:06">this video conversation from 2008</a>, Swartz talked about how he got started as a programmer with Economist blogger Will Wilkinson:</p>
<p class="protected-embed-fallback">This embed is invalid</p><!-- blog has no permission to use protected embeds -->
<p>Swartz had prepared a webpage in the event that he <a href="http://www.aaronsw.com/2002/continuity">was &#8220;hit by a truck&#8221;</a> as he put it:</p>
<blockquote id="quote-i-ask-that-the-conte7"><p>&#8220;I ask that the contents of all my hard drives be made publicly available from aaronsw.com&#8230; please update the footer of this page with a link. Also email the relevant lists and set up an autoresponder for my email address to email people who write to me. Feel free to publish things people say about me on the site. Oh, and BTW, I&#8217;ll miss you all.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>This is a photo of the teenaged Aaron Swartz meeting Creative Commons founder and copyright activist Larry Lessig (<a href="http://www.aaronsw.com/weblog/000291">photo by Richard Gibson</a>)</p>
<p><a href="http://gigaom2.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/larryandme.png"><img src="http://gigaom2.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/larryandme.png?w=720" alt="larryandme"   class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-601349" /></a></p>
<p>Web pioneer and Harvard fellow Doc Searls <a href="http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/doc/2013/01/12/losing-aaron-swartz/">wrote a memorial post for Swartz</a>, along with a picture of him at a conference with Dave Winer &#8212; a conference Swartz had to be driven to by his mom, since he was only 15 &#8212; and said: &#8220;We haven’t just lost a good man, but the better world he was helping to make.&#8221;</p>
<p>Alex Macgillivray, general counsel at Twitter and former Google lawyer, said:</p>
<blockquote class='twitter-tweet' lang='en'><p>. @<a href="https://twitter.com/aaronsw">aaronsw</a> made the internet better in so many ways. We are all worse off for his passing. So. Sad. <a href="http://t.co/ynBGkhdx" rel="nofollow">http://t.co/ynBGkhdx</a></p>&mdash; <br />Alex Macgillivray (@amac) <a href='http://twitter.com/#!/amac/status/290154983591129088' data-datetime='2013-01-12T17:55:13+00:00'>January 12, 2013</a></blockquote>
<blockquote class='twitter-tweet' lang='en'><p>Remembering just some of @<a href="https://twitter.com/aaronsw">aaronsw</a>&#039;s life of service to an open Internet. Cannot express my sadness. <a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/pics/comments/16fjjm/aaron_shwartz_reddit_cofounder_rip/c7vmyea"> reddit.com/r/pics/comment…</a></p>&mdash; <br />David Weinberger (@dweinberger) <a href='http://twitter.com/#!/dweinberger/status/290140928310657024' data-datetime='2013-01-12T16:59:22+00:00'>January 12, 2013</a></blockquote>
<p>A comment on the discussion thread on the Y Combinator site Hacker News that <a href="http://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=5047398">appeared to be from Swartz&#8217;s mother</a> said: &#8220;Thank you all for your kind words and thoughts. Aaron has been depressed about his case/upcoming trial, but we had no idea what he was going through was this painful. Aaron was a terrific young man. He contributed a lot to the world in his short life and I regret the loss of all the things he had yet to accomplish. As you can imagine, we all miss him dearly. The grief is unfathomable.&#8221;</p>
<blockquote class='twitter-tweet' lang='en'><p>Heartbreaking news that my dear friend Aaron Swartz has died at 26. Imaginative, smart about everything, and, best of all, different.</p>&mdash; <br />Edward Tufte (@EdwardTufte) <a href='http://twitter.com/#!/EdwardTufte/status/290167154677006337' data-datetime='2013-01-12T18:43:35+00:00'>January 12, 2013</a></blockquote>
<p>The website <a href="http://public.resource.org">public.resource.org</a> &#8212; founded by freedom-of-information activist Carl Malamud, who worked with Swartz after with his earlier hack of the federal PACER archive &#8212; has gone dark as a tribute, with text that reads in part &#8220;Aaron Swartz made our world more free. Thank you Aaron for what you gave us.&#8221;</p>
<p>Microsoft research and sociologist Danah Boyd <a href="http://www.zephoria.org/thoughts/archives/2013/01/13/aaron-swartz.html">has written about the boy/man she knew</a> for the past nine years, and how he could be both brilliant and frustrating &#8212; but she says the thing that makes her the angriest is how unreasonable his prosecution was: &#8220;He became a toy for a government set on showing their strength. And they bullied him and preyed on his weaknesses and sought to break him. And they did.&#8221;</p>
<blockquote class='twitter-tweet' lang='en'><p>Heartbreaking news that my dear friend Aaron Swartz has died at 26. Imaginative, smart about everything, and, best of all, different.</p>&mdash; <br />Edward Tufte (@EdwardTufte) <a href='http://twitter.com/#!/EdwardTufte/status/290167154677006337' data-datetime='2013-01-12T18:43:35+00:00'>January 12, 2013</a></blockquote>
<p>David Weinberger of Harvard&#8217;s Berkman Center for Internet and Society has a post on his blog in <a href="http://www.hyperorg.com/blogger/2013/01/13/aaron-swartz-was-not-a-hacker-he-was-a-builder/">which he calls Aaron Swartz not a hacker</a> but &#8220;a builder.&#8221; And Weinberger points (as many others have) to a post from Alex Stamos, an expert in information technology who was an expert witness in Swartz&#8217;s case, who argues that his downloading of JSTOR articles <a href="http://unhandled.com/2013/01/12/the-truth-about-aaron-swartzs-crime/">wasn&#8217;t a criminal hack</a>: &#8220;I know a criminal hack when I see it, and Aaron’s downloading of journal articles from an unlocked closet is not an offense worth 35 years in jail.&#8221;</p>
<p>Micah Sifry of TechPresident <a href="http://techpresident.com/news/23363/democratic-promise-aaron-swartz-1986-2013">remembers meeting Aaron in 2004</a>, when he was 18, and being impressed with how dedicated he was: &#8220;I don&#8217;t know where he got the bug, but I understood it. If you have &#8220;change the world&#8221; disease, there is only one cure. And he tried mightily to change the world using every tool at his disposal.&#8221; And Dan Gillmor argues that <a href="http://dangillmor.com/2013/01/12/remember-aaron-swartz-by-working-for-open-society-and-against-government-abuses/">we should remember Aaron by working</a> for open society and against government abuses: &#8220;So amid my grief for Aaron, I’m angry — and committed to working for honorable enforcement of rational laws, and for values Aaron exemplified in his short life.&#8221;</p>
<blockquote class='twitter-tweet' lang='en'><p>The best tribute we can offer Aaron Swartz is to do what he did at his amazing best: work to expand an open Net and stop govt abuses.</p>&mdash; <br />Dan Gillmor (@dangillmor) <a href='http://twitter.com/#!/dangillmor/status/290152893217124353' data-datetime='2013-01-12T17:46:55+00:00'>January 12, 2013</a></blockquote>
<p>James Grimmelmann, a law professor at New York Law School who knew Swartz well, writes about some <a href="http://laboratorium.net/archive/2013/01/12/aaron_swartz_was_26">of the incredible things that he accomplished</a> at such a young age: &#8220;Aaron was a friend, and more than that, he was one of my heroes. No one I have known better embodied the bumper-sticker motto to “be the change you wish to see in the world.” It is hard to believe he is gone.&#8221; And Glenn Greenwald writes at The Guardian about <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/commentisfree/2013/jan/12/aaron-swartz-heroism-suicide1">what he calls the &#8220;inspiring heroism&#8221;</a> of Aaron Swartz &#8212; he didn&#8217;t just talk about internet freedom and civil liberties, Greenwald says, &#8220;He repeatedly sacrificed his own interests, even his liberty, in order to defend these values and challenge and subvert the most powerful factions that were their enemies. That&#8217;s what makes him, in my view, so consummately heroic.&#8221;</p>
<p>A number of academics have tried to honor Swartz&#8217;s commitment to open information by <a href="http://sciencecitizen.org/?p=219">making their journal articles</a> free to download. And Quinn Norton, who was Swartz&#8217;s girlfriend for a time, has written a heart-wrenching post about their time together <a href="http://www.quinnnorton.com/said/?p=644">here</a>. </p>
<p><em>Post and thumbnail images <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/deed.en">courtesy</a> of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Aaron_Swartz_profile.jpg">Fred Benenson</a></em></p>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=601342&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://gigaom.com/2013/01/12/the-web-responds-to-the-death-of-hacker-activist-aaron-swartz/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>36</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://gigaom2.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/aaron_swartz_profile1.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://gigaom2.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/aaron_swartz_profile1.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Aaron Swartz</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/0bdf7ab171ade0708a11fa3378e6d8cb?s=96&#38;d=retro&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mathew</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gigaom2.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/larryandme.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">larryandme</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Man Crush of the Year</title>
		<link>http://boywiththethorninhisside.wordpress.com/2013/01/08/man-crush-of-the-year-eddie-redmayne/</link>
		<comments>http://boywiththethorninhisside.wordpress.com/2013/01/08/man-crush-of-the-year-eddie-redmayne/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2013 18:14:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Nathan Beesley</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[fashion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[actor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[birdsong]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burberry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eddie redmayne]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[esquire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gq]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[les mis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[les miserable]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[man crush]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[men's fashion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sebastian faulks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sebastien falks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[style]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://boywiththethorninhisside.wordpress.com/?p=432</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Despite my pristinely made bedding, zealously strict grooming routine and severely bloated wardrobe, I am actually a happily heterosexual guy with a healthy fondness for all things female. This even extends to, though very rarely, actually entering relations with the fairer sex. I tend to take a somewhat uncompromising stance with regard to my sexuality [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=432&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://boywiththethorninhisside.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/eddie_redmayne_0.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-433" alt="eddie_redmayne_0" src="http://boywiththethorninhisside.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/eddie_redmayne_0.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>Despite my pristinely made bedding, zealously strict grooming routine and severely bloated wardrobe, I am actually a happily heterosexual guy with a healthy fondness for all things female. This even extends to, though very rarely, actually entering relations with the fairer sex.</p>
<p>I tend to take a somewhat uncompromising stance with regard to my sexuality (unlike the rest of my family and friends, I never thought I was gay) and this can create difficulties when one is trying to express ones respect for an attractive role model of the male persuasion.</p>
<p>Luckily, the growing number of English colloquial idioms has provided us with the perfect solution, namely the expression ‘man crush’. This expression allows even the most Neanderthal of homophobes to express their affection for anyone from Joey Essex to Boris Johnson, (although if you have a man crush on either of the aforementioned characters, I would seek immediate medical advice).</p>
<p>The New Year seems like an appropriate time to look back and assess which guy has left the deepest impression on me and, as far as I’m concerned, there is only one contender.</p>
<p>I first came across Burberry darling Eddie Redmayne in the television adaptation of Sebastian Falk’s <i>Birdsong</i>, a book which holds the record for bring me to tears at least twice. I was immediately struck by his impeccable attire, which radiated personal style even when he was donning military uniform. Anyone who can look dapper running into a hail of German machine gun fire is sure to be an idol of mine.</p>
<p>I was made more conscious of him by my favourite style publications, including <i>GQ</i>, who featured him on their list of 50-dressed men. It was Redmayne who later influenced me in quiffing my hair, though I’m still working on replicating his tousled, boyish take on the classic style.</p>
<p><a href="http://boywiththethorninhisside.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/eddie_redmayne.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-434" alt="eddie_redmayne" src="http://boywiththethorninhisside.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/eddie_redmayne.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>Redmayne’s personal style is everything I aspire to. He takes minimalist, versatile pieces of tailoring and mixes these separates to create something truly inspired and refined. There’s always a healthy dose of Sprezzatura, or ‘artful dishevelment’, in everything he does. In a world where men button things up to the extreme, Redmayne takes the opposite approach. Blazer collars are popped, pocket squares are stuffed in, casual henleys and knits are layered effortlessly under sharp, crisp suiting. You just get the sense that Redmayne has just thrown on what he’s wearing, but there’s clearly a strong thought process behind creating this impression.</p>
<p>Jessica Punter, the style and grooming editor for <i>GQ</i>, puts it better than I ever could:</p>
<blockquote><p>‘Baby-faced charm, artfully dishevelled hair and a killer suit. It’s a really simple formula, but boy, does it work’.</p></blockquote>
<p>Boy, does it indeed.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/432/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/432/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=432&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://boywiththethorninhisside.wordpress.com/2013/01/08/man-crush-of-the-year-eddie-redmayne/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/75c6fa19c29352064b65301cd27ac996?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">boywiththethorninhisside</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://boywiththethorninhisside.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/eddie_redmayne_0.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">eddie_redmayne_0</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://boywiththethorninhisside.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/eddie_redmayne.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">eddie_redmayne</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gun Control &#8211; Or People Control?</title>
		<link>http://embeddedinamerica.wordpress.com/2013/01/10/gun-control-or-people-control/</link>
		<comments>http://embeddedinamerica.wordpress.com/2013/01/10/gun-control-or-people-control/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2013 18:49:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>The Prophet</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Guns]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Heritage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gun control]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mexico]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[second amendment]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://embeddedinamerica.wordpress.com/?p=378</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Let&#8217;s face it, an armed society is going to have shootings. Any quick internet search will turn up shootings in every country in which guns are present. This is simply fact. At the same time, there are armed countries &#8211; like Canada &#8211; where shootings are rare. Canadians are armed, no doubt, it&#8217;s just they [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=378&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Let&#8217;s face it, an armed society is going to have shootings. Any quick internet search will turn up shootings in every country in which guns are present. This is simply fact. At the same time, there are armed countries &#8211; like Canada &#8211; where shootings are rare. Canadians are armed, no doubt, it&#8217;s just they don&#8217;t use their arms on their neighbors or their schools or family members. At least, not like us Americans do. The Swiss are armed too &#8211; literally millions of Swiss men have &#8211; get this &#8211; fully automatic weapons in their homes. In fact, nearly every Swiss man does. Same&#8217;s true of a few other northern European countries.</p>
<p>With notable exceptions, these countries experience few shootings.</p>
<p>So what is it about Americans and America that ends up with armed (legal or otherwise) citizens shooting each other?</p>
<p>There&#8217;s two questions posed in the title: Gun Control or People Control? If we are truly egalitarian and say there are no differences between say, us and the Swiss, then what makes it so that the Swiss can remain armed (with the most horrific of arms, the fully-automatic rifle) and yet not shoot each other? Because, if there is no difference, then gun laws won&#8217;t work. Period. The opposite side of that is that Mexico has very strict gun laws, outlawing most private ownership. So law-abiding Mexicans are without arms. You might argue that point and say &#8220;as far as we know&#8221; or some other disclaimer but then I&#8217;d point out the &#8216;law-abiding&#8217; part of the statement. Mexicans are dying, especially in terms of ratios, at record rates to gunfire.</p>
<p>So we have two opposites: heavily armed Swiss that rarely shoot each other and an unarmed populace of Mexicans regularly dying at the hands of illegally armed criminals. If guns are the problem &#8211; why this disparity? Shouldn&#8217;t the Swiss be shooting each other just every other hour?</p>
<p>Gun laws have not worked to keep guns out of the hands of criminals &#8211; whether in America or Mexico.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s true that in America, a good percentage of gun deaths are by those who legally owned guns. Gun laws restricting ownership would then, it would seem, curtail those shootings. At least, the <em>mass</em> shootings. After all, the crimes of passion would probably occur with a knife, club, baggy. Those headline-grabbing shootings, though, they might be limited. So, what gun laws that would most likely affect everyone would do is reduce the number of legally-owned guns that are used in mass shootings. Fair statement?</p>
<p>I can hear ya! No, you gun haters say, it would restrict the number of guns, which in turn would reduce the number of shootings, like from stolen guns. So the gun laws that would affect all gun owners would do is reduce mass shootings by those who legally owned the guns and those who stole legally owned guns. Now are we in agreement?</p>
<p>Even if that&#8217;s true, and I&#8217;ll concede it&#8217;s logical (I don&#8217;t know that logic will necessarily equal true, but let&#8217;s say it does), it doesn&#8217;t fix the problem of the illegal gun shootings.</p>
<p>First, I think we have to address what we want. Because if we do that, we&#8217;re going to see that we are trying to eliminate a very few events (however awful) by affecting a huge number of people. The many will suffer for the few. Heh, sounds like America.</p>
<p>What we want is the mass shootings to stop &#8211; right? Gun control people just said, no, we want all shootings to stop. OK, how? How do we do that? Mexico outlaws almost all gun ownership and I think very few would think that&#8217;s what is going to happen here, no matter how much they want that. So we aren&#8217;t going to eliminate all shootings.</p>
<p>The possible paths are:</p>
<ol>
<li>Nothing changes &#8211; no new restrictions.</li>
<li>The &#8216;assault weapons&#8217; ban is reinstated.</li>
<li>All semi-automatic guns are restricted.</li>
<li>All semi-auto and handguns are restricted.</li>
<li>All guns are restricted.</li>
</ol>
<p>The scenarios are:</p>
<ol>
<li>America &#8211; 275million guns. Convicted felons can&#8217;t own any. Regular Joes can&#8217;t own fully automatic weapons. Most gun ownership has some restrictions on it in every state.</li>
<li>Sweden &#8211; 4million automatic assault weapons plus hunting weapons in the hands of the public.</li>
<li>Mexico &#8211; no legally owned private weapons.</li>
<li>Canada &#8211; much like America with limited access to &#8216;assault weapons&#8217;.</li>
</ol>
<p>So, under 1/1, nothing changes. We live with the fact that, like with any object that can hurt or kill lots of people, under the right (or wrong) circumstances, they will do exactly that.</p>
<p>Under 2/1, we go back to where we were in the Clinton era. Columbine occurred under his watch. So did a rash of school shootings.</p>
<p>The rest, we don&#8217;t know the effects.</p>
<p>The real problem is being obscured and for good reasons. If you were our leaders, how would you frame the real problem? If you came out and said, &#8216;look, we have weapons in our country and we shoot each other. A lot. Canada has weapons, Sweden has weapons and neither country shoot each other much. Mexico has outlawed weapons and we all know what happens there. So maybe it&#8217;s not a gun problem but a people problem. What&#8217;s wrong with our people?&#8217;</p>
<p>Because that&#8217;s the real question. And the answer is the real problem.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/378/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/378/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=378&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://embeddedinamerica.wordpress.com/2013/01/10/gun-control-or-people-control/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>91</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/8db7e988780e08f730272265203406e1?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">norcalal</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>No More Excuses: Time To Be a Hijabi</title>
		<link>http://meditationsofamuslimah.wordpress.com/2013/01/09/no-more-excuses-time-to-be-a-hijabi/</link>
		<comments>http://meditationsofamuslimah.wordpress.com/2013/01/09/no-more-excuses-time-to-be-a-hijabi/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2013 17:30:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Meditating Muslimah</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Islam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[islam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Muslimah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hijabi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wearing hijab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[being a hijabi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[choosing to cover]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://meditationsofamuslimah.wordpress.com/?p=89</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I have been Muslim for about two and a half years now. About 6 months after that, I began dressing more modestly, wearing long sleeves, looser fitting clothes, etc. I knew then that I would eventually want to/ need to wear a hijab, but wasn&#8217;t ready for that. I&#8217;ve been seriously considering wearing a hijab [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=89&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://meditationsofamuslimah.wordpress.com/2013/01/09/no-more-excuses-time-to-be-a-hijabi/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>106</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/74fa25d2f44ea4a4cd915500361bf49c?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">meditatingmuslimah</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://meditationsofamuslimah.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/hijab.jpg?w=640" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">http://www.bing.com/images/search?q=hijab&#38;FORM=BILH#view=detail&#38;id=1ACC5394D61F116309DEAA3223FF7967C33F7593&#38;selectedIndex=31</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Super Brown</title>
		<link>http://graysonqueen.wordpress.com/2013/01/09/brown/</link>
		<comments>http://graysonqueen.wordpress.com/2013/01/09/brown/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2013 04:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>graysonqueen</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[sci-fi/fantasy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[batman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brown skin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[captain america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Comic book]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comic books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[costumes for brown people]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flash]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Green Lantern]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Luke Cage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marvel Comic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spider-man]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Super Hero]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Superhero]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://graysonqueen.wordpress.com/?p=829</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In the beginning, America was a mostly Caucasian dominated society.  From this world comic books were born and, with them, the legendary superheroes we know to this day&#8211;  Superman, Captain America, Batman, Ironman, Flash, Spider-man and on and on.  Men (and a few woman on occasion, because it was also a male-dominated society) drawn in the image of [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=829&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the beginning, America was a mostly Caucasian dominated society.  From this world comic books were born and, with them, the legendary superheroes we know to this day&#8211;  Superman, Captain America, Batman, Ironman, Flash, Spider-man and on and on.  Men (and a few woman on occasion, because it was also a male-dominated society) drawn in the image of their creators: Caucasian.</p>
<p>But that&#8217;s just the way things were.  An artist/creator can&#8217;t be faulted for writing what they know.  And on the times they reached outside that box, they created &#8216;ethnic&#8217; characters that were such stereotypes that they were almost racist.</p>
<p><a href="http://graysonqueen.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/apachechief.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-843" alt="Apachechief" src="http://graysonqueen.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/apachechief.jpg?w=300&#038;h=228" width="300" height="228" /></a><a href="http://graysonqueen.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/luke_cage.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-845" alt="Luke_Cage" src="http://graysonqueen.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/luke_cage.jpg?w=202&#038;h=300" width="202" height="300" /></a>Things have changed as the world becomes interconnected.  There are several African and African American superheroes and villains; a few Asian ones (Asia being any of those countries out near China, but it doesn&#8217;t mater as long as they know some kind of martial art or carry a sword), there are a few Hispanic ones (though I can&#8217;t think of them straight away and I&#8217;m sure some were rebooted out of existence), and I&#8217;m sure there&#8217;s an villain from India (just the one).  Meanwhile Canada and Europe have their own superhero teams galore, despite being some of the smaller percentages of the global population.</p>
<p>Statistically speaking, assuming super powers are gained by random chance; China and India should have a much greater representation in the super-powered community (Followed by the USA, Indonesia and Brazil.  Although now that I&#8217;m seeing this, it might explain why all superheroes are attractive. Imagine a bunch of Brazilian models flying around and saving the day.)</p>
<p>Now you might be thinking I&#8217;m mad or angry or something, but I&#8217;m not.  I&#8217;m really only pointing out a curiosity   As an artist I think  it would be more appalling to force people to create ethnic characters just for the sake of diversity.  If it doesn&#8217;t fit in the story, don&#8217;t do it. But on the other hand&#8230; it <em>can</em> fit in the story.  There are opportunities to have ethnic secondary characters and to run into someone who isn&#8217;t an English-speaking Westerner.</p>
<p>The problem is we are to afraid to let go of the old characters, the ones who no longer fit the current social constructs and have become outdated.  There is no room for new characters and new comics if the old ones are taking up most of the shelf space.  Will the major players be brave enough to move forward.  Will Peter Parker stay dead?  Will the reboots go on forever?  Yes.  Because they are still making money.  Sometimes it&#8217;s a little sad for me to see.  Often as I&#8217;m reading an issue I get angry that this big long soap opera/sitcom will never change.  Sure they&#8217;re trying, the new Green Lantern and a gay wedding, but does that matter when they have to do a retcon to fix everything back to square one?</p>
<p>What is more frustrating is that I find myself falling into the same habits.  My main characters are Caucasian,  they&#8217;re American and they&#8217;re men.  For my recent book I had to make a very specific attempt to integrate ethnicity into my novel.  Is that because I&#8217;m inundated with ethnically-slanted entertainment media?  I&#8217;m sure I could turn that question into a mile long debate.  The only thing that matters to me, a brown person and artist, is that I recognize the box I put over my head and work to fix it.  Because what I want in the next few years is a Halloween where I can dress as something without feeling awkward about being the &#8220;brown version&#8221;.</p>
<p>So I humbly offer this awesome spider based super hero for the taking.</p>
<p><a href="http://graysonqueen.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/brown.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-846" alt="brown recluse" src="http://graysonqueen.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/brown.jpg?w=300&#038;h=289" width="300" height="289" /></a></p>
<h1 style="text-align:center;">The Brown Recluse!</h1>
<p>P.S.  I know there are plenty of ways to explain off why Western, first world nations have a higher percentage of superheroes, but that&#8217;s not the point.</p>
<br /> Tagged: <a href='http://graysonqueen.wordpress.com/tag/batman/'>batman</a>, <a href='http://graysonqueen.wordpress.com/tag/brown-skin/'>brown skin</a>, <a href='http://graysonqueen.wordpress.com/tag/captain-america/'>captain america</a>, <a href='http://graysonqueen.wordpress.com/tag/comic/'>comic</a>, <a href='http://graysonqueen.wordpress.com/tag/comic-book/'>Comic book</a>, <a href='http://graysonqueen.wordpress.com/tag/comic-books/'>comic books</a>, <a href='http://graysonqueen.wordpress.com/tag/costumes-for-brown-people/'>costumes for brown people</a>, <a href='http://graysonqueen.wordpress.com/tag/flash/'>Flash</a>, <a href='http://graysonqueen.wordpress.com/tag/green-lantern/'>Green Lantern</a>, <a href='http://graysonqueen.wordpress.com/tag/luke-cage/'>Luke Cage</a>, <a href='http://graysonqueen.wordpress.com/tag/marvel-comic/'>Marvel Comic</a>, <a href='http://graysonqueen.wordpress.com/tag/spider-man/'>spider-man</a>, <a href='http://graysonqueen.wordpress.com/tag/super-hero/'>Super Hero</a>, <a href='http://graysonqueen.wordpress.com/tag/superhero/'>Superhero</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/829/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/829/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/829/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/829/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/829/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/829/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/829/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/829/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/829/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/829/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/829/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/829/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/829/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/829/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=829&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://graysonqueen.wordpress.com/2013/01/09/brown/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>123</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/ecb9c3d194e055d02edf6dfe48af5db3?s=96&#38;d=retro&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">graysonqueen</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://graysonqueen.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/apachechief.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Apachechief</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://graysonqueen.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/luke_cage.jpg?w=202" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Luke_Cage</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://graysonqueen.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/brown.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">brown recluse</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
