<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2012 01:02:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Skin Deep: Eating Disorder Recovery Tattoos</title>
		<link>http://arenomore.wordpress.com/2012/08/13/skin-deep/</link>
		<comments>http://arenomore.wordpress.com/2012/08/13/skin-deep/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2012 16:03:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Matt Wetsel</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recovery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anorexia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[body image]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bulimia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[compulsive overeating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eating disorder recovery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eating disorders]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[men with eating disorders]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recovery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recovery tattoo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tattoos]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://arenomore.wordpress.com/?p=808</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Currently Reading: Feminism is for Everybody by bell hooks Currently listening: Handwritten by The Gaslight Anthem  Sometimes beauty is skin deep &#8211; like when it comes in the form of beautiful artwork commemorating a commitment to being healthy and happy through the work of recovery. My own recovery tattoo got me thinking &#8211; who else out there [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=808&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Currently Reading: Feminism is for Everybody by bell hooks<br />
Currently listening: Handwritten by The Gaslight Anthem </em></p>
<p>Sometimes beauty <strong>is </strong>skin deep &#8211; like when it comes in the form of beautiful artwork commemorating a commitment to being healthy and happy through the work of recovery. My own recovery tattoo got me thinking &#8211; who else out there has some sweet recovery art? I&#8217;ll start us off, and then I&#8217;m excited to share some of the really great reader submissions that I received!</p>
<p><strong>My Own Recovery Tattoo:</strong><br />
My recovery tattoo was my first tattoo. I got it over the summer of 2005, when I was 22 and had been in recovery for about two years. February of that year, <a href="http://arenomore.wordpress.com/2012/01/13/smash-your-scale-and-anything-else-holding-you-back/" target="_blank">I smashed the scale</a> I had been using in the alley behind my first apartment with a triumphant and cathartic anger (the avatar for my blog, Twitter, etc. is an actual photo of my smashed scale!). The scale had become a physical representation of the otherwise invisible tormentor known as anorexia, an altar upon which my self-worth was constantly debated. I had been making strides in recovery and was doing very well, but I kept coming back to the scale. In February 2005, I hadn&#8217;t weighed myself in months. I came across it, and, in a moment of weakness and curiosity, stepped back on it.</p>
<p><span id="more-808"></span>I knew it was a bad idea, though, and talked to a friend about it the next day. Well, she was furious. She told me everything I already knew – that I didn’t need it, that it was only going to create problems and that I was stronger than this. I agreed with her.</p>
<p>She asked me to get rid of it. Despite agreeing with all her points, I hesitated.</p>
<p>“Just put it in the trunk of your car until you go back to your parents’ house.”</p>
<p>I thought this was reasonable enough. It wouldn’t be sitting under my bed, easy to get to. Still on the phone, I put on my coat and walked out back, scale in hand. I popped the trunk and was about to set the scale down, but I froze.</p>
<p>“Matt? Are you there?” I hadn’t spoken in awhile and my friend thought the phone had cut out.</p>
<p>“Hang on a second,” I said. I set the phone down in the trunk, freeing my left hand, and in one swift motion raised the scale above my head and threw it onto the pavement. The last time I stepped on that scale I wasn’t weighing myself – I was stomping on it with all of my strength.</p>
<p>It was such a turning point for me, and so empowering, that it seemed a suitable image for a recovery tattoo. I took some photos and provided them to a local artist recommended by a friend:</p>
<div id="attachment_809" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://arenomore.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/sst002-header.jpg" target="_blank"><img class="size-medium wp-image-809 " title="SST002 header" src="http://arenomore.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/sst002-header.jpg?w=300&h=167" alt="" width="300" height="167" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">HULK SMASH!</p></div>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://arenomore.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/recovery-tattoo.jpg" target="_blank"><img class="size-full wp-image-810 aligncenter" title="Recovery Tattoo" src="http://arenomore.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/recovery-tattoo.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="666" /></a></p>
<p>The phrase, “Sic Semper Tyrannis,” is on the Virginia state flag, and means, “Thus Always to Tyrants,” which seemed a fitting slogan to the tyranny of anorexia and my refusal to let it ruin my life. Yes, ‘Tyrranis’ is spelled with a U on my leg, which was an accident. I like it, though, because it’s an “imperfection” that I can’t change, and recovery is all about accepting yourself as you are.</p>
<p>For me, getting tattooed definitely played a role in how I thought of my body. Suddenly, I had a custom piece of artwork that no one else has or ever would have. I realized that in my adolescence I had built up a ton of insecurities about how I looked, but none of them had to do with ways I actually felt about myself, just ways I was concerned with how I thought <em>other people</em> might think or feel about me. Getting tattooed contributed in an inadvertent way &#8211; rather than focus on my body, I feel like people focus on the artwork, and suddenly I don&#8217;t care. That wasn&#8217;t my intention when I started getting tattoos but it&#8217;s made me appreciate my body more and feel more like it&#8217;s &#8220;mine&#8221; and not just some &#8220;imperfect&#8221; expression of a male body (as if there is such a thing!)</p>
<p>Enough about me, though. Let&#8217;s check out what others have done!</p>
<h2>Reader Submissions:</h2>
<p>Recovery pieces seem to range from elaborate, custom pieces to simple phrases which have special meaning to someone. Some go for a simple, elegant recovery symbol popularized by the National Eating Disorders Association and featured in their logo. Behind each one, though, is a commitment to health and recovery, and a reminder of how far each person has come.</p>
<p><strong>Lindsay Gemmel:</strong></p>
<p>Our first reader submission actually has multiple recovery tattoos! Here are her pictures and the story behind each one:</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://arenomore.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/lindsbreathe.jpeg" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-811" title="LindsBREATH" src="http://arenomore.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/lindsbreathe.jpeg" alt="" width="500" height="375" /></a></p>
<p><em>&#8220;BREATHE- when I was very sick with an ED, I often would attend support groups/individual therapy, and I had an extremely difficult time trying to talk because of my anxiety. I would be so anxious, that I would literally stop breathing until I suddenly had to take a deep breath of air. This tattoo, which is my own handwriting which my tattoo artist traced, reminds me to breathe through my anxiety! and also the 3 middle letters spelling &#8220;EAT&#8221;, remind me that I must continue to nourish myself to stay well. Also, it&#8217;s a reminder of <a href="http://www.projectbreathe.webs.com/" target="_blank">project brEAThe</a>, my amazing campaign that has kicked off tremendously.&#8221;</em></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://arenomore.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/lindssilver.jpeg" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-813" title="LindsSilver" src="http://arenomore.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/lindssilver.jpeg" alt="" width="500" height="375" /></a></p>
<p><em>&#8220;Silvers&#8217; Hope- Silver was my best friend who passed away in 2009. She also struggled with anorexia. She told me I was her hope. This is my daily reminder and a big motivation in my recovery.&#8221;</em></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://arenomore.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/lindsneda.jpeg" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-812" title="LindsNEDA" src="http://arenomore.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/lindsneda.jpeg" alt="" width="500" height="375" /></a></p>
<p><em>&#8220;ED recovery symbol- this speaks for itself! I got it done when I came home from finishing my treatment at Homewood. It was when my full recovery truly began. And it&#8217;s above my scars, and tells a story of how far I truly have come.&#8221;</em></p>
<p>Lindsay brings up a great point here &#8211; getting out of treatment doesn&#8217;t always mean that someone is &#8220;better.&#8221; I view treatment as the method of laying a strong foundation for long-term recovery. Sometimes we want so badly to just put it behind us that we rush it and want to be further along than we are &#8211; but recovery isn&#8217;t a destination. Recovery is something that you <em>do</em>, meal by meal, day by day.</p>
<p><strong>Sadie Jane:</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://arenomore.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/sadie1.jpg" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-815" title="Sadie1" src="http://arenomore.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/sadie1.jpg" alt="" width="353" height="295" /></a></p>
<p><em>&#8220;So here&#8217;s my tattoo. I have &#8216;Namaste&#8217; tattooed on my wrist, with the ED recovery symbol. I decided to ink my wrist mainly for the sake of how visible it is for me, especially when I am eating or struggling with any self-esteem or personal struggles. It reminds me to be mindful and that I have the strength to do this. I love the fact that it is not hidden because it ALWAYS brings up conversation. &#8216;Oh what does your tattoo say?&#8217; Then I explain what it is, and how in treatment we used to say Namaste at the end of groups, meetings, etc. I wanted to take that strong message and the power of that supportive community with me everywhere. This tattoo not only helps me in my recovery journey, it also creates opportunity to educate others.&#8221;</em></p>
<p>Thanks for sharing, Sadie!</p>
<p><strong>Cat S. Ginn</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://arenomore.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/cat1.jpeg" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-816" title="Cat1" src="http://arenomore.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/cat1.jpeg" alt="" width="480" height="480" /></a></p>
<p><em>&#8220;I&#8217;m in recovery from Anorexia for 8 years now –  since 2004. I&#8217;ve been fighting it all my life, it seems. I&#8217;m 50 years old now. I took a piece of my artwork to a tattoo artist. After discussing depth, color, and representation of the &#8220;journey&#8221; that is my life, he tattooed this on the inside of my right wrist&#8230; It represents a difficult, yet transitional point in my life&#8217;s journey. One that has tested my strength, resiliency, and ability to overcome whatever reality comes my way!</em></p>
<p><em>Take THAT, Anorexia! Take THAT, Bipolar Disorder! And Bring it on! Tourettes Syndrome! I&#8217;ve beaten the ass of the toughest amongst you!</em></p>
<p><em>THIS TIME you will NOT overcome! I WILL!&#8221;</em></p>
<p>Wow, Cat &#8211; that&#8217;s quite a battle cry! Thanks for sharing!</p>
<p><strong>Andi:</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://arenomore.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/andi1.jpg" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-817" title="Andi1" src="http://arenomore.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/andi1.jpg" alt="" width="215" height="101" /></a></p>
<p><em>&#8220;I have lived with disordered eating my entire life. when exactly did that became an Eating Disorder? I am not sure. I was 18 by the time I was actually anorexic, but I remember having disordered thoughts as young as 12. I entered Homewood Health Centre in Guelph Ontario in May of 2008, after my husband and doctor realized something had to be done. I was at an all-time low weight and slowly starving myself. Once there I learned not only how to cope and handle my eating, but also made some of the most important relationships I would ever have. Before leaving Homewood, a woman that I had become friends with and I decided a tattoo would be a great way to honor the time we spent there. </em></p>
<p><em>To me, it was also a stamp on my wrist to remind myself daily of the people I met, both patients and staff. Remind myself of how sick I was and how sick i didn&#8217;t want to be ever again. Remind myself to eat. But mostly I wanted people to ask me what it was&#8230;and what it meant. I wanted to be able to tell people that eating disorders don&#8217;t just affect young athletic woman. I wanted to be able to tell people that an eating disorder can hit at any age, any sex, any race, any religion.  I wanted to be able to share with people the knowledge that an eating disorder is a mental illness and my getting sick with one was no different than me getting cancer or diabetes. </em></p>
<p><em>I am incredibly proud of the tattoo on my wrist. Not only has it has made for some awesome conversations over that last four years, but it shows what a fighter I am as I fight every day to be in recovery and no longer let this illness run my life. I believe if society as a whole was more aware of what eating disorders really are then it would not only help reduce many of the negative stigmas but maybe save a life or two by recognizing the symptoms! </em></p>
<p><em>Andi &#8211; age 45&#8243;</em></p>
<p>Thanks for your passion and commitment to educating others about eating disorders, and thanks for sharing your story!</p>
<p><strong>Hilary:</strong></p>
<p><a href="http://arenomore.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/photo.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-839" title="photo" src="http://arenomore.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/photo.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="500" /></a></p>
<p><em>My name is Hilary and this is my recovery tattoo. I got it at the age of 19 ( I am now 23) when I was nearing the end of my treatment at Homewood Health Centre in Guelph. For me this tattoo represents my faith in a higher power that gave me a a second chance at life when I thought ED was going to take it from me.</em></p>
<p><em>I was driving back from Ottawa General with my Mum after a consultation to go into their inpatient program. The doctor there said he would get me in as soon as possible but he couldn&#8217;t say when it would be. We were on the 401 coming into the Toronto and it was dusk and the stars where just starting to appear. My entire body hurt and I was tired. I had a meeting in Guelph at Homewood the next day that my Dad was going to take me too. At that moment I looked up into the sky and prayed..for the first time in my life I asked that if there really was a higher power and if I was meant to survive this they would let met get into Homewood despite the fact I was quite a bit bellow weight restrictions. At that moment I really felt a spiritual connection with something. I had a feeling that someone out there had heard me.</em></p>
<p><em>I was right. The next day Homewood told me to go home, pack my bags and come back the next day to be admitted.</em></p>
<p><em>I do not follow any particular religion but  I know from this experience that there is something out that watching over all of us. I was not meant to die of anorexia, if I was it would have been for years ago. I am meant to LIVE and that is what keeps my fighting. My tattoo is meant to remind me of that and to give thanks for my second chance at Life <img src='http://s0.wp.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif' alt=':)' class='wp-smiley' /> </em></p>
<p><strong>Saige:</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://arenomore.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_0808.jpg" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-834" title="Saige1" src="http://arenomore.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_0808.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="373" /></a></p>
<p><em> Time and time again, my eating disorder has made me feel like a prisoner of my own mind. &#8220;Free your mind&#8221; (in my best friend&#8217;s handwriting who has been my main support through it all) is a continued reminder to allow my mind to be free from my eating disorder. </em></p>
<p>Thanks for sharing, Saige!</p>
<p><strong>Karly:</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://arenomore.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/karly1.jpg" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-842" title="Karly1" src="http://arenomore.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/karly1.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="284" /></a></p>
<p><em>I got this tattoo after getting out of treatment for the first time. It is a constant reminder for me to be strong even when I feel weak. I decided the heart needed to be uneven and strange to challenge my perception of &#8216;perfection&#8217;. Even things that aren&#8217;t perfect can be beautiful.</em></p>
<p>Thanks for sharing Karly, and stay strong!</p>
<p>If you have a recovery tattoo you&#8217;d like to share, I can add it to the post. If I get enough of them, maybe it can become a series!</p>
<p><em>Like this post? Stay up to date by ‘Liking’ my blog on <a href="http://www.facebook.com/pages/Until-Eating-Disorders-Are-No-More/215963771777724" target="_blank">Facebook</a>, following me on <a href="http://twitter.com/TilEDsAreNoMore" target="_blank">Twitter</a> or <a href="http://tiledsarenomore.tumblr.com/">Tumblr</a>, subscribe via email, or just leave me a comment to let me know what you think! </em></p>
<br /> Tagged: <a href='http://arenomore.wordpress.com/tag/anorexia/'>anorexia</a>, <a href='http://arenomore.wordpress.com/tag/body-image/'>body image</a>, <a href='http://arenomore.wordpress.com/tag/bulimia/'>bulimia</a>, <a href='http://arenomore.wordpress.com/tag/compulsive-overeating/'>compulsive overeating</a>, <a href='http://arenomore.wordpress.com/tag/eating-disorder-recovery/'>eating disorder recovery</a>, <a href='http://arenomore.wordpress.com/tag/eating-disorders/'>eating disorders</a>, <a href='http://arenomore.wordpress.com/tag/men-with-eating-disorders/'>men with eating disorders</a>, <a href='http://arenomore.wordpress.com/tag/recovery/'>recovery</a>, <a href='http://arenomore.wordpress.com/tag/recovery-tattoo/'>recovery tattoo</a>, <a href='http://arenomore.wordpress.com/tag/tattoos/'>tattoos</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/808/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/808/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/808/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/808/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/808/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/808/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/808/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/808/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/808/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/808/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/808/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/808/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/808/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/808/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=808&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://arenomore.wordpress.com/2012/08/13/skin-deep/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/802956b4ead5f5784b6aaba49d8c3bd9?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mattnomore</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://arenomore.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/sst002-header.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">SST002 header</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://arenomore.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/recovery-tattoo.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Recovery Tattoo</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://arenomore.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/lindsbreathe.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">LindsBREATH</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://arenomore.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/lindssilver.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">LindsSilver</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://arenomore.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/lindsneda.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">LindsNEDA</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://arenomore.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/sadie1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Sadie1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://arenomore.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/cat1.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Cat1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://arenomore.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/andi1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Andi1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://arenomore.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/photo.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">photo</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://arenomore.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_0808.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Saige1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://arenomore.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/karly1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Karly1</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Spine Poetry Project</title>
		<link>http://trippingpencil.wordpress.com/2012/08/01/book-spine-poem-project/</link>
		<comments>http://trippingpencil.wordpress.com/2012/08/01/book-spine-poem-project/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:06:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>The Tripping Pencil</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Book Spine Poetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Poetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spine Poetry]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://trippingpencil.wordpress.com/?p=274</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The following spine poems are courtesy of friends. With inspiration from Brainpickings&#8217; spine poems volume I, created in celebration of poetry month (April), I sent out an email asking folks to make, photograph, and send through spine poems. Here are the responses: &#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8211; Cape To Cairo Power and Folly Dark Continent, my black arse &#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8211; [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=274&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:left;">The following spine poems are courtesy of friends. With inspiration from Brainpickings&#8217; spine poems <a title="Brainpickings: spine poems volume 1" href="http://www.brainpickings.org/index.php/2012/04/16/book-spine-poetry-future/" target="_blank">volume I</a>, created in celebration of poetry month (April), I sent out an email asking folks to make, photograph, and send through spine poems. Here are the responses:</p>
<div id="attachment_275" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 346px"><a href="http://trippingpencil.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/bold-1.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-275" title="Bold 1" src="http://trippingpencil.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/bold-1.jpg?w=336&h=454" alt="" width="336" height="454" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">By Kate Bold</p></div>
<p style="text-align:center;">&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8211;</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>Cape To Cairo</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>Power and Folly</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>Dark Continent,</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>my black arse</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8211;</p>
<div id="attachment_276" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 378px"><a href="http://trippingpencil.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/bold-2.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-276   " title="Bold 2" src="http://trippingpencil.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/bold-2.jpg?w=368&h=277" alt="" width="368" height="277" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">By Kate Bold</p></div>
<p style="text-align:center;">&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8211;</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>Succulents of South Africa,</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>Joburg, sis!</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8211;</p>
<div id="attachment_277" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 346px"><a href="http://trippingpencil.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/bold-3.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-277" title="Bold 3" src="http://trippingpencil.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/bold-3.jpg?w=336&h=252" alt="" width="336" height="252" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">By Kate Bold</p></div>
<p style="text-align:center;">&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8211;</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>Discovering South Africa:</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>Great Shipwrecks</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8211;</p>
<div id="attachment_278" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 346px"><a href="http://trippingpencil.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/bold-4.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-278" title="Bold 4" src="http://trippingpencil.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/bold-4.jpg?w=336&h=252" alt="" width="336" height="252" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">By Kate Bold</p></div>
<p style="text-align:center;">&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8211;</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>Archy and Mehitabel&#8217;s</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>Songs of Innocence and Experience</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8211;</p>
<div id="attachment_279" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 346px"><a href="http://trippingpencil.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/craig.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-279" title="Craig" src="http://trippingpencil.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/craig.jpg?w=336&h=252" alt="" width="336" height="252" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">By Craig Groenewald</p></div>
<p style="text-align:center;">&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8211;</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>The state of Africa,</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>unzipped.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>Along came a spider.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>April fools histories.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8211;</p>
<div id="attachment_280" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 346px"><a href="http://theculturemuncher.wordpress.com"><img class=" wp-image-280  " title="Deva 1" src="http://trippingpencil.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/deva-1.jpg?w=336&h=252" alt="" width="336" height="252" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">By Deva Lee</p></div>
<p style="text-align:center;">By Deva Lee of <a title="The Culture Muncher: An African in Korea" href="http://theculturemuncher.wordpress.com" target="_blank">The Culture Muncher</a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8211;</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>Big fish,</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>raging rivers,</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>sense and sensibility.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8211;</p>
<div id="attachment_281" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 346px"><a href="http://trippingpencil.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/deva-2.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-281 " title="Deva 2" src="http://trippingpencil.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/deva-2.jpg?w=336&h=336" alt="" width="336" height="336" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">By Deva Lee</p></div>
<p style="text-align:center;">&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8211;</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>Kidnapped in</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>a horrible geography,</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>perishing poles.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>The silver chair,</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>dancing with strangers.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8211;</p>
<div id="attachment_282" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 346px"><a href="http://trippingpencil.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/deva-3.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-282 " title="Deva 3" src="http://trippingpencil.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/deva-3.jpg?w=336&h=252" alt="" width="336" height="252" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">By Deva Lee</p></div>
<p style="text-align:center;">&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8211;</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>Madame Bovary eats,</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>shoots,</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>and leaves Zoo city.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8211;</p>
<div id="attachment_283" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 346px"><a href="http://trippingpencil.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/erica.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-283" title="Erica" src="http://trippingpencil.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/erica.jpg?w=336&h=223" alt="" width="336" height="223" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">By Erica Lombard</p></div>
<p style="text-align:center;">&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8211;</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>Boyhood,</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>a haunted house,</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>another country.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>The heart is in exile,</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>no one belongs here more than you.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8211;</p>
<div id="attachment_284" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 346px"><a href="http://trippingpencil.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/jenny.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-284" title="Jenny" src="http://trippingpencil.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/jenny.jpg?w=336&h=252" alt="" width="336" height="252" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">By Jenny Truter</p></div>
<p style="text-align:center;">&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8211;</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>Skin deep,</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>I like it like that:</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>Eats,</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>shites,</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>and leaves.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8211;</p>
<div id="attachment_285" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 346px"><a href="http://trippingpencil.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/kate.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-285" title="Kate" src="http://trippingpencil.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/kate.jpg?w=336&h=252" alt="" width="336" height="252" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">By Kate Bold</p></div>
<p style="text-align:center;">&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8211;</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>There is honey</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>in the forest.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>Mushrooms,</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>wild flowers.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>Gardening without soil</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>in wildest Africa.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8211;</p>
<div id="attachment_286" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 346px"><a href="http://trippingpencil.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/lucy.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-286" title="Lucy" src="http://trippingpencil.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/lucy.jpg?w=336&h=448" alt="" width="336" height="448" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">By Lucy Morrow</p></div>
<p style="text-align:center;">&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8211;</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>On the road in wonderland,</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>south of the border,</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>west of the sun.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>Chances are&#8230;</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>adventures in probability,</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>and then</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>there were none.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8211;</p>
<div id="attachment_287" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 346px"><a href="http://trippingpencil.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/roderick.png"><img class=" wp-image-287" title="Roderick" src="http://trippingpencil.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/roderick.png?w=336&h=278" alt="" width="336" height="278" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">By Roderick MacLeod</p></div>
<p style="text-align:center;">&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8211;</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>Catch 22</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>just kids</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>learning how to play piano.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>Burning chrome:</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>the slaughterhouse five chronicles.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8211;</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://trippingpencil.wordpress.com/category/book-spine-poetry/'>Book Spine Poetry</a> Tagged: <a href='http://trippingpencil.wordpress.com/tag/poetry/'>Poetry</a>, <a href='http://trippingpencil.wordpress.com/tag/spine-poetry/'>Spine Poetry</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/274/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/274/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=274&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://trippingpencil.wordpress.com/2012/08/01/book-spine-poem-project/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/3d7962ea50117a6a47e527d6e15e7e17?s=96&#38;d=monsterid&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">trippingpencil</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://trippingpencil.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/bold-1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Bold 1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://trippingpencil.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/bold-2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Bold 2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://trippingpencil.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/bold-3.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Bold 3</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://trippingpencil.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/bold-4.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Bold 4</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://trippingpencil.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/craig.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Craig</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://trippingpencil.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/deva-1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Deva 1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://trippingpencil.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/deva-2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Deva 2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://trippingpencil.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/deva-3.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Deva 3</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://trippingpencil.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/erica.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Erica</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://trippingpencil.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/jenny.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Jenny</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://trippingpencil.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/kate.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Kate</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://trippingpencil.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/lucy.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Lucy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://trippingpencil.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/roderick.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Roderick</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Urban Regeneration: Making Good Use of Vacant Structures</title>
		<link>http://notebooknumbernine.wordpress.com/2012/08/13/urban-regeneration-making-good-use-of-vacant-structures/</link>
		<comments>http://notebooknumbernine.wordpress.com/2012/08/13/urban-regeneration-making-good-use-of-vacant-structures/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2012 19:51:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Michael</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Anthropology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[architecture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[city]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Detroit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[environment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[homeless]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Houston]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Manila]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poverty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[regeneration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Texas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[urbanization]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://notebooknumbernine.wordpress.com/?p=311</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[One of the saddest and most compelling indications of a city’s economic decline are the abandoned structures scattered all across its cityscape. They resemble dry skeletons–almost fossilized–haunting a rugged desert. One such city is Detroit. The Motor City lost much fuel after the economic recession, which climaxed at the end of 2008 and beginning of [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=311&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_316" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://notebooknumbernine.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/csc_0113.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-316" title="csc_0113" src="http://notebooknumbernine.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/csc_0113.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="354" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Formerly known as the Enron buildings (Houston, TX). Photo by Michael Mira.</p></div>
<p>One of the saddest and most compelling indications of a city’s economic decline are the abandoned structures scattered all across its cityscape. They resemble dry skeletons–almost fossilized–haunting a rugged desert. One such city is Detroit. The Motor City lost much fuel after the economic recession, which climaxed at the end of 2008 and beginning of 2009. Of course, the entire country felt its effects, its ripples even touched the shores of other continents, but for Detroit–a city whose main industry is automobile manufacturing–it was a hard blow. Once the auto companies such as GM saw the threat of bankruptcy in the horizon many employees were let go to cut costs, which increased the local unemployment rate. The smaller companies that didn’t have the might and value of the big boys did file for bankruptcy and its property foreclosed.</p>
<div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://notebooknumbernine.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/csc_0109.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-321" title="CSC_0109" src="http://notebooknumbernine.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/csc_0109.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="339" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Imagine this mostly-vacant building converted into a vertical farm. Photo by Michael Mira.</p></div>
<p>Many of these properties sit on desolate lots polluted by broken beer bottles, used condoms and the shattered hopes of the blue-collar working class that had spent years, if not decades, depending on company paychecks. The very mass who made Detroit economically robust through most of the 20th Century were the first victims of the economic crisis.</p>
<p>* * *</p>
<p>Somewhere in the Texas Hill Country, near Fredericksburg, a dusty little ‘ghost town’ greeted my mid-sized sedan without much enthusiasm. It may not have been impressed by my presence, but I was fascinated with its history. The town was established in the early 20th Century and had a small population from the beginning, but had a self-sustaining economy. It was a farming town like many of the dispersed towns in the vast state of Texas. When the Great Depression traveled to the South, many farmers experienced the brutality of the economic crash, and the difficulty in living in a microscopic town became too much to bear so the residents moved to larger towns in order to find better opportunities.</p>
<p>The hollow shells stared at me with broken windows for eyes, and the existential void beneath the layers of darkness reminded me of the abandoned buildings littered throughout the city of Houston. I’ve been documenting the evolution of the city photographically for half a decade, and in that time I realized two things: There is a large population of homeless citizens out on the pavement and that there are numerous unused buildings that have been empty for years. It’s ludicrous to me that there are shelters for these people, but a NO TRESPASSING sign and an idle security guard keeps A and B separated. Logic tells me that A plus B equals C, the solution in which abandoned buildings can be used as housing for the homeless, even if only temporarily. But politicians have a different equation, a different kind of mathematics, a different kind of logic. They would rather raze the buildings and sell the lot to developers, thus bringing business to the area, and that would pump money into the city. The only problem with this formula is that this will only extend the gap between those who have the opportunity to work in a brand-spankin’-new department store that had replaced a demolished building and those who are one rung below the laborers in the socioeconomic ladder. What is needed is a fusion of both channels in which the city can develop new businesses in replacement of buildings that are too hazardous and beyond repair, while those that are more stable to reconstruct can be used for the benefit of the community.</p>
<div id="attachment_322" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://notebooknumbernine.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_0036-3.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-322" title="DSC_0036 (3)" src="http://notebooknumbernine.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_0036-3.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="327" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Abandoned buildings can be a sign that a local economy has become stagnant. You can reverse this by simply re-developing parts of the city in order to bring in more business.</p></div>
<p>That is capitalism. I love capitalism because it allows anyone to climb to the top of the ladder through hard work–if given the opportunity. What cities throughout America need is not just a new approach in urban planning, but a new urban policy. Abandoned structures should not only be regenerated as a housing project for the homeless, but also as hosts for education centers to teach the citizens new skills that will allow them to be independent and self-sustaining.</p>
<p>* * *</p>
<p>Close your eyes. Imagine the Empire State Building or the Petronas Towers standing arrogantly before you. Now imagine miniature farms on every single floor instead of cubicles, desks and tacky suits. That is a glimpse of a vertical farm. The concept of urban farming was born in an era filled with environmental issues and mass urbanization. Urban farms not only provide locally grown produce to provide for the city’s hungry, but can also help reduce carbon emissions by cutting down the distance a large diesel-fueled truck has to travel between point A (the farm) and point B (the market). Large vertical farms can also create jobs in the local area. The same people that once loitered and begged on the streets can now be educated in the fundamentals of agronomy and hydroponic growing methods. You’re naive, people may scoff, but isn’t it better than a pessimistic outlook? Would you rather ignore the problems until it grows into a giant social tumor? The world’s population is increasing and more immigrants are coming into the United States. There is now a new sense of urgency in creating solutions to pressing issues. How can we close the gap between mass consumption and the rapid depletion of natural resources? How can we create sustainable cities? What are some new ways to tackle the problems that plague an urban environment, such as poverty, unemployment, homelessness and urban decay?</p>
<p>It doesn’t surprise me that Detroit is setting an example for the rest of the country by proposing the option of using abandoned buildings as shelter for the homeless to city officials as a possible solution to two of the city’s primary problems: homelessness and vacant buildings.</p>
<p>The vertical farm is not a new concept, but now, more than ever, architectural firms and non-profit organizations are making strides in actualizing it.</p>
<p>* * *</p>
<p>When I was driving out of the Texas ghost town, quickly turning into a silhouette against the pink and orange sunset, I took a final glimpse of the hollowed out buildings and houses in my rear-view mirror. The town resembled a disposed film set or a life-sized Legoland. I wondered if this was the same parting shot the citizens saw as they traveled outward to seek a better town almost a century ago.</p>
<p>It brought to mind the family of six I spoke to living in the slums of Manila, back in 2004. Manuel, the patriarch, told me that he was taking his family back to his hometown, out in the countryside, because economic disparity and hazardous pollution was too much to bear for his large family, especially the children. He has lived in the Philippine capital since he was 18 years old and was sad to leave his beloved city behind. I asked him if he would stay had the city officials–or anyone for that matter–came up with solutions for the web of problems, or at least had set up programs to alleviate the situation.</p>
<p>&#8220;If we (the community) had more resources to fix these problems, we would stay,&#8221; said Manuel. &#8220;No doubt about it.&#8221;</p>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=311&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://notebooknumbernine.wordpress.com/2012/08/13/urban-regeneration-making-good-use-of-vacant-structures/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c297bce0e903e6d9479fc5111dab64fd?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">blahzay</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://notebooknumbernine.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/csc_0113.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">csc_0113</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://notebooknumbernine.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/csc_0109.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">CSC_0109</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://notebooknumbernine.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_0036-3.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0036 (3)</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why I feel a bit let down by the closing ceremony.</title>
		<link>http://kjharding.wordpress.com/2012/08/13/why-i-feel-a-bit-let-down-by-the-closing-ceremony/</link>
		<comments>http://kjharding.wordpress.com/2012/08/13/why-i-feel-a-bit-let-down-by-the-closing-ceremony/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2012 13:24:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>kjharding</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[closing ceremony.]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Olympics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://kjharding.wordpress.com/?p=6</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I should preface this by saying that I know the ceremony last night was not all bad, and I also acknowledge that the closing ceremony is not there to do the same job as the opening ceremony. But anyway, here goes. As a newly minted commuter into London I will happily admit that, three weeks [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=6&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I should preface this by saying that I know the ceremony last night was not all bad, and I also acknowledge that the closing ceremony is not there to do the same job as the opening ceremony. But anyway, here goes. </p>
<p>As a newly minted commuter into London I will happily admit that, three weeks ago, I was looking forward to the Olympics with a sense of trepidation. Horror story predictions about the transport system abounded, security was a massive issue, and whenever it was discussed the conversations usually ended with a slight sigh and the phrase &#8220;I&#8217;m sure it won&#8217;t be <em>that</em> bad&#8221;. </p>
<p>And then it started. The opening ceremony was, in my opinion, fantastic: an imaginative, sweeping vista showing the world what Britain is all about. Or, maybe, should be all about. </p>
<p>The following two weeks of athletics was the only Olympics I remember being interested in. I found myself, helped along by the BBC&#8217;s excellent coverage, becoming interested in sports that I&#8217;d only vaguely been aware of previously &#8211; fencing, diving, gymnastics. I became an overnight expert in all fields, sagely informing my better half that, in fencing, if both lights go up at the same time, it means that they&#8217;ve hit each other at exactly the same moment and so the point will go to whoever started their &#8220;attack&#8221; first. Of course. </p>
<p>But it was with Super Saturday that I found myself fully under the spell of the Olympics. Watching this group of people, both British and those representing other countries, striving with everything they had to achieve their dream of winning an Olympic medal of whatever colour was both inspiring and humbling. I found myself teary eyed on numerous occasions, thinking about all the hard work that all of the athletes had put in to reach this point. The sheer effort of making it to the Olympics at all is an achievement in and of itself, but then World and Olympic records started falling with impunity. Athletes were achieving double triples, long distance doubles and cutting whole seconds off their personal bests, all cheered on by an excited public. And me. Shouting at my TV screen, hoping that the runners making up ground on Mo Farah in the final stretch of his epic 5000m final would trip each other up, or fall over themselves, or anything &#8211; just let him win.</p>
<p>I also found the participation and performance of so many of the female athletes cheering. For the first time there were female athletes from each nation competed, and there was female boxing. I am not a fan of boxing (male or female) but I found Nicola Adams to be a great ambassador for her sport. Engaging, eloquent and very obviously excited and pleased with what she&#8217;d achieved. Rightly so. </p>
<p>This was something that typified the vast majority of the competitors, whether winning a medal or not. The young athletes were gracious and humble and fantastic examples to everyone. They had tried to be the best at something and, in some cases, achieved it. In other cases, not quite. But they were happy with their lot nonetheless. </p>
<p>So I was looking forward to the closing ceremony, looking forward to seeing how the organisers could bring to an end such a fantastic fortnight of global celebration and togetherness. </p>
<p>I hate to say it, but I was disappointed. I  did not go into it with the cynicism with which I approached the opening ceremony and yet I still found myself getting more and more disappointed with what I saw. I am finding it hard to put my finger on exactly why, but I think it&#8217;s because I had spent the previous two weeks watching people working their absolute hardest, after several years of working their absolute hardest, and achieving greatness, being the best that they could be, being sportsmanlike, recognising the achievements of their opponents and generally being nice. It was lovely to see. </p>
<p>And how did we celebrate this coming together of nations in achievement, effort and <em>real hard work</em>? We had One Direction being driven on the back of a flat bed truck around the running track miming one of their &#8220;hits&#8221;. We had Jessie J being driven in the back of a huge and ostentatious Rolls Royce singing about it not being about the money. Yeah, we know that, Jessie. We&#8217;ve just watched two weeks&#8217; worth of people whose prime motivation is NOT to make huge wadges of cash &#8211; we don&#8217;t need you, prancing around in a strange be-spangled body suit to tell us that. </p>
<p>The nadir for me, the point at which even the snarky Twitterati could not help me to enjoy myself, was the &#8220;fashion&#8221; segment. I don&#8217;t know if it was partly because I was secretly hoping that Bowie would appear and was annoyed when he didn&#8217;t, but this part left me hollow. I appreciate that they were modelling Alexander McQueen dresses and so were celebrating a British designer who had achieved greatness in his own field, something which was missing from the opening ceremony. I don&#8217;t remember anything about British designers but it is undoubtedly right that they&#8217;re celebrated. But seeing some preening prima donnas best known for their love lives and temper tantrums stalking about the stage was to my mind a bit, well, misjudged. We had just seen a plethora of female athletes at the peak of physical health and fitness, moving away from women valued only for their ability to look good &#8211; valued and appreciated for their contribution to the sport and what they had to say. I felt sad to be moving back in the other direction. I am reliably informed that Russell Brand singing &#8220;I am the Walrus&#8221; was worse, but I seem to have blocked that from my memory. </p>
<p>It was not simply the female side of things which left me feeling deflated, it was the whole thing. The celebrity culture where people are deified for nothing more than simply being on TV had been cast aside for two weeks, and true talent shone through &#8211; these athletes were famous for actually doing something! Although not true of the entire closing ceremony, I felt that certain elements of it (giving prime airtime to allow George Michael to plug his new single, for example) slammed the door shut so that the chink of light cast by the athletes&#8217; talent was no longer visible. </p>
<p>It boils down to this. I think my problem with the closing ceremony is that the Olympics had been a celebration of people&#8217;s real achievements &#8211; a departure from the celebrity culture that has pervaded much of our lives over the past few years. It celebrated humility, hard work and grafting (as a greater man than me said). The female role models on display during the Olympics were real women &#8211; they looked like real women and they acted like real women. All of the athletes were true sportspeople and it saddened me to realise that this display was over. </p>
<p>Basically I think I&#8217;m in mourning for the end of the Olympics. I don&#8217;t know what I would have done instead and I don&#8217;t have any constructive criticism, just an emotionally knee-jerk reaction. The athletes kettled into the Union Flag in the middle seemed to be enjoying themselves, which is the main thing. All I know is that I bloody loved the Olympics and this didn&#8217;t seem to be enough of a send off. </p>
<p>But, joy of joys, the Premier League starts again next week. Talk about preening prima donnas best known for their love lives and temper tantrums&#8230;&#8230;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/6/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/6/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=6&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://kjharding.wordpress.com/2012/08/13/why-i-feel-a-bit-let-down-by-the-closing-ceremony/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>22</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/9a620a103c8326fe7bdd75c08d3c579c?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">kjharding</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Stargazing during the Perseid Meteor Shower</title>
		<link>http://jaymanalo.wordpress.com/2012/08/12/stargazing-during-the-perseid-meteor-shower/</link>
		<comments>http://jaymanalo.wordpress.com/2012/08/12/stargazing-during-the-perseid-meteor-shower/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2012 04:03:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>solarsanction</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adventure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[canon 5d mark iii]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[long exposure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meteor shower]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[night]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[perseid]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shooting star]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[star trails]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stars]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://jaymanalo.wordpress.com/?p=966</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Over the weekend, the annual Perseid Meteor Shower took place. I&#8217;m located in the San Francisco Bay Area, so it&#8217;s hard to get away from all the light pollution. I thought for hours of where I could go watch the amazing event. This year was the first year that I decided I would try to [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=966&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-967" title="_G5A2442" src="http://jaymanalo.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/g5a2442.jpg" alt="" width="630" height="420" /></p>
<p>Over the weekend, the annual Perseid Meteor Shower took place. I&#8217;m located in the San Francisco Bay Area, so it&#8217;s hard to get away from all the light pollution. I thought for hours of where I could go watch the amazing event. This year was the first year that I decided I would try to find the darkest environment in my town after being inspired by the night sky I saw 2 years ago in Alaska. I took a gamble with a local regional park a few miles away from where I lived. To be honest, it wasn&#8217;t too bad.</p>
<p>As the night progressed, it suddenly got darker and the stars were a lot more visible. Falling meteors where everywhere along the sky, but they were so spontaneous that it was difficult to shoot and impossible to predict. Not only that, but they were amazingly fast and faint that my camera probably didn&#8217;t detect them.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-969" title="_G5A2495" src="http://jaymanalo.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/g5a2495.jpg" alt="" width="630" height="420" /></p>
<p>The longer I left my shutter open, the more I started to get.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-968" title="_G5A2477-Edit" src="http://jaymanalo.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/g5a2477-edit.jpg" alt="" width="630" height="420" /></p>
<p>Then I decided to just leave the shutter open really long. Say, 30 minutes?</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-970" title="_G5A2511-Edit-Edit" src="http://jaymanalo.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/g5a2511-edit-edit.jpg" alt="" width="630" height="420" /></p>
<p>Even if I didn&#8217;t get the shot of the meteors across the skies as I imagined, experimenting with long exposures on my DSLR was worth it. This above shot was my last shot before I left and I&#8217;m so glad it turned out well. I would love to come back again.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/966/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/966/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=966&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://jaymanalo.wordpress.com/2012/08/12/stargazing-during-the-perseid-meteor-shower/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>26</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/893058d8c544ea8b21eaa7a7b41c91bb?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">solarsanction</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jaymanalo.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/g5a2442.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">_G5A2442</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jaymanalo.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/g5a2495.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">_G5A2495</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jaymanalo.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/g5a2477-edit.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">_G5A2477-Edit</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jaymanalo.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/g5a2511-edit-edit.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">_G5A2511-Edit-Edit</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Henry Ford (Museum)</title>
		<link>http://adailydoseoffiber.wordpress.com/2012/08/13/the-henry-ford-museum/</link>
		<comments>http://adailydoseoffiber.wordpress.com/2012/08/13/the-henry-ford-museum/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2012 16:53:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>debmoyes</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Road Trip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cool tool]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[design inspiration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Detriot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[road trip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Henry Ford]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://adailydoseoffiber.wordpress.com/?p=3619</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I ran away with the circus last week! ;-D No, not really, but I did run away with Peter. He had work near Detroit and I invited myself along. Being the good guy he is, he agreed. My plan was for us to go to see the Henry Ford Museum after he was done with [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3619&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I ran away with the circus last week! ;-D</p>
<p>No, not really, but I did run away with Peter. He had work near Detroit and I invited myself along. Being the good guy he is, he agreed. My plan was for us to go to see the Henry Ford Museum after he was done with his work. We&#8217;ve been talking about it since we moved to the Midwest. Turns out that it is <em>not</em> The Henry Ford Museum but simply <a href="http://www.hfmgv.org" target="_blank">The Henry Ford</a>! O.K. There is a lot to see there, including the (not) museum, an IMAX theatre and Greenfield Village. Amazingly enough it was raining so an outdoor venue was not a good idea and we wanted to see the indoor collections anyway. THF has lots of collections and after seeing what was on display, all I could wonder was what we weren&#8217;t seeing. I took random photos of things that interested me, and I hope they will interest you! (And please let me say that I took these with poor lighting, through glass displays and with my iPhone.)</p>
<p>What struck me most about the display of the US Industrial Revolution is that up until that point of time, the most complicated machine in the World was <em>the watch</em>&#8230;&#8230; How about that? A lot of the exhibits talked about how the Industrial Revolution in the US made Americans want more &#8220;things&#8221;. Things that were cheaper and more readily available than before. This ad for a sewing machine tickled me, though a sewing machine is a necessity for many of us&#8230;..</p>
<p><a href="http://adailydoseoffiber.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_1906.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-3622" title="Sewing machine ad" src="http://adailydoseoffiber.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_1906.jpg?w=189&h=300" alt="" width="189" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>Here are two sewing machines that were designed to be displayed and used in the livingroom. This first one dates from 1860-1865. It&#8217;s a lovely design but looks very difficult to actually use&#8230;.</p>
<p><a href="http://adailydoseoffiber.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_1914.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-3634" title="1860 sewing machine" src="http://adailydoseoffiber.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_1914.jpg?w=245&h=300" alt="" width="245" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>I don&#8217;t recall what year this one was from, but it has the look of the 1930&#8242;s or 1940&#8242;s. Notice the lovely design and how the stool fits perfectly under the table!</p>
<p><a href="http://adailydoseoffiber.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_1913.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-3635" title="1930's sewing machine" src="http://adailydoseoffiber.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_1913.jpg?w=300&h=294" alt="" width="300" height="294" /></a></p>
<p>From a distance I thought this was a loom, but talk about <em>A Cool Tool </em>! This machine draws lines on paper. Before the invention of this machine, people put a sort of comb down on the paper and had to be careful with their (leaky, difficult) ink pens as they traced  the lines. Wow! Hard to imagine that lined paper was a new invention, but that&#8217;s why museums like THF are so valuable. The machine in front is a small printing press for flyers and small runs.</p>
<p><a href="http://adailydoseoffiber.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_1907.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-3624" title="Line drawing machine" src="http://adailydoseoffiber.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_1907.jpg?w=291&h=300" alt="" width="291" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>No looms were on display but there was a case with some lovely coverlets woven with Jacquard looms. (They were the first sort of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jacquard_loom" target="_blank">computer</a> - and I&#8217;m not joking.) This pattern caught my eye.</p>
<p><a href="http://adailydoseoffiber.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_1909.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-3627" title="Lovely Jacquard" src="http://adailydoseoffiber.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_1909.jpg?w=224&h=300" alt="" width="224" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>I see that I did not take any photos of cars&#8230;.funny! There was an amazing collection which we thoroughly enjoyed looking at. There were lots of trains to admire as well. Look at this early train &#8211; can you see that it is a collection of carriages or stages pulled by an engine? Very fun.</p>
<p><a href="http://adailydoseoffiber.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_1924.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-3638" title="A carriage train" src="http://adailydoseoffiber.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_1924.jpg?w=290&h=300" alt="" width="290" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>And here &#8211; is &#8211; Cinderella&#8217;s carriage! Isn&#8217;t it charming? I don&#8217;t know if you can see how very small the door is for a large, elaborate Cinderella type dress to get through. And the carriage is very tall. There must have been quite a high set of stairs to get the riders safely inside of it.</p>
<p><a href="http://adailydoseoffiber.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_1921.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-3630" title="Cinderella's carriage!" src="http://adailydoseoffiber.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_1921.jpg?w=300&h=252" alt="" width="300" height="252" /></a></p>
<p>Look at this amazing stage coach with what must be the owner&#8217;s faithful dog painted under the seat.</p>
<p><a href="http://adailydoseoffiber.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_1927-2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-3644" title="Painted stagecoach" src="http://adailydoseoffiber.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_1927-2.jpg?w=224&h=300" alt="" width="224" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>This item comes under The Twilight Zone heading! (Are you hearing the theme music?) It is a Philco Predicta Television Receiver!!!! The notation said it was from 1958-1960. I can say I never saw one of these growing up but I am sure that I would have loved it! With this in your livingroom, the aliens would surely be on their way. ;-D</p>
<p><a href="http://adailydoseoffiber.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_1911.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-3632" title="Philco TV" src="http://adailydoseoffiber.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_1911.jpg?w=173&h=300" alt="" width="173" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>And this comes under the heading of simply random&#8230; We woke up on Saturday morning to an odd sound. We looked out the window and could see a crowd milling about. The night before we&#8217;d seen lots of Indian people gathering in the lobby with incredibly lovely saris on and so here was the actual wedding. Out in the parking lot we found the groom (not Indian but enjoying himself) with his family and friends on a horse! Peter realized that they were reenacting the groom going to his bride&#8217;s home to collect her for the wedding! There were drums and more beautifully clad guests having a wonderful time. Peter and I still have our outfits from a trip to India and were sorry that we&#8217;d not been invited to the ceremony. That&#8217;s what makes vacation so much fun; not knowing what might happen next!</p>
<p><a href="http://adailydoseoffiber.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_1931.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-3641" title="Indian wedding" src="http://adailydoseoffiber.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_1931.jpg?w=300&h=258" alt="" width="300" height="258" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3619/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3619/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3619&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://adailydoseoffiber.wordpress.com/2012/08/13/the-henry-ford-museum/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/b9d7e4ce658a9e59757985f81d70e574?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">debmoyes</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://adailydoseoffiber.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_1906.jpg?w=189" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Sewing machine ad</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://adailydoseoffiber.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_1914.jpg?w=245" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">1860 sewing machine</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://adailydoseoffiber.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_1913.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">1930&#039;s sewing machine</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://adailydoseoffiber.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_1907.jpg?w=291" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Line drawing machine</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://adailydoseoffiber.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_1909.jpg?w=224" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Lovely Jacquard</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://adailydoseoffiber.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_1924.jpg?w=290" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">A carriage train</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://adailydoseoffiber.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_1921.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Cinderella&#039;s carriage!</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://adailydoseoffiber.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_1927-2.jpg?w=224" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Painted stagecoach</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://adailydoseoffiber.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_1911.jpg?w=173" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Philco TV</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://adailydoseoffiber.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_1931.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Indian wedding</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Geek out!</title>
		<link>http://sweetsavoryblog.wordpress.com/2012/07/03/geek-out/</link>
		<comments>http://sweetsavoryblog.wordpress.com/2012/07/03/geek-out/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2012 16:11:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sweet Sarah</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Boardgames]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Geekery & Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[90s]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[batman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[board games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crafting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[teen dramas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ticket to ride]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vampires]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[youtube sensations]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://sweetsavoryblog.wordpress.com/?p=403</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Last week one of my favorite people that I work with sent out an email to about a dozen of our colleagues, asking us to reply with the things that we &#8220;geek out&#8221; about. I jumped on the opportunity to do this, and sent him the following list. I learned so much about my co-workers [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=403&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://sweetsavoryblog.wordpress.com/2012/07/03/geek-out/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>12</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://sweetsavoryblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/ticket2ride.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://sweetsavoryblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/ticket2ride.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ticket2ride</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sweetandsavoryblog</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Familiarity and Happiness</title>
		<link>http://seiberg.wordpress.com/2012/08/13/familiarity-and-happiness/</link>
		<comments>http://seiberg.wordpress.com/2012/08/13/familiarity-and-happiness/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2012 10:21:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>seiberg</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[information]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[random]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://seiberg.wordpress.com/?p=60</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Repeated exposure to words, phrases or objects gives rise to an unconscious association of happiness to them. In terms of evolution, this is just the habituation to something we routinely see that poses no risk. In fact, not only do we get used to them, we actually associate happiness to these objects. An interesting study [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=60&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Repeated exposure to words, phrases or objects gives rise to an unconscious association of happiness to them. In terms of evolution, this is just the habituation to something we routinely see that poses no risk. In fact, not only do we get used to them, we actually associate happiness to these objects.</p>
<p>An interesting study was done in a student newspaper, where random turkish words were printed in a box on the front page. Some of the words were repeated numerous times, whilst others just once &#8211; this was done at several universities, with different numbers of multiplicity for each word (i.e. in one newspaper, a word was printed numerous times over the course of the weeks, whilst that word in another newspaper was printed only once &#8211; and vice versa).</p>
<p>This practice was continued for several weeks at different universities until a study was taken, seemingly (to all participants) unrelated to the newspaper boxes. When asked whether each turkish word had a positive or negative sound to it, a significant number of students associated the turkish words which were repeated more with a more positive response compared to the less often repeated words.</p>
<p>This is probably one (of the many) reasons why Coca-Cola and Pepsi still advertise even if the entire world is likely to have heard of them.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/60/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/60/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=60&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://seiberg.wordpress.com/2012/08/13/familiarity-and-happiness/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/1ed718971afe18714dd90cbf396ebcac?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">seiberg</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>PLAYING FOR KEEPS: A Tale of Two Movies</title>
		<link>http://munibrezaie.com/2012/08/13/playing-for-keeps-a-tale-of-two-movies/</link>
		<comments>http://munibrezaie.com/2012/08/13/playing-for-keeps-a-tale-of-two-movies/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2012 13:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>munibrezaie</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gerard Butler]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jessica Biel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jonathan Gray]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movie posters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[paratexts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Playing for Keeps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Show Sold Separately]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://munibrezaie.com/?p=167</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I love movie posters. Throughout my middle- and high school years, I used to make a point of getting to the multiplex extra early in order to have enough time to wander the halls and look at all of the posters for coming attractions. In undergrad, I had a class on movie marketing during my [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=167&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I love movie posters.</p>
<p>Throughout my middle- and high school years, I used to make a point of getting to the multiplex extra early in order to have enough time to wander the halls and look at all of the posters for coming attractions. In undergrad, I had a class on movie marketing during my senior year at the <a href="http://www.umiami.edu">University of Miami</a> taught by Dr. Sam Grogg (now at Adelphi University). Fantastic guy. Fantastic class. We spent A LOT of time covering the concept of key art and analyzing various posters, trailers, and overall marketing campaigns of films being released that fall. The final project involved applying all that we learned throughout the semester to a particular film, dissecting its various posters, trailers, reviews, etc.</p>
<p>I never looked at a poster the same again.</p>
<p>There was so much that could be learned from a single poster. To name but a few:</p>
<ul>
<li>Star power: the size/placement of performers’ names and pictures on a poster as a reflection of their popularity, or perceived popularity</li>
<li>Genre, plot, target audience, etc</li>
<li>Intertextuality: the various other popular culture products the poster refers to through texts or images subtly or not so subtly in order to attract audiences
<ul>
<li>For example: “from the studio/producer/writer/director/actors who brought you…” or a direct reference to another – often more popular – film. Here’s one of my favorite examples:</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="http://munibrezaie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/202713650.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-169 alignright" title="202713650" src="http://munibrezaie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/202713650.jpg?w=276&h=395" alt="" width="276" height="395" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://munibrezaie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/4948.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-168 alignnone" title="4948" src="http://munibrezaie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/4948.jpg?w=278&h=397" alt="" width="278" height="397" /></a></p>
<p>I know, right?!</p>
<p>Then I began my doctoral studies. In my first semester, I learned about Jonathan Gray’s <em><a href="http://amzn.com/0814731945">Show Sold Separately: Promos, Spoliers, and Other Paratexts</a></em>. Gray takes a critical look at the often-ignored world of texts that surrounds a particular film (including trailers, promos, tie-ins, posters, ads, etc) and gives them a name: <em>paratexts</em>. Paratexts <em>“are the greeters, gatekeepers, and cheerleaders for and of the media, filters through which we must pass on our way to ‘the text itself’”</em> (Gray, 6). They create a narrative before we see the actual narrative of the film that is being promoted and <em>“</em><em>hold considerable power to direct our initial interpretations, telling us what to expect and establishing genre, gender, style, attitude, and characterization.”</em></p>
<p>There’s a lot that I could go into about posters, not least of which would be how poorly photoshopped so many of them are. Here’s one of <span style="text-decoration:line-through;">my favorites</span> the worst:</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://munibrezaie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/good-luck-chuck-poster-750.jpeg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-170" title="good-luck-chuck-poster-750" src="http://munibrezaie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/good-luck-chuck-poster-750.jpeg?w=268&h=395" alt="" width="268" height="395" /></a></p>
<p>But I actually started this post because I wanted to talk about one upcoming movie’s paratexts in particular: <em><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1540128/">Playing for Keeps</a>. </em>It illustrates an example of that most fascinating of paratextual behaviors: conflicting messages! I hadn’t heard anything about this movie until all of a sudden it was all over IMDb’s home page. Then all I saw was the poster, presented here:</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://munibrezaie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/playing-for-keeps-poster-larger-500x740.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-171" title="Playing-for-Keeps-Poster" src="http://munibrezaie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/playing-for-keeps-poster-larger-500x740.jpg?w=330&h=489" alt="" width="330" height="489" /></a></p>
<p>The first thing that jumped out at me was Gerard Butler. He takes up the most room on the poster and gets top billing. I like Gerard Butler. I’m interested. Then I see his face and that grin, which just looks smarmy and sleazy, a look often reserved for womanizing sleazebags. It reminds of the poster for <em><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1142988/">The Ugly Truth</a></em> in which, if I remember the trailer correctly (I haven’t seen the film) he WAS a womanizing sleazebag.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://munibrezaie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/the-ugly-truth.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-172" title="the-ugly-truth" src="http://munibrezaie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/the-ugly-truth.jpg?w=348&h=518" alt="" width="348" height="518" /></a></p>
<p>[Sidenote: Seeing this poster again, he really doesn't look that sleazy compared to his look in <em>Playing for Keeps.</em>]<em><br />
</em></p>
<p>Next I see three actresses: Jessica Biel, Uma Thurman, and Catherine Zeta Jones. It’s interesting to me that Biel has the next biggest picture and takes next billing, but mostly because I personally prefer Jones and Thurman. But it makes sense with <em><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1386703/">Total Recall</a></em>’s recent opening as well as Thurman and Jones’ recent absence in major lead roles. In any event, the actresses are known for their sex appeal, though Thurman arguably a little less so.</p>
<p>To recap so far: sleazy Gerard and three beautiful women.</p>
<p>Next I see the tagline: “This holiday season what do you REALLY want?” When that tagline is added to the mix of sleazy Gerard and three beautiful women, I can’t help but think that the poster wants me to think that the answer for Gerard Butler’s character is: “I want more beautiful women!” So far, I am not interested. Not too keen on movies that center on sleazy womanizers. Then I see the title: <em>Playing for Keeps</em> and I don’t really get it, but whatever…Hey, look! Dennis Quaid is in it too! What a beautiful man! And that smile! So based on the poster, I decide to pass. No interest in seeing the movie and no interest in seeing the trailer.</p>
<p>But then I was watching something on Hulu the other day and the trailer for the film came on. I rolled my eyes and thought “uggh, not interested.” But then I was pleasantly surprised. Here it is:</p>
<p><span style="text-align:center; display: block;"><a href="http://munibrezaie.com/2012/08/13/playing-for-keeps-a-tale-of-two-movies/"><img src="http://img.youtube.com/vi/ez9U9bw4XwM/2.jpg" alt="" /></a></span></p>
<p>He’s not a womanizer! He’s just a father trying to do right by his son. It’s a father’s redemption story! He’s not trying to woo Jones, she’s trying to woo him! Away from his son! With a job! His dream job! I am a total sucker for movies dealing with father/son relationships. Now I’m thinking what he REALLY wants this holiday season is to be a better father. A goal that I&#8217;m much more interested in watching him pursue.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/167/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/167/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=167&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://munibrezaie.com/2012/08/13/playing-for-keeps-a-tale-of-two-movies/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>20</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/d535f58013a8eb170c71f64e2ea50c59?s=96&#38;d=&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">munibrezaie</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://munibrezaie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/202713650.jpg?w=209" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">202713650</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://munibrezaie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/4948.jpg?w=210" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">4948</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://munibrezaie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/good-luck-chuck-poster-750.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">good-luck-chuck-poster-750</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://munibrezaie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/playing-for-keeps-poster-larger-500x740.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Playing-for-Keeps-Poster</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://munibrezaie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/the-ugly-truth.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">the-ugly-truth</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Brussels Sprouts with Pistachios and Lemon</title>
		<link>http://lattesandleggings.com/2012/08/13/brussels-sprouts-with-pistachios-and-lemon/</link>
		<comments>http://lattesandleggings.com/2012/08/13/brussels-sprouts-with-pistachios-and-lemon/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2012 16:02:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>lattesandleggings</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vegetables]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brussels sprouts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dinner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lemon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pistachio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recipe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[side dish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vegetable]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://lattesandleggings.wordpress.com/?p=3809</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Manhattan is filled with over twenty thousand restaurants, and it can be hard figuring out where to go for dinner on a Saturday night. Sometimes you just have to pick a neighborhood, walk around, and stumble upon something along the way. This happened on Saturday. After a day at the MET and drinks at one [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3809&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://lattesandleggings.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3152.jpg"><img src="http://lattesandleggings.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3152.jpg?w=640&h=426" alt="" title="IMG_3152" width="640" height="426" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3823" /></a></p>
<p>Manhattan is filled with over twenty thousand restaurants, and it can be hard figuring out where to go for dinner on a Saturday night. Sometimes you just have to pick a neighborhood, walk around, and stumble upon something along the way. This happened on Saturday. After a day at the </a><a href="http://www.metmuseum.org/" target="_blank"> MET </a> and drinks at one of my favorite rooftops,</a><a href="http://www.empirehotelnyc.com/" target="_blank"> Empire Hotel</a>, we decided to head a little closer to home for dinner. That&#8217;s when we stumbled upon </a><a href="http://www.cottanyc.com/" target="_blank"> Cotta Osteria</a> in the Upper West Side. I&#8217;ve walked past it a million times, but never thought to try it. As soon as I walked in the door I knew this was going to become my new favorite wine bar. We sat at the bar and coming from someone who used to bartend, the best service is at the bar, and you get to enjoy yourself and not feel rushed. From the ambience to the wine to the pizza to the great prices, it&#8217;s a great local spot. They have happy hour during the week which includes buy one get one free glasses of wine. If the Sicilian wine is on the list, that could be trouble. In a good way of course.</p>
<p>Enough about the wine. Let me tell you about the pizza. It&#8217;s served Italian style. I never really understood this until my husband went to Italy. They eat a whole pie by themselves. I thought this was crazy until I found myself eating a whole pie Saturday night. The pizzas are small with a thin, flaky crust. It&#8217;s like getting your own personal pizza without all the bread dough. It&#8217;s all about the toppings. The stand out pizza of the night? Brussels sprouts and pancetta pizza. I love love brussels sprouts. The pizza was topped with mounds of shaved brussels sprouts and salty pancetta with mozzarella and parmesan. It was heaven! My husband had the meatball pizza and loved it too.  </p>
<p><a href="http://lattesandleggings.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_29281.jpg"><img src="http://lattesandleggings.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_29281.jpg?w=640&h=426" alt="" title="IMG_2928" width="640" height="426" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3814" /></a></p>
<p>The first time I tried brussels sprouts was at </a><a href="http://www.bluehillfarm.com/food/blue-hill-new-york/menu" target="_blank"> Blue Hill </a> in Greenwich Village. Blue Hill is a farm to table restaurant that cooks seasonal food. I&#8217;ve been twice, and the brussels sprouts still stand out in my mind. It was a side dish of brussels sprouts leaves and pistachios. Very simple, but so good. After all this time, I finally made them, and wanted to share them with you. They are just as good as I remember.</p>
<p><a href="http://lattesandleggings.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_30081.jpg"><img src="http://lattesandleggings.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_30081.jpg?w=640&h=426" alt="" title="IMG_3008" width="640" height="426" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3815" /></a></p>
<p>I included the cores as well as the leaves to add more body to the dish, and I really don&#8217;t like wasting food. </p>
<p><a href="http://lattesandleggings.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3009.jpg"><img src="http://lattesandleggings.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3009.jpg?w=640&h=426" alt="" title="IMG_3009" width="640" height="426" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3816" /></a></p>
<p>Trim the ends of the brussels sprouts. Cut them in half. Then thinly slice them. </p>
<p><a href="http://lattesandleggings.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3047.jpg"><img src="http://lattesandleggings.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3047.jpg?w=640&h=426" alt="" title="IMG_3047" width="640" height="426" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3817" /></a></p>
<p>Pistachios add a nice crunchy texture. </p>
<p><a href="http://lattesandleggings.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3064.jpg"><img src="http://lattesandleggings.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3064.jpg?w=640&h=398" alt="" title="IMG_3064" width="640" height="398" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3818" /></a></p>
<p>And with a little lemon juice&#8230;perfection.</p>
<p><a href="http://lattesandleggings.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3098.jpg"><img src="http://lattesandleggings.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3098.jpg?w=640&h=444" alt="" title="IMG_3098" width="640" height="444" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3820" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://lattesandleggings.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3071.jpg"><img src="http://lattesandleggings.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3071.jpg?w=640&h=426" alt="" title="IMG_3071" width="640" height="426" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-3819" /></a></p>
<p><strong>Brussels Sprouts with Pistachios and Lemon</strong><br />
adapted from </a><a href="http://www.epicurious.com/recipes/food/views/Sauteed-Brussels-Sprouts-with-Lemon-and-Pistachios-241353" target="_blank"> Epicurious </a></p>
<p><em>The key to eliminating the bitterness that brussels sprouts sometimes tend to have is seasoning them well with salt.</em>  </p>
<p>serves 4</p>
<p>Ingredients<br />
3 tablespoons extra-virgin olive oil<br />
1 small shallot, finely diced<br />
1 garlic clove, minced<br />
1 pound brussels sprouts, trimmed, halved and thinly sliced<br />
kosher salt and freshly ground black pepper<br />
1/2 cup pistachios, shelled<br />
juice of 1 small lemon	</p>
<p>Directions<br />
In a large saute pan, heat the oil over medium-high heat. Add the shallot and garlic, and saute for 30 seconds until fragrant. Add the brussels sprouts, 1/2 teaspoon of kosher salt, and a pinch of black pepper. Saute for 4 to 5 minutes, stirring occasionally. Add the pistachios and saute for another 2 to 3 minutes until the brussels sprouts soften. Add the lemon juice and stir. Remove pan from heat. Season with salt and pepper to taste. Transfer to a serving bowl.			</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://lattesandleggings.com/category/food/'>Food</a>, <a href='http://lattesandleggings.com/category/food/vegetables-food/'>Vegetables</a> Tagged: <a href='http://lattesandleggings.com/tag/brussels-sprouts/'>brussels sprouts</a>, <a href='http://lattesandleggings.com/tag/dinner/'>dinner</a>, <a href='http://lattesandleggings.com/tag/food-2/'>food</a>, <a href='http://lattesandleggings.com/tag/lemon/'>lemon</a>, <a href='http://lattesandleggings.com/tag/pistachio/'>pistachio</a>, <a href='http://lattesandleggings.com/tag/recipe/'>recipe</a>, <a href='http://lattesandleggings.com/tag/side-dish/'>side dish</a>, <a href='http://lattesandleggings.com/tag/vegetable/'>vegetable</a>, <a href='http://lattesandleggings.com/tag/vegetarian/'>vegetarian</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3809/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3809/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3809/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3809/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3809/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3809/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3809/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3809/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3809/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3809/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3809/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3809/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3809/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3809/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3809&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://lattesandleggings.com/2012/08/13/brussels-sprouts-with-pistachios-and-lemon/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>41</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a6f0c59fdad1a132a0909991a8ac58e3?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lattesandleggings</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lattesandleggings.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3152.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_3152</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lattesandleggings.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_29281.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_2928</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lattesandleggings.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_30081.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_3008</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lattesandleggings.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3009.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_3009</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lattesandleggings.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3047.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_3047</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lattesandleggings.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3064.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_3064</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lattesandleggings.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3098.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_3098</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lattesandleggings.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3071.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_3071</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>