<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2013 21:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Russian Meteor Could Be Pope Resignation Conspiracy, but I Prefer Science</title>
		<link>http://mjwrightnz.wordpress.com/2013/02/18/russian-meteor-could-be-pope-resignation-conspiracy-but-i-prefer-science/</link>
		<comments>http://mjwrightnz.wordpress.com/2013/02/18/russian-meteor-could-be-pope-resignation-conspiracy-but-i-prefer-science/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2013 05:26:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Matthew Wright</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Environment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Satire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Astronomy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[climate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Current events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meteor strike]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science fiction]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mjwrightnz.wordpress.com/?p=21410</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It was one of those awful coincidences. Last Friday evening I was having a few beers with a friend, in a local pub. He was calculating the likely impact energy if 2012 DA14 &#8211; due to make a close pass over Indonesia &#8211; were to ever hit us. There are websites with Java script that [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=21410&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>It was one of those awful coincidences. Last Friday evening I was having a few beers with a friend, in a local pub. He was calculating the likely impact energy if 2012 DA14 &#8211; due to make a close pass over Indonesia &#8211; were to ever hit us.</h3>
<div id="attachment_19301" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 410px"><a href="http://mjwrightnz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/wright_earth.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-19301" alt="Earth. An image I made with my Celestia installation (cool, free, science package)." src="http://mjwrightnz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/wright_earth.jpg?w=720"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Earth. An image I made with my Celestia installation (cool, free, science package).</p></div>
<p>There are websites with Java script that do this, but it’s easy yourself if you have figures for velocity and mass –  a function of volume and density – plus the formula and a calculator. (Yes, I know it had been published, but it&#8217;s fun to do the math. I&#8217;m a geek and so are my friends. Remember&#8230;geeks won&#8230;.)</p>
<p>Nobody realised another object was about to explode over Chelyabinsk &#8211; &#8216;Tankograd&#8217; of Second World War fame.</p>
<p>The 1200 injured from flying glass is the largest human toll recorded from a meteor strike. The cost to Russia will be in the millions of roubles. Not to mention the fact that thousands of people are facing sub-zero temperatures in windowless homes, until they can be fixed.</p>
<p>All that because the Pope resigned. Well, it&#8217;s obvious. The Conspirating Ruling Archaic Poodles, a secret cabal nobody has ever heard of, used their stooges to drop one of their orbiting Bombs Utilising Low Level Seekrit Hyper Invisible Termination on the Vatican, thus covering up the Pope’s resignation, but because secret organisations always make basic arithmetical errors, it hit Russia instead. I have proof this is true, because they fly in invisible black helicopters. Well, have you seen one? Quite. Proves they exist&#8230;</p>
<p>And yes, I know that is a really, really stupid theory&#8230;but hey, it&#8217;s <a href="http://www.infowars.com/did-russia-shoot-down-meteor/" target="_blank">not the dumbest one out there</a>.</p>
<p>Needless to say, the science involved actually answers all questions. First off &#8211; the energy involved is mind-blowing on the scale of us mere humans.</p>
<p>How mind blowing? Try this. The Russian rock was maybe 10,000 tonnes mass and 17 metres diameter, by NASA estimate. Yet still exploded with an energy equivalent, some estimates suggest, of around 500,000 tons of TNT. How come?</p>
<p>Well, it’s entirely to do with kinetic energy, which you calculate according to the formula 1/2 MV&lt;exp&gt;2.  It was moving at over 63,000 km/h when it hit the atmosphere. That gave it a kinetic energy (roughly) of around 500,000,000,000,000 joules. Translated into human terms, that&#8217;s what a 1-kilowatt fan heater would emit if run constantly for<strong> 15,844 years</strong> (it would run out in about March in that last year).</p>
<p>That&#8217;s a lot of energy. So why did it explode? At the speed this sucker hit us, it was moving so fast it couldn&#8217;t push the atmosphere out of the way. The air was compressed ahead of it, got super-hot, and then began vapourising the front side of the meteor. But the back side was still ice-cold. After a while, differential thermal stresses exceeded the tensile strength of the object – and boom! A lot of the kinetic energy translated into a massive shock wave, shattering glass over that huge area, and powerful enough to be detected in Alaska. Some became heat. Some was retained in the fragments of meteor that hurtled into the ground, which will be found sooner or later (they&#8217;re looking now).</p>
<p>The take-home lesson from Friday? The odds of a damaging meteor hitting us, by human time-spans, are low . But these things do happen. And we didn’t see this one coming despite a determined effort of late to detect everything in our vicinity that might be a threat. We’ve even found the S-1VB stage from Apollo 12, which is lobbing around in a weird orbit nearby. But Friday’s rock – still a city-buster – was too small.</p>
<div id="attachment_21417" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://mjwrightnz.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/636px-jupiter_showing_sl9_impact_sites.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-21417" alt="A Hubble picture of Jupiter after it had been machine-gunned by Comet Shoemaker-Levy in 1994. NASA, public domain, via Wikipedia." src="http://mjwrightnz.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/636px-jupiter_showing_sl9_impact_sites.jpg?w=300&#038;h=283" width="300" height="283" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">A Hubble picture of Jupiter after it had been machine-gunned by Comet Shoemaker-Levy in 1994. NASA, public domain, via Wikipedia.</p></div>
<p>Worse, even if we had seen it, there was nothing we could have done.  The laws of physics are clear; Bruce Willis and a gang of Texan oil-riggers aren’t going to save the day at the last moment. <a title="Forget the Mayan rubbish – this is the REAL astro-apocalypse. Now." href="http://mjwrightnz.wordpress.com/2012/12/16/forget-the-mayan-rubbish-this-is-the-real-astro-apocalypse-now/">I’ve explained why in an earlier post </a>– check it out. Even if you could carry enough rocket fuel to get to an incoming rock and blow it up (which you can’t….trust me…) most of the bits will still hit the Earth with the same net kinetic energy. And it&#8217;s that energy that&#8217;s the problem.</p>
<p>That doesn’t mean we can’t find ways of handling it. Given decades of warning,  even spray-painting the side of a space rock black will work, by changing the way it re-radiates solar energy, asymmetrically. Over years, that will change the orbit.</p>
<p>Of course, space debris usually isn&#8217;t isolated. A comet can break up, leaving trails of objects following its original orbit. Jupiter was slammed by just such a train &#8216;o doom  in 1994. There&#8217;s a fair chance that we might have to try and deflect half a dozen potential impactors all at once.</p>
<p>Personally I’m not going to lose sleep over it. No point worrying about things we can’t control. And the prospect of being slammed by a space rock is pretty far down the list. Here in New Zealand, for instance, it’s more likely we’ll be hit by an earthquake – in fact, there was a small one in my city on Saturday and another tremor this morning.</p>
<p>What’s your take? Should we worry about that which we cannot control? Or get on with life?</p>
<p><em>Copyright © Matthew Wright 2013</em></p>
<p>‘<strong>Kindness 2013’</strong> returns next week. <strong>Coming up this week</strong>: more sixty-second writing tips, Write It Now part 6 – and more.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/21410/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/21410/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=21410&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://mjwrightnz.wordpress.com/2013/02/18/russian-meteor-could-be-pope-resignation-conspiracy-but-i-prefer-science/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a1b9f8718bcd5d6f844d6c888fbb7531?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mjwrightnz</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mjwrightnz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/wright_earth.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Earth. An image I made with my Celestia installation (cool, free, science package).</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mjwrightnz.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/636px-jupiter_showing_sl9_impact_sites.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">A Hubble picture of Jupiter after it had been machine-gunned by Comet Shoemaker-Levy in 1994. NASA, public domain, via Wikipedia.</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trustworthy Voices</title>
		<link>http://justabovesunset.wordpress.com/2013/02/17/trustworthy-voices/</link>
		<comments>http://justabovesunset.wordpress.com/2013/02/17/trustworthy-voices/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2013 04:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Alan</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Economic Confidence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Economic Fairness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Economic Recovery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Minimum Wage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion Journalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thomas Friedman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Billionaires for Human Sacrifice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Columnists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Conventional Wisdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[First Amendment Rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Freedom of the Press]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Friedman Unit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Grand Bargain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[How to Unparalyze Us]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Informed Citizens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mass Marketing of Misinformation on Economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion Columnists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Paul Krugman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Raising the Minimum Wage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reform That Cuts Taxes For The Rich And Corporations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rise of Western Democracies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Slow the Growth of Both Social Security and Medicare Entitlements]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Rights of Man and the Citizen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Who to Trust]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://justabovesunset.wordpress.com/?p=19167</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The eighteenth century gave us lots of things – like Mozart and the steam engine and the guillotine – but it also gave us modern democracies. Monarchies would no longer do. Thanks to Rousseau and others, there was new talk of the rights of man and the citizen – as opposed to the divine or hereditary [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=19167&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">The eighteenth century gave us lots of things – like Mozart and the steam engine and the guillotine – but it also gave us modern democracies. Monarchies would no longer do. Thanks to Rousseau and others, there was new talk of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Declaration_of_the_Rights_of_Man_and_of_the_Citizen" target="_blank">the rights of man and the citizen</a> – as opposed to the divine or hereditary or de facto rights of any king or queen. Citizens could run any country just as well, or better, than some loopy king – they had their own interests in mind and, in charge, would make decisions for the common good. The whim or greed of personal issues of one man would no longer determine day-to-day life for everyone else.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">That&#8217;s how things should be, so the French beheaded their king and queen, and quite a few others, and over here, we also decided we could run this place ourselves – we needed no king at all. Eventually even the British worked out a system where their king or queen at any given moment didn&#8217;t matter much at all. Their monarchs, and all those subordinate peers of the realm, became revered and respected curiosities, like fine old furniture. The House of Lords retained some power for a time, but it eventually became no more than a collection of loveable eccentrics, if you like fox hunting. All the action was in the House of Commons, and the Prime Minister, chosen by the majority party in the House of Commons, administered the affairs of the nation, with the king or queen&#8217;s blessing, which was, eventually, no more than a formality. Other western nations worked out analogous arrangements and Western Democracy was born. Now and then a dictator would arise, assuming monarchial powers, but each of those came to a bad end – like Mussolini hung dead by his heels. Citizens there had had enough of him. Here, George Washington stepped down after two terms. He didn&#8217;t want the presidency to be anything other than a temporary position of trust, granted by the citizens. He knew the age of kings was over. The world had changed.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">There was only one problem with this. It became everyone&#8217;s duty to become an informed citizen – that&#8217;s the only way a democracy works. Otherwise you&#8217;d have chaos – folks voting for nonsense because they really didn&#8217;t know a damned thing about the issues at hand. Yes, we don&#8217;t have a direct democracy, where we each vote on every little thing, but in our representative republic we do vote for those who we think will represent our own interests and the general interests of the nation. You have to know something about the issues, at least in a broad sense, to choose the man or woman to send to Washington to do the right thing. You also have to have a sense of what the right thing might be.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">That&#8217;s hard to come by. That&#8217;s the reason the very first amendment to the Constitution establishes an almost absolute right of free speech, and assures a free press, and keeps religion off to the side, as not an official function of government. All issues can be aired openly – no one is told to shut up, unless they&#8217;re shouting fire in a crowded theater. The press can present all the relevant facts, or what they see as relevant facts, as long as they don&#8217;t lie or commit slander or libel. They can even publish government secrets in some cases, because some of what is secret is no more than what&#8217;s embarrassing and what everyone really needs to know. The <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pentagon_Papers" target="_blank">case of the Pentagon Papers</a> comes to mind – in the end, the press had a First Amendment right to publish information significant to all of us understanding our own government&#8217;s policies, even if they weren&#8217;t pretty – or maybe precisely because they weren&#8217;t pretty. As for those walking around muttering about what God really wants the government to do, because God told them so, such folks are a dime a dozen and seldom agree with each other, and God&#8217;s not exactly parting the clouds and verifying which of them got it right and which of them was having auditory hallucinations. Nothing can be verified. What such folks say is always interesting, but it&#8217;s never that useful. The original agreement was to put that God stuff off to the side. Absolutist talk about the will of God was what got us into trouble in the first place. Kings talked that way.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">That leaves us all with a need to know something about the issues of the day, at least in a broad sense, so we can decide what the right thing to do might be – and then elect an appropriate mayor or governor or congressman or senator or president to do just that. It&#8217;s just that there are endless people telling you what the right thing to do is, and you have to listen to them, because no citizen has the time or energy or even the inclination to do the necessary research. There&#8217;s the job and the wife and kids and the bills to pay and all the rest, and no one&#8217;s a combination economist and political scientist and historian. Someone had to do the grunt work for us, and distill it all down into a form we can understand, rather quickly. The cable news folks purport to do that for us – some watch Fox News to get a sense of what&#8217;s up, and what might be the right thing to do about it. Bill O&#8217;Reilly and Sean Hannity and the rest will tell you that. Others turn to MSNBC for the same – Rachel Maddow or Ed Schultz might do that, even if Chris Matthews is useless. CNN won&#8217;t tell you anything except on Sunday morning, if then. Fareed Zakaria digs deep and explains things clearly. The nightly broadcast news is useless – a quick skim of what&#8217;s hot but little more.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">There&#8217;s talk radio too, with Rush Limbaugh, and wherever Glenn Beck is hanging out these days. Those two are fiery but a bit absurd, or an acquired taste – but there are also the major columnists. The problem there is the issue of reliability. Paul Krugman is an actual economist, with a Nobel Prize and everything – he deals with actual data and verified statistical trends – but on the conservative side, Charles Krauthammer is a former psychiatrist of all things, and George Will is simply a sour and prissy conservative who stuck around for years. They bring little to the table, other than strong opinions based on… strong opinions. William Kristol is the most amusing – the editor of the Weekly Standard and the man who said the Iraq War would be a breeze, and that the whole idea that the Sunni and Shia wouldn&#8217;t get along sheer nonsense, and who was the man behind convincing John McCain that Sarah Palin was wonderful and would assure McCain&#8217;s election. Kristol is still taken seriously for some reason, at least at Fox News – but then they also trot out Karl Rove and just hired Herman Cain. Where citizens turn to find out what&#8217;s what is a minefield.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">What citizens get is either polemic or very conventional wisdom, which is seldom wisdom at all. The master of that is <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thomas_Friedman" target="_blank">Thomas Friedman</a> of the New York Times, whose most popular book is <a title="The World Is Flat" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_World_Is_Flat" target="_blank">The World Is Flat</a> – several hundred pages of the obvious on globalization. He does know the Middle East, but even there tends to state the obvious, and then there&#8217;s the once-famous <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Friedman_Unit" target="_blank">Friedman Unit</a> – a term first coined by Duncan Black on May 21, 2006. You see, a Friedman is a unit of time equal to six months. It has to do with the Iraq War, and how things might turn out – &#8220;the next six months&#8221; was the period in which, according to Friedman, &#8220;we&#8217;re going to find out… whether a decent outcome is possible.&#8221; Friedman made these six-month predictions for two and a half years, actually at least fourteen different times. It became a running joke. Any time anyone said &#8220;the next six months will be critical,&#8221; or said &#8220;just wait six months,&#8221; everyone would smile and say, &#8220;Ah, a Friedman Unit, an FU, as it were.&#8221; On the other hand, the &#8220;the newspaper of record&#8221; paid him for such analysis.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">You might also remember <a href="http://atrios.blogspot.com/2007_08_12_archive.html" target="_blank">how he initially felt about that war</a> as he explained to Charlie Rose on PBS:<br />
</span></p>
<p style="margin-left:36pt;"><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">I think it [the invasion of Iraq] was unquestionably worth doing, Charlie. … We needed to go over there, basically, um, and um, uh, take out a very big state right in the heart of that world and burst that bubble, and there was only one way to do it. … What they needed to see was American boys and girls going house to house, from Basra to Baghdad, um and basically saying, &#8220;Which part of this sentence don&#8217;t you understand?&#8221; You don&#8217;t think, you know, we care about our open society, you think this bubble fantasy, that we&#8217;re just gonna to let it grow? Well Suck. On. This. Okay.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">That was crude and brutal, and made no geopolitical sense, or moral sense, but that&#8217;s what everyone was feeling at the time. That&#8217;s what he offers. What he thinks everyone is thinking, because he thinks it, and it&#8217;s usually true – and the opposite of useful insight. He&#8217;s a mirror, not a searchlight. A few years later he said <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2007/09/30/opinion/30friedman.html" target="_blank">9/11 Is Over</a> and he was just wrong about America&#8217;s need to break down doors from Basra to Baghdad for widespread fellatio by force, because sexual violation and dominance via oral rape was America&#8217;s moral right and in our self-interest. He didn&#8217;t say he&#8217;d been wrong – just that time had passed and there were other things we could do now.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">That might make Friedman seems like a moral monster, but he&#8217;s still chatting with Charlie Rose and writing columns for the New York Times. He also has changed his ways. His latest is <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/02/17/opinion/sunday/friedman-how-to-unparalyze-us.html?pagewanted=all" target="_blank">How to Unparalyze Us</a> – about political gridlock in Washington and the debt crisis and economics and entitlements – which is not his area of expertise at all. It doesn&#8217;t matter. He makes his arguments:<br />
</span></p>
<p style="margin-left:36pt;"><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">Apple is currently sitting on $137 billion of cash in the bank. There are many reasons Apple has not spent its cash hoard, but I&#8217;ll bet anything that one of them is the uncertain economic and tax environment in this country. Think about how much better we&#8217;d all be if Apple, and the many other companies sitting on cash, felt confident enough in the future to spend it. These are the most dynamic companies in the world. They don&#8217;t need any government help to innovate.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">Does that seem right? Dean Baker at the Center for Economics and Policy Research calls this <a href="http://www.cepr.net/index.php/blogs/beat-the-press/its-sunday-and-thomas-friedman-is-abusing-economics-again" target="_blank">mass marketing of misinformation on economics</a>:<br />
</span></p>
<p style="margin-left:36pt;"><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">Okay, Apple is so uncertain about the economic and tax environment in the U.S. that they don&#8217;t invest. (Funny how that works since they sell largely to a world market of which the U.S. is a substantial part, but not the majority.)<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">Friedman goes on to say this:<br />
</span></p>
<p style="margin-left:36pt;"><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">Message: There is no doubt our economy is primarily being held back by the deleveraging and drop in demand that resulted from the 2008 financial crisis. But they are being reinforced today by uncertainty and worry that we do not have our political house in order and, therefore, our tax, regulatory, pension and entitlement frameworks are all in play. So businesses, investors and consumers all hold back just enough for us not to be able to move the growth and employment meters with any robust momentum.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">The whole idea is that the way to get the economy moving again is with a &#8220;grand bargain&#8221; that &#8220;slows the growth of both Social Security and Medicare entitlements&#8221; along with &#8220;reform&#8221; that cuts taxes for the rich and corporations. Friedman says that even a cab driver would know this, but Baker, the actual economist here, is having none of it:<br />
</span></p>
<p style="margin-left:36pt;"><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">Okay, let&#8217;s imagine that one of Friedman&#8217;s cab drivers had access to the Internet and could go to the National Income and Product Accounts that the Commerce Department posts. The cab driver would explain to Friedman that investment in equipment and software is actually pretty healthy. Measured as a share of GDP it is almost back to its pre-recession level. Furthermore, apart from the tech bubble days of the late 90s it has never been much higher than it is today. …<br />
</span></p>
<p style="margin-left:36pt;"><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">In short there is no reason to expect investment to be much higher than it is currently. It doesn&#8217;t appear that uncertainty is very important in this picture.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="margin-left:36pt;"><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">Friedman&#8217;s cab driver would then explain to him that he is also wrong about consumption. Consumers are actually spending at a high rate relative to their income, not the low rate he seems to believe. …<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">Baker has tables and graphs that document this, with details, but notes Friedman also offers this:<br />
</span></p>
<p style="margin-left:36pt;"><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">Our choice today is not &#8220;austerity&#8221; versus &#8220;no austerity&#8221; – that is a straw man argument offered by both extremes. It&#8217;s about whether we phase in – in the least painful way possible – a long-term plan that balances our need to protect the most vulnerable in this generation while funding the most opportunities for the next generation, and still creating growth. We can&#8217;t protect both generations in full anymore, but we must not sacrifice one for the other – favoring nursing homes over nursery schools – and that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re on track to do.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">Baker:<br />
</span></p>
<p style="margin-left:36pt;"><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">You have to love the line:<br />
</span></p>
<p style="margin-left:36pt;"><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">&#8220;We can&#8217;t protect both generations in full anymore.&#8221;<br />
</span></p>
<p style="margin-left:36pt;"><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">Somehow Friedman missed the fact that the problem we are facing is a lack of demand. We need people to spend more not less. How does austerity reduce unemployment and get the economy back to full employment? It hasn&#8217;t worked in Ireland, Greece, Spain, the United Kingdom or anywhere else that can be identified. How on earth does the fact that we now face a huge gap in demand mean that we are less well-situated to &#8220;protect both generations.&#8221; (Of course he doesn&#8217;t say anything about income distribution.)<br />
</span></p>
<p style="margin-left:36pt;"><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">Again, if Friedman could be taught some intro economics it would be hugely helpful here. Suppose Friedman gets his wish for a grand bargain and everyone working today knew that they would be seeing sharply lower Social Security and Medicare benefits in the future. All of those consumers who Friedman thinks are paralyzed by uncertainty will suddenly realize that they can be certain that they will need more money to support themselves in retirement because the Thomas Friedmans of the world have taken away their Social Security and Medicare.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">Friedman is writing nonsense again, of the moral-monster sort actually, and Dave Johnson at Seeing the Forest <a href="http://seeingtheforest.com/tom-friedman-explains-the-problem-with-the-economy/" target="_blank">adds this</a>:<br />
</span></p>
<p style="margin-left:36pt;"><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">You see, the problem isn&#8217;t high unemployment leaving people out of the economy, resulting in businesses not having enough customers coming in the door. That is not the reason businesses don&#8217;t feel confident enough to expand and hire.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="margin-left:36pt;"><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">And the budget problem isn&#8217;t because Bush doubled the military budget after Reagan did the same, after cutting taxes on the rich… And never mind that the budget didn&#8217;t have a deficit before those things… And never mind that they said they were &#8220;cutting the government&#8217;s allowance&#8221; and &#8220;starving the beast&#8221; in order to manufacture a deficit crisis so they could scare people into cutting the things we do to make our lives better. Never mind that they said that was the plan…<br />
</span></p>
<p style="margin-left:36pt;"><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">The real problem with our economy is that regular working people have too much, and the wealthy and their corporate masks have too little.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="margin-left:36pt;"><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">And we need a &#8220;Grand Bargain&#8221; imposed on us from the top, instead of just going with the results of the election we just had or all of the polls in which people said they want JOBS, higher taxes on the wealthy and corporations, military spending decreased, and better retirement and health care packages for regular people…<br />
</span></p>
<p style="margin-left:36pt;"><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">Tom Friedman thinks the wealthy people at the top should be making the decisions, not the people. Surely anyone can see the wisdom in that, right?<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">Right, and <a href="http://www.nndb.com/people/525/000022459/" target="_blank">don&#8217;t forget this</a>:<br />
</span></p>
<p style="margin-left:36pt;"><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">Thomas L. Friedman is a three-time Pulitzer Prize recipient for The New York Times. In 1978 he married an heiress to a fortune in shopping mall properties, and her $3-billion makes the Friedmans one of America&#8217;s wealthiest families.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">One blogger put the whole thing this way – <a href="http://digbysblog.blogspot.com/2013/02/another-billionaire-calls-for-human.html" target="_blank">Another Billionaire Calls for Human Sacrifice</a> – but that may be too harsh, or maybe not. Friedman and his fellow plutocrats argue that raising the minimum wage would hurt business, deepening the recession, but Paul Krugman, the economist, says <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/02/18/opinion/krugman-raise-that-wage.html?hp&amp;_r=0" target="_blank">that&#8217;s not so</a>:<br />
</span></p>
<p style="margin-left:36pt;"><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">First of all, the current level of the minimum wage is very low by any reasonable standard. For about four decades, increases in the minimum wage have consistently fallen behind inflation, so that in real terms the minimum wage is substantially lower than it was in the 1960s. Meanwhile, worker productivity has doubled. Isn&#8217;t it time for a raise?<br />
</span></p>
<p style="margin-left:36pt;"><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">Now, you might argue that even if the current minimum wage seems low, raising it would cost jobs. But there&#8217;s evidence on that question &#8211; lots and lots of evidence, because the minimum wage is one of the most studied issues in all of economics. U.S. experience, it turns out, offers many &#8220;natural experiments&#8221; here, in which one state raises its minimum wage while others do not. And while there are dissenters, as there always are, the great preponderance of the evidence from these natural experiments points to little if any negative effect of minimum wage increases on employment.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="margin-left:36pt;"><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">Why is this true? That&#8217;s a subject of continuing research, but one theme in all the explanations is that workers aren&#8217;t bushels of wheat or even Manhattan apartments; they&#8217;re human beings, and the human relationships involved in hiring and firing are inevitably more complex than markets for mere commodities. And one byproduct of this human complexity seems to be that modest increases in wages for the least-paid don&#8217;t necessarily reduce the number of jobs.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="margin-left:36pt;"><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">What this means, in turn, is that the main effect of a rise in minimum wages is a rise in the incomes of hard-working but low-paid Americans &#8211; which is, of course, what we&#8217;re trying to accomplish.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">And it should go without saying that thinking of workers as bushels of wheat or Manhattan apartments is moral monster territory. It&#8217;s just that this won&#8217;t happen:<br />
</span></p>
<p style="margin-left:36pt;"><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">So Mr. Obama&#8217;s wage proposal is good economics. It&#8217;s also good politics: a wage increase is supported by an overwhelming majority of voters, including a strong majority of self-identified Republican women (but not men). Yet GOP leaders in Congress are opposed to any rise. Why? They say that they&#8217;re concerned about the people who might lose their jobs, never mind the evidence that this won&#8217;t actually happen. But this isn&#8217;t credible.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="margin-left:36pt;"><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">For today&#8217;s Republican leaders clearly feel disdain for low-wage workers. Bear in mind that such workers, even if they work full time, by and large don&#8217;t pay income taxes (although they pay plenty in payroll and sales taxes), while they may receive benefits like Medicaid and food stamps. And you know what this makes them, in the eyes of the GOP &#8211; &#8220;takers,&#8221; members of the contemptible 47 percent who, as Mitt Romney said to nods of approval, won&#8217;t take responsibility for their own lives.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">There you have it. This has nothing to do with the economics, or the particular issues at hand. It&#8217;s kind of abstract, in a moral way, or an immoral way. Yes, it is everyone&#8217;s duty to become an informed citizen – that&#8217;s the only way a democracy works. Otherwise you&#8217;d have chaos – folks voting for nonsense, or voting for those who will vote for nonsense, because they really didn&#8217;t know a damned thing about the issue at hand. And we have columnists, and the cable news folks, explaining things they don&#8217;t quite understand, so we understand those things just as badly as they do. No one expected this. We just wanted no more kings – but nothing is ever simple.</span></p>
<p><a href="http://justabovesunset.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/getoveryourself.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-19181" alt="GetOverYourself" src="http://justabovesunset.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/getoveryourself.jpg?w=300&#038;h=300" width="300" height="300" /></a></p>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=19167&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://justabovesunset.wordpress.com/2013/02/17/trustworthy-voices/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/ff8da738a3dacb21b278b6dac6e2ca39?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">justabovesunset</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://justabovesunset.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/getoveryourself.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">GetOverYourself</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Animated Textflow: Experiencing Old Poems in a New Way</title>
		<link>http://thecuriouspeople.wordpress.com/2013/02/16/animated-textflow-experiencing-old-poems-in-a-new-way/</link>
		<comments>http://thecuriouspeople.wordpress.com/2013/02/16/animated-textflow-experiencing-old-poems-in-a-new-way/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2013 00:16:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>thecuriouspeople</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[animation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[discovery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Emily Dickinson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[literature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[musings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thoughts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wonder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thecuriouspeople.wordpress.com/?p=68</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A good poem is highly compressed in its language. You can’t skim through it and hope to get anything out of it. It’s the antithesis of most online reading, which provides more content, more links, more options… and less likelihood that you’ll read one thing slowly and thoughtfully. Poets.org has a large collection of animated [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=68&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A good poem is highly compressed in its language. You can’t skim through it and hope to get anything out of it. It’s the antithesis of most online reading, which provides more content, more links, more options… and less likelihood that you’ll read one thing slowly and thoughtfully.</p>
<p>Poets.org has a large collection of <a href="http://www.poets.org/page.php/prmID/531">animated textflow poems</a>, classic poems that are “animated” in the sense that the text appears a few words at a time, so that one line of the poem is broken into a stanza of just a word or two per line, and which fades away when complete.<span id="more-68"></span></p>
<p>Here’s a still of the first part of Emily Dickinson’s<a href="http://www.poets.org/viewmedia.php/prmMID/22057"> “A lane of Yellow led the eye” (#1650)</a>:</p>
<p><a href="http://thecuriouspeople.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/a-lane-of-yellow.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-69" alt="a lane of yellow" src="http://thecuriouspeople.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/a-lane-of-yellow.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>Big deal, right?</p>
<p>But here’s the thing: by doling out a poem a word at a time, textflow animation forces you to slow down (you control the pace of the playback). Go ahead and try at the link above. The words appear large even on an iPhone screen (and yes, <a href="http://poemflow.com/">there is an app</a>), and they’re huge if you view them on a computer monitor and set the display to full-screen.</p>
<p>This tiny-bites approach significantly changes the experience of reading the poem. It makes you linger on each word. And all the white space around the type has a simplifying and calming effect &#8212; sort of like the effect of listening to a really good reader, except now it’s the quiet voice inside your head.</p>
<p>They’re the same words as before &#8212; but even this simple animation changes their presentation enough to make them seem new.</p>
<p>In other words, it isn’t just about the content of the experience. It’s also about the mind’s receptiveness to that content. One of the little secrets of experiencing a sense of discovery and wonder is that you can improve your mind’s receptiveness by making relatively small changes to the way you receive or interact with the content. It isn’t that textflow is better than a book, it’s that it’s <em>different</em> (especially if you’re a fast reader). Maybe you’ll like the difference and maybe you won’t, but it provides an opportunity for discovery.</p>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=68&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thecuriouspeople.wordpress.com/2013/02/16/animated-textflow-experiencing-old-poems-in-a-new-way/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/04e8065ec37bfa71fecb6d779faeeacc?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">thecuriouspeople</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thecuriouspeople.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/a-lane-of-yellow.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">a lane of yellow</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rembrandt and Musings on Modern Man</title>
		<link>http://joaninordinarytime.wordpress.com/2013/02/18/rembrandt-and-musings-on-modern-man/</link>
		<comments>http://joaninordinarytime.wordpress.com/2013/02/18/rembrandt-and-musings-on-modern-man/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2013 23:33:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>joanallegretti</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[around town]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[musings]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joaninordinarytime.wordpress.com/?p=3299</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Two weekends ago, two of my girlfriends and I visited the newest exhibit at the Frist Center for Visual Arts: Rembrandt and the Dutch Golden Age.  It was interesting to see the influence of Protestantism on art after the Netherlands broke from Catholic Spain, and while still life isn&#8217;t my favorite, there were lots of [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3299&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two weekends ago, two of my girlfriends and I visited the newest exhibit at the Frist Center for Visual Arts: Rembrandt and the Dutch Golden Age.  It was interesting to see the influence of Protestantism on art after the Netherlands broke from Catholic Spain, and while still life isn&#8217;t my favorite, there were lots of other pieces I really enjoyed.</p>
<p>The first pieces were Rembrandts, and they were my favorite.  I especially liked his Visitation, which I had never seen before.</p>
<p><a href="http://joaninordinarytime.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/rembrandt_van_rijn_190.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-3300" alt="Rembrandt_van_Rijn_190" src="http://joaninordinarytime.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/rembrandt_van_rijn_190.jpg?w=400&#038;h=490" width="400" height="490" /></a></p>
<p>It also included one of his portraits of Christ (of which there are many).  Not his most famous one, but a very nice one.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://joaninordinarytime.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/attributed_to_rembrandt_christ_30-370-s1-376x450.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-3301" alt="Attributed_to_Rembrandt_Christ_30.370-S1-376x450" src="http://joaninordinarytime.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/attributed_to_rembrandt_christ_30-370-s1-376x450.jpg?w=300&#038;h=360" width="300" height="360" /></a></p>
<p>Two of my favorite Rembrandts that weren&#8217;t in the exhibit were his Storm on the Lake of Galilee and his Return of the Prodigal Son.</p>
<p>The way the Frist is laid out, it&#8217;s easy to find yourself in a completely different exhibit while in the middle of walking through another.  While we were walking through the Dutch Masters, we ducked into a <a href="http://fristcenter.org/calendar-exhibitions/detail/camille-utterback">modern exhibit by Camille Utterback</a> &#8220;whose interactive installations and reactive sculptures engage participants in a dynamic process of kinesthetic discovery and play.&#8221;  There were four interactive stations where your movement in front of the wall impacted what you saw in front of you.  For example, one of them had a projection on the wall of letters falling from the sky &#8212; when you walked into the room, you appeared on the screen and the letters fell onto you.  You were able to lift the letters up, shake them off, etc.  Another included the projection of modern art on the wall and as you walked into the room the art changed depending on where you moved, how you moved, etc.</p>
<p>After leaving this highly-interactive exhibit and entering back into the Dutch Masters rooms, my friend joked something along the lines, &#8220;And now we just look at these?&#8221;  She was kidding, of course, but it could be a thought-provoking reflection on our society.  Rembrandt and the great masters created profound works of art after quietly studying their reality.  We could even say <em>contemplating </em>reality.  To full appreciate their art, I think it could be argued that one has to enter into that same contemplation.  Is our modern society able to 1) produce similar masters? 2) appreciate the work of the past masters?</p>
<p>How many people are able to enter that art museum off the street, silence their phones, pause their iPods, leave the noise behind, and engage reality <em>in a completely different manner </em>than what they just silenced and left behind?  It&#8217;s not just a matter of looking at the Visitation by Rembrandt, but encountering it.  It&#8217;s not going to make noise, it&#8217;s not going to change, it&#8217;s not going to move, it&#8217;s not going to &#8220;refresh.&#8221;  But if you allow it, it may speak to you.  It may change you. It may move you.  It may refresh you.  But is modern man able to engage it in that way?  I&#8217;m not so sure.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3299/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3299/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3299&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://joaninordinarytime.wordpress.com/2013/02/18/rembrandt-and-musings-on-modern-man/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/6003d6a097a83c492685bcb3878ca18a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">joanallegretti</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://joaninordinarytime.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/rembrandt_van_rijn_190.jpg?w=400" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Rembrandt_van_Rijn_190</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://joaninordinarytime.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/attributed_to_rembrandt_christ_30-370-s1-376x450.jpg?w=375" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Attributed_to_Rembrandt_Christ_30.370-S1-376x450</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Iraq War: 10 Years Later We Are Stuck With Thought-Terminating Clichés</title>
		<link>http://juliesthinktank.wordpress.com/2013/02/18/iraq-war-10-years-later-we-are-stuck-with-thought-terminating-cliches/</link>
		<comments>http://juliesthinktank.wordpress.com/2013/02/18/iraq-war-10-years-later-we-are-stuck-with-thought-terminating-cliches/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2013 17:15:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Julie</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anti war movement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[casualties]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[George Galloway]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Iraq war]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kurds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opposition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[right or wrong]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Saddam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tony Blair]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://juliesthinktank.wordpress.com/?p=2625</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Allow me to make one thing clear in advance: this post is written from the perspective of someone who strongly supported the invasion of Iraq in 2003 and still maintains the same position. I am not claiming to be entirely unbiased. That said, I always accepted, then and now, that there were legitimate reasons against [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2625&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://juliesthinktank.wordpress.com/2013/02/18/iraq-war-10-years-later-we-are-stuck-with-thought-terminating-cliches/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/5004a1f122fd23afb1ae221dd831e89b?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Julie</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://juliesthinktank.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/38.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">38</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>One Hundred Boy</title>
		<link>http://carrieblueberry.wordpress.com/2013/02/18/one-hundred-boy/</link>
		<comments>http://carrieblueberry.wordpress.com/2013/02/18/one-hundred-boy/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2013 14:07:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>carrieblueberry</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[daily weirdness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[imagination]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kids]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parenthood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[super heroes]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://carrieblueberry.wordpress.com/?p=871</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Not many people I know now realize this, but I own a pink super girl cape. I wrote a lot about being a super hero a few years ago on another blog and somewhere along the way, life did it&#8217;s thing to my brain and my pink cape went into my closet for a very [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=871&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://carrieblueberry.wordpress.com/2013/02/18/one-hundred-boy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>58</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/75a34d1550e8eb7ab5d04c1b43577559?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=R" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">carrielouise</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8502/8435459323_6af6791885_b.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">one hundred boy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8055/8436545784_1bd3fb8000_b.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">take no prisoners</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>On Citation in Video Games Criticism, or Lighting Someone Else&#8217;s Candle</title>
		<link>http://thiscageisworms.com/2013/02/13/on-citation-in-video-games-criticism-or-lighting-someone-elses-candle/</link>
		<comments>http://thiscageisworms.com/2013/02/13/on-citation-in-video-games-criticism-or-lighting-someone-elses-candle/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2013 16:39:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>kunzelman</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Video Games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[game centered criticism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jonas kyratzes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mattie brice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[samantha allen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[taxonomy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video games]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thiscageisworms.com/?p=3042</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Be sure to check the end of this post for responses to this post. They are necessary reading. The topic of citation in popular games criticism is something that I have talked about quite a bit on twitter over the past six months or so. Sometimes I get all enraged about it and tweet long, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3042&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Be sure to check the end of this post for responses to this post. They are necessary reading.</strong></p>
<p>The topic of citation in popular games criticism is something that I have talked about quite a bit on twitter over the past six months or so. Sometimes I get all enraged about it and <a href="http://storify.com/tinysubversions/cameron-kunzelman-on-games-writing">tweet long, expletive-filled rants about how games writers should be citing one another</a>.</p>
<p>That rant comes from a place of love&#8211;the only way that video games writing gets better is by acknowledging the critical accomplishments of other people and then building with them. As Cara Ellison so eloquently put it on twitter this morning:</p>
<blockquote class='twitter-tweet'><p>@<a href="https://twitter.com/ckunzelman">ckunzelman</a> I had a think I think some writers do that thing where they think their light is brighter in the dark&mdash; <br />Cara Ellison (@Carachan1) <a href='http://twitter.com/#!/Carachan1/status/301355660052951041' data-datetime='2013-02-12T15:42:42+00:00'>February 12, 2013</a></p></blockquote>
<blockquote class='twitter-tweet'><p>@<a href="https://twitter.com/ckunzelman">ckunzelman</a> so they don&#039;t cite or lean on people, but actually brilliance is brighter when you light someone else&#039;s candle&mdash; <br />Cara Ellison (@Carachan1) <a href='http://twitter.com/#!/Carachan1/status/301355814789201920' data-datetime='2013-02-12T15:43:19+00:00'>February 12, 2013</a></p></blockquote>
<blockquote class='twitter-tweet'><p>@<a href="https://twitter.com/ckunzelman">ckunzelman</a> that metaphor was strained BUT YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN etc&mdash; <br />Cara Ellison (@Carachan1) <a href='http://twitter.com/#!/Carachan1/status/301355923560075264' data-datetime='2013-02-12T15:43:45+00:00'>February 12, 2013</a></p></blockquote>
<blockquote class='twitter-tweet'><p>@<a href="https://twitter.com/ckunzelman">ckunzelman</a> yeah &#8211; you know that flare that candles have when one wick joins the other &#8211; that&#039;s what we need. We are a body of smart ppl&mdash; <br />Cara Ellison (@Carachan1) <a href='http://twitter.com/#!/Carachan1/status/301357253448056833' data-datetime='2013-02-12T15:49:02+00:00'>February 12, 2013</a></p></blockquote>
<blockquote class='twitter-tweet'><p>@<a href="https://twitter.com/ckunzelman">ckunzelman</a> We all read each other&#039;s work, or should be &#8211; and should be reading *outside* of game crit as well. We just are enthusiast press&mdash; <br />Cara Ellison (@Carachan1) <a href='http://twitter.com/#!/Carachan1/status/301357474701778945' data-datetime='2013-02-12T15:49:55+00:00'>February 12, 2013</a></p></blockquote>
<blockquote class='twitter-tweet'><p>@<a href="https://twitter.com/ckunzelman">ckunzelman</a> that never learned to credit or to read or to be grateful for the people that came before&mdash; <br />Cara Ellison (@Carachan1) <a href='http://twitter.com/#!/Carachan1/status/301357576837283840' data-datetime='2013-02-12T15:50:19+00:00'>February 12, 2013</a></p></blockquote>
<p>So what do I mean by putting citations in your work?</p>
<p>I mean acknowledging that other people have come before you and that their opinions and statements about the game are in conversation with your own. I mean doing something like what <a href="http://www.bitcreature.com/criticism/decipher-the-unexpected-hurt/">Lana Polansky is doing here</a>; you do a search, you find pertinent information, and then you contextualize it in your argument. It is a way of positioning yourself, but it is also a way of acknowledging the labor that other people have put into this this great communal hodgepodge that we call &#8220;games writing.&#8221;</p>
<p>Summed up: we are not writing in a vacuum.</p>
<p>How did things get this way? How did we come to a place in the games writing community where you can write a thousand words <a href="http://www.popmatters.com/pm/post/164085-/">about a game like </a><em><a href="http://www.popmatters.com/pm/post/164085-/">Dear Esther</a> </em>and <a href="http://www.popmatters.com/pm/post/168246-/">not cite a single other writer</a> on the topic? I think part of it is exactly what Ellison is pointing out in her tweets&#8211;the writers about games have largely emerged from the world of enthusiast press.</p>
<p>I have an anecdote to share: a friend was working for a fairly popular rap magazine. He was reviewing an album, and after he listened to it, he started reading other reviews of the album. A coworker asked him what he was doing, and he told her: &#8220;I&#8217;m reading what other reviews have said about this album before I review it.&#8221; She was appalled. His interpretation would be influenced&#8211;it wouldn&#8217;t be &#8220;authentic.&#8221;</p>
<p>This authenticity of the authorial voice is something that we are deeply concerned with in games writing. We want our reviewers to be clean and untouched by any motivating force that could potentially sway them in any way. Last year&#8217;s <a href="http://kotaku.com/5957810/the-contemptible-games-journalist-why-so-many-people-dont-trust-the-gaming-press-and-why-theyre-sometimes-wrong">DoritoGate</a> is the operative example here, although the forumgoer complaint of &#8220;X game bought reviews!&#8221; probably predates the development of agriculture.</p>
<p>I don&#8217;t think it is a coincidence that lots of games writers cut their teeth on game reviews and continue to do them. They are a sort of ground zero for games writing, and doing a good one is particularly difficult&#8211;there is a precarious balance between having some fidelity between expectation, mechanical interaction, and emotional response (<a href="http://www.mammon-machine.com/post/42805935533/review-criticism-a-dead-space-3-review-reignites-the">Mammon Machine&#8217;s post on the recent <em>Dead Space 3 </em>review at Polygon</a> is spectacular in its analysis of that balance). But that testing ground also tempers a writer into certain habits that are expected by the authenticity-chasing readers: every writer is expected to go in without knowledge and make an &#8220;objective&#8221; judgment of the quality of a game.</p>
<p>I think that makes for bad reviews. I think it makes for worse criticism.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s a second part of this that doesn&#8217;t often get talked about, or it only gets brought up in discussions of &#8220;confessional&#8221; writing and its intersection with New Games Journalism. What kind of writing am I talking about here?</p>
<p>We need to start making a formal split between games criticism, games journalism, and essaying. In the world of writing, these things are all separate categories with their own explicit qualities, but games writing has managed to collapse them all into a lump category called &#8220;games journalism,&#8221; which describes maybe 25% of the actual games writing that I read during any given week.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m going to sketch out how I see these three different genres of games writing. These distinctions are written large and they are slippery. Any one piece can roll through any of these categories, but I think that that every piece also ends in one of the three. I would love to see people debating the distinctions in the comments or on Twitter&#8211;at least we would be talking about it. So, a sketch:</p>
<p>Games criticism is the process of making an argument and using evidence to back up that argument. It is the performing of an exegesis on a text or it is making a point about a thing and explaining, in detail, how you came to a conclusion about that thing. What does this <em>mean</em>? An example of this is Margaret Atwood&#8217;s &#8220;<a href="http://books.google.com/books?id=OXvJNu-NftIC&amp;pg=PA93&amp;dq=atwood+%22writing+utopia%22#v=onepage&amp;q=atwood%20%22writing%20utopia%22&amp;f=false">Writing Utopia</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p>Games journalism is the process of breaking down events and factual information for consumption by the public. What <em>happened</em>? A good example of this is Matt Taibbi&#8217;s &#8220;<a href="http://www.rollingstone.com/politics/news/secret-and-lies-of-the-bailout-20130104">Secrets and Lies of the Bailout</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p>Games essaying is the process of writing about anything from an explicitly personal, subjective position with the end goal being a better elucidation of what that personal experience was like (and maybe a big, grand life lesson). What did I <em>experience</em>? A good example of this is anything by David Foster Wallace, but I will pick a personal favorite &#8220;<a href="http://www.gourmet.com/magazine/2000s/2004/08/consider_the_lobster">Consider the Lo</a><a href="http://www.gourmet.com/magazine/2000s/2004/08/consider_the_lobster">bster</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p>Obviously essaying and criticism are interweaved with one another and they bleed back and forth. Journalism benefits from embodied writing&#8211;the &#8220;I&#8221; belongs there as much as anything else does. But I still think that we need to be honest about how all of these kinds of writing are different, and more importantly, that they have different goals in mind. Those three pieces are all great, and they are all personal, but they are doing vastly different things.</p>
<p>I want to focus on criticism here. Journalism requires citations by its very nature&#8211;there have to be facts to report on and you have to communicate those facts to the audience, even if the games writing standard of that journalism is sometimes &#8220;rewrite this press release.&#8221; Essaying doesn&#8217;t require any citation at all. It is so deeply rooted in the subjective and can sort of just ruminate on youth, or lobsters, or the Atlantic ocean, or whatever.</p>
<p>Criticism, however, is about making a point and trying to show other people how you came to the conclusion that that point was valid. Criticism is the process of crafting an argument, and it is almost always a transparent thing; good criticism should build itself in front of the reader. It should be like a master artist sketching in dark and light. Of course, none of us ever get to that point, but you understand what I&#8217;m saying here, hopefully.</p>
<p>So games criticism, by its very nature, needs citations. As I said in my Twitter rants, if you are a games critic, you are working in a community. If you are publishing on Nightmare Mode or Medium Difficulty or Ontological Geek or Midnight Resistance or Game Church or The Border House or First Person Scholar or any of the other websites that bill themselves based on games criticism, you should be citing other people. If you are writing on any topic about video games, I promise you that someone else has written on it. It might be bad, or it might be on some small blogspot, or it might be a brilliant user blog on Gamefaqs (this is very unlikely.) The point is that an hour spent Googling and reading is an hour that will inevitably make your argument stronger and give you a better position to start from.</p>
<p>Other people are writing. You are reading them. Why not cite them? Why not temper your arguments against others? It can only make your argument better. In Ellison&#8217;s words, it makes both your writing and the writing of the person (or bot) you are citing better. It gets everything out in the air. People are able to see the genealogy of your criticism.</p>
<p>A charge that gets leveled at me on this topic often: isn&#8217;t this an academic concern? Won&#8217;t it make video game criticizing more stilted, more academic, and more caught up in proper citations? Let me be honest: I don&#8217;t think online games criticism could be hurt by mimicking academic standards a little. At the same time, no. I&#8217;m not calling for works cited pages or proper in-text citation. I want articles that acknowledge that others have written on the topic. I would even settle for an &#8220;essays I read while preparing this piece&#8221; list at the bottom. Anything to acknowledge the conversation that is happening.</p>
<p>You&#8217;ll notice that I said &#8220;acknowledge&#8221; and not &#8220;generate.&#8221; The conversation is already happening. The moment you publish games criticism online it is read into, read alongside, and overread by lots and lots of people, more so if it makes something like Critical Distance.</p>
<p>What finally forced me to sit down and write this post was a recent post by Mattie Brice on The Border House called &#8220;<a href="http://borderhouseblog.com/?p=10148">Decolonize Me</a>.&#8221; A while ago, Mattie published a piece on called &#8220;<a href="http://nightmaremode.net/2013/01/would-you-kindly-24451/">Would You Kindly</a>&#8221; and Jonas Kyratzes responded with &#8220;<a href="http://www.jonas-kyratzes.net/2013/01/18/would-you-kindly-not/">Would You Kindly Not</a>.&#8221; Samantha Allen then responded to these articles here at <em>TCIW </em>with &#8220;<a href="http://thiscageisworms.com/2013/02/07/can-we-kindly-by-samantha-allen/">Can We Kindly</a>.&#8221; All of these essays are concerned with the same subject matter: what role does personal experience have in video games (and games writing.)</p>
<p>Brice&#8217;s post is totally dependent on the recent conversation on personal writing and its roles in games and games writing. However, the only citation that Brice makes is to <a href="http://www.electrondance.com/after-the-dust-ethics-followup/">an article</a> on <em>Electron Dance</em> that collects some responses to the recent &#8220;<a href="http://www.electrondance.com/after-the-dust-ethics-followup/">The Ethics of Selling Children</a>,&#8221; which interrogates the concept of &#8220;confessional&#8221; games writing.</p>
<p>Let me be clear: Brice is working in criticism here. She is analyzing the arguments being made about confessional writing and sequentially arguing against them, but she chooses not to cite specific arguments or to link to specific arguments. She doesn&#8217;t give us block quotes to parse out on our own. Instead, she presents us with rhetorical phrases like &#8220;a lot of it boils down to&#8230;&#8221; and &#8220;I find this to be a result&#8230;&#8221; which she uses to make her point. Both of these phrases, and in fact most of the arguments that she makes in the article, could be supported with links to recent articles and posts on the subject. The most damaging part of this is that she even <em>recognizes and acknowledges </em>that she is writing in conversation with a number of people, and makes the decision to avoid actively dealing with both her opposition and allies.</p>
<p>What is the effect? In the micro, there probably isn&#8217;t one. At best it just leaves me sad that what could have been a phenomenal essay is merely good and at best a clarification of a point that was already made in much the same way as &#8220;Would You Kindly.&#8221; In the macro, I think that avoiding citations means that we (and I&#8217;m talking outside of this example now) retreat into our own self-sustaining bubbles. I think the traps that games criticism constantly fall into, the tired debates&#8211;&#8221;are games art?&#8221; &#8220;what is a game?&#8221; &#8220;peanut butter in my chocolate?!&#8221;&#8211;are made infinitely worse because we do a damn terrible job of citing and having some fidelity to conversations. Every time you write a piece of criticism without citations, you are legitimizing the practice. Every instance of legitimizing the practice heightens the probability that you will read a piece about the art status of games.</p>
<p>Beyond the comedy option, there is also the fact that citation forces close reading. For instance, Brice tweeted this yesterday:</p>
<blockquote class='twitter-tweet'><p>I think the best part about people critiquing my use of personal experience is that they don&#039;t critique the actual use, just its existence.&mdash; <br />Mattie Brice (@xMattieBrice) <a href='http://twitter.com/#!/xMattieBrice/status/301392955757961216' data-datetime='2013-02-12T18:10:54+00:00'>February 12, 2013</a></p></blockquote>
<p>The problem with this, as Kyratzes points out in a comment on Allen&#8217;s piece, is that is exactly what his initial post is about. In the comment he writes:</p>
<blockquote><p>I think the arguments that Joel and I have made about personal/confessional writing are sometimes mistaken for an attack on all such writing, or as an attack on the expression of the experiences themselves. But I think a close reading of both our articles will show that our concern is with how such writing is produced and used, not a condemnation of all personal writing.</p></blockquote>
<p>Brice&#8217;s opinion on personal experience and its use under contemporary capitalism is fairly explicit in the end of &#8220;Decolonize Me,&#8221; where she writes:</p>
<blockquote><p>This has been the story for decades and centuries. Social progress comes only after those with power gasp and say, ‘Wow, I didn’t know it was <em>that</em> bad!’ In this context, the personal experience is rebellion, it won’t allow the status quo to go unchallenged and stay superior without their readers feeling a major sense of dissonance. Personal games make you intimate with the way works influence players with their politics without the participants’ awareness. The other path isn’t bare because it’s impossible, but because it’s silenced.</p></blockquote>
<p>So for Brice, experiential writing and using her voice to speak and and claim that she exists is rebellion, period. For Kyratzes, experiential writing is produced in certain contexts and is always on slope of being coopted by capitalism, which puts him on edge. The tweet paints Brice&#8217;s critics (and who else could it be other than Kyratzes?) as missing something fundamental in her argument. That isn&#8217;t what is going on here. Kyratzes both understands and is responding, specifically, to Brice&#8217;s <em>exact</em> point.</p>
<p>How could Brice&#8217;s essay <em>not</em> have been made better by actually dealing with the arguments of her interlocutors? In a world where Brice acknowledges that Kyratzes is making very specific responses and claims to her initial article, we could actually get a deeper debate and understanding of how she thinks that experiential writing could resist capitalism. Or we could get the opposite and she could say that it is cooptable and that we should be fine with it.</p>
<p><strong>I don&#8217;t know what she would say because she doesn&#8217;t make the arguments.</strong> By not participating in the conversation, and by not using references and citations, Brice is essentially shouting her arguments about experiential writing into the void.</p>
<p>Games criticism will only get better if we abandon the fantasy of the individual speaker who isn&#8217;t a part of a community. We have to do the work; we have to cite. That&#8217;s the only way out. I want us all to shine together&#8211;I&#8217;ll end on a high note, with what I think should be our mantra as a community going forward. Sincerely, unironically: &#8220;brilliance is brighter when you light someone else&#8217;s candle.&#8221;</p>
<blockquote class='twitter-tweet'><p>@<a href="https://twitter.com/ckunzelman">ckunzelman</a> so they don&#039;t cite or lean on people, but actually brilliance is brighter when you light someone else&#039;s candle&mdash; <br />Cara Ellison (@Carachan1) <a href='http://twitter.com/#!/Carachan1/status/301355814789201920' data-datetime='2013-02-12T15:43:19+00:00'>February 12, 2013</a></p></blockquote>
<p>[Quick note: I am totally on board with experiential writing and I think it is a valuable partner to <a title="On Game Centered Criticism" href="http://thiscageisworms.com/2012/11/29/on-game-centered-criticism/">game centered criticism</a>. I don't think it should be eliminated from the spectrum of games writing.]</p>
<p>&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;-</p>
<p><strong>EDIT:</strong> There have been quite a few responses to this piece on Twitter. I very clearly wasn&#8217;t doing the kind of work that I should have in regards to picking Mattie as a test case. This isn&#8217;t a problem that boils down to Mattie. It is systemic, and the choice I made to make Mattie my example was, as I am not well aware, in bad taste and also just sort of a shitty thing to do.</p>
<p>What follows are some responses to this that I (and Joel McCoy [thanks Joel]) have collected. You should read them all because they are all important and point out some significant problems with my post:</p>
<p><a href="http://storify.com/BooDooPerson/mattie-on-obligation-to-argue">The first is Mattie Brice responding to the general idea that she should always be having to &#8220;debate&#8221; someone while writing games criticism.</a></p>
<p><a href="http://storify.com/ckunzelman/responses-to-citation-article">The second is an ongoing thread</a> where Porpentine, Cara Ellison, and Mattie all discuss with me, specifically, some of the shortcomings and just fucked-up problems that I am perpetuating with my post. At the bottom of that same Storify is Maddy Myers pointing out some basic systemic issues that immediately came to her mind when reading my piece.</p>
<p><strong>EDIT 2: </strong><a href="http://superopinionated.com/2013/02/13/dont-let-calling-yourself-an-ally-get-in-the-way-of-being-a-silencing-jerk-now/">Courtney Stanton has posted</a> about how I frame the debate and how that just fundamentally silences Mattie Brice. She also hones in on how I use the word &#8220;academic,&#8221; which I really meant as a shorthand for recognition of argumentative history, citations, and generally a refusal of the independent speaker problem that I criticize throughout the piece. Of course, that doesn&#8217;t matter, and so she rightly hammers me on the exclusionary rhetoric.</p>
<p><strong>EDIT 3:</strong> <a href="http://realtalkvideogames.tumblr.com/post/43070516489/take-me-personally-babe">Mattie Brice responds</a>.</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://thiscageisworms.com/category/video-games-2/'>Video Games</a> Tagged: <a href='http://thiscageisworms.com/tag/game-centered-criticism/'>game centered criticism</a>, <a href='http://thiscageisworms.com/tag/jonas-kyratzes/'>jonas kyratzes</a>, <a href='http://thiscageisworms.com/tag/mattie-brice/'>mattie brice</a>, <a href='http://thiscageisworms.com/tag/personal-writing/'>personal writing</a>, <a href='http://thiscageisworms.com/tag/samantha-allen/'>samantha allen</a>, <a href='http://thiscageisworms.com/tag/taxonomy/'>taxonomy</a>, <a href='http://thiscageisworms.com/tag/video-games/'>video games</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3042/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3042/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3042/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3042/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3042/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3042/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3042/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3042/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3042/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3042/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3042/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3042/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3042/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3042/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3042&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thiscageisworms.com/2013/02/13/on-citation-in-video-games-criticism-or-lighting-someone-elses-candle/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/7d00a315fd5430114af6ef5c375abcd9?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">kunzelman</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>An Open Letter to the Guy Who Thinks He Can Fix My Life in Five Minutes</title>
		<link>http://mattnt.com/2013/02/16/open-letter/</link>
		<comments>http://mattnt.com/2013/02/16/open-letter/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2013 14:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Matt Thomas</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[assholes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[body issues]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mansplaining]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weight]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mattnt.com/?p=4946</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Thank you so much. When you asked if you could talk to me privately for a few minutes at that party, I totally didn&#8217;t know that you wanted to lecture me about my health. That was so unexpected and appreciated. It&#8217;s certainly not as though there&#8217;s been some version of you ever-present in my life. [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4946&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thank you so much. When you asked if you could talk to me privately for a few minutes at that party, I totally didn&#8217;t know that you wanted to lecture me about my health. That was so unexpected and appreciated. It&#8217;s certainly not as though there&#8217;s been some version of you ever-present in my life. Uncles, friends&#8217; dads, total strangers who &#8220;used to be [my] size.&#8221; So thank you; thank you so much.</p>
<p>As you know, part of your duty as a fit and healthy person is to remind unfit people that they are unhealthy and in need of your help. When you do this, don&#8217;t forget to say something patronizing about how &#8220;you want to keep them around for a long time.&#8221; It&#8217;ll really make them feel good about themselves, showing how much you care by insinuating that you&#8217;re going to outlive them. Be sure to mention how easy it is, how it&#8217;s just a simple combination of diet and exercise. That&#8217;s probably not something they&#8217;ve ever tried before, so there&#8217;s no need to consider whether it&#8217;s insulting to assume they don&#8217;t already know it. What&#8217;s that? No soda? Shouldn&#8217;t eat carbs? No kidding.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m not sure what the world would do without the Guy Who Thinks He Can Fix Our Lives in Five Minutes. Overweight people would simply go about their day, blissfully unaware that they are disgusting and probably going to die soon. Women might walk down the street without realizing that they are dressed like sluts. Coworkers might have to do their jobs normally, without a helpful mansplainer nearby to constantly watch over their shoulder. Wherever you go, you&#8217;re just making sure that the people around you can benefit from your expertise. And for that, on behalf of all of us, <a href="http://iconicphotos.wordpress.com/2009/08/22/johnny-cashs-finger/" target="_blank">I salute you</a>.</p>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4946&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://mattnt.com/2013/02/16/open-letter/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>58</slash:comments>
		<georss:point>30.882963 -87.773047</georss:point>
		<geo:lat>30.882963</geo:lat>
		<geo:long>-87.773047</geo:long>
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/86debe7ed7ece0f968097a768dcbd5cb?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">MNT</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Let There Never Be A Last Picture Show</title>
		<link>http://susannajackson.wordpress.com/2013/02/15/let-there-never-be-a-last-picture-show/</link>
		<comments>http://susannajackson.wordpress.com/2013/02/15/let-there-never-be-a-last-picture-show/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 19:34:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>susannajackson</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[On movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal Essays]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boston]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[independent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NYT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[theaters]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://susannajackson.wordpress.com/?p=40</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I am tired of the multiplex. The chairs may be comfortable but the experience as a whole is not. There is no warmth. No friendliness. On a Friday evening, ticket lines loop around the lobby, no seat is left empty and still the experience is lonely, solitary business. We avoid each others&#8217; elbows on armrests, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=40&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I am tired of the multiplex. The chairs may be comfortable but the experience as a whole is not. There is no warmth. No friendliness. On a Friday evening, ticket lines loop around the lobby, no seat is left empty and still the experience is lonely, solitary business. We avoid each others&#8217; elbows on armrests, we are irritated by someone&#8217;s &#8216;excuse mes&#8217; on the way to the bathroom, and we shoot furious glares at those responsible for the accidental kicking of one&#8217;s seat. Post-film banter with fellow moviegoers is non-existent. It is as if we go to the theater thinking we are headed to our living room and are distraught when we find a naked fat man on our sofa.</p>
<p>The movie theater experience isn&#8217;t this grim everywhere. The independently run theaters are a happy alternative to the multiplex. The folks who sell us our tickets are knowledgeable, the ticket-takers are talkative, the audience is amiable. Popcorn is available, but it is not necessary that you buy a barrel. As you file out of the darkened theater you will often encounter a  fellow film fanatic who wants to talk to you about that clever plot twist or her award-winning performance. I shared one such conversation after seeing <em>Beasts of The Southern Wild</em> at <a href="http://www.coolidge.org/">Coolidge Corner Theater</a> while my eyes were still wet with tears.</p>
<div id="attachment_201" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://susannajackson.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/beasts-of-the-southern-wild1.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-201" alt="Beasts of the Southern Wild (2012)" src="http://susannajackson.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/beasts-of-the-southern-wild1.jpg?w=300&#038;h=158" width="300" height="158" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Beasts of the Southern Wild (2012)</p></div>
<p>Movie production is changing and with it comes a threat against the theaters I love so much. All major production studios will be switching to digital format from celluloid which means that theaters across America will have to update their projection equipment. For Regal, AMC, and the other large theater chains, this poses no problem. But for most independent movie houses, the cost of updating is crippling or impossible.</p>
<p><a href="http://susannajackson.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/20130216_210649_hdr-1-1.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-287 alignright" alt="20130216_210649_HDR-1-1" src="http://susannajackson.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/20130216_210649_hdr-1-1.jpg?w=330&#038;h=450" width="330" height="450" /></a>Eric Hynes, in a <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2012/08/25/movies/resort-towns-face-a-last-picture-show.html?pagewanted=all"><em>NYT</em> article</a> printed last August, said &#8220;John Fithian, president of the <a title="group site" href="http://www.natoonline.org/index.php">National Association of Theater Owners</a>, says 30,000 screens have already been converted, leaving nearly 10,000 in some stage of transition. As he told exhibitors at CinemaCon in 2011, “If you don’t make the decision to get on the digital train soon, you will be making the decision to get out of the business.”&#8221;</p>
<p>Last fall, The Coolidge Corner Theater launched their <a href="http://www.coolidge.org/support-us/digital-cinema-challenge">Digital Cinema Challenge</a> to fundraise over $200,000 to update to digital projection. They were fortunate to reach their goals in a matter of months with donations from over six hundred contributors. Theaters across the country are taking similar initiatives. Another Boston-area theater, <a href="http://brattlefilm.org/">Brattle Theater</a> has a <a href="http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/78747263/brattle-theatre-digital-projection-and-hvac-renova?ref=card">Kickstarter</a> to help them reach their digital goals.</p>
<p>In 1977, <em>NYT</em> article, <a href="http://select.nytimes.com/gst/abstract.html?res=F10F10FF345915768FDDA90A94DA405B878BF1D3">&#8220;The Last Picture Show,&#8221; </a>prematurely predicted the end of the independent movie house. Perhaps the August article is just as prematurely pessimistic. I hope there are people like me who can&#8217;t &#8212; won&#8217;t &#8212; imagine the end of the independent theater. I hope that the digital upgrade is merely a hurdle that requires some community support to overcome.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/40/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/40/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=40&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://susannajackson.wordpress.com/2013/02/15/let-there-never-be-a-last-picture-show/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>37</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://susannajackson.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/1054179352_02e72246af.jpg?w=100" />
		<media:content url="http://susannajackson.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/1054179352_02e72246af.jpg?w=100" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/6a62ed3e3181353b600f14cd04c68776?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F0.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">susannajackson</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://susannajackson.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/beasts-of-the-southern-wild1.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Beasts of the Southern Wild (2012)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://susannajackson.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/20130216_210649_hdr-1-1.jpg?w=330" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">20130216_210649_HDR-1-1</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>We&#8217;re All Living in Portlandia</title>
		<link>http://alexwilgus.wordpress.com/2013/02/15/were-all-living-in-portlandia/</link>
		<comments>http://alexwilgus.wordpress.com/2013/02/15/were-all-living-in-portlandia/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 21:29:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>alexwilgus</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adbusters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[americana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bourgeois]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[carrie brownstein]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crisis of conformity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fred armisen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hipsters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[portlandia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vice magazine]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://alexwilgus.wordpress.com/?p=1015</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Once in a while, a popular word will snowball into a state of such broad explanatory use that thoughtful people must either whittle it down to a more definite size or call for its utter dissolution.  This is the present state of hipster, a term wielded with equal frequency as a fashion, a movement, a [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1015&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://alexwilgus.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/20130215-140957.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full" alt="20130215-140957.jpg" src="http://alexwilgus.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/20130215-140957.jpg?w=720" /></a></p>
<p>Once in a while, a popular word will snowball into a state of such broad explanatory use that thoughtful people must either whittle it down to a more definite size or call for its utter dissolution.  This is the present state of <em>hipster</em>, a term wielded with equal frequency as a fashion, a movement, a demographic, and even an insult.</p>
<p>In 2008, <em>Adbusters</em> ran an article with a title that is, to date, still the only title to successfully convince me to read <em>Adbusters.</em>  It was called &#8220;<a href="http://www.adbusters.org/magazine/79/hipster.html">Hipster: The Dead End of Western Civilization</a>.&#8221;  This article came at just the right time with just the right dose of acid to make it one of the most important pieces of social journalism of our time.  In it Douglas Haddow defined &#8220;hipsterdom&#8221; as an ugly and regrettable mutation of Western counterculture.  Its chameleonic quality&#8211;wearing the symbols of  countercultural movements the world over without taking any stake in any of them&#8211;is rivaled only by its rituals of narcissism practiced by young scenesters who attend nightly parties in hopes of being photographed, then wake up the next afternoon and check the blogs hoping to catch a glimpse of themselves.  All of it, Haddow argues, revolves around consumption.  Hipsterdom is in fact consumerism that has successfully passed itself off as counterculture.  Hipsters are nothing but young yuppies.</p>
<p>Those who rallied to defend the hipster came, perhaps predictably, from the offices of the very magazines and blogs Haddow blamed for creating the hipster monster.  <em>Vice</em> magazine&#8217;s Gavin McInnes&#8211;quoted in Haddow&#8217;s piece&#8211;famously blamed the term hipster on &#8220;chubby bloggers who aren&#8217;t getting laid any more and are bored.&#8221;  Dan Hancox of The Guardian joined in to tell Adbusters to <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/commentisfree/2008/sep/03/fashion">&#8220;lighten up&#8221;</a> and stop worrying about the lives of &#8220;fashion people&#8221; because they aren&#8217;t doing any harm to anyone.  On their count, the hipster does not exist outside of a word invented by jealous, yuppie has-beens to describe youth movements that they, due to age or unattractiveness, are no longer capable of taking part in.  That the term is used to describe such disparate social phenomena as home beer-brewing and european house music is proof of its generalizing, indefinite quality.  It is a derogatory term deployed only by those on the outside looking in.</p>
<p>Yet what are we to think when we see waxed mustaches, thick-rimmed glasses, mid-century haircuts, cutoff jeans, and bright yellow leggings all striding down the sidewalk in the same posse?  If there is no epidemic of irony gripping our nation&#8217;s youth, then why do we laugh when we see a gallery of <a href="http://www.tumblr.com/tagged/hipster%20disney%20princesses">hipster Disney princesses</a>:  stills of Ariel, Jasmine, and Belle caught in unimpressed ho-hum expressions with big glasses superimposed onto them via photoshop?  If fashion is not evolving at the breakneck speed of market appetite, then where have all the keffiyehs gone?  Why is everybody now drinking Shiner Bock instead of Pabst Blue Ribbon?  How can we dismiss the word <em>hipster</em> when its explanatory power still seems so intact, but how can we continue to use it when it seems to apply to almost any current craze?</p>
<p>I think the only satisfactory course is to retire the word &#8220;hipster&#8221; and replace it instead with &#8220;Portlandia.&#8221;  As you may notice, this entails more than a change in semantics. Indeed, it is a complete change of concept.  The genius of Fred Armisen and Carrie Brownstein&#8217;s IFC sketch-comedy is that it&#8217;s not interested in defining one or another particular type of people, rather it is trying to define a place.  No one stereotype dominates the show&#8217;s cast.  By the third season, their cast of regular characters (almost all of them are different pairs played by Armisen and Brownstein&#8211;among them the feminist bookstore owners, the grungy punks, the bar-hopping scenesters, the thirtysomething married couple, the fortysomething rich couple, the mechanic-and-wife couple, and the outdoorsy couple) has swelled to Dickensian levels.  Like Dickens, the duo are not content with satire.  Satirical comedy&#8211;that one can see Armisen perform weekly on SNL&#8211;visits a supposed social type or specific person, skewers them thoroughly, then leaves them to curl up and die.  Armisen and Brownstein on the other hand, double back to revisit their characters over and over, never closing the book on them.  The final episode of season two joins them all together in a multiple blocks-long line for a hot new brunch place.  <em>Portlandia</em> broadens our gaze beyond defining (and roasting) whatever a hipster is, and instead denotes the broader social space that all 21st Century middle-class Americans live in.  &#8221;What&#8217;s going on with those hipsters?&#8221; is not the correct question according to <em>Portlandia</em>.  Instead it&#8217;s, &#8220;what&#8217;s going on with all of us?&#8221;</p>
<p><em>Portlandia</em> makes the radical claim that hipsters, yuppies, granolas, punks, parents, and hippies are all of a type, all in the same socio-cultural-psychological-or-whatever-metaphysical-structure-you-like state, all carried along by the same social currents. Whether it is a debilitating addiction to Battlestar Galactica or a mad impulse to sew birds onto everything, it all comes down to the same sort of obsessive-consumptive behavior.  Regardless of whether or not you think this is an unfortunate predicament gripping America or just another way of life, acting out these unnamable and peculiar drives&#8211;rather than simply attributing them through two-dimensional parody to the actions and agendas of one or another type of people&#8211;makes these oddities and absurdities come alive as nameable sensations that most every middle-class American can relate to.  Portlandia is a place, both in time and physical space, and if you live there you can&#8217;t help but be part of the cast.</p>
<p>I should take a brief moment to say that <em>Portlandia</em> is not really about Portland, Oregon.  It is important to note that the &#8220;-dia&#8221; suffix suggests a broader social space than the city limits of the Rose City.  Portlandia exists in equal measure in Austin, Asheville, Nashville, San Francisco, St. Louis, Chicago, Madison, Minneapolis, Brooklyn, and of course Seattle.  Our word for 21st Century middle-classness must express itself as a specific place&#8211;Portland, Oregon in this case&#8211;to properly describe one of the features of our present bourgeoisie, a proud or perhaps artificial identification with locality.  If it is not marionberry pancakes in Portland, then it is fried avocados in Austin.  But perhaps Portland is the best place to represent our nation&#8217;s many enclaves of this particular strain of <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Bobos-Paradise-Upper-Class-There/dp/0684853787">bourgeois bohemia</a>.  Portland, Oregon is a city with a proud history of middle-classness.  Anti-capitalism, local politics, and petit-bourgeois populism run deep in Portlanders&#8217; veins, (check out Robert D. Johnston&#8217;s <em><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Radical-Middle-Class-Progressive-Twentieth-Century/dp/0691126003">The Radical Middle Class</a></em> for more on that) but what once may have been locally distinct traditions has, in the age of internet, gone national through the interstate avenues of style, consumption, and &#8220;cool.&#8221;  We certainly cannot be sure that the present mood originated in Portland.  Portlanders&#8217; historically rooted desire for self government and a wariness of corporate monopolies may still be a live instinct in certain sectors of middle-class America, but there are also newer cultural forces to explain and contend with&#8211;like why we would rather wait in a three-hour line to taste the marionberry pancakes at the newest &#8220;local&#8221; brunch place instead of spending considerably less money on the &#8220;cup o&#8217; joe side of dough&#8221; special at the (also locally-owned) diner-slash-gift shop down the street.</p>
<p>Obsession is the most central theme of <em>Portlandia</em> (the show.) Everyone is into something so intently that it&#8217;s like they have blinders on and can&#8217;t see the rest of the world around them.  No character is well-rounded (perhaps that&#8217;s a prerequisite for good comedy, but anyway, the point is clear.)  In one rapidly-edited sketch, Armisen madly tweets, facebooks, blogs, and checks his email until Brownstein snaps him out of it.  In another, the two try to one-up each other in newspaper, magazine, and blog articles they have read.  In another, a goateed Armisen goes around to all of his favorite spots, and in each one sees an annoyingly straight-laced man, clearly an out-of-town poser.  He takes such pains to avoid him that when the man grows his own goatee, Armisen shaves his and makes himself over to look like the man originally did. In the end, they&#8217;ve switched places entirely.  Each sketch plays off an obsession with one idea, a single isolated impulse that we are so invested in that we cannot get the lay of the land around us.  The obsessive impulse is evident in the show&#8217;s style.  In the vein of Michael Ian Black, David Wain, and Michael Showalter&#8217;s magnificent <em>Stella</em>, each situation and impulse is taken to its furthest extreme, and so becomes absurd. <em>Portlandia&#8217;s</em> genius lies in its portrayal of so many social types in this same mood.</p>
<p>I should draw attention to my focus on the middle-class.  I do this for two reasons.  One is that I think of myself as middle-class and cannot pretend to comment on ways of life too far outside my realm of life experience.  The other is that &#8220;middle-class&#8221; is a term that, while vague in itself, is usually deployed to mean a way of life that is reasonably moneyed.  It is a fact that having a decent amount of money and living at a certain level of comfort are sufficient conditions for regular outings at brunch, the frequent purchase of clothes, and a shelf full of DVDs.  It is possible that whatever Portlandia is, it is a space that can only be generated given a reasonably moneyed way of life.  But it does not follow that Portlandia and middle-classness is the same thing.  As you will find out if you read <em>The Radical Middle Class</em>, middle-class folks have not always been about the same business as they are today.  Anyway, even if the social and cultural, (or dare I say it&#8230;spiritual?) forces that make up Portlandia are in fact more universal than the economic enablers of a reasonably moneyed lifestyle, I can&#8217;t really speak to how they might manifest themselves in the poorer sections of our country nor those of the super-wealthy.</p>
<p>Fred Armisen <a href="http://www.mtvhive.com/2012/01/04/fred-armisen-interview/">does not believe</a> there is any such thing as a hipster.  If he was any other old uncreative blogger, I would have dismissed such an idea altogether.  But instead, whether he knows it or not, he has added tremendously to the conversation.  If the &#8220;hipster&#8221; is dead, it is not because he has been deconstructed into oblivion or finally defeated by a new cultural movement, nor has it been adequately defined, but because Armisen and Brownstein have given us a better word to describe what&#8217;s going on with the present middle-class.  In <em>Portlandia</em> we might just have a word that is capable of describing whatever it is that&#8217;s going on with us, precisely because it describes a place, not one or another kind of&#8211;to use the horrid word&#8211;subculture.  Though I can&#8217;t pretend it&#8217;s a thorough definition, I do think it&#8217;s better than <em>hipster</em>.  Where do our present consumptive maladies, obsessions, and other general peculiarities come from?  It wasn&#8217;t the hipsters, nor the bloggers.</p>
<p>&#8220;Forget about it Jake, it&#8217;s <em>Portlandia</em>.&#8221;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1015/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1015/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1015&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://alexwilgus.wordpress.com/2013/02/15/were-all-living-in-portlandia/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>17</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/9f46b81e8c3a108ac7e382648c743c7d?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">alexwilgus</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://alexwilgus.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/20130215-140957.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">20130215-140957.jpg</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
