<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2012 22:02:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>By Any Means Necessary: Welcome to the Border State</title>
		<link>http://maxdunbar.wordpress.com/2012/09/09/by-any-means-necessary-welcome-to-the-border-state/</link>
		<comments>http://maxdunbar.wordpress.com/2012/09/09/by-any-means-necessary-welcome-to-the-border-state/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2012 15:01:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>maxdunbar</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Manchester]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Political]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://maxdunbar.wordpress.com/?p=5576</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The decision to revoke London Met&#8217;s ability to teach international students is a curious one. Closing down bogus colleges and visa mills is one thing. Deporting three thousand students is quite another. What was the rationale for this? A UKBA spokesman told the Guardian about &#8216;serious and systemic failings&#8217; that meant that &#8216;Allowing London Metropolitan [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=5576&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a title="The decision to revoke London Met's ability to teach international students" href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/education/2012/aug/30/border-agency-international-students-threat">The decision to revoke London Met&#8217;s ability to teach international students</a> is a curious one. Closing down bogus colleges and visa mills is one thing. Deporting three thousand students is quite another. What was the rationale for this? A UKBA spokesman told the <em>Guardian </em>about &#8216;serious and systemic failings&#8217; that meant that &#8216;Allowing London Metropolitan University to continue to sponsor and teach international students was not an option.&#8217; Universities minister David Willetts said that &#8216;It is important that genuine students who are affected through no fault of their own are offered prompt advice and help.&#8217; Defending the UKBA, conservative writer Ed West <a title="points out that" href="http://blogs.telegraph.co.uk/news/edwest/100178565/student-visas-the-government-continues-to-do-the-right-thing-over-immigration/">points out</a>: &#8217;Student migration is now the largest route for non-European migrants to take, and has been so since 2008&#8242;.</p>
<p>It appears that this is purely a numbers game. And I like Willetts&#8217;s emphasis on &#8216;genuine&#8217; students. Again, people paying a visa mill is one thing. But are we now defining a &#8216;bogus&#8217; student as someone who applies to a UK university with the intention of living in the UK, making use of his degree and contributing to society? I thought we all had to go into education with that kind of vocational motive in mind?</p>
<p>When I first moved to South Manchester the bars were full of American, European and Asian accents heard on the streets and ringing in the twilight of the early evening balcony at Trof Fallowfield. The city would be an emptier place without them. As West points out, London Met is a bad university, 118th out of 120th in the tables. But there&#8217;s nothing I can see that would stop the UKBA applying these restrictions to every university in the UK. Universities already have to recruit UKBA compliance officers. A lecturer told me recently that she regularly receives &#8217;warning emails to keep my registers up to date cause of UKBA.&#8217; This has clearly been mainstreamed and HE professionals are now expected to help track down those the UKBA say are &#8216;illegal&#8217;.</p>
<p>And it was clear from the <a title="Commons debate on this " href="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm201213/cmhansrd/cm120903/debtext/120903-0001.htm">Commons debate on this</a> that London Met is basically a pilot. Potential high flier Tory Amber Rudd got up and said: &#8216;Reducing immigration levels is important to my constituents, who welcomed the admission by the Leader of the Opposition earlier in the year that there had been uncontrolled immigration under the previous Government. May I urge the Minister, therefore, to reform all routes of entry into the UK, including the student visa route, in order to build on the reductions he has already achieved?&#8217;</p>
<p>We have a border agency that hectors universities that they should be doing the UKBA&#8217;s job for them, and is trying to turn Britain&#8217;s universities into a compliance arm of the UKBA. With the coalition&#8217;s obsessive numbers game it is inevitable that bright people from other countries will conclude that it&#8217;s not worth the hassle of trying to study here. I mean, it&#8217;s not like Britain&#8217;s the only country that has good universities. For all the rhetoric about preserving British culture, the UKBA pursues numbers and process at the expense of Britain&#8217;s cultural reputation. <em>Private Eye&#8217;s </em>Lunchtime O&#8217;Boulez column compiles numerous stories of travelling classical musicians hassled and messed around by border police, to the extent that the game just ain&#8217;t worth the candle. So we can deport a few lazy engineering students but not any of the <a title="almost 400 suspected war criminals currently living in this country" href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/law/2011/feb/04/britain-home-to-400-war-criminals">almost 400 suspected war criminals currently living in this country</a>. Doesn&#8217;t it help you sleep soundly in your bed that your borders are guarded by people with such investigative rigour and common sense?</p>
<p>We&#8217;re always being told that we &#8216;can&#8217;t talk about immigration.&#8217; On Thursday there was another parliamentary debate. <a title="Guess which policy area" href="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm201213/cmhansrd/cm120906/debtext/120906-0002.htm#12090626000001">Guess which policy area</a>. It was triggered by a Migration Watch e-petition that urged the government to &#8216;take all necessary steps to reduce immigration to a level that will stabilise the UK’s population as close as possible to its present level and, certainly, significantly below 70 million.&#8217; This was picked up by Tory Nicholas Soames and tedious Merseyside Blue Labourite, Frank Field. The Commons passed this motion.</p>
<p>The anti-migration obsessives will froth and moan, but they can be strangely coy in places. They will highlight real or imagined problems, but maintain a reluctance to answer the basic question: &#8216;What would you do about it?&#8217; The SNP&#8217;s Pete Wishart was one of the few dissenting voices in the chamber that day. He asked a very good question:</p>
<blockquote><p>This nasty little motion mentions &#8216;all necessary steps&#8217;. Does he realise how authoritarian that sounds? The right hon. Member for Mid Sussex mentioned four steps, but what other &#8216;necessary steps&#8217; would the right hon. Member for Birkenhead (Mr Field) propose?</p></blockquote>
<p>I would add a few questions for Field, Soames, Migration Watch, the Daily Mail, Telegraph Blogs and all the others who invest so much emotion and energy in opposing immigration.</p>
<p>- When you say &#8216;all necessary steps&#8217;, what exactly do you mean by that? Could you explain what these steps are and how this would work in practice?</p>
<p>- Who would the &#8216;necessary steps&#8217; apply to? Do you want to cut the numbers of refugees, economic migrants, students or family migrants? What is the selection criteria here?</p>
<p>- You go on about your love for the free market, yet you advocate protectionist policies that would prevent other people competing with your sons and daughters for jobs and university places. Could you explain the contradiction.</p>
<p>- Following on from that, if you close the doors to migrants, <a title="will you be able to find the young workers" href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/commentisfree/2011/may/23/future-policy-elderly-care-on-own">will you be able to find the young workers</a> that we need to sustain an ageing population with subsidised pensions and social care? Do you think that autarky is a sustainable economic policy in a globalised world?</p>
<p>- You say that there are not just economic, but also cultural problems with immigration. For example, you quote an IPPR report that claims &#8216;It is no exaggeration to say that immigration under new Labour has changed the face of the country.&#8217; How would you address this in practice? Would you want to deport people with ILR, who have been naturalised, second and third generation immigrants, people who came over on the Windrush? Would there be a kind of social engineering experiment to recreate Britain in the late 1950s? Just how far with this do you want to go?</p>
<p>- You are concerned about population growth and certainly we have problems with overcrowded housing and schools. It&#8217;s not clear that these are the fault of immigrants alone but never mind that. But have you considered that the population scares of the 1970s turned out to be completely unfounded and that the consequences of having a declining population are <a title="little more difficult to deal with" href="http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/alex-massie/2012/07/britain-is-not-full/">a little more difficult to deal with</a>?</p>
<p>- You moan that you have been called a racist for talking about immigration, and you suffer from the &#8217;fear of saying something that would be called politically incorrect and thus being labelled as racist or anti-immigrant by the media.&#8217; It&#8217;s okay, we are all friends here, no one&#8217;s accusing you of anything and we&#8217;ll take it for granted that you are not racist. But isn&#8217;t it true that the restrictions you propose will disproportionately affect people with different colour skin? Do you accept that <em>some </em>criticism of immigration is demonstrably racist and that all racist parties in this country are committed to stamping out immigration?</p>
<p>- Is there a lower level of immigration that you would be happy with?</p>
<p><img title="immigration" src="http://maxdunbar.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/immigration1.jpg?w=450&h=281" alt="" width="450" height="281" /></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5576/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5576/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=5576&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://maxdunbar.wordpress.com/2012/09/09/by-any-means-necessary-welcome-to-the-border-state/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/8370387cb091e49f97f1f881bf13c0f4?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Max Dunbar</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://maxdunbar.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/immigration1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">immigration</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Vietnamese Chicken Curry</title>
		<link>http://thelemursarehungry.wordpress.com/2012/09/09/vietnamese-chicken-curry/</link>
		<comments>http://thelemursarehungry.wordpress.com/2012/09/09/vietnamese-chicken-curry/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2012 09:21:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>hungrylemur</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[ingredients]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[local foods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vietnamese food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ca ri ga]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chicken]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[curry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dinner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Saigon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vietnam]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thelemursarehungry.wordpress.com/?p=1523</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[By the time Mr Lemur and I hit Saigon on our tour of Southern Vietnam, you might think we&#8217;d have been all marketed out, but Ben Thanh market revitalised us. At first it felt a bit unwieldy with lots of stalls selling cheap clothes, fake plastic fruit and assorted tschotschkes, not to mention the Viet [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1523&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://thelemursarehungry.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/spice-stall-hcmc.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1524" title="spice-stall-HCMC" src="http://thelemursarehungry.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/spice-stall-hcmc.jpg" alt="" width="490" height="325" /></a></p>
<p>By the time Mr Lemur and I hit Saigon on our tour of Southern Vietnam, you might think we&#8217;d have been all marketed out, but Ben Thanh market revitalised us. At first it felt a bit unwieldy with lots of stalls selling cheap clothes, fake plastic fruit and assorted tschotschkes, not to mention the Viet ladies who have no problem whatsoever grabbing you and pushing you aside if you are in their way. (Seriously, they make little old Italian ladies seem reticent.) But we soon warmed to the cheery rudeness of the atmosphere and enjoyed a pretty good pork chop bun for breakfast. Since we were nearing the end of our time in Asia, I felt justified in attempting a bit of food shopping. While it was sadly not feasible to carry home any of the pickled fish I enjoyed in Chau Doc, it did seem reasonable to pick up some dried shrimp and spices. Ben Thanh had some lovely looking shrimp stalls where I&#8217;m fairly certain I was ripped off, and pushy coffee vendors who clearly dealt with tourists a lot. But the spice stall was not set up for tourism and, as you can see above, its proprietor was just a little daunting.<span id="more-1523"></span></p>
<p><a href="http://thelemursarehungry.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/nice-lady-hcmc.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1525" title="nice-lady-HCMC" src="http://thelemursarehungry.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/nice-lady-hcmc.jpg" alt="" width="490" height="326" /></a></p>
<p>I wanted some powdered ca ri ga mix, as Vietnamese curries are very specific and it struck me that this would be kind of a good staple to have in the storecupboard. Luckily, one of the customers took pity on me and decided to help out. You can see the Vietnamese phrasebook in my hand there &#8211; never has a book been less useful. It&#8217;s no insult to the good people at Lonely Planet, as the book is well thought out and does its best, but dear gods, nobody <em>ever</em> understood a single word of Vietnamese that came out of my mouth. This little interaction was a testiment to the magical powers of cross-cultural communication; one of those occasions where you somehow exchange meaning with someone despite sharing absolutely no common language. Shopping for food tends to bring this out in people – maybe it&#8217;s the cultural centrality of food, or the practicality of having lots of things to point at &#8211; but I love &#8216;talking&#8217; to people like this in markets. With this nice lady&#8217;s help, I came home with a box of  curry powder for chicken.</p>
<p><a href="http://thelemursarehungry.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/viet-curry-powder.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1526" title="viet-curry-powder" src="http://thelemursarehungry.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/viet-curry-powder.jpg" alt="" width="490" height="326" /></a></p>
<p>I know someone is going to tell me you can buy the same brand in London and you probably can, but I was happy to have it recommended. I finally tried out the curry powder this week, making a more or less traditional Vietnamese ca ri ga. I omitted the usual potatoes but you can always put them in with the carrots if you like them more than I do! Vietnamese curry is lighter than, say, a southern Thai curry, with less coconut milk and a soupier consistency. Don&#8217;t let that put you off &#8211; the flavour is hearty and reassuring, good for a late summer evening.</p>
<p><strong>Vietnamese chicken curry</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>8 pieces of chicken (either a whole chicken jointed or a selection of thigh and leg pieces)</li>
<li>3 tbsp Vietnamese curry powder</li>
<li>1 tsp chili powder (or to taste)</li>
<li>3 shallots</li>
<li>4 stalks lemongrass</li>
<li>1 thumb ginger</li>
<li>2 cloves garlic</li>
<li>6 lime leaves</li>
<li>2 fresh red chilies, sliced</li>
<li>1/2 can coconut milk</li>
<li>1 onion, cut in thin wedges</li>
<li>2 carrots, thickly sliced</li>
<li>cilantro to garnish</li>
</ul>
<p>Start by rubbing 2 tbsp of curry powder over your chicken with a bit of salt and leaving for at least a half hour.</p>
<p><a href="http://thelemursarehungry.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/marinade-chicken.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1527" title="marinade-chicken" src="http://thelemursarehungry.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/marinade-chicken.jpg" alt="" width="490" height="326" /></a></p>
<p>While you wait, make the curry paste. Chop the garlic, ginger, shallots and lemongrass and either pound in a mortar and pestle or whizz in a mini-prep. Brown the chicken well in a large pan or wok &#8211; I use a flat-bottomed Le Creuset &#8211; until the aromas of the curry are released.</p>
<p><a href="http://thelemursarehungry.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/browning-chicken.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1528" title="browning-chicken" src="http://thelemursarehungry.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/browning-chicken.jpg" alt="" width="490" height="326" /></a></p>
<p>Next, add the curry paste to the chicken and fry a little till it no longer smells raw. Then add the remainder of the curry powder, chili powder to taste (I don&#8217;t like this dish to be too spicy so I go light on the dried chilies), the sliced fresh chilies and lime leaves. Stir briefly and add a cup of water (you might need a bit more depending on your pot). Bring to the boil and then simmer, covered, for 20 minutes.</p>
<p><a href="http://thelemursarehungry.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/viet-curry.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1529" title="viet-curry" src="http://thelemursarehungry.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/viet-curry.jpg" alt="" width="490" height="326" /></a></p>
<p>Add the onions, carrots and coconut milk and simmer for another 15 minutes or until the carrots are cooked. Garnish with a bit of chopped cilantro. Serve with rice or bread.</p>
<p><a href="http://thelemursarehungry.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/viet-chicken-curry1.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1530" title="viet-chicken-curry1" src="http://thelemursarehungry.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/viet-chicken-curry1.jpg" alt="" width="490" height="326" /></a></p>
<p>Serves 4.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1523/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1523/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1523&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thelemursarehungry.wordpress.com/2012/09/09/vietnamese-chicken-curry/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/699b96fce7138da0ea640613c8e03526?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">hungrylemur</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thelemursarehungry.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/spice-stall-hcmc.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">spice-stall-HCMC</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thelemursarehungry.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/nice-lady-hcmc.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">nice-lady-HCMC</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thelemursarehungry.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/viet-curry-powder.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">viet-curry-powder</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thelemursarehungry.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/marinade-chicken.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">marinade-chicken</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thelemursarehungry.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/browning-chicken.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">browning-chicken</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thelemursarehungry.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/viet-curry.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">viet-curry</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thelemursarehungry.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/viet-chicken-curry1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">viet-chicken-curry1</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ramblings of a Pregnant 20-Something: Third Trimester!</title>
		<link>http://kookykuckoo.com/2012/09/05/the-ramblings-of-a-pregnant-twenty-something-the-third-trimester/</link>
		<comments>http://kookykuckoo.com/2012/09/05/the-ramblings-of-a-pregnant-twenty-something-the-third-trimester/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2012 14:08:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Alexandra</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[The Nesting Diaries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Baby shower]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nesting Diaries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pregnancy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Third Trimester of Prgenancy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women's issues]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://kookykuckoo.com/?p=3230</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I’m writing this from the perspective of my last week of pregnancy before my due date. Last week was my final midwife appointment, and I took my Mum, mainly because I was desperate for her to meet my eccentric Midwife ‘J’ who didn’t disappointment… moments after meeting my Mum for example (who is from North [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3230&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://kookykuckoo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/pregnant-gah.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-3231 alignnone" title="pregnant-gah" src="http://kookykuckoo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/pregnant-gah.jpg" alt="" width="545" height="354" /></a></p>
<p>I’m writing this from the perspective of my last week of pregnancy before my due date. Last week was my final midwife appointment, and I took my Mum, mainly because I was desperate for her to meet my eccentric Midwife ‘J’ who didn’t disappointment… moments after meeting my Mum for example (who is from North London) ‘J’ proceeded to ask whether she was “visiting from Australia”. This is the woman who could potentially deliver my baby…</p>
<p>I read an article on the Daily Mail Online about how Drew Barrymore (who is also a couple of weeks off of her due date) is walking around looking distinctly miserable. I sympathise, and I respect her for still ‘walking around’, as the third trimester is very much like glimpsing into the life of an OAP. Lack of mobility, falling asleep in armchairs, proudly listening to Classic FM and waiting for visitors to arrive with offerings of donuts… I’ve stayed as active and as social as I could manage, but there comes a time when sitting in pubs nursing an orange and lemonade and attempting to stay upright on the London Underground becomes unappealing, and then impossible. A final day trip to London Zoo when I spend most of the time moving from bench to bench… pretending to be <em>really</em> interested in the lions when actually I just want another sit down really hammers home the reality that <em>this is it</em>…</p>
<p>Because the third trimester may bring ‘blooming’ but it also obviously brings ‘ballooning’, and I can’t emphasise how heavy that gorgeous bump will get. Assistance is required when getting off of a low couch, feet swell after walking around the block in the summer heat, flip- flops become your best friend…  and as August brings an awful heat-wave of tropical proportions I effectively spend an entire weekend attempting to stay deadly still, with an electric fan trained upon me.</p>
<p>From this sluggish perspective I realise that the date of my Baby Shower is rapidly approaching… I feel like cancelling at one point, after overhearing a family member sniffingly commenting that “baby showers are just an Americanism!” and frankly feeling too tired to even organise getting dressed in the mornings, let alone a party at my house. But I see it through, mainly because I’ve spent the last couple of months ordering pretty bunting and baby shower decorations from ebay, and because my Mum (henceforth known as ‘Supermum’) explains that she will handle all the food… all the drink… just about everything, whilst my best friend volunteers to organise the party games. On the day of the baby shower Supermum arrives with military precision, best friend in the world brings a bounty of party games, family and friends descend with offerings of homemade cakes and oblige with tea-making and frankly bringing the fun (read my post on <a title="My Utterly Scrumptious Baby Shower" href="http://kookykuckoo.com/2012/08/06/my-utterly-scrumptious-baby-shower/" target="_blank">Baby Shower Decorations here</a>). I forget entirely about present giving, because that’s not what the day is about for me (although I do receive some amazing presents!); it’s about getting an extraordinary bunch of women together, and realising what an incredible support network I’m going to have once this baby is born.</p>
<p>The final weeks, take on an odd surrealism, as I try and get my head around how soon there will be an actual baby in the cot, not just my laundry, and that two of us will become ‘three of us’. We attend antenatal classes, led by a frizzy haired and slightly dazed midwife in socks ‘n’ sandals. I realise that the anxieties I’ve been experiencing about labour and becoming a first time Mum are totally common. In fact we are the youngest couple in the class, possibly the most relaxed and after everything that’s happened to us I’m suddenly proud of what we have achieved in nine months. &#8220;But how do you even look after a baby?!!&#8221; one woman suddenly asks in a highly sweeping manner. To which the frizzy haired midwife merely responds &#8220;you&#8217;ll know how to look after your baby, it&#8217;s instinct.&#8221; So I approach ‘Motherhood’, yes feeling the fear, but confident that I can go ahead and do it anyway.</p>
<p><a href="http://kookykuckoo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/congratulations-on-nine-months-of-sobriety.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-3232 alignnone" title="Congratulations on nine months of sobriety" src="http://kookykuckoo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/congratulations-on-nine-months-of-sobriety.jpg" alt="" width="580" height="675" /></a></p>
<h2>Previous Posts:</h2>
<p><a href="http://kookykuckoo.com/2012/08/07/ramblings-of-a-pregnant-twenty-something-the-first-trimester/"><img class=" wp-image-3241 alignnone" title="Gerkins" src="http://kookykuckoo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/gerkins.jpg?w=113&h=130" alt="" width="113" height="130" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://kookykuckoo.com/2012/08/07/ramblings-of-a-pregnant-twenty-something-the-first-trimester/" target="_blank">The Ramblings of a Pregnant Twenty-Something //The First Trimester</a></p>
<p><a href="http://kookykuckoo.com/2012/08/16/the-ramblings-of-a-pregnant-twenty-something-the-second-trimester/"><img class="size-thumbnail wp-image-3240 alignnone" title="pregnant-gah" src="http://kookykuckoo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/pregnant-gah1.jpg?w=150&h=97" alt="" width="150" height="97" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://kookykuckoo.com/2012/08/16/the-ramblings-of-a-pregnant-twenty-something-the-second-trimester/" target="_blank">The Ramblings of a Pregnant Twenty-Something //The Second Trimester</a></p>
<p><a href="http://kookykuckoo.com/2012/08/06/my-utterly-scrumptious-baby-shower/"><img class=" wp-image-3239 alignnone" title="DSCF1589" src="http://kookykuckoo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dscf1589.jpg?w=127&h=102" alt="" width="127" height="102" /></a></p>
<p><a title="My Utterly Scrumptious Baby Shower" href="http://kookykuckoo.com/2012/08/06/my-utterly-scrumptious-baby-shower/" target="_blank">My Utterly Scrumptious Baby Shower</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://kookykuckoo.com/category/the-nesting-diaries/'>The Nesting Diaries</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3230/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3230/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3230&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://kookykuckoo.com/2012/09/05/the-ramblings-of-a-pregnant-twenty-something-the-third-trimester/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>19</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://kookykuckoo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/pregnant-gah.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://kookykuckoo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/pregnant-gah.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">pregnant-gah</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/cedf09b1e32e74b100a0fd2ce32f5706?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F0.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">kookykuckoo</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://kookykuckoo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/pregnant-gah.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">pregnant-gah</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://kookykuckoo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/congratulations-on-nine-months-of-sobriety.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Congratulations on nine months of sobriety</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://kookykuckoo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/gerkins.jpg?w=131" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Gerkins</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://kookykuckoo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/pregnant-gah1.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">pregnant-gah</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://kookykuckoo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dscf1589.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSCF1589</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What It’s Like To Be a Northerner At University.</title>
		<link>http://makinguseofmydegree.wordpress.com/2012/09/08/what-its-like-to-be-a-northerner-at-university/</link>
		<comments>http://makinguseofmydegree.wordpress.com/2012/09/08/what-its-like-to-be-a-northerner-at-university/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2012 16:20:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>zoealice</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture.]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ghetto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Loughborough]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[North]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[society]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[South]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[university]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://makinguseofmydegree.wordpress.com/?p=1776</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[You&#8217;ve done it! You&#8217;ve defied the odds and gotten into university despite being a Northerner! Pat yourself on the back and take a moment to enjoy this achievement. Are you done? Good, because if you&#8217;re heading to a university that has a student population predominantly from the south then that sense of self worth you [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1776&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You&#8217;ve done it! You&#8217;ve defied the odds and gotten into university despite being a Northerner! Pat yourself on the back and take a moment to enjoy this achievement. Are you done? Good, because if you&#8217;re heading to a university that has a student population predominantly from the south then that sense of self worth you currently have will have left you by the end of freshers, where you&#8217;ll be crying yourself to sleep over the taunts you&#8217;ve received regarding your accent and the fact you&#8217;re not rich.</p>
<p>Of course, I&#8217;m joking. However, it&#8217;s impossible to deny that being a Northerner at a university dominated by Southerners isn&#8217;t an experience. I survived it though, and enjoyed it, but there are some things my dear Northerners should be prepared for before arriving at university:</p>
<p><strong>1) Apparently you  sound like you&#8217;re from &#8221;the ghetto&#8221;</strong></p>
<div id="attachment_1777" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://makinguseofmydegree.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/ghetto.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1777" title="ghetto" src="http://makinguseofmydegree.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/ghetto.jpg?w=300&h=249" alt="" width="300" height="249" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Where I sound like I&#8217;m from.</p></div>
<p>Well, <em>I</em> apparently sound like I&#8217;m from the ghetto,  and this wasn&#8217;t just an offhand comment from one person, this was said to me by quite a few people so by the end of it I was thinking &#8221;I get it guys, ok, I get it! I&#8217;m Northern ghetto trash! LEAVE ME AND MY ACCENT ALONE!&#8221; Me and my Sheffield friends who are also at university tried to figure out why I sounded &#8221;ghetto&#8221; and they didn&#8217;t and we established it&#8217;s because I talk slower than them, which doesn&#8217;t help matters because it means I have a dopey voice.</p>
<p><strong>2) Your accent gets mimicked a lot</strong></p>
<div id="attachment_1778" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://makinguseofmydegree.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/300.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1778" title="300" src="http://makinguseofmydegree.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/300.jpg?w=300&h=225" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">What you feel like doing when someone mocks your accent.</p></div>
<p>If you&#8217;re fortunate enough not to get called ghetto, don&#8217;t think you&#8217;ll escape getting your accent mimicked. After the first week or so at university, when people realised I was speaking English and not in Gorilla, the mocking comments came, and they came so thick and fast that I had northern slang beaten out of me by Christmas. The most upsetting thing for me was that it wasn&#8217;t just Southerners and Midlanders mocking me, I even had a fellow Northerner laugh at something I said once (I must REALLY sound ghetto). Basically, there&#8217;s nothing you can do, except take it! If you&#8217;re at a university dominated by southerners, there&#8217;s nothing you can do because you&#8217;re in the minority. If you&#8217;re at a northern dominated university, start a revolution or something.</p>
<p><strong>3) You find out that the &#8221;thick northerner&#8221; stereotype is wrong.</strong></p>
<div id="attachment_1779" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://makinguseofmydegree.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/confused.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1779" title="confused" src="http://makinguseofmydegree.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/confused.jpg?w=300&h=240" alt="" width="300" height="240" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">What I looked like when someone said Loughborough is in the North.</p></div>
<p>Since being at university, I&#8217;ve discovered that the geography of the country is debatable.  For example, I&#8217;ve heard Loughborough described as &#8221;a great Northern university&#8221; and that threw me. Surely everybody knows that Loughborough is in the midlands!? Apparently not. I&#8217;ve also encountered people who say &#8221;Anything above London is North&#8221; which is a very bold if inaccurate statement. Basically, I found out that whilst Northerners have a reputation for being  a little dim, we have better geographical knowledge of the UK than quite a few of our Southern counterparts who seem a little fuzzy on the boundaries between North and South.</p>
<p><strong>4) You don&#8217;t feel &#8221;cold&#8221;</strong></p>
<div id="attachment_1780" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://makinguseofmydegree.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/cali-surf-mens-cali-surf-hibiscus-vintage-boardshort.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1780" title="cali-surf-mens-cali-surf-hibiscus-vintage-boardshort" src="http://makinguseofmydegree.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/cali-surf-mens-cali-surf-hibiscus-vintage-boardshort.jpg?w=300&h=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">My winter wardrobe.</p></div>
<p>Being from the Yorkshire moors, I&#8217;m used to tempestuous weather so when I moved to Loughborough the only thing I noticed was that it rained less. Consequently, my winter wardrobe was my summer clothes with tights, knitwear and a coat, and believe me I heard a lot of &#8221;Aren&#8217;t you cold!?&#8221; The answer was no because I&#8217;m from Yorkshire so this is like the Bahamas for me, also the South particularly London is warmer than the North due to pollution so it&#8217;s no wonder the (midland) wilderness that is Leicestershire is a shock to some people.</p>
<p><strong>5) You begin to feel slightly ashamed of the North</strong></p>
<div id="attachment_1781" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://makinguseofmydegree.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/sheff5.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1781" title="sheff5" src="http://makinguseofmydegree.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/sheff5.jpg?w=300&h=232" alt="" width="300" height="232" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Sheffield, glorious Sheffield.</p></div>
<p>When you spend a lot of time with people from the south, you begin to forge this image of Northerners that&#8217;s similar to the people you see on Jeremy Kyle.  It&#8217;s like you&#8217;ve been brainwashed and it got to the point when I thought of Sheffield I conjured up images of someone in a Sheffield United top shouting &#8221;UP THE BLADES&#8221;, grim. Saying that, the North is a lovely place, but everything is so London orientated these days that you begin to resent living in the North because there aren&#8217;t as many opportunities here. Perhaps it&#8217;s more apt to say that rather than being ashamed of the North, I&#8217;m more indifferent because there&#8217;s a big wide world out there and if you want to see it you have to move out of the North.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1776/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1776/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1776&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://makinguseofmydegree.wordpress.com/2012/09/08/what-its-like-to-be-a-northerner-at-university/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>43</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://makinguseofmydegree.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/3001.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://makinguseofmydegree.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/3001.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">300</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/84d0bd0c976617b8199efe34e5f698dd?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">zoealice</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://makinguseofmydegree.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/ghetto.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ghetto</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://makinguseofmydegree.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/300.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">300</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://makinguseofmydegree.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/confused.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">confused</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://makinguseofmydegree.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/cali-surf-mens-cali-surf-hibiscus-vintage-boardshort.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cali-surf-mens-cali-surf-hibiscus-vintage-boardshort</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://makinguseofmydegree.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/sheff5.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sheff5</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lieutenant Commander Data Analysis</title>
		<link>http://geekyartistlibrarian.wordpress.com/2012/09/07/data/</link>
		<comments>http://geekyartistlibrarian.wordpress.com/2012/09/07/data/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2012 17:31:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Starr Hoffman</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[academia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[geekery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PhD-land]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[statistics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dissertation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[likert]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MATHS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nonparametric]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://geekyartistlibrarian.wordpress.com/?p=3348</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The word &#8220;data&#8221; is pretty meaningless to me right now. I&#8217;m in the data analysis phase of my dissertation, plus Alex and I are re-watching Star Trek: TNG Season 5 (Worf&#8217;s family name has honor again! Tasha Yar&#8217;s half-Romulan daughter is nefarious! Huzzah!), so I hear/say/breathe &#8220;data&#8221; a lot. Data-data-data. Was it ever a real [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3348&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://geekyartistlibrarian.wordpress.com/2012/09/07/data/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>28</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://geekyartistlibrarian.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/data_intoxicated.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://geekyartistlibrarian.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/data_intoxicated.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Data_intoxicated</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/74a34dfe8ab6ecf40d29d3d7be6c25fa?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">geekyartistlibrarian</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://geekyartistlibrarian.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/300px-data_and_lore_2364.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">300px-Data_and_Lore_(2364)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://geekyartistlibrarian.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/celebrity-pictures-burton-spiner-emotion-chip.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">celebrity-pictures-burton-spiner-emotion-chip</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://geekyartistlibrarian.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/data-computer.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Data-Computer</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://geekyartistlibrarian.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/funny-pictures-star-trek-cat-wants-burger12.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">funny-pictures-star-trek-cat-wants-burger12</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Handmaid&#8217;s Tale. A Feminine Dystopia.</title>
		<link>http://oldnewortrue.wordpress.com/2012/09/09/the-handmaids-tale-a-feminine-dystopia/</link>
		<comments>http://oldnewortrue.wordpress.com/2012/09/09/the-handmaids-tale-a-feminine-dystopia/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2012 15:10:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Kate</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Backlist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Book Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Allegory]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dystopia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Feminism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Literature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Margaret Atwood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Satire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Handmaid's Tale]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Utopia]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://oldnewortrue.wordpress.com/?p=500</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[dystopia: n. an imagined place or state in which everything is unpleasant or bad There are books that wrestle with your insides. They twist upon themselves, cramping, writhing, peristalsing until a  peculiar taste rises into your mouth. It surprises you with its bitter, jagged notes&#8230;this doesn&#8217;t do it justice.  The taste defies description. It is [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=500&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://oldnewortrue.wordpress.com/2012/09/09/the-handmaids-tale-a-feminine-dystopia/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>97</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://oldnewortrue.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/ht.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://oldnewortrue.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/ht.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">HT</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/ba376ce797fd6f89944d57f003bdf82d?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">oldnewortrue</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://oldnewortrue.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/ht.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">HT</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Who You Calling an Old Outsider?</title>
		<link>http://horsehorsetigertiger.net/2012/09/06/442/</link>
		<comments>http://horsehorsetigertiger.net/2012/09/06/442/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2012 06:05:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Saara</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Anshun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Language]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://horsehorsetigertiger.net/?p=442</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[老外/Laowai literally means “old outside” but actually just means “foreigner.” The “old” part connotes respect (see the words for teacher, wife, husband and elder: 老师， 老婆， 老公， 老人家, respectively). People usually call us laowai, and that’s fine. I can’t remember Chinese names for shit, so I make up my own names for everyone anyway [the [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=442&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>老外/Laowai literally means “old outside” but actually just means “foreigner.” The “old” part connotes respect (see the words for teacher, wife, husband and elder: 老师， 老婆， 老公， 老人家, respectively). People usually call us <em>laowai</em>, and that’s fine. I can’t remember Chinese names for shit, so I make up my own names for everyone anyway [the people in my neighborhood are Harriet Fruit-Lady, Stella Fruit-Lady, Cecelia NuoMiFan (best 糯米饭 in China, y’all!), Chinese Mr. Rogers (dude rocks a cardigan), and the Green Family (Their restaurant sign is green. Shut up! Clarity beats wit.)]. I hope that our neighbors have special names for us, like “American Fancystockings” and “Foreign Pretty-Glasses,” but I suspect that we’re just <em>The Laowai</em>.</p>
<div id="attachment_444" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 235px"><a href="http://horsehorsetigertigerdotnet.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4150.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-444 " title="She is anonymous. She is legion. " src="http://horsehorsetigertigerdotnet.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4150.jpg?w=225&h=300" alt="" width="225" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Can you spot the foreigner in this picture?</p></div>
<p>No bigs. We’re never going to blend. And it&#8217;s not like there are so many foreigners wandering Anshun&#8217;s streets that they need to differentiate us from each other. When we moved here, we were, as far as we know, the only two foreigners in town. One day at the visa office, we ran into one grumpy American (He was snappish with my waiban. Want to get on the shortlist of people I wouldn’t ask paramedics to pull from a burning cardboard box? Get snappish with the guy who went on a special trip to buy me a space heater because he read that it might get cold that weekend.), but when I asked him how long he’d be in Anshun, he said, “as little as possible,” so I&#8217;m sure he&#8217;s gone by now. Last Thanksgiving weekend, a 70-something Irish dude showed up at our house, and he’s cool. But we only saw him the once. We had Joanne for awhile, a hilarious, whip-smart Bruneian girl who springed (earlier than summering, later than wintering) on the beige shores of Anshun, but she’s abandoned us for stupid college (We miss you, Joanne!). Oh, and there’s a shady dude who wears shiny shirts and tells Eric to shave his beard so he can get with Chinese girls. He (Mr. Shady, not Eric) also pretends he’s British when he clearly isn’t (Has anyone heard of Oslo, England yet? Until then, he’s a creeper.). So I’m saying that, in this town, foreigners are rare. Even tourists don’t pop up much. Several months ago in our Byzantine open market, I walked past two stocking-capped, backpacked foreigners, but they, like many foreigners China, averted their eyes as soon as they saw me (Travelers, what’s up with that? I’ll talk to you in Mandarin if a total immersion experience is really that important to you.).</p>
<p>Anyway: Near campus, they’re used to us; we see the same people every day, get crazy with the small talk (us: Mandarin / them: Anshun’s dialect). Even the people we don’t often talk to see us enough to know we’re teachers at the college who like to snack on 小聚字 and wave at all the street dogs. No one calls us 老外, except 娜娜, who is 18 months old, and whenever she says it, her parents tell her instead to call us “Auntie” and “Uncle” (阿姨 and 叔叔). I’m sure they call us 老外 when we’re not around because what else would you call us? But they get that we&#8217;re not just 老外. Or at least we&#8217;re <em>their</em> 老外.</p>
<p>But whenever we leave our area, we attract stares. And giggles. And catcalls. We go to the train ticket office, and someone yells “haalllllooo” from across the street. When we look, they turn away and laugh.* We go shoe shopping, and mothers grab their toddlers and point and say “看到老外！” (Look at the foreigners!).</p>
<p>On the same day that I saw the two foreigners in the open market, a woman standing not two feet away pointed at me, laughed and yelled “老外！” over my head to her friend across the street. At the time, I hadn&#8217;t learned enough Chinese to deal gracefully, so I glared at her and harrumphed away, trying to cuss away the powerlessness.</p>
<p>I’ve since developed what I hope are friendlyish ways to deal with the attention—I ask people in Chinese how they knew we were foreigners (It’s a funny joke!) or ask them if they’re a foreigner too (Equally funny!). Sometimes, just starting a little conversation with whatever stranger is handy works—1) If the catcaller is still paying attention, they then figure out that I speak Chinese, but more importantly 2) Because the person I’m talking with usually responds graciously, with a combination of enthusiasm and, when I&#8217;m lucky, nonchalance (How I love not being a big deal!), I’m reminded that not every Chinese person is out to yell insensitive crap at me, that I can connect, in whatever momentary way, with the people in my community. Sadly, my Chinese isn’t good enough to have an in-depth conversation about the objectification of the other and the wacky cultural differences in expressions of respect and rudeness, but I take what I can get.</p>
<p>[Also, some people that I try to talk to just stare at me in shock and stammer that they don’t speak English (I don’t think my Chinese is <em>that</em> bad, so I’m not sure what that’s about). But usually, people are nice. I should more often give people the opportunity to remind me that they want to be nice to me.]</p>
<p>[Also also, sometimes, I do not respond gracefully. Sometimes, people catch me when I’m tired—a wise friend pointed out that sleep is the most important resource a PCV has—or hungry or stressed out, and I don’t react well. I stop; I glare; I tell them, in Chinese, to stop being rude (or, once, I mixed up two similar-sounding words and told some poor guy to stop being boring; he looked so sad. I feel really guilty about that one). Sometimes I talk to myself loudly in Chinese about rude people and how they’re annoying me to DEATH! which is so very passive aggressive of me, and I’m not proud, and I’m sorry that I’m not always the best foreigner I can be.]</p>
<p>My Chinese friends say that the catcallers and gawkers don’t mean it badly, that they’re just curious, that they’re trying to be friendly. I don’t exactly buy it. 1) Some of them do mean it badly, which is to say that they mean to make their friends laugh or to make themselves look good and aren’t thinking about us as people, which is understandable and human, but one of the lamer elements of being human. It’s lame when Americans do it—in our own, sneaky American way—to foreigners or homeless people or whomever we think is freaky. It’s lame when Chinese people do it to me. Plus, 2) even if they don’t mean it badly, I don’t know how much that matters. But maybe that’s because I’m American? It seems like my Chinese friends care more about what people <em>mean</em>; I care more about what people <em>do</em>. Neither is a better or worse way to look at things (Really; both have benefits and drawbacks, and of course, it’s so much more complex than I’ll make it sound in a blog post, and really, does it matter, ideas like better and worse?); it’s just difficult sometimes to reconcile two apparently opposing philosophies. And maybe one is a better outlook when you’re living in China, and the other is better when you’re in America.</p>
<p>It’s easy to rethink something or see it from someone else’s perspective, but it’s so difficult to unlearn an emotional reaction. So when strangers yell at me and laugh, I react the way I would in America—I get hurt. I feel angry. No matter how well they mean it. The best I can do most days is keep my auto-pilot reaction on the inside and react like a sane person on the outside. When I don’t have the energy for it, I try not to leave the area of our campus. All that is a lot of emotional work to go through. We have a few friends in town, but the language and culture barriers are such that hanging out with them isn’t exactly a comfort yet; it’s more like an investment in the possibility of future comfort.</p>
<p>I’m glad we moved to China. I love learning new things about Chinese—and, by extension, American—culture. I love learning to speak, read, and write Mandarin. I love that the high school girl that works in Green Family’s restaurant rubs my shoulder to say hello. I love that 娜娜 unwraps gum and gives it to me when I’m done eating at her parents’ restaurant. I love visiting schools in the countryside with our tutor and watching her start gleeful, liquor-fueled crap with people at banquets (even when I don’t understand the dialect she’s using). I love having the same conversation with the Harriet Fruit-Lady every day (You going home? / Yes. How’s business? / Good. / See you tomorrow!). I love working with my students. But living in China as a foreigner can feel isolated sometimes. Isolation, like a dearth of central heat or hot water in the kitchen, is one of the hardships I signed up for, but it still feels pretty whack. In philosophical moments, I get that this is a valuable experience for me to have. I grew up blond on a peninsula of blondness, and as I’ve moved from state to state, I’ve continued fit in, more or less. But in China, I’m irrevocably marked by my skin and my hair and my speech as an other. Of course, I still carry the privilege of being white and American and educated and temporarily-but-not-really-poor (fingers crossed!); I’m not going to pretend. But sometimes it does suck, and suck is suck is suck, no matter how much un-suck I&#8217;m otherwise granted, and no matter how much worse other people have it. Their good isn’t less good because mine is better, right? So the opposite is true too, I think. That’s probably several kinds of logical fallacy, but I’m sticking to it for now.</p>
<p>You are tempted to comment with something inspirational. You want to give me a practical solution. You want to line smog with silver. Please, gentle reader, resist. Sometimes things should be complicated and difficult. Let’s just let me struggle.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>*I should note here that laughter can mean very different things for Chinese people than it does for Americans. Laughter in both places communicates complex, amorphous emotions; but in each country, they&#8217;re slightly different complex, amorphous emotions; plus, where and when it&#8217;s appropriate to laugh is different. So, you know. You know?</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/442/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/442/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=442&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://horsehorsetigertiger.net/2012/09/06/442/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>34</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/275e48b764f712a897c019036423708e?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">saaramyrene</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://horsehorsetigertigerdotnet.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4150.jpg?w=225" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">She is anonymous. She is legion. </media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Next Wave of Computing</title>
		<link>http://twothirdsdone.com/2012/09/08/whentechnologies-collide-the-next-wave-of-computing-2/</link>
		<comments>http://twothirdsdone.com/2012/09/08/whentechnologies-collide-the-next-wave-of-computing-2/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2012 21:07:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>avram miller</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[about business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Post PC Period]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://twothirdsdone.com/?p=931</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This is an amazing graph from GigaOm (see story here).  As readers of my blog  know, I played a very significant role in creating residential broadband starting in 1992 and continuing until 1999, when I resigned my position at Intel as Corp. Vice President of Business Development. While I was sure then that the Internet [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=931&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://twothirdsdone.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/post-pc-slays-pc-11.png"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-932" title="post-pc-slays-pc (1)" src="http://twothirdsdone.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/post-pc-slays-pc-11.png" alt="" width="450" height="390" /></a><br />
This is an amazing graph from GigaOm (see story<a href="http://gigaom.com/2012/09/01/hp-dell-and-the-paradox-of-the-disrupted/"> here</a>).  As readers of my blog  know, I played a very significant role in creating residential broadband starting in 1992 and continuing until 1999, when I resigned my position at Intel as Corp. Vice President of Business Development. While I was sure then that the Internet would change everything, I could not have predicted these results.  Apple was still struggling after Steve Jobs’ return and had a market capitalization of just eight billion dollars.  Amazon had a market cap that was more than twice as high but was basically a book seller.  Google had just eight employees and was based in a garage. Microsoft’s market capitalization was about 270 billion. It had the highest market capitalization in the world, a position now occupied by Apple.  By the way, Intel’s was about 150 billion.  Both of these companies have about the same value now as they had 13 years ago.</p>
<p><strong>The PC Revolution Turns the Computer Industry on its Side</strong><br />
Microsoft, Intel, Dell, Compaq (which became part of HP after first acquiring Digital Equipment Corp a leader of the previous generation of computer companies) were all products of the PC revolution. Apple was not (more on this later).    The PC revolution is an example of what happens when two major and to some extent un-correlated technology discontinuities collide.   The PC industry happened because an independent semi conductor industry lead by Intel met up with an independent software industry lead by Microsoft, and unleashed by accident by IBM.  That flipped the computer industry. Until that time it was  pretty much a vertical where the major computer companies developed all their own technology from disks to operating systems. It was a world of proprietary architecture. The leading companies where IBM, Digital Equipment Company and HP.   Because both Microsoft and Intel were willing and eager to sell to anyone, many companies were formed such as Compaq and Dell to offer PC products. These companies developed little in the way of unique technology.  In fact, to some extent, their innovations were in sales and marketing strategies. I should also give credit to the disk industry which was lead by Seagate in the early days, but this industry did not play a leading role in creating the market.  The difference was that both Microsoft and Intel had near monopolies (we were taught not to say that word at Intel) on their segments ,while the disk  and memory industry had many players and never generated enough profit to be market leaders.  At one time it was thought that Microsoft and Intel had 120% of the profit of the PC industry (meaning many companies participating in the industry actually lost money).</p>
<p><strong>The House of Wintel</strong><br />
While Intel and Microsoft can both take credit for exploiting the opportunity that was created by the collision, neither company had that much to do with the other in the early days of the PC revolution.  In fact, each company would have preferred to see the other weakened and would actually take action from time to time to try to accomplish this. I remember that twice Intel had worked with Apple using Intel programers to convert the Mac OS to run on Intel Architecture (x86) during the 90s when the Mac ran on PowerPC chips only to have Steve Jobs decide not move to Intel. Steve probably was just leveraging Intel to put pricing pressure on Motorola who was the main supplier of the Power PC chips.  Intel also had an active Unix effort which drove Microsoft nuts.  Microsoft would refuse to take advantage of advanced features of Intels’ new microprocessors.  Microsoft even invested in a company called MicroUnity whose mission was to create a new microprocessor architecture that could leap over anything Intel was doing.  The company made amazing claims but failed to live up to them.  Anyway, not all was cozy in the “House of Wintel” as attested to by my friend, Steve McGeady, a former Intel Executive when he testified at the Microsoft Anti-Trust trial in 1998.</p>
<p><strong>The Internet Meets Broadband</strong><br />
Around the middle of 1995 two other technology trends were slated to collide.  They were residential broadband and the Internet.  The early stage of residential broadband (Cable modems and then DSL) was driven primarily by Intel under my direction.  At the time we started the development of cable modem technology in 1992, I was aware of the Internet.  Mosaic, the first browser developed at the University of Illinois by a team directed by Marc Andreessen, was released in 1993.  Netscape Navigator,  the first commercial browser was released towards the end of 1994.  I had a chance to invest in Netscape at a pre-money valuation of eighteen million dollars, which I passed on, thinking it was too expensive -one of the greatest mistakes I made as a venture investor.  At that time,  the internet was mostly used by engineers and academics in universities, businesses and government.  Corporations used things like cc:Mail and Lotus Notes.  Consumers were just beginning to use email within online services like AOL, Prodigy and CompuServe.  But both the business and consumer services were proprietary and it was not possible to communicate between them.  However, for a number of reasons, gateways were created to allow email to be sent out of these “email islands” to the internet and from there it was possible to connect to other islands.</p>
<p><strong>Residential Broadband the Child of TV</strong><br />
Residential broadband was build on a platform that was created for Television Transmission.   The key ingredient that made broadband possible was the development of Digital Cable Transmission of video.  General Instruments, who became Intel’s partners in creating residential broadband for the cable industry, demonstrated the capability to convert analog video to digital in 1989. The cable industry was excited about the potential of this capability and in 1992, John Malone, the CEO of TCI and, at the time, the de facto leader of the Cable Industry, coined the phrase, “the 500 Channel Universe”. I am sure that he never realized at that time he was laying the foundation for the multi million channel universe that is today&#8217;s internet.<br />
Coupled with this was the development of High Definition Television which was to use the same underlying technology.  I have repeated this story on my blog many times so I will not go into a lot of detail here.  Matt Miller, the CTO of General Instruments and I, came to the realization that interactivity would take place in the home via personal computers and not interactive TV&#8217;s and very importantly, that we could use the very same infrastructure developed for digital television to create a broadband network for PCs.  Our respective technical teams worked together to develop early cable modems and head-end equipment (the equipment that was located at the cable operators site). Intel developed the cable modem communications protocols  which we provided to the Cable Labs (the R&amp;D arm of the cable industry).  I evangelized the concept of residential broadband, meeting with the CEOs’ of all the major cable companies, and introduced the concept throughout the world.  Intel licensed manufacturers of cable modems such as Cisco and HP. The rest is as they say, is “history”.</p>
<p><strong>The Web Evolves as the New Platform for Computing and Business Models Change</strong><br />
After a few years, it was clear that the internet would become the online platform of choice for consumers and that applications would be based in the world wide web (www). From the perspective of Intel and Microsoft, the growth  in home computer sales driven in large extent by the availability and acceptance of broadband internet  was a good thing.  But contained in this good thing was something else. More and more of the value derived from using computers in the home was being transferred to the products and services running on the Internet or as we now say, the cloud.  Having a high speed network, wireless access in the home, and a great monitor was more important then having a fast CPU.<br />
Business models were changing.  Previously, consumers bought hardware and software.  Now, new elements were being introduced into the mix.  Consumers were paying monthly subscriptions for access to services like broadband or even music sites.  Importantly, advertising started to appear on the internet. At the time, 1994, I said “advertising will be the killer app of the internet”.    Companies like Intel, Microsoft and Dell were being left out of these growing segments of revenue.   I remember in the mid 90s, speaking to Paul Otellini’s staff at one of their strategy sessions.  Paul who is now the CEO of Intel was running the Microprocessor business at Intel then.  I shared with Paul and his senior managers, some of my thinking about the future of the computer industry and introduced the concept that companies could subsidize the purchase of consumer products if they could couple them with re-occurring service charges.  I said this kind of connection between hardware, software and services could change the business model of the computer industry. It took the iPhone to make this concept happen.   Intel was not in a good position to take advantage of the changes that would follow.  While the company had a very important position with respect to consumer awareness resulting from the very effective “Intel inside” campaign, it had no direct relationship with consumers.  I wanted Intel to start selling peripherals (something that Microsoft did) but frankly that would not have helped much.</p>
<p><strong>The Writing on the Wall for Intel</strong><br />
By the time I left Intel in 1999, the writing was pretty much on the wall.  I left partly in frustration that I was not able to get Intel  to understand that we were entering a new phase of the computer industry.  But frankly, I am not sure I could have made suggestions that would have changed the outcome. I would like to think that had I stayed at Intel, I would have convinced the company to acquire Qualcomm which today has a market cap close to that of Intel, but I am not sure.  I think Microsoft was in a better position to bridge the transition but because so much of the value became software based,  it would have taken very different leadership than that provided by Bill Gates and Steve Balmer.  Even companies like Cisco whose income was primarily derived from selling products to companies that provided internet infrastructure did not take advantage of the transition. Intel needs to find away to couple its primary product, the microprocessor, to the services consumers would be enjoying.  About five years, ago, I figured out how to do that and offered my ideas to Intel (without charge).  They were not appreciative and never took my suggestions seriously.  Probably worked out well for me because I could have gotten sucked back into Intel.</p>
<p><strong>Amazon the Emerges as a Leading Competitor to Apple</strong><br />
Amazon is also on the chart.  Amazon is not really a computer company although it is moving quickly in that direction.  It is an online retailer. Its’ competition is other retailers including Target and Walmart.  It started in the book business and has pretty much succeeded in wiping out traditional brick and mortar book sellers (sadly in some opinions).  It is having a major effect on the way all media is distributed.  But in my opinion the best is yet to come for Amazon (by the way, I own the stock). Amazon is trading at an all time high as I write this post.</p>
<p><strong>Google from Brilliance to Mediocrity</strong><br />
Google has done an amazing job monitoring the internet via advertising.  They are, of course, the leader in internet search.  But Google reminds me of of Microsoft.  They have a dominate  market share and a fantastic financial engine.  But their products are mediocre.  Their offerings in every segment other than search is not very inspiring.  Even hotmail and yahoo have more email users than gmail on the web.  Apple has the most email clients on mobile devices.  I recently said in a talk that I gave that “Google has the mediocrity of Microsoft without the greed of Bill Gates”.  They may be in a good position to take advantage of the next wave of computing which will be described later, but I personally doubt that they will.</p>
<p><strong>Apple the Company I Hate to Love</strong><br />
Finally, I have to talk about Apple the company I loved to hate and now hate to love.  As readers of this blog will know, I have a twisted history with Apple.  It started with meeting Steve Jobs in 1982 when he was just 25 years old, continued through the lawsuit between Franklin Computer where I was president. Apple pretty much killed the company via litigation. I have written much about Steve Jobs and Apple on this blog (do a search if you want to see those posts).  Apple, until recently, belonged to the pre-pc era of computing. While not a totally vertical company, Apple controlled most of the technology in their product.  In many ways, Apple reminded me of Digital Equipment Corp., they were the leader in mini computers.  Obviously, there are key differences.  Apple focused on creative professionals and consumers while Digital focused on Engineers and Scientists. Driven by their respective CEOs Ken Olsen and Steve Jobs, I believe they were building computers that they would want to use themselves.<br />
What has fueled the astounding growth of Apple is that they are riding the next wave of computing.  A phrase coined by John Gage, formally of Sun Microcomputer, sums it up:  The Network is the Computer.  But I want to add another concept: Ubiquitous Computing.  This means that everyone and to a lesser degree everything is connected and intelligent.  I believe this is actually gives rise to the driving factor of what we now call Cloud Computing.  The driver of Cloud Computing is reduction in complexity.  There are other benefits I am sure, like reduced cost, but reduction in complexity is the driver in my opinion.</p>
<p>Just take the issue of accessing  content.  Consumers started ripping music CDs to their computers in 1992.  Digital Compression made it possible for us to store a lot of music on our computers. Then small portable music players came our way that allowed us to take this music with us.  Most of these devices were pretty poor until Apple applied its amazing design capabilities and created the iPod in 2001.  Keeping music synced between a computer and an iPod was not to difficult or complicated.  iTunes was developed with this purpose in mind.  But as I am sure you have experienced, as you try to involve more and more devices (multiple computers, portable players,  and devices to drive home Audio/Visual systems) things get rapidly more complicated.</p>
<p>Eventually, Apple figured out that it is less complicated to store everything in one place “in the cloud” and have every device communicate with the cloud and not directly with each other.  But in doing this they are not really utilizing the open platform that is the internet.  They are just using the Internet infrastructure much in the way that the cable modem used the Cable TV infrastructure.</p>
<p><strong>Computers and Computing Everywhere</strong><br />
Ubiquitous Computing is driving other key technologies. Most prominent in this is mobile communications and form factors.  There is another force that will shape the future of computing and that is security for want of a better word.  As we put more and more of our information in the cloud we become more and more concerned about the security of that information.  I don&#8217;t just mean information theft.  I also mean our ability to access information now and in the future.</p>
<p><strong>When Technologies Collide Money is Made</strong><br />
I started this post talking about what happens when technology discontinuities collide.  I would like to give my views on the next wave of computing.  You can guess that Ubiquitous Computing which will be the driver of Cloud Computing is one of these discontinuities.  But what are the others? I think Network Intelligence will be one.  What I mean here is the application of data mining to personal interactions.  There is evidence of this already with data mining and crowd sourcing.  Amazon suggests  things that I might be interested in buying from looking at my buying patterns and those of others like me.  The same is true for Netflix.  Pandora uses Network Intelligent to suggest music I might like.  Much of these capabilities are being used to market to us.  But this is just a start.</p>
<p>Just think of all the information that a company like Apple will have about us.  It will be interesting to see if the regulatory structure can deal with the access such a company will have to our information.  I for one am not overly concerned, but maybe I should be.  The company that has the most information at the moment is undoubtably Google.  But they will have to recast themselves as a Network Intelligence Company.</p>
<p>I have a lot more to say on this topic but that will have to wait for future posts.</p>
<p><strong>Facebook does not Make the Cut&#8230;</strong><br />
Finally, you may have noticed that I said nothing about Facebook.  This is partly because Facebook was not on the graph but also because I think Facebook is the Yahoo of the next wave.  This statement my surprise some of you because of Facebook&#8217;s strong position in Social Media.  I personally spend a lot of time on Facebook and do believe in the future of Social Media but in the mid 90s I spent a lot of time doing email on AOL.  I still spend a lot of time doing email but have not been on AOL in ten years.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/931/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/931/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=931&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://twothirdsdone.com/2012/09/08/whentechnologies-collide-the-next-wave-of-computing-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>20</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/8e18dcc1c8efb92955656187dd932bdc?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">TwoThirdsDone</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://twothirdsdone.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/post-pc-slays-pc-11.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">post-pc-slays-pc (1)</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Decorating the Spaces Between Bricks</title>
		<link>http://katfriedrich.wordpress.com/2012/09/04/decorating-the-spaces-between-bricks/</link>
		<comments>http://katfriedrich.wordpress.com/2012/09/04/decorating-the-spaces-between-bricks/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2012 16:48:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>K.</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cities]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creativity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bricks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[city art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dispatchers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[legos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[monuments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[street art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[temporary art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[urban art]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://katfriedrich.wordpress.com/?p=1540</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It takes an artistic eye to look at an ordinary wall and see potential spaces for art in the fissures between the bricks. Some artists see the blank spaces between objects as zones where new ideas can emerge. M.C. Escher used white space as a central part of his artwork. Now, in cities around the world, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1540&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It takes an artistic eye to look at an ordinary wall and see potential spaces for art in the fissures between the bricks. Some artists see the blank spaces between objects as zones where new ideas can emerge. <a href="http://www.mcescher.com/">M.C. Escher</a> used white space as a central part of his artwork.</p>
<p>Now, in cities around the world, artists are using plastic bricks to fill in empty spaces and &#8220;patch&#8221; broken walls and monuments. These &#8220;dispatchers&#8221; have collected their handiwork on <a href="http://www.dispatchwork.info/">a website</a> which includes <a href="http://www.dispatchwork.info/manifesto/">their manifesto</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p><em>I don&#8217;t enjoy living in dull and grey cities. Do you? Have you noticed that toys for kids are generally very shiny and colorful? I wonder why that is, given that they are to be brought up to live in mostly dull and gray cities as adults. Since I lived in many of such cities, I am seeking to improve the appearance of public spaces in different ways, in terms of what I consider improvement. Dispatchwork aims to seal fissures in broken walls worldwide, completing the material compilation in urban constructing and adding color to the urban greyscales.</em></p></blockquote>
<p>Like <a href="http://www.graphics.cornell.edu/online/mandala/disk.gif">Buddhist sand mandalas</a>, the repairs are intended to be temporary. Because the plastic will end up in our water systems eventually, I&#8217;d like to see this group experiment with biodegradable LEGOs. Unfortunately, <a href="http://www.architizer.com/en_us/blog/dyn/38781/earth-blocks-the-eco-friendly-lego/">the only biodegradable LEGO-style bricks that exist are a dull shade of brown</a>. Only their scent is attractive; apparently, they smell like green tea.</p>
<p>Since living in Chicago, I have been interested in art projects that reclaim damaged parts of city landscapes. There are many ways to introduce art into cities, including <a href="http://katfriedrich.wordpress.com/2011/12/06/how-majora-carter-changes-the-image-of-cities/">turning vacant lots into parks</a> and <a href="https://www.facebook.com/yarnbombing">yarn bombing</a>.</p>
<p>I participated in a Dispatchers project in Beverly, Massachusetts this weekend. We decorated the entrance of a graffiti-covered building with LEGO-shaped stickers.</p>
<div id="attachment_1541" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://katfriedrich.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dispatchers_2.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1541" title="dispatchers_2" src="http://katfriedrich.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dispatchers_2.jpg?w=300&h=225" alt="A Dispatchers event in Beverly, MA." width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Dispatchers standing next to an entrance covered with LEGO-style stickers.</p></div>
<p>We also inserted LEGOs into the foundation of a building at the Montserrat College of Art, as well as some other buildings including the Unitarian church on Cabot Street. We used friction and a small amount of silicone caulk to hold the LEGOs in place.</p>
<div id="attachment_1542" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://katfriedrich.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/558597_382504805154710_468013060_n.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1542" title="Inserting Lego bricks into the foundation of the Montserrat art school's Hardie Building" src="http://katfriedrich.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/558597_382504805154710_468013060_n.jpg?w=300&h=225" alt="Inserting Lego bricks into the foundation of the Montserrat art school's Hardie Building" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Inserting LEGO bricks into the foundation of the Montserrat College of Art&#8217;s Hardie Building.</p></div>
<p>Curious about whether Dispatchers have been at work in your city? Explore <a href="http://www.dispatchwork.info/">the Dispatchwork website</a> for more details and photos of the installations. Many of the installations are in Europe, but some are in Asia, the Middle East, and North America.</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://katfriedrich.wordpress.com/category/art/'>art</a>, <a href='http://katfriedrich.wordpress.com/category/cities/'>cities</a>, <a href='http://katfriedrich.wordpress.com/category/creativity/'>creativity</a> Tagged: <a href='http://katfriedrich.wordpress.com/tag/art/'>art</a>, <a href='http://katfriedrich.wordpress.com/tag/bricks/'>bricks</a>, <a href='http://katfriedrich.wordpress.com/tag/city-art/'>city art</a>, <a href='http://katfriedrich.wordpress.com/tag/dispatchers/'>dispatchers</a>, <a href='http://katfriedrich.wordpress.com/tag/legos/'>legos</a>, <a href='http://katfriedrich.wordpress.com/tag/monuments/'>monuments</a>, <a href='http://katfriedrich.wordpress.com/tag/street-art/'>street art</a>, <a href='http://katfriedrich.wordpress.com/tag/temporary-art/'>temporary art</a>, <a href='http://katfriedrich.wordpress.com/tag/urban-art/'>urban art</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1540/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1540/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1540&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://katfriedrich.wordpress.com/2012/09/04/decorating-the-spaces-between-bricks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>27</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/2f84af4a45e9c0b1219c0eb4bee99042?s=96&#38;d=&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">katanalyze</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://katfriedrich.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dispatchers_2.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">dispatchers_2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://katfriedrich.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/558597_382504805154710_468013060_n.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Inserting Lego bricks into the foundation of the Montserrat art school&#039;s Hardie Building</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gina Rinehart &#8211; Meme Mining</title>
		<link>http://wemattermedia.com/2012/09/09/gina-rinehart-meme-mining/</link>
		<comments>http://wemattermedia.com/2012/09/09/gina-rinehart-meme-mining/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2012 15:13:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>jonathanandrewbrown</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gender]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[class]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gina rinehart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[memes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mining]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[misogyny]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sexism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://wemattermedia.com/?p=203</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There is a big difference between criticising someone for their actions, their words or their values and criticising someone for their gender or appearance.<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=203&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://wemattermedia.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/screen-shot-2012-09-08-at-11-49-18-pm.png"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-204" title="Gina Rinehart" src="http://wemattermedia.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/screen-shot-2012-09-08-at-11-49-18-pm.png?w=300&h=160" alt="" width="300" height="160" /></a></p>
<p>One of my favourite parts of online culture is the spread of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_meme" target="_blank">memes.</a></p>
<p>Memes are a simple, creative and often hilarious way of making a point, subverting a culture, challenging hypocrisy or to simply have a good laugh.</p>
<p>Memes have also become a surprise source of political commentary and social change. Whenever a public figure makes a big statement you can almost instantly go online and find a series of memes co-opted from their words.</p>
<p>When it was reported that Australian mining magnate Gina Rinehart <a href="http://www.couriermail.com.au/business/gina-rinehart-tells-whingers-get-out-of-the-pub/story-fn7kjcme-1226461328341" target="_blank">made calls for the minimum wage in Australia to be lowered and criticised the country&#8217;s poor</a>, Australians leapt at the opportunity to respond. A variety of memes emerged responding to Rinehart&#8217;s comments:</p>
<p><a href="http://wemattermedia.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/rinehart.jpeg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-205" title="Rinehart" src="http://wemattermedia.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/rinehart.jpeg?w=300&h=200" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://wemattermedia.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/rinehart2.jpeg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-206" title="Rinehart2" src="http://wemattermedia.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/rinehart2.jpeg?w=300&h=212" alt="" width="300" height="212" /></a></p>
<p>Many of the memes provided an important outlet for Australians to respond to Rinehart&#8217;s statements. The role of humour and satire cannot be underestimated in terms of social impact. The memes have contributed to some important social, cultural and political discussions.</p>
<p>However, the spread of the meme has also raised some serious issues about how these online cultures can provide a platform for attacks of another kind:</p>
<p><a href="http://wemattermedia.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/kfc.jpeg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-207" title="KFC" src="http://wemattermedia.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/kfc.jpeg" alt="" width="194" height="259" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://wemattermedia.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/trainer.jpeg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-208" title="trainer" src="http://wemattermedia.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/trainer.jpeg" alt="" width="194" height="259" /></a></p>
<p>After seeing a string of images posted online criticising Rinehart on the basis of her appearance or gender <a href="https://twitter.com/JB_AU/status/244322121608753152" target="_blank">I tweeted the following:</a></p>
<blockquote><p>I love the Gina Rinehart memes calling her out on her bullshit, I do not however like the ones focusing purely on her gender or weight.</p></blockquote>
<p>There is a big difference between criticising someone for <em>their actions, their words or their values</em> and criticising someone for <em>their gender or appearance</em>. There is an inherent viciousness and hypocrisy in Rinehart&#8217;s recent statements towards the less fortunate in our community that is worthy of ridicule. Many of the memes that have spread relating to Rinehart  have been a vital way of helping the community process and respond to her statements. The community rejection of her values has been important, but the community is also served a great disservice by those who criticise Rinehart purely because of her weight or gender.</p>
<p>Just because Gina Rinehart is unpopular in the public eye, does not make it okay to stoop to this level. It&#8217;s cheap, it&#8217;s nasty and it lessens the impact of those making valid statements against her values. It helps to perpetuate the kind of stereotypes and misogyny we wouldn&#8217;t take being targeted at our loved ones so we shouldn&#8217;t accept this behaviour being targeted at our public figures, regardless of how unpopular they might be at the time.</p>
<p>We can do better as a community.</p>
<p>Satirise, argue and joke with Gina Rinehart all you like for her ridiculous views, values and words. <em>It&#8217;s actually really important that you do</em>, but before you make a cheap fat joke or a gendered attack on Rinehart think about the negative culture you&#8217;re contributing to.</p>
<p><strong>- Jonathan Brown</strong></p>
<p><strong>Jonathan is the Creative Director of We Matter Media. You can follow him <a title="JB_AU" href="http://www.twitter.com/jb_au" target="_blank">@JB_AU</a></strong></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/203/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/203/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=203&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://wemattermedia.com/2012/09/09/gina-rinehart-meme-mining/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>47</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://wemattermedia.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/screen-shot-2012-09-09-at-1-18-42-am.png?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://wemattermedia.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/screen-shot-2012-09-09-at-1-18-42-am.png?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen Shot 2012-09-09 at 1.18.42 AM</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">JB</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://wemattermedia.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/screen-shot-2012-09-08-at-11-49-18-pm.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Gina Rinehart</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://wemattermedia.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/rinehart.jpeg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Rinehart</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://wemattermedia.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/rinehart2.jpeg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Rinehart2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://wemattermedia.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/kfc.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">KFC</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://wemattermedia.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/trainer.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">trainer</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>