<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2011 17:16:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>On the Rise: A Conversation With Kris Bowers</title>
		<link>http://alternate-takes.com/2011/12/06/on-the-rise-a-conversation-with-kris-bowers/</link>
		<comments>http://alternate-takes.com/2011/12/06/on-the-rise-a-conversation-with-kris-bowers/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2011 16:34:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Angelika Beener</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Arts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jazz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Earl Travis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Godwin Louis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jehbreal Muhammad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joe Saylor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kenneth Whalum III]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kris Bower]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mike Cottone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thelonious Monk Institute of Jazz]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://alternate-takes.com/?p=1904</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[At the start of the second set at Greenwich Village’s Jazz Gallery last week, pianist Kris Bowers was playing for a packed and eager house.  A packed, eager, young, and particularly diverse house, to be more exact, with a look, vibe and mood much closer to a college music festival versus what the typical jazz [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=1904&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>
<div>
<div>
<div id="attachment_1906" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 248px"><a href="http://alternate-takes.com/2011/12/06/on-the-rise-a-conversation-with-kris-bowers/kris01/" rel="attachment wp-att-1906"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1906" title="kris01" src="http://alternatetakesblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/kris01.jpg?w=238&#038;h=300" alt="" width="238" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Photo by Gianina Ferreyra</p></div>
<p>At the start of the second set at Greenwich Village’s <a href="http://jazzgallery.org/">Jazz Gallery</a> last week, pianist <a href="http://www.krisbowersmusic.com/">Kris Bowers</a> was playing for a packed and eager house.  A packed, eager, young, and particularly diverse house, to be more exact, with a look, vibe and mood much closer to a college music festival versus what the typical jazz audience tends to resemble.  For a brief moment, I thought I was having auditory hallucinations with the amount of hoots and hollers being emitted from young, female voices.  It is a rare occurrence within the jazz club setting.  In Bowers’ performance debut as a leader, that would not be the last series of eyebrow-raising observations for the evening.</p>
<p>Bowers’ band for the evening was an assemblage of up-and-coming fresh faces in jazz with saxophonists Kenneth Whalum III and Godwin Louis, trumpeter Mike Cottone, bassist Earl Travis, and drummer Joe Saylor, with special guest vocalist Jehbreal Muhammad. The band of twenty-somethings played with a fire and focus beyond their years, performing an impressive amount of original material.  Bowers, who is an orchestrator, founder of an <a href="http://campusounds.com/">online music company</a>, and appears on the most significant hip hop album of the 2011, closed the moving set with a song from Bon Iver, the cutting edge indie-folk band, which was been recently riddled with Grammy nominations.  At twenty-two years old, it would be impossible to prognosticate a journey that is just beginning, but it is clear that Kris Bowers is setting a precedent of individuality, pushing the jazz envelope with a fierce, yet understated momentum.</p>
<p>If I’ve misled you to believe that his musical boundlessness and vast experience compromise his significance as a bonafide jazz musician, let me set that record straight nice and early.  He is a tremendous pianist, with a world of history under his fingers, and a conspicuously original sound, balanced by mature restraint.  He’s a bad cat.  He convinced a panel of pianistic paramountcy (which included Herbie Hancock, Ellis Marsalis, Danilo Pérez, Jason Moran and Renee Rosnes) of just that, taking first place at the Thelonious Monk International Jazz Competition earlier this year, beating out some of the best undiscovered pianists in the world.  An experience Bowers described as nothing short of nerve-racking, “I was nervous, definitely.  Because you know, those were like all of my favorites [on the judging panel].  I hadn’t really met any of them&#8230;I knew Jason but other than that I hadn’t met any of them, so to be playing all this stuff that I pretty much got from most of them [laughs] I was trying to&#8230;play the best that I could.”</p>
<p><a href="http://alternate-takes.com/2011/12/06/on-the-rise-a-conversation-with-kris-bowers/krisbowersrockrollhallfamehonorsarethazihcseggwpyl/" rel="attachment wp-att-1907"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-1907" title="Kris+Bowers+Rock+Roll+Hall+Fame+Honors+Aretha+ZIhcsEGgwpYl" src="http://alternatetakesblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/krisbowersrockrollhallfamehonorsarethazihcseggwpyl.jpg?w=300&#038;h=200" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>Like most musicians on the New York City jazz scene, Bowers hails from outside of the five boroughs.  Los Angeles, specifically.  Initially studying classical music, Bowers made an organic transition to jazz, which he studied at both Colburn School for Performing Arts and Los Angeles County High School for the Arts (LACHSA).  After graduating in 2006, Bowers moved to New York, continuing his studies at the Juilliard School.  “The jazz scene in LA&#8230;I mean it’s kind of sad.  It’s pretty bleak,” says Bowers who is now a second-year master of music degree student in the Juilliard Jazz program.  “Mostly because of the geography of the city.  It’s so spread out, it’s kind of hard. Like, we don’t have an area like the Village where there’s a bunch of clubs you can go around to, and to get together to play&#8230;it can take an hour to drive to somebody’s house, [for example].  And then unfortunately, a lot of the clubs are closing down, like The Jazz Bakery.  There’s just not many places to play out there.  I think most of the people want to come to New York once they feel like they’ve gotten to a certain level, or feel like they’re ready.”</p>
<p>Bowers’ New York state of mind has proved a to be a wise one many times over.  If you’re going to be in the right place at the right time, New York is always a good place to start.  Twists of fate work their magic best in The Big Apple, as Bowers explains how a chance subbing gig landed him on the Kanye/Jay-Z <em>magnum opus, Watch the Throne.</em>  “Casey [Benjamin]  plays with Q-Tip and he was on tour with [Robert] Glasper, and he recommended me to do this gig at the Brooklyn Hip Hop Festival, and it just so happened that at that gig, there were special guests like Busta Rhymes, Black Thought, Monie Love, and Kanye, and at the time they were finishing up a couple tracks from <em>Watch The Throne</em> that Tip was working on, and they wanted me to play some string parts on one song, and to write some piano parts on this other song, so it kind of all happened in a matter of days.”</p>
<p>The idea of writing string parts on a hip-hop album was likely intriguing, as you can add budding film scorer to Bowers’ resume.  “That’s something I definitely want to get into, honestly more than playing&#8230;especially eventually,” admits Bowers.  “I’d love to be able to dig into that.  I’ve always admired the role that music plays in a film and how it helps tell the story and how great music can enhance a film and bad music can ruin a film&#8230;just how much power the music has.  And also that it’s a literal translation of emotion; trying to compose and trying to write music that sounds scary, or sounds like this person is falling in love, or this person is angry&#8230;”</p>
<div id="attachment_1918" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 248px"><a href="http://alternate-takes.com/2011/12/06/on-the-rise-a-conversation-with-kris-bowers/krisb_at/" rel="attachment wp-att-1918"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1918" title="KrisB_AT" src="http://alternatetakesblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/krisb_at.jpg?w=238&#038;h=300" alt="" width="238" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Photo by Gianina Ferreyra</p></div>
<p>With so many facets to Bowers’ career, and his expansive musical inclinations, it’s exciting to think about what is in store in terms of his debut album, scheduled for an early 2013 release on the Concord label.  “I have a couple of ideas, a couple of special guests brewing who are pretty awesome,” says Bowers who is currently forming his band, something he is particularly thoughtful about.  “The main thing I’m going for with the band is that I want to feature a band full of guys in our generation. Just because I feel like a lot of these guys with their first albums, it’s just [about] names and they have these veterans, and that’s understandable&#8230;but I feel like playing with the people I’m friends with and who I know is going to put as much energy [into the record] as possible.  They’re not just doing it for a paycheck.”</p>
<p>He elaborates further taking a cue from a master with whom he shared recent company.    “Like Herbie’s debut album <em>Takin’ Off</em>.  He had Dexter Gordon &#8212; he was a veteran &#8212; but everybody else on the record was around Herbie’s age. Even though now they’re jazz legends, at the time they were just like one of Herbie’s contemporaries, so I feel like what I want to do is play with people who are <em>my</em> contemporaries.”</p>
<p>There is certainly no shortage of worthy peers for Bowers to choose from.  The well of young talent in jazz today is startling; most notably on Bowers’ own instrument, particularly as it pertains to African Americans.  Not in the last fifteen years (at least) has there been such a surge of rising Black pianists, all making their mark in the same generation.  Bowers is in great company with the brilliant likes of <a href="https://www.facebook.com/people/Sullivan-Fortner/4301839">Sullivan Fortner</a>, <a href="http://www.npr.org/templates/story/story.php?storyId=127032469">Christian Sands</a>, <a href="http://firehouse12.com/performers.asp?id=39477">David Bryant</a>, <a href="https://www.facebook.com/JoshuaWhite.MusicPage">Joshua White</a> and <a href="http://www.npr.org/artists/91420634/jonathan-batiste">Johnathan Batiste</a>, to name a few.  “It’s pretty great,” says Bowers of the strong representation.  “I remember even being in high school and kind of realizing that there were like three black kids in the jazz department&#8230;in an arts high school&#8230;in LA.  And when you think about the fact that this is our music&#8230;so yeah, it’s pretty great to see some young, Black piano players and all be kind of on the rise.&#8221;</p>
<p>And climbing fast.</p>
<p>===================</p>
<p>Getting To Know You&#8230;</p>
<p><strong>AT: Who are your favorite pianists of now?</strong></p>
<p><strong>KB:</strong> Well, of people closer to my age, I would say Sullivan Fornter is one of my favorites, and also John Batiste.  Also, Lawrence Fields, Gerald Clayton, [Robert] Glasper, Aaron Parks&#8230;</p>
<p><strong>AT: Do you have any favorite albums that came out this year?</strong></p>
<p><strong>KB:</strong> That new Thundercat album.  (Incidentally, that&#8217;s one of my favorites of this year also&#8230;but you&#8217;ll have to wait for the <em>Alternate Takes Best of 2011</em> post for more details!)</p>
<p><strong>AT: What are your favorite Hip Hop albums? </strong></p>
<p><strong>KB:</strong> <em>The Low End Theory </em>by A Tribe Called Quest.  That’s definitely one of my favorites.</p>
<p><strong>AT: The last thing you listened to on your iPod?</strong></p>
<p><strong>KB:</strong> Bon Iver</p>
<p><strong>AT: Name one person you would love work with? </strong></p>
<p><strong>KB: </strong>Quincy Jones</p>
<p><strong><em>Kris Bowers performs Saturday,</em></strong><strong><em> January 28th at the TriBeCa Performing Arts Center at 199 Chambers Street; (212) 220-1460, tribecapac.org.</em></strong></p>
<div></div>
</div>
<div></div>
</div>
</div>
<div></div>
<div><span class="Apple-style-span" style="border-collapse:collapse;color:#333333;font-family:sans-serif;font-size:12px;line-height:20px;white-space:pre-wrap;"><br />
</span></div>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://alternate-takes.com/category/arts/'>Arts</a>, <a href='http://alternate-takes.com/category/culture/'>Culture</a>, <a href='http://alternate-takes.com/category/interviews/'>Interviews</a>, <a href='http://alternate-takes.com/category/arts/jazz-arts/'>Jazz</a>, <a href='http://alternate-takes.com/category/music/'>Music</a>, <a href='http://alternate-takes.com/category/news/'>News</a>, <a href='http://alternate-takes.com/category/reviews/'>Reviews</a> Tagged: <a href='http://alternate-takes.com/tag/earl-travis/'>Earl Travis</a>, <a href='http://alternate-takes.com/tag/godwin-louis/'>Godwin Louis</a>, <a href='http://alternate-takes.com/tag/jehbreal-muhammad/'>Jehbreal Muhammad</a>, <a href='http://alternate-takes.com/tag/joe-saylor/'>Joe Saylor</a>, <a href='http://alternate-takes.com/tag/kenneth-whalum-iii/'>Kenneth Whalum III</a>, <a href='http://alternate-takes.com/tag/kris-bower/'>Kris Bower</a>, <a href='http://alternate-takes.com/tag/mike-cottone/'>Mike Cottone</a>, <a href='http://alternate-takes.com/tag/thelonious-monk-institute-of-jazz/'>Thelonious Monk Institute of Jazz</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1904/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1904/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1904/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1904/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1904/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1904/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1904/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1904/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1904/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1904/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1904/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1904/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1904/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1904/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=1904&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://alternate-takes.com/2011/12/06/on-the-rise-a-conversation-with-kris-bowers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/d4c85d30eb5719aad7acd1ab9800c8a9?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jellybeener</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://alternatetakesblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/kris01.jpg?w=238" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">kris01</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://alternatetakesblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/krisbowersrockrollhallfamehonorsarethazihcseggwpyl.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Kris+Bowers+Rock+Roll+Hall+Fame+Honors+Aretha+ZIhcsEGgwpYl</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://alternatetakesblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/krisb_at.jpg?w=238" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">KrisB_AT</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The World&#8217;s Greatest Grandma</title>
		<link>http://tobefrankblog.wordpress.com/2011/12/06/worlds-greatest-grandma/</link>
		<comments>http://tobefrankblog.wordpress.com/2011/12/06/worlds-greatest-grandma/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2011 15:05:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Frankie</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Craft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DIY]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tobefrankblog.wordpress.com/?p=688</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There was a story read to me as a child, about a grandmother who rides a motorcycle. I was never envious of the little boy in the story, because I knew that he was wrong for thinking his grandma was the coolest grandma in the world. His grandma couldn&#8217;t be the coolest grandma in the [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=688&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div style="text-align:center;">There was a story read to me as a child, about a grandmother who rides a motorcycle. I was never envious of the little boy in the story, because I knew that he was wrong for thinking his grandma was the coolest grandma in the world. His grandma couldn&#8217;t be the coolest grandma in the world because mine was. She has the mouth of a sailor and the dirtiest, funniest, sense of humour. Anyone who has spent any amount of time with her, can&#8217;t help but love her. My friend Jessi, upon hearing I was visiting my grandma this weekend, said, &#8221; Doris! Tell her I say Hi and I love her.&#8221; My grandma, Doris, just has that type of magic. She is literally one of a kind. </div>
<div style="text-align:center;"> </div>
<div style="text-align:center;">Grandma has always been the most encouraging of me and my crafting, so I couldn&#8217;t go visit without a little homemade something. I had picked up this little paper mache elephant at Michael&#8217;s a while back, not knowing what he would become, but unable to resist his dollar price tag. When I went downstairs (to my dungeon craft area) to whip up a little something for Grandma, the little elephant practically honked at me. He would easily become the perfect addition to my Grandma&#8217;s elephant collection. She has the elephant figurines scattered around her apartment, always facing the door, as per the superstitions that this positioning allows them to protect the home. All of her elephants have trunks pointed upward as well, because if an elephant&#8217;s trunk is downward, then all it&#8217;s luck scatters away, but an upward trunk stores the luck for the recipient, in this case Grams.</div>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://tobefrankblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/grandma-elephant.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-689" title="grandma elephant" src="http://tobefrankblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/grandma-elephant.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="278" /></a></p>
<div style="text-align:center;">Keeping in mind, that a white elephant is the luckiest of all, I decorated the elephant. I used leftover magazine cutouts from <a href="http://tobefrankblog.wordpress.com/2011/05/23/first-diy-flower-pots/">this project</a>. I chose shades of blue and turquoise and I modge podged them to the top and around the front. Then I painted the remainder of the elephant white. He was perfect. I knew she would love him and she did. I hope there are more similarly priced animals like this at Michael&#8217;s as I&#8217;d love to decorate other ones to use as tree ornaments.</div>
<div style="text-align:center;"> </div>
<div style="text-align:center;">My visit to grams, was atypical. Some of her magic is veiled by her illness, but I was happy to spend the weekend cleaning and cooking for her. I made her chicken soup, as soup is one of her all time favorite meals, along with chicken cutlets, spinach, and roasted root veggies. I couldn&#8217;t tell you how the soup or cutlets tasted, since I still don&#8217;t eat meat but as always, she loved everything I made for her, even if she didn&#8217;t eat nearly as much as usual. I froze some large portions for her and my grandpa to eat at later dates. I&#8217;m sure she appreciated the present &amp; future home-cooked meals even more than the crafted elephant.</div>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-690" title="grandma pot" src="http://tobefrankblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/grandma-pot.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="424" /></p>
<div style="text-align:center;">While there, I came across several  crafted-by-me things; a relatively recent mermaid painting, a mermaid card, a necklace, and this beautiful hand painted pot. Judging by the crude depiction of her, my grandpa, flowers, and the sun, I made the pot circa 1998 or 1997, when I was eleven or twelve.  And there it was, on her screened in porch, with a plant thriving in it, twelve or thirteen years later. I had to take a picture because it was just so sweet.  On the top, it reads, &#8220;World&#8217;s Greatest Grandma,&#8221; which she was then, still is today, and always will be, even when all the paint has cracked off the pot and I&#8217;m a grandma myself.</div>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/688/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/688/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/688/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/688/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/688/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/688/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/688/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/688/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/688/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/688/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/688/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/688/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/688/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/688/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=688&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tobefrankblog.wordpress.com/2011/12/06/worlds-greatest-grandma/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c3bc3c574b81fe4d8b7e2d28146f6f8a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">franjessica</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tobefrankblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/grandma-elephant.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">grandma elephant</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tobefrankblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/grandma-pot.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">grandma pot</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Information Generation</title>
		<link>http://fasterthanlight.me/2011/12/03/the-information-generation/</link>
		<comments>http://fasterthanlight.me/2011/12/03/the-information-generation/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2011 19:57:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>jandrewhickey</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Philosophy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[information]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[philosophy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rambling]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fasterthanlight.me/?p=472</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Our world is all but digitized. Analogue is becoming a thing of the past, and will likely die with my parents generation, or my own. It will be seen as something collectible, cool, retro, and unique, but nevertheless, dead. Yes, people still flip through books, buy records, and learn instruments, but for how much longer? [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=472&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_473" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 567px"><a href="http://fasterthanlightdotme.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/radiosilence-by-tatiana-plakhova.jpg" target="_blank"><img class=" wp-image-473   " title="RadioSilence by tatiana plakhova" src="http://fasterthanlightdotme.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/radiosilence-by-tatiana-plakhova.jpg?w=557&#038;h=742" alt="" width="557" height="742" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">RadioSilence, by Tatiana Plakhova</p></div>
<p>Our world is all but digitized. Analogue is becoming a thing of the past, and will likely die with my parents generation, or my own. It will be seen as something collectible, cool, retro, and unique, but nevertheless, dead. Yes, people still flip through books, buy records, and learn instruments, but for how much longer? The pushing of tactile buttons, pulling of levers, and turning of knobs, is about to disappear. Soon the distinction between being online and offline will fade. There will be no offline, and thus, no online. Everything and everyone will be forever connected. If we want to disconnect, we&#8217;ll have to painstakingly go out out of our way to do so.</p>
<p>If you are like me, then you feel amiss when you can&#8217;t get online. Usually it happens when visiting parents, grandparents, or rural friends. On one occasion – before I bothered to turn on my laptop – I asked someone what their Wifi password was. They stared at me blankly for a few seconds, before uttering, “Wifi?” The horror. The horror.</p>
<p>But, honestly, there is a certain anxiety that comes over people in my generation when we can’t connect. Technology critics and primitivists usually claim that this anxiety is innately bad, and stems from my generation&#8217;s need for instant gratification. But what&#8217;s so bad about instant gratification? Should I have to work to find the information I want, or need, when it is conveniently at my fingertips? Shouldn&#8217;t information be easy to access?</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://fasterthanlightdotme.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/mays_8.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-522 aligncenter" title="mays_8 by butdoesitfloat" src="http://fasterthanlightdotme.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/mays_8.jpg" alt="" width="299" height="381" /></a></p>
<p>Then again, maybe I am too &#8220;connected&#8221;. Half of my daydreaming is spent in my head, the other half online. To an outsider – typically someone over forty – it must look strange. Blue links highlighted. Flashing windows. Twenty tabs open. Music playing. Headphones on. Lukewarm coffee on desk. Occasionally, I feel less like a person, and more like an amoeba that feeds on tweets, notifications, and followers.</p>
<p>Enter my parent’s generation. The first thing to notice is their sociality. Older people are always talking, or always listening. Rarely are they absorbed in some task on a computer, hunched over with a stiff neck and squinting eyes. (That is, unless they are trying to find the vexatious, &#8220;forward to all&#8221; button). Older generations can get lost in a conversation; yet, their conversations lack something. They tend to get stuck on bits of information that, for the life of them, they cannot remember.</p>
<p>Who was that actresses name? What was that restaurant in San Francisco called? How can we get to the freeway from here? Questions always linger when talking to older people. This isn&#8217;t because they have bad memories – though they certainly can – but, because they aren&#8217;t whipping out their phones, or flinging open their laptops. There is an odd elegance to this. I have to remind myself that for my parents, the world isn’t about information, or, &#8220;instant gratification&#8221;. My mother spends her time watching classic films, visiting family, and reading books. My father rides his mountain bike, shoots guns, and fixes things. <del>I can’t tell if he particularly enjoys this last activity, as much of the time it is littered with “fuck”, and “god damn it”.</del> (Edit: he claims he only cusses when he can&#8217;t fix things).</p>
<p>My parent&#8217;s generation have a laudable simplicity about them. They are sometimes frustrating, asking us to hook up their internet for fix their computers, but those things are essentially foreign to them. Our parents don&#8217;t really belong in the digital world, they just visit it. They are record players, and we are iPods. Besides, I can&#8217;t pretend I&#8217;m entirely used to our digital world either. I still remember the days of connecting to the internet through screeching analogue dial tones, so that I could work on my geocities website into the tiny hours of the morning, or until someone called and I was disconnected. Sometimes I have to remind myself that my generation was the last to grow up before the Internet became truly monolithic. From now on, children will grow up in the shadow of that monolith. While it may be frightening, I think younger generations will be fine. My niece and nephew&#8217;s computer skills already rival their parents, and none are over the age of six.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://fasterthanlightdotme.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/old_recorder-by-but-does-it-float.jpg" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-524" title="Old_Recorder by but does it float" src="http://fasterthanlightdotme.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/old_recorder-by-but-does-it-float.jpg?w=367&#038;h=490" alt="" width="367" height="490" /></a></p>
<p>So, how is my generation – the information generation – handling things? How can we begin to answer this question? Information is violently changing our lives. The Arab world has ignited with social protests, <a title="partially catalyzed by social media" href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2011/feb/25/twitter-facebook-uprisings-arab-libya" target="_blank">partially catalyzed by social media</a>. WikiLeaks has released over 400,000 confidential government documents. The Occupy movement is still going strong, <a title="with rallies being organized online and through social media" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/jeff-elder/occupy-wall-street-and-social-media_b_1077047.html" target="_blank">with rallies being organized online</a>. <a title="The first digital currency, bitcoin, showed signs of being practical, and used on a wide scale" href="http://www.wired.com/magazine/2011/11/mf_bitcoin/all/1" target="_blank">The first digital currency showed signs of being practical</a>. For the first time, Artificial Intelligence is being used widely, <a title="(even if it is rather silly)" href="http://shitsirisays.com/" target="_blank">(even if it is rather silly)</a>. And, somewhere, a twenty-two year old kid writes a blog post about all of it, which could be seen by millions. (I said <em>could</em>.)</p>
<p>My generation is starving for useful, thoughtful, intelligent, and inspiring information. If we want to learn how to do something &#8211; <em>anything &#8211; </em>we can google it, and be on our way; there&#8217;s even a <a title="how-to-do-everything podcast" href="http://howtodoeverything.org/" target="_blank">how-to-do-everything podcast</a>. If that weren&#8217;t enough, Wikipedia has an entry on just about everything, with all links eventually leading back to philosophy. We can learn about the fundamental stuff of the universe – or whatever philosophers ramble about &#8212; with a few mouse clicks. For those of us that don&#8217;t like reading, there are infographics and videos on every topic out there. When we aren&#8217;t absorbing information, we&#8217;re expressing ourselves by the millions, through sites like DeviantArt, Flickr, Tumblr, Etsy, WordPress, and more. Perhaps we are too entitled, too lazy, or too impatient, but, we aren&#8217;t stupid. I don&#8217;t accept that. We have access to more information than any other generation, and we are using it. We are becoming smarter with the information we are using, even if much of it drips through the cracks of obnoxious YouTube videos and incomprehensible memes. Perhaps I&#8217;m being sophomoric, but I think the internet is fundamentally good, because knowledge is fundamentally good. Maybe that crazy greek bastard was onto something when he said, “The only good is knowledge, the only evil is ignorance”. And, if you don&#8217;t know who I&#8217;m talking about, just google it.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/472/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/472/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/472/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/472/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/472/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/472/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/472/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/472/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/472/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/472/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/472/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/472/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/472/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/472/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=472&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://fasterthanlight.me/2011/12/03/the-information-generation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/e48605c21002e39c0580f49ee7c53393?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jandrewhickey</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://fasterthanlightdotme.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/radiosilence-by-tatiana-plakhova.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">RadioSilence by tatiana plakhova</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://fasterthanlightdotme.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/mays_8.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mays_8 by butdoesitfloat</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://fasterthanlightdotme.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/old_recorder-by-but-does-it-float.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Old_Recorder by but does it float</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Peppermint and White Chocolate Macarons</title>
		<link>http://allisoneats.com/2011/12/05/peppermint-and-white-chocolate-macarons/</link>
		<comments>http://allisoneats.com/2011/12/05/peppermint-and-white-chocolate-macarons/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2011 16:37:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>alliedale</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[baking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chocolate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cookies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[festive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[french]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[macarons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mint]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://allisoneats.com/?p=734</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#160; I&#8217;ve wanted to try macaron-making again since the first attempt back in July. So, in the spirit of the holidays and an upcoming &#8220;White Elephant Party,&#8221; I decided it was a good opportunity to give it a whirl-this time with a more festive flavor combo. I&#8217;d heard that chocolate shells are the most difficult [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=734&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://seeallisoneat.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/peppermintmac_1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-736" title="PeppermintMac_1" src="http://seeallisoneat.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/peppermintmac_1.jpg" alt="" width="599" height="387" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://seeallisoneat.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/peppermintmac_2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-737" title="PeppermintMac_2" src="http://seeallisoneat.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/peppermintmac_2.jpg" alt="" width="599" height="387" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://seeallisoneat.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/peppermintmac_3.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-738" title="PeppermintMac_3" src="http://seeallisoneat.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/peppermintmac_3.jpg" alt="" width="599" height="387" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve wanted to try macaron-making again since <a href="http://allisoneats.com/2011/07/18/demystifying-the-macaron/">the first attempt</a> back in July. So, in the spirit of the holidays and an upcoming &#8220;White Elephant Party,&#8221; I decided it was a good opportunity to give it a whirl-this time with a more festive flavor combo. I&#8217;d heard that chocolate shells are the most difficult to make, so this time I went with a basic shell that&#8217;s flavored with peppermint extract. Naturally white chocolate is a good match for this, and pretty holiday-appropriate. Since the Chocolate-Caramel macarons, I&#8217;ve learned some tips in perfecting the texture of the shells:</p>
<ol>
<li>The first time I used a coarse almond meal, which gave the shells a grainy texture. I found they came out much nicer using a fine meal. I think this had a lot to do with the ingredients being able to blend better and gave me a smoother, thinner batter.</li>
<li>Make sure you let your tray of piped batter sit for at least 15 minutes. This gives your shells and smooth and shiny top.</li>
<li>Bake one tray at a time! I learned this after an entire tray of shells cracked during my first batch. I also think a thicker tray helps a lot-I&#8217;ve read that some people stack 2-3 trays on top of one another as well.</li>
<li>Really let them cool before removing from the tray-or the soft interiors will stick to the pan and peel off.</li>
</ol>
<p>So here you go! The recipe for peppermint and white chocolate holiday macarons. Though I must forewarn you, eager bakers, this was an all-day cooking affair! Since I wanted to make a lot of cookies (I ended up with about 50),  you may prefer to halve the recipe. Or, like me, just make sure you plan something to do while you wait for your trays to dry, bake, and cool. I ended up wrapping most of my Christmas gifts! So, while a bit exhausting, the day was extremely productive and the outcome was worth the effort!</p>
<p><strong>Peppermint Macaron Shells </strong><em>adapted from </em><a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0811868710?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=httpalliwanti-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=390957&amp;creativeASIN=0811868710"><em>I Love Macarons</em></a><em></em><em> </em><strong></strong></p>
<p>1 1/3 cup almond flour<br />
3 cups powdered sugar<br />
6 large egg whites, left out, uncovered overnight<br />
½ Cup + 2 TBSP granulated sugar<br />
1/4 tsp peppermint extract<br />
Red Food Coloring (optional)</p>
<p>Line a baking sheet with parchment paper and have a pastry bag with a plain tip (about 1/2-inch, 2 cm) ready. Using a pencil, draw 1-inch circles approximately 1-inch apart on your parchment paper.</p>
<p>In a food processor, blend the almond flour and powdered sugar until well incorporated.</p>
<p>In a stainless-steel bowl of an electric mixer, beat eggs whites on high speed until they are foamy. Gradually add the granulated sugar, peppermint extract and about 20-30 drops of red food coloring to the egg whites and continue to beat until it forms a stiff meringue.</p>
<p>Using a rubber spatula, carefully fold the almond flour/powdered sugar mixture into the meringue in a couple additions. Blend by scopping batter up from the bottom and pressing it against the sides of the bowl. Do this a few times until well incorporated.</p>
<p>Fill pastry bag with the batter and carefully dispense into your drawn circles. Once the tray is filled, rap the baking sheet on the counter to help settle the batter. Let tray sit out at room temperature for 15 minutes so that a slight crust forms on each shell.</p>
<p>Bake at 375 F for 9-12 minutes, until the shells are slightly crisp on top. Allow to cool before removing from the trays. Repeat, one tray at a time until you’ve used up the batter.  Make sure you use a new piece of parchment at least every other batch to assure smooth and round shells.</p>
<p><strong>White Chocolate Ganache</strong></p>
<p>2/3 cup heavy cream<br />
10 oz good quality white chocolate, finely chopped<br />
1 ½ TBSP unsalted butter, at room temperature and cut into 3 pieces</p>
<p>Put the white chocolate in a heat proof bowl. In a small saucepan, bring the cream to a boil, then pour over the chocolate. Using a whisk or rubber spatula, stir together until smooth. Once smooth, stir in the butter. Place the bowl over a larger bowl filled with ice water, stirring constantly until ganache is thick enough to pipe cleanly.  Work quickly, as the ganache will begin to harden again. If this happens, you can set the bowl over a simmering pot of water and stir it until smooth-then repeat the cooling process.</p>
<p><strong>Peppermint Chocolate Macaron Assembly</strong></p>
<p>Pair your cooled macaron shells into like sizes; I recommend you do this before making the ganache filling. Fill a piping bag fitted with a wide, round tip with your white chocolate ganache. Carefully pipe filling onto the flat side of one shell, leaving about 3mm space from the edges. Pick up your filled shell and its empty pair, and place them together, gently twisting as you press.</p>
<p>Store your macarons in the refrigerator. This allows the filling to soak into the shells and give them that distinct chewy bite. They&#8217;re best enjoyed the following day, brought to room temperature.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/734/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/734/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/734/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/734/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/734/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/734/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/734/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/734/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/734/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/734/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/734/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/734/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/734/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/734/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=734&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://allisoneats.com/2011/12/05/peppermint-and-white-chocolate-macarons/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>161</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/1bb33e9f3008b68adf862ce86acc0c89?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">alliedale</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://seeallisoneat.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/peppermintmac_1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">PeppermintMac_1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://seeallisoneat.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/peppermintmac_2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">PeppermintMac_2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://seeallisoneat.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/peppermintmac_3.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">PeppermintMac_3</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What makes you a Runner?</title>
		<link>http://endurancegal.wordpress.com/2011/12/05/what-makes-you-a-runner/</link>
		<comments>http://endurancegal.wordpress.com/2011/12/05/what-makes-you-a-runner/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2011 14:21:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>endurancegal</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Fitness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inspiration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[passion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[running]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://endurancegal.wordpress.com/?p=122</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I started running in 2006. Want to know why? I was afraid of putting on newlywed weight! I had seen so many of my friends get married, and well gain weight. I was determined to starve off the pounds associated with newlywed bliss. There was no agenda, no plan, no time goals, I just started [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=122&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I started running in 2006. Want to know why? I was afraid of putting on newlywed weight! I had seen so many of my friends get married, and well gain weight. I was determined to starve off the pounds associated with newlywed bliss. There was no agenda, no plan, no time goals, I just started running. The good news was that I had some background in exercise and had gone to the gym off/on for most of college. But, running for 30 minutes became my challenge. My husband and I would go to the gym every day and run for 30 minutes. And, to be honest, that was the extent of my running. Then, something happened. I became not just a gym rat, but a runner. How did it happen? What separated me from those that trudge to the gym daily with those that gracefully prance along well worn trails and paths? Like anything meaningful in life, it was a gradual change.</p>
<p><img src="http://a2.sphotos.ak.fbcdn.net/hphotos-ak-snc3/29417_737351863809_1816159_42950804_6128487_n.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<p>We all have reasons for why we start running. But, the reasons we keep doing it are very different. For me, running became a challenge. Challenging myself is what I love most about life. I love pushing the limits. So, I started with 5k. I ran these races trying to get my time down. Then, I progressed to 10k and 1/2 marathon, never thinking a marathon was possible. But, then, there I was standing at the finish of the Boston Marathon wondering, how did this happen? If I am being honest, a lot of it happened selfishly. I wanted to be better than everyone else. I wanted to have something to brag about. But, now, with a baby on the way, my prospective is so much different. I enjoy the breeze on my face, the way my body knows what to do, the fact I can run any time in any place. What makes me a runner? The fact that I never want to stop!<br />
<img src="http://a6.sphotos.ak.fbcdn.net/hphotos-ak-snc6/162850_820316961089_1816159_45659475_5508236_n.jpg" alt="" /><br />
I want you to know that whether you run 3 miles or 33 miles, you can be a runner too. You are a runner even if your pace is more of a jogger. You are a runner even if your form needs work or you are still figuring out how to breathe and talk at the same time. What makes you a  runner, is your passion for it! If you get up every day thinking about running, you are probably a runner. I promise you this is a great identity. There is a sense of commitment that our world lacks today in being a runner. And, you possess it.<br />
<img src="http://a6.sphotos.ak.fbcdn.net/hphotos-ak-ash4/206959_933175776119_1816159_46654889_7592840_n.jpg" alt="" /><br />
I would say I recently became a runner. Not after my first marathon, not after Boston. But, in the last few months. I have learned that no matter how fast, how far, how long I run, I will love every minute of it! I will run with fast runners. I will run with slow runners. I will run with just about anyone! I will run on the treadmill. I will run in the great outdoors. I will run just about anywhere. This is what makes me a runner. Not a Boston qualifying time, although it would be nice, not a contract with Asics, but rather my love for running, makes me a runner. It is no longer a way to shed pounds. But, it is a daily activity that I cherish!</p>
<p>So what makes you a runner? Tell me about it.<br />
<img src="http://a5.sphotos.ak.fbcdn.net/hphotos-ak-snc6/216884_933177158349_1816159_46654920_5547601_n.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/122/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/122/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/122/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/122/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/122/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/122/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/122/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/122/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/122/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/122/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/122/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/122/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/122/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/122/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=122&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://endurancegal.wordpress.com/2011/12/05/what-makes-you-a-runner/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>173</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/5b74cddcdcb04caeb4e1c3ca9f96ff9f?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">endurancegal</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://a2.sphotos.ak.fbcdn.net/hphotos-ak-snc3/29417_737351863809_1816159_42950804_6128487_n.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://a6.sphotos.ak.fbcdn.net/hphotos-ak-snc6/162850_820316961089_1816159_45659475_5508236_n.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://a6.sphotos.ak.fbcdn.net/hphotos-ak-ash4/206959_933175776119_1816159_46654889_7592840_n.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://a5.sphotos.ak.fbcdn.net/hphotos-ak-snc6/216884_933177158349_1816159_46654920_5547601_n.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Carrie Oeding Became a Writer</title>
		<link>http://phdincreativewriting.wordpress.com/2011/12/04/how-carrie-oeding-became-a-writer/</link>
		<comments>http://phdincreativewriting.wordpress.com/2011/12/04/how-carrie-oeding-became-a-writer/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2011 01:54:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>phdincreativewriting</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[authors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[How ---- Became a Writer Series]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to become a writer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ph.A.Q.&#039;s]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://phdincreativewriting.wordpress.com/?p=2613</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[[A] mysterious poet visitor was sitting in an undergraduate workshop at the U of MN. Someone said he was a famous poet from China, and honestly I don’t remember what his name was. I wouldn’t have known who was famous then. Why was he there? He came up after class once and said, “You’re going [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=2613&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p style="text-align:center;"><span style="color:#33cccc;"><em>[A] mysterious poet visitor was sitting in an undergraduate workshop at the U of MN. Someone said he was a famous poet from China, and honestly I don’t remember what his name was. I wouldn’t have known who was famous then. Why was he there? He came up after class once and said, “You’re going to be a good poet one day.” It kind of shook me.</em></span></p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="http://phdincreativewriting.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/13034_177337864518_526909518_2737773_7868535_n.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-2615 alignnone" title="13034_177337864518_526909518_2737773_7868535_n" src="http://phdincreativewriting.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/13034_177337864518_526909518_2737773_7868535_n.jpg" alt="" width="420" height="315" /></a><em></em></p>
<p><strong>Carrie Oeding&#8217;s</strong> first book, <em>Our List of Solutions</em>, won the Lester M. Wolfson prize in 2010, selected by David Dodd Lee. The book was released in 2011 by <a href="http://42miles.wordpress.com/" target="_blank">42 Miles Press</a>, a new poetry series from Indiana University South Bend Press. Carrie’s work has appeared in such places as Colorado Review, Third Coast, Greensboro Review, Mid-American Review, Best New Poets 2005 and elsewhere. She is currently working on a second book of poems and a book of creative nonfiction essays. A native of Minnesota, Carrie has lived in Washington, Ohio, Texas and now resides in West  Virginia with her husband, poet Kent Shaw.</p>
<p>Visit Carrie&#8217;s website: <a href="http://www.carrieoeding.com/" target="_blank">http://www.carrieoeding.com/</a></p>
<p><strong><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Our-List-Solutions-Carrie-Oeding/dp/0983074712"><img class="alignleft" src="http://ecx.images-amazon.com/images/I/31ZdOflHVwL._SX106_.jpg" alt="" width="106" height="151" /></a>Read more by and about Carrie:</strong></p>
<p>Book:<a href="http://www.amazon.com/Our-List-Solutions-Carrie-Oeding/dp/0983074712" target="_blank"> Our List of Solutions</a><br />
“I Have Been In More Uncomfortable Situations Than This&#8221; at <a href="http://thediagram.com/8_2/oeding.html" target="_blank">Diagram</a><br />
Audio at <a href="http://tapingfortheblind.org/Audio_Archives/POETS%20CORNER/POETS%20H-P/POET_OEDING,_CARRIE_09-02-11.mp3" target="_blank">The Poet&#8217;s Corner </a><br />
“Work Harder” at <a href="http://www.versedaily.org/2011/workharder.shtml" target="_blank">Verse Daily</a></p>
<p><strong>How Carrie Oeding Became a Writer</strong></p>
<p>This is the next installment in the <em>How to Become a Writer</em> interview series, which will post here at Ph.D. in Creative Writing every other Sunday (er, or so) until I run out of writers to interview, or until they stop saying yes. Each writer answers the same 5 questions. Thanks to Carrie for saying yes!</p>
<p><strong>1.  Why did you want to become a writer?</strong></p>
<p>I was really in my head as a kid. Books excited me, but they excite a lot of young people, so who knows. When I grew older, I knew I wanted to make art, and I was closest with language as an outlet. When I was a junior in high school, I started telling people I was going to major in creative writing at the University of Minnesota, and then I did.</p>
<p>I was born on a small Minnesota farm, a small working farm where my dad grows corn and soybeans and sometimes raised sheep. I never write poems about where I grew up. There’s no negative or traumatic reason for this. I have, however, one piece in <a href="http://www.creativenonfiction.org/brevity/past%20issues/brev24/oeding_rural.htm" target="_blank">Brevity: A Journal of Concise Creative Nonfiction</a> that is about my relationship with growing up on a farm. I want to say &#8220;in isolation on a farm,&#8221; but I think of my husband laughing when I said we lived 5 miles from town, which was hardly isolation. But it might as well have been 50 miles, as I spent most of my life on the farm. And, anyway, the &#8220;town&#8221; was Luverne, MN&#8211;population: less than 5,000. My husband also likes to chuckle at the image of me stretched across my bed, literally waiting for something to happen, anything. People like to look back and find meaning after the fact about how they got here, some of this is true and some is storytelling. Storytelling is meaning-making, I understand, but I don&#8217;t always trust it. This distrust works well in essays as it creates a constant need for questioning and rethinking.</p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 317px"><a href="http://www.re-title.com/public/artists/5906/1/Louise-Bourgeois-1.jpg"><img src="http://www.re-title.com/public/artists/5906/1/Louise-Bourgeois-1.jpg" alt="" width="307" height="193" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Louise Bourgeois Installation view, Tate Modern, London, 2007 Image © Nathan Strange/AP</p></div>
<p><strong>2.  How did you go about becoming a writer?</strong></p>
<p>In a pretty conventional way. B.A. in English with creative writing emphasis. Attending an MFA program immediately after at the age of 22. Ph.D. in creative writing right after that. But this doesn&#8217;t necessarily explain how I became a writer. I became a writer by writing. I remember almost all of my undergraduate creative writing teachers saying, “Just write, and things will happen,” and when I began to see it was true, I never doubted this. I still don’t. Even when I’m anxious about what’s next.</p>
<p>Was I too young to leave Minneapolis after undergrad and pursue an MFA at 22? Probably. But I was right to make the decision, and I immediately had a real writing life because if it. If I hadn&#8217;t left Minnesota to get an MFA at that time, I likely would be a very unhappy person today who doesn&#8217;t write. Maybe I wouldn&#8217;t, but I wouldn&#8217;t want to go back in time and find out.</p>
<p>I heard someone on NPR a number of years ago, a fiction writer, who said he taught himself how to write stories by retyping Grace Paley&#8217;s short stories. It was an &#8220;I had no idea what I was doing&#8221; confession, but I loved the idea of it. And Grace Paley should be retyped by all of us. I can&#8217;t remember who it was, but then I think he went on to somehow fall into some famous novelist&#8217;s lap who schooled him.</p>
<div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 384px"><a href="http://www.baseballreliquary.org/images/JosephCornell.jpg"><img src="http://www.baseballreliquary.org/images/JosephCornell.jpg" alt="" width="374" height="270" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Joseph Cornell</p></div>
<p><strong> 3. Who helped you along the way, and how?</strong></p>
<p>This is another interesting question, because I again want to answer it in different ways. Some of the people who helped me in the beginning of my writing life were practically strangers whom I had brief encounters with. For instance, a mysterious poet visitor was sitting in an undergraduate workshop at the U of MN. Someone said he was a famous poet from China, and honestly I don’t remember what his name was. I wouldn’t have known who was famous then. Why was he there? He came up after class once and said, “You’re going to be a good poet one day.” It kind of shook me. It didn’t stay with me, though. I just remembered this recently.</p>
<div class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 250px"><a href="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/a/a2/Stevie_Smith.jpg/240px-Stevie_Smith.jpg"><img src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/a/a2/Stevie_Smith.jpg/240px-Stevie_Smith.jpg" alt="" width="240" height="185" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Stevie Smith</p></div>
<p>The writers I read whom initially helped open up the idea of what writing could do&#8212;Stevie Smith, Amy Hempel, Mary Ruefle, Frank O’Hara, Barry Hannah, Larry Levis, Claire Bateman, Russell Edson, Lydia Davis. I feel incredibly unsatisfied stopping here, but I’m just making lists.</p>
<p>My editor, <a href="http://seventeenfingeredpoetrybird.blogspot.com/" target="_blank">David Dodd Lee</a>, for being such a smart reader of my first book (and of poems, period), seeing that it is doing something new, understanding its humor and seriousness, and publishing it. Publishing it in a gorgeous book that completely lives up to my in-print dreams!  Also, my husband, Kent Shaw, who is a poet, who has read more contemporary poetry than anyone I&#8217;ve met and sees the book in the same vein. His writing keeps me excited about poetry, which is funny because when we first started dating we didn&#8217;t read each other&#8217;s work. We are both very critical, and we secretly worried we wouldn&#8217;t like each other’s poems. Our writing was a huge surprise to each other. Then we got hitched.</p>
<p>Some who currently help me are the writers and artists who keep me excited about making things: <a href="http://www.poets.org/poet.php/prmPID/767" target="_blank">Alice Notley</a>, <a href="http://www.eulabiss.net/" target="_blank">Eula Biss</a>, <a href="http://www.wavepoetry.com/authors/62-maggie-nelson" target="_blank">Maggie Nelson</a>, <a href="http://www.mattheaharvey.info/" target="_blank">Mattea Harvey</a>, <a href="http://www.wernerherzog.com/" target="_blank">Werner Herzog</a>, <a href="http://mirandajuly.com/" target="_blank">Miranda July</a>. I am absolutely on fire about artist <a href="http://www.sarahsze.com/" target="_blank">Sarah Sze</a>, but you should see the installations in person.</p>
<p>Something that has helped me from stopping writing after I completed my first book, is taking art classes during my two years in Houston. I saw a Martin Puryear show at the SFMOMA in 2009. I had finished my first book, and it was unpublished. I was alone and at god-awful MLA, and it was one of the best art experiences of my life. Something about walking closely around his sculptures made me feel like I was breathing for the first time in two years. I moved to Houston nine months later and took art classes at the Museum of Fine Art’s Glassell School. I remember the first night of just intro to drawing and how it felt electric to be sketching terribly in the humid Houston August. I think there were times I slept with my art supplies. It’s stupid, I hate these kinds of narratives, but I am going to own this one. Two years of classes weren’t enough, but having that kind of excitement about making anything recharged my writing.</p>
<div class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 257px"><a href="http://www.saraayers.com/graphics/darger/blenguin.jpg"><img src="http://www.saraayers.com/graphics/darger/blenguin.jpg" alt="" width="247" height="196" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Henry Darger</p></div>
<p>Joseph Cornell and Henry Darger were easy to get obsessed with. There is no line between their artistic and personal biographies. Going back to the writer who copied lines of Grace Paley, I like the idea of trying to figure things out on your own&#8211;having a hunch of what you want to do, and like Darger, finding ways on his own to get his collages &#8220;right&#8221; for him.</p>
<p>Also Ana Mendieta, I’m fascinated with, her performance pieces, during which uses her body in ways I’m usually very cynical about.</p>
<p>Louise Bourgeois is one of my favorite artists. Her wit, side view, darkness, and play are right up my alley. And she just works in so many mediums. Never stopped exploring.</p>
<p>I&#8217;d like to be around Marianne Moore. Have her as a neighbor, but I don&#8217;t want to read her biography.</p>
<p><strong>5.  What would you say in a short letter to an aspiring writer?</strong><br />
Write and read, and things will happen.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;re a poet, consider making something in addition to poetry. You need to be making something all of the time, whatever it is. Poems, collages, pancakes.</p>
<p>Be humble. Don&#8217;t romanticize being humble. Don&#8217;t be so easily impressed.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2613/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2613/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2613/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2613/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2613/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2613/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2613/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2613/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2613/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2613/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2613/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2613/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2613/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2613/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=2613&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://phdincreativewriting.wordpress.com/2011/12/04/how-carrie-oeding-became-a-writer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>51</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/d7a7d8f090e1a61dc60f307aa609b22e?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">phdincreativewriting</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://phdincreativewriting.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/13034_177337864518_526909518_2737773_7868535_n.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">13034_177337864518_526909518_2737773_7868535_n</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ecx.images-amazon.com/images/I/31ZdOflHVwL._SX106_.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://www.re-title.com/public/artists/5906/1/Louise-Bourgeois-1.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://www.baseballreliquary.org/images/JosephCornell.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/a/a2/Stevie_Smith.jpg/240px-Stevie_Smith.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://www.saraayers.com/graphics/darger/blenguin.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A single&#8217;s guide to happiness</title>
		<link>http://amylleblanc.wordpress.com/2011/12/04/a-singles-guide-to-happiness/</link>
		<comments>http://amylleblanc.wordpress.com/2011/12/04/a-singles-guide-to-happiness/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2011 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>amylleblanc</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://amylleblanc.wordpress.com/?p=909</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Movies, TV shows, songs, plays, even commercials are all selling love. Actually, &#8220;selling&#8221; is kind of a soft word, it&#8217;s more like they&#8217;re pushing it on us. They&#8217;re like drug pushers &#8211; they&#8217;re love pushers! And while I&#8217;m more the cheesy action fan myself, I&#8217;ve seen enough romantic comedies to understand why so many people [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=909&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://amylleblanc.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/sam_1480ee.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-916" title="SAM_1480ee" src="http://amylleblanc.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/sam_1480ee.jpg" alt="" width="584" height="438" /></a>Movies, TV shows, songs, plays, even commercials are all selling love. Actually, &#8220;selling&#8221; is kind of a soft word, it&#8217;s more like they&#8217;re pushing it on us. They&#8217;re like drug pushers &#8211; they&#8217;re love pushers! And while I&#8217;m more the cheesy action fan myself, I&#8217;ve seen enough romantic comedies to understand why so many people believe that romantic love makes the world go &#8217;round.</p>
<p>From Jerry Maguire&#8217;s &#8220;you had me at hello&#8221;, to Johnny&#8217;s &#8220;nobody puts Baby in the corner&#8221;, and Mr. Darcy&#8217;s &#8220;you&#8217;ve bewitched me body and soul&#8221; (yes, I&#8217;m aware this line would be really creepy if said in this century)&#8230; you get the point. We&#8217;ve been conditioned to believe that life and true happiness starts when your prince charming walks (or gallops) into your life. According to Hollywood, love equals happiness. And I&#8217;m not here to refute that logic, but after many a long conversation with single friends feeling the pressure, I decided to address the issue. Let&#8217;s consider for a moment that perhaps <em>romantic</em> love does not equal happiness. I&#8217;m not an expert on happiness, but if you want my opinion (and since you&#8217;re reading my blog, I&#8217;ll assume that you do), here are my tips on the subject.</p>
<p>1. Be happy with yourself. This is obvious and should be relevant whether in a relationship or not. Whether you are newly-single, looking to be in a relationship, or are intentionally single for a time, you are most likely a pretty decent human being. But since I don&#8217;t know who you are, I can&#8217;t say that for sure. Regardless, learning to be happy with who you are can be a long process and not quite as simple as it sounds, but figure it out &#8211; nothing will be worth it if you don&#8217;t.</p>
<p>2. Keep active. An added bonus to being single means that you can be as selfish as you want in this regard &#8211; your time is your own so make the most of it. Take up hobbies and try new things. I like to read and write but in the past I&#8217;ve also taken up cooking, running, climbing, hot yoga, and more. I&#8217;m also a huge movie fan so going to the cinema is a regular thing for me as well. If you&#8217;re uncomfortable seeing movies alone, find another friend who loves movies as much as you, or find a small indie theatre &#8211; either no one will notice, or in my experience, there tends to be a lot of singles seeing movies on their own at these places. Which brings me to my next point&#8230;</p>
<p>3. Don&#8217;t be afraid to do things on your own. This is probably the biggest challenge for sad-singles. Fact: If you don&#8217;t do the things you want to because you don&#8217;t want to do them alone, there is a very real possibility you&#8217;ll end up on your couch every night. Which, in my opinion is a single&#8217;s guide to depression, not happiness. If you&#8217;re not sure where to start, make a list of things you might be interested in trying and then put them into action (see point two).</p>
<p>4. Make friends! Perhaps more importantly, make friend groups. This isn&#8217;t as lame as it sounds. Making friend groups is a great way to fulfill certain needs. For example, if you&#8217;re a music lover, make friends with people who like to go to concerts, or, if you&#8217;re religious, make friends at your church who you can have coffee nights with. This logic is also true of team sports and book clubs, if that&#8217;s your thing.</p>
<p>5. Have your own &#8220;go-to&#8221; places. This is easier if you&#8217;ve lived in the same place all your life, but if you&#8217;re like me and are constantly traveling, I try to find cafes, restaurants, theatres (or usually, libraries), to frequent. I try to get to know the names of the employees and before long, it feels like a home away from home. These places also come in handy for the nights you just don&#8217;t want to be alone in your apartment.</p>
<p>6. As the old song says, go find somebody to love. As much as you may want to ignore it, love is fundamental to your happiness, but this doesn&#8217;t have to be romantic love. This can be evident in your relationships with friends, family, God, or even strangers. Try spreading the love by doing some volunteer work. As silly as it may sound, on some of my lonely days in Malawi (they <em>will</em> happen), I would visit the animal shelter near my work in Blantyre and play with the dogs, they didn&#8217;t get many visitors and the puppies were just so eager to have someone around. Those little guys instantly lifted my spirits.</p>
<p>I want to make a note here that you should be fully aware of the reasons why you are committing to being single. You don&#8217;t have to justify them to anyone else but yourself, but you should know what they are. If you&#8217;ve been hurt or heartbroken, being single for a while might seem like a good idea but you shouldn&#8217;t live in the past. I encourage you to use this time to heal and move on. Whatever your reasons may be, keep them in mind for the day when they may no longer be relevant. Committing to a single life doesn&#8217;t mean that you have to turn away every Romeo. If you&#8217;re interested, don&#8217;t turn him down just on principal. Being single is meant to feel like freedom, not a prison, so learn to appreciate it.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/909/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/909/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/909/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/909/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/909/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/909/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/909/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/909/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/909/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/909/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/909/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/909/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/909/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/909/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=909&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://amylleblanc.wordpress.com/2011/12/04/a-singles-guide-to-happiness/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>517</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/71ebbc85cb2c13b0f92ca7f0e3cf79de?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">citizenfame</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://amylleblanc.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/sam_1480ee.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">SAM_1480ee</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>On Marines, equality, and my date to the Marine Corps Birthday Ball (Part 1)</title>
		<link>http://matthewphelps.wordpress.com/2011/12/01/on-marines-equality-and-my-date-to-the-marine-corps-birthday-ball-part-1/</link>
		<comments>http://matthewphelps.wordpress.com/2011/12/01/on-marines-equality-and-my-date-to-the-marine-corps-birthday-ball-part-1/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2011 03:13:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Matthew</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[DADT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Equality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Military]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[equality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LGBT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[USMC]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://matthewphelps.wordpress.com/?p=143</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Last year, around this time actually, the Commandant of the Marine Corps, General James Amos, came to the Marine Corps Recruit Depot in San Diego where I was working as a Series Commander for recruit training. I was in the middle of my second cycle in that position, and I was eager to hear what [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=143&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last year, around this time actually, the Commandant of the Marine Corps, General James Amos, came to the Marine Corps Recruit Depot in San Diego where I was working as a Series Commander for recruit training. I was in the middle of my second cycle in that position, and I was eager to hear what our Commandant had to say about the status of our Corps, from operations in Iraq and Afghanistan to personnel issues, particularly the policy known as &#8220;Don&#8217;t Ask, Don&#8217;t Tell.&#8221; I had been following the news on DADT closely for a year, for what are now obvious reasons. Gen Amos had recently testified before Congress that the existing policy was working fine and he was not inclined to repeal the existing policy while Marines were engaged in combat operations on two fronts. The results of the Comprehensive Review Working Group had been compiled and released, and the Marines were clearly the most resistant to changing the 18 year-old policy.</p>
<p><span id="more-143"></span></p>
<p>The general opened the session by introducing his wife, who was traveling with him. He said that he wouldn&#8217;t be where he was today without her many years of sacrifice and support. I honestly have no idea what he said after that. I was overcome by the contradiction between that statement and his testimony on keeping DADT in place and spent the next twenty minutes alternating between finding the appropriate wording for asking the Commandant a question and convincing myself that I should just keep my mouth shut. Anyone who knows me also knows that once an idea enters my head, there&#8217;s really only one way things can go&#8211;I am, after all, a Marine.</p>
<p>I waited for the questions to begin, raised my hand, and was handed a microphone. &#8220;Good morning, General. My name is Captain Matthew Phelps, I&#8217;m a Series Commander with India Company, 3rd Recruit Training Battalion. Sir, in light of the recent issue of the proposed repeal of &#8216;Don&#8217;t Ask, Don&#8217;t Tell&#8217;, can you tell us how, as leaders, we can reconcile the conflict between stressing the importance of family support for our Marines and denying our gay and lesbian Marines even the opportunity to have a family?&#8221; He responded as one might expect a man in his position to respond: Congress had asked his opinion, he gave it, and there was nothing for us to discuss until they reached a decision. A few weeks later, Congress voted to repeal the law upon certification by the President, Secretary of Defense, and Chairman of the Joint Chiefs. On September 20, 2011, the law was finally repealed.</p>
<p>The stress of living under DADT is not something I can begin to describe. Whether you&#8217;re straight or gay, there is little that comes much more naturally than who you are attracted to. Whether you want it to be true or not, you still know, and you know that there&#8217;s no changing it. Now imagine that everything you know and love could disappear if anyone found out who you&#8217;re attracted to&#8211;even if you never acted on it. Imagine you could be fired and humiliated for it, or even go to jail. Imagine that all it has to take is a rumor or suspicion, and that an accusation from anyone could be devastating to your career. How would you deal with people you work with, who stand next to you in formation? How would you approach your job knowing that saying the wrong thing to the wrong person could provoke them to taking their suspicion to your commander?</p>
<p>Even now, as I learn to live without the stress of hiding my sexuality from my fellow Marines, I am realizing the sacrifices that gay, lesbian, and bisexual Marines have made since even before DADT was enacted. At certain points, it was everything I could do to keep from going insane. When I couldn&#8217;t stand it anymore, I searched for outlets to vent my frustration. Most often, these outlets came in the form of telling people what I could about what I was going through, confiding in friends and family, and trying to convey this frustration to the general public and anyone else who would listen, through carefully planned and worded essays, letters, and interviews.</p>
<p>I sent <a href="http://matthewphelps.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/repealing-dadt-op-ed.doc" target="_blank">this letter</a> to the <a href="http://www.marinecorpstimes.com/">Marine Corps Times</a> in response to a letter to the editor that appeared in the February 2, 2009 issue, but it was never published. In May 2010, I wrote <a href="http://www.sldn.org/blog/archives/stories-from-the-frontlines-an-active-duty-marine/" target="_blank">this letter</a> to President Obama as a part of the &#8220;Stories from the Frontlines&#8221; campaign by <a href="http://www.sldn.org" target="_blank">Servicemembers Legal Defense Network</a> but didn&#8217;t sign it, as doing so would have been a violation of DADT. I appeared as &#8220;Michael&#8221; on KABC-AM&#8217;s <a href="http://kabc.com/sectional.asp?id=38823" target="_blank">John Phillips Show</a> December 17, 2010 (just days before the vote in Congress to repeal the law) to discuss my personal experiences under DADT. I worked with SLDN on arranging interviews with other various outlets and spoke with producers of some of the shows. As repeal approached this past summer, I was interviewed by Chris Heath of GQ Magazine for &#8220;<a href="http://www.gq.com/news-politics/big-issues/201109/dont-ask-dont-tell-gay-soldiers-military" target="_blank">Tell: An Intimate History of Gay Men in the Military</a>&#8220;, where I was quoted as &#8220;Marines #2&#8243;. For the actual repeal day, I spoke to a few news outlets in San Diego and appeared again as &#8220;Michael&#8221; in interviews on the local Fox, NBC, and CBS affiliates (links <a href="http://www.fox5sandiego.com/videogallery/64876359/News/Don-t-Ask-Don-t-Tell-Policy-Runs-Out#gl-0" target="_blank">here</a>, <a href="http://www.cbs8.com/story/15510096/why-a-local-gay-marine-says-he-still-wont-tell?autoStart=true&amp;topVideoCatNo=default&amp;clipId=6272290#.TnpbJZornQc.facebook" target="_blank">here</a>, and <a href="http://www.nbcsandiego.com/video/#!/on-air/as-seen-on/Controversial-Military-Law-Ends/130173448" target="_blank">here</a>). I returned to the John Phillips Show (this time as &#8220;Matthew&#8221;) again on October 12. While attending the <a href="http://outserve.org/summit/" target="_blank">2011 OutServe Leadership Summit</a> in Las Vegas, I did interviews for <a href="http://www.frontiersla.com/News/Context/Story.aspx?ID=1556653" target="_blank">this article in Frontiers</a> magazine and <a href="http://www.spiegel.de/politik/ausland/0,1518,792134,00.html" target="_blank">this one in Der Spiegel</a>, a German news magazine. Throughout all of this I became increasingly involved with SLDN, <a href="http://www.outserve.org" target="_blank">OutServe</a>, and the <a href="http://militaryacceptanceproject.org/" target="_blank">Military Acceptance Project</a>, who awarded me one of the first <a href="http://militaryacceptanceproject.org/Salute.html" target="_blank">MAP Salute awards</a>.</p>
<p>Despite all of this work with the media, I always obscured my identity not only for the sake of anonymity under the law, but also for the sake of avoiding the attention being so vocal could have brought on me and my Marines. While there was a part of me dying to just let people know and get it over with, I didn&#8217;t want my Marines to find out I was gay from newspaper headlines, and I didn&#8217;t want to give the impression that I was seeking publicity. Speaking to the press was not about recognition for myself, it was about providing a voice to those who were most impacted by DADT but weren&#8217;t being heard in the debates. It was never about me, it was about all of us. I was in a position where I felt I could speak safely and I did. As a Marine, it is my duty to defend those who cannot defend themselves, and I therefore had no choice but to seek and seize opportunities to do so.</p>
<p>All of the work I and countless others did had paid off and the law was history, but although that chapter was closed and that most difficult time was behind us, a new chapter was beginning. I was among the many people who thought it would be easier with DADT behind us, and in many ways it has been. Whereas I used to get frustrated trying to figure out how to answer questions about my personal life without being specific in referring to dates&#8217; and boyfriends&#8217; names, or even clubs and neighborhoods, I can just be honest. [Despite repeal opponents' insistence that sexuality doesn't come up in day-to-day military life, I would invite any of them to come with me to work and see that the opposite is true. Not a day has gone by since repeal when it hasn't come up in some way or another.] My entire chain of command knows and has been supportive. Contrary to what you may be thinking, this is where things get tough.</p>
<p><a title="On Marines, equality, and my date to the Marine Corps Birthday Ball (Part 2)" href="http://matthewphelps.wordpress.com/2011/12/02/on-marines-equality-and-my-date-to-the-marine-corps-birthday-ball-part-2/">Continued in Part 2</a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/143/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/143/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/143/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/143/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/143/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/143/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/143/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/143/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/143/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/143/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/143/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/143/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/143/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/143/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=143&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://matthewphelps.wordpress.com/2011/12/01/on-marines-equality-and-my-date-to-the-marine-corps-birthday-ball-part-1/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>170</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/4b003bb052a98d195425fefa4dfabf34?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F0.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">matthewphelps</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>4 Cool Looks That Distress Me</title>
		<link>http://topiclessbar.wordpress.com/2011/11/27/4-cool-looks-that-distress-me/</link>
		<comments>http://topiclessbar.wordpress.com/2011/11/27/4-cool-looks-that-distress-me/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2011 08:33:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>topiclessbar</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Korea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dressing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ear hoodie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fashion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[funny]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[glasses no lenses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[musings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[my life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[random]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shazaam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[underoos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vest coat]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://topiclessbar.wordpress.com/?p=797</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Fashion baffles me.  I don’t get it at all and I never will.  People say that fashion is a form of self-expression.  If that’s true, I’ve basically been stuck in a stutter every since my parents stopped dressing me.  I wonder what my clothes say about me?  No I don’t.  I know what they say [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=797&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://topiclessbar.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/ear-hoodie-kid2.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-802" title="ear hoodie kid" src="http://topiclessbar.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/ear-hoodie-kid2.jpg" alt="" width="140" height="175" /></a>Fashion baffles me.  I don’t get it at all and I never will.  People say that fashion is a form of self-expression.  If that’s true, I’ve basically been stuck in a stutter every since my parents stopped dressing me.  I wonder what my clothes say about me?  No I don’t.  I know what they say about me.  They say, “This guy buys all his clothes at Uni Qlo.”  Or they say, “This guy doesn’t wear clothes because he enjoys them.  He wears clothes because he has to.”</p>
<p>Not that I want to be naked or anything.  I’m just saying, if society didn’t expect me to wear a shirt and jeans, as opposed to, I don’t know, some Underoos, I’d probably be at the bar looking like Shazam.</p>
<p>Here in Korea, which, I’m told, is “fashion forward,” I get to see a lot of different looks.  I won’t lie, I’m often impressed<br />
by how well the Koreans and the ex-pat teachers dress.  But once in awhile I see things and I think, “Hmm.  I couldn’t do that.”  It isn’t that these things are bad, per say, they just aren’t possibilities for me, for a variety of reasons.  So here, directly below, are four things I’ve seen recently that I don’t understand.</p>
<p><a href="http://topiclessbar.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/shazam-underoos1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-thumbnail wp-image-803" title="shazam underoos" src="http://topiclessbar.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/shazam-underoos1.jpg?w=150&#038;h=150" alt="" width="150" height="150" /></a></p>
<p>Exhibit A: Coat with No Sleeves</p>
<p>It’s cold outside.  Real cold.  You put on your coat to warm up.  But then you realize that your coat has no sleeves.  Your <a href="http://topiclessbar.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/coat-vest.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-804" title="coat vest" src="http://topiclessbar.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/coat-vest.jpg" alt="" width="150" height="150" /></a>arms are still exposed to the bitter cold.  What kind of loopy coat is this?  Is this some sort of lame joke, like the solar powered flashlight or the book on how to read?  How can a coat have no sleeves?  That’s like buying deodorant that smells like B.O.!</p>
<p>Okay, in all seriousness, the sleeveless coat is kind of cool looking.  If I had muscles, maybe I would wear a vest coat.  Scratch that.  As cool as it looks, the practical aspect of the sleeveless coat is too much for me to handle.  A coat has a specific purpose, which is to keep me warm.  And since I don’t have muscles to help with that, I need sleeves.</p>
<p>Exhibit B: Headphones around the neck</p>
<p><a href="http://topiclessbar.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/headphones.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-806" title="headphones" src="http://topiclessbar.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/headphones.jpg?w=119&#038;h=150" alt="" width="119" height="150" /></a>I like the look of the sleeveless coat (which some people might call a “vest”); on the contrary, I feel wearing headphones around your neck while in a social setting makes you look like a douche bag.  I don’t know why…they’re just headphones…but damn, man, why are they around your neck?  What are you, a DJ?  Go play some techno then, and stop hitting on the cute girls in the bar.  To me, wearing headphones around the neck is as obnoxious as some dude in a band wearing his guitar around his shoulder all night.  Listen, DJ Shadow, get your giant headphones off your neck before they give you scoliosis.  Cause you’re annoying me.</p>
<p>Exhibit C: Glasses with no lenses (or glasses with plastic lenses)</p>
<p><a href="http://topiclessbar.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/glasses-no-lenses.jpg"><img class="alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-807" title="glasses no lenses" src="http://topiclessbar.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/glasses-no-lenses.jpg?w=112&#038;h=150" alt="" width="112" height="150" /></a>Wearing glasses with no lenses reminds me of that episode of Seinfeld where Costanza pretended he was wheelchair bound so people would be nicer to him.  Glasses make a person look smarter, and glasses can be sexy.  But the thing is, you actually have to NEED glasses for these things to be true.  Wearing glasses frames alone doesn’t cut it.  You must deserve to wear glasses.  Personally, I think it’s pretty interesting when someone has a cast on his arm.  You don’t see me walking around with some fake cast, do you?  No, that would be ridiculous.  Only people with broken bones get to wear casts.  And only people with vision problems should get to wear glasses.  That’s the way God intended it when he made vision problems and glasses.</p>
<p>Exhibit D: Ear Hoodie<br />
<a href="http://topiclessbar.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/ear-hoodie-three.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-809" title="ear hoodie three" src="http://topiclessbar.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/ear-hoodie-three.jpg?w=300&#038;h=213" alt="" width="300" height="213" /></a>Now, this isn’t something a guy would wear anyhow, although it would be hilarious if I started showing up places with the “ear hoodie” on.  The “ear hoodie” is more of a kid thing – my girl students at school wear them.  It’s not just for Halloween or something; they wear them daily.  Is it adorable?  Absolutely, 100% yes.  However, like Underoos, one can reach an age where wearing the “ear hoodie” becomes creepy.  You know how you have to be 18 to smoke?  Well, there should be a law saying only people under 14 can purchase the “ear hoodie.”  They should check IDs.  “I’m sorry, miss, but I’m going to need to see some identification.  Oh, you’re 17…under law I can’t allow you to purchase this item.”  And if you’re dating a Korean girl and she wears the “ear hoodie,” you really should be ashamed of yourself.  It’s questionable to want to dress your Korean girlfriend up in a school girl uniform; the “ear hoodie” is totally over the line.  If you want your girlfriend to have teddy bear ears on her head, you’re a disgusting Westerner.  Remember, she never would’ve dated you in the first place if you didn’t have those glasses and the headphones around your neck.</p>
<p>Hmm, maybe this post is getting a bit mean.  It’s further proof that fashion brings out the worst in me.  If you wear any of these things, I still love you.  All I ask in return is that you love me, and my Uni Qlo sweater vests.</p>
<p>*</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/797/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/797/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/797/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/797/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/797/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/797/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/797/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/797/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/797/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/797/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/797/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/797/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/797/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/797/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=797&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://topiclessbar.wordpress.com/2011/11/27/4-cool-looks-that-distress-me/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>528</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/bb7b6ed279ee622a9edae0f4c5a5cbad?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">topiclessbar</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://topiclessbar.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/ear-hoodie-kid2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ear hoodie kid</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://topiclessbar.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/shazam-underoos1.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">shazam underoos</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://topiclessbar.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/coat-vest.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">coat vest</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://topiclessbar.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/headphones.jpg?w=119" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">headphones</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://topiclessbar.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/glasses-no-lenses.jpg?w=112" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">glasses no lenses</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://topiclessbar.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/ear-hoodie-three.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ear hoodie three</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Faces Tell Stories</title>
		<link>http://gmbakash.wordpress.com/2011/10/29/faces-tell-stories/</link>
		<comments>http://gmbakash.wordpress.com/2011/10/29/faces-tell-stories/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2011 04:39:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Gmb Akash</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[akash]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[channel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Color]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[colour photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dhaka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[discrimination]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gmb Akash]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gmbakash]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hard-life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[learning about portrait]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life in port]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Light]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photographers in Dhaka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Portrait]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[portraits photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reuse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ship breaking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shipyard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[south asia]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://gmbakash.wordpress.com/?p=425</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[“Among all &#8211; Human faces are most attractive to me. Every face bears a story. Photographers reveal the undiscovered story through the lens. Faces tell stories, tell the situation of the person, and tell the story of the place the person lives in. Wherever I go I always come across to faces those are different, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=425&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;"><strong><em>“Among all &#8211; Human faces are most attractive to me. Every face bears a story. Photographers reveal the undiscovered story through the lens. Faces tell stories, tell the situation of the person, and tell the story of the place the person lives in. Wherever I go I always come across to faces those are different, &amp; eventually tried to find characteristic of the community; every place has its own perception, story &amp; smell, a person bears these things in his/her appeal. I search for story behind the face, so faces are incredible to me. Through out searching the portrait we could find strange stories of lives of people of different places that we never recognize before. Here I am going to share my experiences &amp; opinion during the journey of finding unnoticed faces</em>” </strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>- Gmb Akash</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/portrait-7.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-426" title="portrait (7)" src="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/portrait-7.jpg" alt="" width="450" height="645" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><em>© GMB Akash / <a href="http://www.gmb-akash.com%20/" target="_blank">www.gmb-akash.com</a></em></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/portrait-3.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-427" title="portrait (3)" src="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/portrait-3.jpg" alt="" width="450" height="645" /></a><em>© GMB Akash / <a href="http://www.gmb-akash.com%20/" target="_blank">www.gmb-akash.com</a></em></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/new011.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-466" title="new01" src="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/new011.jpg" alt="" width="450" height="645" /></a><em>© GMB Akash / <a href="http://www.gmb-akash.com%20/" target="_blank">www.gmb-akash.com</a></em></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/new02.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-467" title="new02" src="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/new02.jpg" alt="" width="450" height="645" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><em>© GMB Akash / <a href="http://www.gmb-akash.com%20/" target="_blank">www.gmb-akash.com</a></em></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">I search for getting an interesting character, a face that is usually undiscoverable. I searches face in the middle of crowd. My first prior attention is the selection of the person, choosing the right character. Before I take any portrait I try to be familiar with the person. I talk to hem and try to build a relationship with the person I will photograph. I give them time to be normal in front of my camera. I introduce myself to them. When the person gives his/her most natural expression to me I take out my camera &amp; start shooting. I believe it is the strongest factor which I practice so far to get a close snap of a human soul.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/portrait-1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-428" title="portrait (1)" src="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/portrait-1.jpg" alt="" width="450" height="313" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><em>© GMB Akash / <a href="http://www.gmb-akash.com%20/" target="_blank">www.gmb-akash.com</a></em></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/new03.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-468" title="new03" src="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/new03.jpg" alt="" width="450" height="313" /></a><em>© GMB Akash / <a href="http://www.gmb-akash.com%20/" target="_blank">www.gmb-akash.com</a></em></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/new04.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-469" title="new04" src="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/new04.jpg" alt="" width="450" height="645" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><em>© GMB Akash / <a href="http://www.gmb-akash.com%20/" target="_blank">www.gmb-akash.com</a></em></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/new05.jpg"><br />
</a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">For me light is the most important element for getting an excellent portrait. I try to use different type of light; I try to shoot in different time of the day to get different colour and mode of light. Every light has its own appeal for creating different portraits of an individual.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/portrait-9.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-429" title="portrait (9)" src="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/portrait-9.jpg" alt="" width="450" height="313" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><em>© GMB Akash / <a href="http://www.gmb-akash.com%20/" target="_blank">www.gmb-akash.com</a></em></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/portrait-8.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-430" title="portrait (8)" src="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/portrait-8.jpg" alt="" width="450" height="313" /></a><em></em></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><em>© GMB Akash / <a href="http://www.gmb-akash.com%20/" target="_blank">www.gmb-akash.com</a></em></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">Technically I use 35mm (f 1.4), 24-70 mm (2.8) lenses. But I take portrait with all kind of lenses I have. Truly to say I do not care about my equipments very much. For me the most important is &#8211; the person. Some times I also use very open aperture like 1.4 to get very low depth of field. So my eyes only go to my subject. As in Some cases the surrounding environment is very important, so in that time I use aperture 8 to get all the elements in focus. But I do not like using very wide angel lens and I do not like a lot of distortion on the photo. I saw many people use wide angel lens for most of their works. If you use very wide thing, the picture look interesting because of the distortion. But in my opinion the picture looks like it has taken by the wide angel lens not by a photographer. So I don’t use too much wide angle. And thus I try to make my images clean and direct.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/portrait-10.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-431" title="portrait (10)" src="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/portrait-10.jpg" alt="" width="450" height="313" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><em>© GMB Akash / <a href="http://www.gmb-akash.com%20/" target="_blank">www.gmb-akash.com</a></em></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/portrait-11.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-432" title="portrait (11)" src="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/portrait-11.jpg" alt="" width="450" height="313" /></a><em></em><em>© GMB Akash / <a href="http://www.gmb-akash.com%20/" target="_blank">www.gmb-akash.com</a></em></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><em><a href="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/new07.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-472" title="new07" src="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/new07.jpg" alt="" width="450" height="645" /></a></em></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><em>© GMB Akash / <a href="http://www.gmb-akash.com%20/" target="_blank">www.gmb-akash.com</a></em></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">I have strong affection for color. I am a color photographer &amp; I believe color photography is more challenging &amp; complicated. When I can meet the challenge I feel relieved. I am always very careful for using light and color. I love shooting in the early morning and late afternoon. But while I take portrait in the mid day I try to shoot them in the shadow, indoor or under flat light. It creates mystical environment.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/portrait-6.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-433" title="portrait (6)" src="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/portrait-6.jpg" alt="" width="450" height="313" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><em>© GMB Akash / <a href="http://www.gmb-akash.com%20/" target="_blank">www.gmb-akash.com</a></em></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/new09.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-477" title="new09" src="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/new09.jpg" alt="" width="450" height="313" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><em>© GMB Akash / <a href="http://www.gmb-akash.com%20/" target="_blank">www.gmb-akash.com</a></em></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/news.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-478" title="news" src="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/news.jpg" alt="" width="450" height="313" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><em>© GMB Akash / <a href="http://www.gmb-akash.com%20/" target="_blank">www.gmb-akash.com</a></em></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><em></em><a href="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/new04.jpg"><img title="new04" src="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/new04.jpg?w=450&#038;h=645" alt="" width="450" height="645" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><em>© GMB Akash / <a href="http://www.gmb-akash.com%20/" target="_blank">www.gmb-akash.com</a></em></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/new06.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-473" title="new06" src="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/new06.jpg" alt="" width="450" height="645" /></a><em>© GMB Akash / <a href="http://www.gmb-akash.com%20/" target="_blank">www.gmb-akash.com</a></em></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">I try to use very simple background while I am taking close up portrait, so that the background might not disturb the subject and I try to use lot of &#8211; window soft light. Eyes have significance to me. One of the most important things in my images is eyes of the person. Eyes tell the story of that person. Eyes tell the unseen background of the person which I always hunt to discover.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/portrait-13.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-434" title="portrait (13)" src="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/portrait-13.jpg" alt="" width="450" height="313" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><em>© GMB Akash / <a href="http://www.gmb-akash.com%20/" target="_blank">www.gmb-akash.com</a></em></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/new081.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-474" title="new08" src="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/new081.jpg" alt="" width="450" height="645" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><em>© GMB Akash / <a href="http://www.gmb-akash.com%20/" target="_blank">www.gmb-akash.com</a></em></p>
<p>- For me the most prior factor is the character of my portrait. The light, color, eyes &amp; the person must have to be blend with me. I align four factors together for taking a special portrait they are – the person, the light, eyes &amp; color.</p>
<p>- Attention is the most hidden factor to get a good portrait. The person need to be familiar with you &amp; the camera, it will be your prior duty to make the person natural as well comfortable for getting a best shot.</p>
<p>- Several rules applied by photographers for getting experimental portraits<strong>. </strong>Every photographer has his/her own style of taking portrait<strong>.</strong> Often the most remarkable portraits are those that break all the rules, so it’s important to create your own rules to get a master copy which might never done by some one before.</p>
<p>-  Expression indicating the direction of the person’s eyes which can impact an image astonishingly. For me it’s important to observe the right moment of the direction of eyes.</p>
<p>- For creating interesting images you need to give trial, for creating interesting placement of your subject. After Creative thinking, creative placement can sometimes create out of the ordinary images.</p>
<p>- There are almost unlimited possibilities when it comes to use light in portraits. Input of light could make a portrait more or less powerful, as well side lighting, back lighting, silhouetting can spot specific features.</p>
<p>- Never fail to align your mind, eyes &amp; lens together to find the inner beauty of the portrait.</p>
<p><a href="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/portrait-2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-435" title="portrait (2)" src="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/portrait-2.jpg" alt="" width="450" height="645" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><em></em><em>© GMB Akash / <a href="http://www.gmb-akash.com%20/" target="_blank">www.gmb-akash.com</a></em></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/portrait-4.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-436" title="portrait (4)" src="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/portrait-4.jpg" alt="" width="450" height="313" /></a><em></em></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><em></em><em>© GMB Akash / <a href="http://www.gmb-akash.com%20/" target="_blank">www.gmb-akash.com</a></em></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/new051.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-475" title="new05" src="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/new051.jpg" alt="" width="450" height="313" /></a><em>© GMB Akash / <a href="http://www.gmb-akash.com%20/" target="_blank">www.gmb-akash.com</a></em></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong><em>“Any Book or text or any experience sharing can not demonstrate “Portraits” practically. Pick your camera explores faces to get a good portrait. &amp; you are welcome if my single practical example or feedback could uphold your knowledge”</em></strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong><em> - </em>Gmb Akash</strong></p>
<p><em></em><a href="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/new04.jpg"><br />
</a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/425/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/425/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/425/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/425/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/425/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/425/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/425/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/425/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/425/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/425/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/425/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/425/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/425/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/425/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=425&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://gmbakash.wordpress.com/2011/10/29/faces-tell-stories/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>224</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/bd304d37acabe39b48231f64a398ac74?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">G.M.B.Akash</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/portrait-7.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">portrait (7)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/portrait-3.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">portrait (3)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/new011.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">new01</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/new02.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">new02</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/portrait-1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">portrait (1)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/new03.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">new03</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/new04.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">new04</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/portrait-9.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">portrait (9)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/portrait-8.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">portrait (8)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/portrait-10.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">portrait (10)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/portrait-11.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">portrait (11)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/new07.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">new07</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/portrait-6.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">portrait (6)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/new09.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">new09</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/news.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">news</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/new04.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">new04</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/new06.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">new06</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/portrait-13.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">portrait (13)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/new081.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">new08</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/portrait-2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">portrait (2)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/portrait-4.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">portrait (4)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/new051.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">new05</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>