<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2012 20:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Shedding Skin</title>
		<link>http://glassrabbitbones.wordpress.com/2012/12/19/shedding-skin/</link>
		<comments>http://glassrabbitbones.wordpress.com/2012/12/19/shedding-skin/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2012 14:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>glassrabbitbone</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Entries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anorexia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bulimia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cutting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-harm]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://glassrabbitbones.wordpress.com/?p=8</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s hard to believe, in the state I am now, that there was ever a time when I was happy with myself. You see, I&#8217;ve never been thin—I&#8217;ve always, always been the fat girl, and though no one ever said anything, I could tell.  I could tell when all my friends went clothes shopping without me, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=8&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s hard to believe, in the state I am now, that there was ever a time when I was happy with myself.</p>
<p>You see, I&#8217;ve never been thin—I&#8217;ve always, <em>always</em> been the fat girl, and though no one ever <em>said</em> anything, I could tell.  I could tell when all my friends went clothes shopping without me, when no one asked me to homecoming, when my horse riding instructor praised the other girls and told me to work harder.  Logic, of course, tells me: it was because I was fat.  I lived with seething hatred of this body for years, but only recently did this hatred manifest itself.</p>
<p>At 175 pounds and 5&#8217;5&#8221;, I was, less than a year ago, just beginning to fall into the pit.  One night I dragged a shaving razor across my thigh and watched as the bad feelings poured out.  I put a bandage on it and swore to never touch a blade again.  But the next night I did it again and soon there was an arsenal in my bedside drawer and red zebra stripes covering my hips and wrists.</p>
<p>It was around this time, too, that I decided I needed to rid myself of my second skin.  I was huge, fatter than fat, disgusting, a whale.  At first I tried something called intermittent fasting, which involved fasting for 24 hours at least 2 times a week.  The other days I was allowed to eat normally.  The idea was that it would cut calories effortlessly, while the pattern of fasting would rev up my metabolism.</p>
<p>While intermittent fasting is a legitimate method for losing weight, I couldn&#8217;t imagine that my parents would approve of me refusing food 2-3 days out of the week.  Thus to complete my fasts, I began coming up with all manner of crazy ways to hide that I was not eating.  I woke up early to avoid my parents&#8217; prying eyes as I had my breakfast of green tea.  When they got suspicious, I crumbled bits of toast onto a plate and left it out on the counter before hiding the uneaten evidence in the trash.  I made excuses to my friends at lunch time and hoarded sandwiches in my room until I could eat them again, though soon I began throwing out the whole brown bag.  Later on, I mastered the art of spitting my food into a napkin, and once chewed and spit two whole slices of toast, unnoticed and without swallowing a bite, right in front of my father.</p>
<p>As the pounds began to drop off, I became more obsessed, restricting even on my non-fasting days.  By spring I was eating 300-600 calories a day and beating my ass on the treadmill to make up for mistakes.  At 150 pounds, people began to notice.  &#8221;Oh, you look like you&#8217;ve lost weight!&#8221; they&#8217;d say happily, never suspecting something could be wrong.  My friends all paid more attention to me.  When I asked a boy to prom, he happily accepted.  And my riding instructor couldn&#8217;t stop telling me how much better I looked (skinnier girls look more elegant on horses).  I got nothing but positive feedback and I was over the moon.  After all, for someone as fat as I was, losing weight could only be a good thing.  But I still wasn&#8217;t skinny enough. No, not even close.</p>
<p>By summer I was falling victim to binges, and my self-hatred grew even more vehement.  As much as I jammed my fingers down my throat, I could not bring my mistakes back up.  After nearly slitting my throat one night, I finally told my mother that her daughter sliced up her skin.  I didn&#8217;t tell her that I wanted to die, nor that my nightmares consisted of fat-laden food that I could not stop eating.  No, I told her about the cutting, and she was kind and supportive and everything a mother should be.  And so I stopped cutting.  I found peace and I stopped starving.  With the pressure of senior year gone, something shifted and I was, for that blessed three-month period, happy.  At least I think I was.</p>
<p>And here I am now, in college—an art major, no less—with dreams of becoming a medical illustrator.  After moving into the dorms, it didn&#8217;t take long for the blades to make their way back into my drawer.  My weight has settled at 145; though this is the lowest I&#8217;ve ever been and is considered a &#8220;healthy weight,&#8221; I cannot be satisfied with it.  With every bite I put in my mouth, I can feel myself losing control.  There is too much here for me to handle, and I need the comfort of starvation again.  It&#8217;s disgusting, I know, and it&#8217;s wrong and no one—none of you—should ever think this way, but I&#8217;ve been eating less and less these past few weeks and making excuses again and I can feel the cold fingers of these thoughts wrap themselves around me, pulling me back into the arms of hunger.</p>
<p>This goes beyond wanting to be skinny.  I have pegged food as the enemy, you see, and I am finding that I can only feel sane when I do not eat.  I am strong when I starve.  I am powerful, I am in control.  I can feel yesterday&#8217;s mistakes and poisons clearing out of this disgusting body and soon, soon I will be clean and pure.</p>
<p>Call me insane.  But I <em>will</em> be thin.  I&#8217;ll be thin if it&#8217;s the last thing I do.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/8/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/8/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=8&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://glassrabbitbones.wordpress.com/2012/12/19/shedding-skin/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/270b5c8d554c544118d82ca5d5c365a8?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">glassrabbitbone</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>But He Can Always Speak</title>
		<link>http://asoulswalk.wordpress.com/2012/12/19/but-he-can-always-speak/</link>
		<comments>http://asoulswalk.wordpress.com/2012/12/19/but-he-can-always-speak/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2012 18:46:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Soul Walker</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[poetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bottom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Listening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Perspective]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Poem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Poetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reflections]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rising.]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://asoulswalk.wordpress.com/?p=1336</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[From here on the floor with the grains of the wood and the stains of blood and whiskey from here is where I rise. Splinters in the wood and scratches all around become the grain of life and so we find a path and pattern in the most unlikeliest of places&#8211; on this floor. There [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1336&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>From here<br />
on the floor<br />
with the grains of the wood<br />
and the stains of blood<br />
and whiskey<br />
from here is where I rise.</p>
<p>Splinters in the wood<br />
and scratches all around<br />
become the grain of life<br />
and so we find a path<br />
and pattern<br />
in the most unlikeliest of places&#8211;<br />
on this floor.</p>
<p>There are lines that speak of order<br />
even down so low as this<br />
and it is God&#8217;s sweet grace<br />
to open our eyes that we might see<br />
the lines beneath the whiskey<br />
and dirt<br />
and blood.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1336/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1336/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1336&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://asoulswalk.wordpress.com/2012/12/19/but-he-can-always-speak/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/baf4ad28fa0be9fc37a0b17a824da698?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">asoulwalker</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Corruption! It&#8217;s How We Roll!</title>
		<link>http://markingtimelivingwar.wordpress.com/2012/12/20/corruption-its-how-we-roll/</link>
		<comments>http://markingtimelivingwar.wordpress.com/2012/12/20/corruption-its-how-we-roll/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2012 13:38:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>docreedy</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Afghanistan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corruption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[daily life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GIRoA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[government effectiveness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vulnerability]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://markingtimelivingwar.wordpress.com/?p=251</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[So, yes, we get the idea that Afghanistan is kind of a corrupt place. But really, with the lawlessness and the massive rift between the political elite and everyone else, what else would we expect? I was part of a meeting that took place in a small village in Paktiya Province. It had been pre-arranged, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=251&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So, yes, we get the idea that Afghanistan is kind of a corrupt place. But really, with the lawlessness and the massive rift between the political elite and everyone else, what else would we expect?</p>
<p>I was part of a meeting that took place in a small village in Paktiya Province. It had been pre-arranged, so all of the village elders came out in force, as did every other male in the village, from age 5 to 85. The village was at the top of a small hill that had a cliff that overlooked the nearby river valley. In fact, it may have looked an awful lot like the village in the banner picture of this blog. As we walked up the goat-trails (easier said than done while in full body armor), the men laid out a giant cloth on the ground and a bunch of padded cushions that were upholstered in red fabric that read, “Japan!”</p>
<p>After the official meeting, we broke into small groups to just chat. I started talking with a man in his early 30s who complained bitterly of politicians doing nothing but hoarding all sorts of money for themselves, playing favorites with projects, and giving public jobs to their family members. Since there was an election coming up, I asked him why he didn’t run for office and try to change things.</p>
<p>He gave me a grin that was somehow proud and sheepish at the same time.</p>
<p>“Because I’d be even worse.”</p>
<p>I had to laugh and he laughed along with me.</p>
<p>Corruption not only happens, it’s expected. But why? Because power corrupts?</p>
<p>Well, partially. People are people, after all, whatever culture we may have been raised in. But there are some particularities of Afghanistan that make what we would call corruption a good idea.</p>
<p>First is the expectation of violence. When you’ve lived through 30 years of war and then combine that with a couple thousand years’ worth of empires marauding through your territory, stability is not exactly the status quo. You expect chaos. You develop a mentality of preparing for it. So to protect yourself and your family, you gather all the resources you can and hold onto them (not unlike zombie apocalypse preparedness). In other words, you become a hoarder par excellence.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://markingtimelivingwar.wordpress.com/?attachment_id=253" rel="attachment wp-att-253"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-253" title="Courtesy of A&amp;E's Show" alt="" src="http://markingtimelivingwar.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/hoarders.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>And if you happen to get into a lucrative position, you take advantage of that and get as much as you can, be it a well in your backyard built by the Americans or a new road to your village or a whole bunch of jobs for your family so you can collectively stockpile as much money as humanly possible before this government goes the way of all the ones before it.</p>
<p>There’s another element to this, though too. Across the Middle East and Central Asia, honor and shame play a major part in society. Sure, honor is important to us all, but in these areas, honor is much more tied up in the family than it is in the US or Europe.  If my brother or cousin or third cousin twice removed does something dishonorable, it doesn’t really reflect on me, but if I live in Afghanistan, my cousin’s shame is my shame. And shame isn’t just about being looked down on, but think Scarlet Letter levels of excommunication. If I am shamed, basic things like getting married, getting a job, etc. are jeopardized.</p>
<p>So to avoid situations like that, you work really hard to earn honor and prestige. Across the Mid East/Asia region there are various formal and informal honor codes that create systems for people to earn honor. Many are pretty similar across countries. Hospitality is a big element of them (to refuse it is to <em><strong>seriously</strong></em> insult your host). Another is protecting guests in your home as fiercely as if they were your family. A third is providing sanctuary, even to your worst enemy.</p>
<p>And charity is a big one (it&#8217;s actually a requirement in Islam). Charity is especially important if you are a powerful or wealthy person. If you have money (or tons of cropland or goats or whatever), you earn immense honor by sharing your wealth, most particularly with your extended family. It earns you loyalty, respect, prestige. It can make you into a Big Man/tribal leader/warlord/sheikh/chieftain/etc. It&#8217;s a pretty common pattern around the world. A leader is someone who shares his wealth.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://markingtimelivingwar.wordpress.com/?attachment_id=254" rel="attachment wp-att-254"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-254" title="&quot;I'd be worse&quot; Village" alt="" src="http://markingtimelivingwar.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/corruption-village.jpg?w=529&#038;h=396" width="529" height="396" /></a></p>
<p>It’s not so different in our culture, really. Every time I go to visit the undisputed matriarch of my family (my little Italian grandmother), she presses $20 into my hand. She has done so since before I can remember and it doesn’t matter that I’m now over 30 with an income that’s probably three times her retirement pay. I wouldn’t dream of refusing it. It’s what she does, a point of pride and, yes, honor. (Besides, if there’s any doubt as to where I get my stubbornness, let me assure you, it’s that side of the family.)</p>
<p>Where it becomes problematic in Afghanistan is when people who live by that ideal get into political power. Taking care of their extended family via what we would call favoritism and nepotism is, in their eyes, the right thing to do. You take care of your own. Period. It just happens that when you do that with public funds and positions, people tend to get a little persnickety about it. While admitting that they would do the exact same thing.</p>
<p>Don’t get me wrong, by no means does everyone do this. There are a <i>lot</i> of Afghans who believe the political system should be free of this kind of thing. They don’t play favorites, they don’t succumb to nepotism, they push hard for anti-corruption investigations and convictions. There just also happen to be a lot of people who have decided to do the best they can for themselves. And for those guys, when they help their people out, they consider it to be the smart, honorable, expected thing to do.</p>
<p>It only becomes “corruption” when you’re the one not getting a cut.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/251/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/251/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=251&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://markingtimelivingwar.wordpress.com/2012/12/20/corruption-its-how-we-roll/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>72</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/60a37fb41070185f13c1abcb21564742?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">docreedy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://markingtimelivingwar.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/hoarders.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Courtesy of A&#38;E&#039;s Show</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://markingtimelivingwar.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/corruption-village.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">&#34;I&#039;d be worse&#34; Village</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>You Don&#8217;t Have to Leave, But You Can&#8217;t Stay Here</title>
		<link>http://johnwegnerblog.wordpress.com/2012/12/20/you-dont-have-to-leave-but-you-cant-stay-here/</link>
		<comments>http://johnwegnerblog.wordpress.com/2012/12/20/you-dont-have-to-leave-but-you-cant-stay-here/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2012 15:20:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>John Wegner</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[college choice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parenting]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://johnwegnerblog.wordpress.com/?p=323</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Blogging, I told someone the other day, is a bit like controlled free-writing for me. In theory, there is a focus to each day&#8217;s post but I&#8217;m not holding myself to the same rigorous standard I might apply to academic writing. This approach lends itself to a wide-variety of posts&#8211;no one will ever accuse me [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=323&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Blogging, I told someone the other day, is a bit like controlled free-writing for me. In theory, there is a focus to each day&#8217;s post but I&#8217;m not holding myself to the same rigorous standard I might apply to academic writing. This approach lends itself to a wide-variety of posts&#8211;no one will ever accuse me of being an &#8220;educational&#8221; or &#8220;political&#8221; blog partly because each day&#8217;s post depends, in many respects, on what I read in the paper.</p>
<p>But today, I want to revisit yesterday&#8217;s post because I fear I might have sounded a little less than enthused about the place I work. Let me say categorically that ASU is a great university. I have colleagues who are some of the best teachers in the business. One of the most frustrating things for me to read are blanket attacks on college professors. My colleagues here, unlike faculty at large research universities, teach a full load, research in moderation, and serve both the campus and the community.</p>
<p>Put simply&#8211;they are some of the finest educators I know, dedicated to helping our students achieve success. We have undergraduate programs that are some of the finest in the nation. Our Physics, Biology, Chemistry, and Geo sciences students regularly participate in undergraduate research, get accepted to medical schools and graduate schools. I&#8217;m partial to our English department and the employability. Our students go to graduate school, teach, and, at times, become officers in the military. Our kids graduate, get jobs, and have some of the lowest student loan debt in the nation. I could go on and on.</p>
<p>But, as I noted yesterday, I still don&#8217;t want my son to go here.</p>
<p>When my wife and I had our first son, I told her my parenting model was Homer Simpson and that the key to great parenting was keeping our expectations low. Remember, I told her, the mind is powerful and we should encourage our kids to repress as many memories as possible.</p>
<p>Of course, the real goal of parenting is to create human beings who are better than you. We do that by giving them appropriate opportunities and steering them into making good choices. Sometimes we have to be surreptitious. And many times we have to let them fail. But most importantly, we have to let them be uncomfortable.</p>
<p>When my son goes off to college, I want him to live someplace where being the tall white kid isn&#8217;t the norm. I want him to live someplace where he doesn&#8217;t know anyone, where the couple living next door is the same gender, and the couple on the other side is multi-racial. And I want him to live someplace where the washing machine is across town and only works with quarters.</p>
<p>I love my son but I don&#8217;t want him to come home every weekend.</p>
<p>Most importantly, I want him to struggle with ideas independent of my wife and I. He needs to see and hear things outside the context of his comfort zone. Certainly, he&#8217;ll be home on the holidays, crashing on the couch, but when he does I&#8217;m hoping he&#8217;s different. He should see us as small town, backwards, and out of touch as the world of ideas and people opens up before him. I have faith he&#8217;ll eventually change perspectives and realize we aren&#8217;t quite as dumb as he thinks, but when he goes to his 10 year reunion, I hope people look at him and say, &#8220;you&#8217;re different.&#8221; That&#8217;s not a bad thing. (At my 10 year reunion, someone told me I talked different. I felt like saying, I&#8217;ve got a PhD in English. I damn well better sound different or I&#8217;ve wasted my money!).</p>
<p>I understand parents who want to keep their kids close. I&#8217;m sure they have the same hopes and dreams. We want our children to be happy and safe (and employed!). Many parents hope their children stay around and live near by. There&#8217;s something to be said for that. We live 7 hours from my wife&#8217;s parents and holidays are a pain. I know her brothers, sisters, and parents would love to see her and our children more often. My relatives live even farther way and I haven&#8217;t seen many of them for years.</p>
<p>And sometimes that&#8217;s the price we pay for sending our kids off into the world. Periodically, I&#8217;ll ask my students where they&#8217;ve traveled. I&#8217;ll have some military children who have been everywhere, a couple of folks who have, at least, crossed into Mexico (we are two hours from the border here), and I&#8217;ll have 5-10 kids who have never been outside Tom Green County. I realize sometimes this is economic, but not always. Usually, it&#8217;s a conscious decision by the parents who don&#8217;t see the need.</p>
<p>Our job as parents, though, isn&#8217;t to encourage our kids to stay around because we want to be near them. We aren&#8217;t supposed to try and turn them into a little us. Our job is to open the world and give them a chance to live in it. I would be thrilled if my kids move off, find love, and come back to San Angelo. But if they come back, they need to make that choice. This needs to be the place they want to live; not the place they have always lived.</p>
<p>The goals of education and the goals of parenting are often the same: we want smart, critical thinking kids, who can both follow direction but who are also capable of telling us how to improve those directions. We want, as the old adage goes, to teach our kids to fish instead of just giving them fish. These goals are long range and largely impossible to measure because they require pushing, pulling, getting out of the way, and, in general, making stuff up as we go along. They require help but they also require times when we don&#8217;t help. We can manufacture successes when necessary and allow failure when it&#8217;s appropriate.</p>
<p>And it also means, eventually, letting go and hoping nothing really bad happens. That is particularly true when our kids turn 18 and that&#8217;s what we hope to do as we encourage our son to choose a school where he can be un-comfortable so he can learn to think, live, love, and become himself.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/323/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/323/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=323&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://johnwegnerblog.wordpress.com/2012/12/20/you-dont-have-to-leave-but-you-cant-stay-here/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>41</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/aa7dc7d9a744a230446a2c2e85d364b3?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">wegnerjohn</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sticky Tahini Buns</title>
		<link>http://veggiezest.com/2012/12/19/sticky-tahini-buns/</link>
		<comments>http://veggiezest.com/2012/12/19/sticky-tahini-buns/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2012 13:44:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>veggiezest</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cookies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Desserts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[caramel sauce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cooking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dates]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[holiday recipe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[local]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sesame seeds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sticky buns]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tahini]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tahini buns]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://veggiezest.com/?p=1574</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This recipe is a variation of cinnamon rolls. You might think why do I need to make a variation of a classic recipe &#8211; the answer is because you must always try new things and new combinations. These buns are delicious and are a wonderful combination of tahini, dates and brown sugar. I have mostly [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1574&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://veggiezest.com/2012/12/19/sticky-tahini-buns/sticky-tahini-buns-01/" rel="attachment wp-att-1575"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-1575" alt="sticky tahini  buns " src="http://veggiezestdotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/sticky-tahini-buns-01.jpg?w=647&#038;h=1024" width="647" height="1024" /></a></p>
<p>This recipe is a variation of cinnamon rolls. You might think why do I need to make a variation of a classic recipe &#8211; the answer is because you must always try new things and new combinations. These buns are delicious and are a wonderful combination of tahini, dates and brown sugar.</p>
<p>I have mostly used tahini in savory combination but these buns are really delicious. The sticky topping adds oodles of flavor to these buns. It takes a little time and a little prep work to make these but the result is totally worth it. These buns are perfect for the holiday season &#8211; wrap them in a festive colors and shapes and gift them to your loved ones. Or warm up an individual bun and enjoy it with a warm cup of coffee for breakfast or in the evening.  Try something different this season!</p>
<p><a href="http://veggiezest.com/2012/12/19/sticky-tahini-buns/sticky-tahini-buns03/" rel="attachment wp-att-1578"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-1578" alt="sticky tahini  buns" src="http://veggiezestdotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/sticky-tahini-buns03.jpg?w=682&#038;h=1024" width="682" height="1024" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://veggiezest.com/2012/12/19/sticky-tahini-buns/sticky-tahini-buns-02/" rel="attachment wp-att-1579"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1579" alt="sticky tahini  buns " src="http://veggiezestdotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/sticky-tahini-buns-02.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://veggiezest.com/2012/12/19/sticky-tahini-buns/sticky-tahini-buns05/" rel="attachment wp-att-1580"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1580" alt="sticky tahini  buns" src="http://veggiezestdotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/sticky-tahini-buns05.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://veggiezest.com/2012/12/19/sticky-tahini-buns/sticky-tahini-buns04/" rel="attachment wp-att-1581"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1581" alt="sticky tahini  buns" src="http://veggiezestdotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/sticky-tahini-buns04.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p><span id="more-1574"></span></p>
<p><em>Serving 8 buns</em></p>
<p><em>Cooking time 1 hour plus rising time</em> for the dough</p>
<p><strong>Things you will need:</strong></p>
<p><em>For the dough</em></p>
<p>3 1/4 cups all purpose flour</p>
<p>2 tsp active dry yeast</p>
<p>2 tbsp sugar</p>
<p>1  egg, slightly beaten</p>
<p>1 cup milk</p>
<p>2 tbsp warm water (to dissolve the yeast)</p>
<p>2 tbsp butter, melted</p>
<ol>
<li>Activate dry yeast by dissolving it in warm water. Keep aside for 10  minutes till it starts getting bubbly.</li>
<li>In a large bow mix 3 cups flour and sugar.</li>
<li>In a separate bowl mix together milk, egg and butter.</li>
<li>Add dissolved and activated yeast to the flour mixture and start mixing with the help of a fork.</li>
<li>Slowly add the milk mixture to the flour. Switch to a wooden spoon or your hands and start mixing the flour and milk mixture to form a dough.</li>
<li>If you feel the dough is too sticky, add the reserved 1/4 cup flour and knead to form a clean dough. The dough should bounce back when you push it slightly with your finger.</li>
<li>Transfer the dough into a lightly oiled bowl (large enough for the dough to rise). Cover with a kitchen towel and place in a warm spot. Let the dough rest for 1 1/2 hours or till it doubles in size.</li>
</ol>
<p><em>For the filling</em></p>
<p>1/2 cup white sesame seeds</p>
<p>1/2 cup brown sesame seeds &#8211; (double the quantity of white sesame seeds if you cant find the dark ones)</p>
<p>1/3 cup sugar</p>
<p>Add all the ingredients in a blender and pulse till it turns into a coarse powder. Keep aside.</p>
<p><em>For the topping</em></p>
<p>1/2 cup chopped dates</p>
<p>1/4 cup sesame seeds, toasted</p>
<p>3/4 cup brown sugar</p>
<p>2 tbsp milk</p>
<p>vanilla extract</p>
<p>pinch of sea salt</p>
<ol>
<li>In a saucepan melt sugar on medium heat.</li>
<li>When the sugar caramelizes, turn the heat off.</li>
<li>Add milk and stir till it blends in.</li>
<li>Add all the other ingredients and mix to form a stick sauce. Keep aside.</li>
</ol>
<p><em>To put the buns together</em></p>
<p>1/4 cup tahini</p>
<ol>
<li>Roll out the dough into a 1/2 inch thick square &#8211; I used a floured square tray to guide me with shape.</li>
<li>Smear tahini evenly on the dough &#8211; this acts almost like a glue in keeping the filling together.</li>
<li>Sprinkle the ground sesame &amp; sugar mixture generously on the dough square leaving 1/2 inch on the corners.</li>
<li>Roll up tightly to form a log, pinch a seal the seam on the long side.</li>
<li>Cut into eight 1 1/2 inch thick slices. Place these slices on a baking sheet, cover with a kitchen towel and let rise for another hour.</li>
<li>Preheat the over at 375 F.</li>
<li>Smear the pre-baked buns generously with the sticky date mixture forcing some of the mixture to go between the buns. Reserve a few tablespoons of this mixture.</li>
<li>Bake the buns in the oven for about 50 minutes or till they turn golden.</li>
<li>Smear the reserved sticky topping as soon as you pull the buns out of the oven.</li>
<li>Cool on the grill, serve warm.</li>
</ol>
<p><em>Suggestions:</em></p>
<ol>
<li>As an option you can chop up some pistachios and mix it in the sticky sauce.</li>
<li>Sprinkle some toasted sesame seeds and a pinch of sea salt before serving.</li>
</ol>
<p><em>This recipe is loosely based on<span style="color:#993300;"><a href="http://whiteonricecouple.com/recipes/fig-pecan-sticky-buns/"><span style="color:#993300;"> Fig Pican Sticky Buns</span></a></span></em></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1574/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1574/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1574&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://veggiezest.com/2012/12/19/sticky-tahini-buns/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>42</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://veggiezestdotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/sticky-tahini-buns-01.jpg?w=94" />
		<media:content url="http://veggiezestdotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/sticky-tahini-buns-01.jpg?w=94" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sticky tahini  buns</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/b7d8d888ad970e5bf7b016ccc4841252?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">pallavigupta14</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://veggiezestdotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/sticky-tahini-buns-01.jpg?w=647" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sticky tahini  buns </media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://veggiezestdotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/sticky-tahini-buns03.jpg?w=682" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sticky tahini  buns</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://veggiezestdotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/sticky-tahini-buns-02.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sticky tahini  buns </media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://veggiezestdotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/sticky-tahini-buns05.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sticky tahini  buns</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://veggiezestdotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/sticky-tahini-buns04.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sticky tahini  buns</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Basement</title>
		<link>http://cabel.me/2012/12/19/the-basement/</link>
		<comments>http://cabel.me/2012/12/19/the-basement/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2012 19:02:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>cabel</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Exploration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[basement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exploration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[history]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spelunking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[urban]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cabel.me/?p=518</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Somewhere in Portland, there&#8217;s a very old building, and that very old building has a very, very old basement. An incredible basement, a video-game-level basement, a set-decorator&#8217;s dream basement. And when you walk past the janitors office, with the wonderfully decked halls&#8230; And tromp down a sunken hallway&#8230; You find a old room. Mostly empty, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=518&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Somewhere in Portland, there&#8217;s a very old building, and that very old building has a very, very old basement. An incredible basement, a video-game-level basement, a set-decorator&#8217;s dream basement.</p>
<p>And when you walk past the janitors office, with the wonderfully decked halls&#8230;</p>
<div class="photofull"><img class="alignleft  wp-image-562" alt="basement40" src="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement40.jpg?w=740&#038;h=986" width="740" height="986" /></div>
<p>And tromp down a sunken hallway&#8230;</p>
<div class="photofull"><img class="alignleft  wp-image-531" alt="basement09" src="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement09.jpg?w=740&#038;h=555" width="740" height="555" /></div>
<p>You find a old room. Mostly empty, dusty, and dead quiet.</p>
<div class="photofull"><img class="alignleft  wp-image-535" alt="basement13" src="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement13.jpg?w=740&#038;h=555" width="740" height="555" /></div>
<p>And then you start to look closer at the walls.</p>
<p>And you start to see things.</p>
<div class="photofull">
<p><img class="alignleft  wp-image-617" alt="basement43" src="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement43.jpg?w=740&#038;h=556" width="740" height="556" /></p>
<p><img class="alignleft  wp-image-533" alt="basement11" src="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement11.jpg?w=740&#038;h=986" width="740" height="986" /></p>
<p><img class="alignleft  wp-image-537" alt="basement15" src="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement15.jpg?w=740&#038;h=556" width="740" height="556" /></p>
<p><img class="alignleft  wp-image-536" alt="basement14" src="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement14.jpg?w=740&#038;h=556" width="740" height="556" /></p>
</div>
<p>(You see that Brown didn&#8217;t often pay his dime for coffee.)</p>
<div class="photofull"><img class="alignleft  wp-image-576" alt="P1020151" src="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/p1020151.jpg?w=740&#038;h=556" width="740" height="556" /></div>
<p>(You see that a lot of calculation was done right on the wall.)</p>
<div class="photofull"><img class="alignleft  wp-image-534" alt="basement12" src="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement12.jpg?w=740&#038;h=556" width="740" height="556" /></div>
<p>(You see that World War I was front and center on everyone&#8217;s mind.)</p>
<div class="photofull">
<p><img class="alignleft  wp-image-549" alt="basement27" src="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement27.jpg?w=740&#038;h=556" width="740" height="556" /></p>
</div>
<p>(You wonder what was being tallied, and if it was better to win or lose.)</p>
<div class="photofull"><img class="alignleft  wp-image-546" alt="basement24" src="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement24.jpg?w=740&#038;h=556" width="740" height="556" /></div>
<p>(And you learn the tongue-in-check &#8220;rules&#8221; of the room.)</p>
<div class="photofull"><img class="alignleft  wp-image-530" alt="basement08" src="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement08.jpg?w=740&#038;h=987" width="740" height="987" /></div>
<p>And eventually, you crawl behind a corner, and discover a bundle of conduit.</p>
<div class="photofull"><img class="alignleft  wp-image-538" alt="basement16" src="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement16.jpg?w=740&#038;h=556" width="740" height="556" /></div>
<p>Conduit for every major internet carrier you&#8217;ve ever heard of.</p>
<div class="photofull"><img class="alignleft  wp-image-544" alt="basement22" src="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement22.jpg?w=740&#038;h=556" width="740" height="556" /></div>
<p>Oh, right. You had almost forgotten.</p>
<p><strong>This building, this basement, is the major internet hub for the entire region.</strong></p>
<p>And a wall, where all this data enters the basement just as you did, you see them.</p>
<div class="photofull"><img class="alignleft  wp-image-525" alt="basement03" src="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement03.jpg?w=740&#038;h=556" width="740" height="556" /></div>
<p>Somehow, still surrounding these cutting-edge, fiber-optic links that burst through the wall, they&#8217;re frozen in time, looking at you.</p>
<p>How are they still there? My god, 2012. Could they even imagine?</p>
<div class="photofull">
<p><img class="alignleft  wp-image-559" alt="basement37" src="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement37.jpg?w=740&#038;h=556" width="740" height="556" /></p>
<p><img class="alignleft  wp-image-550" alt="basement28" src="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement28.jpg?w=740&#038;h=556" width="740" height="556" /></p>
<p><img class="alignleft  wp-image-557" alt="basement35" src="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement35.jpg?w=740&#038;h=556" width="740" height="556" /></p>
<p><img class="alignleft  wp-image-556" alt="basement34" src="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement34.jpg?w=740&#038;h=556" width="740" height="556" /></p>
<p><img class="alignleft  wp-image-554" alt="basement32" src="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement32.jpg?w=740&#038;h=556" width="740" height="556" /></p>
<p><img class="alignleft  wp-image-548" alt="basement26" src="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement26.jpg?w=740&#038;h=556" width="740" height="556" /></p>
<p><img class="alignleft  wp-image-547" alt="basement25" src="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement25.jpg?w=740&#038;h=556" width="740" height="556" /></p>
<p><img class="alignleft  wp-image-527" alt="basement05" src="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement05.jpg?w=740&#038;h=556" width="740" height="556" /></p>
<p><img class="alignleft  wp-image-526" alt="basement04" src="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement04.jpg?w=740&#038;h=987" width="740" height="987" /></p>
<p><img class="alignleft  wp-image-558" alt="basement36" src="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement36.jpg?w=740&#038;h=556" width="740" height="556" /></p>
</div>
<p>On the way out, you chat up a worker in the building.</p>
<p>And his story clicks it all into place.</p>
<div class="photofull"><img class="alignleft  wp-image-553" alt="basement31" src="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement31.jpg?w=740&#038;h=556" width="740" height="556" /></div>
<p>Turns out, he claims, <strong>&#8220;they used to print The Oregonian down here, way back.&#8221;</strong></p>
<p>The pressmen, one imagines, worked day and night down here, working the lumbering machines, spitting out another edition of the day&#8217;s business.</p>
<div class="photofull"><img class="alignleft  wp-image-552" alt="basement30" src="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement30.jpg?w=740&#038;h=556" width="740" height="556" /></div>
<p>And when something caught their eye? <strong>Out came the scissors and the paste.</strong></p>
<div class="photofull"><img class="alignleft  wp-image-612" alt="basement42" src="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement42.jpg?w=740&#038;h=986" width="740" height="986" /></div>
<p>It&#8217;s almost too perfect.</p>
<p>The roar of the presses that ruled these rooms has been replaced, just as we all suspected, with the calculated silence of the conduit that carries our data. This data, in fact. These very photos.</p>
<p>100 years from now, when another one of you goes spelunking around this basement, that data, those bits, today&#8217;s moments, will likely be long, long gone.</p>
<p>But the women on the wall might still be waiting.</p>
<div class="photofull"><img class="alignleft  wp-image-543" alt="basement21" src="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement21.jpg?w=740&#038;h=986" width="740" height="986" /></div>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=518&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://cabel.me/2012/12/19/the-basement/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>227</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/eeb374f5240e534c463fa8fcb1a28caa?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F2.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=R" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cabelsa</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement40.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">basement40</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement09.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">basement09</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement13.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">basement13</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement43.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">basement43</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement11.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">basement11</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement15.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">basement15</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement14.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">basement14</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/p1020151.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">P1020151</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement12.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">basement12</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement27.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">basement27</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement24.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">basement24</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement08.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">basement08</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement16.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">basement16</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement22.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">basement22</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement03.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">basement03</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement37.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">basement37</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement28.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">basement28</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement35.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">basement35</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement34.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">basement34</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement32.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">basement32</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement26.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">basement26</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement25.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">basement25</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement05.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">basement05</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement04.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">basement04</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement36.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">basement36</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement31.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">basement31</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement30.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">basement30</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement42.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">basement42</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cabeldotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/basement21.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">basement21</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Makes No Difference (Who You Are)</title>
		<link>http://eternalappetite.wordpress.com/2012/12/02/makes-no-difference-who-you-are/</link>
		<comments>http://eternalappetite.wordpress.com/2012/12/02/makes-no-difference-who-you-are/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2012 04:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>mjm</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Abortion Series]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://eternalappetite.wordpress.com/?p=3768</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[IV. The Real Boy In this my last entry in a series of commentary on abortion, I want to keep things somewhat more open-ended. I have spent time thus far in sub-issues within the debate which, while important, are mostly peripheral: the selection of terms, the coherence of compromise, and our approach to interlocutors. I [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3768&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://eternalappetite.wordpress.com/2012/12/02/makes-no-difference-who-you-are/screen-shot-2012-11-29-at-9-43-25-pm/" rel="attachment wp-att-3794"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-3794" alt="" src="http://eternalappetite.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/screen-shot-2012-11-29-at-9-43-25-pm.png?w=300&#038;h=278" height="278" width="300" /></a></p>
<p><strong>IV. The Real Boy</strong></p>
<p>In this my last entry in a series of commentary on abortion, I want to keep things somewhat more open-ended. I have spent time thus far in sub-issues within the debate which, while important, are mostly peripheral: the selection of terms, the coherence of compromise, and our approach to interlocutors. I have also suggested the utter necessity, for any traction, that the debate return to its center: the ontological fact of what the unborn being truly is. If I have lingered long at the outskirts while entreating a journey inward, it was with the aim of first clearing what pernicious overgrowth has too often obscured our path. Working through these concerns, I hope to have shown, does not require any profound agreement on the ultimate question: it takes merely a reflective pause, a critical eye to the mechanisms of another&#8217;s belief and one&#8217;s own, to sweep off the mounting detritus that tends to clog our gears and, for it, our vision.</p>
<p>The primacy of that final question, however, cannot be ignored. But while a shift (or perhaps simply a refinement) of concentration is crucial for the debate at large, I have come near the end of what I little I hoped to accomplish in these writings. To advance a positive argument from the roots up with anywhere near the appropriate rigor would be a task much desired, but fit for a space different from this. So instead I will offer one last thought experiment for parting consideration:</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">There is a humble old woodcarver whose friend generously gifts her a small supply of timber for Easter. In gracious spirits, she uses the material to craft two wooden dolls. One day not long after, a man comes by his shop claiming to be a magician. He notices the dolls and tells the carver that he will return at the end of the year, and if the carver has decided to keep them until then, they will be turned into real boys. Lest the poor shopkeeper have any doubts, the magician speaks a soft word to a wooden dove perched on the workbench nearby; the bird twitches its rigid wings, morphs and softens into feathery white, and flies out the window. &#8220;Year&#8217;s end,&#8221; says the magician, and he leaves.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">The carver is stunned. She had always wanted a child of his own, as it turns out. Though bewildered, she has been shown reason enough to believe that this magic is real, the magician&#8217;s word firm and certain. After the shock subsides she regathers her senses, however, and falls deep into thought. Blessing and wish-come-true though a child would be, having two would be a true challenge for a woman of her age and means. After many days of deliberation she decides that she will keep one doll. Having no preference, and wishing to effect none unwittingly, she chooses one at random and has the other destroyed. On Christmas Day the magician returns, casts a silent nod to the carver, and the doll comes to life. The old woman has a son, and the stranger departs.</p>
<p>Has the carver done something blameworthy? Immoral? Some days watching her son play she may wonder whether she should have given him the chance of a sibling. But surely she knew best the nature of her circumstances, and though by her decision another boy undoubtedly would have been, what was lost was, in effect, merely a dream; in substance, a block of wood.</p>
<p>I offer this story as a way to frame another, this one true to life. In August of last year a piece appeared in the <em>New York Times</em> called &#8220;The Two-Minus-One Pregnancy.&#8221; I encourage any who has not read it to do so <a title="The Two-Minus One Pregnancy" href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/08/14/magazine/the-two-minus-one-pregnancy.html?pagewanted=all" target="_blank">here</a> because it is a jolting read and I will not be able to recap it sufficiently. It follows the growing phenomenon of a practice self-described as &#8220;pregnancy reduction.&#8221; Women undergo this procedure to reduce their twin pregnancy to a &#8220;singleton.&#8221; In plain terms, a woman bearing twins decides to abort one and keep the other. Again, I recommend the full read because it has several details worth absorbing: the condition of anonymity on which these women give their testimonials (for fear of the &#8220;stigma&#8221;), <em>in vitro</em> mothers getting more than they bargained for, and decisions to reduce on the basis of sex.*</p>
<p>There are many things I could say about this story but of all those that struck me I would like to draw particular attention to one. As I read reactions to this piece (in the site comments and elsewhere) I began to notice a common preface: many commenters (though by no means all) would begin their remarks will something to the effect of &#8220;I am pro-choice, but . . . &#8221; and proceeded to register their unease or repulsion toward what they had read.</p>
<p>This response reminded me of another. In 2008 at my alma mater, a story broke that a student had been artificially inseminating herself, inducing abortions, and collecting the resultant blood to put on display for her senior art project. You can read more about it <a title="Aliza Shvarts" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yale_student_abortion_art_controversy" target="_blank">here</a>. The news ignited the campus with a firestorm of several weeks, and though the student was not without her defenders her project drew harsh criticism from both sides of the aisle. In the aftermath as conflicting reports arose it became increasingly less clear whether her claims were fact or performance-art fiction (she maintained their truth to the end). But whatever the case it matters not for my point, which is that many pro-choice people found her acts, or at least the idea of them, disturbing.</p>
<p>There are enough differences between these two stories that I do not mean to compare them beyond this shared moral instinct, which exists not only in an intended public spectacle like the abortion art project (which might be objected to merely for its inflammatory provocation of those who <em>do</em> believe lives are at stake), but even in response to a guarded private choice like pregnancy reduction. What accounts for this instinctive discomfort, or in some, even disgust?</p>
<p>With this I turn back to the tale of the carver. How you do feel about her decision? To those who find something deeply unsettling in the recounted stories of &#8220;pregnancy reduction&#8221;: Whether right or wrong, does the carver&#8217;s choice elicit the same response? If wrong, is it wrong in the same way?</p>
<p>Though I don&#8217;t want to presume, my expectation is that few who identify as pro-choice will find serious moral qualm in the carver&#8217;s decision, though a greater number will take issue with some form of pregnancy reduction. My question is why this should be the case. I imagine it might be objected that in attempting to set up this analogy I have hardly brought into equivalence many striking factors and have constructed a poor analogy for the experience of pregnancy. The old carver never carries her child, after all; the physical, mental, and emotional labors of pregnancy are never felt. Neither is there any period of natural gestation in which the dolls develop—the one she chooses to keep passes from wood to human child, fully formed, by instantaneous dint of magic. And the old carver had no ownership in establishing the initial potentiality of the children: though she was fully entitled to an out clause (so to speak), the conditions of the magician—in which mere inaction would result in two children—were put in place by no act of her will.</p>
<p>But imagine if her experience were (in some rough way) more like real pregnancy. The magician tells the carver if she wants the dolls to become children, she not only has to keep them for the next nine months, but keep them well polished. This begins with light touch-ups here and there, but the carver soon notices that the polish has begun to wear off more and more quickly. As time passes this rate of dissolution increases at a surprising rate until she can no longer afford to leave the dolls at the shop for any extended period of time and is forced to carry them wherever she goes. A few times in her care the dolls have even, strangely, burned her hand to the touch. In short, the process is more demanding, restricting, and time-consuming—occasionally painful. After some time under these conditions, or even presented upfront with the knowledge of what would be, would it be anything but <em>more</em> understandable if she should choose to keep only one, for all the same reasons she decided before, but here with the added hope of alleviating her current experience in whatever small way?</p>
<p>What is curious is that it is not the carver&#8217;s choice (in the tale&#8217;s original formation) that draws our discomfort—she who faces the easier path to her end and nevertheless &#8220;reduces&#8221; the potential outcome—but precisely the woman who <em>does</em> go through the pains of pregnancy, who has, in the I.V.F. cases especially, authored the situation in which she finds herself (even if she is surprised by the news of twins). Why then should any pro-choice advocate feel anything but utter sympathy with the woman&#8217;s decision to alleviate her pains and align her condition to her wishes? Why be opposed, when there is no moral content to the choice—when the unborn thing is no more a person than a block of wood? Less, even, for at least the carver&#8217;s doll was wanted property, a work of her hands and an object of care; Fetus No. 2 is an unwanted intrusion, a tumor in the strictest sense.</p>
<p>So whence comes this rejecting instinct? Does it balk at removing the <em>potentiality</em> of a sibling for the lasting child? Then our two responses should be the same. Is it because reducing the biological twin pregnancy is especially &#8220;unnatural&#8221; (more so than an ordinary abortion, at least) when all nature has to do is take it&#8217;s course—and the mother clearly <em>wants</em> children to some degree—while the carver&#8217;s whole operation rests on some mysterious magic? But what is the standard pro-choice account of respected human life but precisely some inscrutable magic—the passing at some mysterious stage from fetus to person, from termination being a thorough non-issue to suddenly and unquestionably a moral wrong the moment after? The &#8220;magic&#8221; of the magician is, in my invention, no less certain its potency, reliability, or finality; it is merely an alternative mechanism for the same outcome.</p>
<p>Does the mother bear some obligation to <em>both</em> potential children since her choices are responsible for their being in the first place (surprise though the number be)? Is it an insult to mothers who desperately wish for children to be blessed with the potential for two and to throw one away? Is it abusing a right whose victory was so hard-fought? Is it senseless when the woman will still be going through pregnancy anyway, and whatever physical alleviation the reduction might provide could only be a matter of degree and not of kind?</p>
<p>A perfect distillation of the operating principle appears in a telling quotation from the article itself (emphasis mine):</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><span style="color:#0000ff;">&#8220;Other doctors refuse to reduce below twins unless the pregnancy presents unusual medical concerns. Among them is Dr. Ronald Wapner, director of reproductive genetics at Columbia and another reduction pioneer. Sometime in the late 1990s, when Wapner practiced in Philadelphia, he received his first two-to-one request. “She said, ‘Either reduce me to a singleton, or I’ll end the pregnancy.’ ” He consulted his staff, all women, <span style="color:#000080;"><em>and they concluded that if a woman can choose to end a pregnancy, she can reduce from two to one</em></span></span>.<span style="color:#0000ff;"> Besides, in this case, the team would be saving a fetus that would otherwise be aborted.&#8221;</span></p>
<p>You could hardly put it more succinctly. So in response to the above questions: Why? Is not that the very beauty of the freedom of choice? Why should there be any obligation, or even suggestion of an obligation, when it is a protected private choice, respected by its mere status <em>as</em> choice, regardless of what one chooses—because there are no victims at stake, and the outcome simply does not matter?</p>
<p>If you happen to find nothing objectionable in &#8220;The Two-Minus-One Pregnancy&#8221; I have not been speaking to you, and there is more we disagree with than I can account for in this course of this blog. If you feel something wrong about it, I ask why that might be. To be fair, it might be that case that one really does attach him- or herself to any of the speculative reasons stated above. I simply wonder whether those reasons can be defended in the full pro-choice context as anything more than mere sentimentality, resting as they do upon prejudices either irrational or extrinsic to the logic of autonomous choice. And I wonder also whether, in those who do experience that strong and immediate sense of retraction, the strength and immediacy of that sense is likely to be the product of some reasoned-out respect for a sympathetic party like the barren mother, or whether it is strong and immediate, and indeed a prejudice, precisely because it strikes a chord at the very heart of the issue.</p>
<p>I can not identify with the experience of holding in combination these two perspectives—a thoroughly pro-choice outlook on the one hand and a repulsion to the abortion of one of two twins on the other—because that is not me. As should be evident from this series I am pro-life, though I hope my meditations have been fair in their treatment of all and have offered as much for the consideration of pro-choicers as they have for those who share my beliefs.</p>
<p>Yet observing this phenomenon from the outside as I do, I cannot say I am surprised that this immediate instinct persists, for it sounds something to me like the sharp but quiet notes of conscience. Perhaps we feel it because it refers to something real. Perhaps it strikes us before we can explain it away because beneath whatever artifices we have put up there lies dormant but present a whisper of the moral truth. Perhaps we have become so numb to it through years of normalized abortion and hallowed choice that it takes drastic stories like the two-minus-one or the senior art project to stir us momentarily out of our slumber. Perhaps we feel differently about the reducer and the carver because one had a baby and the other did not.</p>
<p>I cannot say. This curious sensation is not mine to feel, as I know how I stand. But it would not surprise me. And with that I&#8217;ll close. Thanks for reading if you did.</p>
<p>=====</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">*Not to mention this astonishing line:</p>
<p style="padding-left:60px;"><span style="color:#0000ff;">“Ethics,” [the doctor] said, “evolve with technology.”</span></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3768/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3768/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3768&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://eternalappetite.wordpress.com/2012/12/02/makes-no-difference-who-you-are/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>33</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c9277e38a931099656ffda0f117674ab?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">eternalappetite</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://eternalappetite.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/screen-shot-2012-11-29-at-9-43-25-pm.png?w=300" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How I Deal With Things</title>
		<link>http://slightlyignorant.wordpress.com/2012/12/17/how-i-deal-with-things/</link>
		<comments>http://slightlyignorant.wordpress.com/2012/12/17/how-i-deal-with-things/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 18:23:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>slightlyignorant</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flash fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[school]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shooting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[short story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://slightlyignorant.wordpress.com/?p=1966</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It sounded like fireworks, first. I thought it was maybe fireworks, like maybe one of the big kids brought them to school when they wasn&#8217;t supposed to. We&#8217;re not allowed to bring things like that to school. We&#8217;re not even supposed to have fireworks at all, but one time me and Adam and Jake and [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1966&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://slightlyignorant.wordpress.com/2012/12/17/how-i-deal-with-things/1418049401_7d1548794d/" rel="attachment wp-att-1970"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1970" alt="1418049401_7d1548794d" src="http://slightlyignorant.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/1418049401_7d1548794d.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>It sounded like fireworks, first. I thought it was maybe fireworks, like maybe one of the big kids brought them to school when they wasn&#8217;t supposed to. We&#8217;re not allowed to bring things like that to school. We&#8217;re not even supposed to have fireworks at all, but one time me and Adam and Jake and Hamed, we all had fireworks and we tried to light them but they were bust because they were wet. Adam got them from his big brother, but his big brother musta wet them before giving them to us. I bet he thought it was really funny.</p>
<p>So I didn&#8217;t know why there was fireworks at school. But it didn&#8217;t sound exactly like fireworks because there wasn&#8217;t that after bit. And there was a bit of other noise, like kids yelling and stuff. But I don&#8217;t know if I really heard that or not because Mom and Dad said that I might be imagining some stuff. I don&#8217;t know, I don&#8217;t really get it.<br />
Anyway, Miss Anna, that&#8217;s our teacher, she got really angry when she heard the firework sounds. Popping noises, that&#8217;s how I heard other people talk about it. Popping sounds. So when she heard them, she got angry. And she told us all to be very quiet, but she didn&#8217;t yell it, like she sometimes does. I don&#8217;t know why, but we all did. We got quiet. I was kinda scared of her, I think. Because she looked seriouser than she did other times. I guess she wasn&#8217;t angry, I guess she was worried. I asked Mom about that and Mom said she wasn&#8217;t angry. Just worried. Everyone was worried. We were so worried, that&#8217;s what everyone keeps saying. Mom and Dad were outside when we ran out after everything, and they both hugged me and said we were so worried. I still didn&#8217;t understand why but the sirens hurt my eyes so I put my head into Dad&#8217;s stomach and he thought I was crying. I&#8217;m not crying, I told him, but I know he didn&#8217;t believe me and that&#8217;s when I got real mad and didn&#8217;t talk to him for a while. He always thinks I&#8217;m crying when I&#8217;m not. Just cause he cries all the time. I don&#8217;t have to cry all the time too.<br />
Miss Anna first told us to get under our desks after the popping noises and then she did something she tells us never to do. She answered her phone. It was buzzing, not ringing, but we could all hear it, just like she can hear it if we try to play games with the sound off. She always says she has really sensy tev ears, I don&#8217;t know what she means, but I guess it means she knows when you&#8217;re using your phone even when you shouldn&#8217;t be.<br />
She whispered into the phone instead of talking into to and I didn&#8217;t know how anyone could hear her on the other side because when I try to whisper to Mom on the phone she always says speak up. Then Miss Ann got down on the floor with us and I started to giggle a little because, well, it was funny. And Adam laughed too because he was next to me and he saw it was funny too. Mom told me after that it was okay that I laughed because I didn&#8217;t know what was happening and then it&#8217;s okay to laugh. But I still don&#8217;t really now so maybe it&#8217;s still okay to laugh.<br />
But I guess it&#8217;s not okay to laugh because when I tried to laugh with some woman who had really nice red hair and was standing near Mom at the meeting where we saw the President, Mom told me to hush up. Sometimes she tells me to speak up and sometimes she tells me to hush up. I don&#8217;t know what I&#8217;m supposed to do then. Dad hugged me tightly when we saw the President speak. I know there&#8217;s a big P in President because Miss Anna taught us that last week in school.<br />
There isn&#8217;t any school now. I just stay at home with Mom who isn&#8217;t going to work and Dad comes home from the shop for lunch and we all eat together. Which is really nice. But Mom keeps rubbing my hair a lot and she doesn&#8217;t let me watch anything on tv except for DVDs. And I want to watch something on the Disney channel but she keeps saying no, because she can&#8217;t see the news again. And then she cries. I still don&#8217;t really get why. I asked if it was about the fireworks at school and she looked confused, and so I said that popping noises and she asked where I heard about that. I didn&#8217;t want to tell her that I can&#8217;t sleep so good and that I hear her and Dad watching the news late at night, so I didn&#8217;t tell her. I said I just heard it somewhere. She said yes baby, it&#8217;s about that. And then she said thank god and she hugged me again. Parents are weird sometimes.</p>
<p>_____________</p>
<h4 id="yui_3_7_3_3_1355946846336_1054">Photo / <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/heicktopiertz/">Alexandre Laurin</a></h4>
<p>[Note: Photo has no direct affiliation to this post and is being used for artistic purposes only]</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1966/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1966/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1966&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://slightlyignorant.wordpress.com/2012/12/17/how-i-deal-with-things/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>113</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/8da20d2f899acc8b19c0df3e5a02f71c?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F2.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">slightlyignorant</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://slightlyignorant.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/1418049401_7d1548794d.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">1418049401_7d1548794d</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Debt Bias: Or, how good reforms do bad things to good people</title>
		<link>http://yourbrainonecon.wordpress.com/2012/12/07/the-debt-bias-or-how-good-reforms-do-bad-things-to-good-people/</link>
		<comments>http://yourbrainonecon.wordpress.com/2012/12/07/the-debt-bias-or-how-good-reforms-do-bad-things-to-good-people/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2012 02:09:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>mdsy10</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[debt bias]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Econ for Poets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial reform]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tax coded]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://yourbrainonecon.wordpress.com/?p=999</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve been reading a lot of economic commentary and analysis around two things lately: (1) is, naturally, the negotiations surrounding the &#8220;fiscal cliff,&#8221; and (2) is Prof. Anas Admati&#8217;s argument that the best financial reform we could undertake would be to require banks to have a higher equity ratio (that is, to finance more of [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=999&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve been reading a lot of economic commentary and analysis around two things lately: (1) is, naturally, the negotiations surrounding the &#8220;fiscal cliff,&#8221; and (2) is Prof. Anas Admati&#8217;s <a href="https://gsbapps.stanford.edu/researchpapers/library/BankEquityNotExpensive.pdf">argument</a> that the best financial reform we could undertake would be to require banks to have a higher equity ratio (that is, to finance more of their assets through stock and less through debt, reducing their leverage). I hope to write at greater length about (2) in the future, but, for now, suffice it to say that both of these things center on the &#8220;debt bias&#8221; in the U.S. tax-code, a bias which piqued my interest and so which, after a little research, I should like to tell you about.</p>
<p>Let me start out with some econ for poets. Suppose you&#8217;re a business and you want to make a big expansion&#8211;setting up lots of new stores, opening a new R&amp;D facility, etc.&#8211;that will cost you $1 billion.  Unless you have a lot of cash on hand (which you probably shouldn&#8217;t&#8211;it would have been wasteful to have just accumulated it) there are two ways you could fund this expansion. One, you could issue more shares in your company (that is, sell more stock to the public)&#8211;this is equity. Or, two, you could get a loan from a bank to do this&#8211;this is debt. Which option should you choose? Well, naturally, you should choose whichever one is cheaper&#8211;technically, whichever funding option&#8217;s obligations have a lower net present discounted value (the debt&#8217;s obligations being interest and principle, and the equity&#8217;s obligation being a share of profits and ownership). In reality, which one will be cheaper? Well, theoretically, since these two instruments are both providing the same good&#8211;financing&#8211;they should be about equally expensive. Think about it: if interest rates were relatively high, meaning that debt was more expensive than equity, firms would rush to issue more shares, which would reduce stock prices by increasing their supply, and eschew bank loans, which would force banks to lower their &#8216;prices&#8217; (their interest rates), until the two became equally expensive. So in a perfect market, equity and debt should be about equally expensive for companies, and companies would make their financing decisions as follows:  they would fund their activities through equity if they thought that their shares were slightly overpriced, and through debt if they thought their shares were relatively underpriced.</p>
<p>Now, we&#8217;ve just done some typical Econ 101 theory above, about an ideal market. But in the real world corporate financing decisions are distorted. One major distortion is the U.S. tax code, which includes a deduction for interest payments on debt. The tax code does not include a deduction from dividend payments to shareholders. To the contrary, corporate profits returned to shareholders are taxed twice: once as corporate profits (just before they have been returned to shareholders), and again as capital gains (once they are in the shareholders&#8217; hands). What does this do? Well, it gives companies a strong &#8220;debt bias&#8221; relative to the ideal market we laid out above. Because the obligations they incur from debt-financing in fact reduce their tax burdens, corporations are incentivized to rely relatively more heavily on debt, and less on equity.</p>
<p>Why is this a problem? Well, it isn&#8217;t always, necessarily, a problem for everyone. Indeed, if you&#8217;re a shareholder of a firm that has really great growth prospects for the future, you should be happy with debt-financing&#8211;this &#8220;leverage&#8221; means that you will get a higher share of whatever is left over once debt-obligations are paid off, than if your share had been diluted by the issuance of more equity. But the problems are twofold. First, in general, we as a society want companies to devote their analysis to trying figure out, and their energies to trying to meet, our needs as we express them in the marketplace&#8211;not make their decisions based on how best to game the tax code.  But, second, debt becomes a very big, very tangible problem during an economic downturn, when it can cause a credit crunch, a massive financial crisis, and thence a recession/depression, as you may have heard. We often hear debt analogized to &#8220;leverage,&#8221; because it makes the good times better for companies&#8217; owners (shareholders) and the bad times worse. Consider this super simplified model of a firm buying one asset in one year, with a 2% interest rate: If you&#8217;ve financed a $100 million asset through $50m of equity and $50m of debt (a debt-equity ratio of 1 to 1), if the value of that asset suddenly declines to $85m, you&#8217;re still easily okay&#8211;you can pay back your creditors their $51m, and still have $34m left, which is now the value of your shareholders&#8217; stake, a loss of $16m for them. But if you financed that through $10m of equity and $90m of debt (a debt-equity ratio/leverage of 9 to 1), the same decline in the asset&#8217;s value will bankrupt you: You owe creditors more than you have, and so your shares are worth less than nothing, and you have to enter bankruptcy. If you get the conceptual gist here, you can probably also see how, in good times, when firms are making high profits, &#8220;leverage&#8221; (a high debt-equity ratio) can increase the profits that are returned to shareholders. (But, and this is a bit technical, it does not technically increase shareholder <em>value</em>, because the leverage makes the expected return-on-equity <em>riskier</em>.) It also makes it much easier for firms to slip into bankruptcy when the times are not as good as they had predicted.</p>
<p>So what, then, is the problem with leverage if it just helps shareholders on the upside, and hurts them or causes bankruptcy on the downside? Why should I care if I&#8217;m not a major shareholder, or involved in any way with a highly-levered firm? Or if I am a shareholder, shouldn&#8217;t I be okay with this as long as I have a diversified portfolio that is collectively non-risky? The problem is that, during a credit crunch and financial crisis, bankruptcy is contagious. That is, when a highly-levered firm (which could itself be a bank&#8211;see my upcoming post on Admati) can no longer meet its obligations and enters bankruptcy, it is failing to pay out a cash flow that a bank had been depending on to finance its own activities. So that can send that bank into bankruptcy, or leave it unable to roll over the debt of another firm, sending <em>that</em> firm into bankruptcy. This is basically what a &#8220;credit crunch&#8221; is&#8211;everybody being so indebted to everyone else, that a small economic downturn can cause a string of interlocking insolvencies&#8211;and this is pretty much the story of what has happened in the economy from 2007-present. If companies had had less debt, and financed more of their activities with equity, an economic downturn would have caused their shareholders to take an unpleasant hit, but it would not cause this contagious domino-effect of insolvency.</p>
<p>A lot of what I&#8217;ve written about firms is also true of people, except for the fact that we people don&#8217;t really have the option (yet) of getting outside equity-financing (though some are proposing to equity-finance college loans&#8211;more on this later). For example, we humans have a mortgage-interest deduction, which provides us an incentive to take out relatively larger mortgages on our homes. There are a couple of problems with this. First, since the real-estate market is in reality largely an arms-race to get into the best school district possible, people generally buy the most expensive house they can afford, and so, according to many economists, the economic value of the mortgage-interest deduction is simply capitalized in higher home prices&#8211;i.e., in the aggregate, it doesn&#8217;t provide any easing of financial burdens to homeowners at all. Second, it distorts the market for buying vs. renting property&#8211;and there&#8217;s no particularly compelling reason to do that. And third, and most importantly, as we, again, saw in the financial crisis, more debt makes it easier for you to get wiped out by even small changes in the value of your assets. Suppose bad employment prospects have made it difficult for you to make your mortgage payments&#8211;if, in addition, the value of your house has declined, leaving you &#8220;underwater,&#8221; you won&#8217;t be able to refinance your house, and so you&#8217;ll default. That will reduce the cash flow to the bank that is entitled to them which, in turn, can cause Lehman&#8230; You get the picture. So personal bankruptcies, just like company bankruptcies, are contagious, and they become likelier and more harmful the more debt we all have.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">***</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">I hope that you, gentle reader, do not spend as much time reading economics commentary as I do (because then what use would I be to you?), but one thing I&#8217;ve noticed is that almost all econ-theory minded people want to get rid of all of these distortions. Everyone seems to agree that the ideal tax reform involve lower rates, while getting rid of loopholes and deductions, such that we can actually raise more revenue, while imposing fewer distortions on the marketplace. There&#8217;s a consensus among them. But if there&#8217;s a consensus, why can&#8217;t we get some policy and legal changes done? The answer, of course, is &#8220;vested interests.&#8221; But that term sounds mean, and derogatory, and, more importantly, it understates the difficulty of our challenge.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Because, in this case, the term &#8216;vested interests&#8217; doesn&#8217;t just mean super-rich super-evil tobacco lobbyists, or some such fun-to-hate villain, but actually literally means your mom and dad. Even if your mom and dad have already finished paying off the mortgage on your house, getting rid of the mortgage-interest deduction would hurt them, because it would reduce the sale-value of their house, because it would hurt the real-estate market as a whole (since new buyers won&#8217;t get such large mortgages if they can&#8217;t write them off). And the same goes for the corporate interest deduction&#8211;if we eliminated it, a lot of medium-size firms would  lose a lot of money when they can no longer write off the interest on bonds they issued a decade or two ago. And the same goes for a lot of other loopholes:  if we get rid of the federal deduction of state income taxes, medium-high-income people in high-tax states are going to get badly hurt. All of these people were, when they made these decisions, responding rationally to the incentives our public polices had put in place. They formed rational expectations for the future based off of those expectations. They were good people doing the right thing, in the circumstances and policy landscape that they were presented with, and now the policy changes that we are proposing are going to hurt them and disrupt the life path that the old policies had led them to expect. These people are, quite justly, going to be very upset if their representatives do it.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><strong>This is why reform is hard. </strong></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Nonetheless, I&#8217;ll reiterate that we really should do the right thing and eliminate these distortions and tax loopholes if we can. It would obviously be wrong to leave bad policies in place forever. But the longer we leave them in place, the more and more good, rational, reasonable people build their lives around those policies, making them even more costly to be rid of in the future. So the very best time to take the plunge is right away.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/999/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/999/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=999&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://yourbrainonecon.wordpress.com/2012/12/07/the-debt-bias-or-how-good-reforms-do-bad-things-to-good-people/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/2cc98e89f06c4b83c183bee84df8d647?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mdsy10</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Expedia: Bad for the Traveler, Bad for the Hotel</title>
		<link>http://playazone.wordpress.com/2012/12/04/expedia-bad-for-the-traveler-bad-for-the-hotel/</link>
		<comments>http://playazone.wordpress.com/2012/12/04/expedia-bad-for-the-traveler-bad-for-the-hotel/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2012 16:25:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Tony &#38; Cheri</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recommendations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Hotel & Bar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[expedia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fraud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hotels.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mexico]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://playazone.wordpress.com/?p=4158</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There is a lot of talk in the news these days about the difficulties facing small business owners around the world. Nowhere are these difficulties felt as deeply as in the travel industry. The rapid growth of the control of travel by big business with its multi-billion-dollar internet and advertising power has caused many small [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4158&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://playazone.wordpress.com/2012/12/04/expedia-bad-for-the-traveler-bad-for-the-hotel/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>192</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/59d5b4fb266a1d27d32979d9621607ac?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">playazone</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://playazone.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/fightexpediablog1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Tony &#38; Cheri owners of Luna Blue Hotel in Playa del Carmen Mexico</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://playazone.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/fightexpediablog3.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">fightexpediablog3</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://playazone.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/fightexpediablog2.jpg?w=400" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">fightexpediablog2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://playazone.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/fightexpediablog4.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">fightexpediablog4</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://playazone.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/fightexpediablog5.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">fightexpediablog5</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="https://badge.facebook.com/badge/133786885870.1732.610301680.png" medium="image" />
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
