<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2012 01:02:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Seven Steps to Inspiring the Painter in Your Child</title>
		<link>http://artspip.wordpress.com/2012/08/20/seven-steps-to-inspiring-the-painter-in-your-child/</link>
		<comments>http://artspip.wordpress.com/2012/08/20/seven-steps-to-inspiring-the-painter-in-your-child/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2012 19:02:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bethbanner</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[painting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[confidence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dialogue]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mark-making]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[landscape]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[narrative]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mistakes]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://artspip.wordpress.com/?p=256</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[From top to bottom: Painting alongside my children &#8211; finger painting with my three-year old; observing my seven year old start some abstract art (which I joined in with towards the end); the resulting finished painting. Ingredients: A range of paints – finger paints, acrylics, watercolours, oils (and linseed oil), mark-making tools, and materials to [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=256&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1><strong><a href="http://artspip.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_1478.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-253" title="IMG_1478" src="http://artspip.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_1478.jpg?w=300&h=248" alt="" width="300" height="248" /></a><a href="http://artspip.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_1300.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-254" title="IMG_1300" src="http://artspip.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_1300.jpg?w=300&h=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" /></a><a href="http://artspip.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_1302.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-255" title="IMG_1302" src="http://artspip.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_1302.jpg?w=300&h=242" alt="" width="300" height="242" /></a></strong></h1>
<p>From top to bottom: Painting alongside my children &#8211; finger painting with my three-year old; observing my seven year old start some abstract art (which I joined in with towards the end); the resulting finished painting.</p>
<p><strong>Ingredients:</strong>  A range of paints – finger paints, acrylics, watercolours, oils (and linseed oil), mark-making tools, and materials to paint on – wood, canvas, cartridge paper, collage paper.</p>
<p><strong>The Big Sell</strong>: Let’s paint beside each other and see what we can make together.</p>
<p><strong>Strategy</strong>:  It occurred to me early on as a mum and an artist there was a big gap between mine and my child’s expectations of a painting. I expected them to sit quietly and to concentrate on forming a well composed painting with narrative and clear bright colours. They expected to swish some paint around a space (which included paper but also included the table, chairs, floor, their hands and feet) until a muddy blend plastered the area and they could run off half-decorated and leave me to clear up!</p>
<p>I wondered whether my boys would ever come to enjoy the tranquillity and focus of painting in the way that I did and what the steps were to this taking place. The answer was &#8230; yes they would, and here are some of the steps along that journey to my now seven-year old, who received mainly painting materials for his seventh birthday and loves abstract art more than any other style of painting.</p>
<ol>
<li>From 2 – 3 years onwards, <strong>make painting fun</strong>. Do it outside in the sun and paint on rolls of old wallpaper to make train tracks down the garden path. Paint hands and feet, toys, leaves, stones, feathers – anything that makes a print. Be well prepared with a bowl of warm water and wipes at the ready to clean them up and hang a washing line and pegs against a space wall if you are lacking in drying space.</li>
<li>Introduce <strong>dialogue</strong> into their work from the word go. Once their paintings are dry (an hour or two later) reintroduce them to your child and using a fat marker pen show them what images you have seen in their paintings – turn a splodge into a face, a splash into a fish, a stripe into a stick man.</li>
<li>Once your child starts to understand and enjoy ‘painting with mummy/daddy/carer’, try some <strong>tandem-finger painting</strong>. Pick the subject of their favourite book (such as The Hungry Caterpillar above) and show them how you can recreate the images using sharp shapes and clear bright colours with your hands, if you clean them in between with a wipe or bowl of water.</li>
<li>Now turn to <strong>DIY toy-making</strong>. As they grow in confidence building images from shapes and colours, make their favourite cartoon character by giving them a basic outline to paint in, add finishing touches with black marker once dry, cut out and cover in sticky-back plastic so they can carry it around with them, attached to buggy.</li>
<li>Alongside figurative art work, introduce elements of <strong>abstract art play</strong> &#8211; arrange patterned collage cut outs alongside swishes of paint and discuss what looks pleasing to their eye. Don’t be afraid to show them famous works of art to inspire them – any age can appreciate Matisse, Pollock, Picasso. Talk to them about the colours of their feelings and dreams and ask them to show you.</li>
<li>As your child’s confidence and knowledge of painting grows, support them with increasingly <strong>interesting materials</strong> – by the age of five my eldest son was painting on wood and papier mache, and quickly progressed to canvas at six. Gather interesting mark-making tools – run down pens, bamboo scratching sticks, an old comb – and try using ink and wax to explore ways to build light and dark in images. By this age, they will appreciate a visit to child-friendly art galleries or sculpture parks. Explain that new materials are precious things to be considered and explored, parts of the rites of passage of becoming a skilled artist.</li>
<li>Exhibit your child’s art work – not just with a magnet on the fridge – but by providing them with their own <strong>gallery space</strong>. If you can’t attach any permanent fixtures to a wall, just use a cork board covered in white or black fabric and lean it in a temporary space. Invite the child to be a curator of this exhibition and talk visitors through their paintings, rather than speaking for them.</li>
</ol>
<p>Accompany this arts play with a culture of carrying sketchbooks on any long car or train journey, ready to play ‘Oops!’ – one person makes a ‘mistake’ (jabs a hole in the paper, creates a fold, line or squiggle) and the other has to turn it into something beautiful, before you swap turns.</p>
<p><strong>The verdict: </strong>I’m aware that I may be making this arts development sound too serious and prescriptive, but that is possibly a response to the type of person my eldest son has become – a serious young man who craves authenticity and a ‘grown up’ approach. Other children may prefer to pursue a more freeform route, continuing to explore mess and mayhem indefinitely.</p>
<p>However, I don’t think there is any danger in exposing children to established artwork from a young age, nor from introducing this idea of dialogue and the closeness that comes from ‘drawing alongside’ a parent with their own style and artistic choices. And it goes without saying, NEVER describe yourself as  ‘hopeless’ at art, no matter how lacking in confidence you are – to them you are wonderful and any poor self-esteem you display will only provide them with the weapons to be ashamed of their own efforts.</p>
<p>Differences between you and them as unique artists are a great gift to emphasize, as you journey towards a shared understanding of art as key to expression and freedom.</p>
<p><strong>Catchphrase:</strong> I love painting beside you! It shows me what the world looks like to you.</p>
<p><strong>Left wanting more? </strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Does anyone else remember the fantastic retro-joy of watching Bob Ross paint a laidback landscape?! Type his name into Youtube and enjoy watching him at work with your child!</li>
</ul>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/256/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/256/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=256&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://artspip.wordpress.com/2012/08/20/seven-steps-to-inspiring-the-painter-in-your-child/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/54fbc224fc32d37919530255a5c1b04e?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bethbanner</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://artspip.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_1478.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_1478</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://artspip.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_1300.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_1300</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://artspip.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_1302.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_1302</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tony Scott &#8211; In Memorium</title>
		<link>http://fluffrick.wordpress.com/2012/08/20/tony-scott-in-memorium/</link>
		<comments>http://fluffrick.wordpress.com/2012/08/20/tony-scott-in-memorium/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2012 17:24:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>fluffrick</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Films]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Geekery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chris Pine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crimson Tide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Deja Vu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Denzel Washington]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jerry Bruckheimer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Keira Knightley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Last Boy Scout]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ridley Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spy Game]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tom Cruise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tony Scott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Gun]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fluffrick.wordpress.com/?p=7358</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#160; If you&#8217;ll permit the indulgence, this is how I want to remember British film director Tony Scott, who committed suicide on Sunday:  On a film set, replete with his signature baseball cap, setting up some kind of practically staged set-piece, with mayhem about to be unleashed. He was a director whose career and films arrived [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=7358&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div id="attachment_7359" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://fluffrick.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tony-scott.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-7359" title="Tony Scott" src="http://fluffrick.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tony-scott.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="375" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text"><a class="zem_slink" title="Tony Scott" href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0001716/" rel="imdb" target="_blank">Tony Scott</a>, who died on August 19th 2012 in Long Beach, California. He was 68 years old.</p></div>
<p>If you&#8217;ll permit the indulgence, this is how I want to remember <a href="http://www.empireonline.com/news/story.asp?NID=34930">British film director Tony Scott, who committed suicide on Sunday</a>:  On a film set, replete with his signature baseball cap, setting up some kind of practically staged set-piece, with mayhem about to be unleashed.</p>
<p>He was a director whose career and films arrived roughly in parallel with my love of movies &#8211; one of my abiding memories from my teenage years is of collecting tokens and sending off via mail order for a <em><strong>&#8220;<a class="zem_slink" title="Top Gun" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0092099/" rel="imdb" target="_blank">Top Gun</a>&#8220;</strong></em> movie poster, back when that defining <a class="zem_slink" title="Tom Cruise" href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0000129/" rel="imdb" target="_blank">Tom Cruise</a> vehicle was the action movie par excellence of its day.</p>
<div id="attachment_7360" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://fluffrick.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/top-gun.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-7360" title="Top Gun" src="http://fluffrick.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/top-gun.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="712" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">&#8220;Top Gun&#8221;, from 1986 &#8211; when films seemed simpler, even if the underlying politics were anything but.</p></div>
<p>Whilst a lot of the coverage of his death will focus on the way in which he chose to take his life, please forgive my preference to focus on his work and recommend some of his extensive catalogue of films which you might want to check out.</p>
<p>Scott&#8217;s movies were just that &#8211; commercial, unashamed action-thrillers and dramas.  Whilst his academic career seemingly set him on a path towards fine art, he duly found himself working in commercials &#8211; <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PM3woO0AbCw">see his celebrated, iconic SAAB advert here</a>, which largely influenced producers <a class="zem_slink" title="Don Simpson" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Don_Simpson" rel="wikipedia" target="_blank">Don Simpson</a> and <a class="zem_slink" title="Jerry Bruckheimer" href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0000988/" rel="imdb" target="_blank">Jerry Bruckheimer</a> to hire him for <strong>&#8220;Top Gun&#8221;</strong>.   His first film was the stylish, erotic and singular vampire drama, &#8220;<a class="zem_slink" title="The Hunger (1983 film)" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0085701/" rel="imdb" target="_blank">The Hunger</a>&#8220;, which underperformed in cinemas and led to a prolonged return to the ad world until Simpson and Bruckheimer&#8217;s Air Force drama pitched him onto the directorial A-List.</p>
<p>His career from there is the very definition of diverse.  He made modern classics like &#8220;<a class="zem_slink" title="True Romance" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0108399/" rel="imdb" target="_blank">True Romance</a>&#8220;, &#8220;<a class="zem_slink" title="Crimson Tide (film)" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0112740/" rel="imdb" target="_blank">Crimson Tide</a>&#8221; or &#8220;<a class="zem_slink" title="The Last Boy Scout" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0102266/" rel="imdb" target="_blank">The Last Boy Scout</a>&#8220;, and more eccentric, darker fare like <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0100485/">&#8220;Revenge&#8221;</a> , &#8220;<a class="zem_slink" title="The Fan (1996 film)" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0116277/" rel="imdb" target="_blank">The Fan</a>&#8221; or the unique, one-of-a-kind <a class="zem_slink" title="Keira Knightley" href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0461136/" rel="imdb" target="_blank">Keira Knightley</a> starring, profoundly meta bounty hunter flick, <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0421054/">&#8220;Domino&#8221;</a>, which is the very definition of an assault on the senses.</p>
<p>In recent years, he had formed a reliable working relationship with <a class="zem_slink" title="Denzel Washington" href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0000243/" rel="imdb" target="_blank">Denzel Washington</a> and their collaboration yielded such films as the aforementioned <strong>&#8220;Crimson Tide&#8221;</strong>, <strong>&#8220;Man on Fire&#8221;</strong>, <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0453467/">&#8220;Deja Vu&#8221;</a>, <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1111422/">&#8220;The Taking of Pelham 1,2,3&#8243;</a> and their last film together, <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0477080/">&#8220;Unstoppable&#8221;</a>.</p>
<div id="attachment_7362" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 490px"><a href="http://fluffrick.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/poster_deja_vu_poster_2.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-7362" title="Deja Vu" src="http://fluffrick.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/poster_deja_vu_poster_2.jpg" alt="" width="480" height="645" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Weirdest car chase ever? I think this film is a candidate for that honour&#8230;</p></div>
<p>If I were going to recommend a film which shows Scott and Washington at their best, it would be the very underrated sci-fi thriller, <strong>&#8220;Deja Vu&#8221;</strong> &#8211; a mind-bending tale of time travel, terrorism and a love story which happens across multiple versions of reality.  Sort of.  It&#8217;s indicative of the way that Scott&#8217;s bravura style mellowed in recent years &#8211; the bullets still fly and the helicopters still zip around on-screen like hyperactive dragonflies, but there&#8217;s a human story at the core which makes the more elaborate action sequences somehow mean a bit more.</p>
<div id="attachment_7363" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://fluffrick.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/spy-game.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-7363" title="Spy Game" src="http://fluffrick.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/spy-game.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="737" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Period spy wranglings with <a class="zem_slink" title="Robert Redford" href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0000602/" rel="imdb" target="_blank">Robert Redford</a> and his latter-day matinee idol heir, <a class="zem_slink" title="Brad Pitt" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brad_Pitt" rel="wikipedia" target="_blank">Brad Pitt</a>.</p></div>
<p>If you don&#8217;t like the sound of that, I recommend Scott&#8217;s desperately underrated and fantastic espionage drama, <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0266987/">&#8220;Spy Game&#8221;</a>, which applies his warp-driven visual style to the kind of low-key, introspective story which seemed apposite at the time but utterly thrives on the clash of styles.  Scott loved the inherently dramatic possibilities of a ticking clock and <strong>&#8220;Spy Game&#8221;</strong> is the very model of a story constructed around  impending cataclysm &#8211; veteran spy Robert Redford&#8217;s last day on the job is spent covertly trying to save the life of Brad Pitt, the spook he recruited whose execution is imminent.</p>
<div id="attachment_7364" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://fluffrick.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/unstoppable-1.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-7364" title="Unstoppable" src="http://fluffrick.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/unstoppable-1.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="665" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Two arguing big lugs versus a runaway bomb the size of a football pitch &#8211; sounds like a party&#8230;</p></div>
<p>Scott&#8217;s last film is one of his best &#8211; the runaway train thriller, <strong>&#8220;Unstoppable&#8221;</strong>, marked his fifth film with Denzel Washington and one which deals brilliantly with the ticking clock motif (in this case personified by a train stuffed full of toxic chemicals, barreling almost unchecked towards a small town) present and correct and a pair of plucky, underdog blue-collar heroes in the form of Washington and <a class="zem_slink" title="Chris Pine" href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm1517976/" rel="imdb" target="_blank">Chris Pine</a> who are the only guys who stop things from going boom.</p>
<p>I love movies which pit heroes against nature and eschew heavy firepower in favour of street smarts saving the day &#8211; the compelling thing about this story (nominally based on true events) is that it&#8217;s a thoroughly normal, not essentially heroic pair of guys who find themselves doing the right thing in the face of mind-boggling unlikely odds and with a boatload of personal baggage making their already crappy day worse (Washington&#8217;s seen-it-all before train driver is about to get canned by the railway company and Pine&#8217;s brash young buck is estranged from his partner and having child visitation access problems).</p>
<p>It&#8217;s bonkers, but oddly easy to relate to &#8211; there&#8217;s a purity about his last film which confirms that Scott was a master at diverting your attention from the cliches inherent in a premise and making the arguably shop worn story so compelling that you couldn&#8217;t deny it and were gripped throughout.</p>
<p>I loved a great many of his movies &#8211; he never made high art, but Tony Scott made Friday Night Movies Par Excellence,  filmic escapism which helped erase the woes of the working week for a couple of hours.  And there&#8217;s not much more that you can ask of a film director other than to make movies that people want to see, and sneak some of your personality in there too if possible.  He will be greatly missed by me &#8211; selfishly, I&#8217;ve lost one of the directors who made me love movies and going to the cinema.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Related Posts:</strong></p>
<ul class="zemanta-article-ul">
<li class="zemanta-article-ul-li"><a href="http://geeksyndicate.wordpress.com/2012/08/20/brit-director-tony-scott-1944-2012/" target="_blank">Brit Director Tony Scott &#8211; 1944 &#8211; 2012</a> (geeksyndicate.wordpress.com)</li>
<li class="zemanta-article-ul-li"><a href="http://geektyrant.com/news/2012/8/19/top-gun-director-tony-scott-commits-suicide.html" target="_blank">Top Gun Director Tony Scott Commits Suicide</a> (geektyrant.com)</li>
<li class="zemanta-article-ul-li"><a href="http://www.newsday.com/news/nation/tony-scott-dead-top-gun-director-jumped-from-bridge-authorities-say-1.3914803" target="_blank">Tony Scott dead; &#8216;Top Gun&#8217; director jumped from bridge, authorities say &#8211; Newsday</a> (newsday.com)</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/7358/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/7358/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=7358&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://fluffrick.wordpress.com/2012/08/20/tony-scott-in-memorium/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c8456ecb7723ed8207311ee0eeda263e?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">fluffrick</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://fluffrick.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tony-scott.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Tony Scott</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://fluffrick.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/top-gun.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Top Gun</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://fluffrick.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/poster_deja_vu_poster_2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Deja Vu</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://fluffrick.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/spy-game.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Spy Game</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://fluffrick.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/unstoppable-1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Unstoppable</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>THE TOWER OF JOY: An Adaptation</title>
		<link>http://mccomseycomix.wordpress.com/2012/08/20/the-tower-of-joy-an-adaptation/</link>
		<comments>http://mccomseycomix.wordpress.com/2012/08/20/the-tower-of-joy-an-adaptation/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2012 03:29:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jeff McComsey</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[A song of Ice and Fire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dorne]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Game of thrones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[George R. R. MArtin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jon Snow's parents]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lyanna Stark]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ser Arthur Dayne]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ser Gerold Hightower]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Kingsguard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tower of Joy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Young Eddard Stark]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mccomseycomix.wordpress.com/?p=397</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[ I was one of those guys. Never heard of A Song of Ice and Fire prior to watching season one of A Game of Thrones. I watched season one half a hundred times and decided that season two needed to start immediately. I bought the nice four book set and proceeded to crack open A Clash [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=397&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;"> <a href="http://mccomseycomix.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/toj_1_web4.png"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-409" title="toj_1_WEB" src="http://mccomseycomix.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/toj_1_web4.png?w=471&h=720" alt="" width="471" height="720" /></a><a href="http://mccomseycomix.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/toj_2_web1.png"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-410" title="toj_2_WEB" src="http://mccomseycomix.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/toj_2_web1.png?w=480&h=720" alt="" width="480" height="720" /></a><a href="http://mccomseycomix.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/toj_3_web1.png"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-411" title="toj_3_WEB" src="http://mccomseycomix.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/toj_3_web1.png?w=461&h=720" alt="" width="461" height="720" /></a><a href="http://mccomseycomix.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/toj_4_web1.png"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-412" title="toj_4_WEB" src="http://mccomseycomix.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/toj_4_web1.png?w=462&h=720" alt="" width="462" height="720" /></a>I was one of those guys. Never heard of A Song of Ice and Fire prior to watching season one of A Game of Thrones. I watched season one half a hundred times and decided that season two needed to start immediately. I bought the nice four book set and proceeded to crack open A Clash of Kings and burn all the way through to A Dance With Dragons in a few short months.</p>
<p>Only then did I go back and read A Game of Thrones.  I missed a bunch of great little scenes. None greater than the Tower of Joy. It&#8217;s a beautiful little scene that I think is Just about a page and a half and yet it is probably one of the most talked about scenes in the series. I loved it from my first read through and just couldn&#8217;t help but turn it into a short little comic like I&#8217;m wont to do.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve done a little math and if I started at the beginning of the series and took four pages to adapt every page and a half of text it would takes me 22 years to work up to The Winds of Winter.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/397/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/397/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=397&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://mccomseycomix.wordpress.com/2012/08/20/the-tower-of-joy-an-adaptation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>12</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/30433c2ad09d1ccec8209165259956ea?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">holdenjuliet</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mccomseycomix.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/toj_1_web4.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">toj_1_WEB</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mccomseycomix.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/toj_2_web1.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">toj_2_WEB</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mccomseycomix.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/toj_3_web1.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">toj_3_WEB</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mccomseycomix.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/toj_4_web1.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">toj_4_WEB</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cereal Polygamy</title>
		<link>http://shannonborg.wordpress.com/2012/08/02/kitchen-3-cereal-polygamy/</link>
		<comments>http://shannonborg.wordpress.com/2012/08/02/kitchen-3-cereal-polygamy/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2012 18:19:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Shannon</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[26Kitchens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Geneology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[college]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dorms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kitchens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[memoir]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://shannonborg.wordpress.com/?p=289</guid>
		<description><![CDATA["Denying the daughters of women who cook every day a kitchen is like denying a priestess her altar. We can’t pray like we should - cookies, brownies, blackberry pie. No ritual offerings, it’s throwing me off.”<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=289&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>
<dl>
<dt></dt>
<dd>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>The first wife buried the second wife on the other side of the cemetery.</em></p>
</dd>
</dl>
</div>
<blockquote><p><em>&#8230; and the moon comes up as the moon<br />
</em><em>(All its images are in the dump) and you see<br />
</em><em>As a man (not like an image of a man),<br />
</em><em>You see the moon rise in the empty sky.</em></p>
<p>Wallace Stevens, &#8220;The Man on the Dump&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p><em>Helaman Hall, Brigham Young University, Provo, Utah</em></p>
<p>The Bowl: Deep, but not too deep. Copious. But not too big so as to make your cereal seem small in the space provided. White. Artificial colors look so much brighter against pure white.</p>
<p>The Conversation in my Head: “Crunchberries fit into a food group.”</p>
<p>“The lunch ladies in the dorm cafeteria won’t mind. They feed us just like Mom would -  roast chicken, meatloaf, broiled fish, green beans, white dinner rolls baked daily. Sunday every day. This is just dessert.”</p>
<p>“Nobody’s mother sends it in care packages, least of all mine.”</p>
<p>The Mise en Place: The dorm rooms are 10- by 16-foot. Two single beds, two small desks, two miniscule closets. Jennifer has her 14-inch television set up in the corner and we sprawl out on the beds with our bowls, sharing. Half Cheerios, half Lucky Charms. Half Count Chocula, half Peanut Butter Cap’n Crunch. Whole milk. Two-percent. Non-fat. Each, her bowl. Each, her spoon. It is creative work going on here. A gourmet experimentation free-for-all of the highest order.</p>
<p>“They don’t sell the good stuff on campus. We buy it ourselves, with our allowances, with our government-supplied student loan money.”</p>
<p>“Denying the daughters of women who cook every day a kitchen is like denying a priestess her altar. We can’t pray like we should &#8211; cookies, brownies, blackberry pie. No ritual offerings, it’s throwing me off.”</p>
<p>*</p>
<p>We think about it. We talk about it. We shop in packs for it.</p>
<p>We know it&#8217;s wrong.</p>
<p>*</p>
<p>The Cereal: Pour the cereal in. Well, pour is the understood term, but<em> clank</em> or <em>clunk, tink </em>or <em>shonk</em> is more accurate. Or <em>shuffle</em>. Cap’n Crunch <em>clanks </em>into the bowl. Rice Krispies and Count Chocula &#8211; small puffed things &#8211; make a <em>shuffling</em> sound<em>. </em>Lucky Charms have the ‘lucky’ &#8211; the hard square bits, the ones that tear apart the roof of your mouth, which <em>clink,</em> almost like glass. But the ‘charms’ &#8211; the dried marshmallows in shapes and colors of shamrocks and hearts, are a random <em>thomp. </em>Luck Charms is a waterfall of <em>clink </em>and <em>thomp. </em>Cheerios are a clean, healthy sounding <em>shoosh</em>.</p>
<p>You would never hear Wheaties or God forbid, granola, at this gathering.</p>
<p>*</p>
<p>In our dorm, Helaman Hall &#8211; named after the Mormon prophet and warrior -  social life starts at 10 p.m. when the library closes. The girls &#8211; Jennifer, Jessica, Leslie and I slam Physical Geography or Great Expectations shut as the theme to Hawaii 5-0 rises from the library loudspeaker.  Jocks and thespian jump onto the nearest table and surf - <em>da-da-da-da DAAA DAAA &#8211; da- da- da-da DAAAA</em>.</p>
<p>Most girls have care packages to look forward to. Pumped up and starving, we scurry in packs back to our dorms, set up our worlds like dollhouses: Jiffy Pop, Snickers &#8211; homemade brownies, homemade fruit leather, homemade zucchini bread.</p>
<p>My Secret: My mother is a good cook and a terrible procrastinator. Which is to say she is an excellent procrastinator. Although she is, from the outside &#8211; and in &#8211; the picture of a nurturing, relatively organized mother of seven, she stacks bills in unopened piles. For years, she’s said, “When I have time, I’ll sort through those old pictures.” She was often an hour late to pick me up from piano lessons.</p>
<p>She isn’t a care package kind of gal.</p>
<p>And secretly, I’m not so sure she believes in God.</p>
<p>I never understood the draw of late-night life until I went away. Then I discovered a world much like my mother’s. I picture her sitting at the kitchen table at midnight, eating popcorn and reading Sir Arthur Conan Doyle or Louis L’Amour, scratching out crossword puzzles with my brother, a pair of night owls.</p>
<p>Here in my room, with just the grey-green glow of Twin Peaks and my white bowl, I begin to understand her desire for darkness and quiet, for the buzz and focus of addiction to solitude.</p>
<p>I am with my friends, but I am alone.</p>
<p>The Milk: All the girls use nonfat, of course. But I stick with whole, and occasionally bring what I really want &#8211; half and half. My father taught me to savor the fatty bits of the stew or steak, and ended each meal with a satisfying slice of homemade wheat bread slathered, <em>slathered</em>, with butter <em>and </em>Adams Old Fashioned Peanut Butter. He taught me about another excellent late-night TV snack, graham crackers crunched into a bowl with half and half.</p>
<p>Late night eating is an act of self-determination.</p>
<p>*</p>
<p>On Sundays, I go to my Aunt Lazell’s in Springville for supper.</p>
<p>My father’s sister is the female version of him. She’s a big woman with a strawberry blonde beehive. She has large hands and keeps her long, pointy fingernails painted coral or salmon, as close to the color of her hair as she can get. She drives a beige late ‘70s Oldsmobile Cutlass. She&#8217;s a retired third grade teacher who never married.</p>
<p>Born LaZalia Alta, her Swedish Mormon father named she and her sister, Maureen Montez after the cigars he smoked. I’d sit alone in her pristine one-story duplex living room, everything monochromatic beige, trying to <em>not touch anything</em>, because she would throw me a look, or tell me to pick something up or wipe my feet or wash my hands.</p>
<p>She cooked dinner in her pristine kitchen, like it was a china shop and I was the bull. Cooking and her kitchen shouldn’t go together. But cook she did, and as she did, she talked. Not to me, but at me:</p>
<p>“Well, I don’t know why your father never comes to visit.”</p>
<p>“That bum uncle of yours just abandoned your mother.”</p>
<p>“Well, those cousins of yours don’t respect their mother.”</p>
<p>She was making a fruit salad, cranking cans open with her fingers sprawled out so as not to break her fingernails, dumping can after can into a huge bowl. A whole container of Cool Whip. The more and faster and louder she talked, the more she dumped and stirred.</p>
<p>“That poor child. How that devil of a doctor could do that to my sister, I’ll never know.”</p>
<p>Chopping a whole head of iceberg lettuce, three large tomatoes.</p>
<p>“He can go to hell as far as I’m concerned.”</p>
<p>A pile of steak, a huge mashed potatoes with sour cream and butter and bacon bits on my plate.</p>
<p>“Grandmother was the first wife,” she said. “And she died first. Her sister was the second wife, and buried Grandmother all the way across the cemetery.”</p>
<p>A massive coffin of torn pale green leaves studded with red. A sea of white peaks covering pineapple chunks. Her coral fingernails blotched with Cool Whip.</p>
<p>“Grandpa spent nine months in prison, you know,” she grumbled. “He made saddles for every mucky muck in Salt Lake City.”</p>
<p>Slamming the bottle of bleu cheese dressing <em>down</em> on the table. Fingers greasy. Beehive perfect.</p>
<p>“Well, aren’t you going to eat?”</p>
<p>My plate clean, she fills it again.</p>
<p>“I spent all day cooking, you know.”</p>
<p>I eat and I nod.</p>
<p>“I’ll be left with all this food.”</p>
<p>I chew and chew.</p>
<p>*</p>
<p>The Process: At first, the cereal is fruitily, frightfully itself. Terrifyingly, mouth-ripping, eardrum popping <em>crunchy</em>. This, for two bites. The pain that must be endured. Soon, each bit, whether it be square and brickish or marshmallowy and soft, begins to soak in the liquid.</p>
<p>I want to see, no, to <em>have </em>Kyle MacLachlan, the perfect hero in his suit -  but still a bit of a bad boy, drinking that coffee.  He looks the Mormon missionary, and we all have ours &#8211; boys we will make out a dozen times our freshman year, but never more. We’ll send them off to Belgium or Brazil for two years. We’ll write and wait, then marry them when they return. We’ll live down the street from each other and although the others will have at least six children, I’ll have just three. We’ll cook together and bake and feed each other’s broods. Happily, laughingly and without grumbling.</p>
<p>The The: This is when most of the cereal eating should happen, in the sweet spot between crunch and sog. The moment of utter bliss, of the childhood we just left, regained momentarily. Control of self and the world we knew we could not control. The dorm room is dark but we know there’s brightness in our bowls. The first few melancholic measures of the Twin Peaks theme swell, rising in our hearts as we lay on our bellies, bowls in front of us like pets. Each quietly chewing the personal perfection we each have created. The light of the television glowing warmly on our moist, pudgy faces.</p>
<p>by Shannon Borg</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/289/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/289/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=289&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://shannonborg.wordpress.com/2012/08/02/kitchen-3-cereal-polygamy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://shannonborg.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/unknown.jpeg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://shannonborg.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/unknown.jpeg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Cemetery Polka</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c35eedd95a657789f423a9f679a424fe?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">shannon</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Struggles</title>
		<link>http://brokenlightcollective.wordpress.com/2012/08/19/struggles/</link>
		<comments>http://brokenlightcollective.wordpress.com/2012/08/19/struggles/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2012 17:29:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Broken Light: A Photography Collective</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Depression]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anxiety]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[childhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[depression]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gardening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inspiration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outdoors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[portrait]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sadness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[struggling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brokenlightcollective.wordpress.com/?p=3560</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Photo taken by Jim, a man from Texas who has struggled with depression for much of his life. About the photo: Sometimes Struggles are exactly what we need in our life. If we were to go through life without any obstacles, It would cripple us. We would not be as strong as we could have been [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3560&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://brokenlightcollective.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/120804jwharley6444.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-3561" title="120804jwharley6444" src="http://brokenlightcollective.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/120804jwharley6444.jpg?w=1001&h=700" alt="" width="1001" height="700" /></a></p>
<p>Photo taken by <a title="jim work" href="http://www.jimwork.com/" target="_blank">Jim</a>, a man from Texas who has struggled with depression for much of his life.</p>
<p>About the photo:</p>
<p><em>Sometimes Struggles are exactly what we need in our life.</em><br />
<em> If we were to go through life without any obstacles,</em><br />
<em> It would cripple us.</em><br />
<em> We would not be as strong as we could have been</em><br />
<em> And we could never fly.</em><br />
<em> So next time you are faced with an obstacle,</em><br />
<em> A challenge, or a problem,</em><br />
<em> Struggle a little- then fly.</em></p>
<p><em>Shantanu</em></p>
<p><em>&#8220;I sat in the comfort of my rocking chair under cover from the heat. At first the noise distracted my escape of morning reading and meditation. But then I looked into all the racket, and found that the perfect image of struggle was across the street rather than in my own head.</em></p>
<p><em>We all have struggles. It is personal and as big or small as we make it, but we must move on past the dust and disgust.</em></p>
<p><em>You will have struggles on your journey, that is how you grow.&#8221;</em></p>
<p>____________________________________________________________</p>
<p>**Broken Light submission info <a href="http://brokenlightcollective.wordpress.com/submit-here/" target="_blank">here</a> **Like us on <a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Broken-Light-Collective/217143911732438">Facebook</a> &amp; <a href="https://twitter.com/#%21/BrokenLightCo">Twitter</a>. **Follow below</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3560/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3560/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3560&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://brokenlightcollective.wordpress.com/2012/08/19/struggles/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>17</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://brokenlightcollective.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/120804jwharley6444.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://brokenlightcollective.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/120804jwharley6444.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">120804jwharley6444</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/3c972f2a01500fa51af026e09413a4d7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">brokenlightcollective</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://brokenlightcollective.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/120804jwharley6444.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">120804jwharley6444</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Freeze</title>
		<link>http://sarahpiazza.org/2012/08/10/freeze/</link>
		<comments>http://sarahpiazza.org/2012/08/10/freeze/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2012 18:50:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sarah Piazza</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Nonfiction]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://sarahpiazza.org/?p=893</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[My children are busy cleaning out their rooms. It all started when my husband built a desk for my younger child, who will enter middle school in three weeks&#8217; time. The introduction of the desk into the bedroom necessitated a certain amount of reshuffling and uncluttering. My older son wanted in on this game. So [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=893&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>My children are busy cleaning out their rooms.  It all started when my husband built a desk for my younger child, who will enter middle school in three weeks&#8217; time.  The introduction of the desk into the bedroom necessitated a certain amount of reshuffling and uncluttering.  My older son wanted in on this game.  So now the boys blur past me as they carry toys, books, chairs, and lamps to the basement, which is fast becoming impassable.  My ten-year-old brings me a pile of books and slaps it down on the kitchen counter.  &#8220;Do you want to keep these, or give them away?,&#8221; he asks.  I am silent.  He grows impatient, tapping his foot and sighing.</p>
<p>But I am dumbstruck.  Here in front of me are treasured books, books he once loved so, books I once loved so.  My son seems to understand my conundrum, and, with a softer tone, he points out that he is just too old for these books.  I nod and tell him to put them in the basement.  Is that because I&#8217;ll want to pore over them, someday, or because he will?  I can&#8217;t tell.</p>
<p>My fourteen-year-old takes down a print of the Mona Lisa that had been hanging on his wall.  We&#8217;d bought it at the Louvre last summer, when we visited Paris.  &#8220;It&#8217;s not that it&#8217;s bad art, Mom,&#8221; he argues, by way of explanation, &#8220;but it&#8217;s just obvious.  It&#8217;s too well known, you know?  Overrated.&#8221;  I nod.  My mouth, fish-like, opens, then closes.  It&#8217;s been doing that a lot lately.</p>
<p>And I haven&#8217;t even mentioned the dinosaur sheets.  How my teen used to love dinosaurs.  Once, at the Museum of Natural History in New York, when he was perhaps six, he and I watched some fourth and fifth graders, city kids, on a tour of the dinosaur exhibits.  &#8220;Who knows,&#8221; asked the guide, &#8220;what the word &#8216;pterodactyl&#8217; means, literally?&#8221;  The question fell on silence, until my son yelled, &#8220;Winged lizard!&#8221;  &#8220;Right!,&#8221; beamed the tour guide, without realizing that the child who&#8217;d answered her question wasn&#8217;t even a member of her assigned group.</p>
<p>That same kid slept in dinosaur bedding for years.  A year or two ago, while making his bed, I told him that when he was ready for different sheets, he should let me know, and I&#8217;d be happy to buy him some new ones.  He agreed.  Last week, he told me that his friends had been teasing him about his sheets, and he wanted a new set, a set absent dinosaurs.  I laughed.  &#8220;About time,&#8221; I proclaimed.  And then we went to Target and bought him some solid navy bedding.  At the store a man browsing in the bedding aisle offered my tall son this: &#8220;Good luck in college.&#8221;  &#8220;Not quite college yet,&#8221; I murmured, shocked.</p>
<p>Today I am washing and folding that dinosaur bedding, in preparation for&#8230; well, I&#8217;m not sure, exactly.  I want the bedding, which is still in wonderful shape, to go to a child with dinosaurs in his, or her, eyes, to go to a child who knows the meaning of the word &#8216;pterodactyl&#8217; and forty other facts about pterodactyls, besides.</p>
<p>No, what I really want is to see that boy again, the one who hated to leave the Museum of Natural History, the one who made sure to stop at each and every set of dinosaur bones when it was time to go, to say, &#8220;Goodbye, plesiosaur, goodbye, velociraptor, see you next time.&#8221;</p>
<p>With one son set to begin middle school and the other high school in fewer than twenty days, I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;ve ever been more aware of the one-way signs posted along time&#8217;s road.  I watch each of my children asserting himself, rejecting somebody else&#8217;s notion of his identity and staking out new territory.  I watch my children&#8217;s rooms being transformed from childhood sanctuaries to teen lairs that will serve to define their maturing selves to their friends.  I watch my children as they expand their own worlds, minute by minute, book by book, toy by toy, painting by painting.  I can think of nothing to do.  Witless, I continue opening and closing my mouth, waiting for words that never do arrive.</p>
<p><a href="http://sarahpiazzadotorg.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/20120819-152851.jpg"><img src="http://sarahpiazzadotorg.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/20120819-152851.jpg" alt="20120819-152851.jpg" class="alignnone size-full" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/893/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/893/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=893&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://sarahpiazza.org/2012/08/10/freeze/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>24</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Sarah</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://sarahpiazzadotorg.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/20120819-152851.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">20120819-152851.jpg</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Time Machine</title>
		<link>http://viemagiquesn.wordpress.com/2012/08/19/time-machine/</link>
		<comments>http://viemagiquesn.wordpress.com/2012/08/19/time-machine/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2012 16:46:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sophie Nussle</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General musings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grandfather clock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jura]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Maurienne]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[time]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[time machine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://viemagiquesn.wordpress.com/?p=958</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The heat that pushed us indoors during these dog days of the Alpine summer has placed me in front of the grandfather clock in the only cool room in the chalet, the dining-sitting room, for hours &#8211; working, socialising, keeping fresh. Every hour it strikes the hour twice, at the exact time and two minutes [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=958&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://viemagiquesn.wordpress.com/2012/08/19/time-machine/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>15</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/3c3561a241ce28382dd54d24509f5d5c?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F0.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">viemagiquesn</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8443/7815453418_c131cc089e_z.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">CIMG0205</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8306/7815455746_13b75d08d7_z.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">CIMG0207</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8445/7815456780_df658ceb05_n.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">CIMG0209</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7255/7815458016_86ef15358c_n.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">CIMG0212</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/e/e3/Horloger_Besançon_-_début_XXe.jpg/425px-Horloger_Besançon_-_début_XXe.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://www.maurienne-genealogie.org/images/nouvel2.gif" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ice Cream Parlors</title>
		<link>http://restaurant-ingthroughhistory.com/2012/08/19/ice-cream-parlors/</link>
		<comments>http://restaurant-ingthroughhistory.com/2012/08/19/ice-cream-parlors/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2012 15:40:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>victualling</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[history]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[restaurants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Currie's]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ice cream chains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ice cream stands]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[refreshment gardens]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://restaurant-ingthroughhistory.com/?p=3141</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Ice cream is an affordable, intergenerational family-friendly treat with a mild sedative effect. Historically it’s been associated with the temperance movement, innocent youthful courtship, and after-theater refreshment. For ages ice cream has been primarily a commercial product. As was largely true of soda and beer, it was usually consumed outside the home until after World [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3141&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://victualling.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dairyislebridgeport.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-3147 alignleft" title="dairyIsleBridgeport" src="http://victualling.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dairyislebridgeport.jpg?w=300&h=215" alt="" width="300" height="215" /></a>Ice cream is an affordable, intergenerational family-friendly treat with a mild sedative effect. Historically it’s been associated with the temperance movement, innocent youthful courtship, and after-theater refreshment.</p>
<p>For ages ice cream has been primarily a commercial product. As was largely true of soda and beer, it was usually consumed outside the home until after World War II. Only then did supermarkets and homes acquire extensive freezer capacity. In 1925, according to Jakle and Sculle’s Fast Food, 19% of all ice cream was sold in grocery stores, the bulk of it being marketed through confectioners, drug store soda fountains, wayside stands, restaurants, and lunch counters.</p>
<p>Those who could afford it in the late 18th century often obtained ice cream from confectioners and caterers of European origin who made it each day in summer and served it in outdoor gardens or delivered it to homes for immediate consumption.</p>
<p>Late 18th- and early 19th-century residents of Philadelphia and New York City enjoyed eating ice cream in private parks such as NYC’s Vauxhall, Washington, and Columbian gardens which opened yearly on June 1. An elderly writer recalled in the 1860s that in the 1790s at Contoit’s on Broadway in NYC, “Little alcoves, well shaded, on each side of the gravelled walk, had each its table, where friends or lovers, in undisturbed quiet, could enjoy their cream and cake.”</p>
<p><a href="http://victualling.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/thepolar1866.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-3148 alignright" title="ThePolar1866" src="http://victualling.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/thepolar1866.jpg?w=300&h=134" alt="" width="300" height="134" /></a>Ice cream saloons (the term merely indicating a spacious room) and parlors, as they were called later in the 19th century, were described as gaudy mirrored palaces, lit brightly by gaslight. In 1869 M. F. Brigham &amp; Son opened a Ladies’ and Gentlemen’s Coffee, Lunch and Ice Cream Saloon on Washington Street in Boston, in connection with a confectionery at which they sold candy, pastry, ice cream, frozen puddings, sherbets, jelly whips, charlotte Russe, Roman punch, and other confections.</p>
<p><a href="http://victualling.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/gunthers.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-3149 aligncenter" title="gunther's" src="http://victualling.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/gunthers.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="340" /></a>In Chicago, a number of these “ladies’ cafes,” as they were usually known, sprang up on State Street at the time of the 1893 World’s Fair, among them Gunther’s [pictured] and Plow’s. They featured special attractions – positively non-temperance drinks such as Yum Yum and a special version of Roman punch, the former 13% and the latter 20% alcohol!</p>
<p>It is strange, and a little jarring, to see so many advertisements of 19th-century eating places  specializing in ice cream AND oysters – until you realize the two were not usually consumed together. Featuring both as specialties makes perfect sense, though, since for decades oysters were not eaten during the summer months and ice cream was eaten only then.</p>
<p>Frequently, places that started out with just ice cream and simple refreshments eventually branched into restaurants selling lunches and other meals. When <a href="http://restaurant-ingthroughhistory.com/2008/08/27/when-ladies-lunched-schrafft%E2%80%99s/">Schrafft’s</a> established its first NYC store at Broadway and 36th Street in 1898, for instance, it served nothing beyond candy and ice cream.</p>
<p>With the increase in automobile ownership in the 1920s, and into the 1930s and 1940s, chains of roadside ice cream stands and eateries featuring ice cream began to form, among them Dutchland Farms, Howard Johnson’s, Prince Castle, Henry’s, and Friendly’s. “Soft serve” – a product whose name reflects that it does not meet the official definition of ice cream – caught on in the 1940s, a decade which commenced with the first Dairy Queen, located in Joliet IL.</p>
<p><a href="http://victualling.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/curries1946.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-3150 alignright" title="Currie's1946" src="http://victualling.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/curries1946.jpg?w=300&h=212" alt="" width="300" height="212" /></a>In Southern California, people still fondly remember the Currie’s chain and its “mile-high cone” whose replica was often displayed billboard-style on roofs. The chain was started in 1927 by three brothers named Kuhns. After WWII they sold it to the Good Humor company who later sold it to Lipton in the 1960s. In 1964 the chain opened its 87th store, in North Hollywood. Although Currie’s anticipated launching units in every community in Southern California, only three outlets were listed in the 1967 Los Angeles phone book and the chain had disappeared by the 1980s.</p>
<p>© Jan Whitaker, 2012</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3141/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3141/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3141&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://restaurant-ingthroughhistory.com/2012/08/19/ice-cream-parlors/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>20</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/fa5f8268d1ba0806d5cd5f6e37e321e0?s=96&#38;d=identicon" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">victualling</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://victualling.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dairyislebridgeport.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">dairyIsleBridgeport</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://victualling.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/thepolar1866.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ThePolar1866</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://victualling.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/gunthers.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gunther&#039;s</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://victualling.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/curries1946.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Currie&#039;s1946</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8220;Just Following Orders&#8221;?</title>
		<link>http://karinaschroeder.com/2012/08/19/just-following-orders/</link>
		<comments>http://karinaschroeder.com/2012/08/19/just-following-orders/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2012 02:59:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Karina Schroeder</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Arts + Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Commentary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ann Dowd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[authority]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Compliance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Craig Zobel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dreama Walker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prank call]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sexual harrassment]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://karinaschroeder.com/?p=1418</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Wow. Just… Wow. That was my reaction at the end of Compliance, a highly controversial new film from Craig Zobel (George Washington, Great World of Sound) delving into the psychology of following orders. Gripping and emotional with a superb cast of actors, this film is one of the most important movies you should see this [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1418&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://karinaschroeder.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/compliance-poster.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-1421" title="compliance-poster" src="http://karinaschroeder.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/compliance-poster.jpg?w=392&h=580" alt="" width="392" height="580" /></a></p>
<p>Wow. Just… Wow.</p>
<p>That was my reaction at the end of <strong><em>Compliance</em></strong><em>,</em> a highly controversial new film from <strong>Craig Zobel</strong> (<em><strong>George Washington</strong></em>, <em><strong>Great World of Sound</strong></em>) delving into the psychology of following orders. Gripping and emotional with a superb cast of actors, this film is one of the most important movies you should see this year.</p>
<p>A police officer calls a fast food restaurant in Ohio and tells the manager that a female employee is accused of stealing. He then orders the manager to help his investigation by violating the employee’s privacy and dignity in increasingly horrific ways. The manager obeys him without question.</p>
<p>As it turns out, the man on the phone isn’t really a cop. He’s just a man sitting in his home having fun at another person’s expense.</p>
<p>The events illustrated in <em><strong>Compliance</strong></em> are truly unbelievable- how could anyone be so stupid as to believe this guy, to do all the terrible things he says?</p>
<p><a href="http://www.courier-journal.com/article/20051009/NEWS01/510090392/A-hoax-most-cruel-Caller-coaxed-McDonald-s-managers-into-strip-searching-worker?nclick_check=1">But the truth is they did happen</a>. They happened more than 70 times in restaurants across 30 U.S. states. In each case the managers in charge, when asked how they could have done this, all said they thought they were following police orders.</p>
<p><em><strong>Compliance</strong></em> is a frightening look at how gullible we can be when someone claims to be an authority. We will even go against our own morals and our own common sense if an authority tells us to do so. We may not want to admit it, but study after study has proven this to be true.</p>
<p>The film does an incredible job of showing us how quickly “following orders” can escalate. Once the human psyche has identified and accepted someone as an authority figure, then it can easily be manipulated by that power dynamic.</p>
<p>The manager readily accepts the man on the phone as a local police officer. He claims to have the regional manager, who he mentions by name, on the other line. He threatens to put the young employee in jail if she does not obey. All these actions solidify the man’s claim to authority in the minds of the victims involved- and <em><strong>Compliance</strong></em> illustrates every single detail of the man’s carefully crafted manipulation. This is a wonderful tactic allowing the viewer to assess every factor leading up to this ordeal- and wonder how we would have acted in the same situation.</p>
<p><strong>Ann Dowd</strong> (<em><strong>Marley &amp; Me,</strong></em> <em><strong>Garden State</strong></em>) as <strong>Sandra</strong> the franchise manager, and <strong>Dreama Walker</strong> (<em><strong>Gran Torino, Sex and the City</strong></em>) as <strong>Becky</strong> the young employee are perfect for their roles. <strong>Dowd</strong> is a middle-aged friendly Midwest woman quick to trust anyone and <strong>Walker</strong> is an impressionable teenager who doesn’t want to cause any trouble. While the roles are both difficult and complex, <strong>Dowd</strong> and <strong>Walker</strong> play them convincingly throughout the whole piece.</p>
<p><em><strong>Compliance</strong></em> is disturbing to say the least, yet the cringes are well worth it based on the important debate and questions that the film raises about ourselves. Well-written, well acted, and impeccably filmed, this should be a film everybody is talking about.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1418/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1418/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1418&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://karinaschroeder.com/2012/08/19/just-following-orders/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>23</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/516e4009a627f110200363d4d933a598?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">karinaschroeder</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://karinaschroeder.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/compliance-poster.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">compliance-poster</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What Is There In Writing Except Language</title>
		<link>http://chichikir.wordpress.com/2012/08/19/what-is-there-in-writing-except-language/</link>
		<comments>http://chichikir.wordpress.com/2012/08/19/what-is-there-in-writing-except-language/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2012 12:53:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>chichikir</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ramblings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[literature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[novel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[publishing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[style]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://chichikir.wordpress.com/?p=3567</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Some say that there is a decline in the novel, while others claim that it is not the novel that is in decline but the readership. I personally think that at no time in the history of the novel has there been as many novels and stories published as today. Technology has made it easy [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3567&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Some say that there is a decline in the novel, while others claim that it is not the novel that is in decline but the readership. I personally think that at no time in the history of the novel has there been as many novels and stories published as today. Technology has made it easy for us to publish and read digitally. From advertisement, to courses, to articles and stories, to magazines and novels. People sometimes spend hours online, reading. The internet, twitter, blogging and digital publishing have helped turn us global. However, as Isaac Bashevis Singer, 1978 Nobel Prize winner, said in his Nobel lecture:</p>
<p>“There is no machine and no kind of reporting and no kind of film that can do for us what a Tolstoy or Dostoyevsky or Gogol did. Progress can never kill literature, any more than it can kill religion. The more technology, the more people will be interested in what the human mind can produce without the help of electronics. …if we have people with the power to tell a story, there will always be readers.”</p>
<p><a href="http://chichikir.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/publishing.jpg"><img src="http://chichikir.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/publishing.jpg" alt="" title="Publishing" width="500" height="286" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3576" /></a></p>
<p>Of the ten or so books that I read last month, there was not a single one that I can say I absolutely loved. I only liked some for their story, others for the characters and yet others for the writing itself, for the style in which they were written. In every one of those books there was at least one thing that the writer did well. And then I realized that no matter how bad a book is, there is always something in it that the writer is good at. The genius is the one who gets every aspect of the novel or the story right.  </p>
<p>During an interview the late writer Gore Vidal was asked if there was anything in writing except language, and his reply was:</p>
<p>“In the writing of novels there is the problem of how to shape a narrative. And though the search for new ways of telling goes on- I don’t think there are going to be new discoveries. For one thing, literature is not science. There is no new formula. Some of us write better than others; and genius is never forced.”</p>
<p>On this note I would like to repost a <a href="http://chichikir.wordpress.com/2012/03/08/i-only-wrote-the-truth/" target="_blank">story</a> that I had posted earlier. </p>
<p>A blind boy sat on the steps of a building with a hat by his feet. He held up a sign which said: “I am blind, please help.” There were only a few coins in the hat.<br />
A man was walking by. He took a few coins from his pocket and dropped them into the hat. He then took the sign, turned it around, and wrote some words. He put the sign back so that everyone who walked by would see the new words.<br />
Soon the hat began to fill up. A lot more people were giving money to the blind boy. That afternoon the man who had changed the sign came to see how things were. The boy recognized his footsteps and asked, “Were you the one who changed my sign this morning? What did you write?”<br />
The man said, “I only wrote the truth. I said what you said but in a different way.” I wrote:<br />
“Today is a beautiful day but I cannot see it.”</p>
<p>ChK</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3567/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3567/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3567&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://chichikir.wordpress.com/2012/08/19/what-is-there-in-writing-except-language/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>47</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/6f1dda30f0ae1c06b3adf9e3b497926e?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">chichikir</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://chichikir.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/publishing.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Publishing</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>