<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2012 23:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Crafting</title>
		<link>http://newhomesteaders.com/2012/11/16/crafting/</link>
		<comments>http://newhomesteaders.com/2012/11/16/crafting/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2012 01:48:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jason</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Philosophy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[making]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://newhomesteaders.com/?p=36</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I have a confession to make: I like to play video games. Specifically, I like to play role-playing games (RPGs). I&#8217;m sure this makes me a geek, but there&#8217;s no denying it. My current favorite is Skyrim, part of the Elder Scrolls series. It has everything RPG fans like in a game: scenic vistas, epic [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=36&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I have a confession to make: I like to play video games. Specifically, I like to play role-playing games (RPGs). I&#8217;m sure this makes me a geek, but there&#8217;s no denying it. My current favorite is Skyrim, part of the Elder Scrolls series. It has everything RPG fans like in a game: scenic vistas, epic stories, bad guys &amp; monsters to fight, magic, loot, and crafting.</p>
<p><a href="http://newhomesteaders.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/the-elder-scrolls-v-skyrim-lake-vista.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-58" title="Scenic lake in Skyrim" alt="Scenic lake in Skyrim" src="http://newhomesteaders.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/the-elder-scrolls-v-skyrim-lake-vista.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>Yes, crafting. In Skyrim, you can make things. You can make potions (poisonous or beneficial). You can make weapons. You can make jewelry. You can make food. With the newest expansion, you can even create your own house, complete with greenhouse, garden, and beehives. Skyrim scratches the homesteading itch in more ways than any other game I&#8217;ve played. (Those of you with more RPG experience than me might have another opinion.)</p>
<p>Even with this large variety of crafting available, the actual act of crafting can be repetitive. When you make a weapon in Skyrim, you pick a design from a line of predetermined designs. There&#8217;s the &#8220;Imperial&#8221; line, the &#8220;Dwarven&#8221; line, and the &#8220;Elven&#8221; line, among others. Each of these has the same range of weapons; 2 types of swords (single- and double-handed), a dagger, 2 types of axe, a shield, a bow, and more. Each of these weapons requires certain raw materials which you must collect before you can make the weapon. Making the weapon is a matter of selecting an option in a menu. Similarly, when you make a potion or a recipe, you must collect the appropriate resources, select the resources from a menu, and press a button to make the item.</p>
<p><a href="http://newhomesteaders.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/forge_menu.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-52" title="Forge menu in Skyrim" alt="Forge menu in Skyrim" src="http://newhomesteaders.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/forge_menu.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>This type of crafting has two main problems: lack of creativity and lack of skill required. Instead of selecting from a catalog of similar items, I want to design the weapon myself &#8212; the size and style of the blade, the designs on the hilt, and the materials used in construction. I also want to make my own recipes for potions and food. And instead of hitting a button to create an item, I want the game to require skill in crafting. I&#8217;d like to maintain the appropriate forge temperature and swing the hammer. I want to prepare the ingredients for my potions and boil them in a pot.</p>
<p>This type of immersive system-driven gameplay is coming. Programmers will develop more sophisticated simulations of these various tasks. Gamers will be able to design their own weapons and share them through integrated marketplaces inside the game. They will be able to mix custom potions and create custom recipes, and the games will require skill in making these things.</p>
<p>For me, though, all of this crafting is but a fun diversion while waiting for the ability to do these things in real life. Why should I create virtual recipes when I can cook myself? Why make virtual potions when I can brew at home? Why should I hone my skill in video-game weapon manufacturing when I can learn blacksmithing, traditional timber-framing, and carpentry?</p>
<p><a href="http://newhomesteaders.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/blacksmith.png"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-54" title="Blacksmith heating steel in a forge" alt="Blacksmith heating steel in a forge" src="http://newhomesteaders.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/blacksmith.png?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>If you&#8217;re not sure about this whole homesteading thing but you like games, try Skyrim or another game that has a decent crafting system. Figure out what you like and dislike. Then, find out how to do these kinds of things in real life. I think you&#8217;ll find that real-life role-playing is much more fulfilling than any game.</p>
<p>Now excuse me, I need to go collect mushrooms and herbs for my Invisibility Potion. I&#8217;m hunting dragons.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/36/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/36/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=36&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://newhomesteaders.com/2012/11/16/crafting/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://newhomesteaders.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/skyrim-forge.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://newhomesteaders.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/skyrim-forge.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">A forge in Skyrim</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a4711a27aa480accd98bf7dfba702694?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jrrbrubaker</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://newhomesteaders.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/the-elder-scrolls-v-skyrim-lake-vista.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Scenic lake in Skyrim</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://newhomesteaders.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/forge_menu.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Forge menu in Skyrim</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://newhomesteaders.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/blacksmith.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Blacksmith heating steel in a forge</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Feminist Critique Of Twilight</title>
		<link>http://sarahgetscritical.wordpress.com/2012/11/13/a-feminist-critique-of-twilight-emotional-abuse-child-grooming-and-pro-choice-plots/</link>
		<comments>http://sarahgetscritical.wordpress.com/2012/11/13/a-feminist-critique-of-twilight-emotional-abuse-child-grooming-and-pro-choice-plots/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2012 16:23:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sarah</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Feminism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Literature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Abortion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sex]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twilight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[feminism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[abortion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sex]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[twilight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[child grooming]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://sarahgetscritical.wordpress.com/?p=71</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[With the final film of the Twilight Saga to début in UK cinemas this week, the time is ripe to cast an eye of scrutiny upon one of the most popular franchises of the decade. Twilight could have been a positive force in fiction and film, not least because the book is aimed primarily at girls, with [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=71&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With the final film of the <em>Twilight Saga</em> to début in UK cinemas this week, the time is ripe to cast an eye of scrutiny upon one of the most popular franchises of the decade. <em>Twilight</em> could have been a positive force in fiction and film, not least because the book is aimed primarily at girls, with a female protagonist, speaking of female experience, written by a woman, and with the film itself being directed by a woman. In fact, <em>Eclipse</em> attracted audiences that were 80% female and scraped in a whopping £45 million (1). Since then, <em>Twilight</em> has had a considerable knock-on effect, not least on the revival of vampire fiction, but in the fiction industry &#8211; with <em>50 Shades of Grey</em> starting its life as a slash fiction version of <em>Twilight</em>. The effects of<em> Twilight</em> are boggling, but what other knock-on effects are we missing?</p>
<p><em>Twilight</em> teaches very dangerous lessons to its readers and viewers.</p>
<ol>
<li>Unhealthy, emotionally abusive relationships are desirable &#8211; see Edward and Bella.</li>
<li>Women&#8217;s only life choices (&#8220;choice&#8221; is a key word here) are to get married, have children, and be a stay-at-home mum.</li>
<li>Sex is bad. Abortion is even worse.</li>
<li>Child-grooming is acceptable so long as the adult really loves &#8220;his&#8221; child.</li>
</ol>
<p>(NB. I will be talking in very gender binary and white-washing ways, because <em>Twilight</em> erases all non-het sexualities and people of colour.)</p>
<p><strong>Let&#8217;s begin with number one.</strong> Edward Cullen and Bella Swan have an emotionally abusive relationship. As defined by<em> Women&#8217;s Aid</em>:</p>
<ul>
<li>destructive criticism, name calling, sulking</li>
<li>pressure tactics</li>
<li>lying to you, or to your friends and family about you</li>
<li>persistently putting you down in front of other people</li>
<li>never listening or responding when you talk</li>
<li>isolating you from friends and family, monitoring your phone calls, emails, texts and letters</li>
<li>checking up on you, following you, not letting you go out alone (2)</li>
</ul>
<p>So let&#8217;s go through these. If you&#8217;ve read any of the <em>Twilight</em> books, alarm bells should immediately be ringing in your head right now. Edward constantly employs &#8220;pressure tactics,&#8221; the number one example being manipulating Bella into marrying him. Bella doesn&#8217;t <em>want</em> to get married, she is mortified by the idea, and only goes through with the marriage because she wants to have sex with Edward. This is blackmail. Withholding sex in order to achieve what he wants at the expense of Bella is highly abusive.</p>
<p>Edward monitors Bella throughout the entire series, from having Alice check her future, to literally stalking her to Phoenix, to sneaking into her bedroom to watch her sleep (before they&#8217;ve even spoken! See <em>Midnight Sun</em>), and so on. And what is most worrying about this is that in the context of the narrative, these abusive traits are romanticised and idealised. This normalises abusive behaviour, and considering the demographic as<em> Twilight</em> (tween and teenagers who are first forming their ideas about love and sex) this is even more disgraceful. She even fears telling him the truth: &#8220;I&#8217;d given more information than necessary in my unwilling honesty, and I worried it would provoke the stranger anger that flared whenever I slipped and revealed too clearly how obsessed I was.&#8221; <em>Twilight</em>, chapter 11, p.230. This is not the hallmark of a healthy relationship. This is <em>fear</em>.</p>
<p>We also see Edward isolating Bella from her friends and family. For example, he takes the engine out of her car to prevent her from seeing her friend, Jacob.</p>
<p>Edward lies to Bella at the start of <em>New Moon</em>, when he tells her that he doesn&#8217;t want to be with her any more, when in actuality he is trying to &#8220;protect&#8221; her. This shows his disregard for Bella as an equal in their relationship, with equal input, and ability to make choices for herself. Not only this, but after he disappears from her life, he also removes every item that might remind her of him. All the photographs, tapes, etc. He gives her no choice and has no respect or consideration for how this might effect her.</p>
<p>Examples of destructive criticism can also be found in the books&#8230;</p>
<blockquote><p>“Bella, it&#8217;s not my fault if you are exceptionally unobservant.”</p>
<p>“Bella, you are utterly absurd.”</p>
<p>“Damn it, Bella! You&#8217;ll be the death of me, I swear you will.”</p>
<p>“You aren&#8217;t exactly the best judge of what is or isn&#8217;t dangerous.”</p></blockquote>
<p>Suddenly, Twilight is starting to seem a lot less romantic and a lot more abusive. The last thing that we should ever be doing is glorifying this type of behaviour.</p>
<p><strong>Moving onto point number two</strong>: women&#8217;s life choices or lack thereof.</p>
<p>In the <em>Twilight Saga</em>, we are never presented with any other option for women other than to get married and have children. I&#8217;m not just talking about Bella here. Think about it. Is there any significant female character who does something as subversive as, err, having a career? Renee, Esme, Alice, Rosaline,&#8230;</p>
<p>Drawing a blank? I am too. So let&#8217;s turn to the author of <em>Twilight</em>, Stephanie Meyer to hear her take on this:</p>
<p>&#8220;In my own opinion (key word), the foundation of feminism is this: being able to choose.&#8221; (3)</p>
<p>I wouldn&#8217;t argue that &#8220;being able to choose&#8221; is the keystone of feminism. The keystone of feminism is equality of the sexes in domestic and public arenas and in legislation. However, let&#8217;s continue and tackle what is problematic about <em>Twilight</em> and the &#8220;choices&#8221; available to the female characters: do they have any choices at all?</p>
<p>If you are never presented with an alternative, then you don&#8217;t have any choice. You just have the one path that every woman treads. There is nothing wrong with being married, having children and being a stay-at-home mother. Let me be clear here. But there <em>is </em>something wrong to suggest that is your only option. True, Edward tries to encourage Bella to go to college &#8211; that is go to college and <em>then</em> we&#8217;ll get married. That isn&#8217;t really an alternative option. In fact, the only alternative option that Bella ever gets is to be in a relationship with Jacob instead of Edward.</p>
<p>Besides which, does Bella really have a choice in all of this? The books would suggest otherwise. Let me throw a few quotes at you:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;I didn&#8217;t know if there ever was a choice, really. I was already in too deep.&#8221; <em>Twilight</em>, chapter 7, p.139.</p>
<p>&#8220;Our relationship couldn&#8217;t continue to balance, as it did, on the point of a knife. We would fall off one edge or the other, depending entirely on his decision, or his instincts. My decision was made, made before I&#8217;d ever consciously chosen.&#8221; <em>Twilight</em>, chapter 13, p.248.</p>
<p>&#8220;There was no way around it; I couldn&#8217;t resist him in anything.&#8221; <em>Twilight</em>, chapter 13, p.284.</p></blockquote>
<p>Even if we are to go by Meyer&#8217;s definition of feminism as the presence of choice, <em>Twilight</em> still fails miserably to be a feminist narrative.</p>
<p><strong>Now to point three.</strong> How are sex and abortion handled in the saga?</p>
<p>It will come as no news to you that Stephanie Meyer is a Mormon, who in her spare time preaches abstinence in high schools.</p>
<p>Bella and Edward only have sex once married, surprise surprise. But what is all the more surprising is that despite having sex within the confines of a marriage, Bella is still punished for her sexuality. She becomes immediately pregnant, which she didn&#8217;t want to happen, but what is more important is that the pregnancy she endures is a particularly punishing one. She is violently sick, loses most of her body weight, and would have died had she not been made a vampire during the birth.</p>
<p>The pro-life rhetoric is blatant in the books and film. With everyone but Bella and Rosalie on the &#8220;bad&#8221; side &#8211; that is, the pro-life side. Whilst Bella speaks of the &#8220;baby,&#8221; Edward speaks of the &#8220;foetus.&#8221; Edward tells Bella to &#8220;get rid of it,&#8221; but his pleas do nothing.  We are meant to feel sympathy for Bella, who almost dies trying to keep the child alive. But all that this promotes is that women should carry their pregnancies through to full term, no matter what the danger to them, even at the cost of their lives.</p>
<p><strong>And finally, point four</strong>: child grooming. No matter how many times a Twihard stresses that the child &#8220;imprinting&#8221; in the Twilight books is <em>not</em> paedophilic, I maintain that is is, and this is why&#8230;</p>
<p>For those not familiar with the Twilight universe, werewolf imprinting is when a member of the pack (all male bar one female, who doesn&#8217;t imprint in the books) falls in love unconditionally with a girl. (And of course it&#8217;s a girl, because werewolves can&#8217;t be gay, duh.) And this girl can be of any age, apparently, though conveniently they never imprint on old women. So we see several cases where werewolves imprint on children and even babies. But this isn&#8217;t paedophilic, remember, because he loves the child like a father, brother, uncle until the girl comes of age. And the girl will fall in love with her werewolf because it&#8217;s &#8220;hard to resist that level of devotion.&#8221;</p>
<p>The definition of child-grooming from Wikipedia (4):</p>
<blockquote><p>Child grooming refers to actions deliberately undertaken with the aim of befriending and establishing an emotional connection with a child, to lower the child&#8217;s inhibitions in preparation for sexual activity with the child, or exploitation.</p></blockquote>
<p>And all the parents are understanding and accepting of imprinting &#8211; even Edward and Bella when Jacob imprints on their newborn child! So the child will grow up believing it&#8217;s okay, their parents telling them it&#8217;s okay and encouraging the relationship, being told that the werewolf is in love with her, leaving little room for her own choice in partner.  This relationship throughout their childhood will naturally lead to sex when they come of age &#8211; turn back to Wikipedia: &#8220;in preparation for sexual activity with the child.&#8221;</p>
<p>When you go to see the final Twilight film this week next &#8211; though I would encourage you to watch something else &#8211; please bear all this in mind. When you swoon at the romance of Edward&#8217;s controlling behaviour, Jacob&#8217;s devotion for Renesmee, please try to remember the underlying meaning of all of these plot developments.</p>
<p><span id="more-71"></span></p>
<p>(1) http://www.guardian.co.uk/film/filmblog/2010/jul/12/twilight-eclipse-feminism</p>
<p>(2) http://www.womensaid.org.uk/domestic_violence_topic.asp?section=0001000100220042&amp;sectionTitle=Emotional+abuse</p>
<p>(3) http://stepheniemeyer.com/bd_faq.html</p>
<p>(4) http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Child_grooming</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://sarahgetscritical.wordpress.com/category/ideology/feminism/abortion/'>Abortion</a>, <a href='http://sarahgetscritical.wordpress.com/category/ideology/feminism/'>Feminism</a>, <a href='http://sarahgetscritical.wordpress.com/category/literature/'>Literature</a>, <a href='http://sarahgetscritical.wordpress.com/category/review-2/'>Review</a>, <a href='http://sarahgetscritical.wordpress.com/category/sex/'>Sex</a>, <a href='http://sarahgetscritical.wordpress.com/category/literature/twilight/'>Twilight</a> Tagged: <a href='http://sarahgetscritical.wordpress.com/tag/abortion-2/'>abortion</a>, <a href='http://sarahgetscritical.wordpress.com/tag/child-grooming/'>child grooming</a>, <a href='http://sarahgetscritical.wordpress.com/tag/feminism-2/'>feminism</a>, <a href='http://sarahgetscritical.wordpress.com/tag/marriage/'>marriage</a>, <a href='http://sarahgetscritical.wordpress.com/tag/review/'>review</a>, <a href='http://sarahgetscritical.wordpress.com/tag/sex-2/'>sex</a>, <a href='http://sarahgetscritical.wordpress.com/tag/twilight-2/'>twilight</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/71/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/71/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/71/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/71/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/71/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/71/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/71/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/71/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/71/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/71/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/71/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/71/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/71/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/71/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=71&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://sarahgetscritical.wordpress.com/2012/11/13/a-feminist-critique-of-twilight-emotional-abuse-child-grooming-and-pro-choice-plots/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/70c4515ac1f47484a9b31d2e38dc2994?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Sarizzle</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Coming Clean About My Age</title>
		<link>http://rasjacobson.com/2012/11/14/coming-clean-about-my-age/</link>
		<comments>http://rasjacobson.com/2012/11/14/coming-clean-about-my-age/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2012 03:55:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>renée a. schuls-jacobson</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[When Life Doesn't Fit in a File Folder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Birthday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[getting older]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[I Love Lucy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lucille Ball]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lying about age]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Metairie Park Country Day School]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Survivor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[teaching and age]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rasjacobson.com/?p=13463</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[My birthday is coming up, y’all. Yup, this summer girl was born in November. You know what that means. My parents got busy around Valentine’s Day. It means this year I turn 50. Whaaat? Well, kind of. Lucille Ball once said: &#8220;The secret to staying young is to live honestly, eat slowly and lie about [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=13463&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://rasjacobson.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/screen-shot-2012-11-14-at-10-14-04-pm.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-13497" title="Screen Shot 2012-11-14 at 10.14.04 PM" alt="" src="http://rasjacobson.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/screen-shot-2012-11-14-at-10-14-04-pm.png?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>My birthday is coming up, y’all.</p>
<p>Yup, this <a href="http://rasjacobson.com/2010/08/23/in-which-season-do-you-shine/">summer girl</a> was born in November.</p>
<p>You know what that means.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration:line-through;">My parents got busy around Valentine’s Day.</span></p>
<p>It means this year I turn 50.</p>
<p>Whaaat?</p>
<p>Well, kind of.</p>
<div class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://commons.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Lucy_as_superman_1957.JPG" target="_blank"><img class="zemanta-img-inserted zemanta-img-configured" title="Lucy watches Little Ricky's birthday party fro..." alt="Lucy watches Little Ricky's birthday party fro..." src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/f/f2/Lucy_as_superman_1957.JPG/300px-Lucy_as_superman_1957.JPG" height="385" width="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Lucy watches Little Ricky&#8217;s birthday party from the window ledge. (Photo credit: Wikipedia)</p></div>
<p>Lucille Ball once said:</p>
<h1><span style="color:#3366ff;">&#8220;The secret to staying young is to live honestly, eat slowly and lie about your age.&#8221;</span></h1>
<p>How much do <em>I Love Lucy</em>?</p>
<p>Here’s the 411.</p>
<p>When I first started teaching, I was 23, just a few years older than some of my 12<sup>th</sup> grade students!</p>
<p>When I introduced myself, I made a point of tacking on a few extra years. I said I was 25. Seven extra years seemed like the right amount of padding.</p>
<p>When I moved to New Orleans, I continued to add years. I felt I needed the cushion, so parents would nod and smile instead of raise disapproving eyebrows. And so my students would believe I was seasoned and complete my assignments without giving me grief.</p>
<p>I never lied to my employers. The Headmaster and English Department Chair at Metairie Park Country day School knew precisely how <span style="text-decoration:line-through;">green</span> old I was when I was hired.</p>
<p>A few years ago, I realized I’ve been in my 40’s for nearly fifteen years.</p>
<p>And that made me remember my grandmother who told people she was 29.</p>
<p>For decades.</p>
<p>After she stopped wearing wigs and wore her thinning hair in loose ponytails wrapped in twine, she was 29. After her eyes dulled and her skin wrinkled, she was 29. After her toenails yellowed and her remaining teeth fell out of her mouth, she was 29.</p>
<p>It was preposterous.</p>
<p>No-one bought it. It was silly and a little pitiful.</p>
<p>I vowed to go the other way.</p>
<p>So I padded.</p>
<p>This year, I could have told my students that I was 50.</p>
<p>Because if you tack on five extra years&#8230;well, I look pretty freaking good for 50, right?</p>
<div id="attachment_13495" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 460px"><a href="http://rasjacobson.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/jacobson-barmitzvah-06-23-12-0729-version-2.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-13495 " title="Jacobson.BarMitzvah.06.23.12-0729 - Version 2" alt="" src="http://rasjacobson.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/jacobson-barmitzvah-06-23-12-0729-version-2.jpg?w=450&#038;h=614" height="614" width="450" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Feeling groovy.</p></div>
<p>And yet.</p>
<p>I’ve kind of caught up with myself.</p>
<p>These days, I am grateful for this body that continues to get me where it needs to go – even if I sometimes have <a href="http://rasjacobson.com/2012/01/31/the-curse-of-the-migraine/">headaches</a> and <a href="http://rasjacobson.com/2011/02/07/lessons-from-the-dance-floor/">get dizzy</a> and <a href="http://rasjacobson.com/2010/10/21/i-hit-a-wall/">fall down</a>. I am grateful for my eyes, which still appreciate all the beauty around me – even if the view is a little blurry. I just have to remember to <del>find</del> put on <a href="http://rasjacobson.com/2011/12/01/cat-eye-glasses/">my glasses</a>. I will never have pretty model’s hands, but I have four fingers that help me to tap out what I want to say. Fingers that help me punch buttons on the phone to speak to old friends and new. Fingers that are attached to hands that reach out to offer assistance, to squeeze shoulders. Hands that are attached to arms which can swallow people up in<a href="http://rasjacobson.com/2012/05/09/sons-and-thunderstorms/"> hugs</a>. And even if <a href="http://rasjacobson.com/2010/12/03/an-unwelcome-dx/">my vocal cords are toasted</a>, I realized I have these things called ears that work really well, too.</p>
<p>So the jig is up.</p>
<p>Lucy, we&#8217;re back to living honestly.</p>
<p>On Sunday, I’ll be 45.</p>
<p>Right where I’m supposed to be.</p>
<p>A wife.</p>
<p>A mother.</p>
<p>A daughter.</p>
<p><span style="color:#3366ff;"><a href="http://rasjacobson.com/2012/11/02/do-you-think-i-could-survive/"><span style="color:#3366ff;">A contestant on </span></a></span><a href="http://rasjacobson.com/2012/11/02/do-you-think-i-could-survive/"><i>Survivor</i></a>.</p>
<p>Just kidding.</p>
<p>But a girl can hold onto her dreams, right?</p>
<p><strong><span style="color:#3366ff;">Have you ever lied about your age? How are you doing with the growing older thing? </span></strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">tweet me @rasjacobson</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/13463/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/13463/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=13463&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://rasjacobson.com/2012/11/14/coming-clean-about-my-age/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>86</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/de60920b6ecf2e34dc03b81d177c1fd3?s=96&#38;d=monsterid&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">rasjacobson</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://rasjacobson.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/screen-shot-2012-11-14-at-10-14-04-pm.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen Shot 2012-11-14 at 10.14.04 PM</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/f/f2/Lucy_as_superman_1957.JPG/300px-Lucy_as_superman_1957.JPG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Lucy watches Little Ricky&#039;s birthday party fro...</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://rasjacobson.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/jacobson-barmitzvah-06-23-12-0729-version-2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Jacobson.BarMitzvah.06.23.12-0729 - Version 2</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Irrational Fears</title>
		<link>http://theothercourtney.wordpress.com/2012/11/13/irrational-fears/</link>
		<comments>http://theothercourtney.wordpress.com/2012/11/13/irrational-fears/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2012 21:05:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>crpeterson</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[All Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anxiety]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anxiety girl]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[counselor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fears]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[irrational fears]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mental-health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[people]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[therapist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[therapy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[worry]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://theothercourtney.wordpress.com/?p=3835</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Irrational fears are something I spent a good portion of my time in therapy talking about. After a few months and several hundred dollars, my irrational fears no longer caused panic attacks and I was even able to laugh at them! Sometimes I catch myself slipping into my old way of thinking, which is to [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3835&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://theothercourtney.wordpress.com/2012/11/13/irrational-fears/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>62</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://theothercourtney.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/anxiety-girl-comic.jpeg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://theothercourtney.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/anxiety-girl-comic.jpeg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">anxiety-girl-comic</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/858f39f0d7c6573f0a2612107ea925d1?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">crpeterson</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theothercourtney.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/anxiety-girl-comic.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">anxiety-girl-comic</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>News? What News?</title>
		<link>http://combatbabe.com/2012/11/15/news-what-news/</link>
		<comments>http://combatbabe.com/2012/11/15/news-what-news/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2012 16:58:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Combat Babe</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Debatable]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personally Me]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[daily prompt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[discussions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inquiring minds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[national news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[news stations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unendorsed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[world news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing prompt]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://combatbabe.com/?p=186</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This is the response you will receive from me if you ask &#8220;Did you hear the news?&#8221; The Daily Post&#8217;s prompt today is: Link to an item in the news you&#8217;ve been thinking about lately, and write the op-ed you&#8217;d like to see published on the topic. Well as I do not watch, read or [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=186&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This is the response you will receive from me if you ask &#8220;Did you hear the news?&#8221;</p>
<p>The <a title="WordPress Daily Blog" href="http://dailypost.wordpress.com/" target="_blank">Daily Post&#8217;s</a> prompt today is: <a title="IMHO" href="http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2012/11/15/daily-prompt-imho/" target="_blank">Link to an item in the news you&#8217;ve been thinking about lately, and write the op-ed you&#8217;d like to see published on the topic</a>.</p>
<p>Well as I do not watch, read or notice the news, I haven&#8217;t been thinking about any topic in the news. Do not mistake this for not thinking about the events that are happening in these times. Sandy&#8217;s havoc on the people and the devastation she&#8217;s caused is always on my mind. I live in Florida so we are usually well prepared for hurricanes as the people up there can be more prepared for snow storms (which would scare the pants off of me and I do believe you need pants in a snow storm). Everyone affected by this Sandy is in my heart.</p>
<p>I do occasionally click on news articles that were brought to my attention by a Facebook status, a family member, or a friend. A lot of the times I will just have them tell me about it. It may seem as if I am obtuse or flippant about the news and maybe I am, but first you must understand my reasonings and if you don&#8217;t you can choose to comment or email your thoughts. Or go on your merry way. No harm no foul. My email is in my &#8216;about what&#8217; page (which may be more opinion than fact).</p>
<p><a href="http://combatbabe.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/extra-animation-for-web.gif"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-192" title="Extra-animation-for-web" alt="" src="http://combatbabe.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/extra-animation-for-web.gif?w=300&#038;h=248" height="248" width="300" /></a></p>
<p>Journalism is not today what it was made to be. I can&#8217;t, in fact, say it ever was what it was meant for. There were two men in the 1920s that had very different outlooks on what modern Journalism was. *<em>Yes I Wikipedia, but only put forth information with valid citations.</em></p>
<p>Writer Walter Lippman believed (as I believe) that the Journalist&#8217;s role was to simply be a translator/mediator between the elites [facts/story/government nowadays] and the public. The elites would speak and the Journalist would be the middleman to bring it to the public for the public to understand.</p>
<p>American Philosopher John Dewey believed the public was incapable of understanding the issues created by or responded by the elite that it should be discussed and debated. That journalists should not just pass information, but weigh the consequences of the policies being enacted. His form of Journalism developed to be &#8220;Community Journalism&#8221;.</p>
<p>Now these two types of Journalism can both be beneficial if properly used, but they aren&#8217;t. They have been colored and graffiti-ed and there is now no such thing as being completely unbiased. In America, and I am sure many other countries, the news media is a money profiting business.</p>
<p>A news article and an opinion article are blending to where you cannot tell if you are reading one or the other. If you watch the news, local or national, the &#8220;talking heads&#8221; are using cues given to them by the station on how they should deliver a story; subtle nod here, barely noticeable grimace there, head tilt here, inflections and tones of their voice.</p>
<p>False information can be added, information considered unimportant or damaging to the stance of the news station/paper is taken out. Information is told in such a way they are telling you how to interpret it without giving you the chance to interpret it yourself. This can also be said about independent papers and news websites. People delivering the news to the world may not even realize that they are telling the story how they want it to be understood.</p>
<p>You&#8217;re smart to utilize several sources to get the information, but with such bias going on in local, national, world news how are you to know you&#8217;re really getting the facts. It happened this way here, but happened that way there. A or B? Which do you believe?</p>
<p>Just my honest <strong>opinion.</strong></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/186/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/186/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=186&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://combatbabe.com/2012/11/15/news-what-news/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>18</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://combatbabe.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/extra-animation-for-web.gif?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://combatbabe.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/extra-animation-for-web.gif?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Extra-animation-for-web</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/1e01408a20f7e2b961116ec043486eee?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">combatbabe</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://combatbabe.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/extra-animation-for-web.gif?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Extra-animation-for-web</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nasal Etiquette: The Top Five Offenders</title>
		<link>http://prettyfeetpoptoe.com/2012/11/14/nasal-etiquette/</link>
		<comments>http://prettyfeetpoptoe.com/2012/11/14/nasal-etiquette/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2012 17:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>prettyfeetpoptoe</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bogey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cattle prod]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Comedy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Common cold]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mucus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nasal cavity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nose]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[People]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sinusitis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sneeze]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snot]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://prettyfeetpoptoe.com/?p=1697</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;Coughs and sneezes spread diseases&#8221;. They also bring you out in bruises. Why? because if not managed correctly, people like myself will shove a cattle prod up your rear end, causing you to &#8220;accidentally&#8221; fall down some stairs, that&#8217;s why. We&#8217;re into that niche 364 day period fondly known as &#8220;cold &#8216;n&#8217; flu season&#8221; and this brings [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1697&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://prettyfeetpoptoe.com/2012/11/14/nasal-etiquette/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>33</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/fe4fbc27cfb4a0cbb8989a13f41d9c4e?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">prettyfeetpoptoe</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/a/ac/Fredott.jpg/300px-Fredott.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">English: Fred Ott in mid-sneeze. Still from 18...</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Moments of our life together</title>
		<link>http://diaryofasadwidow.wordpress.com/2012/11/13/96/</link>
		<comments>http://diaryofasadwidow.wordpress.com/2012/11/13/96/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2012 17:35:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>dswidow</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Death]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Grief]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPChallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[memories]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://diaryofasadwidow.wordpress.com/?p=96</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The Goodbye It was time.  I walked in, your wife, your best friend, your lover.  You had been cleaned up, tubes removed, hair combed, fresh gown.  I was able to hold you and kiss you, to say goodbye.  To ask your forgiveness for letting you go.  To tell you how much I loved you and [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=96&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>The Goodbye</strong></p>
<p>It was time.  I walked in, your wife, your best friend, your lover.  You had been cleaned up, tubes removed, hair combed, fresh gown.  I was able to hold you and kiss you, to say goodbye.  To ask your forgiveness for letting you go.  To tell you how much I loved you and always would.  To tell you about everything good and wonderful we had together, and to talk of all we had done, and what we had meant to each other.  I did all the talking; I don’t know if you were aware of my voice or were able to hear what I said, or even know I was there and feel my arms around you and be aware of my presence.  Were you present or were you already gone to whatever next plane of existence does, or does not, exist?  An hour went by, the longest and worst hour of my life.  At the end of that hour, I walked out, your widow.</p>
<p>This is the core, the key moment that changed my life, but it cannot stand alone.  Other moments in the chain of our life need to be told.</p>
<p><strong>The Kiss</strong></p>
<p>You turned toward me and grinned; a rakish, sexy grin, as you suddenly leaned in and kissed me.  We were walking to my car on the way to a ballgame.  It was our third date, and you had not yet made a move.  I had, giving you a big hug after our first date, holding hands on date two and even trying for a kiss you adroitly, suavely, managed to elude.  I had resigned myself to being just friends until you gave me that sweet, unexpected first kiss.</p>
<p><strong>The Proposal</strong></p>
<p>Mid-December; a time of year I would come to realize was your low point.  Memories of family members who were gone, of disappointments and failures haunted you every year at this time.  We stood in my kitchen.  You were depressed and feeling low.  I was giving you a hug.  You turned toward me and said something to the effect of how I really did care, and how we were good for each other.  I agreed, saying we were a team, a unit, a partnership.  You said to me “Who knows how much time we’ll have together.  Let’s be together, always, for whatever time we do have.”</p>
<p><strong>The Realization</strong></p>
<p>It was spring, the sun was shining, and we sat on the couch making plans for the day.  The sun shone through the window and I realized that you were glowing in the light; glowing yellow; glowing a color that was not right, that no healthy person should be.  You had been acting oddly, feeling poorly for some time, going to the doctor for the last 2 years, having tests, being checked for different things, but never with any real diagnosis.  You were tired all the time, less active and not as interested in doing things.  That morning, I realized that there was something seriously wrong with you, and that our lives were going to be massively changed.</p>
<p><strong>The Premonition</strong></p>
<p>Late May, early in the morning as we were getting dressed, I saw you in profile.  You were gaunt and skeletal.  Your legs had lost their musculature, and skin was hanging loose where only a few months ago there had been sleek and shapely muscles.  You had to lean on the wall to put your pants on.  You looked like a ghost, 20 years older than your age, like a man who was fast approaching death.  I had a sudden chill and the hair on my arms rose up; I had a premonition, not a guess, but a moment of sure clarity, and I knew with absolute certainty that you were dying.</p>
<p><strong>The Phone Call</strong></p>
<p>You were in the hospital, having arrived there a week earlier via ambulance.  Don’t worry, the doctors said.  This happens, it’s treatable, and we can adjust medications so it’s less likely to happen again.  The physical therapist came by every day to work with you on standing up, walking, balance, things that had been normal 2 weeks ago.  Recovery, release, rehabilitation; those were our new words.  I had just gotten home after spending all afternoon with you.  The phone rang.  It was the nurse:  “there’s been an accident,” she said; you had been found on the floor, unresponsive.  That night you were moved to Intensive Care; there was evidence of a small stroke, and you were far less responsive than you had been earlier that day.</p>
<p>That was the first time the phrase “circling the drain” started repeating itself in my head.  That was when the conversations with doctors started to shift.  There was no more talk of rehabilitation, recovery, release; I started hearing about transplants and timelines.  There was no more inevitability regarding your getting better.</p>
<p><strong>The Decision</strong></p>
<p>I knew the answer before they said a word, before they entered the room, from 10 feet back.  The grim faces, the apprehensive look, the hesitation; I knew.  The transplant committee had met, and their decision was to turn you down.  There was no other option; you were dying.  No deus ex machina would rescue us; no 11<sup>th</sup> hour reprieve was possible.  You were going to die.  I would be a widow.  It would be soon.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/96/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/96/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=96&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://diaryofasadwidow.wordpress.com/2012/11/13/96/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>27</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/81b0659b139e953a4afd8d2d99791fe6?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">dswidow</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Most Important Moment</title>
		<link>http://rolbos.wordpress.com/2012/11/13/the-most-important-moment/</link>
		<comments>http://rolbos.wordpress.com/2012/11/13/the-most-important-moment/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2012 22:01:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Amos van der Merwe</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[smalltown short stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[instagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[postaday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weekly writing challenge]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rolbos.wordpress.com/?p=1688</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Servaas asked the question simply because  the silence bothered him. Here they all are, glasses in hand , in front of the counter and next to the fire – and nobody has anything to say. Truth be told: the drought has already been discussed, and Kleinpiet’s marriage isn’t news any more. There’s nothing new in [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1688&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignleft" alt="" src="http://ak7.picdn.net/shutterstock/videos/1998323/preview/stock-footage-chronograph-clock-in-motion-clock-minute-second-and-hour-hands-moving-fast.jpg" height="179" width="320" />Servaas asked the question simply because  the silence bothered him. Here they all are, glasses in hand , in front of the counter and next to the fire – and nobody has anything to say. Truth be told: the drought has already been discussed, and Kleinpiet’s marriage isn’t news any more. There’s nothing new in Sammie’s Shop. Rolbos, Servaas has had to accept, has nothing o discuss.</p>
<p>That’s why he asked the question. For a few seconds, the silence endured.</p>
<p>“The moment that changed my life?” Vetfaan scratches his head. “There were a few, I suppose. I kissed a girl in Standard seven. Then I got my driver’s license, called up to the army and received my first Communion all in the same month. And then, in the army <a title="" href="#_edn1">[i]</a>….” No, he can’t tell those stories again.</p>
<p>“I remember the moment clearly,” Gertruida comes to his rescue. “It’s the first time I borrowed a book from the library. <i>Famous Five</i> by Enid Blyton, of course, with the two boys, two girls and the dog named Timothy. I was trapped in that Treasure Island story from the first word. I haven’t stopped reading since. It changed my life.”</p>
<p>The conversation picks up now, with funerals, teachers, sport achievements and the flood of 1988. Old Marco remembers his father telling him the facts of life. Lucinda blushes as she says it was the moment she first set eyes on Boggel.</p>
<p>Boggel doesn’t have to feign his surprise. After all, he’s had his share of life-changing moments . The sad times in the orphanage, and then there was Mary. Mary Mitchell…<a title="" href="#_edn2">[ii]</a> He often wonders about her, remembering the Easter he spent with her. And the moment he shot her father – that certainly had a huge impact on his life – one he dare not share with anybody, ever.  But then Lucinda arrived. Lucinda with the perfect body and the laughing eyes and the endearing way she looks at him.</p>
<p>“Listen,” he says as he serves another round, “you guys are sitting there, trying to define the single moment that had the most impact on your lives. That’s good and well. But I think – my little opinion – that there are many in each of our lives. We draw the first breath. We exhale for the last time. And in between, every second changes you. That’s why we call it Life: I looked it up, and Gertruida can correct me if I’m wrong. The original word was ‘lip’ which was later incorporated into Old English as ‘lif’, which meant ‘<i>to remain, persevere and continue’</i>. And in that, ladies in gentlemen, lies the secret. Anything that continues, has to change. It’s like breathing – if you don’t continue changing, you cannot claim to be living.”</p>
<p>Gertruida looks up in surprise. Since when has Boggel been so clever?  A veritable philosopher? She shakes her head; the little bent man has a way of surprising her every now and then. Taking up the challenge, she sits up straight:</p>
<p>“Yes, that’s true. The very essence of life is change – not only from generation to generation, but from moment to moment. We adapt to circumstances, both physical and emotional. Not a single second of your life is exactly similar to any other second. As long as we live, this is a continuous process. And then, eventually, all living things die – when change becomes physically impossible and we decay away to whatever we are made of. In all forms of life , this is true, except…” here she glances over at Boggel with a triumphant smile, “the immortal jellyfish &#8211; <i>Turritopsis nutricula. </i>Scientists think this hydrozoa can indefinitely regenerate itself; provided it doesn’t get smashed on a rock or eaten by some predator.”</p>
<p>“There is another thing that doesn’t die, Gertruida. At least I think so. Love. Affection can degenerate, so can fascination and friendship. But love – true love – endures and changes and goes on continuing. That, I think, is the most significant event in anybody’s life: when he or she discovers love. Love is the thing that makes you adapt. Without it, hate takes over and you remain rooted to the spot, unable to persevere, continue or remain alive.”</p>
<p>“Well, blow me down!” Servaas sits back in wonder. “You guys are suddenly cleverer than a crate full of owls! I simply asked a silly question to break the silence; now I have to take notes to go and study at home.”</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">***</p>
<p>That’s the funny thing about Boggel’s Place. Out there in the Kalahari, the people have a lot of time to think. This makes them quite different to customers in the bar around the corner in any given city, where people discuss subjects that lead to a static life: empty jokes and hollow phrases that’ll never change lives and cannot be recalled when the hangover draws a blanket over the next day.</p>
<p>Here the slow seconds tick by, and every one of them counts. Sometimes they lead to some hilarity, sometimes to chaos and sometimes even to sadness when grief is shared. But always, always, the patrons go home a little different to what they were when they went there. Not different in an alcoholic way – different because they talked, laughed, cried and shared stories. They communicated – in the deepest sense of the word.</p>
<p>Life-changing moments?</p>
<p>They are the speciality of the house at Boggel’s: every second counts. It&#8217;s so sad that many people never realise this simple fact.</p>
<p>Jellyfish can start all over again.</p>
<p>We can&#8217;t.</p>
<p>There are too many rocks in the way.</p>
<span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='640' height='390' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/RZUonmbtVQo?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span>
<p><b>Alfredo</b></p>
<p>Let&#8217;s drink, let&#8217;s drink from the joyous chalices</p>
<p>that beauty so truly enhances.</p>
<p>And the brief moment will be inebriated</p>
<p>with voluptuousness.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s drink for the ecstatic feeling</p>
<p>that love arouses.</p>
<p>Because this all-powerful eye aims straight to the heart.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s drink, my love, and the love among the chalices</p>
<p>will make the kisses warmer.</p>
<p><b>Chorus</b></p>
<p>Ah! Let&#8217;s drink, and the love among the chalices</p>
<p>will make the kisses warmer.</p>
<p><b>Violetta</b></p>
<p>With you all, I can share</p>
<p>my happiest times.</p>
<p>Everything in life</p>
<p>which is not pleasure is foolish.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s enjoy ourselves</p>
<p>for the delight of love is fleeting and quick.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s like a flower that blooms and dies</p>
<p>And we can no longer enjoy it.</p>
<p>So enjoy; A keen and flattering</p>
<p>voice invites us!</p>
<p><b>Chorus</b></p>
<p>Let&#8217;s enjoy the wine and the singing,</p>
<p>the beautiful night, and the laughter.</p>
<p>Let the new day find us in this paradise.</p>
<p><b>Violetta</b></p>
<p>Life means celebration.</p>
<p><b>Alfredo</b></p>
<p>Only if one hasn&#8217;t known love.</p>
<p><b>Violetta</b></p>
<p>Don&#8217;t tell someone who doesn&#8217;t know.</p>
<p><b>Alfredo</b></p>
<p>But this is my fate&#8230;</p>
<p><b>All</b></p>
<p>Let&#8217;s enjoy the wine and the singing,</p>
<p>the beautiful night, and the laughter.</p>
<p>Let the new day find us in this paradise</p>
<div>
<p><a title="" href="#_ednref1">[i]</a> <a href="http://wp.me/p2alIz-iN">http://wp.me/p2alIz-iN</a></p>
<p>And</p>
<p><a href="http://rolbos.wordpress.com/2012/05/10/vetfaans-war/">http://rolbos.wordpress.com/2012/05/10/vetfaans-war/</a></p>
<p><a title="" href="#_ednref2">[ii]</a> <a href="http://rolbos.wordpress.com/2012/02/04/just-another-winters-tale/">http://rolbos.wordpress.com/2012/02/04/just-another-winters-tale</a></p>
</div>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1688/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1688/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1688&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://rolbos.wordpress.com/2012/11/13/the-most-important-moment/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f0ea25119b3f13f8c7a30dea4afb2460?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">javdm</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ak7.picdn.net/shutterstock/videos/1998323/preview/stock-footage-chronograph-clock-in-motion-clock-minute-second-and-hour-hands-moving-fast.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Instant I Was Broken</title>
		<link>http://crankygiraffe.wordpress.com/2012/11/13/the-instant-i-was-broken/</link>
		<comments>http://crankygiraffe.wordpress.com/2012/11/13/the-instant-i-was-broken/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2012 04:03:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>crankygiraffe</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Abuse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPchallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[postaday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Relationships]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crankygiraffe.wordpress.com/?p=117</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In the shower.  Water is beating down against my back.  Hot water, scalding hot, hotter that I can handle.  I can&#8217;t feel the heat.  I can&#8217;t feel anything &#8211; I am numb. What just happened to me?  I don&#8217;t know.  I can&#8217;t know.  I don&#8217;t want to know. The water is running off my body [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=117&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the shower.  Water is beating down against my back.  Hot water, scalding hot, hotter that I can handle.  I can&#8217;t feel the heat.  I can&#8217;t feel anything &#8211; I am numb.</p>
<p>What just happened to me?  I don&#8217;t know.  I can&#8217;t know.  I don&#8217;t want to know.</p>
<p>The water is running off my body &#8211; hot, dirty, stained.  Out Damned Spot, Out I Say&#8230; It&#8217;s not coming out, it&#8217;s not washing off.  It didn&#8217;t work for her, it won&#8217;t work for me.</p>
<p>In my own house.  In my own bed.  My own lover&#8230; is he a lover?  Monster?  Yes, Monster. What just happened to me?</p>
<p>Knocking on the bathroom door.  Go Away!  Go Away!  I&#8217;m crying.  Words come sopping wet out of my mouth.   Tears are hot, hotter than the water, burning holes in my face.  My beautiful face &#8211; not beautiful anymore.</p>
<p>I thought I was safe, I thought I was loved.  I was in control, yes?  No.  I said No.  Didn&#8217;t I say No?  I thought I said No.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m sorry, he said.  It was a mistake, he said.  I didn&#8217;t mean it, he said.  I Love You&#8230; he said.</p>
<p>He&#8217;s yelling &#8211; through the door, over the water &#8211; the hot, burning water.  I&#8217;m locked in and there&#8217;s no way out.  I am weak.  I was weak.</p>
<p>I am broken. I am gone.</p>
<p>In an instant.</p>
<p>Loved becomes abused.  Confidence becomes uncertainty.  Faith becomes doubt. Life becomes worthless.</p>
<p><em>In response to the <a href="http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2012/11/12/weekly-writing-challenge-in-an-instagram/">weekly writing challenge</a></em></p>
<br /> Tagged: <a href='http://crankygiraffe.wordpress.com/tag/abuse/'>Abuse</a>, <a href='http://crankygiraffe.wordpress.com/tag/dpchallenge/'>DPchallenge</a>, <a href='http://crankygiraffe.wordpress.com/tag/poetry/'>poetry</a>, <a href='http://crankygiraffe.wordpress.com/tag/postaday/'>postaday</a>, <a href='http://crankygiraffe.wordpress.com/tag/relationships/'>Relationships</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/117/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/117/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=117&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crankygiraffe.wordpress.com/2012/11/13/the-instant-i-was-broken/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>19</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/327ea6fd8b8d1f6bce49974f86de1738?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">crankygiraffe</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Transpacific</title>
		<link>http://kingdomofsharks.wordpress.com/2012/11/13/weekly-writing-challenge-transpacific/</link>
		<comments>http://kingdomofsharks.wordpress.com/2012/11/13/weekly-writing-challenge-transpacific/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2012 20:33:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Andrew Johnston</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[People's Republic of China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Changchun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[postaday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://kingdomofsharks.wordpress.com/?p=1046</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[What the hell am I doing here? The leitmotif of my life has been indecision, an unwillingness to take any serious risks. Vacations spent at home, going to the same restaurants and bars &#8211; that&#8217;s me. So what made me think that taking a job overseas was a good idea? Because someone mentioned that it [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1046&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>What the hell am I doing here?</em></p>
<p>The leitmotif of my life has been indecision, an unwillingness to take any serious risks. Vacations spent at home, going to the same restaurants and bars &#8211; that&#8217;s me. So what made me think that taking a job overseas was a good idea? Because someone mentioned that it was a possibility?</p>
<p>This isn&#8217;t me. But maybe there was some part of me that wished I could be that person, that person who sees and does things that others never do.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s just before midnight. I&#8217;m in the backseat of a car driving away from the airport, headed somewhere. The company driver presumably knows, and that&#8217;s all that matters, I guess. We&#8217;re on the freeway, or whatever they&#8217;d call a &#8220;freeway&#8221; around here. It&#8217;s mostly black, interrupted at spaces by lights from buildings in the distance. I feel like I&#8217;m eight years old again, counting the hours on a long drive to the Rockies.</p>
<p><img class="alignleft" title="Lights" alt="" src="http://mw2mk.files.wordpress.com/2008/09/0011.jpg?w=183&#038;h=137" height="137" width="183" />The lights are becoming larger, more focused &#8211; we must be in the city. I stare out the window at the buildings, covered in illuminated signs in an unfamiliar language. I try to pick out words, run them through my head, but I&#8217;m so exhausted that nothing&#8217;s coming. It&#8217;s just so many lines being beamed into my face.</p>
<p>The buildings grow smaller, and the car slows down. We&#8217;re off the freeway now. I can see people on the sidewalks, going about their business. I always wanted to live in a city where the world didn&#8217;t just shut down at ten o&#8217;clock, and I must have found it. Most of them are young people, gathered around tables in the streetlights. They&#8217;re playing chess, but not the kind I&#8217;m used to. Others are just sitting around outside their apartments, laughing and bullshitting and doing what kids do.</p>
<p>The friendly woman in the passenger seat is trying to point out buildings I should remember. This one is a hot pot restaurant. Over there is a bar where they have live music. Here&#8217;s a dry cleaner &#8211; you might need that one day. There&#8217;s no way I&#8217;ll remember any of these places. I don&#8217;t even know where I am. Is this the center of the city? The edge? Would knowing that even help?</p>
<p>Finally, the car comes to a stop behind a building. It&#8217;s damn dark here. I can&#8217;t make anything out &#8211; the buildings are just giant silhouettes against the city lights. I pull myself out of the car, dragging my luggage behind me. A door opens, letting a band of light loose into the alley. There&#8217;s a staircase behind the door, six flights &#8211; the maximum before the building codes require an elevator. I&#8217;m at the very top.</p>
<p>Great.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve insisted upon carrying most of my things, which was clearly a mistake. Gravity has me in a chokehold now. Each time I clear a flight, I&#8217;m thankful I didn&#8217;t slip and pitch down the stairs. How stupid would that be &#8211; to come all this way, only to get my ass kicked by steps? By the fourth floor, I can&#8217;t feel my legs, and I&#8217;m wondering if I&#8217;m even going to make it. But I muscle through, all the way to floor six. The door swings open on my apartment. It&#8217;s not so bad &#8211; I&#8217;ve lived in worse places, and in smaller ones. I drag my things into the bedroom and let them fall to the floor. The woman hands me a complicated-looking key and then I&#8217;m on my own.</p>
<p><a href="http://kingdomofsharks.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/045.jpg"><img class="alignright  wp-image-1047" title="Room" alt="" src="http://kingdomofsharks.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/045.jpg?w=240&#038;h=180" height="180" width="240" /></a>Now I&#8217;m alone. I&#8217;ve lived alone before, but this is different. I try to take a shower, but there&#8217;s no pressure &#8211; I should have paid attention when the woman was explaining the water tank. There are some instant noodles and orange juice in the kitchen, but even though it&#8217;s been hours since I&#8217;ve eaten anything, I&#8217;m not hungry. I&#8217;m just tired. Too tired to sort through my luggage, too tired to change clothes, too tired to do anything but drop on the bed and stare at the ceiling.</p>
<p>It hits me: I&#8217;m here for a year. Twelve months. What the hell am I doing here? I&#8217;ll never make it.</p>
<p>But I did.</p>
<p>(Written for the WordPress <a href="http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2012/11/12/weekly-writing-challenge-in-an-instagram/">Weekly Writing Challenge</a>)</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1046/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1046/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1046&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://kingdomofsharks.wordpress.com/2012/11/13/weekly-writing-challenge-transpacific/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/ee2579316d61c5f697367e4d0e50b618?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">killsmiley</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mw2mk.files.wordpress.com/2008/09/0011.jpg?w=848" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Lights</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://kingdomofsharks.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/045.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Room</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>