<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 23:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Past Present, Future Present and Past Future</title>
		<link>http://amostagreeablepastime.wordpress.com/2012/10/30/past-present-future-present-and-past-future/</link>
		<comments>http://amostagreeablepastime.wordpress.com/2012/10/30/past-present-future-present-and-past-future/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2012 08:34:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Old Gaulian</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[The Library]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Portal 2]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Time Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Doctor Who]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TARDIS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Duke Nukem Time to Kill]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cave Johnson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aperture Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shadow of Memories]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://amostagreeablepastime.wordpress.com/?p=2199</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Time blows my mind.  One minute I&#8217;m a strapping young lad with my whole life ahead of me, and the next minute I&#8217;m a disillusioned nearly-thirty young man looking forward to my next cup of tea.  So if that&#8217;s how I handle time imagine how I handle time travel. Rather not well. Which sucks because [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2199&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://amostagreeablepastime.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/tardis.jpeg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-2208" title="TARDIS" alt="" src="http://amostagreeablepastime.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/tardis.jpeg?w=590"   /></a>Time blows my mind.  One minute I&#8217;m a strapping young lad with my whole life ahead of me, and the next minute I&#8217;m a disillusioned nearly-thirty young man looking forward to my next cup of tea.  So if that&#8217;s how I handle time imagine how I handle time travel.</p>
<p>Rather not well.</p>
<p>Which sucks because I like the idea of wibbly wobbly timey wimey stuff.  Travelling around having an actual causal effect on the world around you is, well let&#8217;s face it,  exciting.  Too bad it&#8217;s also impossible.  Or is it? Actually best not think about it, I like my brain and the thought of little bits of it oozing from my ears doesn&#8217;t really tickle my fancy.  Watching it as a third party however &#8211; that might be a bit of a hoot.  Wait can I even watch myself die?</p>
<p>In a moth to a flame kind of way, despite having a fear of all streams of time &#8211; past present, future present and past future &#8211; I am drawn to media that depicts time travel and all of the perils that lie therein.  And there have been some rather good ones.  But the way time travel is treated in video games is seldom full of twists and turns and a real sense of causality beyond any binary changes to one or two, or a handful at the very most, variables.  Even then the effect seldoms bleeds from one causal event to another, leading to worlds which are in some cases restricted to only a handful of end-game states even where there can be up to ten times more individual changeable events.  This lack of interconnectedness leads to worlds which feel contrived and where it becomes obvious that time travel only exists to serve a narrative or structural purpose within the game.  That&#8217;s awesome and all, but with a concept that can be so mind blowing, it is equally as frustrating to see the treatment of time travel not evolve beyond something that is surface deep.</p>
<p>So why is this?  Why when we have the world plus more in our games these days are we confined to such a piecemeal look into one of the most interesting sci-fi concepts around?</p>
<p>It&#8217;s because time travel is simply the easiest way to present the player with a variety of environments, enemies and challenges without breaking the game&#8217;s narrative.  I feel like I&#8217;m mentioning the PS1 pseudo classic <em>Duke Nukem: Time to Kill </em>every time I write something, but there really is no better example I can think of that uses the concept of time travel simply as a way of putting you into a whole stack of unique locales.  Wild West?  Don&#8217;t mind it I do.  Ancient Greece?  Don&#8217;t forget to bring a toga.  It&#8217;s cool and interesting, or was at least when it was released way back in the late nineties, but it&#8217;s not <em>clever</em> and never makes good use of the fact that good old Duke can go back in time in order to change the future.  Beyond a few scripted events at least.</p>
<p>And honestly you don&#8217;t need time travel to do that.  Evoking the feeling of an era and a time long forgotten doesn&#8217;t require a TARDIS or even some wizz-bang portal, it just requires intelligent thinking.  And when I think intelligent thinking I instantly think of Portal 2 because to put it simply, it is bloody clever.  But not just in the way you first think of it to be clever, what with all the manipulating physical space to solve puzzles and the like.  It is actually a great example of how the narrative and design of the game manages to send the player back in time without ever formally doing so, which is quite a feat.  Using the long forgotten test labs of <em>Aperture Science</em> founder Cave Johnson, complete with 1980&#8242;s decor and office design, Valve were able to send the player back in time to not only capture a time and place long before the game is actually taking place, but to also add layers upon layers of depth to the present within the construct of the game world.  Sure it&#8217;s not <em>actually </em>involving any time travelling but that&#8217;s just the point because it does the &#8216;different time and place&#8217; thing better than games that actually have you stepping back into the past or the future.</p>
<p><a href="http://amostagreeablepastime.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/cave-johnson-portal-2.jpeg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2214" title="Cave Johnson - Portal 2" alt="" src="http://amostagreeablepastime.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/cave-johnson-portal-2-e1351584737878.jpeg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>But when time travelling games get it right, they get it right.  Which brings me to Shadow of Memories, which for me serves as a bit of a benchmark in time travelling video games.  The underrated PS2 classic served up a smorgasbord of choices for the player to make throughout time in a quest to prevent your own murder, that all seemed to have a broader impact on other characters and the gaming world throughout multiple layers of time.  And to keep things interesting as you spend time in the past time still passes in the present.  It is this complex treatment of timelines, spanning multiple centuries from 1584 to 2001, that makes this adventure game stand above the rest in the time travelling stakes.  Sure the game wasn&#8217;t perfect, but it served to present the player with a cohesive where there were multiple points of cause and effect that served to (whether it was real or not) shape the world around you and give you a sense of agency in the outcomes of main character Eike&#8217;s actions.</p>
<p><a href="http://amostagreeablepastime.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/shadow-of-memories.jpeg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2215" title="Shadow of Memories" alt="" src="http://amostagreeablepastime.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/shadow-of-memories.jpeg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>It is frustrating that developers don&#8217;t think beyond the obvious when delving into the depths of time travel.  Sure, Doctor Who boggles my mind sometimes with the seemingly impossible often being the outcome.  But that&#8217;s what I want.  I want time travel to present to me something I have to think about for a while and even when I think I&#8217;ve worked it out, being left unsure as to whether my understanding of the complex weave of time is actually the right one.  I want to walk away from a game with that feeling I get when someone tells me the universe is infinite and ever expanding, the feeling where you just can&#8217;t even contemplate something so your brain just goes into overdrive.  Because time travel, like the universe doesn&#8217;t make sense in most of our minds.  That doesn&#8217;t mean that video games can&#8217;t try and make sense of it.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2199/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2199/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2199&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://amostagreeablepastime.wordpress.com/2012/10/30/past-present-future-present-and-past-future/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/2b1936948ef1b1b95d12e8741fdeaf16?s=96&#38;d=retro&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Old Gaulian</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://amostagreeablepastime.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/tardis.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">TARDIS</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://amostagreeablepastime.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/cave-johnson-portal-2-e1351584737878.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Cave Johnson - Portal 2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://amostagreeablepastime.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/shadow-of-memories.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Shadow of Memories</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gourd Vibrations</title>
		<link>http://measureandstir.com/2012/10/31/gourd-vibrations/</link>
		<comments>http://measureandstir.com/2012/10/31/gourd-vibrations/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 16:04:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Joseph Tkach</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[original creations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alcohol]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bartending]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[booze]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[campari]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[carrot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[carrot juice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cinnamon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cinnamon syrup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cocktail]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cocktailc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[craft cocktails]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drinking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drinks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[juice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[liquor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mixed drinks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mixology]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://measureandstir.com/?p=1414</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Happy Halloween! I wanted to use the scariest ingredient I could think of to make this drink, so I chose Campari, because although it does not scare me, many people seem to be averse to it. I personally enjoy challenging ingredients; I see them as new territories to conquer. James and I had a meal [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1414&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Happy Halloween! I wanted to use the scariest ingredient I could think of to make this drink, so I chose Campari, because although it does not scare me, many people seem to be averse to it. I personally enjoy challenging ingredients; I see them as new territories to conquer. James and I had a meal at a Seattle restaurant called <a href="http://alturarestaurant.com/">Altura</a>, where they served us an aperitif consisting of blood orange juice, carrot juice, and Campari in a miniature hurricane glass. It was only a taste, but the flavor of carrot and Campari paired surprisingly well. Perhaps it should not have been a surprise, as Campari contains the flavor of bitter orange peels, and carrot orange juice is a classic Moroccan combination, with a bit of ginger. </p>
<p>For holidays, I always like to do something a little bit special (just wait til Thanksgiving, wherein I will garnish a drink with a whole roast turkey&#8230;maybe), and James and I had been tossing around the idea of using a gourd as a serving vessel for a while. A raw gourd has sour, savory, and vegetal notes, and we were worried that it might strike a dissonant chord with a mixed drink if we used it as a vessel. The realization that made this whole thing come together was that the flavor of carrot juice could work as a bridge between the gourd vessel and the other flavors in the drink, provided that they mixed well with carrot.</p>
<p>The Gourd vessel itself was unexpectedly resilient. We were sure it was going to leak, but through artful placement of bamboo skewers, we managed to build a chalice that was thoroughly seaworthy. After that, the hardest part of making this drink was coming up with a suitable pun. Names that did not make the cut:</p>
<ul>
<li>The Gourd, the Bad, and the Ugly</li>
<li>Oh My Gourd!</li>
<li>Gourd with the Wind</li>
<li>Here Today, Gourd Tomorrow</li>
<li>Gourd out of my Mind</li>
<li>Gourds and Ghoblins</li>
<li>Casper the Friendly Gourd</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;<br />
OK, I&#8217;m done. And I&#8217;m sorry.<br />
 <a href="http://measureandstir.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/halloween-gourd-drink.png"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1415" title="halloween gourd drink" alt="" src="http://measureandstir.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/halloween-gourd-drink.png?w=590" /></a></p>
<blockquote><p><strong>Gourd Vibrations</strong><br />
2 oz Carrot Juice<br />
1.5 oz Bourbon (Evan Williams)<br />
.75 oz Campari<br />
.5 oz Cinnamon Syrup<br />
Dash of Aromatic Bitters (Angostura)<br />
Shake over ice and double-strain into a chalice made out of a freaking gourd. Garnish with a cinnamon stick and a sense of accomplishment.
</p></blockquote>
<p>As with many fresh juices, carrot juice has a mild flavor, easily overpowered by the more robust qualities of common cocktail ingredients. I had to add a full two ounces before it could stand up to the bourbon and cinnamon syrup. The quantity of Campari in this was also counter-intuitive, but when you are creating a cocktail, the rule is add a little bit, taste, add a little bit, taste. It&#8217;s a process that won&#8217;t always take you to the place you expect.</p>
<p>Bottoms Up!</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1414/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1414/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1414&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://measureandstir.com/2012/10/31/gourd-vibrations/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/004183c462114f4c70c7cfb8ee681e63?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">josephtkach</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://measureandstir.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/halloween-gourd-drink.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">halloween gourd drink</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Just Say No to Rugs</title>
		<link>http://contimplating.com/2012/10/30/just-say-no-to-rugs/</link>
		<comments>http://contimplating.com/2012/10/30/just-say-no-to-rugs/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2012 21:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>contimplating.com</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Potpourrhetoric]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beauty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cosmetics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hair]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mid-life crisis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Occupy movement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ronco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spray hair]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[toupees]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://contimplating.com/?p=318</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Now that I&#8217;m into my mid-forties, I am looking for ideas on what to do for my mid-life crisis that 20 years from now I can look back on and say, “Wow, was that ever a mid-life crisis!”  I&#8217;m talking crazy, dangerous things like juggling flaming machetes or switching to briefs. One idea I&#8217;ve had [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=318&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Now that I&#8217;m into my mid-forties, I am looking for ideas on what to do for my mid-life crisis that 20 years from now I can look back on and say, “Wow, was that ever a mid-life crisis!”  I&#8217;m talking crazy, dangerous things like juggling flaming machetes or switching to briefs.</p>
<p>One idea I&#8217;ve had is to get my iPhone out and use my Sprint service to get my Facebook friends together and go to Sears to purchase a bunch of Columbia tents, then pitch them in a public park while we survive on Starbucks and Kraft Mac&#8217;n'Cheese cooked over a Coleman stove in our soggy Levi&#8217;s and Patagonia rain coats in the hopes of getting ABC, NBC or CBS to cover us as we rail against evil corporations. But somebody&#8217;s already done that.</p>
<p>As I mentioned last post, I think I&#8217;d like to do something stupid with my hair—specifically my hairline, which is backing up to the point where OSHA is making me install a safety signal. (Beep. Beep. Beep. Beep.) I tend to be continually frustrated with the looks of my hair even though I spend upwards of $12 on it every eight weeks.  I need to do something.</p>
<div id="attachment_329" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 230px"><a href="http://contimplating.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/contimplating-logo-2.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-329" title="contimplating logo" alt="" src="http://contimplating.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/contimplating-logo-2.jpg?w=590"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Don&#8217;t let my logo fool you; I do not have this much hair.</p></div>
<p>Transplants are something to do but can run about $20,000, which is more than even my teenagers&#8217; grocery bill and therefore unaffordable. Besides that, I&#8217;m more than a little concerned about the area from which the hair is harvested.</p>
<p>A lot of guys my age are getting toupees in order to make them look vernal and virile, as opposed to paternal and viral. This is definitely an option for me because it is a known fact that toupees make one resemble an Adonis. As you remember, Adonis is the Greek god of beauty who seduced Aphrodite by walking around in public with an opossum on his head.</p>
<p>Toupee manufacturers often claim that a toupee looks great and blends into one&#8217;s natural hair such that it is undetectable by the casual observer. This is true assuming that the definition of &#8216;casual observer&#8217; is from a focus group of Stevie Wonder and Jose Feliciano. I had a professor in graduate school who wore a toupee that was &#8216;undetectable&#8217; aside from the six metal barrettes he used to keep it from sliding off his shiny noggin. I didn&#8217;t learn much in that class because I was always distracted by what might happen if he was being chased by Wile E. Coyote in a giant crane magnet.</p>
<p>Come to think of it, I had a hard time learning much in any of my classes&#8230;Hmmm. It&#8217;s probably their fault.</p>
<p>If one happens to be <span style="text-decoration:line-through;">bald</span> follicly challenged and wants more hair on his head, my suggestion is to choose a coonskin cap over a toupee. The coonskin cap provides excellent scalp coverage and a full head of thick, furry hair. It has been a symbol of manly ruggedness ever since Daniel Boone wore it on his show in the &#8217;50s and has the added bonus of coming with a handsome striped ponytail feature that can be detached and tied to one&#8217;s car antenna. It also has a distinct advantage over the toupee in that in social situations, it is less noticeable.</p>
<p>Another option for stopping apparent hair loss is to get plugs. This is where a semi-doctor takes little clumps of hair and inserts them directly into one&#8217;s scalp. The upside is that the hair is placed directly into the head and will not blow off should you be on the East Coast this week. The downside is that your hairline looks like that of a Mrs. Beasley doll that has been in the toy box since 1974.</p>
<p>The least expensive option is of course, Spray Hair in a Can. This is a product that acts much like spray paint in that you spray it onto your exposed bald parts and they miraculously take on the color of the pigmented granules contained in the can. Hair in a Can is brought to you by the good people at Ronco, the same company that gave us the Pocket Fisherman and the phrase &#8216;O-Matic,&#8217; so quality is not a question. Not including masking tape and drop cloths this option costs about $20. Or you can go the Rustoleum route for about $6 and have the added benefit of a variety of color schemes—not to mention the rust protection you will need should you have a death in the family during a nasty break-up while chopping onions.</p>
<p>What&#8217;s all the rage right now is having a hairline tattooed right onto your scalp. This is supposed to simulate the tiny hairs of a shaved head but in actuality resembles a hairline tattooed right onto your scalp. As I have an aversion to sticking needles into my head ever since I saw the voodoo-doll episode of Gilligan&#8217;s Island, I am not considering having this done. Plus, the procedure runs between $2000 and $3000. I&#8217;m thinking I could do it myself with a couple of fine-tip Sharpies for about eight bucks.</p>
<p>Maybe I&#8217;ll just part it on the other side.</p>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=318&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://contimplating.com/2012/10/30/just-say-no-to-rugs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/0ddc7c15eab1ba47762a7d4d4529257b?s=96&#38;d=wavatar&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tdwestveer</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://contimplating.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/contimplating-logo-2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">contimplating logo</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Star Wars is Changing Hands But My Childhood Lives On.</title>
		<link>http://lostingreymatter.com/2012/10/31/star-wars-is-changing-hands-but-my-childhood-lives-on/</link>
		<comments>http://lostingreymatter.com/2012/10/31/star-wars-is-changing-hands-but-my-childhood-lives-on/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 16:16:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jake Thomas</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://lostingreymatter.com/?p=872</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[So, you probably heard the news yesterday that George Lucas sold Star Wars, otherwise known as LucasFilm to Disney yesterday for an impressive $4.05 billion. With that came news that Disney was already beginning work on an Episode 7, due for release in 2015. Let me start by saying how enormous of a Star Wars [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=872&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://lostingreymatter.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/star-wars-anh1.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-874" title="star-wars-anh1" alt="" src="http://lostingreymatter.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/star-wars-anh1.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>So, you probably heard <a href="http://www.thewrap.com/movies/column-post/new-star-wars-coming-2015-62821" target="_blank">the news yesterday</a> that George Lucas sold Star Wars, otherwise known as LucasFilm to Disney yesterday for an impressive $4.05 billion. With that came news that Disney was already beginning work on an Episode 7, due for release in 2015.</p>
<p>Let me start by saying how enormous of a Star Wars fan I am. Aside from the toys, the customizable card game, the novels, and yes, the now famous Darth Vader cardboard cutout that sits in my living room, Star Wars has always been an important anchor for me. The stories provide a valuable connection back to my childhood, reminding me of what it feels like to be completely immersed in my own imagination.</p>
<p>In my (more) adult years, the stories themselves have served as introductions into the wisdom of comparative mythologist, Joseph Campbell and his work on the hero archetype and the hero&#8217;s journey, from which many believe the Star Wars trilogy is derived. In a sense, I&#8217;ve aged with them, growing up to pull intellectual and (try not to laugh) even spiritual wisdom from the stories.</p>
<p>But, the sadness I felt yesterday upon hearing the news of Lucas&#8217; sale, was, in part, due to the assumption that Star Wars would now be exploited without any thought of restraint. But, those are the feelings of a crotchety old-timer. I had every toy imaginable as a child, why should today&#8217;s kids be denied the same thing, because I hold Star Wars in some sacred regard?</p>
<p>But, that was just part of the remorse.  The other part came from a feeling that purists, not unlike myself, who had criticized Lucas so heavily, going as far as to create documentaries devoted to exposing his shortcomings, had driven him to part ways with his child.</p>
<p>While I&#8217;m sure that Lucas would disagree with this statement, I can&#8217;t help feeling there may be some truth to it. In fact, Lucas&#8217; departure was all but spelled out in a <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2012/01/22/magazine/george-lucas-red-tails.html?pagewanted=3&amp;_r=4" target="_blank">NYT interview</a> released 10 months ago alongside his latest film Red Tails, a project that provided even more insight into his beliefs as a man and as a filmmaker. When asked about the fans&#8217; distaste spawned by his merchandising of the franchise and re-release of the films, the columnist wrote this:</p>
<blockquote><p>“I think there are a lot more important things in the world” than feuds with fanboys, Lucas says with a kind of weary diffidence. But then he gets serious, even a little wounded&#8230;“On the Internet, all those same guys that are complaining I made a change are <em>completely </em>changing the movie,” Lucas says, referring to fans who, like the dreaded studios, have done their own forcible re-edits. “I’m saying: ‘Fine. But my movie, with my name on it, that says I did it, needs to be the way I want it.’ ”</p>
<p>Lucas seized control of his movies from the studios only to discover that the fanboys could still give him script notes. “Why would I make any more,” Lucas says of the “Star Wars” movies, “when everybody yells at you all the time and says what a terrible person you are?”</p></blockquote>
<p>It&#8217;s sad. But the reality, as often described by those who worked closely with George over the years, was that his passion and sage-like wisdom lied in editing, not writing, not directing&#8230;editing. The man loved to tinker, loved to see how technology could change the face of his beloved films and no one acknowledges this.</p>
<p>I mean, the man founded Industrial Light &amp; Magic, the world&#8217;s first special effects studio, invented simply because he had no other way to create the expansive space shots he dreamed up while filming A New Hope. And then he founded Skywalker Sound, because he needed audio to match visuals.</p>
<p>All those who love and appreciate cinema, as most fanboys do, love to complain about how the movie industry is driven by corporate greed, and that true works of art are increasingly more difficult to discover and produce. Well, George Lucas broke free of that in 1978, ensuring that no movie studio would have the final editing rights over his works of art. The result was the greatest trilogy our world has ever seen.</p>
<p>I will never be able to fully grasp the impact that Star Wars has had on my life, my career choices, the intellectuals whom I now study and look up to, the importance I place on my own imagination and creativity, the way I will raise my own children and who I&#8217;ve grown into as a person.</p>
<p>I owe that to George Lucas and his vision as a filmmaker.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/872/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/872/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=872&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://lostingreymatter.com/2012/10/31/star-wars-is-changing-hands-but-my-childhood-lives-on/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>12</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/5e5bf7b9b274e3f835f776f310c729a4?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">snaketronic23</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lostingreymatter.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/star-wars-anh1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">star-wars-anh1</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Smarter than a 4th Grader?</title>
		<link>http://mycommunitymatters.wordpress.com/2012/10/31/smarter-than-a-4th-grader/</link>
		<comments>http://mycommunitymatters.wordpress.com/2012/10/31/smarter-than-a-4th-grader/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 16:38:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>mbrock</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Civil Rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mycommunitymatters.wordpress.com/?p=298</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In a previous post I introduced my Swedish immigrant ancestors the Andersons, who came here in search of the American dream.  The Andersons had two children, Wallace and Pearl. Pearl was my great grandmother and Wallace grew up to have a family of his own, with a wife and three children.  But Wallace and his [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=298&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://mycommunitymatters.wordpress.com/2012/10/31/smarter-than-a-4th-grader/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>15</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c0bd42c86cda71543b40f2fe13c97e19?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">maritbrock</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mycommunitymatters.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/imag0512.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMAG0512</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mycommunitymatters.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/imag0501.jpg?w=104" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMAG0501</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mycommunitymatters.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/mn4allfamilies-12_600.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mn4allfamilies-12_600</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Around Sapa</title>
		<link>http://jonsanwell.wordpress.com/2012/10/31/around-sapa/</link>
		<comments>http://jonsanwell.wordpress.com/2012/10/31/around-sapa/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 15:23:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jon Sanwell</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vietnam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[landscape]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[portrait]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sapa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[south east asia]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://jonsanwell.wordpress.com/?p=2012</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[My trip to Sapa seems like a long time ago now, though I&#8217;ve only been back for two and a half weeks.  The cool temperatures, clean air and mist were a world away from Saigon&#8217;s humidity and smog.  When the sun came out for the last few days, I was even a bit disappointed.  These pictures [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2012&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2017" style="border:5px solid white;margin-top:25px;margin-bottom:25px;" title="vietnam-sapa-1" alt="" src="http://jonsanwell.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/121003-019-edited.jpg?w=590"   /></p>
<p>My trip to Sapa seems like a long time ago now, though I&#8217;ve only been back for two and a half weeks.  The cool temperatures, clean air and mist were a world away from Saigon&#8217;s humidity and smog.  When the sun came out for the last few days, I was even a bit disappointed.  These pictures were all taken in the countryside and villages around the town over the course of a few long-ish walks.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2018" style="border:5px solid white;margin-top:25px;margin-bottom:25px;" title="vietnam-sapa-2" alt="" src="http://jonsanwell.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/121003-112-edited.jpg?w=590"   /></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2019" style="border:5px solid white;margin-top:25px;margin-bottom:25px;" title="vietnam-sapa-3" alt="" src="http://jonsanwell.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/121003-136-edited.jpg?w=590"   /></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-2020" style="border:5px solid white;margin-top:25px;margin-bottom:25px;" title="vietnam-sapa-4" alt="" src="http://jonsanwell.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/121003-143-edited.jpg?w=810&#038;h=540" height="540" width="810" /></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2014" style="border:5px solid white;margin-top:25px;margin-bottom:25px;" title="vietnam-sapa-5" alt="" src="http://jonsanwell.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/121004-080-edited.jpg?w=590"   /></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2013" style="border:5px solid white;margin-top:25px;margin-bottom:25px;" title="vietnam-sapa-6" alt="" src="http://jonsanwell.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/121004-074-edited.jpg?w=590"   /></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2015" style="border:5px solid white;margin-top:25px;margin-bottom:25px;" title="vietnam-sapa-7" alt="" src="http://jonsanwell.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/121004-128-edited.jpg?w=590"   /></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2043" style="border:5px solid white;margin-top:25px;margin-bottom:25px;" title="vietnam-sapa-8" alt="" src="http://jonsanwell.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/121008-258-edited1.jpg?w=590"   /></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2042" style="border:5px solid white;margin-top:25px;margin-bottom:25px;" title="vietnam-sapa-9" alt="" src="http://jonsanwell.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/121008-253-edited1.jpg?w=590"   /></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2062" style="border:5px solid white;margin-top:25px;margin-bottom:25px;" title="vietnam-sapa-10" alt="" src="http://jonsanwell.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/121008-154-edited-23.jpg?w=590"   /></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2044" style="border:5px solid white;margin-top:25px;margin-bottom:25px;" title="vietnam-sapa-11" alt="" src="http://jonsanwell.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/121008-363-edited1.jpg?w=590"   /></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2040" style="margin-top:25px;margin-bottom:25px;" title="vietnam-sapa-12" alt="" src="http://jonsanwell.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/untitled-13.jpg?w=590"   /></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2024" style="border:5px solid white;margin-top:25px;margin-bottom:25px;" title="vietnam-sapa-13" alt="" src="http://jonsanwell.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/121008-017-edited.jpg?w=590"   /></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2032" style="margin-top:25px;margin-bottom:25px;" title="vietnam-sapa-14" alt="" src="http://jonsanwell.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/untitled-3.jpg?w=590"   /></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2027" style="border:5px solid white;margin-top:25px;margin-bottom:25px;" title="vietnam-sapa-15" alt="" src="http://jonsanwell.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/121008-174-edited.jpg?w=590"   /></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2025" style="border:5px solid white;margin-top:25px;margin-bottom:25px;" title="vietnam-sapa-16" alt="" src="http://jonsanwell.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/121008-094-edited.jpg?w=590"   /></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2023" style="border:5px solid white;margin-top:25px;margin-bottom:25px;" title="vietnam-sapa-17" alt="" src="http://jonsanwell.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/121007-398-edited.jpg?w=590"   /></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2031" style="margin-top:25px;margin-bottom:25px;" title="vietnam-sapa-18" alt="" src="http://jonsanwell.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/untitled-23.jpg?w=590"   /></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2012/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2012/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2012&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://jonsanwell.wordpress.com/2012/10/31/around-sapa/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/94919e3092fd2e501523d6c90d78fa7f?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jonsanwell</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jonsanwell.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/121003-019-edited.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">vietnam-sapa-1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jonsanwell.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/121003-112-edited.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">vietnam-sapa-2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jonsanwell.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/121003-136-edited.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">vietnam-sapa-3</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jonsanwell.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/121003-143-edited.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">vietnam-sapa-4</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jonsanwell.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/121004-080-edited.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">vietnam-sapa-5</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jonsanwell.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/121004-074-edited.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">vietnam-sapa-6</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jonsanwell.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/121004-128-edited.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">vietnam-sapa-7</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jonsanwell.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/121008-258-edited1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">vietnam-sapa-8</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jonsanwell.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/121008-253-edited1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">vietnam-sapa-9</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jonsanwell.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/121008-154-edited-23.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">vietnam-sapa-10</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jonsanwell.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/121008-363-edited1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">vietnam-sapa-11</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jonsanwell.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/untitled-13.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">vietnam-sapa-12</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jonsanwell.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/121008-017-edited.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">vietnam-sapa-13</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jonsanwell.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/untitled-3.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">vietnam-sapa-14</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jonsanwell.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/121008-174-edited.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">vietnam-sapa-15</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jonsanwell.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/121008-094-edited.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">vietnam-sapa-16</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jonsanwell.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/121007-398-edited.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">vietnam-sapa-17</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jonsanwell.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/untitled-23.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">vietnam-sapa-18</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Room to Read Changed My Life</title>
		<link>http://portraitsofaddiction.com/2012/10/30/how-2007-changed-my-life/</link>
		<comments>http://portraitsofaddiction.com/2012/10/30/how-2007-changed-my-life/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 02:33:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lilee</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Change the World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[charity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[John Wood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[literacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pyramids in egypt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[room to read]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://portraitsofaddiction.com/?p=226</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I will always think of 2007 as the year that changed my life.  I was 25 years old, a two-time college drop-out, and in a mentally and emotionally controlling relationship.  I partied a lot, barely saw my friends or my family and had completely lost focus of who I was and what I wanted to [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=226&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://portraitsofaddiction.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/room-to-read1.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-230" title="room to read" alt="" src="http://portraitsofaddiction.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/room-to-read1.jpg?w=590"   /></a>I will always think of 2007 as the year that changed my life.  I was 25 years old, a two-time college drop-out, and in a mentally and emotionally controlling relationship.  I partied a lot, barely saw my friends or my family and had completely lost focus of who I was and what I wanted to achieve in life.  I went to work and I went home.  I was lost in a spiral of depression I didn&#8217;t know how to climb out of, that is assuming, of course, that I could even figure out where to begin.  I had completely lost sight of who I was and what I wanted from my life.  The only time I ever felt any escape from the dark hole I had dug for myself was when I picked up a book and began to read.  No matter what was going on in my life I always had an escape and to this day I swear that reading is what saved my sanity.</p>
<p>Through my books I walked the battlefield at Gettysburg, fought in the Battle at Bull Run, and explored the Pyramids in Egypt.  I also learned about various cultures, sub-cultures, philosophies, religions and theories.  I had this aching knowledge that there was so much more to life than what I was doing and how I was living but I couldn&#8217;t figure out how to be a part of it.  I didn&#8217;t know what to do and my depression didn&#8217;t help motivate me to figure it out.  Then, one day in the Fall of 2007 I was in a used book resale shop and I picked up a book by <a class="zem_slink" title="John Wood (Room to Read)" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Wood_%28Room_to_Read%29" target="_blank" rel="wikipedia">John Wood</a> called &#8216;Leaving Microsoft to Change the World.&#8221;  It changed my life.</p>
<p>In 1998, John Wood was an executive at Microsoft with a big future ahead in the company and walked away from it all after a vacation to <a class="zem_slink" title="Nepal" href="http://maps.google.com/maps?ll=27.7,85.3166666667&amp;spn=10.0,10.0&amp;q=27.7,85.3166666667 (Nepal)&amp;t=h" target="_blank" rel="geolocation">Nepal</a>.  In interviews he says that his vacation became a &#8220;spiritual journey&#8221; after he met a Nepalese &#8220;Education Resource Officer&#8221; on a hiking trip and was invited to visit a school in nearby village.  This school, in a shack that would be considered a condemned building by US standards, had only 5 books in their library.  One book was a Danielle Steele romance, one was a travel guide to Mongolia, and a few other miscellaneous cast-offs.  In an effort to protect the few literary resources they had the books were kept under secure lock and key.  When John went to leave the Nepalese Education Resource Officer said to him, &#8220;Perhaps, Sir, you will someday come back with books?&#8221;  John returned home on a mission.  He immediately contacted friends and associates and within two months had raised over 3,000 books to support his mission to change the world &#8220;one book and one child&#8221; at a time.  He returned to Nepal with eight donkeys loaded with books and helped create their first true library.  In 1999 John Wood resigned from Microsoft and founded <a class="zem_slink" title="Room to Read" href="http://www.roomtoread.org/" target="_blank" rel="homepage">Room to Read</a> (<a href="http://www.roomtoread.org/" target="_blank">www.roomtoread.org</a>).</p>
<p>Since 1999 Room to Read has benefited over 6 million children by building 13,599 libraries and 1,566 schools.  They have also published 707 books in the native languages for Nepal, Cambodia, <a class="zem_slink" title="Tanzania" href="http://maps.google.com/maps?ll=-6.307,34.854&amp;spn=1.0,1.0&amp;q=-6.307,34.854 (Tanzania)&amp;t=h" target="_blank" rel="geolocation">Tanzania</a>, Zambia (see a <a href="http://www.roomtoread.org/page.aspx?pid=433">full list</a> of where they work) and distributed over 11 million books to promote literacy worldwide.  In addition to building libraries and schools, distributing books, publishing books and educating the world Room to Read also funds the education for impoverished girls.  <a href="http://www.roomtoread.org/page.aspx?pid=284">Girl&#8217;s education</a> is the <a href="http://www.roomtoread.org/page.aspx?pid=284">program</a> I have chosen to support in 2012.  In the developing world 42% of girls do not have access to education.</p>
<p>Of the 793 million illiterate people in the world over 67% are female.  This has to change and $250 will fund the education expenses for one girl for one year.  In 2012 I have set <a href="http://www.closedthecover.com/room-to-read.html">a goal</a> to raise $1,250 to fund the education for five girls.  You can read more about my fundraiser on my website, <a href="http://www.closedthecover.com/room-to-read.html">Closed the Cover</a>.</p>
<p>After reading John Wood&#8217;s book in 2007 I found a renewed sense of myself and I reconnected with my own goals and desires and beliefs about faith and life.  Since then I have re-enrolled in college and graduated with my first degree, ended that relationship, quit partying and drinking and reconnected with my own sense of purpose.  I know the joys of reading because I live in a place where I am lucky enough to have access to books and education however there are others who are not so lucky.  I can&#8217;t quit my job and travel to Nepal with eight donkeys loaded with bags of books but I can make a donation to help support the people that run the programs that can.  Everyone should have access to education.  As one Nepalese Headmaster said, &#8220;We are too poor to afford education; but without education, we will always be poor.&#8221;  They need help and I try to help them as much as I can.</p>
<p>Anyone interested in making a donation can visit: <a href="http://roomtoread.kintera.org/faf/donorReg/donorPledge.asp?ievent=316667&amp;lis=1&amp;kntae316667=88978B723DC7418EBE6F139D55FF1C83&amp;supId=366990200" target="_blank">ROOM TO READ</a></p>
<p>**Thank you Andrew for allowing me to share my program with your readers.</p>
<p>- Ashley</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/226/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/226/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=226&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://portraitsofaddiction.com/2012/10/30/how-2007-changed-my-life/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>41</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://portraitsofaddiction.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/2.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://portraitsofaddiction.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/2.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/b6a371d96dd8f74c0946175587726306?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ashlilee</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://portraitsofaddiction.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/room-to-read1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">room to read</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Survive a Natural Disaster</title>
		<link>http://brothertoussaint.wordpress.com/2012/10/31/how-to-survive-a-natural-disaster/</link>
		<comments>http://brothertoussaint.wordpress.com/2012/10/31/how-to-survive-a-natural-disaster/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 04:18:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>brothertoussaint</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Natural Disaster]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York City]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hurricanes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sandy]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brothertoussaint.wordpress.com/?p=103</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Twenty years ago, as I eagerly awaited the first day of school, there stood a category 3 hurricane in the Atlantic Ocean. This storm would go down as the most devastating storm in United States history (until Katrina). Every year we watched the summer storms batter the Caribbean; Haiti, Jamaica, Cuba and the Bahamas. Usually, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=103&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_106" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 294px"><a href="http://brothertoussaint.wordpress.com/2012/10/31/how-to-survive-a-natural-disaster/andrew2/" rel="attachment wp-att-106"><img class="size-full wp-image-106" title="andrew2" alt="" src="http://brothertoussaint.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/andrew2.jpg?w=590"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Hurricane Andrew, 1992.</p></div>
<p>Twenty years ago, as I eagerly awaited the first day of school, there stood a category 3 hurricane in the Atlantic Ocean. This storm would go down as the most devastating storm in United States history (until Katrina). Every year we watched the summer storms batter the Caribbean; Haiti, Jamaica, Cuba and the Bahamas. Usually, by the time the storms reached the shores of South Florida, they would lose their strength and touch down as tropical storms or at worse, at category 1 hurricane. It is said that Miami sees nearly 100 thunderstorms a year, so we were used to lightening, heavy rains, rough winds and blackouts.</p>
<p>By the time I was twelve, I can say that I had survived at least six hurricanes. All of them had been quite disappointing until Andrew in 1992. Sure, a few trees would fall, some light flooding occurred and we&#8217;d be out of electricity for a few days, but that was to be expected. But Andrew changed Miami forever. The category 3 hurricane rocked Dade County, leaving over 100,000 homeless. People sought shelter and protection in their closets because their windows were blown out and their roofs were torn away, and when they came out, they could see endless destruction as far as their eyes could see. Residents had to spray paint their addresses on the street, because their homes were blown away.</p>
<p>A massive mango tree fell on my neighbor&#8217;s house, we heard the crack, the thud and the screams. Our kitchen door was ripped off of its hinges. My father chased after it into the storm and nailed it back into the threshold. We prayed that it would remain put until the storm ended. With winds running through the house over 100 miles per hour, it would have pushed our roof off. We were lucky. After eight hours of torrential rains and winds, I am blessed to say that we survived Andrew with minimal damage. A few damaged windows, some roof damage and worn-out kitchen door.</p>
<p>We were without electricity for two weeks. School was cancelled for at least three and we all had a new-found respect for mother nature.</p>
<p>Sandy reminds me a lot of Andrew. New Yorkers (in the boroughs) got a taste of what a hurricane might bring, but Irene was misleading. I&#8217;m not sure what preparations were made along the Jersey Shore, Lower Manhattan or some of the lower-lying coastal areas, but I don&#8217;t believe those communities were physically or mentally prepared for the kind of aftermath that comes with a storm of Sandy&#8217;s magnitude. You can never really be prepared for &#8220;the storm,&#8221; you can only learn.</p>
<p>I will never forget what Andrew did, therefore I have the utmost respect for mother nature. Aside from stocking up on batteries, non-perishables, and clean water, there was not a whole lot anyone could do to really prepare for Sandy. From here on out, it&#8217;s all about the aftermath. How will the people respond? How will the local government, state government and F.E.M.A. handle the situation?</p>
<p>Once again, I was lucky, I think one tree was actually uprooted on my block, in Morningside Heights. Others were not so fortunate. Lower Manhattan is underwater. Flooding has redrawn the New Jersey shoreline. Breezey Point (Queens) was devastated by an uncontrollable blaze, leaving over one hundred homes charred to the ground and hundreds of thousands are left in the dark, without electricity.</p>
<p>The text messages, facebook check-ins and phone calls started at 5 a.m. &#8220;We are fine, thanks for checking up on us,&#8221; I quickly replied. They called from Miami, the Midwest, Boston and even West Africa. I rolled out of bed, fixed myself a bowl of cereal and began to watch the local news. The images were breath-taking and the stories were heart-breaking. I cannot believe that all this mayhem and destruction occurred all within the a few miles from my doorstep.</p>
<p>So I have survived Andrew, Katrina and now Sandy, three of the most costly natural disasters in United States history. How did I do it?  With a little intuition and a whole lot of luck.</p>
<div id="attachment_109" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 287px"><a href="http://brothertoussaint.wordpress.com/2012/10/31/how-to-survive-a-natural-disaster/sandy-3/" rel="attachment wp-att-109"><img class="size-full wp-image-109" title="sandy" alt="" src="http://brothertoussaint.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/sandy2.jpg?w=590"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Hurricane Sandy, 2012.</p></div>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/103/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/103/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/103/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/103/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/103/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/103/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/103/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/103/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/103/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/103/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/103/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/103/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/103/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/103/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=103&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://brothertoussaint.wordpress.com/2012/10/31/how-to-survive-a-natural-disaster/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>16</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/6f3a9383e6f2416e6a50d6ae06552e47?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">brothertoussaint</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://brothertoussaint.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/andrew2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">andrew2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://brothertoussaint.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/sandy2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sandy</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What the Penguin &amp; Random House Merger Means for Authors</title>
		<link>http://blaiselucey.com/2012/10/30/penguin-random-house-merger/</link>
		<comments>http://blaiselucey.com/2012/10/30/penguin-random-house-merger/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2012 22:44:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>blaiselucey1</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Essay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[For Writers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ebooks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blaiselucey.com/?p=407</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[For the past few years, authors have kind of looked on in dismay as publishing houses like Penguin and Random House lumbered like dinosaurs underneath the growing shadow of the meteoric threat known as ebooks. I was &#8211; and continue to be &#8211; part of that group, so I was proud to hear of the [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=407&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://noiseattwilight.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/randomhousepenguinmerger.jpg"><img class="alignleft  wp-image-410" title="RandomHousePenguinMerger" alt="" src="http://noiseattwilight.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/randomhousepenguinmerger.jpg?w=257&#038;h=314" height="314" width="257" /></a>For the past few years, authors have kind of looked on in dismay as publishing houses like Penguin and Random House lumbered like dinosaurs underneath the growing shadow of <a href="http://blaiselucey.com/2011/05/23/ebooks-the-future-of-writing-once-everyone-gets-over-it/">the meteoric threat known as ebooks</a>.</p>
<p>I was &#8211; and continue to be &#8211; part of that group, so I was proud to hear of the <a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2012/10/29/us-pearson-idUSBRE89S0C120121029">Penguin &amp; Random House merger</a>.</p>
<p>I firmly believe that, at the rate the industry is going, it&#8217;s imperative for publishers to move fast to adapt to this stuff.</p>
<p>Think about it:</p>
<p><span id="more-407"></span></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://blaiselucey.com/2011/05/23/ebooks-the-future-of-writing-once-everyone-gets-over-it/">the number of self-published books have jumped by 287%</a> over the past six years</li>
<li><a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/books/2012/aug/06/amazon-kindle-ebook-sales-overtake-print">Kindle ebook sales</a> have actually outpaced Amazon print sales</li>
<li>Three of the <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/books/2012/aug/06/amazon-kindle-ebook-sales-overtake-print">top 10 2012 Kindle authors</a> were published by Kindle Direct Publishing</li>
</ul>
<p>Amazon is casting a big shadow over the industry and no one quite knows what to make of it.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s why I was happy to see that Random House and Penguin, after months of courting one another, took the plunge and <a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052970204840504578086080253161770.html">officially merged</a>&#8230; and even happier that they weren&#8217;t shy about the reasons, either: ebooks.</p>
<p>Pearson (Penguin&#8217;s parent company) Chief Executive Marjorie Scardino <a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2012/10/29/us-pearson-idUSBRE89S0C120121029">explained</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Together, the two publishers will be able to share a large part of their costs, to invest more for their author and reader constituencies and to be more adventurous in trying new models in this exciting, fast-moving world of digital books and digital readers.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<h3><strong>Why this is good and not bad</strong></h3>
<p>I don&#8217;t know about you, but it&#8217;s pretty hard for me to see mergers as good things.</p>
<p>Alarm bells go off in my head about monopolies, money grabs, and mature-capitalism-limiting-consumer-options-to-the-point-of-tyrannical-corporate-control-and-terrible-customer-service (looking at you, Comcast).</p>
<p>But I can&#8217;t help but think positively about this merger as a necessary adjustment to the rapidly changing landscape.</p>
<p>Why? Because I&#8217;m hopeful that <span style="color:#000000;"><b>by combining forces, Penguin and Random House will be innovative. </b></span></p>
<p>There are so many possibilities for big-name publishers when it comes to ebooks,<strong> if they choose to be advocates for authors instead of stockholders.</strong></p>
<p>I&#8217;ve <a href="http://blaiselucey.com/2011/05/23/ebooks-the-future-of-writing-once-everyone-gets-over-it/">talked about</a> a few of them before:</p>
<ul>
<li>Monthly subscription on a chapter-by-chapter basis, with new content delivered straight to mobile devices (there&#8217;s already been <a href="http://paidcontent.org/2012/10/26/uks-valobox-launches-pay-by-the-piece-ebooks-with-oreilly-and-guardian/">a semi-promising step in pay-per-page trends</a>)</li>
<li>Hiring agents whose job it is to find those ebooks in the rough&#8230; yes, reversing the model on its head</li>
<li>Creating the next definition of &#8220;book&#8221; (shorter? more pictures? more social?)</li>
<li>PR departments for self-published authors</li>
<li>Interactive books for tablets &amp; smartphones</li>
</ul>
<p>Now, there are potential downsides to the merger, too. There&#8217;s already talk about consolidation, that small publishers won&#8217;t be able to compete and they&#8217;ll have to join with Random-Penguin&#8230; and the notion that <a href="http://consumerist.com/2012/10/29/will-the-marriage-of-penguin-random-house-hike-book-prices/">the merger may send book prices &#8220;soaring.&#8221;</a></p>
<h3>What it means for authors</h3>
<p>Authors are a suspicious bunch. We curl our noses at violent changes like this, because it&#8217;s just another distraction from our Masterpiece.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s too early to gauge the long-term reverberations of the Penguin &amp; Random House merger. We don&#8217;t even know if it will be deemed legal yet.</p>
<p>However, if you polish Scardino&#8217;s statement enough, you can glean some meaning.</p>
<p><strong>If Random House and Penguin are focusing on &#8220;new models&#8221; for books, then you should, too. </strong></p>
<p>This is a big move by big publishers trying to adjust to the digital age and authors need to follow in their footsteps.</p>
<p>How? Well, you can&#8230;</p>
<ul>
<li>Make a website</li>
<li>Publish things <em>everywhere</em></li>
<li>Create a dynamic presence that can be Googled</li>
<li>Don&#8217;t write in a bubble</li>
</ul>
<p>Sure, writing in a bubble is necessary for authors who want to do any critical thinking, ever. You need to be at peace with your thoughts and enter your zone.</p>
<p>But don&#8217;t get too isolated. Authors need to be as digitally savvy as publishers, because when you start knocking on their doors with a manuscript and you don&#8217;t even have a blog&#8230; well&#8230;  consider your bubble popped.</p>
<p>You&#8217;ll realize, as you free-fall to earth, publishers like Penguin and Random House &#8211; along with thousands of authors &#8211; are scrambling up Digital Mountain, even if none of them are sure what&#8217;s at the top.</p>
<p><em><strong>How are you adjusting your writing to the digital era? Let me know below &amp; <a href="http://survey.constantcontact.com/survey/a07e6ksoh28h8xmjxff/start">sign up for </a></strong></em><strong><a href="http://survey.constantcontact.com/survey/a07e6ksoh28h8xmjxff/start">The Creative Brief </a><em><a href="http://survey.constantcontact.com/survey/a07e6ksoh28h8xmjxff/start">newsletter</a> afterwards because&#8230; why not?</em></strong></p>
<p><em>Photo Credit: Anne Froehlich</em></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/407/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/407/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=407&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://blaiselucey.com/2012/10/30/penguin-random-house-merger/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>18</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/092c3822248575af3c7cf9b42d31e82d?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">blaiselucey1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://noiseattwilight.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/randomhousepenguinmerger.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">RandomHousePenguinMerger</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Wikipedia As Textbook</title>
		<link>http://arundquist.wordpress.com/2012/10/30/wikipedia-as-textbook/</link>
		<comments>http://arundquist.wordpress.com/2012/10/30/wikipedia-as-textbook/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 02:34:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Andy "SuperFly" Rundquist</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[physics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[teaching]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://arundquist.wordpress.com/?p=502</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve been kicking around some ideas to avoid (for the students) the incredibly high cost of the texts I was planning on using next semester in Modern Physics and Theoretical Mechanics. I wanted to get some of the thoughts down here and get some feedback, if possible. Why do I like free? Well, it is [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=502&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve been kicking around some ideas to avoid (for the students) the incredibly high cost of the texts I was planning on using next semester in Modern Physics and Theoretical Mechanics. I wanted to get some of the thoughts down here and get some feedback, if possible.</p>
<p>Why do I like free? Well, it is nice to be nice to the students, and it&#8217;s nice to know that they&#8217;ll actually have the book, since often they just don&#8217;t buy it. But it&#8217;s also great to have a book that allows you to digitally augment it and to project in class. I used that to great effect last semester in Physical Optics with this <a href="http://optics.byu.edu/textbook.aspx">awesome free optics book</a>.</p>
<h2>Old Modern Physics</h2>
<p>For Modern Physics, I was trying to decide between what I usually use (<a href="http://www.amazon.com/Quantum-Physics-Molecules-Solids-Particles/dp/047187373X">Eisberg and Resnick</a>), what my colleague most recently used (<a href="http://www.amazon.com/Modern-Physics-Raymond-Serway/dp/0534493394/ref=sr_1_7?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1351648648&amp;sr=1-7&amp;keywords=serway">Serway</a>), something with spin first (maybe the<a href="http://www.amazon.com/Six-Ideas-That-Shaped-Physics/dp/0072397136/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1351648681&amp;sr=1-1&amp;keywords=six+ideas+Q"> 6 ideas book</a>, though I think that&#8217;s too low of a level), and something totally free.</p>
<p>For now, I think I&#8217;ll use the 1961 early version of the Eisberg text, because it&#8217;s <a href="http://archive.org/details/FundamentalsOfModernPhysics">free and in pdf form online</a>. Flipping through it, it seems to be close enough to the &#8217;80&#8242;s Eisberg and Resnick text, plus it has a chapter or two on relativity, whereas the later one relegates that to a terse appendix.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s interesting, of course, to think about a 50 year old book used in a &#8220;Modern Physics&#8221; course, but most of us know that old joke.</p>
<h2>Wikipedia is what they read anyways</h2>
<p>I recently read<a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2012/10/surmounting-the-insurmountable-wikipedia-is-nearing-completion-in-a-sense/264111/"> how wikipedia is darn near comprehensive</a>. I was pretty impressed with the numbers in that article, and it caused me to reflect on how I almost always find things that I&#8217;m looking for when I use it, especially when it comes to the topics I teach. I&#8217;ve used it a ton when preparing lectures/class activities, as there are often different explanations of things I&#8217;m not as familiar with than the text I&#8217;m using.</p>
<p>What I wondered is whether I could leverage Wikipedia to let me go without my $250 text for Theoretical Mechanics (<a href="http://www.amazon.com/Classical-Dynamics-Particles-Systems-Thornton/dp/0534408966/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1351649134&amp;sr=1-1&amp;keywords=thornton+marion">$90 is the cheapest I saw on Amazon for my usual text</a>). I did a quick google search along the lines of &#8220;combine wikipedia articles&#8221; and found out that wikipedia itself provides a &#8220;create book&#8221; option. So I dug in, and, from a technology perspective, I was pretty impressed. It doesn&#8217;t just paste in the multiple articles you flag, it really re-formats them for the printed page, and strips out things that wouldn&#8217;t make sense (like the table of contents links at the top of each page). It also lets you organize the material by adding in chapter headings, and it makes a nice table of contents for the entire &#8220;book.&#8221; You can download it as a pdf or as a few different e-book formats.</p>
<p>My first attempt at using this was to try to recreate a chapter from the text I use. I chose the &#8220;calculus of variations&#8221; chapter, and made some decent headway on wikipedia. I then went on to look at the &#8220;central forces&#8221; chapter. Again, I was mostly happy. <a href="https://docs.google.com/open?id=0B-N21MFujA8BOUxIc1dlNWlEZms">You can see the result of both of those here</a>.</p>
<p>I moved on from there to the first (non-math) chapter on Newton&#8217;s laws. I wasn&#8217;t as happy here because the articles I found seemed to have too much tangential material. <a href="https://docs.google.com/open?id=0B-N21MFujA8BYUhBMnZJcFZ1ZHc">Here&#8217;s my stab at that</a>. If I were to use that, I&#8217;d likely have to filter the pages I would want my students to read before coming to class.</p>
<h2>Focus on standards</h2>
<p>Then I hit on a really interesting idea. What if I used <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1nw-hOZ7zRMFrSBEM5xdtHB-ByA9EGM2huubmzuXV1sM/edit?authkey=CO29vfMN">my standards</a> for the class as the focus, instead of the chapters in the text that I&#8217;m used to? This idea felt very freeing to me, as I realized that even the text I use really has some material that causes my students to lose focus from what we&#8217;ve collectively decided is important. I figure I could collect articles that would provide help/context/explanation for a particular standard, and likely augment that with examples, videos, etc from me. For the moment, at least, I&#8217;m going to give that plan a try and see how I feel about the wikipedia books that I&#8217;ll create.</p>
<h2>Additional issues</h2>
<p>There are some issues with the wikipedia books I thought I&#8217;d mention here as well. First, the hyperlinks are mostly lost, making the books less useful than just a collection of hyperlinks pointing to the original source. On the other hand, the formatting looks great, and the students can have a small pdf with exactly what&#8217;s needed when they come to class to work on activities.</p>
<p>Second, you have to create the books all in one sitting, as you can&#8217;t seem to rely on the cookies to remember where you were at. One book seemed to be remembered for a couple of days as I kept going back to the site, but then later that same day it just disappeared. If you&#8217;re an &#8220;authorized&#8221; user of wikipedia (at least 4-day-old account with at least 10 edits), you do get a save button. However, I&#8217;ve never edited wikipedia so I&#8217;m not sure if I want to get to the 10-edits level. For this new standards-based approach (as opposed to the chapter-based approach) I think doing it in one sitting is likely very possible.</p>
<h2>What do you think?</h2>
<p>I&#8217;d love to hear what you think about these two approaches I&#8217;m considering for next year. Do you try to minimize student costs? Do you assign secondary (or more) texts? Do you trust Wikipedia? Have you tried forgoing texts entirely for courses like this? Do you see these sorts of texts as great reference materials that physics majors should own?</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/502/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/502/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=502&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://arundquist.wordpress.com/2012/10/30/wikipedia-as-textbook/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>33</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/dfa2dc3dcaa417a53167ca6579516cf2?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">hamlinephysics</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>