<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2011 23:19:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Steve Jobs and Me: A journalist reminisces</title>
		<link>http://tech.fortune.cnn.com/2011/10/25/steve-jobs-brent-schlender/</link>
		<comments>http://tech.fortune.cnn.com/2011/10/25/steve-jobs-brent-schlender/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2011 09:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Fortune Editors</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Contributors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brent Schlender]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPod]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iTunes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Macs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NeXT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pixar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Steve Jobs]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tech.fortune.cnn.com/?p=72311</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Fortune contributor Brent Schlender shares some of the stories and personal photographs he collected during more than two decades as Steve Jobs&#8217; chronicler and confidant. FORTUNE &#8212; Most of us who wrote in depth about the brilliant career of Steve Jobs sooner or later came to realize that we were complicit in the making of [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=72311&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Fortune contributor <a href="mailto:letters@fortune.com">Brent Schlender</a> shares some of the stories and personal photographs he collected during more than two decades as Steve Jobs&#8217; chronicler and confidant.</strong></p>
<div id="attachment_72354" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 350px"><a href="http://fortunebrainstormtech.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/brent_schlender_steve_jobs.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-72354" title="brent_schlender_steve_jobs" src="http://fortunebrainstormtech.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/brent_schlender_steve_jobs.jpg?w=340&#038;h=255" alt="" width="340" height="255" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Jobs’ scribe: Schlender (left) interviewing Jobs at a Next company picnic</p></div>
<p>FORTUNE &#8212; Most of us who wrote in depth about the brilliant career of Steve Jobs sooner or later came to realize that we were complicit in the making of a modern myth. You simply couldn&#8217;t avoid it. And while it is true that Jobs was as charismatic as Clooney and as manipulative as Machiavelli, the legend we helped him construct served many purposes beyond pumping up his own ego. He was an irresistible force who knew that in order to bring to market the amazing technological wonders that bubbled in his imagination, he also had to become the Svengali of the digital revolution that was to be the hallmark of his generation.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, Steve was merely mortal. And his storied life was one of dissonances and contradictions. He proudly flouted authority, yet he embodied extreme self-discipline. He wouldn&#8217;t suffer fools, but that wouldn&#8217;t keep him from turning on the charm to woo a &#8220;bozo&#8221; who had something he needed. He was the ultimate nano-manager, who also could limn the grand strokes of a big picture that others rarely could fully perceive without his help.</p>
<p>While he never settled for anything but the extraordinary and dearly loved his Gulfstream jet, he led a curiously modest domestic life, especially after he had married and embraced fatherhood. He was intensely private, yet he hid in plain sight. He took his physical health far more seriously than most of us, yet his body utterly failed him. And the final irony is that when he died, by many measures he was at long last reaching his full stride. Yes, he had manipulated other people all along the way, sometimes callously. Likewise, we journalists exploited his fame and charisma whenever we could. But now that he&#8217;s gone, it&#8217;s plain to see that in the process of transforming all of our lives, Steve used himself up.</p>
<p><a href="http://fortunebrainstormtech.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/steve_jobs_up_close_brent_schlender.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-72355" title="steve_jobs_up_close_brent_schlender" src="http://fortunebrainstormtech.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/steve_jobs_up_close_brent_schlender.jpg?w=612&#038;h=174" alt="" width="612" height="174" /></a></p>
<p>Looking back on my 25 years of dealings with Steve as an outsider who occasionally was invited in, there were chapters in his story I was never able to tell, either because they would violate a personal confidence or because what I had learned didn&#8217;t really fit into a typical analytical business story. They are the kinds of observations and experiences that, for me, gave Steve a three-dimensionality and a depth of humanity that myths inevitably foreshorten.</p>
<p>Indeed, over the years the Jobs legend all too often bordered on cliché. And in many ways he liked it that way. Consequently one of the challenges &#8212; and there were many in telling his story &#8212; was to come up with apt and original ways to describe his uncanny knack for fanning something akin to lust for just about anything he chose to tout, whether it be a computer mouse or a software upgrade or a Pixar movie. Early on, when Steve was still in his twenties, one of his engineers called him a walking, talking &#8220;reality distortion field,&#8221; and the metaphor (which he detested) stuck. Likewise, &#8220;brash&#8221; and &#8220;mercurial&#8221; became the overused adjectives of choice for many when describing his notoriously prickly personality.</p>
<p>In reality, his talents and idiosyncrasies were so diverse, complementary, and unusual that there were many different ways to interpret and describe his genius, and that was a big part of the fun. Ross Perot called him &#8220;the damnedest one-man band I&#8217;ve ever seen.&#8221; <a href="http://money.cnn.com/video/technology/2011/10/13/t_gc_collins_apple_jobs.fortune/">Business guru Jim Collins</a> likened him to the &#8220;Beethoven of business.&#8221; Silicon Valley billionaire Larry Ellison dubbed him &#8220;our Picasso.&#8221;</p>
<p>In various <a href="http://money.cnn.com/galleries/2011/technology/1110/gallery.steve_jobs_fortune_covers.fortune/index.html"><em>Fortune</em> cover stories</a> I called him the computer industry&#8217;s &#8220;chief esthetic officer&#8221; at Apple (<a href="http://money.cnn.com/quote/quote.html?symb=AAPL">AAPL</a>) and the &#8220;original impresario of virtual reality&#8221; at Pixar. And during Apple&#8217;s sluggish stasis in the early 2000s, prior to <a href="http://money.cnn.com/galleries/2009/fortune/0906/gallery.steve_jobs_career_timeline.fortune/7.html">hatching the iPod</a> that would turbocharge its growth, I mockingly called him the &#8220;graying prince of a shrinking kingdom.&#8221; Truth be told, that elicited a quick phone call from the &#8220;brash and mercurial&#8221; Jobs to tell me how it had given him a good laugh. Seriously.</p>
<div id="attachment_72351" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 622px"><a href="http://fortunebrainstormtech.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/1999_product_review_steve_jobs.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-72351" title="1999_product_review_steve_jobs" src="http://fortunebrainstormtech.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/1999_product_review_steve_jobs.jpg?w=612&#038;h=170" alt="" width="612" height="170" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">1999 - Product review: Jobs scrutinizes the “dock” of icons that appears on the bottom of the screen of Apple’s OS X user interface with an anxious team of engineers, designers, and marketers.</p></div>
<p>I first met Steve Jobs in February 1987, not long after moving to the San Francisco Bay Area to be the lead technology reporter for the <em>Wall Street Journal</em>. This was early in his &#8220;wilderness period,&#8221; after he had been booted out of Apple in 1985. Within months Jobs had recruited a band of Apple colleagues to start a new computer company, <a href="http://money.cnn.com/galleries/2009/fortune/0906/gallery.steve_jobs_career_timeline.fortune/4.html">appropriately called Next</a>. On a whim, in 1986 he also plunked down $10 million to buy the digital-animation skunkworks that would come to be called Pixar Animation Studios, from <a href="http://postcards.blogs.fortune.cnn.com/2011/10/06/george-lucas-steve-jobs/">film director George Lucas</a>. It was a steal of a deal and would eventually make Steve an honest-to-God billionaire a decade later, after he took it public in 1995. (When Disney (<a href="http://money.cnn.com/quote/quote.html?symb=DIS">DIS</a>) <a href="http://money.cnn.com/magazines/fortune/fortune_archive/2006/02/20/8369109/index.htm">acquired Pixar in 2006</a> and he became Disney&#8217;s biggest shareholder and a director, his stake was worth many billions.)</p>
<p>Jobs cultivated our relationship because he wanted to stay in the public eye in order to promote Next and Pixar and to rebuild his credibility as a business and technology savant. He knew that I also covered Apple for the <em>Journal</em>, and let me know that if I ever wanted to exchange &#8220;intelligence&#8221; or needed a back channel to understand the real dynamics of what was becoming an ongoing soap opera in Cupertino, he was around.</p>
<p>I wrote several feature stories for the <em>Journal</em> about both Next and Pixar before moving on to <em>Fortune</em> in 1989. Jobs and I seemed to click personally, in part because we were virtually the same age and had experienced similar adolescent rites of passage, and we shared a strikingly similar taste in books and movies and music. We would find out a few years later that one of my best friends from high school had very nearly married Steve&#8217;s sister, the novelist Mona Simpson. Talk about a small world. (Steve, who was adopted as an infant, was in the process of tracking her down when I first met him.)</p>
<p>Still, I was always the reporter and Steve was the source and subject; I was the ink-stained wretch, and he was the rock star. More than anything, he wanted to get his stories told to the biggest and best audience possible, and I could give him that. For my part, I could sense he was bound for even bigger things and wanted to have a front-row seat. And so the overarching purpose for our social and personal interactions over the next 20 years would be journalistic transactions. And not all of them would please him.</p>
<div id="attachment_72352" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 622px"><a href="http://fortunebrainstormtech.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/2001_apple_keynotes_steve_jobs.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-72352" title="2001_apple_keynotes_steve_jobs" src="http://fortunebrainstormtech.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/2001_apple_keynotes_steve_jobs.jpg?w=612&#038;h=171" alt="" width="612" height="171" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">2001 - Front-row seat to history: Schlender captured on camera the iPod launch event (left and center); nine months earlier he traveled to Macworld Toyko and watched Jobs (right) prep for his keynote.</p></div>
<p>The goal in most of my encounters with Steve was to bump him out of <a href="http://tech.fortune.cnn.com/2011/09/09/stevie-jobs-aka-stevie-wonder/">keynote mode</a> and get him to extemporize about business, technology, the arts and media, politics and world events, and even his personal life. His instant analyses could be as sharp as they were blunt. That&#8217;s when you would begin to see the true depth of his insight and intelligence, and realize that his penchant for performing was also something of a smoke screen that obscured his incredibly quick mind. There was so much one could learn in an unscripted hour with Jobs that my top editors at <em>Fortune </em>in New York City timed trips so that they could tag along on my interviews with him.</p>
<p>In one instance, John Huey, who is now Time Inc.&#8217;s editor-in-chief, joined me at Apple headquarters in Cupertino in 2003, not for a story interview but instead to get Jobs&#8217; advice on how he would clean up our struggling parent company, then known as AOL Time Warner. Steve looked at us incredulously and muttered something about what a waste of time it was to look in the rearview mirror. He then proceeded to spend the next 20 minutes methodically explaining in excruciating detail why AOL&#8217;s business model of being a dial-up Internet service was a complete mismatch and had served only to slow down Time Warner&#8217;s build-out of its much more promising broadband business. Then he waxed acerbic about why AOL&#8217;s &#8220;postcard production values&#8221; for its online content were so &#8220;hopelessly last-century.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Well, I guess that means you don&#8217;t think it could be fixed,&#8221; Huey said. To which Jobs replied, &#8220;I didn&#8217;t say that. I know how you could fix it. I&#8217;m just not interested.&#8221; Then, inexplicably, he went to the whiteboard and spent 15 more minutes mapping out a strategy right off the top of his head to turn AOL into something more like a media company. (That&#8217;s more or less the course AOL (<a href="http://money.cnn.com/quote/quote.html?symb=AOL">AOL</a>) eventually followed, albeit with mixed success, <a href="http://money.cnn.com/video/fortune/2010/07/23/f_bst_aol_ceo_strategy.fortune">after being spun out</a> of Time Warner (<a href="http://money.cnn.com/quote/quote.html?symb=TWX">TWX</a>) several years later.)</p>
<p>&#8220;That&#8217;s how I&#8217;d do it,&#8221; he concluded, snapping the cap back on the dry marker with a flourish. &#8220;But like I said, I&#8217;m not interested.&#8221;</p>
<div id="attachment_72353" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 622px"><a href="http://fortunebrainstormtech.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/2003_fortune_cover_shoot_steve_jobs.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-72353" title="2003_fortune_cover_shoot_steve_jobs" src="http://fortunebrainstormtech.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/2003_fortune_cover_shoot_steve_jobs.jpg?w=612&#038;h=169" alt="" width="612" height="169" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">2003 - Cover shoot: When photographer Michael O’Neill shot singer Sheryl Crow and Jobs for a Fortune cover, Schlender was there with a digital camera of his own.</p></div>
<p>The most enlightening meetings often were ones that Steve himself initiated, usually with a telephone call to my home out of the blue and always with a very specific purpose in mind. One Saturday morning in May 1995, he rang up and asked me to grab my two grade-school-age daughters and bring them over to his house in Palo Alto right away. &#8220;I&#8217;m watching Reed this morning, and I&#8217;ve got something cool to show them&#8221; was all he would say.</p>
<p>When we arrived, 3-year-old Reed Jobs greeted us at the kitchen door, wrapped in blue and red silk scarves and screeching, &#8220;I&#8217;m a witch!!!&#8221;</p>
<p>After making some popcorn and getting the kids some juice, Steve led us into the den and slapped a VHS cassette into the player. The music swelled and a stream of illegible, pencil-drawn storyboards simulating the opening credits of a movie flashed on the screen. And then, suddenly, an entirely new kind of animation burst forth in full color. All three kids were spellbound, even though the full animation had been completed for only half the movie. The soundtrack was finished, but entire scenes were only partially animated or in storyboard form.</p>
<p>It turned out that this was an early cut of <em>Toy Story</em>, the movie that would put Pixar on the map after its premiere six months later. The board of directors hadn&#8217;t even seen this much of it. But this was market research, Steve Jobs-style. When it was over, he asked my kids (not me), &#8220;Whaddya think? Is it as good as <em>Pocahontas</em>?&#8221; Greta and Fernanda nodded vigorously. &#8220;Well, then, is it as good as <em>The Lion King</em>?&#8221; Fernanda replied, &#8220;I won&#8217;t be able to make up my mind until I see <em>Toy Story</em> five or six more times.&#8221;</p>
<p>Meeting with Steve wasn&#8217;t always fun and games. On the Sunday after Christmas in 1995, Steve summoned me to his house to &#8220;talk on background&#8221; about the drama unfolding at Apple. This was around the time it had been rumored that either Sun Microsystems or Philips NV was about to make a bid to acquire the troubled company, and Steve was dropping hints that he and his &#8220;best friend&#8221; Ellison, the founder and CEO of Oracle (<a href="http://money.cnn.com/quote/quote.html?symb=ORCL">ORCL</a>), were contemplating making their own bid for the company if that happened.</p>
<p>It seemed an odd gambit, and I told him it sounded to me like courting trouble. Steve replied that he wasn&#8217;t really that serious about it. Still, he swore me to secrecy and then walked me out to my car. When he saw the decaying 1976 Toyota Celica parked at the curb, he stopped short. &#8220;I sure hope you don&#8217;t drive your kids around in that thing! I&#8217;m not joking. That car has no airbags. Get rid of it.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://money.cnn.com/galleries/2011/technology/1110/gallery.how_steve_jobs_changed_the_world.fortune/index.html">10 ways Steve Jobs changed the world</a></strong></p>
<p><strong></strong>A year later, in late 1996, rather than team up with Ellison to make a run at Apple, Jobs persuaded Apple CEO Gil Amelio to acquire Next for $400 million and take him on as a special adviser. Once inside, it wasn&#8217;t long &#8212; seven months to be exact &#8212; before he had engineered a palace coup and put his team from Next in charge. <a href="http://money.cnn.com/magazines/fortune/fortune_archive/1998/11/09/250880/index.htm">Jobs&#8217; wilderness years had ended</a>, and the sequel to the Steve Jobs Myth was about to begin.</p>
<p>During the next seven years I wrote four cover stories about Steve&#8217;s transformative leadership at Apple and edited another. He gave <em>Fortune</em> an exclusive first look at the Mac OS X operating system. He also allowed me to be the only journalist to observe how frighteningly temperamental he could be during the final rehearsal for one of his Macworld keynote speeches. In 2001 he showed me the first iPod (under embargo) several weeks before it was publicly announced, primarily so he could see what I thought of his remarks for the introduction. And a year later he gave <em>Fortune</em> a first look at the iTunes Music Store before it went live online.</p>
<p>Of course, he took serious issue with some of the stories we published about him, and when he did, I&#8217;d be the first to hear about it. When we used him as the cover image for a June 2001 story called &#8220;<a href="http://money.cnn.com/galleries/2011/technology/1110/gallery.steve_jobs_fortune_covers.fortune/7.html">Inside the Great CEO Pay Heist</a>,&#8221; he threatened to pull Apple ads from <em>Fortune</em> indefinitely. Although I didn&#8217;t write that story, I encouraged him to write a letter to the editor to make the case that the story unfairly maligned him. He had a point, but in the end, he didn&#8217;t ever hold a grudge. Not against me, at least.</p>
<p>I feel more strongly about Steve Jobs than any other famous person I have written about for one other reason. Like him, I have spent a lot of time in the hospital. Fifteen years ago I had my first heart attack, and when Steve heard about it, he called my hospital room to chew me out for being a smoker for much of my life. Six years ago I nearly died after a freak infection in an artificial heart valve turned into meningitis in my spine and brain, which in turn wiped out most of my hearing. I was in the hospital for five weeks, and Steve came to visit me twice, even though I was bordering on delusional at the time. I couldn&#8217;t hear him either, so he had to write down what he wanted to say to me, which included a joke about Bill Gates that shouldn&#8217;t be repeated.</p>
<p>When I recovered, I started planning a book project I wanted to call <em>Founders Keepers</em> that would attempt to explain why certain entrepreneurs seem to be able to grow as business leaders even faster than the companies they create. Steve consented to be one of the primary subjects of the book, along with <a href="http://tech.fortune.cnn.com/2011/10/24/steve-jobs-walter-isaacson/?iid=SF_F_Lead">Bill Gates</a>, Michael Dell, and Andy Grove. All of them had agreed to meet with me for a roundtable discussion in Silicon Valley in late November 2008.</p>
<p>One week before the meeting, Steve called me at home. &#8220;I really hate to do this, Brent, but I have to back out of our meeting.&#8221; Maybe it was just my new hearing aid, but he sounded uncharacteristically subdued. &#8220;I trust you not to say anything to anyone about why I&#8217;m canceling on you, but I&#8217;ll tell you the truth. I really have to get to the bottom of my health problems once and for all. I&#8217;m in no condition to meet with anyone and am going to go on an extended medical leave after Thanksgiving.&#8221; Three weeks later <a href="http://apple20.blogs.fortune.cnn.com/2009/06/20/inside-steve-jobs-liver-transplant/">he received a liver transplant</a>. We spoke only a few times after that. And three years later he was gone.</p>
<p>Steve Jobs certainly was a living legend and a prima donna, as well as a journalist&#8217;s dream interview. He could be a beguiling charmer when he wanted to be and a petulant whiner when things didn&#8217;t go his way. He loved his family. Yes, he was larger than life, but life deserted him. In other words, he was as human as they come.</p>
<p><em>This article is from the November 7, 2011 issue of </em>Fortune<em>.</em></p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://tech.fortune.cnn.com/category/contributors/'>Contributors</a>, <a href='http://tech.fortune.cnn.com/category/uncategorized/'>Uncategorized</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/72311/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/72311/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/72311/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/72311/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/72311/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/72311/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/72311/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/72311/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/72311/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/72311/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/72311/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/72311/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/72311/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/72311/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=72311&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tech.fortune.cnn.com/2011/10/25/steve-jobs-brent-schlender/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">fortuneeditors</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://fortunebrainstormtech.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/brent_schlender_steve_jobs.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">brent_schlender_steve_jobs</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://fortunebrainstormtech.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/steve_jobs_up_close_brent_schlender.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">steve_jobs_up_close_brent_schlender</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://fortunebrainstormtech.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/1999_product_review_steve_jobs.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">1999_product_review_steve_jobs</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://fortunebrainstormtech.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/2001_apple_keynotes_steve_jobs.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2001_apple_keynotes_steve_jobs</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://fortunebrainstormtech.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/2003_fortune_cover_shoot_steve_jobs.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2003_fortune_cover_shoot_steve_jobs</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Urban citizens of cool</title>
		<link>http://boboontherun.com/2011/09/12/urban-citizens-of-cool/</link>
		<comments>http://boboontherun.com/2011/09/12/urban-citizens-of-cool/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2011 13:51:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bobo on the run</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Berlin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Buenos Aires]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[citizens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cool]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creative expression]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[graffiti]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[street art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[This Is Not Art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[urban]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vandalism]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://boboontherun.com/?p=546</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There’s a story in my hometown of Newcastle that reads more like folklore than fact. The story is about a legendary piece of graffiti that was written by a frustrated uni student on the upper extremities of one of the city’s most unsightly destitute buildings. Abseiling down from the roof of the building one night, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=546&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://boboontherun.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/street-art-73.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-549" title="Street Art 1" src="http://boboontherun.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/street-art-73.jpg?w=640&#038;h=470" alt="" width="640" height="470" /></a><a href="http://boboontherun.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/street-art-21.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-550" title="Street Art 2" src="http://boboontherun.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/street-art-21.jpg?w=640&#038;h=480" alt="" width="640" height="480" /></a><a href="http://boboontherun.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/street-art-101.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-552" title="street art 3" src="http://boboontherun.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/street-art-101.jpg?w=640&#038;h=426" alt="" width="640" height="426" /></a>There’s a story in my hometown of Newcastle that reads more like folklore than fact. The story is about a legendary piece of graffiti that was written by a frustrated uni student on the upper extremities of one of the city’s most unsightly destitute buildings. Abseiling down from the roof of the building one night, he scrawled the immortal words, ‘This Is Not Art’. The rest they say is history. This famous act of vandalism has since become the title for an annual national ‘Independent, emerging and experimental arts festival’, which provides ‘a platform for innovative and passionate culture makers to present their ideas.’ <em>(This Is Not Art, 29 Sept – 3 Oct, Newcastle, Australia)</em></p>
<p><em></em>Needless to say, I’ve been intrigued by graffiti and street art ever since. It stops me in my tracks and takes me by surprise. It makes me angry and it makes me smile. It gets me thinking and it opens my eyes. In fact, rarely do I visit a new city without snapping shots of street murals, wall art and stencils. You can’t miss them, they’re everywhere &#8211; in wide-open public spaces, dark alleyways and car parks. Stairwells, fences and overpasses. Bridges, doorways and trains. But what’s the difference between street art and graffiti? Is it a battle of culture makers and political &amp; social commentators? Or is it just plain vandalism? Who’s to say? Does street art <em>legitimize</em> vandalism?</p>
<p>It seems this debate (and the tensions between the two camps) has been festering for years. Surely the common link between street art and graffiti is that they’re both trying to make a statement in their own way, with the difference being between their ideas, aesthetic approaches, culture and history.</p>
<p>Perhaps the answer lies in the eye of the beholder…Check out my pics of urban expressionism from Berlin, Bondi Beach, Buenos Airs and Barcelona.</p>
<p><a href="http://boboontherun.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/street-art-4.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-553" title="Street Art 4" src="http://boboontherun.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/street-art-4.jpg?w=640&#038;h=480" alt="" width="640" height="480" /></a><a href="http://boboontherun.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/street-art-8.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-554" title="Street Art 5" src="http://boboontherun.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/street-art-8.jpg?w=640&#038;h=480" alt="" width="640" height="480" /></a><a href="http://boboontherun.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/street-art-9.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-555" title="Street Art 6" src="http://boboontherun.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/street-art-9.jpg?w=640&#038;h=966" alt="" width="640" height="966" /></a><a href="http://boboontherun.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/street-art-13.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-557" title="street art-13" src="http://boboontherun.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/street-art-13.jpg?w=640&#038;h=378" alt="" width="640" height="378" /></a><a href="http://boboontherun.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/street-art-1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-558" title="Street art 8" src="http://boboontherun.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/street-art-1.jpg?w=640&#038;h=532" alt="" width="640" height="532" /></a><a href="http://boboontherun.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/street-art-5.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-559" title="Street art 9" src="http://boboontherun.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/street-art-5.jpg?w=640&#038;h=480" alt="" width="640" height="480" /></a><a href="http://boboontherun.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/street-art-revised-v2-3.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-561" title="street art 12" src="http://boboontherun.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/street-art-revised-v2-3.jpg?w=640&#038;h=429" alt="" width="640" height="429" /></a><a href="http://boboontherun.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/street-art-revised-1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-562" title="street art 14" src="http://boboontherun.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/street-art-revised-1.jpg?w=640&#038;h=426" alt="" width="640" height="426" /></a><a href="http://boboontherun.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/street-art-15.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-563" title="street art-15" src="http://boboontherun.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/street-art-15.jpg?w=640&#038;h=411" alt="" width="640" height="411" /></a><a href="http://boboontherun.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/street-art-revised-v3-1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-565" title="street art 14" src="http://boboontherun.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/street-art-revised-v3-1.jpg?w=640&#038;h=403" alt="" width="640" height="403" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/546/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/546/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/546/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/546/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/546/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/546/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/546/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/546/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/546/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/546/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/546/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/546/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/546/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/546/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=546&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://boboontherun.com/2011/09/12/urban-citizens-of-cool/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>12</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/48ff71edc3928d2d1ae170e27bd4898f?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">zoemarsh001</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://boboontherun.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/street-art-73.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Street Art 1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://boboontherun.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/street-art-21.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Street Art 2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://boboontherun.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/street-art-101.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">street art 3</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://boboontherun.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/street-art-4.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Street Art 4</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://boboontherun.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/street-art-8.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Street Art 5</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://boboontherun.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/street-art-9.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Street Art 6</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://boboontherun.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/street-art-13.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">street art-13</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://boboontherun.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/street-art-1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Street art 8</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://boboontherun.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/street-art-5.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Street art 9</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://boboontherun.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/street-art-revised-v2-3.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">street art 12</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://boboontherun.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/street-art-revised-1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">street art 14</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://boboontherun.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/street-art-15.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">street art-15</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://boboontherun.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/street-art-revised-v3-1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">street art 14</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Coronado Speed Festival 2011: Bonus Content</title>
		<link>http://timscribbles.com/2011/10/23/coronado-speed-festival-2011-bonus-content/</link>
		<comments>http://timscribbles.com/2011/10/23/coronado-speed-festival-2011-bonus-content/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2011 00:13:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>fullcoupe</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[350z]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Coronado]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[demo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drift]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[f18]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fc3s]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Festival]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hornet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leap frogs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mazda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nissan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[p40]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parachute]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rx7]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[s13]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[s14]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[s15]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sc400]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[seals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[silvia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[soarer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[speed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[toyota]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[z33]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://timscribbles.com/?p=3708</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Words by Matt Willis Here&#8217;s some &#8220;extra&#8221; material that didn&#8217;t fit into the main coverage pieces&#8230;enjoy! At the end of each race day, the drift drivers always have a little fun. Here are a few track-side shots&#8230; Tim getting up close to the action&#8230; As part of the pre-race ceremonies, the Navy coordinates a few [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=3708&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://timscribbles.com/2011/10/23/coronado-speed-festival-2011-bonus-content/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/de145dff02b4f40d86136454dd2312b3?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">darkstormcr</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6221/6219035415_d3652f7670_b.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_8729</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6174/6219558252_5317a1c614_b.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_8737</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6226/6219558226_f4643efa52_b.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_8731</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6240/6219036849_c693a5b292_b.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_8747</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6152/6219037673_fbdaef6058_b.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_8769</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6164/6219038935_886fbc66b0_b.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_8787</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6170/6219562628_9a07e31d8d_b.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_8798</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6049/6219563406_c1ab3192d8_b.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_8802</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6111/6219563880_fb93077d49_b.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_8818</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6162/6262541091_66e6094d74_b.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_1858</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6159/6219564938_31a3270aeb_b.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_8836</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6217/6219566130_0ace64b38f_b.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_8863</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6041/6219044477_41d7a9e31c_b.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_8867</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6094/6219045207_dab77cf94b_b.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_8873</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6110/6219045819_3543650747_b.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_8902</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6211/6263065668_a340fb3ea3_b.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_1900</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6231/6219568804_77398bbb3f_b.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_8932</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6228/6219048185_b8d888a18c_b.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_8977</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6174/6219571734_b55e862437_b.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_9008</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6214/6219050289_a10d8bab01_b.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_9022</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6050/6219051087_600d7f7ca5_b.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_9053</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6094/6219051809_5cb09fc8e8_b.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_9073</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6180/6262541463_a2871a9a3b_b.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_1879</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6053/6219574738_00b3b06b62_b.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_9101</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6046/6262541497_28c016b4e9_b.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_1893</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6220/6262541557_0e8ccd7a6f_b.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_1905</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6176/6263064986_e337af0973_b.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0993</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6236/6263064960_cdeaeafb46_b.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0990</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6158/6263064854_5841b292e8_b.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0969</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6158/6262540791_f9271f8d65_b.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0971</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6118/6262540817_e468b18cd3_b.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0972</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6033/6263064942_47e6a5c231_b.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0989</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>When applause means more than, &#8220;You didn&#8217;t kill us!&#8221;</title>
		<link>http://pithypants.com/2011/09/20/when-applause-means-more-than-you-didnt-kill-us/</link>
		<comments>http://pithypants.com/2011/09/20/when-applause-means-more-than-you-didnt-kill-us/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2011 13:31:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>pithypants</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Adventures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[airplane]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alaska Air]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[customer service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flying]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jobs]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://pithypants.com/?p=3719</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I flew to LA yesterday for work, and I&#8217;m about to say something that (I&#8217;m sure) will jinx me: I. Had. The. Best. Flight. Ever. Seriously? I hate flying. Really hate it. I&#8217;m pretty sure I&#8217;d feel that way just on the basis of how often I do it, but it doesn&#8217;t help that in [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=3719&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_3723" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 500px"><a href="http://pithypants.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/screen-shot-2011-09-19-at-7-14-41-pm.png"><img class="size-full wp-image-3723" title="Image Source: http://travelblog.viator.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/airtour.jpg" src="http://pithypants.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/screen-shot-2011-09-19-at-7-14-41-pm.png?w=490&#038;h=391" alt="" width="490" height="391" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">It was kind of like this. But in a bigger plane.</p></div>
<p>I flew to LA yesterday for work, and I&#8217;m about to say something that (I&#8217;m sure) will jinx me: I. Had. The. Best. Flight. Ever.</p>
<p>Seriously? I hate flying. Really hate it. I&#8217;m pretty sure I&#8217;d feel that way just on the basis of how often I do it, but it doesn&#8217;t help that in a past walk of life, I was spoiled with First Class tickets and lear jets. Once you&#8217;ve seen what&#8217;s on the other side of the curtain, it&#8217;s kind of hard to go back. Especially when going back means being wedged between a screaming baby and an Arm Rest Hog.</p>
<p>When I fly coach, I&#8217;m usually just looking for a safe flight. As a control freak, I spend a fair amount of time concerned that the pilot is either tired or drunk, and that the mechanic was either rushed or frustrated with his employer when he gave our ride the once-over. Every bump of turbulence sends me speculating about how we&#8217;ll meet our fiery death. <em>(Will I pass out from a lack of oxygen, or still be conscious when each organ bursts?)</em></p>
<p><span id="more-3719"></span>Yesterday morning, I headed into the flight expecting it to be worse than average. For starters, I had accidentally left my iPad at home. The same iPad I updated the night before specifically so it would have the latest issue of Vanity Fair and my book club&#8217;s October pick on it. I won&#8217;t lie &#8211; there was more than a moment of panic when I realized I was facing a five hour flight without entertainment.</p>
<p>Of course, the entertainment was a back-up plan. Whenever I travel for work, I try to work on the plane. But if it&#8217;s a horrible flight that has me convinced we won&#8217;t actually arrive at our destination with a pulse, I need some kind of major distraction to prevent me from getting all the passengers worked up about the safety of our flight. So I boarded Alaska Air in DCA with a sense of dread, thinking about my iPad, still snuggled in my sheets where I left it.</p>
<p>It was a full flight, but I was fortunate to share my row with a gay couple from Portland who had just been in DC for a friend&#8217;s wedding. At least, I assume they were a couple because they had matching his-and-his travel coffee mugs. I was impressed when they fished them out of their bags, shortly before the beverage service commenced.</p>
<p>I pointed at them. &#8220;Do you do that for environmental reasons?&#8221; They nodded. Right on! Sharing my row with thin, polite, eco-friendly gay men? It&#8217;s kind of like a Friday night dinner party at my house! I remember checking the &#8220;aisle&#8221; preference for my seat assignment, but it&#8217;s like Alaska Air actually did a personality profile to make sure I was flying with friends.</p>
<p><a href="http://pithypants.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/screen-shot-2011-09-20-at-9-26-24-am.png"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-3731" title="Image Source: http://www.msnbc.msn.com/id/12057042/ns/travel-business_travel/t/airline-coffee-bitter-cup-indeed/" src="http://pithypants.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/screen-shot-2011-09-20-at-9-26-24-am.png?w=260&#038;h=300" alt="" width="260" height="300" /></a>Unfortunately, the flight attendant didn&#8217;t understand why they had brought their own mugs. She thought they were trying to cheat the system and get more than their fair share of coffee. &#8220;Sorry, but I can&#8217;t fill those up,&#8221; she told them.</p>
<p>&#8220;That&#8217;s fine,&#8221; the guy next to me said. &#8220;I&#8217;ll take whatever you can give me, but I&#8217;d like it if you could pour it in here.&#8221; He held out his mug.</p>
<p>&#8220;Sorry. I can put it in this cup? Then you can pour it from the cup into your mug?&#8221; She offered.</p>
<p>&#8220;But that defeats the point. We don&#8217;t want to use as plastic cup.&#8221;</p>
<p>She wasn&#8217;t getting it, but the exchange was still pleasant, unlike what I&#8217;ve witnessed on other airlines. &#8220;But I can&#8217;t let the coffee pot touch something that isn&#8217;t clean&#8230;&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Fine, I&#8217;ll skip the coffee then,&#8221; the guy said. But he said it in a simple, accepting way, not the bitchy way someone else might deliver that line.</p>
<p>&#8220;So you don&#8217;t want coffee?&#8221; she asked, now truly confused.</p>
<p>&#8220;I <em>do</em> want coffee. I just don&#8217;t want to waste a plastic cup,&#8221; he explained.</p>
<p>A lightbulb went off and she managed to pour the coffee into his travel mug without the pot touching it. Bravo! Meanwhile, I continued sipping my Diet Coke, feeling very guilty as I eyed the plastic cup <em>and</em> the aluminum can on my tray table. Sigh. Definitely going to eco-hell for this. As if the carbon emissions trailing the plane weren&#8217;t enough to feel guilty about.</p>
<p>I fired up my laptop and decided to work. You know what else makes Alaska Air rock? In-flight WIFI for $4.95. That&#8217;s a dollar an hour. And it allowed me to plow through a pile of work. I was happily clicking away, chatting people back on the ground, when the woman across the aisle from me began to take an interest in what I was doing.</p>
<p>She leaned over and started to grill me with questions. <em>What do you do? How long have you done that? Where do you live? Do you travel a lot? Do you like your Apple laptop? Is the wifi free on this flight? How long are you in LA? Is this plane cold?</em></p>
<div id="attachment_3733" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://pithypants.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/screen-shot-2011-09-20-at-9-30-00-am.png"><img class="size-medium wp-image-3733" title="Image source: www.shechive.com" src="http://pithypants.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/screen-shot-2011-09-20-at-9-30-00-am.png?w=300&#038;h=171" alt="" width="300" height="171" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Her nails did NOT look like this. But these are definitely disturbing. Especially to a candy lover.</p></div>
<p>I tried my best to answer succinctly and get back to work, but she clearly wanted a conversation. I studied her, looking for something that could engender a larger exchange. All I could come up with were her nails, which were absurdly long and looked like Jackson Pollack had painted them.</p>
<p>I decided to forget the conversation and continue working.</p>
<p>Apparently the pilot had other plans, because he came over the intercom and announced, &#8220;Folks. Great news! Our flight path takes us right over the Grand Canyon today and it&#8217;s pretty clear so you&#8217;ll get a nice view out the right side of the plane in about 15 minutes. I&#8217;m going to check with ground control to if we can change our course a little bit so that both sides of the plane will get a view.&#8221;</p>
<p>I continued worked until &#8211; fifteen minutes later &#8211; the pilot came back on the PA system and said, &#8220;OK. So I&#8217;m going to tilt us to a bit so everyone can get a good view out the right side of the plane. And we tilted and the windows were suddenly full with nothing but the expanse of the Grand Canyon.</p>
<p>After flying that way for about five minutes, the pilot said, &#8220;And now I&#8217;ll give the left side their view.&#8221; And he did.</p>
<p>After a total of about ten minutes, he popped back on. &#8220;I hope everyone was able to see something. The Grand Canyon is something special!&#8221; And the passengers started clapping in response. I was somewhat dumbfounded, since the only other applause I&#8217;ve heard on planes is after a particularly dicey landing.</p>
<p>As a trainer who is in Los Angeles specifically to talk with new hires about the role they have been charged with in our organization, <em>that&#8217;s</em> what I want to convey: that passion for your job can have a ripple effect. We don&#8217;t always get applause, but we have it in our power to make the world a wee bit better than we found it.</p>
<p>When I got off the plane, I thanked the pilot and the flight attendants for a great flight and was ready to start singing the praises of anything from Alaska. But then I remembered Sarah Palin.</p>
<p>I think I&#8217;ll limit my enthusiasm to the airline, thanks.</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://pithypants.com/category/adventures-2/'>Adventures</a>, <a href='http://pithypants.com/category/travel-2/'>Travel</a>, <a href='http://pithypants.com/category/work/'>Work</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3719/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3719/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3719/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3719/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3719/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3719/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3719/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3719/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3719/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3719/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3719/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3719/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3719/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3719/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=3719&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://pithypants.com/2011/09/20/when-applause-means-more-than-you-didnt-kill-us/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>18</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/d04a6da77ac46a7b95e2b8f83683e30c?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">pithypants</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://pithypants.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/screen-shot-2011-09-19-at-7-14-41-pm.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image Source: http://travelblog.viator.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/airtour.jpg</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://pithypants.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/screen-shot-2011-09-20-at-9-26-24-am.png?w=260" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image Source: http://www.msnbc.msn.com/id/12057042/ns/travel-business_travel/t/airline-coffee-bitter-cup-indeed/</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://pithypants.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/screen-shot-2011-09-20-at-9-30-00-am.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image source: www.shechive.com</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Getting to the Starting Line, Ramblings From My First Marathon</title>
		<link>http://signaturemoms.com/2011/10/24/getting-to-the-starting-line-ramblings-from-my-first-marathon/</link>
		<comments>http://signaturemoms.com/2011/10/24/getting-to-the-starting-line-ramblings-from-my-first-marathon/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2011 17:18:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ashley Andrews</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Kris Berry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mommy Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parenting Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brockton hospital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brockton hospital Signature Moms blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospital mommy blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kris Berry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mommy blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mommy blogger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[signature healthcare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[signature mommy blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[signature moms]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://signaturemoms.com/?p=1495</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[By:  Kris Berry As I shared with you previously, I love to run.  It’s my little selfish outlet, time for myself to do something alone (or with a friend to chat with), it’s time to do something just for me.  It’s something I need in my life.  As my husband says, it keeps me sane.  [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=1495&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>By:  Kris Berry</strong></p>
<p><a href="http://signaturemoms.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/pa160002.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-1496" title="OLYMPUS DIGITAL CAMERA" src="http://signaturemoms.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/pa160002.jpg?w=346&#038;h=259" alt="" width="346" height="259" /></a>As I shared with you previously, I love to run.  It’s my little selfish outlet, time for myself to do something alone (or with a friend to chat with), it’s time to do something just for me.  It’s something I need in my life.  As my husband says, it keeps me sane.  My family knows when I need to run and, if I’m cranky, my kids will hand me my sneakers and tell me to go for a run.</p>
<p>As I already admitted, running has become a bit of an addiction for me.  It began innocently enough as a way to exercise. then I started running road races and realized how much I loved the excitement and the adrenaline rush that I got running in them.  A 10k turned into a ½ marathon.  Then that led to several more ½ marathons and the itchy little thought in the back of my head that maybe I could run a full marathon.  It’s something I have had on my “bucket list” for a while now, even before I started doing races.  So this year I signed up (and talked my poor sister-in-law into doing it with me).</p>
<p>About two months ago, I wasn’t sure I was actually going to get to the starting line.  Because of my training, I developed bursitis in my hip and tendinitis in my knee.  These conditions made it painful and very difficult for me to run.  I had to take an entire week off of running and then take it very slow and reduce my mileage for the rest of the training program.  This meant that I had to cut down two of my longest runs.  Sure, I wasn’t going for a Boston Qualifying time, but I had told myself that I was going to complete a marathon and I was disappointed that I was having set backs.  I went from trying to calculate what a “respectful finishing time” for me would be to just resolving to finish the thing.  Then, three days before the marathon I woke up with a cold that made me winded just walking up stairs.  I felt like cards were being stacked up against me.  A lot of people will tell you just getting to the starting line is the most important part of a training plan, it is totally true.</p>
<p><a href="http://signaturemoms.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/pa1600051.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-1499" title="OLYMPUS DIGITAL CAMERA" src="http://signaturemoms.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/pa1600051.jpg?w=384&#038;h=288" alt="" width="384" height="288" /></a>On October 16<sup>th</sup> I got in the starting line at the Baystate Marathon.  I told myself to really try to enjoy the run, take it all in, and realize what was happening every second of the way.  And as crazy as it sounds, I really did enjoy it, as much as a person can enjoy running 26.2 miles that is.  There were moments when I struggled, but I ran the entire thing, which was something I was totally not expecting, and I finished well within my goal time.   When I saw the 26 mile marker I burst into tears.  Of course, with a stuffy nose that only made things worse so I tried to hold back my emotions until I finished.  Then I rounded the corner to finish and saw my kids and my husband ringing their cow bells and cheering.  I blew them a kiss and crossed the finish line.  To say I was elated was a complete understatement.  I can’t articulate the feeling but, other than having my three children, nothing I have done in my life has made me prouder.</p>
<p>If I got anything out of this experience it is to not be afraid to try something outside of your comfort zone every once in a while.  Running a marathon isn’t something I would have ever thought was in the realm of possibilities for me.  But with the support of my family, and some pretty long training runs, I did it.  And for a not-so-fast runner, I kinda rocked it!  Will I run another marathon?  You betcha.  Just not for another few years (so I can forget about those 3+ hour training runs and my sore legs).</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://signaturemoms.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/pa160008.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1498" title="OLYMPUS DIGITAL CAMERA" src="http://signaturemoms.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/pa160008.jpg?w=384&#038;h=288" alt="" width="384" height="288" /></a></p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://signaturemoms.com/category/kris-berry-2/'>Kris Berry</a>, <a href='http://signaturemoms.com/category/mommy-advice/'>Mommy Advice</a>, <a href='http://signaturemoms.com/category/parenting-advice/'>Parenting Advice</a> Tagged: <a href='http://signaturemoms.com/tag/brockton-hospital/'>brockton hospital</a>, <a href='http://signaturemoms.com/tag/brockton-hospital-signature-moms-blog/'>brockton hospital Signature Moms blog</a>, <a href='http://signaturemoms.com/tag/hospital-blog/'>hospital blog</a>, <a href='http://signaturemoms.com/tag/hospital-mommy-blog/'>hospital mommy blog</a>, <a href='http://signaturemoms.com/tag/kris-berry/'>kris Berry</a>, <a href='http://signaturemoms.com/tag/mommy-blog/'>mommy blog</a>, <a href='http://signaturemoms.com/tag/mommy-blogger/'>mommy blogger</a>, <a href='http://signaturemoms.com/tag/signature-healthcare/'>signature healthcare</a>, <a href='http://signaturemoms.com/tag/signature-mommy-blog/'>signature mommy blog</a>, <a href='http://signaturemoms.com/tag/signature-moms/'>signature moms</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1495/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1495/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1495/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1495/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1495/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1495/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1495/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1495/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1495/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1495/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1495/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1495/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1495/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1495/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=1495&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://signaturemoms.com/2011/10/24/getting-to-the-starting-line-ramblings-from-my-first-marathon/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>21</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/54d3a3240438819fe47c5ad1fb0c8d71?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">missashley27</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://signaturemoms.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/pa160002.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">OLYMPUS DIGITAL CAMERA</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://signaturemoms.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/pa1600051.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">OLYMPUS DIGITAL CAMERA</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://signaturemoms.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/pa160008.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">OLYMPUS DIGITAL CAMERA</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Metastatic Breast Cancer</title>
		<link>http://toddlerplanet.wordpress.com/2011/10/17/metastatic-breast-cancer-day/</link>
		<comments>http://toddlerplanet.wordpress.com/2011/10/17/metastatic-breast-cancer-day/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2011 11:49:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Susan / @WhyMommy</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[breast cancer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[metastasis]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://toddlerplanet.wordpress.com/?p=3333</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I am a woman with metastatic breast cancer.  My cancer was first detected as inflammatory breast cancer nearly 4.5 years ago, although I&#8217;ve also had invasive breast cancer, Paget&#8217;s disease, and recurrences as the cancer spread to lymph nodes under my left arm (2010), to lymph nodes in the center of my chest (New Year&#8217;s [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=3333&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I am a woman with <a href="http://mbcn.org/">metastatic breast cancer</a>.  My cancer was first detected as <a href="http://www.ibcresearch.org/">inflammatory breast cancer</a> nearly 4.5 years ago, although I&#8217;ve also had invasive breast cancer, Paget&#8217;s disease, and recurrences as the cancer spread to lymph nodes under my left arm (2010), to lymph nodes in the center of my chest (New Year&#8217;s 2011), and then to my bones in March 2011.</p>
<p>Metastatic breast cancer means that cancer cells have spread from my right breast to other sites, made themselves at home, and reproduced so many times that now each cell has become a mass of cells detectable by today&#8217;s x-rays, CT scans, PET scans, and MRIs.  I have those tests frequently now, to determine how well my current treatment is proceeding, whether the cancer is progressing or held at bay, and when we should change treatments to something that might be more effective.  Last week&#8217;s tests and scans showed that there is still cancer in my neck, spine, ribs, and hips.  The blood tests had been showing a reduction in the total load of cancer cells in my body, but as the numbers slowed to a standstill, they agreed with the increasing pain in my hips, left ribs, and neck, one that agrees with the scans; we will have to change treatments.</p>
<p>Just to survive, I spend a day at the hospital every two out of three weeks now, receiving chemotherapy through the port implanted in my chest.  To lessen the pain of bone metastasis, caused by swelling of the bone as the cancer cells populate the core and push outward against its thin covering, I am undergoing pallative radiation therapy this month:  each workday for three weeks.  It is working &#8211; Thank God, it is working! &#8211; but it takes the whole morning to go for treatment and back, and then I sleep it off for several hours, waking when my children arrive home from school.  Yes, I have two little children.  It is hard to balance treatment with their care, but I am grateful for the opportunity to try.  I am grateful that my body responded to treatment the first time, that my chemotherapy, surgery, and radiation in 2007-8 beat back the cancer and gave me another chance to live, to be their mom &#8212; the baby, after all, is only four-and-a-half.</p>
<p>But, like 30% of other breast cancer survivors, the cancer came back.  I blamed myself, but we now know that the recurrence of cancer was not my fault.  Researchers now say that if a cancer is going to recur, cancer cells have already escaped the breast for other parts of the body even <em>before the primary cancer is detected</em> by today&#8217;s best methods of detection, let alone breast self-exams, the most highly recommended method of detection of breast cancers.</p>
<p>I am not alone.  Over 150,000 women and some men are living with metastatic breast cancer in the U.S.  45,000 die each year.  There is no cure.  [In 1980, the median survival after initial diagnosis of metastatic breast cancer (that is, not one that was diagnosed earlier, like mine) was 3 years.  Twenty years later, that number has not significantly changed.]</p>
<p>There are treatments that improve quality of life, like my radiation therapy this month, and chemotherapy to reduce the tumor burden that we have to struggle against, but these treatments are given to improve quality of life, not to cure.  The end result, after all, is the same.</p>
<p>In January of this year, I participated in my first clinical trial, eager to help move research forward, excited about participating in research on metastatic disease.  It was unsuccessful; by February, I was confined to bed, the soles of my feet red hot, skin peeled off, and in terrible shape.  Only then did I *really* understand that a Phase I/II clinical trial first tests toxicity; the amount of drug that the body can bear within reason.  The level that I was given was too much.</p>
<p>I started a new trial in March that compared standard-of-care injections with less frequent injections.  That was fine, except I did worry whether the study would be successful, as I was assigned to have less frequent injections, and was I hurting my chances for survival with this decision?  No one knew, and that was the purpose of that clinical trial.  I continue receiving those injections, but was moved off the trial when the next round of scans showed that the cancer spread to my bones.  My next treatment will be with a different drug.</p>
<p><a href="http://toddlerplanet.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/feb2_2011-1011.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-3338" title="Spring 2011" src="http://toddlerplanet.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/feb2_2011-1011.jpg?w=225&#038;h=300" alt="" width="225" height="300" /></a>I believe in research.  I believe in it so much that I have put my body on the line, participating in clinical trials before I even understood the rarity of the opportunity.  Trials for metastatic disease are few and far between &#8212; for the FDA mandates that before any clinical trial on metastatic disease start, the drug be shown effective in reducing primary breast cancers first.  But many researchers are now saying that metastatic disease does not behave the same as primary disease, so what good does this regulation do for those of us whose cancer has already come back, despite the drugs we used for our primary disease?</p>
<p>The regulation protects us, yes.  But it also makes the testing of new drugs that might work on metastatic breast cancer much rarer than it might otherwise be.</p>
<p>I have attended two significant events with other metastatic women this year, and each time we have asked the organizers and advocates how we can participate in more clinical trials.  How we can donate tissue, or time, or our very bodies &#8230; so that others may benefit from the research, and so that we can see the community actively working toward control of &#8212; or even a cure for &#8212; metastatic breast cancer.</p>
<p>With everything from groceries to debit cards going pink this month, special coverage on the news and advertisements on the radio, there is money and energy flowing in for awareness, treatment, and research on primary breast cancer.  <strong>But the funding for metastatic breast cancer remains at 3% of all funding for breast cancer research in the United States.</strong></p>
<p>Metastatic breast cancer is a variation of the breast cancer we hear about every day; it is a progression of that disease, and a deadly one.  It is what I feared; it is what so many of us cancer survivors diagnosed with Stage I, II, or III breast cancer fear.  While women with Stage I, II, or III breast cancer look for the &#8220;cure&#8221; and celebrate &#8220;hope,&#8221; those of us who have had a recurrence or are diagnosed first at Stage IV are not quite so happy and shiny this month of October.  Our &#8220;hope&#8221; is more desperate, and there is no chance today that we our cancer will ever be &#8220;cured.&#8221;</p>
<p>We attend the Pinktober events, the celebrations of progress for breast cancer, perhaps <a href="http://www.advancedbc.org/node/26">standing on the sidelines</a>, quietly cheering our sisters on.  We are genuinely thrilled for the progress that has been made in understanding about the importance of breast cancer self-exams; about follow up testing for everyone, no matter their ability to pay; and in the discovery of 20 or so chemotherapies that can beat back primary breast cancers, alone or in combination.  We smile as our Stage I, II, and III sisters take the stage, thrilled to share their stories and years of survival since that day each found a lump in her breast, and we clap as hard as anyone else for their survival.  It is, after all wonderful news.  We lower our eyes in remembrance of the women that the organization has lost in the past year, and we try to cheer for the hopeful outlook of more awareness, more research that the organizers swear to us will come if we just buy one more t-shirt, sell ten more tchotchkes, write that check before you leave.  We accept the pink ribbon and pin it to our shirts, but we often feel that it doesn&#8217;t quite fit.</p>
<p>The pink ribbons and survivor pride and celebrations are parts of a wonderful day, <em>but our day is not done</em>, you see.  When we go home, we take off our ribbons and take our pills and set our alarms, for in the morning, we have a chemo appointment.  Or a follow-up visit.  A scan.  Or we&#8217;re just waiting to see the results &#8212; has the cancer progressed since last time?</p>
<p>There is often deep reflection on those dark nights.  We support early detection, breast self-exams, mammograms, and we smile when someone shows us their pink ribbons or tries on pin one on us.  But still, we may come away from events like this with a tear in our eye, or mad as hell.  If there are so many reasons to &#8220;hope,&#8221; we ask, then can we please be included?  If all these walks and collections and special pink hair dryers and vacuum cleaners are being sold &#8220;for the cure,&#8221; is some of it, at least some of it, going to research metastatic disease?</p>
<p><strong>Why is research on metastatic disease funded at a level of just 3% of all breast cancer research, when metastatic disease is the state that all breast cancer patients reach if their cancer recurs?</strong>  Here&#8217;s a dirty little secret:  <em>very few people die of breast cancer confined to the breast</em>.  Breast cancer deaths are caused by treatment or metastasis, after the initial cancer has spread away from the breast and into vital organs.  We need to research that end of the cancer spectrum too.</p>
<p>Yes, let&#8217;s prevent cancer.  By all means, let&#8217;s prevent one more woman from suffering with this disease.</p>
<p>But let&#8217;s also research metastatic cancer, more, and faster, and let&#8217;s prevent women from <em>dying</em> from this disease.</p>
<p>Over 30% of women diagnosed with Stage I, II, and III breast cancers will suffer a recurrence and become metastatic.   Many more are diagnosed at Stage IV, after the initial cancer has already spread.  There is no cure.  And yet only 3% of the funding is focused on this end state.</p>
<p>How is this right?</p>
<p><em>For more on Metastatic Breast Cancer Day: this article in <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/mobileweb/2011/10/13/metastatic-breast-cancer-awareness-day_n_1009572.html">the Huffington Post</a>, the <a href="http://mbcn.org/">Metastatic Breast Cancer Network</a>, <a href="http://www.metavivor.org/">Metavivor.org</a>, @ihatebreastcancer <a href="http://ihatebreastcancer.wordpress.com/">Katherine O&#8217;Brian</a>, age 45; @ccchronicles <a href="http://cancerculturenow.blogspot.com/">Sarah</a>, age 41; @justenjoyhim <a href="http://justenjoyhim.com/2011/10/13/featured-charity-metastatic-breast-cancer-network/">Judy</a>; @jodyms <a href="http://womenwcancer.blogspot.com/">Women with Cancer</a>, @pinkribbonblues <a href="http://gaylesulik.com/2011/10/metastatic-breast-cancer-awareness-day/">Gayle Sulik</a>, a cancer fighter&#8217;s</em><em> stunning alterego @<a href="http://www.chemobabe.com/2011/10/everything-is-temporary/">Chemobabe</a>; </em> and the wonderful Twitter stylings of @stales, @talkabouthealth, and others who gather at #bcsm and #mbc.  <strong>Thank you for reading</strong>; our goal is to increase research funding for metastatic disease and to <em>change the conversation.  When you hear &#8220;buy this and we&#8217;ll donate to breast cancer!&#8221; I hope you&#8217;ll wonder, or even ask, <strong>&#8220;What percentage of your organization&#8217;s funds go to research metastatic breast cancer?&#8221;</strong></em></p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://toddlerplanet.wordpress.com/category/breast-cancer/'>breast cancer</a>, <a href='http://toddlerplanet.wordpress.com/category/metastasis/'>metastasis</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3333/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3333/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3333/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3333/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3333/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3333/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3333/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3333/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3333/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3333/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3333/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3333/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3333/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3333/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=3333&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://toddlerplanet.wordpress.com/2011/10/17/metastatic-breast-cancer-day/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>68</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/2578f4b5f8d8354d3061aa9837bdebd1?s=96&#38;d=wavatar&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">whymommy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://toddlerplanet.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/feb2_2011-1011.jpg?w=225" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Spring 2011</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Review: A powerful &#8216;Mountaintop&#8217;</title>
		<link>http://peteratthetheater.wordpress.com/2011/10/14/review-a-powerful-mountaintop/</link>
		<comments>http://peteratthetheater.wordpress.com/2011/10/14/review-a-powerful-mountaintop/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2011 10:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Peter D. Kramer</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA["The Mountaintop"]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Angela Bassett]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Broadway]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samuel L. Jackson]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://peteratthetheater.wordpress.com/?p=120</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;The Mountaintop,&#8221; Katori Hall&#8217;s powerful and compelling play imagining Martin Luther King Jr.&#8217;s last night, opened at Broadway&#8217;s Jacobs Theatre last night. Directed by Kenny Leon (&#8220;Fences&#8221;), it stars Hollywood icons Samuel L. Jackson and Angela Bassett. That&#8217;s it — and that&#8217;s plenty. For 94 minutes, the two denizens of the big screen fill David [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=120&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;The Mountaintop,&#8221; Katori Hall&#8217;s powerful and compelling play imagining Martin Luther King Jr.&#8217;s last night, opened at Broadway&#8217;s Jacobs Theatre last night.</p>
<p><a href="http://peteratthetheater.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/mountaintop.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-126" title="The MountaintopBernard B. Jacobs Theatre" src="http://peteratthetheater.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/mountaintop.jpg?w=400&#038;h=271" alt="" width="400" height="271" /></a></p>
<p>Directed by Kenny Leon (&#8220;Fences&#8221;), it stars Hollywood icons Samuel L. Jackson and Angela Bassett. That&#8217;s it — and that&#8217;s plenty.</p>
<p>For 94 minutes, the two denizens of the big screen fill David Gallo&#8217;s remarkable letterbox set — depicting the drab Room 306 at Memphis&#8217; Lorraine Motel on April 3, 1968 — with true-to-life, honest-to-goodness, flesh-and-blood characters: one we know from history, the other an intriguing revelation.</p>
<p><span id="more-120"></span>It&#8217;s raining buckets outside the Lorraine when King arrives from delivering what would be his final speech, at a Memphis church, the speech that ended with the words: &#8220;I&#8217;ve been to the mountaintop. I don&#8217;t mind. &#8230; Like anybody, I would like to live a long life. Longevity has its place. But I&#8217;m not concerned about that now.  I just want to do God&#8217;s will. And he&#8217;s allowed me to go up to the mountain and I&#8217;ve looked over and I&#8217;ve seen the promised land. I may not get there with you, but I want you to know tonight that we, as a people, will get to the promised land. I&#8217;m happy tonight. I&#8217;m not worried about anything. I&#8217;m not fearing any man. Mine eyes have seen the glory of the coming of the Lord.&#8221;</p>
<p>We don&#8217;t hear that speech in &#8220;The Mountaintop.&#8221; What we get, instead, is a glimpse of the humanity of their speaker.</p>
<p>Jackson&#8217;s King is jittery, shaken by the crack of thunder, chain-smoking Pall Malls as he wrestles with his next speech — the one he&#8217;ll never deliver.</p>
<p>This is not the King of the federal holiday. He&#8217;s the man who complains that his wife forgot to pack his toothbrush again.</p>
<p>He&#8217;s not the man who addressed the throng at the Lincoln Memorial. He&#8217;s the man with the holes in his smelly socks.</p>
<p>Actually, he&#8217;s both.</p>
<p>If the portrayal isn&#8217;t reverent, it is certainly compelling.</p>
<p>It is also a bit disturbing to Bassett&#8217;s character, Camae, the first-day-on-the-job Lorraine Motel maid who brings King his room-service coffee despite the downpour. She has seen King before &#8220;on the TV down at the Woolworth&#8217;s.&#8221; And this is not the King — she calls him &#8220;Preacher Kannnng&#8221; — she expects.</p>
<p>Camae is all smiles at first, practically genuflecting in the presence of the Great Man. Before long, though, she lets down her guard and tells it like it is. Truth to power.</p>
<p>Bassett&#8217;s charm is unquenchable. She seems lit from within. If Jackson&#8217;s King is a bundle of nerves, Bassett&#8217;s character is a bundle of energy, even if at times her portrayal is overly broad, her accent flagging here and there.</p>
<p>Jackson is rock steady, playing King as weary but driven, hoarse but unbowed, a man who lives in fear, the same fear that proves to him he&#8217;s alive.</p>
<p>The chemistry between Jackson and Bassett is clear: in a funny scene where Camae teaches the preacher how to &#8220;smoke like the people&#8221; and King poses for her invisible camera; or when she gives the good doctor a few pointers on making a powerful speech.</p>
<p>An air of sexuality hangs over the proceedings. The air in the Jacobs Theater crackles with it whenever the two find themselves in a compromising position, which is more than once. You can hear the audience suck in their breath nervously at these moments, too, as if they don&#8217;t want to go down that road. We&#8217;re ready to see King human, but not <em>that</em> human.</p>
<p>Hall&#8217;s script also mines a disconnect between the rarefied air of King and his &#8220;siditty&#8221; (pretentious) inner circle and the men they came to Memphis to support. Folks in Memphis, including Camae, call them garbage men. King and his group call them sanitation workers.</p>
<p>Gallo&#8217;s set employs a low proscenium, giving the proceedings a claustrophic air. Add the raging storm — courtesy of Brian MacDevitt&#8217;s lights and Dan Moses Schreier&#8217;s sound — and the walls seem to be closing in on the King-Abernathy suite.</p>
<p>There are moments of nuance that delight: When Bassett removes the preacher&#8217;s jacket from her shoulders, she folds it gently and smells it as she lays it back on the bed.</p>
<p>But there is much more to Camae than meets the eye, as revealed in a plot twist you must see to appreciate. The story shifts abruptly and telescopes out, thanks to Gallo&#8217;s remarkable effects, in a stunning continuum that brings the story closer to us and puts Bassett&#8217;s powers on magnificent display.</p>
<p>We know how the story ends, at 6:01 p.m. on April 4, 1968, on the balcony just outside this very motel room. But the journey of &#8220;The Mountaintop&#8221; turns that tragic event into something far greater: a beginning, not an ending.</p>
<p><strong>“The Mountaintop,&#8221;</strong> Bernard B. Jacobs Theatre, 242 W. 45th St. www.Telecharge.com. 212-239-6200. <a href="http://www.themountaintopplay.com/" target="_blank">Go to &#8220;The Mountaintop&#8221; website.</a></p>
<p><em>Photo by Joan Marcus: Samuel L. Jackson and Angela Bassett in &#8220;The Mountaintop&#8221; on Broadway.</em></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/120/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/120/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/120/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/120/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/120/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/120/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/120/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/120/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/120/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/120/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/120/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/120/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/120/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/120/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=120&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://peteratthetheater.wordpress.com/2011/10/14/review-a-powerful-mountaintop/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/ef29f160aedf913be8efac7c10cc5aac?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">peteratthetheater</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peteratthetheater.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/mountaintop.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The MountaintopBernard B. Jacobs Theatre</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mud. Run. Fun.</title>
		<link>http://discoverwashingtononeweekendatatime.wordpress.com/2011/10/26/mud-run-fun/</link>
		<comments>http://discoverwashingtononeweekendatatime.wordpress.com/2011/10/26/mud-run-fun/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2011 04:42:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Seattle Sun</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adventure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[carnation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gladiator]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hell run]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mud run]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[north bend]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[running]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[warrior dash]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Washington]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://discoverwashingtononeweekendatatime.wordpress.com/?p=119</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[What I love about the Northwest is the outdoors. Regardless of the weather, people in Washington all share a bond of loving the outdoors, rain or shine. Of course most of the time it is better when it shines, but there are some events that really are a hoot no matter what the weather conditions. [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=119&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://discoverwashingtononeweekendatatime.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/img_1636.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-121" title="IMG_1636" src="http://discoverwashingtononeweekendatatime.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/img_1636.jpg?w=225&#038;h=300" alt="" width="225" height="300" /></a>What I love about the Northwest is the outdoors. Regardless of the weather, people in Washington all share a bond of loving the outdoors, rain or shine. Of course most of the time it is better when it shines, but there are some events that really are a hoot no matter what the weather conditions. One of those events is a mud run. If you have never experienced one, I suggest that you hop onto this band wagon and hop on real quick.<br />
My first love affair with a mud run began at <a href="http://warriordash.com/register2011_washington.php">Warrior Dash</a> in North Bend. The Warrior Dash is about 3.5 miles, complete with 11 obstacles ranging from a fire pit to a cargo climb. I had heard about various mud run obstacle courses and wanted to try it out. When I heard that the Warrior Dash was coming to Washington for the first year, I thought this was the perfect opportunity. The <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bcsvL_oyRHE&amp;feature=related">video of Warrior Dash </a>is really the selling point. People in crazy costumes, running through mud, having a ridiculously good time. I thought to myself, I like to dress up in costumes, run, have a good time, challenge myself and get dirty so this is really a win win.</p>
<p><a href="http://discoverwashingtononeweekendatatime.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/img_1638.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-122" title="IMG_1638" src="http://discoverwashingtononeweekendatatime.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/img_1638.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a><br />
Patrick and I signed up for the race and showed up decked out in black face paint, camo and fake tattoos. I’m sure the pig tails also screamed warrior, it really seemed to give me an edge.</p>
<p>After snapping a million pictures, because I like to capture everything possible, we checked in and took our place at the starting line. We started off going slow because of the mass of people, but after passing the pack, the route widened up. The obstacles for the most part were manageable, but the end was by far my favorite.</p>
<p><a href="http://discoverwashingtononeweekendatatime.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/img_1668.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-127" title="IMG_1668" src="http://discoverwashingtononeweekendatatime.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/img_1668.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a></p>
<p>I scrambled my way up a cargo net only to be greeted on the other side by not one, but two fire pits. This immediately stopped me in my tracks, but after encouraging words and screams from the crowd, I was able to overcome my fear and jump over the flames (twice).<a href="http://discoverwashingtononeweekendatatime.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/img_1664.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-126" title="IMG_1664" src="http://discoverwashingtononeweekendatatime.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/img_1664.jpg?w=225&#038;h=300" alt="" width="225" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>The end of the race was signaled by a mud crawl. No way around it, unless you wanted barbed wire to scrap you. <a href="http://discoverwashingtononeweekendatatime.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/img_1674.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-128" title="IMG_1674" src="http://discoverwashingtononeweekendatatime.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/img_1674.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a> The end result is below. A muddy fun mess. A word of advice, bring a change of clothes. You will thank me. Another fantastic plus of the warrior dash is you get a fun shirt and a fuzzy warrior hat.</p>
<p><a href="http://discoverwashingtononeweekendatatime.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/img_1663.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-125" title="IMG_1663" src="http://discoverwashingtononeweekendatatime.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/img_1663.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a></p>
<p>When I heard there was yet another mud run hitting the area, this one with 13 obstacles and MORE mud, I just had to get in on it. <a href="http://www.hellrun.com/seattle/">Hell Run </a>out in carnation is another incredibly fun must do. This time, it seemed appropriate to dress like super hero, but really any costume is acceptable as long as you don&#8217;t mind getting muddy. <a href="http://discoverwashingtononeweekendatatime.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/img_1856.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-130" title="IMG_1856" src="http://discoverwashingtononeweekendatatime.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/img_1856.jpg?w=225&#038;h=300" alt="" width="225" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>Kelly, Patrick and I tested our toughness in Carnation decked out in as much face paint, spandex and flair as we could muster. Hell Run was similar to Warrior Dash, containing the key ingredients, mud, running, costumes and beer. But let me tell you , there was a lot more MUD. There were mud pits or as I would like to consider lagoons. It really is impossible not to get dirty on this one and you get muddy a lot sooner. We also had to wade through an ice cold river. Did I mention that it is October!??<a href="http://discoverwashingtononeweekendatatime.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/img_1864.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-132" title="IMG_1864" src="http://discoverwashingtononeweekendatatime.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/img_1864.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a></p>
<p>Though I don&#8217;t think mud runs are unique to Washington, I think that we have some great spots to hold these fantastic events. There is one coming up this weekend called <a href="http://www.gladiatorrocknrun.com/event_oct_29.html">Gladiator run </a>that you might want to consider. Don&#8217;t let my bad assness in these photos fool you, most people can complete these, it&#8217;s all about the fun : ) What are some of your favorite running events? I&#8217;m looking for a new challenge.<a href="http://discoverwashingtononeweekendatatime.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/img_1881.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-136" title="IMG_1881" src="http://discoverwashingtononeweekendatatime.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/img_1881.jpg?w=225&#038;h=300" alt="" width="225" height="300" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/119/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/119/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/119/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/119/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/119/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/119/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/119/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/119/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/119/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/119/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/119/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/119/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/119/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/119/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=119&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://discoverwashingtononeweekendatatime.wordpress.com/2011/10/26/mud-run-fun/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/6979abf3da073813158eac3a7a511414?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sultrysun</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://discoverwashingtononeweekendatatime.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/img_1636.jpg?w=225" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_1636</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://discoverwashingtononeweekendatatime.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/img_1638.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_1638</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://discoverwashingtononeweekendatatime.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/img_1668.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_1668</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://discoverwashingtononeweekendatatime.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/img_1664.jpg?w=225" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_1664</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://discoverwashingtononeweekendatatime.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/img_1674.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_1674</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://discoverwashingtononeweekendatatime.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/img_1663.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_1663</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://discoverwashingtononeweekendatatime.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/img_1856.jpg?w=225" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_1856</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://discoverwashingtononeweekendatatime.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/img_1864.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_1864</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://discoverwashingtononeweekendatatime.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/img_1881.jpg?w=225" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_1881</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>diy: purple people eater luminaries</title>
		<link>http://diyandfyi.wordpress.com/2011/10/24/diy-purple-people-eater-luminaries/</link>
		<comments>http://diyandfyi.wordpress.com/2011/10/24/diy-purple-people-eater-luminaries/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2011 17:00:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>christine</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[diy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crafts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[halloween]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[halloween decorations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[purple people eater]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://diyandfyi.wordpress.com/?p=379</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Halloween is in one week (yeah-uh!!) so if you&#8217;re in a pinch for some spooky decor, here&#8217;s a super easy craft that is cute and fun to make, especially with children. This craft was inspired by the classic &#8220;Purple People Eater&#8221; song, which I could put on repeat forever!! MAKE IT! 1 – You will [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=379&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:left;"><a href="http://diyandfyi.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/purpleppleater_3.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-396" title="purpleppleater_3sm" src="http://diyandfyi.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/purpleppleater_3sm.jpg?w=225&#038;h=300" alt="" width="225" height="300" /></a>Halloween is in one week (yeah-uh!!) so if you&#8217;re in a pinch for some spooky decor, here&#8217;s a super easy craft that is cute and fun to make, especially with children. This craft was inspired by the classic &#8220;Purple People Eater&#8221; song, which I could put on repeat forever!!</p>
<p><strong><strong>MAKE IT!</strong><strong><br />
1 – You will need:<br />
</strong></strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Purple paper bags</li>
<li>Paper (in white and black)</li>
<li>Scissors</li>
<li>Circle cutter</li>
<li>Cutting mat</li>
<li>Scrapbooking adhesive tape</li>
<li>Sand or small pebbles</li>
<li>Tealight candles</li>
</ul>
<p><strong><strong>2 – </strong>EYES.</strong> There are two ways to make the monster&#8217;s eye. You can make them on the computer and print it out and cut the eye. OR you can be crafty and use a circle cutter to cut white and black circles. If you go this route, use the scrapbooking adhesive to tape the black circle onto the white circle.</p>
<p><a href="http://diyandfyi.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/purpleppleater_1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-381" title="purpleppleater_1" src="http://diyandfyi.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/purpleppleater_1.jpg?w=490&#038;h=570" alt="" width="490" height="570" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://diyandfyi.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/purpleppleater_2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-382" title="purpleppleater_2" src="http://diyandfyi.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/purpleppleater_2.jpg?w=490&#038;h=328" alt="" width="490" height="328" /></a></p>
<p><strong><strong>3 – MOUTH</strong>.</strong> Cut out slits to make the mouth. I lightly bent the front face of the bag in half so that I can make the mouth in a few quick cuts. You could also use an exacto knife but don&#8217;t forget to put a piece of cardboard inside the paper bag so you don&#8217;t cut through to the back face. Though, I suppose your monster could have a face on both sides. :)</p>
<p><a href="http://diyandfyi.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/purple-037.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-385" title="purple 037" src="http://diyandfyi.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/purple-037.jpg?w=490&#038;h=367" alt="" width="490" height="367" /></a></p>
<p><strong><strong>4 – TEETH</strong>.</strong> Using the white paper, cut small triangles to make fangs. Dab a small amount of adhesive tape on the base of the triangle and stick it on the inside of the bag&#8217;s front face. Be goofy and give one of &#8216;em an underbite!</p>
<p><a href="http://diyandfyi.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/purpleppleater_4.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-397" title="purpleppleater_4sm" src="http://diyandfyi.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/purpleppleater_4sm.jpg?w=490&#038;h=367" alt="" width="490" height="367" /></a></p>
<p><strong><strong>5 – FINAL DETAILS</strong>.</strong> Fill the base of the paper bag with some sand or small pebbles. Set a tealight candle in the middle and light it! And you&#8217;re done!</p>
<p><a href="http://diyandfyi.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/purpleppleater_6.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-405" title="purpleppleater_5sm" src="http://diyandfyi.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/purpleppleater_5sm1.jpg?w=490&#038;h=368" alt="" width="490" height="368" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://diyandfyi.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/purpleppleater_6.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-398" title="purpleppleater_6sm" src="http://diyandfyi.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/purpleppleater_6sm.jpg?w=490&#038;h=330" alt="" width="490" height="330" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://tipjunkie.com"><img class="size-full wp-image-407 alignleft" title="TipMeTuesdayButton1" src="http://diyandfyi.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/tipmetuesdaybutton1.png?w=150&#038;h=150" alt="" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="http://thediyshowoff.blogspot.com/"><img class="size-full wp-image-410 alignleft" title="DIYShowOffbuttonsmall" src="http://diyandfyi.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/diyshowoffbuttonsmall.jpg?w=115&#038;h=136" alt="" width="115" height="136" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/379/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/379/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/379/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/379/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/379/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/379/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/379/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/379/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/379/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/379/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/379/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/379/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/379/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/379/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=379&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://diyandfyi.wordpress.com/2011/10/24/diy-purple-people-eater-luminaries/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>24</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/11709b83ce188d6c2bc848f88f641a2e?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">rcofsd</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://diyandfyi.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/purpleppleater_3sm.jpg?w=225" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">purpleppleater_3sm</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://diyandfyi.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/purpleppleater_1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">purpleppleater_1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://diyandfyi.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/purpleppleater_2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">purpleppleater_2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://diyandfyi.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/purple-037.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">purple 037</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://diyandfyi.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/purpleppleater_4sm.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">purpleppleater_4sm</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://diyandfyi.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/purpleppleater_5sm1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">purpleppleater_5sm</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://diyandfyi.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/purpleppleater_6sm.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">purpleppleater_6sm</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://diyandfyi.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/tipmetuesdaybutton1.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">TipMeTuesdayButton1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://diyandfyi.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/diyshowoffbuttonsmall.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DIYShowOffbuttonsmall</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Book Fiend&#8217;s Fantasy</title>
		<link>http://chronicledefforts.wordpress.com/2011/10/26/a-book-fiends-fantasy/</link>
		<comments>http://chronicledefforts.wordpress.com/2011/10/26/a-book-fiends-fantasy/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2011 09:14:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Geetanjali</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adventure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shopping]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://chronicledefforts.wordpress.com/?p=234</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;m still recuperating from the most exciting Sunday in my life. Last week I booked a train ticket to Delhi because I thought it would be fun to spend the weekend with my aunt and cousins. But I must admit that I went with another less familial intention as well. That other intention being the [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=234&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m still recuperating from the most exciting Sunday in my life. Last week I booked a train ticket to Delhi because I thought it would be fun to spend the weekend with my aunt and cousins. But I must admit that I went with another less familial intention as well. That other intention being the exciting sport of book shopping! Now it may be a little baffling to think that I went all the way to Delhi to buy a couple of books I could have easily bought from a bookshop closer to home. But I didn&#8217;t shop at any ordinary book shop. In fact I didn&#8217;t even shop at a book shop! The place I picked to let loose and book binge was the Sunday Book Bazaar in the Daryaganj area of Old Delhi.</p>
<div id="attachment_235" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 1034px"><a href="http://chronicledefforts.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/dsc05183.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-235" title="DSC05183" src="http://chronicledefforts.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/dsc05183.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=768" alt="" width="1024" height="768" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The reason I haven&#039;t written in a while</p></div>
<div id="attachment_236" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 235px"><a href="http://chronicledefforts.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/dsc05185.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-236 " title="DSC05185" src="http://chronicledefforts.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/dsc05185-e1319615345184.jpg?w=225&#038;h=300" alt="" width="225" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">A picture taken in the beginning. As we moved on we found that it was increasingly difficult to take pictures, and much busier.</p></div>
<p>Although this area of town is known to be busy throughout the week, Daryaganj is most famous for its Sunday Book Bazaar. Every Sunday the footpath of this market is transformed into India&#8217;s biggest second hand book market. This book market, guaranteed to make any book owl swoon in delight, goes on for over a kilometer and a half. And this being my first experience of the Daryaganj Book Market I was a little more than shocked to see books sold like clothes at a discount sale. Although some of the books were arranged neatly, most of the books were piled together or simply thrown together according to price. It kind of felt like I had stepped into a Farmer&#8217;s Market except instead of vegetables and fruit there were books, magazines, notebooks and journals.</p>
<p>One of the reasons these books are sold so cheap is because the book sellers don&#8217;t realize the value or the difference between the rare and the ordinary books. I don&#8217;t know what wisdom is used to separate the 20 Rupee books from the 30 Rupee books, but I have a strong feeling that the size and general appearance more than the content of the book plays a major role in the division. There was only one book seller who seemed to know his books well. But even his books were extremely cheap by regular standards. Of course most of the books here are discards by people who have no use for them, others are unclaimed books found on buses and trains later auctioned by the transport authorities to book sellers, and still others are old surplus copies of an edition that publishers aren&#8217;t able to sell. With the different sources that contribute to this unique second hand bazaar it isn&#8217;t surprising that all sorts of books can be found here. From the ubiquitous Nora Roberts to rare editions of the classics, this market appears to have it all. All you need to shop here is a keen eye and a love for wading and digging through stacks of books.</p>
<div id="attachment_237" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://chronicledefforts.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/dsc05186.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-237 " title="DSC05186" src="http://chronicledefforts.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/dsc05186.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Me having a difficult time zipping up while my cousin watches incredulously</p></div>
<p>It goes without saying that the key to dealing in this particular market is a good bargain. It&#8217;s also very important to come here looking bored and uninterested, more so if you spot a book you want to get your hands on. As long as you&#8217;re able to keep the glint out of your eye you&#8217;ll find that bargaining is a breeze and buying 20 Rupee books is like everyday business. I still can&#8217;t believe that I bought The Bridges of Madison County for only 20 Rupees! The Daryaganj Book Market is, like one article in a Delhi newspaper put it, an Aladdin&#8217;s cave to the penniless book lover. And when I stepped off the bus and found myself surrounded by books, books, and more books! &#8211;I knew exactly how Aladdin must have felt in that cave. I bought 22 books plus 3 proper drawing pads and I spent only 800 Rupees!</p>
<p>If you&#8217;re ever in Delhi and if you&#8217;re as crazy about the written word as I am, you must make it a point to visit this part of Old Delhi on a Sunday. But be warned, the Daryaganj Book Market is not a place for snobs. People of all kinds can also be found here pushing and shoving their way about. But this is really an extremely small price to pay in the bargain of getting to buy your favourite books at throw away prices.</p>
<div id="attachment_240" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://chronicledefforts.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/dsc05191.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-240" title="DSC05191" src="http://chronicledefforts.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/dsc05191.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Catching up on some Peanuts and Garfield while waiting for the bus</p></div>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/234/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/234/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/234/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/234/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/234/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/234/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/234/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/234/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/234/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/234/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/234/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/234/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/234/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/234/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=234&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://chronicledefforts.wordpress.com/2011/10/26/a-book-fiends-fantasy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/2868636d1ee7bfa8fd33ceb152f71b2b?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">chronicledefforts</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://chronicledefforts.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/dsc05183.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC05183</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://chronicledefforts.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/dsc05185-e1319615345184.jpg?w=225" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC05185</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://chronicledefforts.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/dsc05186.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC05186</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://chronicledefforts.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/dsc05191.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC05191</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>