<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2012 21:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>The Torajan Funeral</title>
		<link>http://ltomkiw.wordpress.com/2012/11/29/the-torajan-funeral/</link>
		<comments>http://ltomkiw.wordpress.com/2012/11/29/the-torajan-funeral/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2012 19:24:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lydia</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Indonesia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tana Toraja]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funeral]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kampung Dole]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tradition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Water Buffalo]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ltomkiw.wordpress.com/?p=4412</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[If my life was a movie, this day would have been titled: One Funeral, One Proposal and Four Faintings. OK, I only saw two people faint, but you get my drift. As, I wrote earlier, I wasn&#8217;t entirely comfortable with the idea of being a foreign tourist at the funeral of a complete stranger, but [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4412&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If my life was a movie, this day would have been titled: One Funeral, One Proposal and Four Faintings. OK, I only saw two people faint, but you get my drift.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-4414" title="Colorful Smiles" alt="" src="http://ltomkiw.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4547.jpg?w=590"   /></p>
<p>As, I wrote <a href="https://ltomkiw.wordpress.com/2012/11/24/hiking-through-torayas-rice-harvest/" target="_blank">earlier</a>, I wasn&#8217;t entirely comfortable with the idea of being a foreign tourist at the funeral of a complete stranger, but our Torajan guide, Pak Agust, reassured us we wouldn&#8217;t be intruding and that people were used to tourists. The day before the funeral, Pak Agust told us that it&#8217;s customary to bring gifts for the family, including bags of sugar or cartons of cigarettes. So we walked into a little shop with Pak Agust and bought some cancer sticks — really I wasn&#8217;t thrilled about giving cigarettes, but welcome to the gray area of travel, again.</p>
<p><a href="http://ltomkiw.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4519.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-4470" title="Singing" alt="" src="http://ltomkiw.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4519.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>We drove for nearly an hour to a small Torajan village named Kampung Dole. The drive was picturesque — green rice fields and rolling hills. When we arrived at the village, we followed a steady stream of people up a hill to an area with structures built for the funeral. As we arrived, men stood in a circle chanting, telling the life story of the man who had died. Pak Agust said the chanting was also a prayer in <em>bahasa Toraya </em>(the local language). One of the man&#8217;s relatives served as the master of ceremonies for the event. He would occasionally cackle into the microphone, it was a haunting sound. Pak Agust said he did it because the funeral is not supposed to be a somber affair. This was day one of a five day funeral.</p>
<p><a href="http://ltomkiw.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4540.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-4471" title="MC" alt="" src="http://ltomkiw.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4540.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>As we walked up the hill, several animals were also headed that way. Poor guy, I think he knew what was about to happen. The squealing sound pigs make towards the end is one of the most horrific noises I&#8217;ve ever heard.</p>
<p><a href="http://ltomkiw.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4511.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-4472" title="No Chance" alt="" src="http://ltomkiw.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4511.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>I want to warn you that after the jump there are some graphic photos of the water buffalo slaughter, this is, however a part of life and culture in Toraja.</p>
<p><span id="more-4412"></span></p>
<p>After the chanting, the coffin was lifted on to an upper platform, the best view for the funeral.</p>
<p><a href="http://ltomkiw.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4533.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-4473" title="Coffin" alt="" src="http://ltomkiw.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4533.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>The traditional dress and bead-work that the women were wearing was truly stunning. I asked if I could photograph them, and they agreed.</p>
<p><a href="http://ltomkiw.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4551.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-4474" title="Dressed" alt="" src="http://ltomkiw.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4551.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://ltomkiw.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4335.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-4519" title="Beaded" alt="" src="http://ltomkiw.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4335.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>I had a good chuckle when I caught the beautifully dressed lady checking her cellphone. Even in a rural village, Indonesia&#8217;s mania with cellphones has taken hold, I guess somethings have become universal.</p>
<p><a href="http://ltomkiw.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4526.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-4475" title="Texting" alt="" src="http://ltomkiw.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4526.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>Pak Agust explained to us that Torajan society, even today, is very stratified with upper and lower nobility. You could leave Toraja, become an international celebrity and billionaire but it wouldn&#8217;t change what class you were born into. We were attending the funeral of a high class member. Pak Agust said the man was a grandfather.</p>
<p><a href="http://ltomkiw.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4554.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-4476" title="Bored" alt="" src="http://ltomkiw.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4554.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>I wasn&#8217;t sure how I would react to watching a large animal being slaughtered. But it was all done in such a matter of a fact way, that I wasn&#8217;t in the least bit squeamish. Men tied down the buffalo while kids ran around in flip flops. Then with one swift swing, the buffalo was killed. The buffalo fell to the ground. It moved violently and then after a few minutes it stopped, but then suddenly, a minute or two later, it would spasm. A European tourist fainting caused more of a commotion among the Torajans than the slaughter did. Some wealthier villagers can afford to give the gift of a water buffalo for a funeral, and you can go and pick one out at the water buffalo market (stay tuned for that post).</p>
<p><a href="http://ltomkiw.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4569.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-4477" title="The Kill" alt="" src="http://ltomkiw.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4569.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>The water buffaloes are immediately butchered on the spot and the meat and all other parts are distributed to the family and other villagers. The stereotype around Indonesia is that Torajans are very wealthy because of their elaborate funerals. Pak Agust laughed when we asked him about this. He said that Torajans live poorly to save for a funeral. The big funerals will involve the slaughter of more than 24 water buffaloes, a sign of wealth. The buffaloes help transport the soul to the Torajan version of heaven. Traditional homes are decorated with the animal horns, the more horns, the more prosperous the family. Sometimes when people die, there isn&#8217;t enough money for a funeral, so the body will remain in the family home, sometimes for years, until enough money is saved for a proper send off. Funerals are usually held from June to October, during the dry season, when it&#8217;s easier for people to return home.</p>
<p><a href="http://ltomkiw.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4598.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-4478" title="Butchering" alt="" src="http://ltomkiw.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4598.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>All of the foreign tourists were taken to a sitting area. There were large buckets of rice and traditional Torajan food, including pork that is cooked in bamboo. Torajans are officially Christians, but obviously this is blended with old traditions. Missionaries converted Torajans, and Pak Agust told us that before that, in the old, old days, funerals could last months.</p>
<p><a href="http://ltomkiw.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4558.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-4479" title="Bamboo Pork" alt="" src="http://ltomkiw.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4558.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>On our way back down the hill, we stopped to meet the family and give them our gift. One of the female relatives of the dead man, offered us snacks and deliciously sweet black Torajan coffee. We sat around and chatted with her and then with some other guides and I spoke some French with a tourist from Paris. The amount of French and Spanish tourists in the area was astounding, some guidebook must have really highlighted this. We didn&#8217;t meet a single American during our whole trip. While drinking coffee, Pak Agust and another guide, Rudi, told dirty jokes about the type of &#8220;flowers&#8221; women are. As we prepared to go, the female relative, who was delighted by our Indonesian, decided to tell us she had two sons. We were a bit confused and then a mischievous smile appeared on her face and we knew exactly what she meant. So we all smiled and then took a group photo together.</p>
<p><a href="http://ltomkiw.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4602.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-4480" title="Coffee With the Family" alt="" src="http://ltomkiw.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4602.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>So, perhaps funeral is a bad word to describe all of this. It really was a celebration.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4412/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4412/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4412&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://ltomkiw.wordpress.com/2012/11/29/the-torajan-funeral/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/202020132d656e24120d416cf1d77de3?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ltca3232</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ltomkiw.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4547.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Colorful Smiles</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ltomkiw.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4519.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Singing</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ltomkiw.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4540.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">MC</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ltomkiw.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4511.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">No Chance</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ltomkiw.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4533.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Coffin</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ltomkiw.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4551.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Dressed</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ltomkiw.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4335.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Beaded</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ltomkiw.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4526.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Texting</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ltomkiw.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4554.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Bored</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ltomkiw.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4569.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The Kill</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ltomkiw.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4598.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Butchering</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ltomkiw.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4558.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Bamboo Pork</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ltomkiw.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4602.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Coffee With the Family</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Immigration Officers Day the Darnedest Things</title>
		<link>http://karenslatte.wordpress.com/2012/12/03/immigration-officers-say-the-darnedest-things/</link>
		<comments>http://karenslatte.wordpress.com/2012/12/03/immigration-officers-say-the-darnedest-things/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2012 02:36:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>The Skinny Jeans and Starbucks Chronicles</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Fun Stuff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Happiness Stuff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canadian Immigration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grateful]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[immigration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Justin Beiber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life is good]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Selena Gomez]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tim Hortons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://karenslatte.wordpress.com/?p=2136</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[If for some reason you have felt my blogging absence in your soul for the past week- don&#8217;t fret, children. I actually have a legit excuse this time.  As a lot of you already know, my never-ending immigration problems with Canada have been a constant source of bemoaned bitch fests on this blog. Around this [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2136&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#000000;">If for some reason you have felt my blogging absence in your soul for the past week- don&#8217;t fret, children. I actually have a legit excuse this time.  As a lot of you already know, my never-ending immigration problems with Canada have been a constant source of bemoaned bitch fests on this blog.</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#000000;">Around this time last year, I wrote a <a href="http://karenslatte.wordpress.com/2011/11/21/letter-to-canada/" target="_blank">very heartfelt letter to Canada</a> making a pretty strong case of why this country needs to drop all this Bollywood-style drama and welcome me to the family already. Unfortunately, none of the big wigs in Ottawa read my blog or they would have seen that my love for Canada knows no bounds.</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#000000;">I&#8217;ve been living here as a foreigner for so long that I was sure the government must have either forgotten about me or has been using my application as a place-mat for their Tim Hortons&#8217; coffee cups.</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#000000;">And then last week, just as I was in the middle of writing a miserable blog post about why Hallmark should hire me as their executive greeting card writer (I clearly have big dreams), I received an email from my immigration lawyer. It was an email I have been waiting a very very long time for.</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#000000;">I&#8217;m getting teary-eyed even writing this sentence: After 8 years, 3 months, and 21 days, my immigration application to become a permanent resident in Canada was finally <span style="text-decoration:underline;"><strong>APPROVED</strong></span>.</span></p>
<div id="attachment_2138" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 570px"><a href="http://karenslatte.wordpress.com/2012/12/03/immigration-officers-say-the-darnedest-things/attachment/7262636/" rel="attachment wp-att-2138"><img class="size-full wp-image-2138   " alt="I was a little most excited about becoming immigrant than these people were about Canada winning gold at hockey in the Vancouver Olympics. " src="http://karenslatte.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/7262636.jpg?w=590"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">I was a little more excited about becoming an immigrant than these people were about Canada winning gold at hockey in the Vancouver Olympics. (Source: www.chicagotribune.com)</p></div>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#000000;">The past eight years of my time in Canada were probably the happiest and the hardest years of my life. I met some of the most amazing people whom I eventually called friends, I developed an anxiety disorder over my job, I started this blog, I found religion, my first immigration application was denied, my status was incorrectly filed and as a result I lost my entire savings to the government in taxes leaving me completely broke. And then I broke my foot.</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#000000;">I laughed about it all till I almost peed my pants, and I cried about it all till I almost peed my pants&#8230;and eight years later, all of it came full circle as I stood in the immigration line clutching my confirmation letter- happy, proud, relieved and exhausted all at the same time.</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#000000;">But as much as I would love to tell you all more about my harrowing immigration ordeal, the whole point of this post was actually to tell you about the awesome immigration officers who marked the end of this chapter in my life.</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#000000;">Border immigration officers have always scared the crap out of me. They are stoic, expressionless fixtures who are trained to be suspicious of everything from puppies to empty tuna cans. Part of the whole charade of becoming a landed immigrant in Canada meant that I actually had to &#8220;land&#8221; in the country.</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#000000;">This required a drive to Niagara Falls, crossing the border into the States and then &#8220;landing&#8221; in Canada at the border on the way back. </span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#000000;">Crossing the US border is a feat in and of itself. I blame it on the fact that I was born in Kuwait. Names of Middle-Eastern countries stamped in your passport are never meritorious in these situations. We had a two hour wait in the line up in the immigration office at the US border.</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#000000;">The US immigration official dealing with my passport was a young man with the same stoic appearance as everyone else.</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#000000;">He asked me some questions, and then stared suspiciously back and forth between me and my passport. I almost shit my pants.</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#000000;"><strong>US Immigration officer</strong>: &#8220;How long are you going to be in the States?&#8221;</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#000000;"><strong>Karen</strong>: &#8220;Just a day&#8221;</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#000000;"> US Immigration officer </span><span style="color:#000000;">stares at me again. I was sure I was never going to get out of here. </span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#000000;"><strong>US Immigration officer</strong>: &#8220;Do you know who Selena Gomez is?&#8221;</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#000000;"><strong>Karen</strong>: &#8220;Huh? Umm yeh.&#8221;</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#000000;"><strong>US Immigration officer</strong>: &#8220;You look like her&#8221;</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#000000;"><strong>Karen:</strong> &#8220;Thanks. I get that all the time&#8221;</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#000000;"><strong>US Immigration officer: </strong>&#8220;Sorry to hear about you and Justin Beiber&#8221;</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#000000;"><strong>Karen</strong>: &#8220;I&#8217;m not crying myself to sleep over it&#8221;</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#000000;"><strong>US Immigration officer</strong>: &#8220;Good to see you&#8217;re pulling through.&#8221;</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#000000;"><strong>Karen:</strong> &#8220;I do what I can&#8221;</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#000000;"><strong>US Immigration officer</strong>: &#8220;Here&#8217;s your passport. Have a good trip.&#8221;</span></p>
<div id="attachment_2137" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 339px"><img class="size-full wp-image-2137" alt="When a US Immigration officer pays you such a high compliment, there's no other choice but to believe it. " src="http://karenslatte.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/selenakaren.jpg?w=590"   /><p class="wp-caption-text"><span style="color:#000000;">When a US Immigration officer pays you such a high compliment, there&#8217;s no other choice but to believe it.</span></p></div>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#000000;">It was a relief to know that the Americans weren&#8217;t trying to link me to some terrorist ring&#8230;just to Justin Beiber. Clearly they already thought I was Canadian enough. Now no one can say that US Immigration officers don&#8217;t have a sense of humor.</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#000000;">_____________________________________</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#000000;">The Canadian border immigration officers also had an unusual sense of humor&#8230;which they displayed through this very cruel prank they played on me.</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#000000;">Our car pulls up to the window and we hand the immigration officer lady our passports.</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#000000;"><strong>Canadian Immigration officer</strong>: &#8220;Who&#8217;s doing their landing here?&#8221;</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#000000;"><strong>Karen</strong>: &#8220;I am!&#8221;</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#000000;">Canadian Immigration officer looks at me confused.</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#000000;"><strong>Canadian Immigration officer</strong>: Umm&#8230;were you told to come to the border to do your paper work?&#8221;</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#000000;"><strong>Karen</strong>: &#8220;Yes. I was told I could come to the border anytime.&#8221;</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#000000;"><strong>Canadian Immigration officer</strong>: &#8220;Who told you this? I&#8217;m sorry, but we don&#8217;t do permanent residence paper work on Saturdays. You&#8217;ll have to come back.&#8221;</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#000000;">For the second time that day I almost shit my pants.</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#000000;"><strong>Karen</strong>: &#8220;What?!? No!! Please. I was told I could get it done anytime.&#8221;</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><strong style="color:#000000;">Canadian Immigration officer</strong><span style="color:#000000;">: &#8220;No ma&#8217;am, you can&#8217;t. Also, do you realize your visa here expired a couple of days ago?&#8221;</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#000000;"><strong>Karen</strong>: &#8220;NO IT DIDN&#8217;T!&#8221;</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#000000;">I was visibly on the verge of tears. The Canadian Immigration officer took one look at me and burst out laughing.</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#000000;"><strong>Canadian Immigration officer</strong>: &#8220;I&#8217;m so sorry. I&#8217;m just messing with ya. Come on out. Breathe. We&#8217;ll go in and do your paperwork&#8221;</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#000000;">I chalked this one down to the fact that maybe this woman was sitting out all day tired, probably needed a little entertainment and I was the perfect scapegoat.</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#000000;">The officers inside took all my forms, stamped all my documents.</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#000000;">They finally handed all my stuff back to me and said the words I never thought I&#8217;d hear:</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#000000;">&#8220;Congratulations, you are now a landed immigrant in Canada. Sorry you had to wait for so long.&#8221;</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#000000;">A declaration AND a quasi apology from a Canadian government official. </span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="color:#000000;">I smiled and walked out of that office feeling like I just won the life lottery.</span></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2136/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2136/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2136&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://karenslatte.wordpress.com/2012/12/03/immigration-officers-say-the-darnedest-things/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>90</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/0b26e865593313fad3f3a820234624ac?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">karen0909</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://karenslatte.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/7262636.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">I was a little most excited about becoming immigrant than these people were about Canada winning gold at hockey in the Vancouver Olympics. </media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://karenslatte.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/selenakaren.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">When a US Immigration officer pays you such a high compliment, there&#039;s no other choice but to believe it. </media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Wherein I Offer You a Few Disjointed but Heartfelt Memories of My Dead Friend Frank on Remembrance Day</title>
		<link>http://onetrackmuse.com/2012/12/07/intermezzo-wherein-i-offer-you-a-few-disjointed-but-heartfelt-memories-of-my-dead-friend-frank-on-pearl-harbor-remembrance-day/</link>
		<comments>http://onetrackmuse.com/2012/12/07/intermezzo-wherein-i-offer-you-a-few-disjointed-but-heartfelt-memories-of-my-dead-friend-frank-on-pearl-harbor-remembrance-day/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2012 17:36:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>maedez</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Intermezzo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[American HIstory]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[December 7]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Essay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Friends]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Friendship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nonfiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pearl Harbor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pearl Harbor Remembrance Day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onetrackmuse.com/?p=5452</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Dear World, Frank died at 87 1/2 years old. Picture this: When he was a tow-headed little boy, just a toddler, his parents dressed him in short pants and a striped shirt and posed him on the hood of the family Model T, grinning. Feisty. He was named after a prominent ancestor, Benjamin Franklin, and [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=5452&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dear World,</p>
<p>Frank died at 87 1/2 years old. Picture this: When he was a tow-headed little boy, just a toddler, his parents dressed him in short pants and a striped shirt and posed him on the hood of the family Model T, grinning. Feisty. He was named after a prominent ancestor, Benjamin Franklin, and they shared more than a name: both were brilliant, larger-than-life, charismatic. Actually, he came from a long line of characters: a grandfather who died, in his 90s, as the result of a bar fight, a father who was an early aviator. That family bred their men big, bold, and memorable. Frank, my Frank, my friend, came of age during the Great Depression. He had an older brother, equally brilliant; when it came time for Frank to attend college in &#8217;37 or &#8217;38, there was no money left. None. His brother had the degree that Frank would never get. He didn&#8217;t sweat it, moved on with life. Somewhere along the way he met a beautiful lady and they got married. Everything changed on 7 December 1941.<span id="more-5452"></span></p>
<p>I worked with Frank for 9 years, at a pays-all-the-bills day job when I was really young. Before I could do this all day, every day. He was nearly 77 when we met, but the glint in his eyes was that of a curious young man. He started his work day earlier than everyone but the owner. When I arrived at work on 7 December, 5 1/2 months after we met, he immediately came up to me and asked if I knew what day it was. It was a test, and I was the only one who passed. &#8220;Of course, Frank,&#8221; I said, &#8220;It&#8217;s the 7th of December. Pearl Harbor Remembrance Day. It&#8217;s been, what, 55 years?&#8221; His smile was huge and sun-bright. He unbuttoned his shirt and opened it, revealing his special surprise. I was new, so I&#8217;d never seen it before. (Minds out of the gutter, people. Minds out of the gutter. Actually, minds back in the gutter, people. Minds back in the gutter. Frank would like that.) Under the rumpled, short-sleeved, vaguely patterned button-down that he wore at least twice a week, every week, for a decade, was a white, hand-decorated T-shirt. On the front, thick black letters proclaimed: Peal Harbor, December 7, 1941. The back, as I discovered later, said simply and profoundly: NEVER FORGET. Frank never did, because that day forever changed his life and his country&#8217;s.</p>
<p>World War II made Frank a real pilot, like his dad. He flew for the United States Marine Corps Aviation, enlisting soon after that tragic December day. He was stationed in the Pacific. He killed people, saved lives, retreated, carried a wounded buddy to safety as the enemy sent gunfire over his head. Picture this: In between action, he posed, shirtless and tan, wearing a pair of white pants rolled up above the ankles, his pet monkey sitting on his shoulder, grinning. He was in his mid-twenties. His beautiful wife and young daughters were at home, thousands of miles away. He missed them, he always missed them, every day, every moment, but he did it all over again in Korea.</p>
<p>Frank refused to join his local VFW post, believing that the quickest way to grow old was to spend time with other senior citizens. Instead, he worked. He loved being around younger people. He kept up with the pop culture landscape, and could talk about current events better than the rest of us combined. Like those old veterans he refused to associate with, he loved talking about the wars that shaped his character and expanded his world-view. I heard the same stories a hundred times, and I enjoyed every second of every retelling. Unable to become a scientist, he read physics books for fun. He discussed philosophy over the morning coffee and classic strategies of war over lunch. He was the best part of my work day.</p>
<p>Back from two wars, he settled permanently into private life, at last, with his red-haired wife and four redheaded daughters. A charmer and a talker, he became a successful salesman. When he retired in the early 1970s, a year or two before I was born, he didn&#8217;t do so quietly: he immediately went out and found a part-time job at the gallery that was to bring us together two decades later. He stayed there more than 30 years, as rooted to the place as the uneven wooden floorboards and the crinkly original business license that was dated 5 February 1953.</p>
<p>If my knowledge of Pearl Harbor Remembrance Day sealed our friendship, my long red tresses started it: The day we met, he whipped out his wallet and showed me photographs of all five of his beauties. It was Frank who gave me a nickname that has stuck for eleven years. After seeing the movie <strong><em>Shrek</em></strong>, he told me that I looked just like the before, non-ogre version of Princess Fiona. To this day, if you call out the name Fiona, I will turn and look. Thanks, Frank. Every morning, like a Grandpa with the gait of a 30-year-old, he came into my workroom and handed me one Werther&#8217;s Original and gave me a peck on the cheek. He was still handsome, dynamic, sly, a bit naughty. Picture this: Tall if turned a bit paunchy, white-haired, beautiful-eyed, he was the easiest person to have hour-long conversations with about history, classic movies, war, politics, and anything else that crossed your mind. The man who, more than half a century earlier, had power enough and some to spare to charm a lovely young woman into matrimony and a monkey out of a tree on a forgotten island in the Pacific Ocean.</p>
<p>Frank died 5 1/2 years ago. He would have been 93 later this month. I loved him, and I miss him like he was family. During the hours that I listened to his war stories, his childhood memories, his humorous lessons, his unique Frank-philosophy-hours that must have, by the end, amounted to weeks or months of my life-I often thought that he was the ideal subject for a book. In the back of my writer&#8217;s mind, I knew that I should ask him to sit down and talk, recording device on the table. Before it was too late. He would have obliged, been honored. I never did it, and I&#8217;ve no idea why. It wasn&#8217;t due to shyness or propriety or doubt. As a writer, I could have given his story to the world, shared a few slivers of his brilliant mind with the masses. With you. So that you would know a little of the Frank that I knew, worked with, and loved for a decade. Frank as he wanted to be remembered, and certainly was: patriotic, charming, sharp, funny as fuck, brave, adventurous, handsome, loyal, family oriented, philosophical, and smarter than any of us. He was my friend, from first to last, and this open letter is all I have to give you, in honor of him. Today is Pearl Harbor Remembrance Day. NEVER FORGET.</p>
<p>Love,</p>
<p>Princess Fiona</p>
<div id="attachment_5535" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 594px"><img class="size-full wp-image-5535" alt="Where I met Frank." src="http://onetrackmuse.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/0021.jpg?w=590"   /><p class="wp-caption-text">Where I met Frank.</p></div>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5452/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5452/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=5452&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://onetrackmuse.com/2012/12/07/intermezzo-wherein-i-offer-you-a-few-disjointed-but-heartfelt-memories-of-my-dead-friend-frank-on-pearl-harbor-remembrance-day/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>34</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/97483067ebc497c49010fdbeca180991?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">maedez</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://onetrackmuse.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/0021.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Where I met Frank.</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Yar She Blows</title>
		<link>http://girlandgun.com/2012/12/10/yar-she-blows/</link>
		<comments>http://girlandgun.com/2012/12/10/yar-she-blows/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2012 01:54:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Briohny Doyle</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[comedy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hollywood Film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[postaday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Romance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Comedy of remarriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[film theory]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Philadelphia Story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women in film]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://girlandgun.com/?p=562</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I don&#8217;t know when romantic comedy became such a ubiquitously glib genre. When did the women of romcom lose their moxie and their smarts? When did tripping over and eating cupcakes become sufficient characterisation of a heroine? And when did realising that you might be better off fucking the guy who doesn&#8217;t resemble your dreams [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=562&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I don&#8217;t know when romantic comedy became such a ubiquitously glib genre. When did the women of romcom lose their moxie and their smarts? When did tripping over and eating cupcakes become sufficient characterisation of a heroine? And when did realising that you might be better off fucking the guy who doesn&#8217;t resemble your dreams become a reasonable epiphany to drive a script?</p>
<p>In a reactionary position (often hard to maintain from the couch) romcoms are to be appreciated strictly as trash, taken with a grain of salt and only intellectually engaged with on a dangerous, subconscious level &#8211; i.e. repression and conformity.</p>
<p>It wasn&#8217;t always like this. The romcom of the 1940s was fast paced, well scripted. A caper movie the territory of which was no less than the emotional lives of women and the men they loved and didn&#8217;t love. Sure, there were still misogynistic flourishes and unhelpful gendered portraits, however for the most part the characters were fully realised, complex humans within a context, which included not only gender but class and religion (though notable never, ever race. In the 1940s romcom not only the sheets had to be white). They still related to the theatrical genre, comedy of manors. Genre was a vehicle for sailing stormy seas not a tank to drown in.</p>
<p>Perhaps the most interesting of these old movies were a smattering that the philosopher of film Stanley Cavell called &#8216;comedy of remarriage&#8217;.  Responding to the Hays Code which explicitly ruled against the filmic depiction of immoral acts &#8211; cardinal amongst them adultery &#8211; this genre concentrated women&#8217;s emotional conflict about love from their position between marriage and divorce.</p>
<p>Typically they featured a primary couple whose connection remains enigmatic to the audience. They were married. And deeply in love. Though it didn&#8217;t work out. Now, separated, the female seeks to remarry and the dilemma over her choice in partners occurs from this decision.</p>
<p>My favourite romcom <i>His Girl Friday</i> is of this genre. Also, <i>It Happened One Night </i>and <i>Bringing Up Baby. </i>Cavell argues that the comedy of remarriage is one of the most important achievements of the Hollywood &#8216;talkie&#8217; in that it was an attempt to reconstruct marriage as an institution which centred around love first and foremost.</p>
<p>Usually, in these films, the woman goes back to her husband because she realises, despite any other aspirations she may hold, she still loves the cad, gosh damn it. The male for his part spends his time hang dogging and scheming and looking out for his gal. I love to see Cary Grant hangdogging and scheming and looking out for a gal. What a catch of a cad he is.</p>
<p><i>Philadelphia Story</i> is one of the most famous examples of the genre. It was written as a Broadway play for Katherine Hepburn. In it she plays a wealthy Philadelphia heiress, separated from an upper class cad who enjoys boozing and boating and who failed to live up to her high expectations.</p>
<p>She never understood his pain, or his &#8216;deep and gorgeous thirst&#8217; (!). And he, for his part, did her wrong. Now she seeks to marry a meeker, more conservative and obviously totally boring man. The story takes place in the lead up to the wedding during which time various men around her deliver their summations on her character, that she is like a goddess (not in a good way) placing herself above everyone else and with no tolerance for human frailty. And she&#8217;s a &#8216;prig&#8217;, a &#8216;perennial spinster&#8217; no matter how many husbands she has. Somewhat patronisingly the men around her (perhaps because, unlike Hepburn they are used to power and authority and have the correct equipment to deal with it), urge her to cultivate a forgiving heart in order to be &#8216;a first class woman or a first class human being&#8217;.</p>
<p>In the film, Cary Grant plays her ex husband, and James Stewart a reporter for a local tabloid, who, against his better judgment ends up covering Hepburn&#8217;s impending nuptials as part of a fairly elaborate web of blackmail and protection.</p>
<p>The story runs along at a cracking pace, and though it is obvious that Hepburn can&#8217;t marry her poor sap of a fiancé, the intrigue doesn&#8217;t flounder. As a heroine she is robust, exciting, intelligent and headstrong. We love her, as do all the men around who seek to take her down a peg.</p>
<p>Understandably, the insults and sermons bring on something of a personal crisis, though its nothing that a couple of bottles of champagne and night in the pool with James Stewart can&#8217;t sort out. The message is that she needs to let down her hair, lose control so that she can forgive those around her their faults. In this way, it&#8217;s Hepburn who seems to be enforcing the paternal order.</p>
<p>As I&#8217;m describing this I&#8217;m conscious that it sounds like a more complex version of the same line we are fed in today&#8217;s romcoms. I.e. bitch, get over yourself and marry that loser cause he loves you.</p>
<p>But it feels different in <i>The Philadelphia Story</i>. Because nobody actually teaches the heroine a lesson. And because she isn&#8217;t another &#8216;silly woman who doesn&#8217;t know her mind&#8217;, rather she is choosing between love and a more stable social security. And because you can&#8217;t separate these narratives from their context, in which a woman caught between marriages was committing crimes of morality. The kind of crimes that could not even be represented, which had to remain out of sight. In bringing these crimes out of the shadows, the film seems to imply that the morality is false, should be shed. Why aren&#8217;t women allowed to participate in the same developmental sluttery as men?</p>
<p>&#8220;What wives fail to realise is that their husbands&#8217; philandering has nothing to do with them,&#8221; Hepburn&#8217;s father tells her. It&#8217;s a remark that mirrors itself, becoming &#8211; what husband&#8217;s fail to understand is that their wives’ fidelity has nothing to do with them either.</p>
<p>The world is unfair and unequal. Men and women take on the unforgiving standards of conformity and make a big ol&#8217; mess of their lives as result.</p>
<p>In such a world, isn&#8217;t it best to pair up with someone who understands you? Well, that&#8217;s the romcom line all over.</p>
<p>As Hepburn, predictably, makes a morally sound choice, she promises her new husband that she will be a good wife. &#8216;Be whatever you want to be,&#8217; he tells her. It&#8217;s a message that spreads its arms across the script with warm generosity.</p>
<p>There is an association in the film of marriage as a yacht. A craft like the True Love, which Hepburn and Grant took their honeymoon on, bright and true and fast -&#8217;yar&#8217;, in the yachtsman drawl. But even a yar craft gets dry rot and has to be taken to dock and rebuilt from keel to hull.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a metaphor that can easily be extended to the genre of the rom com, which though finding its routes in something progressive, which leans toward emotional depth and complex interactions with dominant social modes, ends up running back into something worse than death: mindless formula. The dry rot of screenwriting.</p>
<p>Perhaps it&#8217;s time to haul the whole genre outta the drink and do some rebuilding so that we can make a true passage once more. Today&#8217;s rom coms feel like riding the man-made lake on a jetski. Films like a <i>The Philadelphia Story</i> may have been flawed, but my oh my, they were yar.</p>
<span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='640' height='360' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/IQC2guz8oGc?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span>
<p><i> </i></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/562/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/562/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=562&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://girlandgun.com/2012/12/10/yar-she-blows/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/8ffb0c2f24471bfc492829286ca2cb3b?s=96&#38;d=monsterid&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">briohnydoyle</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>I Don&#8217;t Need Any of This.  I Want All of This.</title>
		<link>http://imightbetheproblem.com/2012/12/08/i-dont-need-any-of-this-i-want-all-of-this/</link>
		<comments>http://imightbetheproblem.com/2012/12/08/i-dont-need-any-of-this-i-want-all-of-this/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2012 04:49:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>IMightBeTheProblem</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Conversations with Todd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[I should be taking this a bit more seriously]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Doctor Who]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Game of Thrones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kenny Loggins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Michael Kors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TARDIS]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://imightbetheproblem.com/?p=321</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Todd and I don&#8217;t agree on how to do Christmas. I mean, we both want a tree and presents and a house that smells just like a tree and sometimes cinnamon, but after that we sort of branch off in our own ways. Todd, as far as I can tell, hates joy. When I want [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=321&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Todd and I don&#8217;t agree on how to do Christmas. I mean, we both want a tree and presents and a house that smells just like a tree and sometimes cinnamon, but after that we sort of branch off in our own ways. Todd, as far as I can tell, hates joy. When I want to buy the children everything they have ever seen, he comes in and goes &#8220;but look, this is what we call a budget. And you have already spent $1000 on them so you have to stop now,&#8221; and then I&#8217;m like &#8220;BUT IT&#8217;S CHRISTMAS TODD AND I WANT TO BUY ALL THE THINGS.&#8221; We also disagree on gifts for each other. He feels that, as an adult, it is simply practical to just buy what we want for ourselves and then wrap it up and put it under the tree so the children can witness their parents opening presents and their parents, in turn, get exactly what they want. My approach is somewhat different. I want to drop hints all year pointing toward precisely what I want and then be surprised by which of those exact things I end up getting. I like the surprise, is what I&#8217;m saying. Yes, I want exactly what I want. But I want exactly what I want without having to come out and say &#8220;this is exactly what I want&#8221; and I&#8217;m not sure WHY that&#8217;s so unreasonable.</p>
<p>Last year, I did very well with this disconnect. There was a very specific sewing machine I wanted, so I very specifically said &#8220;I WANT THIS EXACT SEWING MACHINE.&#8221; And I wanted to learn knit, so we bought some knitting things. And I wanted a new iPhone, so we bought a new iPhone. But then Todd inadvertently ruined his own life by surprising me with a new iPad (an iPad that required a scavenger hunt, which delighted me. I&#8217;m seven, FYI) and now I am, once again, delighted by surprises. So he keeps asking me what I want and I keep saying &#8220;I want you to buy me whatever you think I would like&#8221; and he is probably going to kill me in my sleep because there are only so many shopping days left until Christmas. So I agreed to compromise. I will make a very BIG list, and then I can be surprised by which items from that list that I end up with. And then I will start therapy and learn how to be an adult.</p>
<p><strong>1) <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0097CZJEO/ref=as_li_qf_sp_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=B0097CZJEO&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=imibethpr0a-20" target="_blank">iPhone 5</a></strong></p>
<div id="attachment_337" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://imightbetheproblem.com/2012/12/08/i-dont-need-any-of-this-i-want-all-of-this/newisbetterthanold/" rel="attachment wp-att-337"><img class="size-full wp-image-337" alt="LOOK. It's bigger yet smaller and won't work with any of my current chargers. Need." src="http://imightbetheproblem.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/newisbetterthanold.jpg?w=590"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">LOOK. It&#8217;s bigger yet smaller and won&#8217;t work with any of my current chargers. Need.</p></div>
<p>I honestly have no idea how this is different from my iPhone 4, other than the obvious bigger screen/thinner everything else. It&#8217;s just the new one so I want it. Plus I have broken the screen on my iPhone 4 five times this year which makes me pretty confident that the iPhone 4 is structurally unsound because there&#8217;s no way I did something to break it on five separate occasions. That doesn&#8217;t sound like something I would do.</p>
<p><strong>2) <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B009MVT5EK/ref=as_li_qf_sp_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=B009MVT5EK&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=imibethpr0a-20" target="_blank">New TARDIS case for new iPhone</a></strong></p>
<div id="attachment_329" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://imightbetheproblem.com/2012/12/08/i-dont-need-any-of-this-i-want-all-of-this/amazontardiscase/" rel="attachment wp-att-329"><img class="size-full wp-image-329" alt="Not unlike the iPhone 5 itself, the TARDIS is both big and small.  " src="http://imightbetheproblem.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/amazontardiscase.jpg?w=590"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Not unlike the iPhone 5 itself, the TARDIS is both big and small.</p></div>
<p>My iPhone 4 has a TARDIS skin that looks exactly like this, but Todd seems to think that the lack of protection has a lot to do with all the breaking. So I will agree to a hard case this year, but it must make my new phone look exactly like my current phone, because the whole point of this is to have the exact same phone that I already have except NEWER. So <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B009MVT5EK/ref=as_li_qf_sp_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=B009MVT5EK&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=imibethpr0a-20" target="_blank">this one</a> by Rikki Knight on Amazon will do just fine. With the white sides, obvs, because I want the phone to be the white one before I cover it with a case so you won&#8217;t be able to see what color it is anyway.</p>
<p><strong>3) <a href="http://www.michaelkors.com/p/MICHAEL-Michael-Kors-MICHAEL-Michael-Kors-iPad-Saffiano-Stand/prod18810063/?ecid=MKCIGoogleProductAds&amp;ncx=n&amp;uEm=%%CSE%%&amp;ci_sku=prod18810063skuTANGERINE&amp;ci_gpa=pla&amp;ci_kw={keyword}" target="_blank">Michael Kors iPad Saffiano Stand</a></strong></p>
<div id="attachment_324" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 482px"><a href="http://imightbetheproblem.com/2012/12/08/i-dont-need-any-of-this-i-want-all-of-this/michaelkorsipadstand/" rel="attachment wp-att-324"><img class="size-full wp-image-324" alt="Pretend this is green.  Or orange, if you must.  " src="http://imightbetheproblem.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/michaelkorsipadstand.jpg?w=590"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Pretend this is green. Or orange, if you must.</p></div>
<p>This is where I win the iPhone argument, because I have had my iPad for a year with no case and have not broken it once (I never broke my iPhone 3, either, but whatever. Keep blaming me. It&#8217;s FINE.) Four days ago or so, I finally found an iPad case/stand that I really like and my search was, I thought, over. See this one? It comes in a really pretty green. Four days ago, that green color was all over the Michael Kors and Neiman Marcus web pages. Now there&#8217;s no green to be found. Good one, universe. Back up color? <a href="http://www.michaelkors.com/p/MICHAEL-Michael-Kors-MICHAEL-Michael-Kors-iPad-Saffiano-Stand/prod18810063/?ecid=MKCIGoogleProductAds&amp;ncx=n&amp;uEm=%%CSE%%&amp;ci_sku=prod18810063skuTANGERINE&amp;ci_gpa=pla&amp;ci_kw={keyword}" target="_blank">Orange.</a> Since it&#8217;s clearly not ME that&#8217;s breaking the iProducts, I probably don&#8217;t need this. But now that I found it and love it in what is probably a discontinued color, I need it in my life.</p>
<p><strong>4) <a href="http://www.michaelkors.com/p/Michael-Kors-Michael-Kors-Golden-Oversized-Runway-Watch-GOLDEN/prod2420007_cat20403_cat35701_/?index=1&amp;cmCat=cat000000cat145cat35701cat20403&amp;isEditorial=false" target="_blank">Michael Kors Golden Oversized Runway Watch</a></strong></p>
<div id="attachment_325" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://imightbetheproblem.com/2012/12/08/i-dont-need-any-of-this-i-want-all-of-this/siriwannabuythiswatchformymommaplease/" rel="attachment wp-att-325"><img class="size-full wp-image-325" alt="Sir I want to buy this watch, for my Momma please.  It's Christmas Eve and this watch is just her size.  " src="http://imightbetheproblem.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/siriwannabuythiswatchformymommaplease.jpg?w=590"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Sir I want to buy this watch, for my Momma please. It&#8217;s Christmas Eve and this watch is just her size.</p></div>
<p>Yes. I do already have almost this exact same watch. But it&#8217;s silver and rose and diamondy. I love my watch. My watch is my favorite. Last Mother&#8217;s Day, I talked about my watch for a month so that I would get it as a surprise for Mother&#8217;s Day, and it worked. So I&#8217;m going to talk about that same watch but in a different color for the next couple of weeks because I want another one. So far, my entire list is a variation of things that I already own, and I&#8217;m fine with that. And so is Michael Kors. And that is why he keeps making <a href="http://www.michaelkors.com/p/Michael-Kors-Michael-Kors-Golden-Oversized-Runway-Watch-GOLDEN/prod2420007_cat20403_cat35701_/?index=1&amp;cmCat=cat000000cat145cat35701cat20403&amp;isEditorial=false">this same watch</a> in different colors every year. Because it&#8217;s awesome and we should all have all of them.</p>
<p>(Psst&#8230;I want <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B006IYS0Y0/ref=as_li_qf_sp_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=B006IYS0Y0&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=imibethpr0a-20" target="_blank">this one</a>, too.)</p>
<p><strong>5) <a href="http://www.potterybarn.com/products/pb-classic-terry-robe/" target="_blank">Pottery Barn Classic Terry Robe</a></strong></p>
<div id="attachment_326" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 495px"><a href="http://imightbetheproblem.com/2012/12/08/i-dont-need-any-of-this-i-want-all-of-this/fancyhotelrobe/" rel="attachment wp-att-326"><img class="size-full wp-image-326" alt="This seems like a very grown up robe.  I want a robe who knows what it wants out of life and knows how to get there.  " src="http://imightbetheproblem.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/fancyhotelrobe.jpg?w=590"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">This seems like a very grown up robe. I want a robe who knows what it wants out of life and knows how to get there.</p></div>
<p>You know how when you put on a hotel terry robe it&#8217;s like the perfect terrycloth and the robe is all absorbent when you get out of the shower but also warm if you&#8217;re just waking up and throwing it on in the morning? That&#8217;s what I&#8217;m looking for in a robe. Usually I look at Pottery Barn to feel bad about how poorly put together my house is and then I look at Ikea to see what I can actually afford. But<a href="http://www.potterybarn.com/products/pb-classic-terry-robe/"> this robe</a> from Pottery Barn seems like the robe I want in my life. I desire a posh terry cloth hotel-like robe. Like a GROWN UP. Plus my initials can be embroidered on this one so nobody can steal it, and that just makes good sense to me.</p>
<p><strong>6) <a href="http://www.etsy.com/listing/108188018/game-of-thrones-stark-siblings-womens" target="_blank">Stark Siblings Women&#8217;s Tee Shirt</a></strong></p>
<div id="attachment_327" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://imightbetheproblem.com/2012/12/08/i-dont-need-any-of-this-i-want-all-of-this/starkshirt/" rel="attachment wp-att-327"><img class="size-full wp-image-327" alt="Even tee shirts single Jon out.  Not cool.  " src="http://imightbetheproblem.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/starkshirt.jpg?w=590"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Even tee shirts single Jon out. Not cool.</p></div>
<p>On the hierarchy of things over which I will completely nerd out, <em>Game of Thrones</em> is right up there with <em>Doctor Who</em> and <em>Harry Potter</em>. My concern over George R.R. Martin&#8217;s health is with me always. He tried to break my heart at the end of the fifth book. If something happens to him before he finishes the next two, I&#8217;ll pretty much never talk to anyone ever again. This really isn&#8217;t important information. I just want this shirt from <a href="http://www.etsy.com/listing/108188018/game-of-thrones-stark-siblings-womens" target="_blank">FencingNArchery</a> on Etsy. It&#8217;s cute, no?</p>
<p><strong>7) <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B005CWJB5G/ref=as_li_qf_br_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=B005CWJB5G&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=imibethpr0a-20" target="_blank">Apple MacBook Air</a></strong></p>
<div id="attachment_330" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://imightbetheproblem.com/2012/12/08/i-dont-need-any-of-this-i-want-all-of-this/macbook/" rel="attachment wp-att-330"><img class="size-full wp-image-330" alt="The best thing about macs is I work on a pc all day so it will take me twice as long to do anything.  " src="http://imightbetheproblem.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/macbook.jpg?w=590"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The best thing about Macs is I work on a pc all day so it will take me twice as long to do anything on a Mac.</p></div>
<p>Every Christmas list needs a hail mary.</p>
<p>(Really I just want my own laptop. I mean, my own that isn&#8217;t for work. And that isn&#8217;t Todd&#8217;s. And isn&#8217;t the desktop. We need a fourth computer, basically. And I don&#8217;t know anything about laptops or what a laptop should have but <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B009US2BKA/ref=as_li_qf_br_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=B009US2BKA&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=imibethpr0a-20" target="_blank">this one</a> is also pretty.)</p>
<p><strong>8) <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00AIIGG0C/ref=as_li_qf_br_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=B00AIIGG0C&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=imibethpr0a-20" target="_blank">Kenny Loggins Signed Guitar </a></strong></p>
<div id="attachment_331" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://imightbetheproblem.com/2012/12/08/i-dont-need-any-of-this-i-want-all-of-this/kennylogginswhatwhat/" rel="attachment wp-att-331"><img class="size-full wp-image-331" alt="My youth had a soundtrack.  And that soundtrack was played on this guitar.  " src="http://imightbetheproblem.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/kennylogginswhatwhat.jpg?w=590"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">My youth had a soundtrack. And that soundtrack was played on this guitar.</p></div>
<p>Oh. Hello, Conversation Piece.</p>
<p>Imagine that you own this. Now imagine the dinner parties. You own this, and you become &#8220;that girl with the Kenny Loggins guitar.&#8221; Yea. I want to be that girl, too.</p>
<p><strong>9) <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001J6NXO4/ref=as_li_qf_sp_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=B001J6NXO4&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=imibethpr0a-20" target="_blank">TOMS </a></strong></p>
<div id="attachment_332" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://imightbetheproblem.com/2012/12/08/i-dont-need-any-of-this-i-want-all-of-this/toms/" rel="attachment wp-att-332"><img class="size-full wp-image-332" alt="I love how everytime TOMS are mentioned, someone links to that same page that talks about how TOMS are dumb.  Let's do that again in the comments.  It's the best.  " src="http://imightbetheproblem.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/toms.jpg?w=590"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">I love how every time TOMS are mentioned, people fight.  Over shoes.  Let&#8217;s do that again in the comments. It&#8217;s the best.</p></div>
<p>It&#8217;s weird to me how people have really strong opinions on <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B001J6NXO4/ref=as_li_qf_sp_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=B001J6NXO4&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=imibethpr0a-20" target="_blank">TOMS</a>. Yes. I know that their organization isn&#8217;t ideal and the one for one structure is recognized by most to suck and blah blah blah. TOMS are my kick around and do whatever shoes. I like them. They are comfortable and the fact that they are ugly makes me happy because you just don&#8217;t ever have to wonder if they go with your outfit. They don&#8217;t go with any outfit. They&#8217;re ugly. And you probably aren&#8217;t doing all the good you think you&#8217;re doing by buying them. Anyway, I need a new pair. I&#8217;d like a pair in black AND ash this time. Size 6.5. At least they&#8217;re not UGGS, you know?</p>
<p><strong>10) <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B005GK3IVW/ref=as_li_qf_br_asin_il_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=B005GK3IVW&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=imibethpr0a-20" target="_blank">Robot Maid From the Future </a></strong></p>
<div id="attachment_333" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://imightbetheproblem.com/2012/12/08/i-dont-need-any-of-this-i-want-all-of-this/rosie/" rel="attachment wp-att-333"><img class="size-full wp-image-333" alt="This actually IS a Cogswell Cog, I think.  " src="http://imightbetheproblem.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/rosie.jpg?w=590"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Looks an awful lot like a Cogswell Cog, doesn&#8217;t it?</p></div>
<p>The first year Todd and I lived together, I really wanted a new vacuum. So for Christmas we bought an expensive vacuum. That thing sucks. It breaks pretty much all the time. But the little button that sucks the cord back up when you&#8217;re done using it is pretty fun. This has no cord, but does possibly have the ability to emote. I&#8217;m not sure. All I know is it means I don&#8217;t have to vacuum. And I can refer to it as my robot maid, which I have wanted to do pretty much my whole life because the Jetsons promised we&#8217;d have them by now. So I would like a robot maid and also a real maid, please.</p>
<p><strong>11) <a href="http://www.bodygraphics.com/contact-hours-locations.php" target="_blank">New Tattoo</a></strong></p>
<div id="attachment_334" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 466px"><a href="http://imightbetheproblem.com/2012/12/08/i-dont-need-any-of-this-i-want-all-of-this/noregrets/" rel="attachment wp-att-334"><img class="size-full wp-image-334" alt="No regrets.  " src="http://imightbetheproblem.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/noregrets.jpg?w=590"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">No regrets.</p></div>
<p>I made myself a promise awhile back that I wouldn&#8217;t get any new tattoos until I had gone through the pain and expense of removing my existing tattoos because that&#8217;s how you&#8217;re supposed to learn lessons, or something. But really, I&#8217;m a 34 year old mother of two. My hip and back are exposed to the world like twice a year, and I&#8217;m not exactly the only mid-thirties mom hitting the beach with the Japanese character for &#8220;regret&#8221; permanently emblazoned on her lower back. So I would like a new tattoo in a far more obvious place because I obviously make good decisions. I&#8217;m not sure how you give a tattoo to someone for Christmas, but I&#8217;m rarely worried about what others will have to go through to get me what I want. So there&#8217;s that.</p>
<p>Oh. And also? I made you guys some stuff for Christmas, too. You just have to pay for it first. You&#8217;re Welcome.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.zazzle.com/cuckoldry_and_christmas_tee-235572742222018078" target="_blank">Cuckoldry and Christmas Ladies Tee</a> &#8211; This tee shirt is expensive. I put it on this particular tee shirt because this is the tee shirt I would wear. It can go on all the other, less ridiculously expensive versions too, though.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.zazzle.com/11_oz_standard_mug-168288607573202349" target="_blank">Put Your Mouth On This Mug</a> &#8211; I have a coffee mug at work and the design is on the wrong side and so when I drink coffee it looks like I have a really boring plain white coffee mug to everyone else and so they all probably have no idea that my mug is delightful and so am I. You will not have that problem here. Lookit. Goes all the way around, my design. And not because I didn&#8217;t know how to resize it, either. I totally know what I&#8217;m doing here.</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://imightbetheproblem.com/category/conversations-with-todd/'>Conversations with Todd</a>, <a href='http://imightbetheproblem.com/category/i-should-be-taking-this-a-bit-more-seriously/'>I should be taking this a bit more seriously</a> Tagged: <a href='http://imightbetheproblem.com/tag/christmas/'>Christmas</a>, <a href='http://imightbetheproblem.com/tag/doctor-who/'>Doctor Who</a>, <a href='http://imightbetheproblem.com/tag/game-of-thrones/'>Game of Thrones</a>, <a href='http://imightbetheproblem.com/tag/ipad/'>iPad</a>, <a href='http://imightbetheproblem.com/tag/iphone/'>iPhone</a>, <a href='http://imightbetheproblem.com/tag/kenny-loggins/'>Kenny Loggins</a>, <a href='http://imightbetheproblem.com/tag/michael-kors/'>Michael Kors</a>, <a href='http://imightbetheproblem.com/tag/shopping/'>Shopping</a>, <a href='http://imightbetheproblem.com/tag/tardis/'>TARDIS</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/321/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/321/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/321/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/321/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/321/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/321/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/321/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/321/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/321/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/321/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/321/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/321/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/321/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/321/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=321&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://imightbetheproblem.com/2012/12/08/i-dont-need-any-of-this-i-want-all-of-this/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>53</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/7765693e2abfa75d5c317009434eb7b6?s=96&#38;d=monsterid&#38;r=R" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">imightbetheproblem</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://imightbetheproblem.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/newisbetterthanold.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">LOOK. It&#039;s bigger yet smaller and won&#039;t work with any of my current chargers. Need.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://imightbetheproblem.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/amazontardiscase.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Not unlike the iPhone 5 itself, the TARDIS is both big and small.  </media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://imightbetheproblem.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/michaelkorsipadstand.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Pretend this is green.  Or orange, if you must.  </media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://imightbetheproblem.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/siriwannabuythiswatchformymommaplease.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Sir I want to buy this watch, for my Momma please.  It&#039;s Christmas Eve and this watch is just her size.  </media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://imightbetheproblem.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/fancyhotelrobe.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">This seems like a very grown up robe.  I want a robe who knows what it wants out of life and knows how to get there.  </media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://imightbetheproblem.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/starkshirt.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Even tee shirts single Jon out.  Not cool.  </media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://imightbetheproblem.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/macbook.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The best thing about macs is I work on a pc all day so it will take me twice as long to do anything.  </media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://imightbetheproblem.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/kennylogginswhatwhat.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">My youth had a soundtrack.  And that soundtrack was played on this guitar.  </media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://imightbetheproblem.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/toms.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">I love how everytime TOMS are mentioned, someone links to that same page that talks about how TOMS are dumb.  Let&#039;s do that again in the comments.  It&#039;s the best.  </media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://imightbetheproblem.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/rosie.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">This actually IS a Cogswell Cog, I think.  </media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://imightbetheproblem.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/noregrets.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">No regrets.  </media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The White House Joins Pinterest, Invites Users to Holiday Social</title>
		<link>http://digiphile.wordpress.com/2012/12/08/white-house-pinterest-white-house-social/</link>
		<comments>http://digiphile.wordpress.com/2012/12/08/white-house-pinterest-white-house-social/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 08 Dec 2012 21:26:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Alex</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[government 2.0]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social bookmarking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://digiphile.wordpress.com/?p=1695</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The White House joined Pinterest today. Over the past several years, the White House digital team has sought to leverage the growing unprecedented scale of its connections on these networks to influence national debates on proposed laws, policies and rules, applying public engagement to politics with mixed results. Now the team will be pinning as [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1695&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/pinterest">White House joined Pinterest</a> today. Over the past several years, the White House digital team has sought to leverage the growing unprecedented scale of its connections on these networks to <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/alexander-howard/government-social-media_b_958579.html">influence</a> national debates on proposed laws, policies and rules, applying <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/alexander-howard/social-media-and-politics_b_1072798.html">public engagement to politics</a> with mixed results. Now the team will be pinning as well as tweeting, blogging, liking and plussing.</p>
<div style="padding-bottom:2px;line-height:0;"><a href="http://pinterest.com/pin/157274211958886643/" target="_blank"><img alt="" src="http://media-cache-ec3.pinterest.com/upload/386183736766746725_E9kWy9OE_c.jpg" height="685" width="554" border="0" /></a></div>
<div style="float:left;padding-top:0;padding-bottom:0;">
<p style="font-size:10px;color:#76838b;">Source: <a style="text-decoration:underline;font-size:10px;color:#76838b;" href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/pinterest">whitehouse.gov</a> via <a style="text-decoration:underline;font-size:10px;color:#76838b;" href="http://pinterest.com/digiphile/" target="_blank">Alex</a> on <a style="text-decoration:underline;color:#76838b;" href="http://pinterest.com" target="_blank">Pinterest</a></p>
</div>
<p>As has often been the case over the past four years, I learned about the news first on Twitter, directly from a tweet by White House Digital Director Macon Phillips:</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p>Joining @<a href="https://twitter.com/pinterest">pinterest</a> should be a lot of fun! please share ideas on what you&#8217;d like to see cc @<a href="https://twitter.com/ks44">ks44</a><a title="http://m.whitehouse.gov/pinterest" href="http://t.co/WUhkzJyC">m.whitehouse.gov/pinterest</a></p>
<p>— Macon Phillips (EOP) (@macon44) <a href="https://twitter.com/macon44/status/277495140787027968">December 8, 2012</a></p></blockquote>
<p>While this digital team has often joined services early enough to secure an optimal namespace, this time, they were a bit late to the pinning party and can be found as <a href="http://pinterest.com/whitehouse44">WhiteHouse44</a>, not /WhiteHouse.</p>
<p>The decision by the White House to join Pinterest comes as the photo sharing website ends a period of hypergrowth in 2012 that resulted in a ranking amongst the most popular social media platforms in the United States.  According to <a href="http://blog.nielsen.com/nielsenwire/social/2012/">Nielsen&#8217;s 2012 Social Media Report</a>, Pinterest grew by over 1,000% over in the United States in 2012, with even high year over year growth in unique mobile Web (4,225%) and mobile app (1,698%) users. Given that the White House has an official presence on every other major social media platform, the move recognizes a new reality: Pinterest is now in the top five social destinations in the country, and therefore worth investing time and resources for staff to engage there.</p>
<p>The White House had already joined other popular social networks over the years, including:</p>
<ul>
<li>Facebook: <a href="https://www.facebook.com/WhiteHouse" target="_blank">The White House</a></li>
<li>MySpace: <a href="http://www.myspace.com/whitehouse" target="_blank">The White House</a></li>
<li>Google+: <a href="https://plus.google.com/+whitehouse" target="_blank">The White House</a></li>
<li>Twitter: <a href="http://twitter.com/#%21/whitehouse" target="_blank">The White House</a></li>
<li>LinkedIn: <a href="http://www.linkedin.com/groups?gid=2199632" target="_blank">The White House Group</a></li>
<li>YouTube: <a href="http://www.youtube.com/user/whitehouse" target="_blank">The White House Channel</a></li>
<li>Vimeo: <a href="http://vimeo.com/whitehouse" target="_blank">The White House</a></li>
<li>Flickr: <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/whitehouse" target="_blank">The White House’s photostream </a></li>
<li>iTunes: <a href="http://itunes.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewArtistLegacy?cc=us&amp;id=299652047" target="_blank">White House Podcasts</a></li>
<li>Foursquare: <a href="https://foursquare.com/whitehouse">The White House</a></li>
<li>Socrata: <a href="http://opendata.socrata.com/profile/whitehouse/bhnt-uir2" target="_blank">whitehouse</a></li>
<li>SlideShare: <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/whitehouse" target="_blank">White House</a></li>
<li>Storify: <a href="http://storify.com/whitehouse" target="&quot;_blank">The White House</a></li>
<li>Digg: <a href="http://digg.com/whitehouse" target="_blank">The White House</a></li>
<li>Github: <a href="http://github.com/whitehouse" target="_blank">White House</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Kori Schulman, the director of online engagement for the Office of Digital Strategy in the White House, blogged about the <a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/pinterest">White House joining Pinterest</a> at the WhiteHouse.gov blog.</p>
<p>Schulman described the White House&#8217;s new Pinterest account as another way to open up the White House to more people today:</p>
<blockquote><p>From the very beginning, President Obama and the First Lady have taken steps to make this the most open White House in history. “It’s the “People’s House,” said First Lady Michelle Obama, “It’s a place that is steeped in history, but it’s also a place where everyone should feel welcome. And that&#8217;s why my husband and I have made it our mission to open up the house to as many people as we can.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>That’s why the White House is open for virtual tours 24/7 through the <a href="http://www.googleartproject.com/collection/the-white-house/museumview/">Google Art Project</a> and why you can follow us on <a href="http://twitter.com/whitehouse">Twitter</a>, <a href="http://facebook.com/whitehouse">Facebook</a>, <a href="http://flickr.com/whitehouse">Flickr</a> and other places around the web. And, it’s why we&#8217;re now thrilled to add <a href="http://pinterest.com/whitehouse44/">Pinterest</a> to the list.</p>
<p>The <a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/about/inside-white-house/holidays">holidays</a> are an especially exciting time for the White House to start pinning. During the 2012 holiday season alone, more than 90,000 visitors will have the chance to tour the White House holiday decorations, all hung with care by a team of crafty staff and volunteers. To kick off our presence on Pinterest, we&#8217;re <a href="http://whitehouse.gov/social">inviting some of our newest followers</a> to join us for a Holiday Social at the White House. Pinners will be invited to check out the décor, meet with the people that helped transform the White House for the holidays, join us for a craft project — and share it all with the Pinterest community.</p></blockquote>
<p>According to Schulman, the White House will roll out its first pinboards on December 17th, the day of its first &#8220;<a href="www.whitehouse.gov/social">White House Holiday Social</a>,&#8221; a new, more general term for an in-person meeting between White House staff and people who follow its official accounts on social media platforms.</p>
<p>The White House has held a series of &#8220;tweetups&#8221; for Twitter users over the past year, starting with the first Twitter Town Hall. (I went to the <a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/44/post/white-house-tries-to-stay-connected-with-top-tweeters/2011/07/22/gIQAyJJ6TI_blog.html">second White House tweetup</a>, which coincided with an in-person town hall with President Obama at the University of Maryland, where he told students that he was &#8220;<a href="http://gov20.govfresh.com/obama-i-am-absolutely-convinced-that-your-generation-will-help-us-solve-these-problems/">absolutely convinced that your generation will help us solve these problems</a>.&#8221; </p>
<p>The new approach to a &#8220;White House Social&#8221; will be more broadly applicable to future meetups, assuming that a second Obama administration continues to value creating bridges between offline and online networks of supporters. </a></p>
<p>The last descriptor is key: the White House has been experimenting the Internet, generally &#8212; and with social media, specifically &#8212; to share the images, media and ideas that the administration wants to promulgate to the country, from proposed policies to political action. White House staff, including communications director Dan Pfieffer, have gone on the record to say that they believe social media campaigns have affected the debt ceiling debate and offline outcomes.</p>
<p>The White House&#8217;s most recent effort at public engagement through social media, in which the administration encouraged Americans to share what $2,000 dollars meant to them, resulted in 100,000 submissions at WhiteHouse.gov and 250,000 tweets that used the #My2K hashtag. That conversation was catalyzed this past week when President Obama logged on to Twitter himself again for a <a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2012/12/04/watch-president-obamas-twitter-q-a">presidential Q&amp;A</a> in which he urged Americans to call, email and tweet to Congress regarding the so-called fiscal cliff.</p>
<p>As I&#8217;ve written before, however, real issues with meaningful use of social media by Congress persist, including an <a href="http://radar.oreilly.com/2011/05/nstic-analysis-identity-privacy.html">online identity</a> ecosystem that has not provided Congress with ideal means to identify constituents online. The reality, when it comes to which <a href="http://www.frogloop.com/care2blog/2011/2/3/latest-report-what-messaging-and-channels-influence-congress.html">channels influence Congress</a>, in-person visits and individual email or phone calls from constituents remain far more influential with Congressional staffers than tweets. The probability that pins will prove to be any more significant in political debates remains to be seen.</p>
<p>The White House won&#8217;t alone there. While Massachusetts Senator-Elect Elizabeth <a href="http://techpresident.com/news/23217/worries-over-copyright-infringement-kept-warrens-senate-campaign-pinterest-aide-says">Warren&#8217;s campaign stayed off of Pinterest</a> because of worries that copyright infringement claims could lead the social sharing site to be shut down, a growing number of political campaigns and government entities have joined the platform over the last six months.</p>
<p>Why? Pinterest represents not just a new horizon for White House digital efforts but one in which a specific interest group &#8212; women &#8212; can be found in engagement numbers that they are not elsewhere. Pinterest is <a href="http://techland.time.com/2012/02/15/men-are-from-google-women-are-from-pinterest/">strongly identified with women</a>, with Pew Internet research back in February 2012 finding that <a href="http://www.pewinternet.org/~/media//Files/Reports/2012/PIP_OnlineLifeinPictures.pdf">1 in 5 women on the Internet</a> are on the social sharing service. </p>
<p>Whether the White House&#8217;s pins resonate will also depend upon whether politics, Pinterest and political media become more intertwined. To date, blogs, Facebook, YouTube and Twitter have been the primary online forums for digital politics. In 2013, pinning may take on new significance.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1695/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1695/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1695&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://digiphile.wordpress.com/2012/12/08/white-house-pinterest-white-house-social/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/46fa2eecd111960d686233e2ebdd3194?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">digiphile</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://media-cache-ec3.pinterest.com/upload/386183736766746725_E9kWy9OE_c.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Five Best Ways to Beat Reader’s Block</title>
		<link>http://dysfunctionalliteracy.com/2012/12/09/the-five-best-ways-to-beat-readers-block/</link>
		<comments>http://dysfunctionalliteracy.com/2012/12/09/the-five-best-ways-to-beat-readers-block/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2012 02:50:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>dysfunctional literacy</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Dysfunctional Literacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[literature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writers block]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dysfunctionalliteracy.com/?p=3773</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Reader’s block doesn’t get the respect that writer’s block does.  People (especially writers and artists) can sympathize with writer’s block because a writer is creating something, and creating something can be difficult.  Reader’s block gets less sympathy because all a reader needs to do to read is read.  Complaining about reader’s block is like being [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3773&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://commons.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:CC_No_05_Moby_Dick.JPG" target="_blank"><img class="zemanta-img-inserted zemanta-img-configured" title="Cover scan of a Classics Comics book" alt="Cover scan of a Classics Comics book" src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/5/55/CC_No_05_Moby_Dick.JPG/300px-CC_No_05_Moby_Dick.JPG" height="412" width="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">When I was a kid, this was the only way I could read Moby Dick without getting reader&#8217;s block. Who am I kidding? It&#8217;s still the only way. (Photo credit: Wikipedia)</p></div>
<p>Reader’s block doesn’t get the respect that writer’s block does.  People (especially writers and artists) can sympathize with writer’s block because a writer is creating something, and creating something can be difficult.  Reader’s block gets less sympathy because all a reader needs to do to read is read.  Complaining about reader’s block is like being the kid with all the toys in his room griping about being bored. </p>
<p>Reader’s block can be frustrating and deserves to be taken (just a little) seriously.  Yes, reading is more passive than writing, but it still takes mental activity.  Reading requires concentration and a willingness to get through difficult exposition/narration (hopefully with a payoff). </p>
<p>“Block” can happen with even the most passive of activities.  I’ve gotten television watching block.  The symptom for that is mindless flipping of channels.  I’ve gotten video game block.  The symptom for that is intentionally ending games early by getting myself killed (in gruesome, violent ways if possible).  I’ve even gotten “music block,” when I change radio stations and playlists until I eventually give up. </p>
<p>I’ve never gotten “football watching block.” </p>
<p>But reader’s block is the worst because reading is the activity (that I can write about) that I enjoy the most (except maybe watching football, but nobody wants to read what I write about watching football).  It doesn’t make sense that I can get bored with books when there are so many good books out there.  There are enough good books out there that nobody (who really knows how to read) should get reader’s block. </p>
<p>Complaining about reader’s block doesn’t cure reader’s block.  But there are several methods that can. </p>
<p>1.  STOP READING. </p>
<p>Yeah, I know that writers are always supposed to read (especially when they’re not writing), but rules are made to be broken (every once in a while and only if nobody gets hurt).  This doesn’t mean that a reader should stop reading altogether.  Reading comic books, blogs, cereal boxes, or closed captioning on television counts as reading. </p>
<p>And if a reader does stop reading altogether, nobody cares.  Last summer I went on vacation and deliberately did not read or write anything.    I was told I was a much more pleasant person to be around when I wasn’t trying to read and write.  There was no pressure put on me to start reading and writing again. </p>
<p>2. READ CLASSIC LITERATURE. </p>
<p>Readers who aren’t into classic lit should choose a short book.  <b><i>The Great Gatsby</i></b> is great for reader’s block.  <b><i>Les Miserables</i></b> might be a disaster. </p>
<p><b><i>Moby Dick</i></b>?  Haha!  <b><i>Moby Dick</i></b>. </p>
<p>Classics that have gotten me out of reader’s block: </p>
<p><b><i>Frankenstein</i></b>- by Mary Shelley</p>
<p><b><i>The Great Gatsby</i></b>- by F. Scott Fitzgerald</p>
<p><b><i>Ulysses</i></b>- by James Joyce (Okay, I’m kidding!) </p>
<p>3.  READ A BOOK YOU KNOW YOU&#8217;LL DISLIKE. </p>
<p>Make sure it’s short.  If you choose a long book, that’s okay too because you really don’t have to finish it. </p>
<p>Books that I knew I’d dislike that got me out of reader’s block: </p>
<p><b><i>Gorilla Beach</i></b> by Snookie- supposedly written by somebody else. </p>
<p>I really don’t like admitting that I actually read a few pages of that. </p>
<p>4.  READ A BOOK YOU&#8217;VE READ BEFORE. </p>
<p>This is risky.  Sometimes staying in a comfort zone is what causes the rut in the first place.  Reading a familiar book may only prolong the reader’s block.  Or it may kick-start a reader’s enthusiasm for reading. </p>
<p>Favorites that have temporarily cured my reader’s block: </p>
<p><b><i>Marathon Man</i></b>- by William Goldman</p>
<p><b><i>The Godfather</i></b>- by Mario Puzo</p>
<p><b><i>The Thin Man</i></b>- by Dashiell Hammet </p>
<p>5.  DO A LOT OF WRITING. </p>
<p>This might seem like bad advice.  If a reader can’t muster enough energy to read, how can the reader find the enthusiasm to write?  Sometimes writing can get the brain going.  And if it doesn’t, then maybe the reader will get so frustrated by writing that reading will become an easy alternative. </p>
<p>I had reader’s block when I started writing “Long Story” for Dysfunctional Literacy.  It’s only been a few weeks, but I’ve been eagerly reading ever since.  I’m not sure what the cause-effect relationship is, but writing may have influenced my enthusiasm to read.  Or maybe I don’t know what I’m talking about. </p>
<p>***** </p>
<p>Thankfully, I don’t have reader’s block right now. Not having reader’s block is a great time to write about having reader’s block.  Next time I have reader’s block, maybe I’ll come back and read my own solutions.  Or I might not… because I’ll have reader’s block and won’t feel like reading it. </p>
<p>It’s not cool when I get reader’s block on my own stuff.</p>
<p> *****</p>
<p>For more about reader’s block and what NOT to do about it, read  <a href="http://dysfunctionalliteracy.com/2012/06/18/5-bad-reasons-to-read-a-book/">5 Bad Reasons to Read a Book</a> .</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3773/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3773/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3773&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://dysfunctionalliteracy.com/2012/12/09/the-five-best-ways-to-beat-readers-block/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>40</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/df86266e0665ed52b4a05767dfb936c2?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">dysfunctionalliteracy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/5/55/CC_No_05_Moby_Dick.JPG/300px-CC_No_05_Moby_Dick.JPG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Cover scan of a Classics Comics book</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Om Malik in Conversation with Matt Mullenweg</title>
		<link>http://om.co/2012/12/10/wordpress-matt-mullenweg-om-malik/</link>
		<comments>http://om.co/2012/12/10/wordpress-matt-mullenweg-om-malik/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2012 20:32:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Om Malik</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Me In Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Le Web 2012]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Matt Mullenweg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Paris]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wordpress]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://om.co/?p=6922</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[At Le Web 2012, I chatted on stage with my friend Matt Mullenweg. We discussed a variety of topics, but the conversation kicked off with our growing disgust with the un-customer centric approach of social networks. In their bid to become dominant platforms, they are sacrificing the needs of Internet users, and perhaps that is [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=6922&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At Le Web 2012, I chatted on stage with my friend <a href="http://ma.tt">Matt Mullenweg</a>. We discussed a variety of topics, but the conversation kicked off with our growing disgust with the un-customer centric approach of social networks. In their bid to become dominant platforms, they are sacrificing the needs of Internet users, and perhaps that is why it is time for the Internet entrepreneurs to think different about how we build the future. </p>
<span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='610' height='343' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/DABu2TFijZo?version=3&#038;rel=0&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=6922&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://om.co/2012/12/10/wordpress-matt-mullenweg-om-malik/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/89c6ff98059617751fcf312690965fa0?s=96&#38;d=identicon" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">om</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Like An Airport Luggage Carousel</title>
		<link>http://ohtomeohmy.wordpress.com/2012/12/09/like-an-airport-luggage-carousel/</link>
		<comments>http://ohtomeohmy.wordpress.com/2012/12/09/like-an-airport-luggage-carousel/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2012 21:24:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>cleveport</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Irony]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wry]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://ohtomeohmy.wordpress.com/?p=101</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[That&#8217;s how I&#8217;ve been feeling lately. Going round and round, with the baggage just piling on. Maybe it&#8217;s the holiday season, maybe it&#8217;s the short days and cold weather, maybe it&#8217;s Maine, or the way Portland shuts down&#8211; in both the commercial sense, where the stores and activities close early or entirely for the season; [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=101&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>That&#8217;s how I&#8217;ve been feeling lately. Going round and round, with the baggage just piling on. </p>
<p>Maybe it&#8217;s the holiday season, maybe it&#8217;s the short days and cold weather, maybe it&#8217;s Maine, or the way Portland shuts down&#8211; in both the commercial sense, where the stores and activities close early or entirely for the season; and in the personal sense, where people just don&#8217;t want to be friendly and go out and be nice to people. We&#8217;re probably all experiencing some level of SAD. </p>
<p>I knew that winter would suck. Last winter was terrible. It was long and daunting, and I never thought it would end. I had a perpetual storm cloud over my head, just waiting to blizzard over me. I was holding on with laces, wearing down from the weight, threatening to snap. But spring came, and I didn&#8217;t need those laces&#8211; I broke free, and things looked good again, hopeful, full of life. </p>
<p>And winter is upon us again, and I&#8217;ve had to go back to those laces, worn and becoming threadbare. Here&#8217;s to hoping they won&#8217;t snap. It&#8217;s going to be a long season, perhaps even longer than last year. </p>
<p>But it&#8217;s sunny today, so while I feel like I&#8217;m losing my jaunt (and I apologize to everyone around me for being weird these last few weeks. I&#8217;m acutely aware of the strange things that have come dribbling out of my mouth and the idiotic look that has been frozen to my face), I hope this will make up for it, or explain some things:</p>
<p>I love New Year&#8217;s Eve. That&#8217;s my favorite holiday&#8211; you don&#8217;t have to worry about gifts, you get to buy a new frock, get a little glitzed up,  and rock out with friends and have a bright and shiny time. The New Year brings hope and promise and fresh new start to a stale existence. Someone likened this to When Harry Met Sally (<em>which has always been my favorite film&#8211; I definitely need to get that on DVD</em>). I told him that that scared me. The first thing that flashed into my mind was the scene where Sally is overcome with desperation when she learns that her ex is getting married, and she doesn&#8217;t know where she went wrong in her life. The other part I saw was Harry alone on New Year&#8217;s, reassessing his life. But of course, he rushes to Sally and tells her that the moment you realize you want to spend the rest of your life with somebody, you want that moment to be now. One thing leads to another and happy ending. </p>
<p>I am nowhere near that. There is no chance or even prospect of that happening. I&#8217;m somewhere between Sally&#8217;s panicked lament, &#8220;and I&#8217;m going to be 40!!!&#8221; and the bewildered, alone on New Year&#8217;s Harry. My life plays out like a movie until the happy ending&#8211; just a series of comedic, pathetic mishaps to NO end. </p>
<p>I&#8217;m flying home again for Christmas this year. This year will be different. I will spending a few days with my parents, at their house. I called my mom and asked her if I&#8217;ll be sleeping on the floor again. She said yes, but I can bring my air mattress with me (like that doesn&#8217;t weigh 40 pounds and folds up into a 26&#8243; suitcase). Because, you know, having more than one bed in a 5-bedroom house is a ridiculous concept, and keeping my old room totally void of any furniture is not weird, it&#8217;s just &#8220;minimalist.&#8221; </p>
<p>I&#8217;m leaving the Friday after; I could have stayed til New Year&#8217;s Day, but spending NYE with my parents, who will most likely go to bed well before the ball drops, is only slightly more depressing than passing out on my own couch alone, away from my hometown friends who are all coupled up, or have young kids, or will be somewhere more exciting. </p>
<p>At this point, I&#8217;m just carrying on, hoping that one day there will be an out, an open door to something bigger and more promising. This year went completely awry&#8211; I was supposed to move to Boston with my boyfriend, have an awesome job, make new friends, save a little money. Instead, my boss rescinded her offer to transfer me, my boyfriend broke up with me (<em>rather unceremoniously, too&#8211; 4 1/2 years warrants a face-to-face conversation, or at least a phone call&#8211; not a cowardly text message, &#8220;I&#8217;ve reassessed my life and you&#8217;re not in it. By the way, I&#8217;m moving to Boston in the spring to open our new location and i&#8217;ve been offered an obscenely high salary. Good luck, bitch!&#8221;</em>), I have no idea where everyone is, and I&#8217;ve been undergoing way too much retail therapy, so I have no idea where my money is either. </p>
<p>So, 2012: please collect your belongings, 2013 is en route and there&#8217;s no room for your crap.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/101/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/101/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=101&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://ohtomeohmy.wordpress.com/2012/12/09/like-an-airport-luggage-carousel/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>32</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/38906c4455c9c8857e931e6d012960d7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cleveport</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Latkes and Compromise: The Secret to a Happy Marriage</title>
		<link>http://saltandserenity.com/2012/12/06/latkes-and-compromise-the-secret-to-a-happy-marriage/</link>
		<comments>http://saltandserenity.com/2012/12/06/latkes-and-compromise-the-secret-to-a-happy-marriage/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2012 03:24:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>saltandserenity</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Potatoes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[compromise in marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hanukkah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jewish Holiday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Potato Latkes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Potato pancake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[potatoes]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://saltandserenity.com/?p=7600</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Several weeks ago I was asked if I would appear on a local cable TV show and demonstrate how to make &#8220;low-fat &#8221; latkes. This disturbed me greatly and I quickly responded that unfortunately I do not believe in low fat latkes. I think latkes are meant to be eaten only once a year, the [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=7600&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://saltandserenity.com/2012/12/06/latkes-and-compromise-the-secret-to-a-happy-marriage/with-sour-cream-and-applesauce-1/" rel="attachment wp-att-7621"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-7621" alt="with sour cream and applesauce 1" src="http://saltandserenity.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/with-sour-cream-and-applesauce-1.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>Several weeks ago I was asked if I would appear on a local cable TV show and demonstrate how to make &#8220;<em>low-fat</em> &#8221; latkes. This disturbed me greatly and I quickly responded that unfortunately I do not believe in low fat latkes. I think latkes are meant to be eaten only once a year, the real way. (fried in oil!) A once a year indulgence really celebrates and honours Chanukah the way it was intended. She responded &#8220;OK – You’ve convinced me!  You make a good point.  I was thinking of the healthy diets people are seeking.  But you’re right that maybe the normal latkes represent what Chanukah is about.  So let’s go ahead.&#8221; Unfortunately, the timing of the taping coincided with when I was going to be out-of-town, so we shelved the idea for next year.</p>
<p>This Saturday (December 8) marks the first night of Chanukah. In the second Century, the Holy Land was ruled by Syrian Greeks. King Antiochus IV was in control of the region. Under his rule, Jews were severely oppressed and not allowed to practice their religion openly. Against all odds, a small band of faithful Jews defeated one of the mightiest armies on earth, drove the Greeks from the land, reclaimed the Holy Temple in Jerusalem and rededicated it. When they sought to light the Temple&#8217;s menorah they found only a single vial of olive oil that had escaped contamination by the Greeks. Miraculously<b>,</b> the one-day supply burned for eight days. And hence, the reason for the tradition of eating foods fried in oil during Chanukah.</p>
<p>Every year I see recipes for all kinds of variations on the traditional latke. Several years ago  Bon Appetit magazine promised a “Gorgeous Chanukah Feast” featuring both cumin scented beet latkes and gingered carrot latkes.   While at first glance they seem intriguing, I could not actually see myself preparing either of these or any of the other interesting variations I have read about.  In the first place my family would revolt.  In the second place, I only make latkes once a year and I crave the traditional potato variety from my childhood.  I suspect that many of your families are similar to mine and sweet potato-parsnip latkes would not be met with cheers of joy.</p>
<p>My mother has an incredible sense of smell.  In our family, we joke that she can smell foul odours a day before they actually occur.  My childhood memories are filled with her going from room to room, sniffing and muttering, “What’s that smell?”  One of her least favorite smells was that of food cooked in oil.  She claimed that she could smell the oil for weeks afterwards.  Now I must be honest here and admit that I inherited my father’s sense of smell – that is to say that his lack of sense of smell.  He had sinus problems and his nose malfunctioned often.</p>
<p>That being said, once a year, on Chanukah, we had latkes. My mom’s latkes are fantastic.  They are lacy shreds of potatoes, fried until crisp.  The lingering smell of frying oil was quickly chased away by my mother’s secret blend of cleaning agents, a potent, lethal combination of Joy and Ajax.  Do not try this at home unless you are wearing a gas mask.</p>
<p>The first time my husband took me home to meet his family (we were not married yet, we had only been dating for about 3 months) was during Chanukah. His mom made latkes.  They were thick and creamy, not the thin lacy crispy shredded latkes that I grew up with.  After we were married we had our families over for a Chanukah party.  Of course, we could not agree on which kind of latkes to make, so we ended up making both.  The guests were starving by the time the latkes actually appeared at the table so both kinds were gobbled up very quickly.  Not being able to resolve which type were superior, I created a compromise recipe.  These latkes are thin and crispy around the edges, but still creamy in the centre.</p>
<p>Russet potatoes are my choice for the best latkes.</p>
<p><a href="http://saltandserenity.com/2012/12/06/latkes-and-compromise-the-secret-to-a-happy-marriage/potatoes-peeled/" rel="attachment wp-att-7620"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-7620" alt="potatoes peeled" src="http://saltandserenity.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/potatoes-peeled.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>A Cuisinart makes fast work of the shredding.</p>
<p><a href="http://saltandserenity.com/2012/12/06/latkes-and-compromise-the-secret-to-a-happy-marriage/cuisinart-2/" rel="attachment wp-att-7611"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-7611" alt="cuisinart" src="http://saltandserenity.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/cuisinart.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>Half the shredded potatoes are set aside and the other half go back in the Cuisinart with an onion to be coarsely chopped with the steel blade.</p>
<p><a href="http://saltandserenity.com/2012/12/06/latkes-and-compromise-the-secret-to-a-happy-marriage/onions-and-potatoes-in-cuisinart/" rel="attachment wp-att-7617"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-7617" alt="onions and potatoes in cuisinart" src="http://saltandserenity.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/onions-and-potatoes-in-cuisinart.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://saltandserenity.com/2012/12/06/latkes-and-compromise-the-secret-to-a-happy-marriage/onions-and-potatoes-processed/" rel="attachment wp-att-7618"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-7618" alt="onions and potatoes processed" src="http://saltandserenity.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/onions-and-potatoes-processed.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>The shredded and grated potatoes and onions get wrapped in cheesecloth and then you squeeze the heck out of them. Let the liquid sit for a few minutes. Drain off the liquid but keep the potato starch. This is the secret to latkes that do not fall apart while cooking.</p>
<p><a href="http://saltandserenity.com/2012/12/06/latkes-and-compromise-the-secret-to-a-happy-marriage/cheesecloth/" rel="attachment wp-att-7610"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-7610" alt="cheesecloth" src="http://saltandserenity.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/cheesecloth.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://saltandserenity.com/2012/12/06/latkes-and-compromise-the-secret-to-a-happy-marriage/potato-liquid-and-starch/" rel="attachment wp-att-7619"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-7619" alt="potato liquid and starch" src="http://saltandserenity.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/potato-liquid-and-starch.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>Add a beaten egg, some kosher salt and about 2 tablespoons of matzoh meal or panko bread crumbs.</p>
<p><a href="http://saltandserenity.com/2012/12/06/latkes-and-compromise-the-secret-to-a-happy-marriage/egg-and-matzoh-meal/" rel="attachment wp-att-7612"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-7612" alt="egg and matzoh meal" src="http://saltandserenity.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/egg-and-matzoh-meal.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>I like to fry my latkes in vegetable oil in a cast iron skillet. A heavy-duty non-stick pan will work if you do not have cast iron. A slotted serving spoon makes it easy to get the latke mixture into the pan.</p>
<p><a href="http://saltandserenity.com/2012/12/06/latkes-and-compromise-the-secret-to-a-happy-marriage/frying-1a/" rel="attachment wp-att-7614"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-7614" alt="frying 1a" src="http://saltandserenity.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/frying-1a.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://saltandserenity.com/2012/12/06/latkes-and-compromise-the-secret-to-a-happy-marriage/frying-3/" rel="attachment wp-att-7616"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-7616" alt="frying 3" src="http://saltandserenity.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/frying-3.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>I made some applesauce to go with the latkes. No recipe here. I used a combination of Granny Smith, Honey Crisp and Golden delicious apples. I quartered the apples. No need to peel or seed if you have a food mill. I added about 1/2 a cup of   water to the pot, covered it with a lid and cooked it on medium heat for about 10 minutes until soft. Then I put the whole mess through the food mill, which does a great job of filtering out the peel and seeds.</p>
<p><a href="http://saltandserenity.com/2012/12/06/latkes-and-compromise-the-secret-to-a-happy-marriage/apples-3/" rel="attachment wp-att-7609"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-7609" alt="apples" src="http://saltandserenity.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/apples.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://saltandserenity.com/2012/12/06/latkes-and-compromise-the-secret-to-a-happy-marriage/apples-in-pot/" rel="attachment wp-att-7608"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-7608" alt="apples in pot" src="http://saltandserenity.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/apples-in-pot.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://saltandserenity.com/2012/12/06/latkes-and-compromise-the-secret-to-a-happy-marriage/apples-in-food-mill/" rel="attachment wp-att-7631"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-7631" alt="apples in food mill" src="http://saltandserenity.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/apples-in-food-mill.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<h2>Click here to print recipe for <a href="http://saltandserenity.com/2012/12/06/latkes-and-compromise-the-secret-to-a-happy-marriage/compromise-latkes-recipe-2/" rel="attachment wp-att-7625">Compromise Latkes </a>.</h2>
<p><a href="http://saltandserenity.com/2012/12/06/latkes-and-compromise-the-secret-to-a-happy-marriage/with-sour-cream-and-applesauce-1/" rel="attachment wp-att-7621"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-7621" alt="with sour cream and applesauce 1" src="http://saltandserenity.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/with-sour-cream-and-applesauce-1.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/7600/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/7600/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=7600&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://saltandserenity.com/2012/12/06/latkes-and-compromise-the-secret-to-a-happy-marriage/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>51</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/da4e616454164f66d6799d001db3d517?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">saltandserenity</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://saltandserenity.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/with-sour-cream-and-applesauce-1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">with sour cream and applesauce 1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://saltandserenity.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/potatoes-peeled.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">potatoes peeled</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://saltandserenity.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/cuisinart.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cuisinart</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://saltandserenity.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/onions-and-potatoes-in-cuisinart.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">onions and potatoes in cuisinart</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://saltandserenity.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/onions-and-potatoes-processed.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">onions and potatoes processed</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://saltandserenity.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/cheesecloth.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cheesecloth</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://saltandserenity.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/potato-liquid-and-starch.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">potato liquid and starch</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://saltandserenity.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/egg-and-matzoh-meal.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">egg and matzoh meal</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://saltandserenity.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/frying-1a.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">frying 1a</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://saltandserenity.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/frying-3.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">frying 3</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://saltandserenity.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/apples.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">apples</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://saltandserenity.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/apples-in-pot.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">apples in pot</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://saltandserenity.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/apples-in-food-mill.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">apples in food mill</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://saltandserenity.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/with-sour-cream-and-applesauce-1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">with sour cream and applesauce 1</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
