<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2013 20:02:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Bad Coffee Makes Me Sad</title>
		<link>http://ajviola.wordpress.com/2013/01/31/bad-coffee-makes-me-sad/</link>
		<comments>http://ajviola.wordpress.com/2013/01/31/bad-coffee-makes-me-sad/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 18:19:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>ajviola</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[coffee]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ajviola.wordpress.com/?p=196</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s no secret that I love coffee. Over the past couple of years my relationship with coffee has gone to a whole new level. We used to be just friends who would meet every once in a while and only when I was really tired. Also, I never really let coffee be itself around me. [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=196&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s no secret that I love coffee. Over the past couple of years my relationship with coffee has gone to a whole new level. We used to be just friends who would meet every once in a while and only when I was really tired. Also, I never really let coffee be itself around me. I always forced it to take on different appearances and flavors. I never allowed it to be who it really was. It was a very selfish relationship.</p>
<p>Things have changed now. I&#8217;ve repented of my ways and really feel like coffee and I have gotten to a level of our relationship that we can both be proud of.</p>
<p>Coffee represents something much stronger to me than flavor.</p>
<p>Even now as I write this I&#8217;m staring a 5lb bag of coffee that the coffee club I helped start (<a href="http://raleighcoffeeclub.com/" target="_blank">Raleigh Coffee Club</a>) purchased for an organization that works with the homeless and at-risk population here in Raleigh (<a href="http://lovewins.info/" target="_blank">Love Wins</a>). That&#8217;s the sort of thing coffee represents for me. Something much greater than a hot cup of black liquid.</p>
<p>It represents community. It represents hard work. It represents friendships. It represents love.</p>
<p>Every time I brew coffee at home, which takes me longer than most people, I&#8217;m not just trying to get caffeine in me&#8230;I&#8217;m participating in an act that not only supports people I care about, but supports employees and farmers I&#8217;ve never met, but because they are human I care about them.</p>
<p>It represents to local roasters that I&#8217;ve created such good friendships with. It represents the passion they have for their product.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s why bad coffee makes me sad.</p>
<p>Because I know how good it can be. And I don&#8217;t mean bad just on the basis of flavor and taste, which I&#8217;ve had my fair share of, but also bad in the sense of where it comes from and how the workers are treated where it&#8217;s roasted and farmed. When you drink &#8220;bad&#8221; coffee you are supporting that.</p>
<p>And I say without shame, what you buy, eat, drink and do shows what you support.</p>
<p>You can&#8217;t say you care about people and serve bad coffee. And again, I don&#8217;t just mean by flavor, because that is incredibly subjective&#8230;but having coffee that tastes good isn&#8217;t a bad idea either.</p>
<p>Don&#8217;t take this as a guilt trip, because I, by no means, buy every single thing that supports the right things&#8230;but I am making an effort.</p>
<p>Drink good coffee. Good tasting. Good supporting. Good.</p>
<p><a href="http://ajviola.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/20130131-213954.jpg"><img src="http://ajviola.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/20130131-213954.jpg?w=720" alt="20130131-213954.jpg" class="alignnone size-full" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/196/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/196/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=196&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://ajviola.wordpress.com/2013/01/31/bad-coffee-makes-me-sad/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>21</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c388f816d99175c83c9c980cb9ede326?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ajviola</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ajviola.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/20130131-213954.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">20130131-213954.jpg</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>First Rains: To Quench</title>
		<link>http://africafarandwide.wordpress.com/2013/01/29/first-rains-to-quench/</link>
		<comments>http://africafarandwide.wordpress.com/2013/01/29/first-rains-to-quench/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 20:29:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Africa far and wide</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Beira]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mozambique]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[african]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Expat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Floods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fotografia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lightning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photo essay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Storm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[volunteer]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://africafarandwide.wordpress.com/?p=738</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The rainy season has arrived in Mozambique. After a drought-stricken couple of years, I can almost hear the sigh of relief as plants, animals and people are soaked to the core with torrential rain. The excitement that comes with the first rains is almost contagious. The bull frogs start emerging from deep under, children enjoy [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=738&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://africafarandwide.wordpress.com/2013/01/29/first-rains-to-quench/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>20</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://africafarandwide.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/excitement.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://africafarandwide.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/excitement.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Excitement</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/9d942d5f591cb272290d76986e4bf953?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">africafarandwide</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://africafarandwide.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/storm-over-cane.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Storm over Cane</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://africafarandwide.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/hard-rain.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Hard Rain</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://africafarandwide.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/snail-explosion-copy.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Snail Explosion copy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://africafarandwide.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/water-lily-copy.jpg?w=112" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Water lily copy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://africafarandwide.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/paddy-baby-copy.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Paddy baby copy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://africafarandwide.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/netting-in-the-rain-copy.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Netting in the rain copy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://africafarandwide.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/rain-on-the-railway.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Rain on the Railway</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://africafarandwide.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the-railway-cane-cutter.jpg?w=112" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The Railway Cane cutter</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://africafarandwide.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/wet-bread.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Wet Bread</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://africafarandwide.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/men-at-work.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Men at work</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://africafarandwide.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/make-do-raincoat.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Make-do Raincoat</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://africafarandwide.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/first-rains.jpg?w=106" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">First rains</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://africafarandwide.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/bucket-shelter.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Bucket Shelter</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>“Why I’m Rooting for the 49ers,” or “The Shot Heard Round My Backyard”</title>
		<link>http://fatpastor.me/2013/01/31/why-im-rooting-for-the-49ers-or-the-shot-heard-round-my-backyard/</link>
		<comments>http://fatpastor.me/2013/01/31/why-im-rooting-for-the-49ers-or-the-shot-heard-round-my-backyard/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 20:21:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>The Fat Pastor</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Personal Reflection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[basketball]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brothers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[football]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Harbaugh]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Superbowl]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fatpastor.me/?p=3089</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Jim Harbaugh is the head coach of the San Francisco 49ers.  This Sunday Jim is leading his team into the Superbowl, and on the opposing sidelines will be his oldest rival, his big brother John.  Jim and John Harbaugh have justifiably received a lot of attention these last two weeks.  The Harbaugh brothers have reached [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3089&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_3092" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 192px"><a href="http://fatpastor.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/harbaughs.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-3092 " alt="John Harbaugh is the coach of the Baltimore Ravens.  His younger brother Jim is the coach of the San Francisco 49ers" src="http://fatpastor.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/harbaughs.jpg?w=720"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">John Harbaugh is the coach of the Baltimore Ravens. His younger brother Jim is the coach of the San Francisco 49ers</p></div>
<p>Jim Harbaugh is the head coach of the San Francisco 49ers.  This Sunday Jim is leading his team into the Superbowl, and on the opposing sidelines will be his oldest rival, his big brother John.  Jim and John Harbaugh have justifiably received a lot of attention these last two weeks.  The Harbaugh brothers have reached the pinnacle of the football world.  On Sunday they will share the biggest stage in the world.  Not too long ago, they shared a bedroom.</p>
<p>Jim and John Harbaugh were born 15 months apart.  They were fierce competitors growing up.  Gifted with more natural talent, Jim went farther as an athlete.  He was one game away from playing in the Superbowl as the quarterback of the Indianapolis Colts.  Yet here they are, meeting as head coaches at the top of their career.</p>
<p>There are other famous pairs of siblings in the sports world.  Peyton and Eli Manning, and Serena and Venus Williams are two pairs that have made some headlines.  In most of these matchups, I tend to root for the younger sibling.  I root for the little brother because I know how that feels.</p>
<div id="attachment_3091" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 266px"><a href="http://fatpastor.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/figure-four.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-3091 " alt="My brother got pretty good at the Figure Four Leg Lock. " src="http://fatpastor.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/figure-four.jpg?w=720"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">This not my brother and me, but anyone that thinks wresting is fake has never been trapped in a figure four leg lock. This happens to be Ric Flair on the right, playing my brother, and I believe Steve Austin on the left, playing me.</p></div>
<p><strong>My brother and I were born almost six years apart, so we weren’t exactly rivals.</strong>  My younger years were spent in perpetual servitude and resentment.  Yet at the same time, my older brother was always there.  He was someone for me to look up to and emulate.  He showed me how to swing a bat and a golf club.  He taught me how to put together a hot wheels racing tournament with my cars.  He taught me how to build lego cars, card houses, and do card tricks. He was even willing to demonstrate on me how to do a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DDT_(professional_wrestling)" target="_blank">D.D.T</a>, a Figure-four Leg Lock (pictured), and a <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bBL89_n4lCc" target="_blank">Camel Clutch</a>.  In time, he became my best friend, and we stood next to each other at each of our weddings.  There was no thought to asking anyone else to be there for me in that moment.</p>
<p>My big brother was always there.  Sometimes he made me angry enough to cry or scream or attack with a ferocity I didn’t know I had.  One time he tickled me until I puked.   Most of the time he was teaching me something.  And he taught me so much, the important stuff and trivial stuff.  He taught me about girls and sarcasm and sports, and life.  He taught me to like chocolate and peanut butter ice cream, and the Macho Man, and Seinfeld.  My big brother is the smartest person I know, and there are few people with whom I laugh more.  He still teaches me stuff.  I still look up to him, even though he stopped being my “big brother” by the time I was about 15 years old.</p>
<p><strong>That’s why I usually cheer for Eli and Serena, and why I’ll probably be cheering for Jim</strong> (although he is kind of a lunatic, and I think I’d rather play for John).  I know a little of what Jim will feel when he looks across the field and sees John: pure love, admiration, and respect; and a desire to beat him that is pure and burns white-hot.</p>
<p>I didn’t beat my brother much growing up.  He was bigger than me, stronger than me, faster than me, and smarter than me.  It wasn’t until I was about 15 or 16 when some of those things started to change.  My brother and I had some epic basketball games over the years.  Some were Nerf games, where he had to play on his knees and there were no holds barred.  Some were on our back patio, where the flowers were out of bounds, the crack was the three-point line, and you had to take the ball back to the grill.</p>
<p><strong>The summer after I graduated high school was our last summer together</strong>.  That fall, he started his second year of medical school,  and I went off to college.  We played a lot of basketball games that summer.  One-on-one, to 30, winner’s outs, win by two.  There were a series of intense games.  I discovered I had a distinct advantage inside.  He was still quicker than me and a better all-around athlete.  All were close, but he won them all.  He had a winning streak that dated back to the early 1980s.  It was the kind of streak that the Harlem Globetrotters could envy.  Finally, The Streak ended.  It was an intense game.  We were well into the 30s, going back and forth.</p>
<p>Michael Jordan’s last shot with the Bulls is one of those plays that is ingrained into the collective memory of thousands of basketball fans.  I can still see it as vividly today as I did when he hit it to beat the Jazz for his sixth World Championship.  Jordan’s shot, and that memory, have the distinct advantage of having been shown over and over for years.</p>
<span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='640' height='390' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/PRCTp57LQro?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span>
<p>The Shot was not recorded.  The only spectator was my Mom watching from the kitchen window.  Yet it was ingrained into my mind as clearly as any of my sports memories.  I have watched my teams win World Championships.  I jumped out of my skin as the Illini came back against Arizona.  I wept openly when the Paul Konerko clutched the last out of the 2005 World Series, and I still get goosebumps when I recall the Phillies beating the Devil Rays.</p>
<p>None of these moments are as important to me as the time I drove to my left toward the baseline, backed in a little, then pivoted to face the hoop, and took a little jumper leaning away from the basket from about five feet, just in front of the rock garden in the corner, and I beat my big brother.  <strong>It was, at the time, the greatest moment of my life</strong>.</p>
<p>Covered in sweat, drained, and tired, I simply pumped my fist.  We went inside.  Mom asked us, “Who won?”  I don’t think either of us answered with words.  We didn’t have to.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3089/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3089/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3089&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://fatpastor.me/2013/01/31/why-im-rooting-for-the-49ers-or-the-shot-heard-round-my-backyard/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/8b78752692fc59c90e983ddaa1415bfd?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F2.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The Fat Pastor</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://fatpastor.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/harbaughs.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">John Harbaugh is the coach of the Baltimore Ravens.  His younger brother Jim is the coach of the San Francisco 49ers</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://fatpastor.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/figure-four.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">My brother got pretty good at the Figure Four Leg Lock. </media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>I Don&#8217;t Miss Sleep Anymore</title>
		<link>http://livenowandzen.com/2013/01/30/sacrificing-sleep/</link>
		<comments>http://livenowandzen.com/2013/01/30/sacrificing-sleep/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 05:43:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>livenowandzen</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Being Present]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Boys]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Motherhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Perspective]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Peace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sleep habits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trust]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://livenowandzen.com/?p=4332</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The other night our double bedroom doors burst wide open at 1:03 a.m., startling both hubby and I awake. From the light in the hallway, I could make out that the perpetrator of our early morning wake up call was our youngest son, Luke. &#8220;What&#8217;s up, Luke?&#8221; I asked, although I already knew the answer [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4332&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_4334" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 235px"><a href="http://livenowandzen.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/p7130001.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-4334" alt="Safe haven " src="http://livenowandzen.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/p7130001.jpg?w=225&#038;h=300" width="225" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">My three men&#8230;all wiped out together</p></div>
<p>The other night our double bedroom doors burst wide open at 1:03 a.m., startling both hubby and I awake. From the light in the hallway, I could make out that the perpetrator of our early morning wake up call was our youngest son, Luke.</p>
<p>&#8220;What&#8217;s up, Luke?&#8221; I asked, although I already knew the answer to this question.</p>
<p>Luke is our &#8220;good&#8221; sleeper. While his brother tosses and turns in the top bunk, Luke slumbers peacefully. He sleeps in cars, on planes, and in restaurants. When he&#8217;s down for the count, you usually don&#8217;t have to worry about him again.</p>
<p>&#8220;I had a nightmare,&#8221; he replied as he quietly closed the door behind him with sudden politeness.</p>
<p>&#8220;Really? What about?&#8221; I said.</p>
<p>As he began to climb onto our bed, he started recalling a dream wherein he was being chased in Roblox, which is some new video game he and his brother have been playing. He sat on the end of our already cramped, queen-size bed telling us about snakes (like Indiana Jones, he hates snakes) and death. He was visibly unsettled. Often he will just tell us about his nightmares, and then head back to his room. Sometimes, though, he needs real comfort. I could tell this was one of those times. Finished with his story, he finally crawled toward the top of the bed, pulled back the covers between me and hubby, and began to insinuate himself between us.</p>
<p>&#8220;So&#8230;sorry about this, guys,&#8221; he told us as he nestled in and began to settle down to get some more sleep.</p>
<p>When Luke was small, we experienced periods during which the only way he would fall asleep was in our bed. He slept in a bassinet in our room until he was four months old. He slept with us again off and on from 9 months to roughly 14 months. Sometimes he would fall asleep in our bed and we would transfer him. Sometimes we were so tired he ended up staying with us all night. When we would tell other people about Luke&#8217;s sleeping habits, most would cluck their tongues and tell us what a mistake we were making. We brushed it off.</p>
<p>In the house I grew up in, we were not allowed to sleep in my parents&#8217; room. Ever. It simply was not done. My parents gave us our own rooms, and they expected us to be in them. End of story. When we had our children, I assumed that our kids would have the same experience that I did. But, our kids are not like my sisters and me. Our kids have vivid imaginations and stressful dreams. Joe sleepwalks. Luke, if aroused from sleep by an unexpected noise, is often unable to calm down enough to go back to sleep. We do what we can to get sleep when we can, and sometimes that only occurs when we let the boys sleep in our room. It is what it is. We have made our peace with it.</p>
<p>I flipped around as Luke was in our bed the other night, unable to go back to sleep. I could not get comfortable because what was once 20 pounds is now 55 pounds and takes up a lot more room. I was about to resign myself to taking Luke&#8217;s place in his bed while letting him rest peacefully with his dad when, out of nowhere, the announcement came.</p>
<p>&#8220;I think I&#8217;ll go back to my own bed now,&#8221; he said, grabbing his stuffed animal and climbing carefully over his father and out of the bed.</p>
<p>I walked with him down the hall and tucked him back into his bunk bed underneath his sleeping brother to make sure he was truly ready to settle down. He pulled his stuffed Husky dog, Shasta, towards him, curled into a little ball on his side, and closed his eyes. He was calm, and I knew I would not be seeing him again until the morning.<br />
I&#8217;ve thought a lot about the way we &#8220;spoil&#8221; our kids by letting them do things like sleep in our room on occasion. Truth is that I don&#8217;t feel the slightest bit of remorse about it. I don&#8217;t think it&#8217;s undermined their confidence or made them any less capable of handling their fears. Instead, I think it&#8217;s allowed them to believe that when things get scary, they can turn to us. When they feel confident and relaxed, they always move forward without us. Sure. We&#8217;ve definitely lost some sleep with restless boys in our bed or on an air mattress in our room, but I think the trade off of knowing that they know they can count on us is worth it. Besides, these days are numbered. Someday they will be out of the house, and I will miss hearing that door burst open in the middle of the night and knowing that they need me. I&#8217;ll catch up on my sleep then.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4332/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4332/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4332&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://livenowandzen.com/2013/01/30/sacrificing-sleep/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>39</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/91d794e2e5ebdd3184e9b4b1e49af688?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">livenowandzen</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://livenowandzen.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/p7130001.jpg?w=225" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Safe haven </media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Godfather: Retro Reviews</title>
		<link>http://imthemadman.wordpress.com/2013/01/30/the-godfather-retro-reviews/</link>
		<comments>http://imthemadman.wordpress.com/2013/01/30/the-godfather-retro-reviews/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2013 16:55:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>imthemadman</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Film Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[On a More Serious Note]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews and Critiques]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Serious Film Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Funny]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Serious]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[al pacino]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[francis ford coppola]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gangsters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mario puzo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marlon brando]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the godfather]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://imthemadman.wordpress.com/?p=542</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I truly can’t do The Godfather justice in a mere thousand words.  And, unfortunately, many have already written volumes analyzing and exploring this divine document.  But as someone extremely fussy and picky about film quality, and someone attempting to better educate themselves about the history of cinema, I feel I’m doing an injustice not to [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=542&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://imthemadman.wordpress.com/2013/01/30/the-godfather-retro-reviews/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>21</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/489b7a68344224e744966e8d9baaae85?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=X" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">imthemadman</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://g-ecx.images-amazon.com/images/G/01/DVD/Paramount/detailpages/TheGodfather/GdfthrColl_Still_H2_L.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">the godfather al pacino crime sitting in chair </media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://i2.listal.com/image/3508184/600full-the-godfather-screenshot.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">the godfather marlon brando al pacino old retired micheal don corleone</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mayor Ed Koch</title>
		<link>http://anafternoonwith.com/2013/02/01/mayor-ed-koch/</link>
		<comments>http://anafternoonwith.com/2013/02/01/mayor-ed-koch/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 17:42:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>AnAfternoonWith...</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[ALL FEATURES]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BRONX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BROOKLYN]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ICONS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[INTERIOR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MANHATTAN]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apartment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[deceased mayors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ed koch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ed koch home]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ed koch phone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edward koch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[headphones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interior]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[koch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leather seating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Manhattan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mayor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mayor ed koch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mayor's homes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mayor's life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nyc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nyc apartments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nyc homes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nyc mayor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photograph]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pictures of ed koch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[portrait]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rent stabilization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rent stabilize]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rent stable]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rent stablized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[story]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://anafternoonwith.com/?p=3848</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Growing up in New York City, the honorable Mayor Edward Irving Koch was a big part of my life. This is an afternoon I spent with him for House &#38; Garden back in the 90&#8242;s. I was just with him three weeks ago, and he was as funny and clever as ever. I&#8217;m sorry to [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3848&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://anafternoonwith.com/2013/02/01/mayor-ed-koch/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>22</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/8d548cd0990b438b3599fb7789a3a487?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F2.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">michaelmundy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://michaelmundy.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/mayor-ed-koch_p1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mayor Ed Koch photographed in his home in Manhattan, New York. Copyright Michael Mundy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://michaelmundy.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/mayor-ed-koch_p2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mayor Ed Koch&#039;s Living Room. Copyright Michael Mundy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://michaelmundy.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/mayor-ed-koch_p3.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mayor Ed Koch&#039;s Apartment. Copyright Michael Mundy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://michaelmundy.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/mayor-ed-koch_p5.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mayor Ed Koch&#039;s Dining Room. Copyright Michael Mundy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://michaelmundy.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/mayor-ed-koch_p4.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mayor Ed Koch&#039;s Bedroom. Copyright Michael Mundy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://michaelmundy.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/mayor-ed-koch_p6.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mayor Ed Koch Grilling Outside NYC. Copyright Michael Mundy</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Evidence from Evolution and Biology</title>
		<link>http://quantumveil.wordpress.com/2013/01/31/the-evidence-from-evolution-and-biology-part-1/</link>
		<comments>http://quantumveil.wordpress.com/2013/01/31/the-evidence-from-evolution-and-biology-part-1/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 14:03:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dennis Rice</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Biology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Metaphysics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Physics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quantum Physics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://quantumveil.wordpress.com/?p=87</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[My previous posts have focused on the evidence for a rational agent inherent in the laws of physics.  There has been an implicit assumption that the laws of physics are rigorously deterministic.  But clearly life is not deterministic, so it was necessary for me to point to some possible feature of the laws of physics [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=87&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>My previous posts have focused on the evidence for a rational agent inherent in the laws of physics.  There has been an implicit assumption that the laws of physics are rigorously deterministic.  But clearly life is not deterministic, so it was necessary for me to point to some possible feature of the laws of physics that allowed for the wild variation and unpredictability of life.  I will summarize my thought process as follows:</p>
<ol>
<li>The universe is ordered by deterministic laws and forces such as the force of gravity and electromagnetism.  There are also non-deterministic laws such as quantum theory.  One of the laws that combine both features is the law of increasing entropy.  Entropy always increases throughout the universe, but it is allowed to decrease locally.  Since quantum theory ultimately controls all interactions in the universe, all forces are non-deterministic at the quantum level.  (The only possible exception is gravitation which has not yet been unified with quantum theory.)</li>
<li>The deterministic laws (electromagnetism, etc.), by themselves, cannot account for life and consciousness.  There must be another factor in the fundamental laws of physics that allows living organism to lower entropy.  The process of lowering entropy is essential to life because it concentrates energy for future use and organizes the genome for transmission to future generations.</li>
<li>That factor in the laws of physics is the collapse of the wave function in quantum physics, also called decoherence.  Decoherence is absolutely necessary for any measurable energy transfer.  In decoherence, the universe actually chooses an outcome for every transfer of energy.  This choosing, or decisionality, on the part of the universe is what I have called rational agency and it is responsible for the forward direction of time.</li>
<li>This decisionality on the part of the universe is always mixed up with randomness because we are prohibited from knowing precisely all the states of matter, particularly the states of entanglement between particles.  This is a consequence of a kind of cosmic censorship hypothesis.  The Heisenberg uncertainty principle is one such limitation on our knowledge.</li>
<li>There can be no ordering principle or lowering of entropy based on true randomness.  True randomness, by definition, is maximum entropy.  In all of physics the only candidate for non-random yet non-deterministic action is decoherence.</li>
<li>Therefore, this choice by the universe is directed choice.  It is a rational choosing based on the laws of physics and contains within it the possibility of lowering entropy.  It is the physical undergirding of all life and consciousness.  It is the physical action responsible for the forward direction of time.</li>
</ol>
<p>Essentially, I think that the laws of physics favor life or are conducive to life.  In general, nature prefers to disperse energy; therefore there must be physical explanations for how energy gets concentrated.  Just as there is an explanation for how nature concentrates energy for lightning, there must also be an explanation for how living organisms concentrate energy and lower entropy.   These six steps summarize my explanation.  In this series on evolution and biology, I will lay out the case for the laws of physics favoring life as opposed to the case for life adapting to the laws of physics.  Both dynamics occur, but only laws conducive to life can create life from inanimate matter.</p>
<p>I don’t consider this logic highly dependent on particular experimental results.  Scientific theories are always provisional; they can be superseded by better theories or more accurate results.  My reasoning is broadly based on the general properties of physical laws.  A portion of the laws are rigorously deterministic and use mathematics to make predictions about future events.  A portion of the laws of physics deals with the presence of uncertainty in the universe.  I fully expect the laws of physics to be revised and improved, but I don’t expect that these general characteristics will be much altered.  If string theory is proved true, that would not change my basic logic, but my perspective might need to accommodate rational agency operating in a multiverse scenario.   String Theory, for all its promise, does not yet make any testable predictions.</p>
<p>Along with the laws of physics, I view the theory of evolution as a valid scientific theory.  It is a theory based on the idea that all living organisms adapt to their specific environment and pass along adaptive traits through procreation.  Darwin’s concept of “natural selection” was devised in contradistinction to “artificial selection,” whereby human breeders selected the best mates in order to raise generations of specifically adapted animals.</p>
<p>Biology is a complex science.  For someone like me, who has spent a major part of his life focused on math and the physical sciences, the main shock of encountering biology is the sheer astronomical diversity of life.  Last year, I took one of the online courses offered from UC Berkeley.  It was the basic undergraduate course for biology majors and it was something I needed because my previous biology class must have been in high school.  It was just as well that I didn’t have very much previous instruction because so much has changed between then and now.  The sheer volume of information is astounding.  I found myself wondering how on earth does anyone organize this much data.  In fact, it took three teachers to cover the material.  One instructor had a background in molecular biology; one was a specialist in genetics and one was from a medical background.  I had the distinct feeling that complete mastery was beyond the capability of any one individual.  But, I am still learning and I do have some observations based on my perspective from the physical sciences.</p>
<p>One observation concerns the principle of emergence.  Emergence is the concept that complex living organisms are able to exhibit new properties and traits by virtue of their complexity and organization.  The example from the textbook for the UC Berkeley class is one that interests me:  “For example, although photosynthesis occurs in an intact chloroplast, it will not take place in a disorganized test-tube mixture of chlorophyll and other chloroplast molecules.  Photosynthesis requires a specific organization of these molecules in the chloroplast.”  The text is saying that photosynthesis is an emergent phenomenon.  That is fine.  That helps organize knowledge, but for someone who wants to know how things work, there is a further question:  How is it that the particular organization contributes to function?  What are the properties of the constituent parts that enable the composite function to emerge?  Too often, emergence is used simply as label for a new function that can’t be explained any further.  When that happens, it becomes a kind of false knowledge: a category without explanatory power.</p>
<p>To take another example, water is composed of two room-temperature gases: hydrogen and oxygen.  I suppose you could say the emergent property of water is its liquidity.  But, with water, one can trace its properties to the molecular properties of hydrogen and oxygen and the strong bond between them as well as the weak bond between water molecules.  These particular molecular properties can also be used to explain surface tension, freezing and boiling.  My expectation is that biology will someday be explained in terms of molecular dynamics.  That day is a long way into the future.</p>
<p>Biological scientists are answering these kinds of questions and it is painstaking work.  It is slow and tedious work to demonstrate how biological molecules work, but I suppose, that is the part of biology that mainly interests me.  I have two main areas of interest in the biological sciences.  One is photosynthesis because of its use of quantum coherence for efficient transmission of sunlight energy to the “reaction center” where chemical food production begins.  The other is the biological molecule tubulin.</p>
<p>Tubulin is a protein molecule that assembles into microtubules.  Microtubules are long, narrow, hollow tubes that play an amazing variety of roles in living cells.  There is a natural tendency for microtubules to assemble themselves because of the positive and negative polarity on the tubulin molecule.  Once assembled, microtubules play key roles in biological cell functions.  They play an essential role during mitosis, cell division, by grabbing hold of the chromosomes and causing the genome to precisely separate toward opposite ends of the cell.  Microtubules are part of the cell’s cytoskeleton; they give shape and form to the cell.  In plants, microtubules guide the alignment of cellulose and direct plant growth at the cellular level.</p>
<p>Microtubules form the infrastructure that transports molecules from outside the cell to the inside and <i>vice versa</i>.  Motor proteins “walk” vesicles containing molecules back and forth along microtubules to their destination.  For example, pancreas cells that make insulin transport the insulin from inside the cell to the outside by this method.   In addition, microtubules are used for cell interaction with its environment.  They form some types of flagella and cilia for locomotion of the cell or movement of particles in the cell’s environment.  For example, the human sperm cell is propelled by action of a flagella made up of microtubules.</p>
<p>In short, microtubules are a very versatile cellular component.  Furthermore, they are an essential part of nerve cells.  Tubulin, the protein that forms microtubules, has a very high density in brain tissue.  That has led some researchers to project a key role in brain activity and consciousness for microtubules.  Microtubules are long, hollow, round tubes that might be ideal for quantum coherence.  There has been some research along these lines.</p>
<p>Tubulin is the protein building block of microtubules and it or similar proteins are probably very ancient, perhaps going back to the beginning of life.  One source specified that all cells had such proteins, except blue-green algae also known as cyanobacteria.  However, cyanobacteria have a tubulin-like molecule (a homologue) called “Ftsz.”  An interesting connection between my two main interests is that the cyanobacteria use photosynthesis for energy harvesting from sunlight.  It is the light harvesting complex from cyanobacteria that are used in the experiments testing quantum coherence.</p>
<p>Cyanobacteria are among the oldest life forms on Earth, perhaps as old as 3.5 billion years.  It would be a very interesting development if microtubules or microtubule-like structures go back to the beginning of life and if it can be demonstrated that quantum coherence played a key role in efficient energy transmission in these structures.  Those are two very big “ifs” and most researchers are very cautious about any evidence pointing towards quantum coherence in biological molecules.  But I remember some fairly incautious statements about the beginning of life from many years ago.</p>
<p>I think it was probably in high school chemistry class that the teacher, one day, covered the Miller-Urey experiment.  This experiment was conducted in 1952 and involved sending a spark of electricity (to simulate lightning) through a mix of chemicals assumed to represent Earth’s primitive atmosphere.  The result was a mixture of amino acids and sugars, both essential building block of life.  Stanley Miller and Harold Urey had demonstrated that organic compounds necessary for life could be easily formed from reasonable atmospheric compounds, such as water, methane, ammonia and hydrogen.  Not only that, but the teacher thought that we would soon be able to synthesize life in the test tube.  Well, that was over 50 years ago and the synthesis of life seems as elusive as ever.  Science doesn’t yet know what makes biochemicals spring to life.</p>
<p>The mystery of the beginning of life notwithstanding, the theory evolution brought incredible organizing power to the huge diversity of biology.  Darwin’s “natural selection” brought explanatory power to the huge diversity of species on Earth.  In the mid-twentieth century, the discovery of DNA and the genetic code brought into the evolutionary system a mechanism for adaptation.  This has led to what has been called the “central dogma” of molecular biology:  DNA makes RNA which makes proteins.  DNA contains coded information that is used to create a coded sequence of RNA which is used to create a sequence of amino acids which make up proteins.   The next step, which isn’t explicitly stated and is poorly understood, is that proteins must fold into a specific three dimensional form in order to be useful.   What is startling to me, coming from a computer programming background, is that the coded sequence of DNA contains just four characters representing four small molecules: A (adenine), C (cytosine), G (guanine) and T (thymine).</p>
<p>These four codes are interpreted in groups of three which gives 64 possible “words” for amino acids in the genetic code (4 X 4 X 4).  Of the 64 possible combinations of DNA code only 20 are actually needed, because there are only 20 amino acids that are needed to make all the known proteins.  Most of the 64 DNA sequences specify the same amino acid as another sequence, so there is built-in redundancy.  Only Tryptophan and Methionine rely on a single coded sequence; all the others have at least two sets of DNA codes and some (Serine, Leucine and Arginine) have six.  It seems possible to me that different evolutionary branches developed a reliance on different DNA sequences for the amino acids.  For someone with a data processing background, the DNA codes are reminiscent of a computer system that has been copied and modified to meet different objectives – even to the extent that duplicate codes are mainly sequential (e.g., Leucine: TTA, TTG, CTT, CTC, CTA, CTG).  From a “systems design” perspective it would seem that at one time there was provision for expansion with 64 codes for all 20 amino acids, but after evolutionary modifications all 64 codes are now in use.  I suppose that if there developed a need for a 21st amino acid, one of the existing redundant codes would be used.  The whole process is very complex, but the same basic DNA, RNA and amino acids are found in all life forms on Earth.  This amazing discovery of the genetic code is universal to life as we know it.  (There are some exceptions.  The <i>Paramecium</i> uses the “stop” codons, UAG and UAA, to code for Glutamate.)</p>
<p>“Natural selection” coupled with the genetic code has given enormous explanatory power to evolutionary biology.  But like all theories, it is a conceptual model of the physical processes that occur.  There remain many questions such as how did life begin.  And then there’s the question asked by Stephen Hawking, “What is it that breathes fire into the equations and makes a universe for them to govern?”  What is it that actually makes the world act in a way that is consistent with the conceptual model?  Readers of my previous posts will suspect that my answer is similar to what I’ve written before: there is a decisional power at work in the universe that breathes life into biological molecules.  It is this decisionality that insures that time flows forward and therefore gives evolution direction.</p>
<p>Some of the evidence for my answer resides in the evidence for directionality in evolution.  But, first of all, the evolutionary model is a rational model.  Even more amazing is that the implementation of the genetic code is an abstract, rational system!  Who would have thought that nature would have arrived at the very rational system of using a three character code to specify a sequence based on 20 amino acids that comprise the proteins for all life?   Let me be direct: The genetic code <i>is</i> information.  The central dogma of molecular biology <i>is</i> an information processing system.  The end results are proteins and decisional governance of the cell. This is exactly the type of system one might expect from a rational agent acting through nature.</p>
<p>As to directionality, the immediate form of the evidence is in the form of the adaptability of evolutionary change.  Evolutionary change produces living organisms that get better at adapting to their environment.  Not only are more advanced organisms better adapted, but they are better at adapting!  For higher life forms like mammals and particularly humans, this implies a higher consciousness.  Therefore, the longer range implication of evolution is higher consciousness.  I think this trend is evident from the archeological and historical record.  For almost 4 billion years, life has survived under the constant threat of a cosmic catastrophe such as the one that brought an end to the dinosaurs.  Today, we are beginning to track the asteroids and comets that have the potential to cause another life-ending cataclysm.  That would not be possible without some sort of advanced consciousness.  In a strange sort of self-reflection, adaptation has become adaptability for which is needed a higher consciousness.  This implies a robust moral development as well, but that is beyond what I can cover in these posts on science and reason.</p>
<p>But a rational agent is not the only explanation.  The alternative view is that evolution is the byproduct of random mutation.  First of all, I don’t think randomness is a good scientific answer.  Science succeeds when it finds and explains rational patterns.  To say that a process is random is to admit defeat from a scientific point of view.  The second thing I would say is that when someone refers to random mutation, it is unclear what type of randomness they are referring to: lack of knowledge randomness or the genuine non-determinism of quantum physics.  The common view of evolution is that it requires generations of offspring in order for nature to select the best attributes and pass those on to future generations.  Is evolution inherently random because some individuals show up at the wrong place at the wrong time or, alternatively, at the right place at the right time?  Is it random because a cosmic ray has altered the genome?  Is it random because we can’t predict how our children will turn out?  The most likely reason mutation might be random is because of a transcription or copying error.  But modern cells have evolved elaborate safeguards against such copying errors.</p>
<p>It turns out that when evolutionists speak of “random mutation,” they mean something specific.  My biology textbook (on Kindle!) only uses the phrase once in over 1000 pages of small font text, and that one occurrence refers to copies of genes that have lost functionality (i.e. the gene has been degraded) over time.  The textbook does not refer to new functionality as “random mutation,” but does use the phrase, “accidents during meiosis” (cell division in reproductive cells).  This phrase, too, has a specific meaning that might not be expected by normal English interpretation.  In general, the textbook prefers to state evidence positively, in terms of what we know rather than in terms of what we don’t know.  As to genetic mutation, it refers to various mechanisms for altering the genome, such as transposition of small portions of the DNA from one location to another.</p>
<p>One internet site was particularly helpful in tracking down the origin of the phrase “random mutation.”  This site was associated with UC Museum of Paleontology (at Berkeley).  The website is a teaching guide for evolution named “Evolution 101.”  This source was very explicit:</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><b>“</b><strong>Mutations are random.</strong><br />
Mutations can be beneficial, neutral, or harmful for the organism, but mutations do not “try” to supply what the organism “needs.” In this respect, mutations are random—whether a particular mutation happens or not is unrelated to how useful that mutation would be.”</p>
<p>Behind this brief description is a debate that began with Darwin.  Prior to Darwin, there was a French biologist named Jean-Baptiste Lamarck who held the view that (1) Individuals acquire traits that they need and lose traits that they don’t need and (2) Individuals inherit the traits of their ancestors.  He gave as examples the Giraffe whose neck was assumed to have stretched in order to reach higher leaves in trees and blacksmiths whose strong arms appeared to have been inherited by their sons.  But these ideas have been debunked.</p>
<p>When Darwin published Origin of Species in 1859, he gave some credibility to Lamarck’s view, but later evolutionists elevated Lamarck’s idea to a major theme of evolution.  By the mid-twentieth century, biologists had become adept at doing experiments with bacteria.  In 1943, two biologists, Max Delbrück and Salvador Luria, wanted to test Lamarck’s hypothesis for bacteria, which were thought to be the more likely organism to use Lamarckian adaptation.  The Luria-Delbrück experiment tested whether bacteria exposed to a lethal virus would develop any adaptive mutation and whether that mutation would be acquired prior to exposure or not.  Their experiment showed conclusively that some bacteria had acquired an adaptive mutation prior to exposure, as did subsequent experiments by others, including Esther and Joshua Lederberg who are referenced on the “Evolution 101” website.</p>
<p>So, based on experiments, what evolutionists mean when they say that mutations are random is that some adaptive mutations occur before any exposure to infectious agents in a test.  The mutations do not occur because of exposure.  Now this is a somewhat contentious finding because it defies the rather commonsense view that mutations happen for a reason, most likely that reason is related to some inoculation or exposure to an agent.  In other words, either the finding appears to violate causality or the explanation is an admission of ignorance about the cause of adaptation.</p>
<p>I take the view that the finding is an admission of ignorance.  We really don’t know what might have caused an adaptive mutation to occur before exposure.  The real scientific question is what causes the mutation and biologists prefer to focus on what we can discover.  One such biologist is James A. Shapiro, professor of microbiology at the University of Chicago.  He characterizes the association of “random mutation” with the Luria-Delbruck experiment as follows:</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">One has to be careful with the word &#8220;proof&#8221; in science. I always said that conventional evolutionists were hanging a very heavy coat on a very thin peg in the way they cited Luria and Delbrück. The peg broke in the first decade of this century.</p>
<p>Professor Shapiro goes on to write about mechanisms that bacteria have for “remembering” previous exposure to infectious agents.  Those mechanisms include modification of the bacteria DNA.  He states that Delbrück and Luria would have discovered this if they had not used a virus that was invariably lethal and if they had the tools for DNA analysis.  The announcement of the DNA structure would take place in 1953, ten years after the Luria-Delbrück experiment, and the tools for analysis are still being developed.  It should not be too big a surprise that bacteria have elaborate mechanisms for DNA sharing and modification. The human immune response to invasive agents also includes the recording of information in the DNA of certain white blood cells (lymphocytes).   You can read Shapiro’s entire article here: <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/james-a-shapiro/epigenetics-ii-cellular-m_b_1668820.html">http://www.huffingtonpost.com/james-a-shapiro/epigenetics-ii-cellular-m_b_1668820.html</a>.</p>
<p>It is no longer fashionable to speak of Lamarckian inheritance, but the field of epigenetics is devoted to adaptation by means other than DNA modification.  My own view is that the amount of debate and discussion on the issue of “soft” inheritance points to a conclusion that this is unsettled science.  Microbiologists today have many more tools and techniques for answering questions about causes for adaptive inheritance then they did sixty years ago and I suspect that they would prefer to look at changes to the DNA and other molecules rather than make statistical inferences as Luria and Delbrück did.  Current research of the type that James Shapiro is doing is demonstrating specific causes for adaptation.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/87/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/87/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=87&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://quantumveil.wordpress.com/2013/01/31/the-evidence-from-evolution-and-biology-part-1/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>21</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/36d172fb014922b16b7c097e00fcdf44?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">djrfree</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>\&#8221;It\&#8217;s Okay, You Aren\&#8217;t Broken.\&#8221;</title>
		<link>http://shaunanagins.com/2013/01/30/sex-lies-and-story-time-its-okay-you-arent-broken/</link>
		<comments>http://shaunanagins.com/2013/01/30/sex-lies-and-story-time-its-okay-you-arent-broken/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2013 18:22:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>shaunanagins</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Lifestyle & Brainwaves]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants & Raves]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[feminism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[liberation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sex]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sexuality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thoughts]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://shaunanagins.com/?p=1202</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I have wanted to write about this for a long time.  I have so much to say about it. The problem is that I don’t have any stories about it&#8211; not that I am willing to share, at least. The world belongs to people who have the best stories.  Sexual liberation belongs to women who [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1202&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span id="internal-source-marker_0.14823800511658192">I have wanted to write about this for a long time.  I have so much to say about it. The problem is that I don’t have any stories about it&#8211; not that I am willing to share, at least. The world belongs to people who have the best stories.  Sexual liberation belongs to women who are willing to stand up and say “I have sex! I have <em>this much</em> sex with <em>this many</em> people, and it’s okay!” or  “I dress <em>like this</em>, so take that society!” Purity, modesty, and all that is pro-Virgin power comes from personal testimonies and Conservatively told bible stories.</span></p>
<p>And then there’s me.</p>
<p>Of course, I admire people who do tell their stories. They have changed my life, and the world really does belong to them.  Stories have a neat way of improving social consciousness, evolving into full-blown movements. [Insert Pokemon evolution joke here?].</p>
<p>Me, I really don’t have a story that will change your life.  I could probably make you laugh, but ultimately I’m not willing to share whether I’ve said Yes or No&#8211;certainly, I’m not telling the internet, nor my parents, nor most people I know. That doesn’t make me ashamed, by the way. I am fully comfortable with my sexuality. And I’m fully comfortable with keeping it to myself.</p>
<p>But since stories run the show, I will tell you the stories that I know.</p>
<p>I know stories about women saying Yes, and it being a big problem. I know stories about women saying No, and it being a big problem. I know stories about misogyny disguised as miscommunication.  I also know stories of miscommunication disguised as misogyny&#8211;God bless the little boys who receive mixed messages and lowered bars from society every day.</p>
<p>I know stories about people ashamed of what they <em>have</em> done, because that big bully “Society&#8221; told them they ought to be.  Then there the people ashamed of what they <em>haven’t</em> done. There’s also shame in the couldn’t do, wouldn’t do&#8211;or, God forbid, <em>like</em> to do.</p>
<p>Oh, and there’s shame in what people <em>don’t like</em> to do, too. Sometimes, the don’t likes meet the likes and they confuse and shame <em>each other</em>.  Fun, right?</p>
<p>I know stories about women who proudly wear the title “sexually liberated” because, well, they have a lot of sex and they want to own it and <em>good for them</em>.  I know stories about women are “sexually liberated,” or “sex positive,” but don’t have a lot of sex at all.  I have heard tall tales from people who pretend they have <em>more</em> sex than they actually do, because they want to be part of the conversation. And then, of course, there are heartbreaking stories from folks who pretend they have <em>less</em> sex than they actually do, because that’s what is acceptable.</p>
<p>To make matters more confusing, these stories can all belong to the same person.  Whether you’re in a Eucharist line or a picket line, chances are your sexual history is more definitive of who you are as a person than it should be.</p>
<p>Yes, I know stories.  And so many of these stories make want to run up and give their keepers a big hug and say “It’s okay! You’re okay! <strong>You aren’t broken</strong>.”</p>
<p>Everyone is just trying to figure their s**t out. If sexuality was sensible, reasonable, formulated, and mundane, then it wouldn’t be so friggin’ funny. And it is funny. It’s ridiculous. It’s romantic. It’s silly.</p>
<p>Welcome to human relationships, friends&#8211;they’re <em>weird</em>.  When people take their clothes off, they get even <em>weirder</em>. So no, they don’t need your judgement.  They need your love, and they need God’s love.  Please leave the close-mindedness at the door.</p>
<p>Oh, yes, there are serious things involved in sexuality: Health. Pregnancy. HIV. Disease. Emotional well-being. Rape. Consent.  And we’re awfully good at confusing people about the serious parts by making up stupid rules about the ridiculous parts.  These things need to be discussed honestly, but we keep loading them down with arbitrary social standards.  Why? Do we really need to make sex <em>more</em> emotionally loaded and confusing?</p>
<p>Here’s what we need to do:  Care about the stories. Let them speak. Respect the storytellers.  Share your own stories, if you want to.  And whatever your story is, however different it is than someone elses, whatever you choose to do with it: <em><strong>You aren’t broken.</strong></em></p>
<p>You’re just another person with a story and a body, and no matter what, those two things belong to you and you alone.</p>
<div id="attachment_1212" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 647px"><a href="http://shaunanaginsdotcom.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/shaunanaginstumbnail2.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-1212  " alt="ShaunanaginsTumbnail2" src="http://shaunanaginsdotcom.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/shaunanaginstumbnail2.jpg?w=637&#038;h=421" width="637" height="421" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Photo by Samantha Polzin for shaunanagins.com, January 2013</p></div>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1202/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1202/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1202&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://shaunanagins.com/2013/01/30/sex-lies-and-story-time-its-okay-you-arent-broken/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>72</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/50de525dd174548194718ce1d17a0beb?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">shaunanagins</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://shaunanaginsdotcom.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/shaunanaginstumbnail2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ShaunanaginsTumbnail2</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Saying Goodbye</title>
		<link>http://culturallife.wordpress.com/2013/01/31/weekly-writing-challenge-saying-goodbye/</link>
		<comments>http://culturallife.wordpress.com/2013/01/31/weekly-writing-challenge-saying-goodbye/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 13:41:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Grace @ Cultural Life</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing challenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPchallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospitals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[illness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surgery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing challenge]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://culturallife.wordpress.com/?p=925</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[When I saw this week’s writing challenge from The Daily Post, I planned to write a fun story about the characters we see in the photo. But then I thought about the wider theme I interpreted in this picture: saying farewell. The people in the photo could be greeting each other, I suppose, but to [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=925&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://culturallife.wordpress.com/2013/01/31/weekly-writing-challenge-saying-goodbye/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>90</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/fdc11863ca43ee6576b35316bc7fed0f?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">culturallife</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://culturallife.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/couple-embrace.jpg?w=241" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>1,000 Words, Take Two</title>
		<link>http://littlemisswordy.wordpress.com/2013/01/30/weekly-writing-challenge-1000-words-take-two/</link>
		<comments>http://littlemisswordy.wordpress.com/2013/01/30/weekly-writing-challenge-1000-words-take-two/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2013 14:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>littlemisswordy</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Challenges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Inspiration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Storytelling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thoughts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[death]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DP Challenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hug]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inspiration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mental-health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[siblings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[storytelling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weekly writing challenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://littlemisswordy.wordpress.com/?p=1542</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I cling to him, feeling the slippery slope of time catching up to me as the ticks on my watch drum in my ears like a tribal rain dance circling round my brain. If only I could freeze time and force it to turn around and head back in the opposite direction, even if it [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1542&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://littlemisswordy.wordpress.com/2013/01/30/weekly-writing-challenge-1000-words-take-two/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>92</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/70f0e4f24da2a226a165a3455da6dce9?s=96&#38;d=wavatar&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">littlemisswordy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://littlemisswordy.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/couple-embrace.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">couple-embrace</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
