<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2012 20:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Sweet Potato Pie and I Shut My Mouth: The Narrative Craft of Country Music.</title>
		<link>http://sequoyareview.com/2012/10/09/sweet-potato-pie-and-i-shut-my-mouth-the-narrative-craft-of-country-music/</link>
		<comments>http://sequoyareview.com/2012/10/09/sweet-potato-pie-and-i-shut-my-mouth-the-narrative-craft-of-country-music/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2012 01:29:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>J.R. Sullivan</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[country music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Drive-By Truckers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[John Prine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lucinda Williams]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tom Waits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://sequoyareview.com/?p=1332</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As a writer, I often find myself delving into other mediums of art for inspiration, longing to improve my craft by taking cues from the masters of forms of media outside my own. Literature and film have always been close friends, swapping plots and characters freely, but often I find country music just as inspiring [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1332&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://sequoyareview.com/2012/10/09/sweet-potato-pie-and-i-shut-my-mouth-the-narrative-craft-of-country-music/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		<georss:point>35.045016 -85.296329</georss:point>
		<geo:lat>35.045016</geo:lat>
		<geo:long>-85.296329</geo:long>
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/622fe149760f74310c43938e7a76df44?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sinsofmemphisto123</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Holiday: My Good Luck Charm Movie</title>
		<link>http://levhardware.wordpress.com/2012/10/10/holiday/</link>
		<comments>http://levhardware.wordpress.com/2012/10/10/holiday/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2012 00:59:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>levhardware</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[My Daily Art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the only ones for me are the mad ones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cary grant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dreams]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[george cukor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[holiday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[katherine hepburn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movies]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://levhardware.wordpress.com/?p=1255</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[ (image from: http://amoviescrapbook.blogspot.com/2012/09/holiday-one-of-cukors-classic-gems.html ) I love movies, and when pressed to name my favorites, it&#8217;s always a difficult list to compile. I mean, how can you compare The Red Shoes with Cool Hand Luke or The Thin Man? Where do I even begin ranking Meek&#8217;s Cutoff, The Last Days of Disco, Notorious and In The [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1255&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://levhardware.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/url2.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-1271" title="Holiday 2" src="http://levhardware.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/url2.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a> <em>(image from: http://amoviescrapbook.blogspot.com/2012/09/holiday-one-of-cukors-classic-gems.html )</em></p>
<p>I love movies, and when pressed to name my favorites, it&#8217;s always a difficult list to compile. I mean, how can you compare <em>The Red Shoes</em> with <em>Cool Hand Luke </em>or <em>The Thin Man</em>? Where do I even begin ranking <em>Meek&#8217;s Cutoff,</em> <em>The Last Days of Disco, Notorious </em>and <em>In The Mood For Love</em>? For many years, <em>The Princess Bride</em> has reined supreme as my all-time favorite movie, because I just love it, and I can watch it a million times and never get sick of it. I can quote the entire thing and never get annoyed at myself (although I can&#8217;t speak for those around me).</p>
<p>George Cukor&#8217;s <em>Holiday</em> starring Cary Grant and Katherine Hepburn is creeping in for a tie as #1. I can watch it again and again, and each time I am moved to tears, laughter and deep thoughts about my life. I <em>am</em> Johnny Case and Linda Seaton (Grant and Hepburn&#8217;s characters). I <em>get</em> this movie, and it<em> gets</em> me, in a deep and ancient way.</p>
<p>Cary Grant&#8217;s character, Johnny Case, falls for a pretty girl named Julia, who turns out to be super rich and have a sister named Linda, played by Katherine Hepburn. Johnny has worked hard all his life, is doing pretty well now at age 30, and he wants to quit and see the world, figure out life, start working again once he finds out what he&#8217;s working for. This is a crazy notion to his new fiance Julia, who wants him to work for her father at the bank and make millions. Her sister, Linda, the black sheep of the family, understands Johnny&#8217;s dream and wants something similar for herself.</p>
<p>Johnny and Linda are fighting against a society that wants them to behave according to certain rules. But they have a different idea, one that is crazy and might not work but they want to try anyway. I tear up watching Linda try to explain her desires to her sister and father: realizing they do not understand, not knowing how to break away from them, seeing her brother Ned who has already given up. And when Johnny decides to stay and work at the bank, looking so dejected, my insides clench up, knowing that conflict between his own desires and what others want him to do.</p>
<p>I feel like my life is often in conflict with the world, with society. So many people tell me what I &#8220;should&#8221; do, or ask when I&#8217;m going to get a &#8220;real&#8221; job or ask me what my &#8220;plan&#8221; is. There&#8217;s this thing that I want, this desire, this crazy idea that burns inside me. Sometimes it almost feels physical, wanting it so badly. I make decisions that often seem strange or illogical to others, in order to live the life I want. And I work really hard to make it happen. But I&#8217;m doing it.</p>
<p>And then I find those other beautiful souls who want this thing too, like Linda and Johnny who recognize that burning in each other. When I meet these people my heart brightens, I almost want to cry because it can feel so lonely sometimes.</p>
<p><em>Holiday</em> puts that burning on the screen. This movie is a friend, a keepsake, a good luck charm I want to keep in my pocket and rub between my fingers when I get scared or cold.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1255/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1255/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1255&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://levhardware.wordpress.com/2012/10/10/holiday/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/386b67864700161875f79fc76df8ba01?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">levhardware</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://levhardware.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/url2.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Holiday 2</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Defining Crazy</title>
		<link>http://blackboxwarnings.wordpress.com/2012/10/04/defining-crazy/</link>
		<comments>http://blackboxwarnings.wordpress.com/2012/10/04/defining-crazy/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2012 17:42:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>saradraws</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Guest Blogger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Albert Einstein quote]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[highly sensitive people]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[history of psychiatry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hysteria]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mental disorder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mental health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pharmaceuticals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[psychiatry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[therapy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[webcomic]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blackboxwarnings.wordpress.com/?p=406</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[From the Oxford Dictionary Definition of crazy - adjective (crazier, craziest): mad, especially as manifested in wild or aggressive behaviour. &#8211; archaic (of a ship or building) full of cracks or flaws; unsound. We&#8217;ve all had our moments of crazy. Little peeks behind the sanity curtain. In context, it&#8217;s fine, like screaming like a banshee at the television during the substitute for [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=406&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://blackboxwarnings.wordpress.com/2012/10/04/defining-crazy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>161</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/9c1f9c2e992ca344a431721b52157dde?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">saradraws</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://blackboxwarnings.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/paint-1-001.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Hysteria</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ruination Day: A Year After the Flood</title>
		<link>http://rollergiraffe.com/2012/10/06/october-6th-revelation-day/</link>
		<comments>http://rollergiraffe.com/2012/10/06/october-6th-revelation-day/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2012 13:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>rollergiraffe</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Anxiety]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncomfortable Sharing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anxiety]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[future me]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[house]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[husband]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[serious]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vision board]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zombie apocalypse]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rollergiraffe.com/?p=949</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[So. It&#8217;s been exactly one year since I came home expecting a nice hot bath and found my ceiling on my goddamn floor. That turned out to be the high point of the last 366 days (Leap year! One bonus extra day of misery!); at least we were giddy and insane with grief at that [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=949&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So. It&#8217;s been exactly one year since I came home expecting a nice hot bath and <a href="http://rollergiraffe.com/2011/10/09/oh-f-it/">found my ceiling on my goddamn floor</a>. That turned out to be the high point of the last 366 days (Leap year! One bonus extra day of misery!); at least we were giddy and insane with grief at that point. The <a href="http://rollergiraffe.com/2012/03/22/i-am-about-to-get-all-existential-on-yall-bear-with-me/">ensuing incompetence, maliciousness, and random bad luck</a> that followed aged and embittered us enough to fill therapists pockets for years to come. But it&#8217;s been a year. The acceptable period of grief is over. The unfortunate legal battles and insurance bullshit is not, but there comes a point where we either get sucked under by it or we move on with our lives.</p>
<p>But I am still sad. And unmotivated. I have terrible first world problems like hating our house. Every little detail from the reno represents some sort of <del>loud discussion</del> compromise or hasty decision we had to make. We keep trying to divert our attention to fun things, but you can only go to so many amusement parks before you figure out that amusement parks are creepy and contribute to malaise. My hobbies are emotional eating and insomnia. Basically, I am in a giant rut. <a href="http://rollergiraffe.com/2012/08/22/a-rollergiraffe-at-work/">And this time I don&#8217;t have any cow bones or a spirited little partner to help me out of it. </a></p>
<p>But the time for that is over too. I need a goddamn plan. Although I mostly feel like laying down most of the day, I am tired of feeling that way. Being the proactive beast I am, I drank <del>a bottle of</del> a very small quantity of wine for inspiration (and perhaps <del>a whole lot of</del> a teeny amount of Balvenie Double Wood.. heh, insert adolescent sex joke here) and concocted one.</p>
<p><strong>A Rollergiraffe&#8217;s 7 Point Plan for the Future</strong></p>
<p><strong>1. Get a damn job.</strong> I need to use my brain again and earn some money. This is likely going to be in the industry I worked in pre-kids, without the benefit of the last four years of training, networking and general career trajectory. And I would have to go to interviews which make me sweat and self-deprecate. I am still a little traumatized from getting laid off by voicemail from my last job, and I have no filters left that will allow me to function in an office setting. I might try to give my co-workers time outs when they disagree with me. Ok, so this might not work out in a hurry.</p>
<p><strong>2. Do charity work.</strong> In the absence of a paying job, I should be giving back to the community. I am pretty sure I have a lot to offer in this regard, with my environmental experience and all. Right? It doesn&#8217;t matter that the only journal I read in the last four years is US Weekly, right? People are dying for celebrity news, aren&#8217;t they? And I would need to pay for child care to do charity work which .. or I could do it in the evenings, right? After the kids go to bed and the house is somewhat restored from the garbage dump look we&#8217;ve adopted through the day? Ok, so this one&#8217;s out too for now.</p>
<p><strong>3. Exact revenge on the </strong><strong><del>contractor</del> </strong><strong>fuckstick weasel who wrecked our house and tried to ruin our lives.</strong> This one is just a fantasy. He&#8217;s already sitting on a heap of debt, both karmic and financial. And I am an adult who is able to control their emotions (totally not true except for the legal adult part). Plus, I am way too lazy to do a good job, so I&#8217;d just basically annoy him a little and then end up on Canada&#8217;s Stupidest Criminals, if such a show exists.</p>
<p><strong>4. Become a domestic goddess.</strong> HAHAHAHAHAHAHAHAHAHAHA. Nope.</p>
<p><strong>5. I am still laughing over the domestic goddess thing.</strong> Mount Washmore is so goddamn high, you guys.</p>
<p><strong>6. Spend time preparing for the zombie apocalypse.</strong> I am on <a href="http://loveandlunchmeat.com/2012/08/29/reasons-you-want-me-on-your-team-during-the-zombie-apocalypse/">Love and Lunchmeat&#8217;s Zombie apocalypse team</a> (even if I can&#8217;t figure out how to put badges on my blog. Fuckballs, I am hopeless at the internets), so I am sure this would be a worthwhile endeavor. If it&#8217;s not the zombies, it&#8217;s going to be something. Except all that canning I did totally went to waste and my shoulder is ruined from carrying twins around all day so I am not sure improving my marksmanship is really a good idea. And every time I think about the apocalypse I think about <a href="http://www.randomhouse.com/kvpa/cormacmccarthy/">The Road</a>, and I am not sure at this point in my life I would be the one who filled the bathtub when the loud noises were heard. My survival instinct is kind of dull right now, is what I am saying.</p>
<div id="attachment_999" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 360px"><a href="http://rollergiraffe.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/fall-2012-070.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-999 " title="Fall 2012 070" src="http://rollergiraffe.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/fall-2012-070.jpg?w=350&#038;h=233" alt="" width="350" height="233" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">I was only ever good at shooting quarters anyway.</p></div>
<p><strong>7. Have another baby</strong>. Because less sleep is totally the answer.</p>
<p>So obviously I have no plan. <strong>Tell me, gentle readers, have you ever been stuck in a rut before? How did you get out?</strong> Do you think I should keep my hair short? Why does Mitt Romney want to fire Big Bird? What is your favourite snack? Why isn&#8217;t anyone talking about the Higgs Boson anymore? Is it because they accidentally made themselves a big black hole? Answer any of these questions below in the comments.</p>
<p>P.S. If you read the Ringmistress&#8217; blog, <a href="http://lamentsandlullabies.wordpress.com/2012/09/16/is-35-too-young-to-have-a-midlife-crisis/">Laments and Lullabies</a>, a 35 year old having a mid-life crisis will sound disturbingly familiar to you. I totally drunken plagiarized her, and then apologized, but she laughed at me and told me to post it anyway because she&#8217;s amazing that way. And lots of other ways too.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/949/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/949/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=949&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://rollergiraffe.com/2012/10/06/october-6th-revelation-day/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>96</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/04bd77013ed8df27770fe2618429a14f?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=R" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">rollergiraffe</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://rollergiraffe.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/fall-2012-070.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Fall 2012 070</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Generation Y Redefines Success</title>
		<link>http://lostgenygirl.com/2012/09/18/generation-y-redefines-success/</link>
		<comments>http://lostgenygirl.com/2012/09/18/generation-y-redefines-success/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2012 18:28:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Kayla Cruz</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gen Y Issues]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Happiness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gen-Y Myths]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[On Being Young at Work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Decision Making]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Change]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gen Y]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[geny]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[millennials]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[choices]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[change]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[generation y]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[innovation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[college]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inspiration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[twentysomething]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[career]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[post grad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[graduation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[young professionals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[motivation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[success]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[happy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[careers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://lostgenygirl.com/?p=1421</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[My senior year of high school, I had the genius idea of taking AP Physics, AP Calculus, and AP Statistics, all at the same time. I pushed myself so hard that year all because I wanted to earn college credits and therefore graduate from college in less than four years. I did that. I started [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1421&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://lostgenygirl.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/success-is-liking-yourself-liking-what-you-do-and-liking-how-you-do-it1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1429" title="Success is liking yourself liking what you do and liking how you do it" src="http://lostgenygirl.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/success-is-liking-yourself-liking-what-you-do-and-liking-how-you-do-it1.jpg" alt="" width="375" height="475" /></a></p>
<p>My senior year of high school, I had the genius idea of taking AP Physics, AP Calculus, and AP Statistics, all at the same time.</p>
<p>I pushed myself so hard that year all because I wanted to earn college credits and therefore graduate from college in less than four years.</p>
<p>I did that.</p>
<p>I started working a full-time job at the age of 19 and earned my bachelor’s degree in two and a half years.</p>
<p>I figured that if I got my degree early and had some experience under my belt, I’d be ahead of the game career-wise and would be taking steps towards my journey up the quote-on-quote career ladder. If I did this, I would be a few steps closer to becoming the VP of some great company where my work would consume all of my energy every day.</p>
<p>That’s what success looked like most of my life.</p>
<p>I was taught, growing up, that in order to be a successful woman I&#8217;d have to work really hard so that I could one day break through these ceilings that were said to be made of glass. And if I did manage to achieve this, well,  I&#8217;d become the much-respected senior executive of some company where I would spend 40+ hours every week.</p>
<p>That’s what I was supposed to want.</p>
<p>That’s what I’ve always been capable of doing.</p>
<p>To not reach that goal, I was told, would be a waste of my potential. It would be a waste of my intellect. I would be a failure.</p>
<p>So all my life, this is the goal that I’ve worked towards.</p>
<p>In doing so, however, I&#8217;ve allowed others to determine what success looks like in my life.</p>
<p>A few years later, having been in the workforce, I look at the senior executives of many great organizations and I think to myself…really? This is what I want? This is what I’ve worked so hard for all these years?</p>
<p>To work 60 hours a week? To not have time to do the things that I love to do? To have better relationships with the strangers I go to meetings with once a month than with the people I&#8217;ve known all my life?</p>
<p>Something’s wrong here.</p>
<p>I know, in my heart, that I DON’T want that.</p>
<p>But I’m supposed to, right?</p>
<p>I’m smart, I’m ambitious, I have big dreams….OBVIOUSLY that’s what success looks like, right?</p>
<p><strong>WRONG.</strong></p>
<p>You see, success can’t be defined so narrowly. Success, also, shouldn’t be defined for you by anyone else. Success is very personal and it varies.</p>
<p>My definition of success can be very different from your definition.</p>
<p>Likewise, my definition of success at 22 can be very different from my definition of success at 40.</p>
<p>That’s okay.</p>
<p>The point is that today I look back on the past few years of my life and although I don’t regret the way my life has played out, I wish that I had allowed myself to form my own definition of success.</p>
<p>Without the influence of society.</p>
<p>Without the influence of my friends.</p>
<p>Without the influence of my parents.</p>
<p><strong>Success should have been between me and me alone.</strong></p>
<p>Today, when I think of success, I don’t think about working for some multi-million dollar corporation managing all of the best accounts, swiftly climbing the corporate ladder.</p>
<p>Instead, I think about being happy. I think about finding a career that I love, one that challenges me. I think about a career that allows me to help others, that allows me to give back in some way. I think about having time to travel and hang out with my friends. I think about making sure that I have enough time to devote to a relationship and building a family one day. Success, to me, means being inspired and having interesting work to do. Success, therefore, is not being bored.</p>
<p>That doesn’t make me any less ambitious.</p>
<p>That doesn’t make me any less determined.</p>
<p>It just means that I’m working towards something different.</p>
<p>And I’ll never apologize for that.</p>
<p>I think that Generation Y wants to succeed, we want to be successful. But at the same time, our picture of success is very different from that of generations before us. The idea of working 80 hours a week behind a desk with no time to pursue our other interests is not really all that appealing.</p>
<p>That’s why we’re asking for <a title="flex" href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2011-06-03/ys-just-wanna-have-fun-and-flexibility-.html">flex time</a>.</p>
<p>That’s why there no longer exists a <a title="ladder" href="http://www.inc.com/flash-steinbeiser/gen-y-says-bye-bye-corporate-ladder.html">corporate ladder</a>.</p>
<p>That’s why we’re seen as so <a title="demanding" href="http://thegrindstone.com/office-politics/businesses-are-bowing-to-the-demanding-gen-y-workforce-741/">demanding</a>.   </p>
<p><strong>We want more to life than just work.</strong></p>
<p>And for that… I’m sorry that I’m not sorry.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://lostgenygirl.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/success-direction.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-1424" title="success-direction" src="http://lostgenygirl.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/success-direction.jpg?w=392&#038;h=283" alt="" width="392" height="283" /></a></p>
<h3>Other stuff you might like:</h3>
<p><a title="Don't Wait" href="http://lostgenygirl.com/2012/05/28/dont-wait-be-happy-now/">Don&#8217;t Wait, Be Happy Now</a></p>
<p><a title="Relax" href="http://lostgenygirl.com/2012/04/05/relax-being-lost-is-a-good-thing/">Relax, Being Lost is a Good Thing</a></p>
<p><a href="http://lostgenygirl.com/2012/07/08/random-ramblings-on-being-a-young-adult-the-importance-of-vision-boards/">Random Ramblings on Being a Young Adult </a></p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://lostgenygirl.com/category/change/'>Change</a>, <a href='http://lostgenygirl.com/category/decision-making/'>Decision Making</a>, <a href='http://lostgenygirl.com/category/gen-y-issues/'>Gen Y Issues</a>, <a href='http://lostgenygirl.com/category/gen-y-myths/'>Gen-Y Myths</a>, <a href='http://lostgenygirl.com/category/happiness/'>Happiness</a>, <a href='http://lostgenygirl.com/category/on-being-young-at-work/'>On Being Young at Work</a> Tagged: <a href='http://lostgenygirl.com/tag/business/'>business</a>, <a href='http://lostgenygirl.com/tag/career/'>career</a>, <a href='http://lostgenygirl.com/tag/careers/'>careers</a>, <a href='http://lostgenygirl.com/tag/change-2/'>change</a>, <a href='http://lostgenygirl.com/tag/choices/'>choices</a>, <a href='http://lostgenygirl.com/tag/college/'>college</a>, <a href='http://lostgenygirl.com/tag/gen-y/'>Gen Y</a>, <a href='http://lostgenygirl.com/tag/generation-y/'>generation y</a>, <a href='http://lostgenygirl.com/tag/geny/'>geny</a>, <a href='http://lostgenygirl.com/tag/graduation/'>graduation</a>, <a href='http://lostgenygirl.com/tag/happiness/'>Happiness</a>, <a href='http://lostgenygirl.com/tag/happy/'>happy</a>, <a href='http://lostgenygirl.com/tag/innovation/'>innovation</a>, <a href='http://lostgenygirl.com/tag/inspiration/'>inspiration</a>, <a href='http://lostgenygirl.com/tag/life/'>life</a>, <a href='http://lostgenygirl.com/tag/millennials/'>millennials</a>, <a href='http://lostgenygirl.com/tag/motivation/'>motivation</a>, <a href='http://lostgenygirl.com/tag/post-grad/'>post grad</a>, <a href='http://lostgenygirl.com/tag/success/'>success</a>, <a href='http://lostgenygirl.com/tag/twentysomething/'>twentysomething</a>, <a href='http://lostgenygirl.com/tag/young-professionals/'>young professionals</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1421/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1421/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1421&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://lostgenygirl.com/2012/09/18/generation-y-redefines-success/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>84</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/e89c8642b387c0846f47e75976297005?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=X" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">kaylachristina</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lostgenygirl.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/success-is-liking-yourself-liking-what-you-do-and-liking-how-you-do-it1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Success is liking yourself liking what you do and liking how you do it</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lostgenygirl.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/success-direction.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">success-direction</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Monstrum&#8217;s Awesome Playgrounds</title>
		<link>http://crhofmann.com/2012/10/09/monstrums-awesome-playgrounds/</link>
		<comments>http://crhofmann.com/2012/10/09/monstrums-awesome-playgrounds/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2012 12:23:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Catherine Hofmann</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[build, plan & preserve]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[design & creativity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[images & videos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thoughts & ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[danish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[monstrum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[playground]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://crhofmann.com/?p=1067</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Monstrum, a Danish design firm, builds thoughtful imaginative wooden playgrounds all over the world. They create playgrounds with child development in mind, building to challenge and stimulate the child. Not only are they great for kids, but as an adult, I certainly appreciate the aesthetic and inventiveness. Sadly, many schools in the United States are cutting recess [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1067&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.monstrum.dk/">Monstrum</a>, a Danish design firm, builds thoughtful imaginative wooden playgrounds all over the world. They create playgrounds with child development in mind, building to challenge and stimulate the child. Not only are they great for kids, but as an adult, I certainly appreciate the aesthetic and inventiveness.</p>
<p>Sadly, many schools in the United States are cutting recess and playtime with major drawbacks in children&#8217;s health and behavior. A study by the Elementary School Journal in 2008 found that almost 25% of schools did not have recess. I find this more perplexing with childhood obesity rates on the rise– 20% of 6-11 year olds were obese in 2008. Plus, many studies have found a strong positive correlation between child&#8217;s play and self-esteem.</p>
<p>&#8220;I get this feeling in my legs when they want to run and that feeling moves up to my belly and when that feeling moves up to my head I can&#8217;t remember what the rules are.&#8221;<br />
- Nadav, 7, Pittsburgh</p>
<p><a href="http://crhofmann.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/nords_museet1_1.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1070" title="Nords_museet1_1" src="http://crhofmann.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/nords_museet1_1.jpg" alt="" width="545" height="204" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://crhofmann.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/playground.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1069" title="playground" src="http://crhofmann.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/playground.jpg" alt="" width="545" height="181" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://crhofmann.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/nords.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1071" title="nords" src="http://crhofmann.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/nords.jpg" alt="" width="545" height="181" /></a><a href="http://crhofmann.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/gedde_pike2.jpeg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1068" title="Gedde_pike2" src="http://crhofmann.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/gedde_pike2.jpeg" alt="" width="545" height="241" /></a></p>
<p>http://www.cdc.gov/healthyyouth/obesity/facts.htm</p>
<p>http://www.livescience.com/15555-schools-cut-recess-learning-suffers.html</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1067/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1067/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1067&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://crhofmann.com/2012/10/09/monstrums-awesome-playgrounds/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>27</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/d7cd14877bfc7a90298d808fe190ae48?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F1.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">crjh</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://crhofmann.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/nords_museet1_1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Nords_museet1_1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://crhofmann.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/playground.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">playground</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://crhofmann.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/nords.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">nords</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://crhofmann.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/gedde_pike2.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Gedde_pike2</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Greedily, I Want the Right To Live AND The Right To Die</title>
		<link>http://robinince.wordpress.com/2012/10/04/greedily-i-want-the-right-to-live-and-the-right-to-die/</link>
		<comments>http://robinince.wordpress.com/2012/10/04/greedily-i-want-the-right-to-live-and-the-right-to-die/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2012 15:49:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>robinince</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[assisted dying]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dignity in dying]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kervorkian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[peter singer]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://robinince.wordpress.com/2012/10/04/greedily-i-want-the-right-to-live-and-the-right-to-die/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[On Monday, I agreed to become one of the many patrons of Dignity in Dying. here are some of my thoughts on why I said yes. As usual I wrote far too much, so I have severely edited it. I hope it makes sense. Happy to have appalling spelling, punctuation or logic pointed out to [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=224&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On Monday, I agreed to become one of the many patrons of Dignity in Dying. here are some of my thoughts on why I said yes. As usual I wrote far too much, so I have severely edited it. I hope it makes sense. Happy to have appalling spelling, punctuation or logic pointed out to me (thought don&#8217;t be too picky)</p>
<p><em>“I don’t feel it’s our obligation to choose for someone else how much pain and suffering they go through”  The words of a nurse after trial of right to die campaigner, Jack Kervorkian</em></p>
<p>I believe I only have one life. It is the life I am living now on this planet. When disease or age destroys my ability to think and breathe, to be aware of myself, then that’s it. The me that is me is gone. Physics offers some cheer. At least I know that all atoms that are currently gathered together in the shape of me will go to making other stuff in this universe for as long as it exists, just as they have been spread around all sorts of animate and inanimate things over billions of years. The particles that make you and me have been many things before and will be many things again. They are not my atoms, they are the universe’s atoms, I’ve got them for a while, many of them fleetingly. There goes some of my skin dust again.</p>
<p>I find the idea that enough atoms put together in a certain way can make a mind that is aware of love, death, pottery and the universe, startling and odd, but I am glad of it. The downside of these minds and their self awareness; their ability to prepare for the winter and coach their offspring to adulthood, is that with the prescient ability to have a sense of the future, we can also see that one day we must die. It’s a daunting prospect to know your thoughts and memories will one day end In a society of so many consumer choices, there will come a point when, however much we wish to still live, our death will happen. Though there will come a time when we run out of ways of avoiding death, I believe that in certain situations we should have the choice of dying before nature insists upon it.</p>
<p>I have recently become a patron of Dignity in Dying, an organization that campaigns for the right to assisted dying for those who find the agony of their life too great. When I tweeted about this I called the organization’s campaign an enlightened one.</p>
<p>I was taken to task over the idea that a society where assisted dying is legal is an enlightened one.</p>
<p>I believe the desire to live, especially for those who see no glow of an afterlife, is too great for us to just switch off our existence on a whim, as some of those against assisted dying seem to suggest.  Some  critics commented, “there must be other options?”</p>
<p>I think there are other options, assisted dying is not the first and only option, but the final one, when all else has failed and no hope can be glimpsed. It is not about people feeling a bit down on Tuesday and lying in the morgue by Thursday.</p>
<p>I do not know at what point of pain or sense of futility I would give up my life. I try to imagine it. I am sure that the childless have a burning urge to live too, but as a parent, the idea of leaving my son fatherless makes me feel physically sick. From the transcripts I’ve read of those who have chosen to die, all possibilities have been discussed on many occasions and, with a frightful battle against their innate senses, a love has been shown, the love that accepts a family members wish to die, an understanding that that wish can only come from unbearable suffering.</p>
<p>I try to imagine what situation would be enough for me to choose death. I think of what I have just done in the last few seconds – I have picked up a banana and taken a bite from it, grasped a coffee cup, tasted and swallowed a swig of it, typed this sentence (I still am), inhaled with ease and turned without aid to look at the sun reflected on the overgrown banks of the railway. I briefly imagine all of those simple things lost to me. Would I want to live without even those simple actions available to me? I don’t know. I hope I might find some solace somewhere, but I can also imagine that the loss of dignity in my existence would eat away at me. I would like to know I could grasp hold of the right to die when I wished, to know that if I saw no life beyond a hell and that when all those around me failed to persuade me that I should live on, I was permitted to take the greatest decision of any life.</p>
<p>I have heard people say that to choose to die is to take “the easy way out”, I cannot see how knowingly ending all your experiences of your world is “easy”.</p>
<p>There is also evidence that suggests that mere availability of the choice of assisted dying offers relief. Knowing there is a way out does not mean you will take it.</p>
<p>Some say, “there must be a better way?”</p>
<p>Hopefully one day through our scientific imagination we will find a way.</p>
<p>Perhaps there will be a way where people can escape from the cages of their bodies or have them repaired or even find some way of providing stimulation that will reduce the mental torture some face when disease or accident ravages them.</p>
<p>For now, to not give access to choice in when we wish to die, to see people dying before they wish because they will be unable to make their journey to Dignitas, to see constant living despair considered better than peaceful death, that is barbarism.</p>
<p>For some, who wake up from dreams in which they run to find themselves paralyzed and totally dependent, knowing there is the option of an exit when they choose can be enough to make life livable. What right have we to make those who see no end to suffering, those who have no chance of recovery, live a life without reward until natural causes finally take them?</p>
<p>Information about Dignity in Dying is <a href="http://www.dignityindying.org.uk/includes/spaw2/uploads/files/A%20matter%20of%20facts%20May%202011.pdf">here </a></p>
<p>Peter Singer’s Rethinking Life and Death offers an interesting contribution on this subject</p>
<p>Here is a twitter discussion I had with Baptist Pastor Jon Somerville on <a href="http://tooktheredpill.blogspot.co.uk/">this issue </a></p>
<p>My Happiness through Science tour continues until December, dates <a href="http://www.robinince.com">here </a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/224/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/224/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=224&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://robinince.wordpress.com/2012/10/04/greedily-i-want-the-right-to-live-and-the-right-to-die/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>39</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/0699132fd32e05a8345688e66eecae3b?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">robinince</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ethiopia: God Is Even Bigger Than We Think</title>
		<link>http://cathleenfalsani.com/2012/10/06/ethiopia-god-is-even-bigger-than-we-think-2/</link>
		<comments>http://cathleenfalsani.com/2012/10/06/ethiopia-god-is-even-bigger-than-we-think-2/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2012 18:37:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tgf</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[From Sojo.net]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GODSTUFF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VASCO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Addis Ababa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AIDS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blantyre]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bobby Shriver]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[California]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ethiopia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[one campaign]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cathleenfalsani.com/?p=4879</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[My flight's about to board for Ethiopia.

I'm not looking for anything or anyone. I'm going with an open hand and heart.

And I know — more than I ever could express in words — that God is even bigger than we think. <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4879&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://cathleenfalsani.com/2012/10/06/ethiopia-god-is-even-bigger-than-we-think-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/cc435ed440814d4b3330d6bf38d75d37?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">godgrrl</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cathleenfalsani.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/6bf902c20fce11e2a77f22000a1c00cf_7.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">6bf902c20fce11e2a77f22000a1c00cf_7</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cathleenfalsani.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/vasco-slider-2.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">vasco slider 2</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Save Dessert For Later</title>
		<link>http://mylifeisthebestlife.wordpress.com/2012/10/09/save-dessert-for-later/</link>
		<comments>http://mylifeisthebestlife.wordpress.com/2012/10/09/save-dessert-for-later/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2012 19:42:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>mylifeisthebestlife</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Universe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bob marley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fear]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[husbandio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life in a day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[offspring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[purpose]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[toddler tornado]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mylifeisthebestlife.wordpress.com/?p=369</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I can&#8217;t believe I said that, but I mean it. I had today&#8217;s post all kind of figured out in my head.  You guys were going to learn all about the joys of Banoffee, one of my favorite desserts ever. Then I came home (half day today) and watched Life in a Day on Netflix. Have you [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=369&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I can&#8217;t believe I said that, but I mean it.</p>
<p>I had today&#8217;s post all kind of figured out in my head.  You guys were going to learn all about the joys of Banoffee, one of my favorite desserts ever.</p>
<p>Then I came home (half day today) and watched <em>Life in a Day </em>on Netflix.<em><br />
</em></p>
<p>Have you ever seen a movie that really got to you?  Because this one totally got to me.  It&#8217;s basically a bunch of clips sent in from all over the world, of people filming their life on July 24, 2010.  Ok, I thought&#8230;big deal, right?  A look into people&#8217;s lives.  But you guys &#8211; it&#8217;s so nuts.</p>
<p>The movie itself was good.  It asked three questions: What do you love, what do you fear, and what is in your pocket.  Then everyone on the planet answers them.  We&#8217;re all <strong>so different</strong>.  I mean, we&#8217;re all exactly the same &#8211; we love our family, we&#8217;re scared of spiders, blah blah blah.  But SO MUCH STUFF is happening every day.  No matter where you are on the planet, someone else is doing exactly what you&#8217;re doing, and someone else is doing something you&#8217;ll never do in your life.  Someone is kissing their baby, and someone else is slitting a goat&#8217;s throat.  Someone is falling asleep, and someone is waking up to gunfire.  Someone is grumbling about having to go to work, and someone can&#8217;t get a job because who would look after his motherless children?</p>
<p>This was all very eye-opening and all, but at the end of the day, we&#8217;re human and what we think is how am <strong><em>I</em></strong><em> </em>involved in all of this?</p>
<p>For me it was an easy, but terrifying answer.</p>
<p>What I love and what I fear are exactly the same thing.</p>
<div id="attachment_370" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 648px"><a href="http://mylifeisthebestlife.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/family.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-370" title="Family" src="http://mylifeisthebestlife.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/family.jpg" alt="family" width="638" height="960" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">This is everything, you guys. Everything.</p></div>
<p>There is nothing on the planet that I love more than my family.  Nothing.  No $5000 boots, no winning lottery tickets, no fulfilling career, it&#8217;s THEM.  And there is <strong>nothing</strong> that scares me more than losing them.  I think part of what kept me carefree and single for so long was the avoidance of these exact bonds.  It&#8217;s easy to be fearless when you&#8217;re solo.  But now I know fear &#8211; TRUE fear.  Because I couldn&#8217;t wake up if it wasn&#8217;t for them.</p>
<p>I don&#8217;t give a shit about what&#8217;s in my pocket, because I know what&#8217;s in my heart.</p>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=369&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://mylifeisthebestlife.wordpress.com/2012/10/09/save-dessert-for-later/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>119</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/294e34fb784ad9104a5e095c12b77af6?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=X" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mylifeisthebestlife</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mylifeisthebestlife.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/family.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Family</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>An Almost French Apple Tart</title>
		<link>http://laurenelisephotography.wordpress.com/2012/10/09/french-apple-tart/</link>
		<comments>http://laurenelisephotography.wordpress.com/2012/10/09/french-apple-tart/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2012 01:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>laurenelisephotography</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[DIY]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lauren Elise Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://laurenelisephotography.wordpress.com/?p=260</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[mmmmm Autumn&#8230; crisp air, crunchy orange leaves, big knit sweaters, and most importantly, comfort foods! Here in CA it&#8217;s finally beginning to feel like Fall, and how can that not be inspiring in one way or another? It&#8217;s been a while since I&#8217;ve baked and the recent season change needed welcoming, so an apple tart [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=260&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>mmmmm Autumn&#8230; crisp air, crunchy orange leaves, big knit sweaters, and most importantly, comfort foods!</p>
<p>Here in CA it&#8217;s finally beginning to feel like Fall, and how can that not be inspiring in one way or another?</p>
<p>It&#8217;s been a while since I&#8217;ve baked and the recent season change needed welcoming, so an apple tart made it&#8217;s way onto my list of things to do!</p>
<p>This tart is so easy to make, so do it. Seriously, everyone will love you and be impressed. Also, if you have a man you&#8217;re trying to get married to, give him this, he will immediately inquire on where the nearest jeweler is (I say this from experience).</p>
<p>I found the recipe at <a title="Saveur" href="http://www.saveur.com/article/Recipes/Saveur-100-2011-French-Apple-Tart" target="_blank">Saveur</a>, but as usual, I can&#8217;t follow any recipe without adding or taking away something (one time I tried to get fancy with microwavable top Ramen&#8230; let&#8217;s just say some recipes should be left alone).</p>
<p><a href="http://laurenelisephotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/mg_1703.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-261" title="tart1" src="http://laurenelisephotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/mg_1703.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=640" alt="" width="1024" height="640" /></a></p>
<p>Now, let me start out by stating the obvious so I don&#8217;t confuse all you hard core foodie types out there.</p>
<p>1. I know, I know, I know, this is a pie dish. But give a girl a break, I live in Bakersfield for crying out loud, I looked for a tart pan everywhere. Apparently the art of tart making has been lost here. Time for a revival? Sure thing.</p>
<p>11. It&#8217;s not the prettiest thing in the world, I know. I used an apricot jam to glaze this guy up and usually this would require straining, but I wanted those chunks of sugary apricots cuddling up with my apples. Get over it Bobby Flay, it&#8217;s delicious.</p>
<p>Anyways, let&#8217;s continue so you can make this thing already!</p>
<p>First things first, ingredients!</p>
<p><em>1 1/4 cups flour, plus more for dusting</em><br />
<em>12 tbsp. unsalted butter, cubed and chilled</em><br />
<em>1/4 tsp. kosher salt </em><br />
<em>7 Golden Delicious apples, peeled, cored, and halved (I used less because of the whole pie dish thing&#8230;)</em><br />
<em>1/4 cup sugar</em><br />
<em>1/2 cup apricot jam</em><br />
<em>Whipped cream or vanilla ice cream, for serving</em></p>
<p><a href="http://laurenelisephotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/mg_1661.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-265" title="_MG_1661" src="http://laurenelisephotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/mg_1661.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=640" alt="" width="1024" height="640" /></a></p>
<p>You&#8217;ll also need a chef&#8217;s knife and a melon baller (if you don&#8217;t have an apple corer handy).</p>
<p>Step 1. Combine flour, 8 tbsp. butter, and salt in a food processor and pulse until pea-size crumbles form, about 10 pulses <em>(If you live in Bakersfield like me where both a tart pan and a food processor are hard to come by, you can always work the butter into the flour with a fork)</em>. Drizzle in 3 tbsp. ice-cold water and pulse until dough is moistened, about 3—4 pulses <em>(Another tip! Seriously cool, I just found this <a title="recipe" href="http://www.littlebcooks.blogspot.com/2012/08/perfect-pie-dough.html" target="_blank">recipe</a> where you add vodka to the dough and it makes it super amazing because it adds extra moisture without creating gluten. Haven&#8217;t tried it yet, but I will be doing it next time!)</em>.</p>
<p><a href="http://laurenelisephotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/mg_1665.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-266" title="_MG_1665" src="http://laurenelisephotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/mg_1665.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=639" alt="" width="1024" height="639" /></a></p>
<p>Transfer dough to a work surface and form into a flat disk; wrap in plastic wrap and refrigerate for 1 hour. Unwrap dough and transfer to a lightly floured work surface. Using a rolling pin, flatten dough into a 13″ circle and then transfer to a 11″ tart pan (<em>ha.) </em>with a removable bottom; trim edges; chill for 1 hour.</p>
<p><a href="http://laurenelisephotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/mg_1668.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-267" title="_MG_1668" src="http://laurenelisephotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/mg_1668.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=639" alt="" width="1024" height="639" /></a></p>
<p>Step 11. Heat oven to 375º. Wash, peel, and core all apples. Snack on apple peels or Al Gore will come after you for being wasteful.</p>
<p><a href="http://laurenelisephotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/mg_1672.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-268" title="_MG_1672" src="http://laurenelisephotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/mg_1672.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=640" alt="" width="1024" height="640" /></a></p>
<p>Then working with one apple half at a time, thinly slice into sections, keeping slices together. Be very careful to keep slices consistent. Press sliced apple half gently to fan it out; repeat with remaining apple halves. Using your knife to slide under and pick up <em>(see photo)</em>, place 1 fanned apple half on outer edge of the tart dough, pointing inward; repeat with 7 more apple halves <em>(again, if you have a tart pan you will fit all those apples, I could not)</em>.</p>
<p><a href="http://laurenelisephotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/mg_1681.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-269" title="_MG_1681" src="http://laurenelisephotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/mg_1681.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=640" alt="" width="1024" height="640" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://laurenelisephotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/mg_1682.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-270" title="_MG_1682" src="http://laurenelisephotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/mg_1682.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=640" alt="" width="1024" height="640" /></a></p>
<p>Separate remaining apple slices. Starting where the apple halves touch and working your way in, layer apples to create a tight rose pattern. Fill in any gaps with remaining apple.</p>
<p>For a complete picture tutorial on creating the apple rosette, go <a title="here" href="http://www.saveur.com/gallery/The-Art-of-the-Tart/1" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<p><a href="http://laurenelisephotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/mg_1685.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-271" title="_MG_1685" src="http://laurenelisephotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/mg_1685.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=640" alt="" width="1024" height="640" /></a></p>
<p>Sprinkle with sugar and then dot with remaining butter. Bake until golden brown, 60—70 minutes.</p>
<p><a href="http://laurenelisephotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/mg_1687.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-272" title="_MG_1687" src="http://laurenelisephotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/mg_1687.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=640" alt="" width="1024" height="640" /></a></p>
<p>Meanwhile, heat apricot jam in a small saucepan until warmed and loose; pour through a fine strainer into a small bowl and set aside. Transfer tart to a wire rack; using a pastry brush, brush top of tart with jam. <em>(I also spooned some of the apricot jam onto the bottom of the crust before placing the apples inside, just to add some extra flavor). </em>Let cool completely before slicing and serving with whipped cream.</p>
<p>And violá! A French apple tart/pie! This is super good and I&#8217;m sure way better served à la mode! It&#8217;s a nice take on the classic apple pie and a great way to bring all the boys to your yard&#8230; I mean, to welcome the Fall season! Enjoy!</p>
<p><a href="http://laurenelisephotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/mg_1699.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-273" title="_MG_1699" src="http://laurenelisephotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/mg_1699.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=640" alt="" width="1024" height="640" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://laurenelisephotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/mg_1701.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-274" title="_MG_1701" src="http://laurenelisephotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/mg_1701.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=640" alt="" width="1024" height="640" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://laurenelisephotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/mg_1706.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-275" title="_MG_1706" src="http://laurenelisephotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/mg_1706.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=639" alt="" width="1024" height="639" /></a></p>
<p>P.S. I had extra apple slices left so I tossed them in cinnamon and made apple chips! So yummy!</p>
<p><a href="http://laurenelisephotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/mg_1688.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-276" title="_MG_1688" src="http://laurenelisephotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/mg_1688.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=640" alt="" width="1024" height="640" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Edit!</strong> I completely forgot to write in a tip of mine, but thanks to one of the lovely ladies who left a comment, I was reminded! Every time I make a sweet pie, including in this recipe, I will add at least a tsp of both cinnamon and sugar to the dry ingredients in the crust. It makes is so much better, promise!</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/260/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/260/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=260&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://laurenelisephotography.wordpress.com/2012/10/09/french-apple-tart/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>121</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/8ac590a1595893036f5b96a214cf6087?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">laurenelisephotography</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://laurenelisephotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/mg_1703.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tart1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://laurenelisephotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/mg_1661.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">_MG_1661</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://laurenelisephotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/mg_1665.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">_MG_1665</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://laurenelisephotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/mg_1668.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">_MG_1668</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://laurenelisephotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/mg_1672.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">_MG_1672</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://laurenelisephotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/mg_1681.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">_MG_1681</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://laurenelisephotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/mg_1682.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">_MG_1682</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://laurenelisephotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/mg_1685.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">_MG_1685</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://laurenelisephotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/mg_1687.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">_MG_1687</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://laurenelisephotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/mg_1699.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">_MG_1699</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://laurenelisephotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/mg_1701.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">_MG_1701</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://laurenelisephotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/mg_1706.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">_MG_1706</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://laurenelisephotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/mg_1688.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">_MG_1688</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>