<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2012 22:02:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Synchronized</title>
		<link>http://vagabondwithfamily.wordpress.com/2012/09/12/synchronized/</link>
		<comments>http://vagabondwithfamily.wordpress.com/2012/09/12/synchronized/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2012 14:02:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>vagabondwithfamily</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blogs About Anything]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[high school]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nostalgia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[old girlfriends]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[romance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sentimental yearnings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[teenage love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the 1980's]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Warwick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[youth]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vagabondwithfamily.wordpress.com/?p=202</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Dizzy.  Rolling out of control.  Scenery, like the internal images of a rotating kaleidoscope in the hands of an eagerly entertained youngster, flashed by in a mixture of shapes and sizes.  Intoxicated by the rush of doing something utterly different, wondering if we had lost all sense of reality, and feeling as if my heart [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=202&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://vagabondwithfamily.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/5638122219_92957b9a00_o1.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-321" title="Lady in Red" src="http://vagabondwithfamily.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/5638122219_92957b9a00_o1.jpg?w=133&h=150" alt="" width="133" height="150" /></a>Dizzy.  Rolling out of control.  Scenery, like the internal images of a rotating kaleidoscope in the hands of an eagerly entertained youngster, flashed by in a mixture of shapes and sizes.  Intoxicated by the rush of doing something utterly different, wondering if we had lost all sense of reality, and feeling as if my heart would never be one complete piece again, I found myself with arms wrapped tightly around my chest, rolling sideways down a dew-dampened grassy hillside in the nascent light of day.  It was June some-teenth, 1987, in the middle of our town at the local cemetery on the morning after high school graduation and our senior all-night party, a night which begat a mere two hours of interrupted catnaps in the back of my 1979 Chevy Impala.  Despite feeling as if those few moments were catapulting me into another realm of consciousness, the realization hit me upon my final revolution at the bottom of the hill that my life was to continue without her.  Two teenagers in love, we would, in a few moments, go our separate ways.  Forever.</p>
<p>Nowadays, over two decades later, most memories of my senior-year girlfriend have lost their edge.  No longer do I recall with vivid sharpness the majority of our moments shared, for the twenty-plus intervening years wreak havoc on the everyday details of yesteryear—especially that last year of high school.  Oft I am found wondering if my mind can be trusted to do justice to all that we entailed.  However, I suppose I am accepting of all this diminished recollection and atrophy of nostalgia as a natural process in life.  For the most part, I am willing to chalk it up as inevitable, but there are vestiges of those days that still tenaciously linger in the deepest recesses of my heart.  Years of countless life experiences, thousands of miles literally and figuratively traveled in between, and lovers and loves that have come and gone in my life like cab drivers on a rush-hour Manhattan street all bury images of her under piles of more-easily-recalled, recent sentiment. And even after finding the love of my life, my wife, and knowing that she and I were meant to be through the ages, I can admit that my senior year girlfriend will forever have an indelible place in my heart, if only a fraction of all that I have had and all that I will be.</p>
<p>To have shared a few months of our lives together during that last year of secondary school all came at the right time.  For at least the last year-and-a-half beforehand, I had experienced so many ups and downs with nearly uncontrollable teenage angst, my parent’s disruptive divorce, and a move from New York to Virginia and then back to New York to finish six months of schooling there before graduation.  Though I had a good circle of friends that gave life a good dose of meaning at the time, I was riddled with self-doubt about life, feeling as if I was stuck between perpetually abandoned and incessantly melancholic.  So it was with her, Christine, that I found a sense of adolescent stability, albeit just for a few months towards the end of that year.  We, simply put, had fun.  Events that all senior years comprise were shared.  Good-bye parties.  Prom.  Parties to celebrate our pending manumission.  After school get-togethers.  Parties for the sake of partying.  It was a frenetic, exciting time, for we didn’t have many cares in the world when we walked hand in hand or embraced for hours.</p>
<p>Regardless of the dust-covered cobwebs that mask the details of my relationship with her, moments of<em> us</em> do find their way back to me from time to time.  For instance, she bestowed upon me the nickname “Mr. Hands” at a party one night when we found ourselves in a dark back bedroom with perhaps a dozen other friends surrounding us in semi-privacy.  With no need to detail her rationale, one can suffice it to say that those last weeks before graduation were a frenzy of bonding, emotionally and physically, and that evening was no exception.  Perhaps it was the underlying knowledge that we would soon part ways or maybe just teenage desires manifesting themselves all at once.  Sentimental yearnings like to label it as the former in order to paint such images with a hue of innocence.  Whatever it was, “Mr. Hands” was developing a sense that she was someone with whom he would soon entrust a responsibility of eternal remembrance.</p>
<p>Driving in my car together just to fill time because teenagers had nothing else to do in such a rural town, watching television after school with friends in her family room, and chatting on the phone until day’s end are other hazy recollections of our abridged paragraph in the story of life together, yet none of those times can compare to the events the week of graduation because I had made a decision then to move the day after graduation to Minnesota, a state halfway across the nation—which was, for a provincial teenager, seemingly halfway around the globe.  We had known she was to go to college in New York state later that fall, so we would have, otherwise, only had a few months of summer love to inscribe in our hearts and etch in our psyches, but the pronouncement of my imminent departure to take place the day after graduation immediately terminated any hopes of building more together.  It was with that knowledge that those last few days became profoundly surreal, all leading to a consummation of our teenage hopes and shared desires; two days before graduation, with tears still flowing and cheeks damp from hours of weeping together over our fast-approaching parting of ways, we shared a tenderness that completed our time together.  Within a mere two days, we would say goodbye.  Within a matter of moments, we left an impression on our hearts to last a lifetime.</p>
<p>At sometime during the all-night festivities after graduation earlier that evening, Christine and I danced to Chris Deburgh’s “Lady in Red”.  I felt like a man for the first time, in the full sense of the word, when I looked at her and realized she was herself wearing a red sweater.  I had experienced an unsurpassed intimacy of the heart those few days, so with maturity of foresight, I devised a way to forever remember our time together.  As if I had a pre-destined knowledge of my vagabond lifestyle and waywardly ways awaiting me in the years ahead, I knew that I wanted another substantive, tangible experience with which to connect with her, forever.  Hours later, I drove her to a place that I felt would increase the chance of recollection later in life: the local cemetery.  And it was there that we promised we would forever remember each other at that moment as we lied down in wet grass at the top of a hill to begin our whimsical, rolling descent downward.  Our existence for that moment, the last time I ever saw Christine, was… synchronized.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/202/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/202/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=202&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://vagabondwithfamily.wordpress.com/2012/09/12/synchronized/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/65c900412fe25f2d28109a2b6833ebe2?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">vagabondwithfamily</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://vagabondwithfamily.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/5638122219_92957b9a00_o1.jpg?w=133" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Lady in Red</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Breaking Up and The X</title>
		<link>http://jenibo.com/2012/09/11/breaking-up-and-the-x/</link>
		<comments>http://jenibo.com/2012/09/11/breaking-up-and-the-x/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2012 02:43:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>jenibo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Romance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[breaking up]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[breakup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[college]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pictures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[postaday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The X]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://jenibo.com/?p=1447</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;m lying on my parents&#8217; living room floor with my chin on a crocheted pillow, a stomach full of caramel popcorn, and at least fourteen mosquito bites on my pudgy legs from this past Sunday at Hot Fiance&#8217;s house where we celebrated his mom&#8217;s birthday. Despite the itching and three days of spoiled-brat-part-time-jobbing this week, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1447&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m lying on my parents&#8217; living room floor with my chin on a crocheted pillow, a stomach full of caramel popcorn, and at least fourteen mosquito bites on my pudgy legs from this past Sunday at Hot Fiance&#8217;s house where we celebrated his mom&#8217;s birthday. Despite the itching and three days of spoiled-brat-part-time-jobbing this week, I think I&#8217;ll be okay. I think I can manage to smile a little more, laugh, even, at the pages and pages of journal entries I found time to peruse earlier about an overbearing boyfriend who thought he should come over right away to discuss his feelings about my Myspace conversations with Explorer earlier that year and the way I failed to mention how very close we were to being just slightly more than friends. Like, sorry, The X.</p>
<p><a href="http://jenibo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/09112012e.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1449" title="09112012e" src="http://jenibo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/09112012e.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="507" /></a></p>
<p>Years and years later, I&#8217;d think<em> that was significant</em>. And <em>people need to know about us</em>. I&#8217;d think I should write my thoughts on the nearest Post-It and save it in my purse for the future when I can empathize with The X and remember driving through town one day after school, telling him how much of a Real Boyfriend he looked like when he wore his Ray-Bans.</p>
<p><a href="http://jenibo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/09112012d.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1448" title="09112012d" src="http://jenibo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/09112012d.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="507" /></a></p>
<p>I still have a hard time with that. When we were dating, I told him of a dream I had in which we were in some kind of open car on the highway with a white sheet above us, blowing in the wind. I could see the sun on his face, and he touched mine. We were laughing as he steered with his feet, and I felt safe and cool and as if I&#8217;d be happy there forever. Breaking up was my idea, but that didn&#8217;t mean I wasn&#8217;t hurt or angry for all the times he made me sit on the couch in his two-bedroom apartment picking the feathers out of his pillows while he told me the exact words I should have said to keep from upsetting him. It wasn&#8217;t nice, and I needed to be a lesbian or a murderer to vent my frustration.</p>
<p><a href="http://jenibo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/09112012h.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1452" title="09112012h" src="http://jenibo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/09112012h.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="504" /></a></p>
<p>And the anger makes me feel crazy, so I think I should write a story about a crazy person&#8211;a woman with a good man like Hot Fiance, reason to be upset, and the fear that her mind is no longer her own but a vessel for something she never meant to keep. But I&#8217;ll probably never write it, because all I know about being insane is so Hollywood or teenagery and every reason for illness I can imagine seems so trivial that it just makes me sick and embarrassed for whoever I believe he made me become.</p>
<p><a href="http://jenibo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/09112012f.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1450" title="09112012f" src="http://jenibo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/09112012f.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="497" /></a></p>
<p>I meant to have goals for this month. I wrote these down at work, but stuffed them at the bottom of my purse with all my other grand ideas because I&#8217;m not sure I can follow through and if I can&#8217;t, I don&#8217;t want to be reminded by a Post-It on my mirror that I didn&#8217;t. Hot Fiance is always supportive and suggested I take part in &#8220;<a href="https://twitter.com/#!/search/shaytember" target="_blank">Shaytember</a>&#8221; which I was all for until it begun and all I could think of were stupid goals and Positivity, which I&#8217;m not even sure I agree with.</p>
<p><a href="http://jenibo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/09112012i.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1451" title="09112012i" src="http://jenibo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/09112012i.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="627" /></a></p>
<p>Breaking up with The X was a grueling process that took months. I remember telling him that I needed a holiday, and made sure he listened to this <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rQJOUqh_NxY" target="_blank">song</a>. It was very twenty-ish and juvenile, but his insisting that I stay and my inability to forcefully disagree meant he&#8217;d have to listen to <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RNKDHmNcIvI" target="_blank">this</a> and <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lZmqWBDGCpg" target="_blank">this</a> and <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NPgH56TFsDo" target="_blank">this</a> and <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KMuOZJZlBZY" target="_blank">this</a> (which was not a completely accurate representation of my feelings, but still expressed some of the feelings I could not rightly communicate) until he got the message. Suffice it to say, something worked, and the day I felt we were <em>really</em> broken up was the night he proposed, the night I saw <em>he</em> was the crazy one, the night he threw his cellphone to the pavement in the dark and drove away feeling pretty stupid.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1447/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1447/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1447&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://jenibo.com/2012/09/11/breaking-up-and-the-x/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>28</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/8f4d488f8d779709bbb3056b493070d4?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jenibo</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jenibo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/09112012e.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">09112012e</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jenibo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/09112012d.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">09112012d</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jenibo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/09112012h.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">09112012h</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jenibo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/09112012f.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">09112012f</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jenibo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/09112012i.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">09112012i</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Toronto Film Festival &amp; the Fine Art of Celebrity Stalking</title>
		<link>http://breezyk.wordpress.com/2012/09/11/tiff-and-the-fine-art-of-celebrity-stalking/</link>
		<comments>http://breezyk.wordpress.com/2012/09/11/tiff-and-the-fine-art-of-celebrity-stalking/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2012 13:20:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>breezyk</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[James Franco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Selena Gomez]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TIFF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Toronto]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://breezyk.wordpress.com/?p=3158</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Well folks, it&#8217;s that time of year again: when the red carpets get rolled out, the champagne flows like water and A-List celebs fill the streets of Toronto. No, not my birthday, fools.  Y&#8217;all know Ryan and I prefer to celebrate that with a nice bottle of Beaujolais and a quiet night in: Of course, what I&#8217;m REALLY talking about here is TIFF: the Toronto [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3158&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well folks, it&#8217;s that time of year again: when the red carpets get rolled out, the champagne flows like water and A-List celebs fill the streets of Toronto.</p>
<p>No, not my birthday, fools.  Y&#8217;all know Ryan and I prefer to celebrate that with a nice bottle of Beaujolais and a quiet night in:</p>
<div id="attachment_3174" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 500px"><img class="size-full wp-image-3174 " title="meryan3" src="http://breezyk.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/meryan3.jpg" alt="" width="490" height="312" /><p class="wp-caption-text">&#8220;Oh Ryan- I just love quiet nights in with you. Not even the fact that my head is 3x the size of yours can get in the way of our love&#8221;</p></div>
<p>Of course, what I&#8217;m REALLY talking about here is TIFF: the Toronto International Film Festival.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3180" title="tiff3" src="http://breezyk.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/tiff3.jpg" alt="" width="490" height="245" /></p>
<p>Now for me, film festival time usually means putting my stalkin&#8217; pants on and trawling the streets of Toronto with camera in hand, stopping only to stare in the windows of the Ritz Carlton while making this face:</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3167" title="kimkrazy" src="http://breezyk.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/kimkrazy.jpg" alt="" width="398" height="498" /></p>
<p>Until I get escorted off the premises.</p>
<p>This year, however, I was given the chance to kick my stalking up a notch when my friend Michelle offered  me an extra ticket to the premiere of the movie <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt2101441/"><em>Spring Breakers.</em></a></p>
<p>A chance to see a cool movie and some celebs IRL? Sign me up. Plus, this was totally one of those things you could  post on facebook to make yourself seem all cool and in the &#8220;scene&#8221; when really all you did was shell out 40 bucks and hit &#8220;Refresh&#8221; an exorbitant amount of times on your web browser.</p>
<p>The movie, directed by Harmony Korine, is about four college girls (Selena Gomez, Vanessa Hudgens, Ashley Benson and Rachel Korine) who rob a restaurant in order to fund their spring break trip to Saint Petersburg, Fla. Once there, they wind up hooking up with a corn-rowed, silver toothed drug dealer named &#8220;Alien&#8221; (James Franco) who gets them into some seriously un-Disney sh*t.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-3183" title="springbreakers" src="http://breezyk.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/springbreakers.jpg?w=1024&h=268" alt="" width="1024" height="268" /></p>
<p>Sounds Oscar-worthy, right??</p>
<p>Since my 8-year-old-niece Lola is in love with Selena and for some reason is under the impression that I look exactly like her (ok, I paid her to say it), my ultimate goal was to solidify my role as &#8220;best aunt ever&#8221; by meeting Selena and taking a real photo with her to replace this splitscreen I <del>keep under my pillow and stare at every night</del> made once as a joke for a blog post and never looked at again:</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3161" title="meselenasplitscreen2" src="http://breezyk.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/meselenasplitscreen2.jpg" alt="" width="490" height="281" /></p>
<p>We arrived at the theatre somewhat late and were in a mad rush to pick up our tickets when we were stopped directly in our tracks by an oncoming limo.  The door opened, and out walked Selena Gomez and Vanessa Hudgens. Not even 2 feet away from us.</p>
<p>I was like:<br />
<a href="http://s1094.photobucket.com/albums/i452/breannk1/?action=view&amp;current=faint.gif" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter" style="border:0 currentColor;" src="http://i1094.photobucket.com/albums/i452/breannk1/faint.gif" alt="Photobucket" width="319" height="176" border="0" /></a></p>
<p>Needless to say,  by the time I came to, I totally missed my opportunity to <del>become besties with</del> get a picture with Selena. Good thing I can still buy my niece&#8217;s affection with McDonald&#8217;s and other sh*t she&#8217;s not supposed to have.</p>
<p>Anyway, we watched the red carpet progression for a while, listening to hundreds of tweens shouting &#8220;SELENA I LOVE YOU&#8221; and &#8220;WHERE&#8217;S JUSTIN BIEBER&#8221; before making our way into the movie.</p>
<p>Now, the movie itself was sort of interesting and arty and all, but my enjoyment of it was somewhat hindered by the following factors:</p>
<ul>
<li>apparently they don&#8217;t serve popcorn at TIFF screenings?? Call me un-kla$$y, but for me, a movie without popcorn is like Ice without Coco. It just doesn&#8217;t work.</li>
<li>I had chosen to wear my hair in a sock bun for the event:</li>
</ul>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3181" title="sockbun2" src="http://breezyk.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/sockbun2.jpg" alt="" width="360" height="450" /></p>
<p>which, although incredibly chic and red-carpet looking, also renders it damn near impossible to sit back in your chair like a normal person.</p>
<p>Finally, after an hour and a half of shifting hungrily in my seat, the movie was over and the cast &amp; director came onstage for a brief Q&amp;A.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-3165" title="tiff" src="http://breezyk.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/tiff.jpg?w=922&h=691" alt="" width="922" height="691" /></p>
<p>This was cool, but would have been way MORE fun had my friend not grabbed my hand and pulled it back down whenever I tried to ask one of my many stupid (albeit hilarious) questions.</p>
<p>After the Q&amp;A we hightailed it to the back entrance where we knew the stars would be exiting the theatre. Unfortunately, we weren&#8217;t the only ones who knew the secret and had to jostle into position with hundreds of other fans.</p>
<p>As I got my iPhone out and preset my instagram filter to &#8220;<em>You wish your life was this cool</em>&#8220;, I remembered an interview I saw recently with a 16-year-old American girl known as &#8220;<em>Stalker Sarah</em>&#8220; for her talent of hunting down celebrities and getting her photo taken with them. Sarah has photos with over 5,000 celebrities, and prides herself in knowing all of the best stalking tactics.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3182" title="sarah" src="http://breezyk.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/sarah.jpg" alt="" width="490" height="327" /></p>
<p>As I dodged random elbows and struggled to see past the 6&#8217;4 man in front of me,  I wondered to myself, &#8220;<em>What would Stalker Sarah do?&#8221;&#8230;</em> while at the same time cursing my own name for not having the same alliterative potential.</p>
<p>Un (?)fortunately my question remained rhetorical, because just then the cast busted out of the theatre and <em>Running of the Bulls: Toronto Edition</em> commenced. Somehow I managed to snap the following pic before I met my untimely demise of being trampled to death by a gaggle of crazed Selena Gomez fans:</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-3164" title="selena" src="http://breezyk.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/selena.jpg?w=614&h=819" alt="" width="614" height="819" /></p>
<p>Just kidding. I&#8217;m totally still alive. But what a way to go.</p>
<h2 style="text-align:center;">Question of the Day: Ever been to a movie premiere? Ever had a star sighting?</h2>
<p style="text-align:center;"> </p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3158/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3158/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3158&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://breezyk.wordpress.com/2012/09/11/tiff-and-the-fine-art-of-celebrity-stalking/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>39</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/074733a320f565b357cea64d1720a00b?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">breezyk</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://breezyk.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/meryan3.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">meryan3</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://breezyk.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/tiff3.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tiff3</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://breezyk.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/kimkrazy.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">kimkrazy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://breezyk.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/springbreakers.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">springbreakers</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://breezyk.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/meselenasplitscreen2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">meselenasplitscreen2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://i1094.photobucket.com/albums/i452/breannk1/faint.gif" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Photobucket</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://breezyk.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/sockbun2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sockbun2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://breezyk.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/tiff.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tiff</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://breezyk.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/sarah.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sarah</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://breezyk.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/selena.jpg?w=768" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">selena</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Are Happy Online Personas a Lie or a Matter of Protocol?</title>
		<link>http://godsofadvertising.wordpress.com/2012/09/10/are-perpetually-happy-online-personas-a-big-lie-or-simply-a-matter-of-protocol/</link>
		<comments>http://godsofadvertising.wordpress.com/2012/09/10/are-perpetually-happy-online-personas-a-big-lie-or-simply-a-matter-of-protocol/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2012 14:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Steffan1</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[depression]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online personas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[our true selves]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shiny happy people]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media guidelines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media protocol]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the idealized self]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://godsofadvertising.wordpress.com/?p=6526</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Status update: &#8220;Posing with the Beaver!&#8221; One of the wonders of social media is that it allows us to present only what we want of ourselves to the world. Wrinkles, warts and divorces remain hidden. We put our best face forward and keep ugliness and negativity far from curious eyes. We show only virtues and [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=6526&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://godsofadvertising.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/images1.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-6527" title="images" src="http://godsofadvertising.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/images1.jpg?w=460" alt=""   /></a></p>
<p>Status update: &#8220;Posing with the Beaver!&#8221;</p>
<p>One of the wonders of social media is that it allows us to present only what we want of ourselves to the world. Wrinkles, warts and divorces remain hidden. We put our best face forward and keep ugliness and negativity far from curious eyes. We show only virtues and rarely defects of body and character. Frankly, we are being more than pleasant. We are presenting idealized versions of ourselves: who we aspire to be versus (perhaps) who we really are. Facebook is the textbook example but the myriad other microblogging platforms provide ample camouflage as well. Duh, you say. Why would anyone want to share anything less than bliss in his or her personal life let alone Tweet about it?</p>
<p>The dilemma (if dilemma is even the right word) is that everyone is living a kind of virtual lie and one that grows bigger and deeper with every status update and adorable photograph we upload. Say a gal posts only sugar and spice and everything nice; her idealized self, the woman she hopes to be and wants others to think she is. But what if that same person is, in fact, seriously depressed or even suicidal? Is it a kind of betrayal to her friends and family to be falsely presenting all that positivity? Is it dangerous? On the other hand, is bad news better left unsaid? Does it fall under the category of “too much information?”</p>
<p><a href="http://godsofadvertising.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/images-1.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-6533" title="images-1" src="http://godsofadvertising.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/images-1.jpg?w=460" alt=""   /></a></p>
<p>Status update: &#8220;I ripped Bob&#8217;s face off for betraying me!&#8221;</p>
<p>I don’t know the answer. After all, I’m just as shiny and happy on Facebook as you are. I post photographs of my adorable children just like you do. I am happy. We are “totally enjoying dinner at Café Louise!” Or I am “so looking forward to Lily’s dance recital tomorrow.” And so on. The bitter argument I had with my spouse last night is never communicated. My disdain for dance recitals is avoided like the plague. God forbid my numerous Facebook “friends” think I have challenges at home or am anything less than a perfect husband or father.</p>
<p>Et tu?</p>
<p>When I scroll through your Facebook pages I rarely see anything but delighted and happy people. Sure, you post snarky comments about this politician or that pop star but when it comes to you and yours you are as positive as a Disney Princess.</p>
<p><a href="http://godsofadvertising.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/aa09_18.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-6530" title="AA09_18" src="http://godsofadvertising.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/aa09_18.jpg?w=300&h=200" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a></p>
<p>Status update: &#8220;Gary may be gay but our love will last forever!&#8221;</p>
<p>Some people are braver than others: like the man who shares his battle with cancer or the woman who opens up about her struggle to land a job. So, yes, there are plenty of examples of self-disclosure taking place online. Yet, the vast majority of us don’t “go there.” Our Facebook pages are like a fifties-era sitcom. Sis and Johnny love school and sports and going on vacation. Father’s knows best. And mom is always “That Girl!”</p>
<p>I don’t expect any of us will change this &#8220;Life is Beautiful!&#8221; approach to social networking but I am calling bullshit. Life is messy and complicated. Relationships implode. People get sick and die. Children are maladjusted. In the end shit happens all the time. Just not on Facebook.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/6526/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/6526/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=6526&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://godsofadvertising.wordpress.com/2012/09/10/are-perpetually-happy-online-personas-a-big-lie-or-simply-a-matter-of-protocol/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>59</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/265771772e4a486da4c17fd0014080ed?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">SRP</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://godsofadvertising.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/images1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">images</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://godsofadvertising.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/images-1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">images-1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://godsofadvertising.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/aa09_18.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">AA09_18</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Evolution of a Friend</title>
		<link>http://jefferytodd.wordpress.com/2012/09/06/the-evolution-of-a-friend/</link>
		<comments>http://jefferytodd.wordpress.com/2012/09/06/the-evolution-of-a-friend/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2012 12:49:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>jefferytodd</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Comedy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[changes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Friends]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[friendship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[theater]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://jefferytodd.wordpress.com/?p=447</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Had dinner with my two best buds in Chicago last night and it got me thinking how friendships change over the years. When you&#8217;re a kid it comes down to who has the best stuff. At eight years old, you could have bought my undying devotion if you would have lent me the newest Hot [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=447&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Had dinner with my two best buds in Chicago last night and it got me thinking how friendships change over the years.</p>
<p>When you&#8217;re a kid it comes down to who has the best stuff. At eight years old, you could have bought my undying devotion if you would have lent me the newest Hot Wheel or picked me for baseball. As a teen, getting to ride your mini-bike was the only thing needed to cement our BFF status. Before graduating high school my coolest interaction with a guy was when Rob L. bought me beer cause I let him cheat off  me. What can I say, I needed the status and I had been letting all the pretty girls cheat off me for years-at least I got something this time. Although it was warm and sat in my trunk&#8230;never did drink it.</p>
<p>I wasn&#8217;t one to stay in touch with high school friends, perhaps because I moved away to the city while others stayed in the suburbs or went to college. Or maybe it was the fact that I lost a lot of weight and wanted to lose the old life along with the pounds. Or maybe it was because I went temporarily insane and that&#8217;s also the reason I got married at eighteen.</p>
<p>Whichever the correct choice (c, say it&#8217;s c, c is the right answer, everybody knows it&#8217;s c) I was divorced and onto a new group in my twenties.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration:underline;">The Theater, The Theater</span></p>
<p>These people were shaped by my interest in improvisation and performing. We played theater games, went to experimental theater performances and saw Woody Allen films because we thought cool chicks dug smart guys and if that little dweeb could get the hot girls then, pssh, I mean, come on. And by little dweeb I mean his character in his early films. I have the highest respect for Mr. Allen and I&#8217;ve got a great script if you feel the need to help a new writer get his first film produced.</p>
<p>We laughed. We laughed a lot. When class was over we went to El Jardin for killer margaritas. And then we really laughed. The great thing about a class on a Monday night is that you can get sloppy drunk because you&#8217;re the only ones that are in the restaurant.</p>
<p>But all the fun ends at eight weeks when the class ends. &#8220;Let&#8217;s Keep in Touch&#8221; and  &#8221;I Love You Man&#8221;  fade with the hangover. <img src='http://s0.wp.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif' alt=':)' class='wp-smiley' />   And eventually people drop off. The performing life is a difficult one and very few end up doing it for a living.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Your mama</span>&#8230;</p>
<p>So those that do, end up bonding together. Being in the comedy biz, we don&#8217;t tend to share as much as try to &#8220;one-up&#8221; each other. If you do happen to say something of a personal nature, it will be pounced on faster than Tigger rolled Pooh. The shared connection is the desire to get liquid to spit out of another&#8217;s (or in the greatest victory, everyone&#8217;s) nose. But you can feel the respect when you have a really good one-liner. Usually accompanied by jealousy that you didn&#8217;t think of it first. It&#8217;s a special club being a professional entertainer: it doesn&#8217;t mean you&#8217;re more talented, it means that you stuck it out and you&#8217;re on the phone and in front of your computer doing the work; doing the business of show. As time goes on, you talk about IRA&#8217;s and Google keywords as much as you do about &#8220;bits.&#8221; Eventually my show biz buddies married and had kids and we didn&#8217;t see each other as much. That and I moved twenty three hundred miles away.</p>
<p>So that brings me to the present. I don&#8217;t feel the need to be on all the time like I once did and as an aspiring writer, I want to explore emotion and depth. The majority of the time I do this on a laptop or an iPhone, and since I don&#8217;t have Siri, my thoughts and opinions go unchallenged, meaning I am always right and I&#8217;m brilliant.</p>
<p>But once every few months I have dinner with my boys Don and Thom when in town. We all have different jobs doing our own thing and we&#8217;re comfortable in our skin but still hungry for growth. I&#8217;ve never had an easier time talking to two people. Six months feels like five. We get the obligatory &#8220;what&#8217;s new&#8221; out before we even order and then the conversation darts in and out of all sorts of subjects. The focus goes from one person to the other as if our brains were doormen, tipping their hats and saying &#8220;after you.&#8221; And we do what good guy friends do: who gives a s#*t what you were saying when a pretty girl goes by. That&#8217;s why we always eat at outdoor cafes.</p>
<p>But the most important thing is, these two guys got really &#8220;good stuff&#8221; in their minds and hearts. I&#8217;m lucky to know them.</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://jefferytodd.wordpress.com/category/comedy-2/'>Comedy</a>, <a href='http://jefferytodd.wordpress.com/category/humor-2/'>Humor</a> Tagged: <a href='http://jefferytodd.wordpress.com/tag/changes/'>changes</a>, <a href='http://jefferytodd.wordpress.com/tag/friends/'>Friends</a>, <a href='http://jefferytodd.wordpress.com/tag/friendship/'>friendship</a>, <a href='http://jefferytodd.wordpress.com/tag/theater/'>theater</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/447/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/447/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=447&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://jefferytodd.wordpress.com/2012/09/06/the-evolution-of-a-friend/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/3b5acb1c10aa89fddfd3c8c7df6a1ca0?s=96&#38;d=&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jefferytodd</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Interview with Zadie Smith</title>
		<link>http://theasylum.wordpress.com/2012/09/12/zadie-smith-interview/</link>
		<comments>http://theasylum.wordpress.com/2012/09/12/zadie-smith-interview/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2012 08:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>John Self</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Smith Zadie]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://theasylum.wordpress.com/?p=5546</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Zadie Smith&#8217;s new novel NW was &#8211; mathematically &#8211; one of the longest awaited of the year, and its mixed reception surprised me. For every 850 words of closely-argued praise, there was a crowd of cavils by a normally perceptive critic. I had expected critical near-unanimity on this one, with the only disagreement being which [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=5546&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Zadie Smith&#8217;s new novel <em>NW</em> was &#8211; mathematically &#8211; one of the longest awaited of the year, and its mixed reception surprised me. For every <a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/culture/books/9508844/NW-by-Zadie-Smith-review.html">850 words of closely-argued praise</a>, there was a <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/books/2012/aug/31/nw-zadie-smith-review">crowd of cavils by a normally perceptive critic</a>. I had expected critical near-unanimity on this one, with the only disagreement being which section was best. Anyway the attention paid to the book affirmed that any new work by Zadie Smith is a publishing event, and this time, in my view, a literary event too. I was grateful for the opportunity to ask the author some questions about <em>NW</em> and her writing.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><em>(You can buy any of the books mentioned by Zadie Smith from the excellent independent bookshop <a href="http://booksellercrow.typepad.com/the_bedside_crow/">Bookseller Crow</a> by clicking on the images below.)</em></p>
<p><a href="http://theasylum.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/zadie-smith-nw-2012-use-c-dominique-nabokov-2012.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5559" title="Zadie Smith by Dominique Nabokov, 2012" src="http://theasylum.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/zadie-smith-nw-2012-use-c-dominique-nabokov-2012.jpg" alt="" width="470" height="658" /></a></p>
<p><strong><em>NW</em> is a novel in varied parts, about the lives of very different people in one area of London. Did you always know that their stories would be part of something larger? How did the novel find its form?</strong></p>
<p>I didn’t begin with any stories, really. Just this single idea of a girl coming to the door. The novel found its form slowly, over a long period. I wrote the first lines almost nine years ago. And that’s really how it was built: sentence by sentence, hoping the shape would emerge by itself. But once I had the idea of the girl coming to the door, I started to read around the idea of guests and hosts… and there’s sort of a long philosophical history to those ideas, and inevitably they ended up being a part of the book, and shaping it. And from “Who gets invited?” I went to “Once you’re invited, what kind of hospitality is ideal?” – and that gets you into thinking about utopia and dystopia… And those ideas ended up being another room in the house of the book. It’s hard for me to explain, but I guess as a general rule I find the characters subconsciously, but then the conscious part of a novel are these larger ideas. The whole trick for me is not to let the ideas overwhelm that subconscious work, which is where I feel the real life of the thing is. But perhaps for 90 percent of readers all the larger framework goes unnoticed and all they see is a lot of uncouth Kilburn people, talking… I can never tell. It doesn’t really matter. I think that’s just the risk you take when you shape a novel round the present. People distrust the present – it looks formless, unserious. They want the security of the past, and of familiar forms.</p>
<p><a href="http://booksellercrow.moonfruit.com/#/johnselfzadiesmith/4568650657"><img class="aligncenter size-thumbnail wp-image-5602" title="Zadie Smith: NW (click to buy from Bookseller Crow)" src="http://theasylum.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/zadiesmith_big1.jpg?w=99&h=150" alt="" width="99" height="150" /></a></p>
<p><strong>Much of the strength of the book lies in the way it reports communication between characters, particularly those of different social and cultural backgrounds. Is <em>NW</em> a state-of-England (or part of it) novel?</strong></p>
<p>I find that idea really boring: ‘state of the nation’. It’s one of those phrases that people who secretly dislike fiction use to pretend a novel is just a spring board to enter into some other, less embarrassing discussion: a political analysis or a sociological portrait. I really don’t presume to know the state of England. I’m a fiction writer. I’m interested in trying to find ways to depict experience through a medium that can never succeed in depicting experience fully: language. It’s a fool’s task, but I know that the pleasure I have as a reader is watching different writers attempt it. And this is just my attempt, to add to all the attempts by others that have come before it. Of course some of that experience involves ‘having been born and bred in England,’ but a sense of place is just one part of a larger concern, as it is with all novelists, no matter where they were born. How does language feel to hear and use? How does time feel? How can we know other people are real and not just projections of our own desires or fears? What does the thought of death do to us? These are the sort of vulgar, childlike question that novelists ask – at least, the kind of novelists I’m interested in. Because it’s just so odd to be alive! And fiction is about that. I think all good novels are about “the state of being alive.” Trying to make them act as national sociological descriptors isn’t the worst crime in the world, but focusing on that aspect ignores the very particular linguistic thingyness of the form. To me writing is deeply irrational, idiosyncratic, because its medium – language – has so much ambiguity built into it. That argument that Alice and Humpty Dumpty have about the instability of meaning that’s the epigraph of a million graduate dissertations… Language is the absurd bit of writing that can’t be entirely suppressed or controlled by journalistic ideas like ‘state of the nation’ novels. Maybe the phrase, if it’s used at all, is best used satirically, as Amis used it.</p>
<p>Sometimes it feels that in England and America especially there is this desire that the novel behave itself and exist as only a sort of mildly creative interpretation of the news. Faction. Solid, recognizable, like a TV sitcom written down. But a novel <em>should</em> have a little witchcraft in it, don’t you think? It should be a little weird. It should try to do something that can <em>only </em>be done in <em>this </em>form, in language.</p>
<p><strong>When reading <em>NW</em>, I thought of other books. <em>London Fields </em>(obviously), which is similarly controlled in its prose yet enacts the messiness of life even as it portrays it. Or Evan S Connell&#8217;s <em>Mrs Bridge</em>, which like the &#8216;Host&#8217; section in <em>NW</em>, makes up a whole life in short discrete scenes. Does the book have any direct literary inspirations or influences?</strong></p>
<p>Hmmm… When I think of <em>London Fields</em> I think of <em>White Teeth</em>. And there the influence is direct. But nothing could have been further from my mind writing <em>NW</em> than <em>London Fields&#8230;</em> I see books in terms of their sentences and to me the sentences of <em>White Teeth</em> and <em>NW</em> are really from different planets! But this may be my own delusion. In the end, you have to defer to readers: you can’t instruct them to see a sentence your way – they have to see it themselves.</p>
<p>Anyway, <em>Mrs Bridge</em> was certainly in there, though perhaps not as much as Roland Barthes&#8217; autobiography, Raymond Queneau’s variations, and various books of epigraphs I was reading. I became envious of that numbered structure – and then it seemed to suit Natalie so perfectly, with her determination to march boldly into the future. Originally her section was in a sort of fractured first person. Everyone who read it hated it – me included. Then another writer said to me: “You’re the only writer I know who can create no sympathy in the first person.” I thought: that’s right! When I write the pronoun “I”, I think of myself and end up being incredibly cruel. I’m not sympathetic to myself, as it turns out. I need the she and he.</p>
<p><a href="http://booksellercrow.moonfruit.com/#/johnselfzadiesmith/4568650657"><img class="aligncenter size-thumbnail wp-image-5603" title="Evan S. Connell: Mrs Bridge (click to buy from Bookseller Crow)" src="http://theasylum.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/images.jpeg?w=97&h=150" alt="" width="97" height="150" /></a></p>
<p><strong><em>NW</em> is on the one hand psychologically acute and strongly character-driven, but also experiments with form and content &#8211; it&#8217;s littered with up-to-date cultural references, has typographical trickery and surprising appearances of the way we live now (such as a chapter made of Google Maps directions). Do these elements come easily? Or is &#8220;<a href="http://www.newstatesman.com/fiction/2009/12/novel-culture-smith-wood">the culture doing strange things to novels</a>&#8220;?</strong></p>
<p>Oh, not so strange. You could find far, far stranger in 1918 or 1761. Nothing new under the sun. The novel has always been a weird form, full of oddities. If there’s trickery in this one, I’m sorry for it: I genuinely wanted to try and get closer to reality, not to obscure it. I mean, look: a version of the most realistic novel possible right now would be the one that took into account the fact that for much of each day in the west, the consciousness of many of us is projected outwards into a 14-inch lit screen, and any thought we have constantly penetrated by news, trivia, gossip, adverts, glimpses of content, and email, always email. I can’t figure out a way to do that, but some younger writer will. Not in the dull manner of ‘putting emails in a novel’ but some organic and genuine way of representing that reality. And stuff like that will always be called ‘trickery’ and accused of shallowness and then fifty years later it will be understood as pure realism. I remember David Foster Wallace saying somewhere that his ‘real’ life did not involve walking by a stream, pausing under an apple tree and having a deep internal monologue about the nature of the world – yet that’s what his fiction teacher expected of him and it’s true to this day that much contemporary fiction hangs upon what are actually quite unrealistic premises. But people still call it realism and think of it as completely ‘natural,’ not strange at all. To me it’s a little strange.</p>
<p>The same goes – at the most banal level – for content. When I first started writing, people often asked why I insisted on this ‘multicultural’ cast. To them it was a publishing ‘angle’ or some kind of post-modern trick. Slowly you realize: <em>these people live in an entirely white social world. </em>So to them it probably <em>is </em>exotic, it <em>is </em>an angle. I had interviewers – especially abroad – congratulating me on the “trendiness” of my family, as if I had picked out a black mother and a white father for fashion purposes. But to me what’s exotic is a world in which everyone is white. I’ve never lived in that world. Being mixed race is not some kind of gimmick: a third of the kids in my school had families like that, and nothing could have been more dull to all of us, more everyday. I remember, too, the shock of reading reviews that took it for granted that Willesden is a sort of piteous place to live, unutterably ‘grim.’ And if a character of mine isn’t living in a four storey house in Hampstead their lives are also described as ‘grim,’ or brutally modern, or whatever. It makes you wonder: where do these reviewers <em>come </em>from? This is just bog standard London life I’m describing, the lives of millions. But perhaps the only ‘moral’ of my fiction is that one person’s strange is another person’s normal.</p>
<p><a href="http://booksellercrow.moonfruit.com/#/johnselfzadiesmith/4568650657"><img class="aligncenter size-thumbnail wp-image-5604" title="Roland Barthes by Roland Barthes (click to buy from Bookseller Crow)" src="http://theasylum.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/images-1.jpeg?w=100&h=150" alt="" width="100" height="150" /></a></p>
<p><strong>Your essay &#8216;Two Directions for the Novel&#8217; attracted much attention, contrasting lyrical realism (in Joseph O&#8217;Neill&#8217;s <em>Netherland</em>) with the &#8216;alternative road&#8217; of Tom McCarthy&#8217;s <em>Remainder</em>. Where do you place your own work in this context?</strong></p>
<p>I don’t really. The critic in me and the writer in me are two different people. The critic writes of what she would ideally like to read; the writer only writes what she can. Criticism is easy; fiction hard. I know what I’m doing when I write an essay. I have no idea what I’m doing when I write a novel. Fiction is a much riskier enterprise.</p>
<p>And then that essay is a polemic, and describes what I felt, at the time, to be an extreme situation in publishing. I think China Miéville – my Kilburn neighbour! – said recently that English fiction tends to privilege recognition over strangeness and alienation, and I think that has often been true. Personally I adore the recognition Jane Austen provides but I also love the strangeness of B.S. Johnson or Octavia Butler. In “healthy” times there’s no need for the polemic: it’s a wide church and both types of writers can exist perfectly happily in there. But it didn’t seem to me to be a very healthy time. I think it’s got a little better, at least from the books that I’m being sent. And the ideal – as I think I said in the essay – are those books that defy all categorization, that are great on their own idiosyncratic terms. I was describing two particular paths in the tradition of the novel, but what marks the most interesting novels is their absolute particularity. You can’t pin them down so easily. What kind of a novel is <em>Invisible Cities</em>? What kind of novel is [Naipaul's] <em>Half a Life? </em>I’m afraid real writing laughs in the face of polemical essays. They were rare four hundred years ago, two hundred years ago, fifty years ago, yesterday – great books will always be rare. <em>Lolita</em> doesn’t come around every day. <em>Heart of Darkness</em> doesn’t come around every day. Most novels are just “good enough”, and given that this is so, shouldn’t they be welcomed in their full variety? Great writing comes in a trickle, not a flood. And we’re not so drowning in riches that we can afford to dam up certain tributaries.</p>
<p>As for my own writing, I’m surprised to find I’m quite excited about the future, which I’ve never really been before. <em>NW</em> feels like my first novel in some ways, maybe because it’s the first I’ve written as what my mother would call “a grown ass woman.” So I’m just going to keep on shuffling down my own path, wherever it leads me. The next novel I have in mind is actually a sort of speculative fiction, set in the future, so I don’t know where that lies along those two paths. I don’t think I care!</p>
<p><a href="http://booksellercrow.moonfruit.com/#/johnselfzadiesmith/4568650657"><img class="aligncenter size-thumbnail wp-image-5605" title="Italo Calvino: Invisible Cities (click to buy from Bookseller Crow)" src="http://theasylum.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/unknown.jpeg?w=114&h=150" alt="" width="114" height="150" /></a></p>
<p><strong>As a reader, I&#8217;ve discovered that since becoming a parent, limited reading time means I&#8217;m much less forgiving of – or willing to continue with – mediocre books. Does parenthood have any comparable effect on writing? Are the short sections of <em>NW</em> an effect of this?</strong></p>
<p>Sure. But that makes it sound purely practical. To me, the intense awareness of time that parenthood creates makes a different person of you, and necessarily a different writer. I hate waste of all kinds now. I hate padding. I want only essential things. A good analogy is party-going. I love to drink and I love to dance. I didn’t used to need an excuse to do those things. But now it better be the best party that man has ever invented, otherwise I ain’t going. Otherwise I’m not paying the babysitter, enduring the tears, texting to check the child hasn’t died, and so on and so forth. The same logic works on the page. If I’m going to write it, it better be a necessary word. It better be essential. Because otherwise I could be hanging out with my family, which most days is about infinity times more enjoyable than struggling over a paragraph in the library.</p>
<p><strong>Parenthood is also a central subject in <em>NW</em>. Is this something that came from the essence of the characters Leah and Natalie, or from a desire to write about something prominent in your own life?</strong></p>
<p>I began the book five years before I had a child. That seems to be a pattern with me. <em>On Beauty</em> is about a marriage of thirty years standing, but at the time I had been married only two. I don’t know the reasons. You’d have to ask a psychiatrist.</p>
<p><strong>Can you recommend an overlooked book or author for readers of this blog?</strong></p>
<p>I don’t know if it’s overlooked, but someone just recommended it to me and I’m enjoying it. It’s got a great title, too: <em>How to make love to a negro without getting tired </em>by Dany Laferrière.</p>
<p><a href="http://booksellercrow.moonfruit.com/#/johnselfzadiesmith/4568650657"><img class="aligncenter size-thumbnail wp-image-5606" title="Dany Lafferière: How to Make Love to a Negre Without Getting Tired (click to buy from Bookseller Crow)" src="http://theasylum.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/images-2.jpeg?w=112&h=150" alt="" width="112" height="150" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5546/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5546/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=5546&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://theasylum.wordpress.com/2012/09/12/zadie-smith-interview/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>24</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/8ccf7ad01ccdf883eddf4d553e0ac319?s=96&#38;d=monsterid&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">johnself</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theasylum.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/zadie-smith-nw-2012-use-c-dominique-nabokov-2012.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Zadie Smith by Dominique Nabokov, 2012</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theasylum.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/zadiesmith_big1.jpg?w=99" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Zadie Smith: NW (click to buy from Bookseller Crow)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theasylum.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/images.jpeg?w=97" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Evan S. Connell: Mrs Bridge (click to buy from Bookseller Crow)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theasylum.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/images-1.jpeg?w=100" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Roland Barthes by Roland Barthes (click to buy from Bookseller Crow)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theasylum.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/unknown.jpeg?w=114" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Italo Calvino: Invisible Cities (click to buy from Bookseller Crow)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theasylum.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/images-2.jpeg?w=112" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Dany Lafferière: How to Make Love to a Negre Without Getting Tired (click to buy from Bookseller Crow)</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Imagine: How Did This Happen?</title>
		<link>http://allaboutwork.org/2012/09/09/imagine-how-did-this-happen/</link>
		<comments>http://allaboutwork.org/2012/09/09/imagine-how-did-this-happen/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2012 01:10:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>allaboutwork.org</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creative]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[organizations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[publishing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://allaboutwork.org/?p=543</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This past week, I had the opportunity to read Jonah Lehrer’s Imagine -  the book that’s part of the controversy about plagiarism and fabrication in Lehrer’s writing. Imagine has been pulled by its publisher as a result of that controversy, so pointing out additional problems with it may now be somewhat redundant. (The copy I [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=543&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This past week, I had the opportunity to read Jonah Lehrer’s <a title="Imagine page on Lehrer's website" href="http://www.jonahlehrer.com/books/imagine/" target="_blank"><em>Imagine</em></a> -  the book that’s part of the controversy about <a title="Edward Champion's analysis of Lehrer's writings" href="http://www.edrants.com/how-jonah-lehrer-recycled-his-own-material-for-imagine" target="_blank">plagiarism</a> and <a title="Michael Moynihan's article on Lehrer's fabricated Bob Dylan quotes" href="http://www.tabletmag.com/jewish-news-and-politics/107779/jonah-lehrers-deceptions" target="_blank">fabrication</a> in Lehrer’s writing. <em>Imagine</em> has been <a title="Houghton Mifflin offers refunds to Imagine purchasers" href="http://paidcontent.org/2012/08/02/lehrers-publisher-runs-ads-telling-bookstores-to-send-back-imagine-for-a-refund/" target="_blank">pulled by its publisher</a> as a result of that controversy, so pointing out additional problems with it may now be somewhat redundant. (The copy I read came from my public library.) Nevertheless, after reading it, I want to outline the problems I found with the referencing in the book &#8211; an area which other commentators <a title="Michael Moynihan suggests that Imagine has referencing problems" href="http://www.twitlonger.com/show/ilk1jt" target="_blank">have also raised concerns about</a>.<span id="more-543"></span></p>
<p>I have a professional interest in <a title="my Canadian Journal of Administrative Sciences article about reports on the Hawthorne studies" href="http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1936-4490.2005.tb00368.x/abstract" target="_blank">how scientific research findings get communicated to general audiences</a>, but as a reader I&#8217;m in some disbelief that a book with this many obvious problems ever got published as it is.  The fact that it did goes beyond the <a title="Update: “Self-Plagiarising” Writer Admits to Fabricating Quotes" href="http://allaboutwork.org/2012/07/30/update-self-plagiarising-writer-admits-fabricating-quotes/">ethical debates around Lehrer’s own conduct</a>, and should make publishers question their editorial processes and where they choose to invest resources in a project.</p>
<p>Referencing in non-fiction writing is important. It’s important because:</p>
<ul>
<li>it gives factual support to the writer’s claims;</li>
<li>it demonstrates that the writer is familiar enough with existing knowledge about the subject to be able to make an informed contribution of new knowledge;</li>
<li>it tells readers who want to learn more about the subject where they can find other sources of information; and,
<p><div id="attachment_546" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 287px"><a href="http://allaboutworkdotorg.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_1945.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-546 " title="IMG_1945" src="http://allaboutworkdotorg.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_1945.jpg?w=277&h=300" alt="" width="277" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">An example of a reference list</p></div></li>
<li>it gives credit where credit is due for work by other writers or researchers.</li>
</ul>
<p>Accurate referencing is particularly important for a book like <em>Imagine</em>, which positions itself as an investigation of the “science of creativity”. Since no single author or researcher could possibly cover this huge subject on their own, they’re going to have to draw on other sources for at least some of their material &#8211; and those sources need to be acknowledged. <em> </em></p>
<p><em>Imagine </em>is written for a popular (non-scientist) audience, so obviously it shouldn’t be held to the same rigorous standard of referencing as, say, a scientific research article in a peer-reviewed academic journal. However, the book does include a reference list (p. 255-263), so to some extent it sets its own standard that referencing is expected. If a book is structured to include a reference list, it’s reasonable for the reader to expect that everything in the book that should be referenced <em>is</em> going to be referenced, and is going to be referenced accurately.</p>
<p>Before I outline what I found, I’ll present a few disclaimers/boundaries. I am not trained as a neuroscientist, so I can’t tell whether the neuroscience research described in <em>Imagine</em> is accurately reported or referenced, and I can&#8217;t address the <a title="article on selective presentations of research in Imagine and other popular science works" href="http://www.alternet.org/jonah-lehrer-and-problems-pithy-science-writing?paging=off" target="_blank">allegations of selective &#8220;cherry-picking&#8221; from that body of research.</a>  Instead, I checked the reference list while I was reading the book, and I marked points in the text where I thought there should have been a reference &#8211; and there wasn’t &#8211; or where I felt that a referenced topic was close enough to my own expertise that I could reasonably assess whether the referenced material was accurately reported.</p>
<p>The first problematic reference in <em>Imagine </em>is within its first few pages, on page xvi of the Introduction:  “A recent survey of psychology papers published between 1950 and 2000 revealed that less than 1 percent of them investigated aspects of the creative process”. Clearly, this statement should have a reference, since it reports factual material from a secondary source. But there is no reference included in the book’s reference list.  So I ran a search using five <a title="EbscoHost homepage" href="http://www.ebscohost.com/" target="_blank">EbscoHost</a> reference databases (PsycInfo, PsycArticles, Academic Search Premier, Business Source Complete, and ERIC) that include psychology journals, as well as searching <a title="Google Scholar &quot;about&quot; page" href="http://scholar.google.com/intl/en/scholar/about.html" target="_blank">Google Scholar</a> - and I could not find a published article that fit all of the identifiers of the study as described in the sentence. The sentence contributes to setting up the premise of the book:  i.e., “how creativity works” hasn&#8217;t been extensively researched, so the book&#8217;s contribution is to examine this important yet overlooked topic.  Given this premise, the lack of a reference for this study is, in my opinion, a serious omission.</p>
<p>Other problems that I found relating to referencing published academic research:</p>
<ul>
<li>Page 140 includes a discussion of research on trends in scientific production. The referenced article is <a title="abstract of Jones (2007) &quot;Burden of Knowledge&quot;" href="http://restud.oxfordjournals.org/content/76/1/283.abstract" target="_blank">this one</a>. However, from the description of the article’s contents and findings, it appears that the article actually being discussed is <a title="Wuchty, Jones &amp; Uzzi (2007) &quot;The Increasing Dominance of Teams&quot;" href="http://www.sciencemag.org/content/316/5827/1036.abstract" target="_blank">this one</a>.</li>
<li>Page 141 contains a discussion of an “epic study of nearly every musical produced on Broadway between 1877 and 1990, analyzing the teams behind 2,258 different productions”. The study in the <a title="Uzzi &amp; Spiro (2007) &quot;Collaboration and Creativity&quot;" href="http://www.jstor.org/discover/10.1086/432782?uid=2134&amp;uid=2&amp;uid=70&amp;uid=4&amp;sid=21101171862251" target="_blank">referenced article</a> looked at musicals produced from 1945 to 1989, and examined 474 musicals with 2,092 participants.</li>
<li>A discussion starting on page 162 describes a research study on the effects of dissent on group decision making, and explains how subjects were placed in groups and asked to answer questions, with a “plant” in some groups shouting a wrong answer. The <a title="Nemeth &amp; Ormiston (2007) &quot;Creative Idea Generation&quot;" href="http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/ejsp.373/abstract" target="_blank">referenced study</a> investigates the impact of stable or changing group membership on a group’s creativity. It does not report on an experiment structured like the one described.</li>
</ul>
<p>Three other academic studies that were mentioned did not have references.</p>
<p>There are also problems with incomplete or inaccurate references to other types of sources. For example:</p>
<ul>
<li> Keith Johnstone, a theatrical improvisation teacher, is quoted directly on page 103. The source of the quote is not referenced. A Google search indicates that Malcolm Gladwell uses the same quote in his book <a title="publisher's website for Malcolm Gladwell's Blink" href="http://www.hachettebookgroup.com/books_9780316004992.htm" target="_blank">Blink</a>. I do not have a copy of that book, so I could not determine if a source was identified there.</li>
<li>Page 108 contains a discussion of how Rolling Stones guitarist Keith Richards came up with the guitar riff for the song Satisfaction. There is no reference for the direct quotes, although there’s contextual information that makes <a title="NPR's Terry Gross interviews Keith Richards, 2010" href="http://www.npr.org/templates/transcript/transcript.php?storyId=130722581" target="_blank">the source</a> relatively easy to find. However, there is a discrepancy between the content of the direct quotes in the source transcript and the content of the direct quotes in <em>Imagine</em>:</li>
</ul>
<blockquote><p><em>Imagine</em>: “There, in some sort of ghostly version, is the opening of a song.”<br />
<em>NPR transcript</em>: “There, in some sort of ghostly version, is (singing) da, da, da, da, da &#8211; I can&#8217;t get no satisfaction.”</p></blockquote>
<ul>
<li>Footnote 3 on page 101 describes the “cinematic improv” of actor Mike Myers in a scene in an Austin Powers film (the Austin Powers film containing the scene is not identified, but it’s fairly easy to discover through Google that it’s <a title="IMDB listing for Austin Powers: International Man of Mystery" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0118655/" target="_blank">the first one</a>). However, there’s no reference for the assertion that “Myers made it up on the spot”. According to <a title="director Jay Roach discusses the &quot;shhh&quot; scene in the first Austin Powers film" href="http://www.dga.org/Craft/DGAQ/All-Articles/0902-Summer-2009/Interview-Jay-Roach.aspx" target="_blank">this interview with the film’s director,</a> the basis of the scene was spontaneous, but what appeared in the film was not constructed quite in the way that <em>Imagine</em> suggests it was.</li>
</ul>
<div id="attachment_547" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 276px"><a href="http://allaboutworkdotorg.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_1946.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-547 " title="IMG_1946" src="http://allaboutworkdotorg.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_1946.jpg?w=266&h=300" alt="" width="266" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">An example of a reference list</p></div>
<p>And finally, I found four factual statements (e.g. on page 180: “the United States, for example, is 81 percent urbanized”) that were not referenced, along with two instances of discrepancy between the information in the text and the information in the reference. There are also extended discussions of three topics &#8211; the development of Silicon Valley, the creative process at Pixar, and Shakespeare’s creative inspirations -  which only have general references to secondary sources and/or to author interviews, making it difficult to determine which material is from the secondary sources and which material is the author’s own work.</p>
<p>All of these problems &#8211; in addition to <a title="article on problems with Imagine" href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10000872396390444226904577559322045607092.html" target="_blank">the other problems in <em>Imagine</em> that have already been identified</a> &#8211; seriously make me question how this book ever got published as it is.</p>
<p>In <em>Imagine</em>’s acknowledgements (p. 265-267), Lehrer thanks an editor, a number of readers who reviewed drafts of various parts of the book, and a copy editor. It’s entirely possible that some of those readers looked at conceptual or structural issues, and thus missed any referencing problems.  I don’t know the specific details of the editorial or production process that <em>Imagine</em> went through – but I find it disturbing that apparently there was no point in the process when the references in the reference list were cross-verified with the text, or when unreferenced material was identified and flagged for correction.</p>
<p>I am not sure what lesson the publishing industry will take away from the saga of <em>Imagine</em>, other than being very careful with any subsequent work by its author. But <a title="commentary on book publishing and the current state of fact checking" href="http://www.emilywillinghamphd.com/2012/07/bob-dylan-jonah-lehrer-nonfiction.html" target="_blank">as this commentator indicates</a>, the publishing industry has put itself at risk for these kinds of catastrophes by cutting back or eliminating fact-checking resources. I suppose I fall into the particular sub-category of reader that Willingham describes as having “an eye for detail” &#8211; but, in fairness, for many of the referencing problems I identified in <em>Imagine</em>, I was able to find the correct information in less than a few seconds through Google. And using a research database to search journal content is not that much different from running a Google search. Neither kind of search is particularly time-consuming, highly skilled, or prohibitively expensive.</p>
<p>Hopefully, another lesson of the <em>Imagine</em> story for publishers will be that investing in fact-checking is worth the cost – not only to avoid the financial and reputational consequences of uncorrected errors, but also to be sure that authors are fulfilling their part of the responsibility for the accuracy of their work.</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://allaboutwork.org/category/business/'>business</a>, <a href='http://allaboutwork.org/category/creative/'>creative</a>, <a href='http://allaboutwork.org/category/media/'>media</a>, <a href='http://allaboutwork.org/category/organizations/'>organizations</a>, <a href='http://allaboutwork.org/category/publishing/'>publishing</a>, <a href='http://allaboutwork.org/category/research/'>research</a>, <a href='http://allaboutwork.org/category/writing/'>writing</a> Tagged: <a href='http://allaboutwork.org/tag/business/'>business</a>, <a href='http://allaboutwork.org/tag/creative/'>creative</a>, <a href='http://allaboutwork.org/tag/media/'>media</a>, <a href='http://allaboutwork.org/tag/publishing/'>publishing</a>, <a href='http://allaboutwork.org/tag/research/'>research</a>, <a href='http://allaboutwork.org/tag/writing/'>writing</a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=543&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://allaboutwork.org/2012/09/09/imagine-how-did-this-happen/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/7c21e89ac0b384696f36295093685b20?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">fionamcquarrie</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://allaboutworkdotorg.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_1945.jpg?w=277" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_1945</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://allaboutworkdotorg.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_1946.jpg?w=266" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_1946</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Convoluted Paths and Shakespeare, Sonnet 29</title>
		<link>http://trophos.wordpress.com/2012/09/10/convoluted-paths-and-william-shakespeare-sonnet-29/</link>
		<comments>http://trophos.wordpress.com/2012/09/10/convoluted-paths-and-william-shakespeare-sonnet-29/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2012 04:09:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>trophos</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[around Phila]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[identity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[language]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[literature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[philadelphia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shakespeare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sonnet]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://trophos.wordpress.com/?p=1225</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Another mellow Sunday &#8211; although one on which I will not, as I did last week, forget to include a poem! The husband and I went downtown to check out the Philly Greenfest (or some such). It mostly wasn&#8217;t aimed at us &#8211; I mean, we are pretty much dirty hippies as far as our [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1225&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://trophos.wordpress.com/2012/09/10/convoluted-paths-and-william-shakespeare-sonnet-29/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>30</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/bfa14f44576ba18fca228c9a49d6a7a0?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F2.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">trophos</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What Makes a Post Freshly Press-able: The Rise of eBooks—Evil or Essential?</title>
		<link>http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2012/09/12/what-makes-a-post-freshly-press-able-the-rise-of-ebooks-evil-or-essential/</link>
		<comments>http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2012/09/12/what-makes-a-post-freshly-press-able-the-rise-of-ebooks-evil-or-essential/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2012 13:58:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Cheri Lucas</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Freshly Pressed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tactics/Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[better blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tips]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dailypost.wordpress.com/?p=10114</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Every day, 19 WordPressers are featured on the Freshly Pressed section of WordPress.com. And every day, many more wonder, “What do I have to do to get Freshly Pressed?” Well, it’s time to reveal what the folks who push the launch button are thinking. Each week, a member of our editorial team will do a [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=10114&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Every day, 19 WordPressers are featured on the Freshly Pressed section of WordPress.com. And every day, many more wonder, “What do I have to do to get Freshly Pressed?”</em></p>
<p><em>Well, it’s time to reveal what the folks who push the launch button are thinking. Each week, a member of our editorial team will do a close-up on one post and why we thought it was Press-worthy. We hope we can provide insight into the process and give you tips and tools to make your blog the best it can be.<br />
</em>_________________________________________________________</p>
<p>We love when a blogger jumps head first into a debate and uses their blog as a forum, and that&#8217;s exactly what Clare, the writer behind <a href="http://cer90cer.wordpress.com">A Little Blog of Books and Other Stuff</a>, does with the recently Freshly Pressed post, <a href="http://cer90cer.wordpress.com/2012/08/28/the-rise-of-ebooks-evil-or-essential/#">&#8220;The Rise of eBooks: Evil or Essential?&#8221;</a></p>
<p>First of all, Clare&#8217;s writing is solid, the humor is sharp, and her voice is authoritative. Good, confident writing goes a long way. But what else stands out?</p>
<p><span id="more-10114"></span></p>
<h2><a href="http://dailypost.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/screen-shot-2012-09-06-at-10-17-07-pm.png"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-10127" title="Screen shot 2012-09-06 at 10.17.07 PM" src="http://dailypost.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/screen-shot-2012-09-06-at-10-17-07-pm.png?w=300&h=180" alt="" width="300" height="180" /></a>The post title poses a question.</h2>
<p>Sensationalist headlines can be intriguing:</p>
<p><em>Is Facebook Making Us Lonely? </em></p>
<p><em>Can Your Jeans Kill You?</em></p>
<p>The title &#8220;<em>The Rise of eBooks: Evil or Essential?&#8221;</em> is just as attention-grabbing. If you&#8217;re presenting two sides of a debate, whether it&#8217;s a controversial political issue or a lighthearted discussion on chocolate versus vanilla, pique your reader&#8217;s interest immediately in the title. Be bold and brief: use this headline to reveal what your discussion will be about.</p>
<p>In this case, since many people already have an opinion on the topic of eBooks (and the value of printed books), asking a simple yet provocative question is a surefire way to lure a reader.</p>
<p>This type of title isn&#8217;t appropriate for all posts, but it can be effective when you&#8217;re weighing the pros and cons of something, or asking your reader to consider different perspectives.</p>
<h2><a href="http://dailypost.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/screen-shot-2012-09-06-at-10-16-43-pm.png"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-10128" title="Screen shot 2012-09-06 at 10.16.43 PM" src="http://dailypost.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/screen-shot-2012-09-06-at-10-16-43-pm.png?w=300&h=179" alt="" width="300" height="179" /></a>The format is effective.</h2>
<p>A clean, easy-to-follow format is the simplest way to keep a reader happy and engaged with your text until the end. Clare presents the disadvantages and advantages of eBooks in a series of short, snappy paragraphs, each with lead-in sentences in bold. As a result, each point she makes is clear.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;re writing a post like this in which you&#8217;re presenting numerous points, avoid long paragraphs that don&#8217;t allow your readers to breathe. Consider using a bullet or numbered list to keep your post focused and succinct. Or, experiment with the use of bold, italicized, and underlined fonts to draw attention to specific parts of your discussion.</p>
<h2>The author allows you to decide for yourself.</h2>
<p>At the time of writing, this post had nearly 350 comments—a fair amount of which are personal, passionate comments about reading and publishing. Why did this post generate such a healthy, lively discussion? One, the Clare&#8217;s take is opinionated but extremely balanced: she presents both sides—as well as a &#8220;neutral point&#8221; at the end—allowing readers to come to their own conclusions. Two, she ends the post with questions:</p>
<blockquote><p>What do you think? Are you a total convert to e-readers or do you remain devoted to the humble paperback?</p></blockquote>
<p>As you can see, you can engage your readers when you give them the space to express their opinions.</p>
<p>What did you think of this Freshly Pressed pick? Do you want to read more from this blogger?</p>
<p><em>For more on our Freshly Pressed content, check out <a href="http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2012/09/05/what-makes-a-post-freshly-press-able-los-rodriguez-life/">last week’s Freshly Press-able post</a>, read our roundup of <a href="http://en.blog.wordpress.com/2012/09/04/freshly-pressed-editors-picks-for-august-2012/">Editors’ Picks for August</a>, or read <a href="http://en.support.wordpress.com/freshly-pressed/">So You Want to Be Freshly Pressed</a>.</em></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/10114/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/10114/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=10114&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2012/09/12/what-makes-a-post-freshly-press-able-the-rise-of-ebooks-evil-or-essential/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>49</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/36207d4c7c014b0999b995ca3971d383?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">CL</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dailypost.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/screen-shot-2012-09-06-at-10-17-07-pm.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen shot 2012-09-06 at 10.17.07 PM</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dailypost.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/screen-shot-2012-09-06-at-10-16-43-pm.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen shot 2012-09-06 at 10.16.43 PM</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>On Bach &amp; Music</title>
		<link>http://poojabharat.wordpress.com/2012/09/10/on-bach-music-part-1/</link>
		<comments>http://poojabharat.wordpress.com/2012/09/10/on-bach-music-part-1/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2012 06:59:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>ilovetabascosauce</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chaconne]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Clara Schumann]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[classical music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coetzee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gene Weingarten]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Johann Sebastian Bach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joshua Bell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thoughts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[views]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://poojabharat.wordpress.com/?p=630</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I have been listening to Bach&#8217;s Ciaconna in D Minor, the infamous Chaconne, on loop recently. This piece comes like a punch to the face at the end of Bach&#8217;s Partita No. 2, the last and longest movement of five. I first learnt about it in this article, a famous one called &#8216;Pearls Before Breakfast&#8216; by [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=630&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I have been listening to Bach&#8217;s Ciaconna in D Minor, the infamous Chaconne, on loop recently. This piece comes like a punch to the face at the end of Bach&#8217;s Partita No. 2, the last and longest movement of five. I first learnt about it in this article, a famous one called &#8216;<a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-dyn/content/article/2007/04/04/AR2007040401721.html" target="_blank">Pearls Before Breakfast</a>&#8216; by Gene Weingarten (he won a Pulitzer for this article, and although many &#8211; fair &#8211; criticisms have been leveled at the experiment it carries out, I think it&#8217;s worthy of one nonetheless; very few articles in the world have the power to engage someone so entirely <em>and</em> make them think very hard about certain things, and this definitely does!). In the article, Joshua Bell is quoted as calling the Chaconne &#8216;one of the greatest pieces of music ever written&#8217;. I was curious to see what sort of piece could earn itself such an epithet, and I didn&#8217;t (still don&#8217;t) know much about classical music anyways, though I liked listening to it when studying (no lyrics to distract!), so I figured it would be as good a place to start as any. And <em>boy</em>, was it.</p>
<p>(In the experiment the article carries out, Joshua Bell starts off by playing this Chaconne &#8211; he&#8217;s pretending to be yet another busker in some metro station in DC, only he&#8217;s a world-renowned violinist who&#8217;ll be playing a Stradivarius or something. The experiment is to see how many people will notice &#8216;genius&#8217; and &#8216;greatness&#8217;, if you will, and stop to pay attention even in the middle of rush hour. Very few people paid attention to the Chaconne, which <em>amazes</em> me &#8211; never mind getting to work on time; <em>this is the Chaconne</em>. I would run out of my college MCR every time a violinist on Turl Street started playing the Chaconne, which he often did in the evenings; he wasn&#8217;t even a Joshua Bell. Oxford is a lovely place to hear this played, especially when someone plays it on the streets in the evening. It melts into the dusk and into the buildings.)</p>
<p>I don&#8217;t think I could ever get bored of it: every hearing reveals new layers to the piece that I hadn&#8217;t noticed previously; it fits almost any mood (except the exercise-adrenalin mood, unfortunately &#8211; but Bach was not to know of treadmills way back then, so can&#8217;t blame him!). I sometimes think perhaps the whole of life and its emotions are encapsulated in this song; the exuberant moments, the calm ones, the sad ones; mornings with a pink and orange sunrise, and the slight rain that falls briefly before the big shower comes; the way crowds slowly increase in certain parts of town (any town) as the morning progresses, the tempo of life rising alongside increments in time; there are traffic jams and cars speeding on highways. I can hear necessary cups of coffee in it; heartbreak and reconciliation; determination, decision. It&#8217;s all in there. I could list a thousand more odds and ends that come to my mind as I listen to this song, but that would probably consume this post and a thousand more.</p>
<p>Brahms rightly identifies the most extraordinary quality about this piece, in a letter to Clara Schumann - <em>how does anybody, any human being, feel enough to compose such a piece?</em> Sometimes it is hard enough just listening to it. (Miles told me that while poor Schumann was being treated for syphillis with mercury, which is highly poisonous, his wife was having an affair with Brahms; I would have been wary if I were Brahms, but then again, perhaps Schumann was the philanderer&#8230;) <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Partita_for_Violin_No._2_(Bach)#cite_note-1" target="_blank">Brahms writes to Clara</a>,</p>
<blockquote><p>On one stave, for a small instrument, the man writes a whole world of the deepest thoughts and most powerful feelings. If I imagined that I could have created, even conceived the piece, I am quite certain that the excess of excitement and earth-shattering experience would have driven me out of my mind.</p></blockquote>
<p>This might be presumptuous, and I might have no right to &#8211; but I agree with him entirely. It&#8217;s an echo of a sentiment that Shakespeare himself expressed (albeit as Othello), of the soul &#8211; &#8220;if it were to die now, &#8217;twere now to be most happy; for, I fear, my soul hath her content so absolute that not another comfort like to this suceeds in unknown fate&#8221;. It&#8217;s almost as if there can be no better expression of feeling (unknown, undefined) and emotion (ditto) than this. These quantities have to be left vague and undefined, because I think they elude definition &#8211; to claim it is a dirge for his first wife is a bit too simplistic, and worse, it simplifies something extremely complex and profound.</p>
<p>There can be no easy attempt to ascribe meaning to the music, because I think that&#8217;s impossible &#8211; a Bach scholar called Helga Thoene suggests that the Chaconne is actually written <em>in memoriam</em> of Bach&#8217;s first wife, of whose death he had learnt shortly before composing the piece. But I&#8217;m not sure. It&#8217;s definitely sad at parts, but also peaceful if not exuberant in others. Miles and I have many violent (and nerdy) arguments about meaning in (instrumental) music; I hold staunchly (and perhaps without enough subtlety/philosophical delving into the issue) that music cannot formally present meaning, that it&#8217;s without a formal means of reference. Miles says I&#8217;m silly and that of course music is referential (but he is unsure about what referentiality is, as he hasn&#8217;t been forced to consume copious amounts of poststructuralist theory). A book I foraged from my father&#8217;s book cupboard yesterday, called <em>Musicophilia</em> by someone called Oliver Sacks, agrees with me (HA!); he writes,</p>
<blockquote><p>But why this incessant search for meaning or interpretation? It is not clear that any art cries out for this and, of all the arts, music surely the least &#8211; for while it is the most closely tied to the emotions, music is wholly abstract; it has no formal power of representation whatsoever. We may go to a play to learn about jealousy, betrayal, vengeance, love &#8211; but music, instrumental music, can tell us nothing about these. Music can have wonderful, formal, quasi-mathematical perfection, and it can have heartbreaking tenderness, poignancy, and beauty (Bach, of course, was a master at combining these). But it does have to have any &#8216;meaning&#8217; whatsoever. One may recall music, give it the life of imagination (or hallucination) simply because one likes it  - this is reason enough. Or perhaps there is no reason at all, as Rodolfo Llinás points out.&#8221; <strong>p. 37</strong></p></blockquote>
<p>Leaving aside the somewhat short shrift he gives to other art forms, I guess I agree almost completely with this characterization of (instrumental) music: it becomes almost a <em>tabula rasa</em>, to be inscribed upon at will. I cannot see that it even controls what themes or emotions one might choose to associate with it &#8211; what I hear as sadness might very well be someone else&#8217;s happiness. There is no necessary common denominator in these issues. Bach&#8217;s Chaconne is a rich <em>tabula rasa</em> indeed, because of its many variations and leaps and twirls &#8211; one can read almost anything (and everything) into it, which brings me back to what I said about the whole of life being encapsulated in this one piece. And it is an extraordinary quality. And technically &#8211; I know nothing about music, and maybe that&#8217;s why I find it so difficult to believe, even though I <em>know</em> now, that all these sounds (sometimes simultaneous) are coming from one instrument and one person. But they are!</p>
<p>The version of the Chaconne I have is by Yehudi Menuhin, though I had actually wanted a version by Itzhak Perlman (one of the few violinists I know). It sounded amazing though, so I couldn&#8217;t complain. Miles later corrected my ignorance about Menuhin, and that explains why it is so very good, too.</p>
<p>A clip for you all, of Menuhin playing the Chaconne (this is only Part 1, so 7 mins long):</p>
<span style="text-align:center; display: block;"><a href="http://poojabharat.wordpress.com/2012/09/10/on-bach-music-part-1/"><img src="http://img.youtube.com/vi/lm1q3gadv50/2.jpg" alt="" /></a></span>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>It would be fitting to conclude this post with one of my favourite paeans to Bach, by my favourite author in my favourite book (a lot of likes in this sentence, eh!) &#8211; from Coetzee in <em>Diary of a Bad Year</em>. (Some people say that this whole book is a paean to Bach, with its descent into a three-part structure.) I&#8217;ve never heard anything expressed so honestly as himself (and for once, I think I am right to see <em>Coetzee</em>, and not his character, saying this!); I didn&#8217;t think it would be possible to hear such unqualified, unquestioning praise from a man who questions <em>everything</em>. But here it is:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;The best proof we have that life is good, and therefore that there may perhaps be a God after all, who has our welfare at heart, is that to each of us, on the day we are born, comes the music of  Johann Sebastian Bach. It comes as a gift, unearned, unmerited, for free. How I would like to speak just once to that man, dead now these many years! &#8220;See how we in the twenty-first century still play your music, how we revere and love it, how we are absorbed andmoved and fortified and made joyful by it,&#8221; I would say. &#8220;In the name of all mankind, please accept these words of tribute, inadequate though they are, and let all you endured in those bitter last years of yours, including the cruel surgical operations on your eyes, be forgotten.&#8221; <em>Diary of a Bad Year, J. M. Coetzee (&#8216;On J. S. Bach&#8217;)</em></p></blockquote>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://poojabharat.wordpress.com/category/books-2/'>Books</a>, <a href='http://poojabharat.wordpress.com/category/music-2/'>Music</a>, <a href='http://poojabharat.wordpress.com/category/opinion/'>Opinion</a>, <a href='http://poojabharat.wordpress.com/category/personal/'>Personal</a>, <a href='http://poojabharat.wordpress.com/category/video/'>Video</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/630/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/630/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=630&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://poojabharat.wordpress.com/2012/09/10/on-bach-music-part-1/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>53</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/5184cca44a409f8b1b7ba7dcd03cea9a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">pbrat</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>