<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2011 14:00:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>My First Encounter With Dementia: Daddy Pat (Part 1)</title>
		<link>http://daddoesntknowme.wordpress.com/2011/04/18/my-first-encounter-with-dementia-daddy-pat-part-1/</link>
		<comments>http://daddoesntknowme.wordpress.com/2011/04/18/my-first-encounter-with-dementia-daddy-pat-part-1/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2011 13:15:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>jeromesdaughter</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Alzheimers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dementia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[elder care]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grandparents]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[senior]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[seniors]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://daddoesntknowme.wordpress.com/?p=82</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Some people may claim they had the best grandfathers in the world, but I really did. Wylie Patterson, aka Daddy Pat, was an old country boy who farmed, worked at a cotton gin, and then went on to work at the Panama Canal until literally 3 months after I was born. He was, and remains, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=82&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Some people may claim they had the best grandfathers in the world, but I really did. Wylie Patterson, aka Daddy Pat, was an old country boy who farmed, worked at a cotton gin, and then went on to work at the Panama Canal until literally 3 months after I was born. He was, and remains, the best man I&#8217;ve ever known.</p>
<div id="attachment_229" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://daddoesntknowme.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/mpat-dpat-anniv2.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-229" title="The Best Grandparents EVER" src="http://daddoesntknowme.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/mpat-dpat-anniv2.jpg?w=300&#038;h=223" alt="" width="300" height="223" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Mommy and Daddy Pat celebrating their 50th wedding anniversary, 1973</p></div>
<p>To say that I was lucky to have spent so much time with Daddy Pat feels funny to me because of the reasons behind our frequent visits. My mother was diagnosed with colon cancer when I was seven years old. She spent the remaining two years of her life in and out of the hospital, fighting the good fight. Thus, Mommy and Daddy Pat became very important adults in my life not only as grandparents, but also as caretakers. I spent many nights at their house when I was sick so my father could go to work.</p>
<p>It was during these &#8220;live-ins&#8221; that I really learned about the man my grandfather was. He used to quietly wake me in the middle of the night so we could sneak into the kitchen and eat Mommy Pat cookies on vanilla ice cream. Since he was a man of few words, this was a pretty easy task for him. Others might have called him stoic, but he really wasn&#8217;t. He was dear, quiet, sweet, and funny. He was my Daddy Pat.</p>
<p>As I got older and needed less attention, he changed. He slowly became moody. He resisted any and all offers to help with his lawn. He resisted to the point of taking out several of the fruit trees in his back yard. He told me he did it because the trees crowded the yard. Mommy Pat told me he took them out because he couldn&#8217;t take care of them on his own anymore and he didn&#8217;t want to admit it.</p>
<p>He also became repetitive. He told the same story about cranking up a Model A and nearly breaking his arm. I must have heard the same story about driving the sharecroppers to the fields via a deep dip in the road a million times. &#8220;Them older guys knew to hold on. All the new boys would damn near fly out of the bed of my truck!&#8221;</p>
<p>Slowly, he became even quieter, less talkative, to the point of near silence. But he always lit up when he saw me. He always hugged me, pat me on the back, kissed my cheek and said, &#8220;My girl is here!&#8221; (still brings tears to my eyes) Then, he always made sure I got one of the good swivel rockers in their living room. Mommy Pat and I would rock and talk for hours while Daddy Pat sat and listened, smiled and laughed, or frowned and said &#8220;Oh no!&#8221; (mostly when I spoke about boys)</p>
<p>Then, he&#8217;d be back to his old self, or as close as he ever got again. He and Mommy Pat began recounting events during the first weeks and months following my mother&#8217;s death. Daddy Pat would say, &#8220;Ernestine, tell her about how she&#8217;d wait for Joy&#8221; (my mother). So, they&#8217;d recount the times I stood by their front window, looking outside, for what seemed hours at a time, nearly 10 years prior.</p>
<p>&#8220;Honey girl, what you doin&#8217; at that window?&#8221; Mommy Pat would ask.</p>
<p>&#8220;Waiting for mommy to come and get me.&#8221;</p>
<p>Daddy Pat would tell me this story over and over again, then he&#8217;d look me in the eyes and do something I&#8217;d never seen him do before. He&#8217;d cry. He&#8217;d say how sorry he was that I had that life. He&#8217;d tell me he wished he could have done more for me. We&#8217;d spent a lot of time consoling each other and it would end with, &#8220;You know, you&#8217;re my very favorite grandpa?&#8221; He&#8217;d say, &#8220;I&#8217;m the only one you know.&#8221; Then we&#8217;d agree that&#8217;s why I only had one, because the other might have felt left out.</p>
<p>This is when I first notice his mood swings. The man who once only showed a level head around me began to cry and get mad in front of me. Mostly, he got mad at Mommy Pat and his son, my sweet Uncle Sonny.  He usually cried about the fact I was so young when mom died or how my cousin Kenny worked so hard to help his mom, my Aunt Helen, through her battle with cancer. Sometimes it felt refreshing to see these new displays of love and grief, but mostly they confused me. At the time, I had no idea what all these symptoms meant. My grandfather was invincible. The thought his mind was failing never occurred to me.</p>
<p>Then I got that dreaded call from Mommy Pat. At the time, I was living in Denton attending the University of North Texas. She called to tell me she had to move Daddy Pat to a nursing home because &#8220;he&#8217;s too hard for me to handle on my own. He&#8217;s not himself anymore, sweetie.&#8221;</p>
<p>(To be continued&#8230;.)</p>
<div id="attachment_230" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://daddoesntknowme.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/mpat-dpat-nursing-home1.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-230" title="Mommy and Daddy Pat " src="http://daddoesntknowme.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/mpat-dpat-nursing-home1.jpg?w=300&#038;h=250" alt="" width="300" height="250" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Mommy and Daddy Pat in the nursing home.</p></div>
<p style="text-align:center;"><em>NOTE:</em><br />
<em>In honor of JHP, JR, retired Attorney-At-Law, who taught me to CYA, I offer readers the following disclaimer:</em><br />
<em>Please do not mistake any of the information on My Father Doesn&#8217;t Know Me as medical or therapeutic advice. All of the information contained in this site is based on Lucy Parker Watkins&#8217; experiences, personal research and advice she received during the course of her father&#8217;s treatment for dementia.</em></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/82/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/82/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/82/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/82/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/82/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/82/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/82/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/82/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/82/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/82/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/82/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/82/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/82/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/82/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=82&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://daddoesntknowme.wordpress.com/2011/04/18/my-first-encounter-with-dementia-daddy-pat-part-1/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/1613e8b68819f049eaf71a5933070b7c?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jeromesdaughter</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://daddoesntknowme.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/mpat-dpat-anniv2.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The Best Grandparents EVER</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://daddoesntknowme.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/mpat-dpat-nursing-home1.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mommy and Daddy Pat </media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Montenegro</title>
		<link>http://peteandkimmybird.wordpress.com/2011/04/17/montenegro/</link>
		<comments>http://peteandkimmybird.wordpress.com/2011/04/17/montenegro/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2011 20:33:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Kimmy</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Places]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://peteandkimmybird.wordpress.com/?p=318</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I had heard that Montenegro was incredibly beautiful. Even though I was prepared for a gorgeous drive, it is still is surprising to see this out the bus window: I mean, heck, road trips to me have been to California through the not-so-lovely desert. After the bus ride, we ended up in Podgorica, Montenegro. A [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=318&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I had heard that Montenegro was incredibly beautiful. Even though I was prepared for a gorgeous drive, it is still is surprising to see this out the bus window:</p>
<p><a href="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/bus-ride.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-319" title="bus ride" src="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/bus-ride.jpg?w=640&#038;h=359" alt="" width="640" height="359" /></a></p>
<p>I mean, heck, road trips to me have been to California through the not-so-lovely desert.</p>
<p>After the bus ride, we ended up in Podgorica, Montenegro. A city that is mainly meant for business. There isn&#8217;t really anything to see in the city. Fortunately, Pete had a contact through a man who was in Hungary on a couple mission at the same time. This contact was a German man named Hasko who was in Montenegro to help the policing system there. Montenegro is hoping to become part of the EU, so the country is making steps to rid corruption and start systems that are accepted by the EU. Hasko was hired by the EU to help with the corruption. We met Hasko and his assistant, Andrea (23 year old from Montenegro), at Hasko&#8217;s office. Because there isn&#8217;t much tourism here, hotels are pricey. Hasko was generous enough to let us stay at his apartment. This was just one of the many things that Hasko helped with; I can&#8217;t believe how kind and generous he was to strangers!</p>
<p>Pete and I had such a great time with Hasko and Andrea. Hasko drove us to Lake Shkodor. What a beautiful lake! I&#8217;ve never seen a lake where the mountains popped out of the lake so dramatically. It was also so peaceful to hear the wildlife, rather than the rushing city life that we&#8217;ve been surrounded in so much of the time.</p>
<p><a href="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/lake-shkodor.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-320" title="lake shkodor" src="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/lake-shkodor.jpg?w=640&#038;h=359" alt="" width="640" height="359" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/lake-shkodor-2.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-321" title="lake shkodor 2" src="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/lake-shkodor-2.jpg?w=640&#038;h=359" alt="" width="640" height="359" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/lake-shkodor-us.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-322" title="lake shkodor us" src="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/lake-shkodor-us.jpg?w=640&#038;h=771" alt="" width="640" height="771" /></a></p>
<p>This is a rare orchid that Hasko spotted. It is protected in Germany. It takes the form of an insect to entice other insects to visit and then spread the pollen. It also smelled very good!</p>
<p><a href="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/rare-orchid.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-324" title="rare orchid" src="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/rare-orchid.jpg?w=384&#038;h=653" alt="" width="384" height="653" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pete-pic.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-323" title="pete pic" src="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pete-pic.jpg?w=640&#038;h=359" alt="" width="640" height="359" /></a></p>
<p>I feel pretty short in this pic with Pete and Hasko on either side. Ha.</p>
<p><a href="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/with-hasko.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-325" title="with hasko" src="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/with-hasko.jpg?w=640&#038;h=204" alt="" width="640" height="204" /></a></p>
<p>The next day, Hasko drove us down (along with Andrea) to the coast of Montenegro, to the bay of Kotor. I told you they are so generous! I loved having conversations with them. If you think about it, Pete and I have been together 24 hours a day for the last two and a half weeks, and we haven&#8217;t really had any genuine conversations with anyone else. It was refreshing to be able to talk about Hasko&#8217;s past jobs working in India, Pakistan, and Afghanistan. Andrea is also a blast to talk to. She is very educated and offers a wonderful perspective on Montenegro&#8217;s past and present.</p>
<p>While driving down to Kotor, we stopped in a tiny village to get some smoked ham. Holy cow, what great ham it is! We got a half kilo. The smokehouse looked like an ordinary home from the outside; you&#8217;d never know it was a smokehouse. The couple who helped us was so sweet. These pictures are all a bit blurry because I didn&#8217;t want to blind everyone with a flash. Plus, I never like how things look when taken with a flash; I&#8217;d rather it be blurry.</p>
<p><a href="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/meat-1.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-333" title="meat 1" src="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/meat-1.jpg?w=640&#038;h=359" alt="" width="640" height="359" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pete-meat.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-340" title="pete meat" src="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pete-meat.jpg?w=640&#038;h=359" alt="" width="640" height="359" /></a></p>
<p>Here he is explaining what types of meat are hanging and whatnot.</p>
<p><a href="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/meat-house.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-334" title="meat house" src="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/meat-house.jpg?w=640&#038;h=359" alt="" width="640" height="359" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/meat.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-339" title="meat" src="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/meat.jpg?w=384&#038;h=683" alt="" width="384" height="683" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/meat-man.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-337" title="meat man" src="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/meat-man.jpg?w=384&#038;h=683" alt="" width="384" height="683" /></a></p>
<p>Then we drove and drove on such a windy, beautiful road. We saw scenes like this (the bay of Kotor from above):</p>
<p><a href="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/kotor-bay.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-342" title="kotor bay" src="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/kotor-bay.jpg?w=640&#038;h=359" alt="" width="640" height="359" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/kotor-bay-us.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-343" title="kotor bay us" src="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/kotor-bay-us.jpg?w=640&#038;h=359" alt="" width="640" height="359" /></a></p>
<p>We made it into the city, found a sweet apartment (internet, private bathroom, washing machine!) for two nights. We are staying in the old town. One thing I&#8217;ve noticed about this area of the world is that every city seems to have an old city where the fortress is and people from way back when lived only inside the fortress walls. The U.S. just doesn&#8217;t have that kind of history.</p>
<p><a href="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/fortress.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-347" title="fortress" src="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/fortress.jpg?w=640&#038;h=354" alt="" width="640" height="354" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/old-city-house.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-351" title="old city house" src="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/old-city-house.jpg?w=384&#038;h=683" alt="" width="384" height="683" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/kotor-city-1.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-350" title="kotor city 1" src="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/kotor-city-1.jpg?w=640&#038;h=359" alt="" width="640" height="359" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/bridge-1.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-345" title="bridge 1" src="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/bridge-1.jpg?w=384&#038;h=658" alt="" width="384" height="658" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/cathedral.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-346" title="cathedral" src="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/cathedral.jpg?w=640&#038;h=518" alt="" width="640" height="518" /></a></p>
<p>Some views from the balcony of our apartment/hotel room:</p>
<p><a href="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/view-from-balcony.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-352" title="view from balcony" src="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/view-from-balcony.jpg?w=640&#038;h=359" alt="" width="640" height="359" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/view-from-hotel.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-353" title="view from hotel" src="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/view-from-hotel.jpg?w=384&#038;h=683" alt="" width="384" height="683" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/balcony-flower.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-344" title="balcony flower" src="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/balcony-flower.jpg?w=384&#038;h=683" alt="" width="384" height="683" /></a></p>
<p>For the first afternoon here, we went out to the bay and read, relaxed, and enjoyed the view. Pete took some photos with his nice camera, so hopefully he&#8217;ll post those eventually. I&#8217;ve found that I&#8217;ve still been able to get some good images with a point and shoot, though!</p>
<p><a href="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/kotor-boat.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-349" title="kotor boat" src="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/kotor-boat.jpg?w=640&#038;h=359" alt="" width="640" height="359" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/kotor-bay-low.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-348" title="kotor bay low" src="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/kotor-bay-low.jpg?w=640&#038;h=359" alt="" width="640" height="359" /></a></p>
<p>After Kotor, we went to a nearby city on the beach called Budva. We ended up at a really cool hostel where there were people from Australia, England, Italy, Mexico, and Serbia. We did a bbq with them one night (we grilled pineapple and only the Mexican girl had heard of that). The English owner made Indian curry the next day&#8230;. so good! Budva is definitely a place that is best visited when it&#8217;s warm, but we still had fun wandering around the beach. We also walked to a nearby beach (2 hour walk, but beautiful the whole way). I bet we&#8217;ll visit here again!</p>
<p><a href="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/us-sea.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-380" title="us sea" src="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/us-sea.jpg?w=640&#038;h=359" alt="" width="640" height="359" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pete-sea.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-377" title="pete sea" src="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pete-sea.jpg?w=640&#038;h=359" alt="" width="640" height="359" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/old-city.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-375" title="old city" src="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/old-city.jpg?w=640&#038;h=359" alt="" width="640" height="359" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/wall.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-381" title="wall" src="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/wall.jpg?w=640&#038;h=309" alt="" width="640" height="309" /></a></p>
<p>The water was really cold, and Pete was crazy enough to go into the water knee deep!</p>
<p><a href="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pete-cold-sea.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-376" title="pete cold sea" src="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pete-cold-sea.jpg?w=384&#038;h=683" alt="" width="384" height="683" /></a></p>
<p>Budva also had a nice fortress/old town to explore.</p>
<p><a href="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/kimmy-church.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-373" title="kimmy church" src="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/kimmy-church.jpg?w=384&#038;h=683" alt="" width="384" height="683" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/budva-old-city.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-372" title="budva old city" src="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/budva-old-city.jpg?w=640&#038;h=359" alt="" width="640" height="359" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/budva-church.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-371" title="budva church" src="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/budva-church.jpg?w=640&#038;h=640" alt="" width="640" height="640" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/storm.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-379" title="storm" src="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/storm.jpg?w=640&#038;h=359" alt="" width="640" height="359" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/kimmy-sea.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-374" title="kimmy sea" src="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/kimmy-sea.jpg?w=640&#038;h=359" alt="" width="640" height="359" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/seashell.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-378" title="seashell" src="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/seashell.jpg?w=640&#038;h=359" alt="" width="640" height="359" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/318/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/318/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/318/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/318/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/318/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/318/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/318/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/318/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/318/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/318/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/318/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/318/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/318/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/318/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=318&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://peteandkimmybird.wordpress.com/2011/04/17/montenegro/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/f0996d3b77aa71b84e87430a5c8b331d?s=96&#38;d=monsterid&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">peteandkimmybird</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/bus-ride.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bus ride</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/lake-shkodor.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lake shkodor</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/lake-shkodor-2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lake shkodor 2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/lake-shkodor-us.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lake shkodor us</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/rare-orchid.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">rare orchid</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pete-pic.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">pete pic</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/with-hasko.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">with hasko</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/meat-1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">meat 1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pete-meat.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">pete meat</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/meat-house.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">meat house</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/meat.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">meat</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/meat-man.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">meat man</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/kotor-bay.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">kotor bay</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/kotor-bay-us.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">kotor bay us</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/fortress.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">fortress</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/old-city-house.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">old city house</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/kotor-city-1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">kotor city 1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/bridge-1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bridge 1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/cathedral.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cathedral</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/view-from-balcony.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">view from balcony</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/view-from-hotel.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">view from hotel</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/balcony-flower.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">balcony flower</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/kotor-boat.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">kotor boat</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/kotor-bay-low.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">kotor bay low</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/us-sea.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">us sea</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pete-sea.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">pete sea</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/old-city.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">old city</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/wall.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">wall</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pete-cold-sea.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">pete cold sea</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/kimmy-church.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">kimmy church</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/budva-old-city.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">budva old city</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/budva-church.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">budva church</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/storm.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">storm</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/kimmy-sea.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">kimmy sea</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peteandkimmybird.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/seashell.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">seashell</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>We Need More Taxes</title>
		<link>http://pegoleg.wordpress.com/2011/04/18/we-need-more-taxes/</link>
		<comments>http://pegoleg.wordpress.com/2011/04/18/we-need-more-taxes/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2011 12:30:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>pegoleg</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General Ramblings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bad habits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[musings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[postaweek2011]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[taxes]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://pegoleg.wordpress.com/?p=1700</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[What’s wrong with America is some of y’all need to be paying more taxes.   Taxes raise money, sure, but the government also uses them to change our behavior.  We are encouraged to do some things (buy houses and windmills) and not do others (smoke, drink and drive cars).  I’ve come up with a comprehensive tax [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=1700&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://pegoleg.wordpress.com/2011/04/18/we-need-more-taxes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/afe31f68cb85b812adaa3707fab66883?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">pegoleg</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://pegoleg.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/taxlien.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">taxlien</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Saturday&#8217;s Storm</title>
		<link>http://thesedaysofmine.com/2011/04/18/saturdays-storm/</link>
		<comments>http://thesedaysofmine.com/2011/04/18/saturdays-storm/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2011 10:29:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dianna</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Traveling Days]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[storm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tornado]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thesedaysofmine.com/?p=5585</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[  Here in southeast Virginia, tornadoes are a rare occurence.  I can only remember about a half dozen or so ever hitting around our area. But Saturday evening,  severe storms came through Virginia and North Carolina, and what appeared to be a tornado caused considerable damage within about 10 miles of us. The majority of it [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=5585&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p> </p>
<p>Here in southeast Virginia, tornadoes are a rare occurence.  I can only remember about a half dozen or so ever hitting around our area.</p>
<p>But Saturday evening,  severe storms came through Virginia and North Carolina, and what appeared to be a tornado caused considerable damage within about 10 miles of us. The majority of it was downed trees, power lines, etc. But many houses were also damaged.</p>
<p>This is the home of friends of ours. They were hunkered down in the tub during the storm. Can you tell that some of their furniture is still in place, even though the back wall is completely gone? It reminds me of furniture inside a doll house.</p>
<p><a href="http://boonstoon.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/brown1-4-17-2011-2-14-39-am.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5589" title="brown1 4-17-2011 2-14-39 AM" src="http://boonstoon.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/brown1-4-17-2011-2-14-39-am.jpg?w=500&#038;h=334" alt="" width="500" height="334" /></a></p>
<p>Their vehicles (and garage) were destroyed.</p>
<p><a href="http://boonstoon.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/vehicles-4-17-2011-2-15-25-am.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5590" title="vehicles 4-17-2011 2-15-25 AM" src="http://boonstoon.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/vehicles-4-17-2011-2-15-25-am.jpg?w=500&#038;h=334" alt="" width="500" height="334" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://boonstoon.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/mustang-4-17-2011-2-14-45-am.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5591" title="mustang 4-17-2011 2-14-45 AM" src="http://boonstoon.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/mustang-4-17-2011-2-14-45-am.jpg?w=500&#038;h=334" alt="" width="500" height="334" /></a></p>
<p>Just across the highway, an elderly lady was upstairs in this house, but, miraculously, was uninjured.</p>
<p><a href="http://boonstoon.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/house-with-center-destroyed-4-17-2011-2-25-48-am.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5592" title="house with center destroyed 4-17-2011 2-25-48 AM" src="http://boonstoon.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/house-with-center-destroyed-4-17-2011-2-25-48-am.jpg?w=500&#038;h=334" alt="" width="500" height="334" /></a></p>
<p>And in a nearby area, this beautiful old home was damaged.</p>
<p><a href="http://boonstoon.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/house-with-columns-4-17-2011-3-16-34-am.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5604" title="house with columns 4-17-2011 3-16-34 AM" src="http://boonstoon.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/house-with-columns-4-17-2011-3-16-34-am.jpg?w=500&#038;h=333" alt="" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p>What warmed my heart was the number of vehicles in their yard. It reminded me of an old-time barn raising; neighbors helping out neighbors in need.</p>
<p><a href="http://boonstoon.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/barn-raisin-4-17-2011-3-18-53-am.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5596" title="barn raisin 4-17-2011 3-18-53 AM" src="http://boonstoon.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/barn-raisin-4-17-2011-3-18-53-am.jpg?w=500&#038;h=334" alt="" width="500" height="334" /></a></p>
<p>Even though our immediate area wasn&#8217;t in the line of storms, it was scary enough for us. I can&#8217;t imagine what it was like for the folks living in these houses.  No one was injured in the houses I&#8217;ve shown here, but within an hour of us, there were three deaths associated with this storm.</p>
<p>We&#8217;re thankful the storm missed us, but our hearts go out to those who were in its path.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5585/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5585/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5585/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5585/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5585/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5585/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5585/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5585/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5585/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5585/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5585/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5585/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5585/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5585/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=5585&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thesedaysofmine.com/2011/04/18/saturdays-storm/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/112d8dbb286ec626336df82db95c46c5?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">boonstoon</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://boonstoon.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/brown1-4-17-2011-2-14-39-am.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">brown1 4-17-2011 2-14-39 AM</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://boonstoon.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/vehicles-4-17-2011-2-15-25-am.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">vehicles 4-17-2011 2-15-25 AM</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://boonstoon.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/mustang-4-17-2011-2-14-45-am.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mustang 4-17-2011 2-14-45 AM</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://boonstoon.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/house-with-center-destroyed-4-17-2011-2-25-48-am.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">house with center destroyed 4-17-2011 2-25-48 AM</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://boonstoon.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/house-with-columns-4-17-2011-3-16-34-am.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">house with columns 4-17-2011 3-16-34 AM</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://boonstoon.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/barn-raisin-4-17-2011-3-18-53-am.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">barn raisin 4-17-2011 3-18-53 AM</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Beyond Persuasion There Is Enchantment</title>
		<link>http://rstrategic.com/2011/04/16/beyond-persuasion-there-is-enchantment/</link>
		<comments>http://rstrategic.com/2011/04/16/beyond-persuasion-there-is-enchantment/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2011 19:56:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>r strategic</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Brand Management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enchantment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Guy Kawasaki]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rstrategic.com/?p=125</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Guy Kawasaki&#8217;s new book Enchantment is his most detailed revelation to date about the art of marketing elevated to spiritual experience. Kawasaki was a lead evangelist with Apple during its break-out years and was one of the main spark plugs that fired up Apple&#8217;s legendary brand loyalty. Kawasaki&#8217;s recounts the evolution of persuasion as it applies to [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=125&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://greenbydesignhawaii.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/picture-181.png"><img class="alignleft" style="border-color:initial;border-style:initial;border-width:0;" title="Picture 18" src="http://greenbydesignhawaii.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/picture-181-e1300475897802.png?w=163&#038;h=240" alt="" width="163" height="240" /></a>Guy Kawasaki&#8217;s new book <em>Enchantment</em> is his most detailed revelation to date about the art of marketing elevated to spiritual experience. Kawasaki was a lead evangelist with Apple during its break-out years and was one of the main spark plugs that fired up Apple&#8217;s legendary brand loyalty.</p>
<p>Kawasaki&#8217;s recounts the evolution of persuasion as it applies to his Apple experience. Guy really, really believed Apple was the best computer, and he made a lot of other people really, really believe it too. But, the power of harnessing <em>Enchantment</em> can be applied to any deeply held belief the reader has a burning desire to share.</p>
<p>Kawasaki refined his skills as a post-Apple venture capitalist, and founder of Alltop, the ubiquitous online content directory. His new book is his best because he&#8217;s still engaged and learning. And, in our brave new world of the internet, ten second attention spans and social media you either learn or retire.</p>
<p>In <em>Enchantment</em>, Kawasaki takes us into the inner algorithm of his methodology. This is a “how to” book for a subject that is viewed as almost mystical by many. It is not just a compelling read on how to apply good old fashioned enthusiasm and communication skills to create curiosity, buy-in, and loyalty (in that order) for your product or service. It goes well beyond the ordinary. Kawasaki shares his creative insights into how advocacy can transcend its normal boundaries and become an infectious, life-altering intervention.</p>
<p><em>Enchantment</em> is a primer on how to make any good idea contagious.</p>
<p><em>Enchantment</em> is the best, and most revealing, book yet by Guy Kawasaki. After a amazingly successful career where he has perfected the art of persuasion and motivation. It is generous of Kawaski to share some of the magical secrets of his unique abilities.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/125/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/125/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/125/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/125/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/125/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/125/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/125/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/125/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/125/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/125/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/125/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/125/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/125/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/125/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=125&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://rstrategic.com/2011/04/16/beyond-persuasion-there-is-enchantment/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/0f6d60110f65687a16b85e801b9a47f2?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">rstrategic</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://greenbydesignhawaii.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/picture-181-e1300475897802.png?w=204" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Picture 18</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Coconut Macaroons</title>
		<link>http://theshortlists.wordpress.com/2011/04/18/coconut-macaroons/</link>
		<comments>http://theshortlists.wordpress.com/2011/04/18/coconut-macaroons/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2011 01:53:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Leanne</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Chocolate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cookies, Bars & Brownies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holiday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sweets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chocolate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coconut]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[egg whites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kosher]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[macaroons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Passover]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://theshortlists.wordpress.com/?p=2878</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Passover comes and goes each year and I usually don&#8217;t pay much attention. We would have our own, eager version of Pesach every year growing up &#8211; passing the book around the table, dutifully serving matzoh, finding the afikoman. Even though we were never the family to keep kosher or even pretend to care, I [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=2878&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://theshortlists.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/dsc00405.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2882" title="coconut macaroons" src="http://theshortlists.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/dsc00405.jpg?w=600&#038;h=450" alt="" width="600" height="450" /></a></p>
<p>Passover comes and goes each year and I usually don&#8217;t pay much attention. We would have our own, eager version of Pesach every year growing up &#8211; passing the book around the table, dutifully serving matzoh, finding the afikoman. Even though we were never the family to keep kosher or even pretend to care, I never really liked the traditional food.</p>
<p><a href="http://theshortlists.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/dsc00390.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-2883" title="mixin'" src="http://theshortlists.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/dsc00390.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a>Besides the canedelach (matzoh ball soup), nothing was really worth getting excited for. (When chicken soup with matzoh-flour dumplings are the most exciting thing on the table, things aren&#8217;t looking good.) The haroset, a mixture of grated apples, nuts and spices, sounds delicious but really isn&#8217;t. And don&#8217;t even get me started on the bitter herbs.</p>
<p>So imagine my delight when I was asked to supply dessert for a seder we&#8217;ve been invited to this year. First of all, this will be my first Passover seder at someone else&#8217;s house and Francesco&#8217;s first Passover ever. And I&#8217;m a little nervous for the both of us. I&#8217;m not sure he even knows what Passover is all about. I should probably warn him that he&#8217;ll have to wait in between each glass of wine. If left to our own devices, Francesco and I would skip Passover altogether and continue to plan our epic Easter feast. (Sorry, mom.) Once tapeworm arrives, things may change. But for now, I will avoid maztoh for as long as I can.</p>
<p><a href="http://theshortlists.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/dsc00395.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2884" title="balls of macaroon dough" src="http://theshortlists.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/dsc00395.jpg?w=527&#038;h=396" alt="" width="527" height="396" /></a></p>
<p>As my roots are more or less not Eastern European, and my mother is adamantly opposed to anything even resembling reconstituted fish, I&#8217;ve been spared Passover staples like gefilte fish and maztoh brei. To their credit, my parents always tried their hardest to make Passover palatable. This was usually achieved by lots of wine, some homemade liver pate to liven up the maztoh, and a very colorful reading of the Passover book. (Sorry again, mom, I don&#8217;t know what it&#8217;s called.) This year, they tell me they&#8217;re planning to stuff a leg of lamb with squash puree and sauteed spinach. They&#8217;re just trying to up the ante and give my relatives no excuse (gefilte fish) to not show up. As far as dessert was concerned, when the kids turned their noses up at the haroset, my parents would send us off to the ice cream shop with money in our pockets and tell us to bring something back for everyone.</p>
<p><a href="http://theshortlists.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/dsc00396.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2885" title="insides" src="http://theshortlists.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/dsc00396.jpg?w=496&#038;h=372" alt="" width="496" height="372" /></a></p>
<p>As my acquaintance with specifically kosher-for-passover desserts is pretty much non-existent, my mind flitted to that beast of a <a title="La Bête Noire" href="http://theshortlists.wordpress.com/2010/12/04/la-bete-noire/">flourless chocolate cake</a> I made a few months ago. But I decided against using up the entire supply of chocolate in the Southern Hemisphere. So I asked my mother what I should make. She suggested macaroons, which is exactly what I thought she&#8217;d say. That woman will eat anything even resembling a macaroon, especially if it&#8217;s dipped in chocolate.</p>
<p>So macaroons it would be. They&#8217;re traditional, don&#8217;t require any yeast or grains or leavening or dairy, are a cinch to make and a delight to eat. I finally settled on a <a href="http://pamelasalzman.com/coconut-macaroons/">recipe</a> that looked too good not to try  (I already had all the ingredients in the pantry), and, just a little while later, I was biting into what is probably the best macaroon I&#8217;ve ever had.</p>
<p><a href="http://theshortlists.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/dsc00399.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2886" title="dipped" src="http://theshortlists.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/dsc00399.jpg?w=497&#038;h=373" alt="" width="497" height="373" /></a></p>
<p>I should say that my macaroons looked almost nothing like the pictures on the <a href="http://pamelasalzman.com/">wonderful website</a> I followed (which, should you be in need, has lots more Passover-friendly desserts). Her macaroons were pale and pyramid shaped, with just a glow of baked goodness. Mine look more like little balls of hay, dirt and mud all mixed together then dipped in chocolate. But while the aesthetics may be lacking, what matters &#8211; the taste &#8211; is all there. They are crispy on the outside, chewy on the inside and not too sweet. The only change I made was swapping maple extract for the vanilla. I think it gives them a nice, nutty flavor.</p>
<p>Now that I know what we&#8217;ll be having for dessert on Passover, now I just need to psyche myself up for the rest of the meal. Who knows? Maybe you&#8217;ll be seeing a recipe for gefilte fish up here soon. Then again, probably not.</p>
<p><a href="http://theshortlists.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/dsc00406.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2887" title="yum" src="http://theshortlists.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/dsc00406.jpg?w=600&#038;h=395" alt="" width="600" height="395" /></a></p>
<h2 style="text-align:center;"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">COCONUT MACAROONS</span></h2>
<p style="text-align:center;"><em>The best macaroons ever? Judge for yourself. Definitely a fine way to end any Passover seder. Adapted from<a href="http://pamelasalzman.com/coconut-macaroons/"> this recipe</a> from Pamela Salzman at pamelasalzman.com, which she adapted from David Lebovitz. Makes about 36 cookies and can be made up to a week ahead if stored in the fridge.</em></p>
<p style="padding-left:120px;">2 ½ cups unsweetened shredded coconut</p>
<p style="padding-left:120px;">1 cup sugar</p>
<p style="padding-left:120px;">1 tablespoon raw honey or maple syrup</p>
<p style="padding-left:120px;">¼ cup almond meal (or, if Kosher is not your thing, flour)</p>
<p style="padding-left:120px;">½ teaspoon salt</p>
<p style="padding-left:120px;">4 egg whites</p>
<p style="padding-left:120px;">½ teaspoon vanilla (or maple or almond) extract</p>
<p style="padding-left:120px;">4 ounces dark chocolate, chopped (optional, this is for dipping)</p>
<p>In a large bowl, combine coconut, sugar, honey, almond meal, salt, egg whites and extract (all the ingredients except the chocolate) and mix well with a wooden spoon. Take a large skillet and pour the mixture in. Place over medium-low heat on the stove, and stir constantly for about 5 minutes. When the mixture just begins to stick to the bottom of the pan, almost about to scorch, remove from the heat.  The mixture should be sticky, not dry and pasty.</p>
<p>Transfer back to the bowl you used to mix everything and let cool to room temperature.  You can refrigerate the dough for up to one week or freeze up to one month.</p>
<p>When you&#8217;re ready to bake, preheat the oven to 350F/180C.  Line 2 baking sheets with parchment paper. Using a small ice cream scoop or your hands, form the dough into little mounds and space them evenly on the prepared pans.  Shape them into little pyramids, if desired. (Mine were far too sticky for this.) Bake for 18-20 minutes or until golden brown.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;re like my mother and can&#8217;t resist anything dipped in chocolate, melt some chocolate in a heat -proof (metal) bowl set over a saucepan of simmering water, aka a double boiler.  Dip the cooled macaroons in chocolate (wherever you like — tops, bottoms, sides) and allow to cool completely on cooling rack or on a parchment-lined baking sheet if you dipped the bottoms.</p>
<p>To store, put in an airtight container and keep in the fridge for up to a week or freezer for I don&#8217;t know how long. Probably not very long once you taste one. They&#8217;ll be gone before you have time to pack up and head for the dessert. (Ha. I know, not funny.)</p>
<p><a href="http://theshortlists.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/dsc00404.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2888" title="Passover macaroons" src="http://theshortlists.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/dsc00404.jpg?w=600&#038;h=450" alt="" width="600" height="450" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2878/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2878/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2878/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2878/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2878/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2878/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2878/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2878/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2878/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2878/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2878/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2878/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2878/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2878/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=2878&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://theshortlists.wordpress.com/2011/04/18/coconut-macaroons/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/2a10435358bb50451a9458d09cc5805a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">theshortlists</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theshortlists.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/dsc00405.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">coconut macaroons</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theshortlists.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/dsc00390.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mixin'</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theshortlists.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/dsc00395.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">balls of macaroon dough</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theshortlists.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/dsc00396.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">insides</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theshortlists.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/dsc00399.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">dipped</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theshortlists.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/dsc00406.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">yum</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theshortlists.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/dsc00404.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Passover macaroons</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>TV Turnoff Week</title>
		<link>http://learnersedgeinc.wordpress.com/2011/04/18/tv-turnoff-week/</link>
		<comments>http://learnersedgeinc.wordpress.com/2011/04/18/tv-turnoff-week/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2011 11:26:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Learner's Edge Inc.</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Interesting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tools We Love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology sabbatical]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TV Turnoff Week]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://learnersedgeinc.wordpress.com/?p=672</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Although the website's not really fancy, the folks behind TV Turnoff Week have a simple, but great idea going.  Turn off your TV for a full week.  Do something else with that time.  What's the downside?  You learn new activities?  You spend face-to-face time?  You play a non-electronic (gasp!) board game?  YES.  DO IT.  If you don't like it, you can always turn the TV back on again after 7 days of trying.<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=672&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_674" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 190px"><a href="http://learnersedgeinc.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/173380_100000853610481_7361825_n.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-674" title="173380_100000853610481_7361825_n" src="http://learnersedgeinc.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/173380_100000853610481_7361825_n.jpg?w=180&#038;h=240" alt="" width="180" height="240" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">My crazy son and husband</p></div>
<p>Welcome to TV Turnoff week: the week where you elect to turn off your TV for 7 days, and find other stuff &#8211; stuff that&#8217;s good for your brain &#8211; to do.</p>
<p>Ever since my son was born, I have found myself watching less and less TV; we are down to 1-1 1/2 hours a week now.  One large reason is him &#8211; my husband and I subscribe to the <a href="http://www.aap.org/sections/media/toddlerstv.htm">AAP research</a> that says children under 2 should not watch TV.  <em>We have been known to watch it while holding him faced away from the TV, but even that&#8217;s rare. </em> We&#8217;re too busy doing other things &#8211; playing with fingers and toes, pulling the sheets on and off our heads, changing diapers, being SO BIG! and practicing petting Doggie Hurley and Kitty Taylor.  Now that the weather is getting nicer here, we will be out in the stroller, in the backyard, and may even move the bouncy chair near the garden so that Mom and Dad can dig in the dirt, and Jameson can observe. As you may be able to see from the impish look on my son&#8217;s face, he&#8217;s not a sedentary kid.  He needs to constantly be in motion &#8211; most pictures of him include some level of blur.  Even if we did put him in front of the TV, I can see that buying us 3 minutes &#8211; max.  He&#8217;d shortly be taking apart the remote and eating the batteries, and no one wants that.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s actually kind of nice not watching TV.  True, I can&#8217;t be part of office discussions or pools (American Idol comes to mind), and I don&#8217;t really have a grasp of current programming.  I get my news from NPR and the web, and that&#8217;s all I really need.  To be fair, though, I&#8217;m not the reason for TV Turnoff Week.  Kids are.</p>
<p>Although the <a href="http://www.turnoffyourtv.com/turnoffweek/TV.turnoff.week.html">website&#8217;s</a> not really fancy, the folks behind TV Turnoff Week have a simple, but great idea going.  Turn off your TV for a full week.  Do something else with that time.  What&#8217;s the downside?  You learn new activities?  You spend face-to-face time?  You play a non-electronic (gasp!) board game?  <strong>YES.  DO IT.</strong> If you don&#8217;t like it, you can always turn the TV back on again after 7 days of trying.  The website even has a list of possible activities in which to partake, in case you are just sitting around awkwardly staring at the people in your house that you&#8217;ve avoided this long.</p>
<p>Another idea is turning off the phone and computer &#8211; truly a technology &#8220;sabbatical,&#8221; if you will, but that&#8217;s harder because of school, work and obtaining valued information (I&#8217;m thinking bank statements, weather reports, reading <em>ChalkBlog</em>&#8230;you get the picture).  I find myself taking weekends off of Facebook so I can remind myself that my life neither depends on nor is made truly more interesting seeing every little status update and cute picture. What an interesting lesson for kids, too &#8211; a great challenge.  It certainly teaches delayed gratification, if nothing else.</p>
<p>Who&#8217;s with me?  Are you gonna do it?  Are you gonna challenge your students to do it?<br />
Dawn<br />
<a href="dawn@learnersedgeinc.com">dawn@learnersedgeinc.com</a></p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://learnersedgeinc.wordpress.com/category/interesting/'>Interesting</a>, <a href='http://learnersedgeinc.wordpress.com/category/technology/'>Technology</a>, <a href='http://learnersedgeinc.wordpress.com/category/tools-we-love/'>Tools We Love</a> Tagged: <a href='http://learnersedgeinc.wordpress.com/tag/technology-sabbatical/'>technology sabbatical</a>, <a href='http://learnersedgeinc.wordpress.com/tag/tv/'>TV</a>, <a href='http://learnersedgeinc.wordpress.com/tag/tv-turnoff-week/'>TV Turnoff Week</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/672/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/672/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/672/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/672/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/672/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/672/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/672/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/672/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/672/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/672/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/672/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/672/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/672/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/672/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=672&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://learnersedgeinc.wordpress.com/2011/04/18/tv-turnoff-week/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/35f50aec81f644332570daec5ad577f2?s=96&#38;d=monsterid&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">learnersedgeinc</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://learnersedgeinc.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/173380_100000853610481_7361825_n.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">173380_100000853610481_7361825_n</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>manic maniac monday</title>
		<link>http://bryannachapeskie.wordpress.com/2011/04/18/manic-maniac-monday/</link>
		<comments>http://bryannachapeskie.wordpress.com/2011/04/18/manic-maniac-monday/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2011 11:26:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bchapeskie</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[colour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[illustration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[line]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[monday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yellena james]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://bryannachapeskie.wordpress.com/?p=568</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Happy Monday Maniacs, So I feel like the reason for my lack of arting and blogging can be summed up perfectly by a line from the song Keep On Rockin Me Baby by the Steve Miller Band, and it goes something like &#8220;Well I&#8217;ve been lookin&#8217; real hard, and I&#8217;m trying to find, but it [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=568&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://bryannachapeskie.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/yjames8.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-thumbnail wp-image-575" title="yjames8" src="http://bryannachapeskie.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/yjames8.jpg?w=150&#038;h=150" alt="" width="150" height="150" /></a>Happy Monday Maniacs,</p>
<p>So I feel like the reason for my lack of arting and blogging can be summed up perfectly by a line from the song Keep On Rockin Me Baby by the Steve Miller Band, and it goes something like &#8220;Well I&#8217;ve been lookin&#8217; real hard, and I&#8217;m trying to find, but it just keeps getting tougher everyday&#8221;. Voila. So let&#8217;s get inspired by these amazingly beautiful and colourful illustrations full of lines and life! Yellena James has amazing work. Please, PLEASE! Visit her <a href="http://yellena.com/">website</a>!<br />
Enjoy!</p>
<p><a href="http://bryannachapeskie.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/yjames2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-571" title="yjames2" src="http://bryannachapeskie.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/yjames2.jpg?w=500&#038;h=500" alt="" width="500" height="500" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://bryannachapeskie.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/yjames7.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-574" title="yjames7" src="http://bryannachapeskie.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/yjames7.jpg?w=584&#038;h=319" alt="" width="584" height="319" /></a><br />
<a href="http://bryannachapeskie.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/yjames.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-569" title="yjames" src="http://bryannachapeskie.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/yjames.jpg?w=584&#038;h=467" alt="" width="584" height="467" /></a><a href="http://bryannachapeskie.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/yjames1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-570" title="yjames1" src="http://bryannachapeskie.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/yjames1.jpg?w=500&#038;h=500" alt="" width="500" height="500" /></a><a href="http://bryannachapeskie.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/yjames4.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-572" title="yjames4" src="http://bryannachapeskie.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/yjames4.png?w=478&#038;h=599" alt="" width="478" height="599" /></a><a href="http://bryannachapeskie.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/yjames6.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-573" title="yjames6" src="http://bryannachapeskie.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/yjames6.jpg?w=584&#038;h=584" alt="" width="584" height="584" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/568/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/568/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/568/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/568/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/568/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/568/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/568/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/568/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/568/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/568/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/568/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/568/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/568/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/568/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=568&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://bryannachapeskie.wordpress.com/2011/04/18/manic-maniac-monday/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/23660ab32161b8c7fd24375382975fe7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bchapeskie</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://bryannachapeskie.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/yjames8.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">yjames8</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://bryannachapeskie.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/yjames2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">yjames2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://bryannachapeskie.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/yjames7.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">yjames7</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://bryannachapeskie.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/yjames.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">yjames</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://bryannachapeskie.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/yjames1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">yjames1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://bryannachapeskie.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/yjames4.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">yjames4</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://bryannachapeskie.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/yjames6.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">yjames6</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Vermilion Lakes, Banff</title>
		<link>http://curtispatterson.wordpress.com/2011/04/17/vermilion-lakes-banff/</link>
		<comments>http://curtispatterson.wordpress.com/2011/04/17/vermilion-lakes-banff/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2011 04:34:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>curtispatterson</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[365 Photo Project 2011]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[postaday2011]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://curtispatterson.wordpress.com/?p=619</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=619&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://curtispatterson.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/dsc_0449.jpg"><img src="http://curtispatterson.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/dsc_0449.jpg?w=518&#038;h=780" alt="" title="DSC_0449" width="518" height="780" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-620" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/619/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/619/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/619/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/619/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/619/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/619/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/619/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/619/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/619/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/619/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/619/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/619/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/619/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/619/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=619&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://curtispatterson.wordpress.com/2011/04/17/vermilion-lakes-banff/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/525a4da9e7baa9784327e183232b1ada?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">curtispatterson</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://curtispatterson.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/dsc_0449.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0449</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Data Visualization Technology: Where Do Your Tax Dollars Go?</title>
		<link>http://techland.time.com/2011/04/18/data-visualization-technology-where-do-your-tax-dollars-go/</link>
		<comments>http://techland.time.com/2011/04/18/data-visualization-technology-where-do-your-tax-dollars-go/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2011 13:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Doug Aamoth</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[gadgets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data visualization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[taxes]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://timenerdworld.wordpress.com/?p=77221</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[If you&#8217;re grumbling your way through a mountain of tax forms at the last minute today (or if you forgot today was tax day—hurry!), you may be wondering where all your hard-earned money is going. Google wondered the same thing, and sought to answer that question with what it calls the Data Viz Challenge. Per [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=77221&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://techland.time.com/2011/04/18/data-visualization-technology-where-do-your-tax-dollars-go/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/9c8df542e0f7376bd2d58f707dbdff00?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F1.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">daamoth</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://timenerdworld.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/taxdollars.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">taxdollars</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>