<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2013 20:54:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>For Roger</title>
		<link>http://etheriel.wordpress.com/2013/04/05/for-roger/</link>
		<comments>http://etheriel.wordpress.com/2013/04/05/for-roger/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2013 11:23:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Grace</dc:creator>
		
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://etheriel.wordpress.com/?p=1903</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[“Start writing. Short sentences. Describe it. Just describe it.” Roger said, when I asked him about writer’s block. Then he quoted the first three paragraphs of his &#8220;Persona&#8221; review and told me that it had completely baffled him in 1967 but this strategy worked brilliantly. Tonight, as I sit here numbly staring at the screen [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1903&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-1904" alt="Rog 1" src="http://etheriel.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/img_9777.jpg?w=600&#038;h=400" width="600" height="400" /></p>
<p>“Start writing. Short sentences. Describe it. Just describe it.”</p>
<p>Roger said, when I asked him about writer’s block. Then he quoted the first three paragraphs of his &#8220;Persona&#8221; review and told me that it had completely baffled him in 1967 but this strategy worked brilliantly. Tonight, as I sit here numbly staring at the screen with the hardest writer’s block I’ve ever known, I place my fingers on the keyboard to follow the advice of the greatest man I know, and just describe it.</p>
<p>How do you describe it? Knowing Roger Ebert. Most people gasp in delight at the mention of his name, usually followed by outpourings of affections, “I grew up reading him,” they would say, “I watched him every week!” The connection is always personal. The love deep.</p>
<p>I didn’t know him like that. I didn’t grow up reading him and only caught At The Movies on television occasionally. We met through the internet – as writers – after he had lost the ability to speak, and that is where majority of our conversations took place. It started with a comment about &#8220;The Hurt Locker&#8221; that quickly descended into emails, and haiku, and then there was never a reason to stop. Roger is a natural conversationalist and a collector of interesting people. He loved holding court, even virtually, and playing matchmaker linking people together, introducing and shuffling. He had an innate sense for character and impeccable judgment of situations and he was proud of that, telling me that it was a gift. He brought the Far-Flung Correspondents together, even though at the beginning I thought it was bold if presumptuous – who is going to read about a couple random strangers talk about movies on the net just because Roger Ebert decided they should? But he was delighted in the idea and convinced that it was valuable, and he proceeded to make it happen. I remember standing at a freezing bus stop one winter morning on my way to a soul-crunching job when I got the email from Roger asking me to write for him. Feeling inadequate, I asked for time to think about it. “Why?” He asked. “I don’t have any academic background in film,” I said. “And you think I did?” “But I’m not you!” “You’re not me, that’s why I need you on the site. You are going to end up in a very interesting place in this lifetime.”</p>
<p>Those words sank into me like a shot to the heart, and I have never forgotten them.</p>
<p>And that’s how he was: persistent, decisive, wise, and generous. He embraced people from all walks of life with all kinds of beliefs. He was incredibly open-minded and thoughtful. Intensely curious – if something caught his attention he will focus on it until he figures it out. He also had a great reserve of sympathy and used them with abandon, especially for those who need them. He kept up correspondences with people who he feared would be lost without them, for years. He forwarded to selected friends letters of cries for help that he would receive, sometimes a stranger’s devastating life story, and asked for support. He was always busy and on a deadline but these stories kept coming, and he always found time for them when he could.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-1905" alt="Rog 2" src="http://etheriel.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/img_9778.jpg?w=600&#038;h=400" width="600" height="400" /></p>
<p>I’m making it sound like I know him, and out of the hundreds and thousands of emails we’ve exchanged perhaps I do know a part of him, but not all. He was an intensely private person and one who kept great many friends, to each he has a particular personal connection to. I can’t help but feel that every one of those lucky people would feel exactly how I feel, having been basked in the glow of such a generous and joyful spirit.</p>
<p>In our short time I did come to know one side of Roger: his poetic, idealistic side, and that is the one we bonded over. He loved haiku and appreciated the Romantic poets. He could quote Yeats at the drop of a hat and work sonnets into an otherwise mundane paragraph that makes you wonder how it could have existed without. His fierce intelligence was unparalleled, and you could sense the gears turning, jolting, from one to the other. It is not unlike him to cover topics of philosophy, politics, culture, and film all in one email, before finishing it with a poetic flourish.</p>
<p>And then there was Ebertfest, the annual gathering of all that he loved in his home town of Champaign-Urbana, Illinois. I, along with the rest of the FFCs, was inducted into the circle of guests four years ago and made to feel at once at home. Roger organized a special brunch just for the Correspondents in that first year, all of whom he had never met, and spent time with each person, asking about their families, looking at the gifts presented to him from foreign lands, and patiently jotting down concise and hilarious notes that he would then ask someone to read aloud. We sat there and looked forward to those notes, those brief moments of connections from him. We all loved him and admired him. He sat on a couch against the wall or on a special lazy-boy armchair at the back of the beautiful Virginia theater and people huddled around him, taking photos and asking for autographs and telling him how much he means to them. He patiently indulged every request. At times you could tell he wanted to say something but couldn’t before the moment was gone and it frustrated him, but he never let it slow him down. He was always there and he was loved.</p>
<p>And that was what it came down to: how deeply and fiercely and widely Roger was loved by all who knew and did not know him. He was that kind of person: an inimitable man, a passionate soul, generous spirit, and utterly one of a kind. Beyond it all, he made it personal. Always. He believed in goodness and he lived it, every day. He loved Chaz and his family completely and he told the world about them. Millions of people are mourning the loss of someone whose words have touched them and resonated with that of their own. He never spoke from above – even though he had the power – he spoke from the heart.</p>
<p>And it is from the heart that this deep hole will remain. I have been lucky to know him, to love him, to scribble random notes and long thoughts to him, to be privy to his friendship and his protection. It is a pure honor. To me, he was a complicated mix of protective big brother, patient mentor, and loyal friend. He accepted everything I had to offer, spotted what I didn’t even know I had, and nurtured them, as he did for many others. He sent me my first Criterion film and introduced me to Simenon, Colette, Cather, McCarthy. We talked about Bresson. “You know… when someone falls in love with Bresson, it&#8217;s the sign of a true cineaste. Not everybody does.” A few weeks later, <i>Notes on the Cinematographer</i> by Bresson arrived in the mail. I didn’t tell him about my first film until it was finished. He never asked why, only that I send a DVD instead of an online screener. Then he wrote me a beautiful note, and it was enough. I’m not sure why he believed, but I am so, so grateful.</p>
<p>And that is all. When I saw the news on twitter (which he fittingly got me onto), I stared for a full long while and then clicked refresh, and refresh, and refresh, until the condolences started to blur and my chest felt hollow. I cried. I called my dearest friends and told them what an amazing person he was and how it is unfair and how I wish there was more time, but there was not. Then I found myself walking outside, down streets, walking like Rog once loved to do. It was sunny and people were coming home from work and everyone looked happy, but I felt numb. Eventually I ended up at a park that overlooked the freeway down a grassy hill with the sun shining brightly and dogs running around, playing (he would’ve liked that). I picked a spot and sat down, clasped my hands, looked to the tallest tip of a lone power tower on the horizon and said my goodbyes. Then, a gust of wind blew by, and I thought maybe somewhere he is looking down and saying: Gracie, I’ll get back to you.</p>
<div id="attachment_1906" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><img class="size-large wp-image-1906   " alt="Rog 3" src="http://etheriel.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/img_9779.jpg?w=600&#038;h=400" width="600" height="400" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Chicago, May 2011. Photos by Grace Wang</p></div>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1903/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1903/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1903&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://etheriel.wordpress.com/2013/04/05/for-roger/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>15</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/dd47d91291cdbbc8acc2ab0bac2db9f9?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F1.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Grace</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://etheriel.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/img_9777.jpg?w=600" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Rog 1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://etheriel.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/img_9778.jpg?w=600" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Rog 2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://etheriel.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/img_9779.jpg?w=600" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Rog 3</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Iconic</title>
		<link>http://tuckedintoacorner.wordpress.com/2013/04/02/wordpress-weekly-writing-challenge-iconic/</link>
		<comments>http://tuckedintoacorner.wordpress.com/2013/04/02/wordpress-weekly-writing-challenge-iconic/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 03:03:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tuckedintoacorner</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Humour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clothing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPchallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iconic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[postaday]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tuckedintoacorner.wordpress.com/?p=222</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[For this week’s challenge, we want you to snap a photo of something that is iconic to you. It can even be a picture of your favorite pair of shoes that you wear nearly every day and has come to personify your personal style. Morning. The human drags herself out of bed and we wait by [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=222&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><i>For this week’s challenge, we want you to snap a photo of something that is iconic to you. It can even be a picture of your favorite pair of shoes that you wear nearly every day and has come to personify your personal style.</i></p>
<p><i>Morning</i>. The human drags herself out of bed and we wait by the wardrobe door. Nowadays it’s winter, and so we don’t get to live inside the big cozy space that our colleagues do. Still, we shiver and don’t protest, proud that the human relies on us so much. Our other colleagues are relegated to the rack, tucked away and hibernating. We like to think she chooses us so often because we are the best of the lot: in winter, scruffy sneakers and flimsy flats just can&#8217;t compete. Normally we can tell if the human is up with a good amount of time, or if she has overslept: if it’s the former, she’ll idly make lunch and gather her things. If it’s the latter, she’ll rush around, yank fabric on her feet and reach for us, then flutter around in a panic finding keys, books and mutter about buying lunch.</p>
<p>She keeps us on standby, probably so as not to have to dig around for us. We stand tall and proud by the door, ready and waiting. If she’s in a temper, which does seem to happen as she’s not a morning person, she’ll stomp around and it does irritate us a little bit. <i>Can’t she calm down or at least be a bit gentler?</i> Calm down, she does not: she has been known to express irritation with thrown items or kicked doors. We are careful not to leave scuff marks.</p>
<p>Sometimes we have to wait while she fusses around, makeup or selecting another top, and we just have to be graceful and obliging about it.</p>
<p>Once she’s done with her morning house-ritual, we walk together to the big vehicle that takes her to university. It’s a brief walk, but utterly silent. The human walks alone, and she jams little white things in her ears and takes out a little metal box. Occasionally sounds spill out from the box, and we suppose she must be listening to something quite loud. We must hinder her walking progress, because sometimes she looks down the road and sees the vehicle coming, and doesn’t get to the stop in time. This is when she’ll sometimes curse quietly and possibly scuff us against the ground; whether she is punishing us, or just annoyed at waiting, we can’t tell.</p>
<p>On the vehicle, we sit quietly. She takes out a book and either reads or writes, or just sits and listens to music. It’s often that she’ll stare out the window. Some days, which especially annoy her, are the ones where the vehicle has so many humans that some have to stand.</p>
<p><i>Midday.</i> The human will be at university and it’s our busiest time. She scuffs over pavement, taps over tiles, kicks leaves aside and digs her foot into soft flooring. We see hundreds, thousands of humans every day, and no two people are the same. These humans carry books with strange words and intriguing titles. Our human is interested by some, as we see by the way she tilts her head to get a better look at the book-spine and we imagine that she would want to study such things. Her own books are quite fascinating, we think, but we never get a chance to prove this theory because she doesn’t read aloud much. Sometimes she does, and the words are funny words, not at all the kind we hear in daily conversation.</p>
<p>The humans also carry bags and shiny boxes with which they take notes or talk to others. We wonder what we might be inclined to do if we were human for a day.</p>
<p>Our human often sits near her next class and has lunch. Other humans will join her and they will talk about anything. She will sometimes ask random questions or make idle comments, and the people will look at her like she might be speaking another language. Then again, given that she likes to read funny-word languages, she well might be.  She does speak a second language, too – not the funny words she reads aloud, but something different.</p>
<p>In class, we sit and listen quietly. We are interested by all the things the lecturing human is talking about; we don’t always understand it, but it sounds clever. Our human likes clever, and she diligently scribbles her notes. She comments that her handwriting is terrible, but we are hidden under her desk and we can’t see for ourselves.</p>
<p>Classes finish and the human walks to another place to get the big vehicle home. She doesn’t linger at university much; after class, she packs away her books and chats a bit with other humans before drifting away and calling her ‘see you later’. It’s around this time that we might punish her by hurting her legs or ankles; she will sometimes retaliate with threats to replace us, to throw us into the very back of the wardrobe where we shall never see the light of day again. The threat always works, and we behave ourselves. We don’t want to be tossed aside and forgotten.</p>
<p><i>Evening.</i> We have reached another evening. The human tugs us off and sets us down. She yawns and it’s evident she likes evenings better than mornings. Over the next few hours she comes alive again, waking up more and doing various tasks. We watch as she heads to the dining room for dinner, puts the radio on or flips it off with a murmur about a horrible piece of noise, not to be dignified with the title of <i>song</i>. At times she will put on our cousins, but the cousins look softer and more comfortable. We envy our cousins, who are not so tall and glossy.</p>
<p>Before bed, she will put us by the wardrobe and sometimes coax us into standing straight. By midnight, we are tired and starting to droop a bit. Even when she is asleep, she appears to hear us, and slips out of bed to encourage us to stand up. We do so, and by the light of one of her little metal gadgets, she will sometimes set a pair of the strange feet-fabric by us.</p>
<p>The temperature dips and we hear a clicking sound which is apparently meant to keep her warm. We stand there all night, waiting patiently for the morning when the human will next need us for the day.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/222/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/222/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=222&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tuckedintoacorner.wordpress.com/2013/04/02/wordpress-weekly-writing-challenge-iconic/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tuckedintoacorner.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/img_0076.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tuckedintoacorner.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/img_0076.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0076</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/ed1cb5866ab8ae7649c7e1cdc4821e84?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tuckedintoacorner</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Great South Gate of Jeonju: Pungnammun Remembers</title>
		<link>http://greenwalledtower.wordpress.com/2013/04/02/the-great-south-gate-of-jeonju-pungnammun-remembers/</link>
		<comments>http://greenwalledtower.wordpress.com/2013/04/02/the-great-south-gate-of-jeonju-pungnammun-remembers/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 12:26:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>David Stewart</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Dusk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPchallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[history]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iconic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jeonju]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Korea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pungnammun]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://greenwalledtower.wordpress.com/?p=1429</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The Prosperous South Gate they named me, and I have borne that name with pride for centuries. I have been a rampart against attackers and a conduit of prosperity to my people within; the First Fortress of the Honam region, I was the first, the greatest, and now I am the last. I am Pungnammun. [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1429&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://greenwalledtower.wordpress.com/2013/04/02/the-great-south-gate-of-jeonju-pungnammun-remembers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>16</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/69148ccb56f97ff7965c9c73d60e9ea8?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">greenwalledtower</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://greenwalledtower.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/pungnammun-sign.jpg?w=490" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Pungnammun sign</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://greenwalledtower.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/pungnammun-old.jpg?w=490" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Pungnammun in the 19th century. Source.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://greenwalledtower.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/pungnammun-night.jpg?w=490" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Pungnammun at night</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fixing Education and Cyclical Poverty with Incentivized Parenting</title>
		<link>http://politicdiscourse.com/2013/04/03/fixing-education-and-cyclical-poverty-with-incentivized-parenting/</link>
		<comments>http://politicdiscourse.com/2013/04/03/fixing-education-and-cyclical-poverty-with-incentivized-parenting/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 12:06:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>J. Palmer</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Welfare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accountability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education Reform]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poverty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Welfare Reform]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://politicdiscourse.com/?p=255</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In response to a new legislative proposal in Tennessee that seeks to tie student performance to welfare benefits, David Phillippe at Punditocracy wrote a critical response yesterday deeming the measure a “poverty punishment policy.” As a former public school teacher in a low income school district, some disturbing aspects regarding education in America lead me [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=255&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://politicdiscourse.com/2013/04/03/fixing-education-and-cyclical-poverty-with-incentivized-parenting/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>37</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/fa1cd70c251dc6ecc137f7099c5d0a54?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F0.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">politicdiscourse</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="https://encrypted-tbn3.gstatic.com/images?q=tbn:ANd9GcRAFAw1BbsBEChuZ8GRkQDPJpyIrFWZNvll7bvKBfFQawV9j2QTCA" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/290-width/images/print-edition/20130119_IRC788_1.png" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Fool and His Folly</title>
		<link>http://marydpierce.com/2013/04/03/a-fool-and-his-folly/</link>
		<comments>http://marydpierce.com/2013/04/03/a-fool-and-his-folly/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 05:15:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>marydpierce</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[DPchallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dreams]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[folly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stonehenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://marydpierce.com/?p=4282</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There are variations of my grandfather&#8217;s story, but I prefer this one.  Mostly, because it came from my great-aunt Sophie and she never said anything that wasn&#8217;t true.  Or at least, true enough.  She was the keeper of our stories.  From births to deaths, weddings to wakes; new jobs, new homes, new dreams, if it [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4282&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_4286" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 539px"><a href="http://marydpierce.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/iconic-stonehenge-pm-smaller2.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-4286    " alt="iconic stonehenge pm smaller" src="http://marydpierce.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/iconic-stonehenge-pm-smaller2.jpg?w=529&#038;h=541" width="529" height="541" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">This is the photo of Stonehenge that set my grandfather&#8217;s heart ablaze.</p></div>
<p>There are variations of my grandfather&#8217;s story, but I prefer this one.  Mostly, because it came from my great-aunt Sophie and she never said anything that wasn&#8217;t true.  Or at least, <em>true enough</em>.  She was the keeper of our stories.  From births to deaths, weddings to wakes; new jobs, new homes, new dreams, if it involved a Webster, Aunt Sophie wrote it down.  That job fell to me a few years ago when, at the age of eighty-two, she fell off her bicycle, hit her head, and died.</p>
<p>(Let that be a lesson for you &#8212; <em>You are never too old to wear a helmet</em>.  Aunt Sophie would back me up on this if she could.)</p>
<p>This story began fifty years ago when grandpa Webster had a dream.  In it he dreamed that his ancestors had been druids, and this pleased him immensely.  The whole wise man, mystical nature thing.  He thought it might be true.  But, when he told others about it, they said &#8212; <em>Don&#8217;t be daft, you fool</em>.  <em>It&#8217;s just a dream.  </em>So he shut up about it.</p>
<p>Still.  A wisp of the dream remained.</p>
<p>Shortly after that grandpa bought a box.  He was fond of auctions, and even fonder of bidding on <em>blind</em> boxes &#8211; blind in the sense that you had no idea of the contents, but were willing to chance that there might be something of value inside.  In this instance, the thing of value was the tinted photo of Stonehenge you see above.</p>
<p>How that photograph took hold of my grandfather.  He kept it on his nightstand.  It was the last thing he looked to before he closed his eyes, and the first thing he saw upon waking, his wife coming in a poor second.  But she was patient because she loved him.  And she knew about his druid wish.  For even a wisp of a dream carries a sweet, smoky odor that a good spouse can smell.  She went to the public library and brought back a book &#8212; <em>The Stonehenge Myth &#8212; </em>and set it next to the photo on my grandfather&#8217;s side of the bed.</p>
<p>My grandparents owned a small farm at the time.  Eighty acres on which they grew corn and wheat and raised chickens, sheep, and some dairy cows.  (My father grew up on this farm, and knew before he was eighteen that he wanted something else in life, but that&#8217;s another story, for another time.)  Four months after his finding the Stonehenge photo, six months after the druid dream, my grandfather dragged home his first big rock, a four foot by two foot slab of stone that he slid off the back of a flat-bed trailer at the end of the sheep field.  The neighbors wondered what use could be made from a stone that size, but my grandmother had an inkling.</p>
<p>Over the next six months my grandfather brought home twelve more boulders and stone slabs of various sizes.  He paid his four strapping boys and their friends to help him arrange the stones in a circle.  He borrowed a backhoe and a front end loader.  He carried the Stonehenge photograph in his shirt pocket, and when people asked him what in blue blazes was he trying to build, he pulled out the photo and handed it to them.</p>
<p><em>This</em>, he said.  <em>I&#8217;m building this.  It&#8217;s iconic.</em></p>
<p>Some people thought he said <em>ironic</em>.</p>
<p>Over the years my grandfather and his folly became legend.  There were stories told that he danced drunken and naked in the moonlight among those stones.  Aunt Sophie said that wasn&#8217;t true.  She said that he simply found comfort in sitting in that stone circle while the sun rose or set and he could think about the day ahead of or behind him.  It brought him peace.</p>
<p>For my father and his brothers it brought them something else.  There were more than a few times when they and their friends dared one another to strip and whoop it up around the rocks.  For them, it was a level of coolness others didn&#8217;t have.</p>
<p><em>We were the only kids with Stonehenge in our back yard.</em></p>
<p>Fifteen years ago, as my grandparent&#8217;s fiftieth wedding anniversary approached, their sons wanted to gift them with a trip to England, to see the real Stonehenge, they said.  My grandparents turned them down.  Why spend all that money, when they were happy with the one they had?</p>
<p><em>I&#8217;m no fool</em>, my grandfather told his boys.</p>
<p>It was the truest thing I ever heard him say.</p>
<div id="attachment_4305" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 539px"><a href="http://marydpierce.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/a-stonehenge-1-pm1.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-4305" alt="The Webster family Stonehenge that stands in what used to be a sheep pasture on the farm.  The stones are not as big as they look, not nearly like those at the actual Stonehenge, but they were good enough for dancing around in the moonlight." src="http://marydpierce.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/a-stonehenge-1-pm1.jpg?w=529&#038;h=256" width="529" height="256" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The Webster family <em>Stonehenge</em> standing in the sheep pasture on the farm. The stones are not as big as they look, certainly not like those at the actual Stonehenge, but they&#8217;re good enough for dancing around in the moonlight.</p></div>
<p>n.b.  This is not a true story.  It is fiction.  I wanted to see if I had a photo that was iconic to me (for the <a href="http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2013/04/01/weekly-writing-challenge-iconic/">Weekly WP Writing Challenge</a>), and then make up a story to fit the picture.  Also, I <em>have</em> been to the real Stonehenge.  I wasn&#8217;t allowed to dance around the stones, though, naked or otherwise.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4282/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4282/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4282&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://marydpierce.com/2013/04/03/a-fool-and-his-folly/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>44</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/048b4ca39541e4ca73df55c6b09985aa?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">marydpierce</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://marydpierce.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/iconic-stonehenge-pm-smaller2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">iconic stonehenge pm smaller</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://marydpierce.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/a-stonehenge-1-pm1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The Webster family Stonehenge that stands in what used to be a sheep pasture on the farm.  The stones are not as big as they look, not nearly like those at the actual Stonehenge, but they were good enough for dancing around in the moonlight.</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Studio Night Saved my Marriage</title>
		<link>http://projectophile.wordpress.com/2013/04/03/how-studio-night-saved-my-marriage/</link>
		<comments>http://projectophile.wordpress.com/2013/04/03/how-studio-night-saved-my-marriage/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 16:24:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Clare</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://projectophile.wordpress.com/?p=514</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[“But there never seems to be enough time, to do the things you want to do once you find them…” &#8211;Jim Croce:  Musician, Lover, Dreamer, Mustache-Wearer A funny thing happens when you commit your life to another person:   You don’t get to do what you want all the time. Then the two of you make [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=514&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong><span style="color:#ff00ff;"><em>“But there never seems to be enough time, to do the things you want to do once you find them…”</em></span></strong><br />
&#8211;Jim Croce:  Musician, Lover, Dreamer, Mustache-Wearer</p>
<div id="attachment_508" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 347px"><a href="http://projectophile.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/jimcroce.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-508   " alt="jimcroce" src="http://projectophile.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/jimcroce.jpg?w=337&#038;h=337" width="337" height="337" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Jim never took anything for granted. Which is good, cause he died in a plane crash in 1973.</p></div>
<p>A funny thing happens when you commit your life to another person:   You don’t get to do what you want all the time.</p>
<p>Then the two of you make a new little person (or two or three), and then you really can’t do anything that you want, EVER.   You can’t get drunk and spontaneously  board a bus to Milwaukee.  You can’t eat ice cream for dinner.  You can’t get busy in the parking lot behind Radio Shack.*  You can’t even keep fresh cut flowers on the table, because certain little people will knock over the vase, spill the water and eat the flowers.</p>
<p>Don’t get me wrong—despite what my combat-boot-wearing self said 15 years ago about perpetuating the oppression of the patriarchy— I love being married.  I adore my children.  Being trapped in this straightjacket of domesticity is like being embraced in a warm, sticky hug, 24 hours a day, and I wouldn&#8217;t trade it for anything.</p>
<div id="attachment_512" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 378px"><a href="http://projectophile.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/whatdidijustdo.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-512  " alt="WHATDIDIJUSTDO" src="http://projectophile.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/whatdidijustdo.jpg?w=368&#038;h=392" width="368" height="392" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">When you get married in a basement, it&#8217;s all uphill from there.</p></div>
<p style="text-align:left;">However, there comes a time when you have to scrape off the boogers, pull on some real pants (with a belt), and shift your energy to more creative pursuits.  But, girl, it’s not as easy as it sounds.</p>
<p>Since I’ve started this blog, a couple of people have asked me, “where do you find the time to do all this crap?”  And the answer is, STUDIO NIGHT!</p>
<p><em>(Also, my house usually looks like this:)</em><br />
<a href="http://projectophile.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/picture-1143.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-511" alt="Picture 1143" src="http://projectophile.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/picture-1143.jpg?w=584&#038;h=421" width="584" height="421" /></a>Strangely, nobody ever asks Scott where he finds the time for his comics, but if they did, the answer would be “STUDIO NIGHT!” (plus a day job where nobody seems to pay attention to what he’s doing).</p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><strong><span style="color:#ff00ff;">WHAT IS STUDIO NIGHT?</span></strong><br />
STUDIO NIGHT is on Monday.  It starts when the kids go to bed. It ends when we go to bed.  It lasts about 3 hours.  There’s no TV watching, no talking about our days or about our feelings or what needs to be done around the house.  There is only doing.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration:underline;">There are two simple rules to STUDIO NIGHT:</span><br />
<strong>1)    Do something creative</strong><br />
<strong>2)    Don’t bother me</strong></p>
<p><strong><span style="color:#ff00ff;">A BRIEF HISTORY OF STUDIO NIGHT:</span> </strong><br />
When I met Scott, he was already a father to an adorable 4-year-old boy.  We quickly settled into a routine that revolved around the custody schedule: Max nights (Tuesday, Thursday, every other weekend), and Date nights (Monday and Wednesday).  There was always enough time to spend with Max, and each other, and alone.  This worked well for a few years.</p>
<div id="attachment_517" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 441px"><a href="http://projectophile.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/215772_1015440498649_8312_n.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-517" alt="See why I married him?" src="http://projectophile.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/215772_1015440498649_8312_n.jpg?w=431&#038;h=296" width="431" height="296" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">See why I married him?</p></div>
<p style="text-align:left;">Then, in the span of 4 short years, Scott and I got married, had a baby, and then had another baby.   Oh, and I lost my job right before the first baby was born.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Suddenly, I was a full-time mommy.   I loved my babies, but at the end of the day I wanted nothing more than a glass of wine and some adult conversation.  I didn’t care so much about art, or writing, or making stuff.   It was enough to get through another day.</p>
<div id="attachment_513" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 536px"><a href="http://projectophile.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/img_2985.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-513 " alt="IMG_2985" src="http://projectophile.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/img_2985.jpg?w=526&#038;h=394" width="526" height="394" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Whoah, how did this happen?</p></div>
<p style="text-align:left;">I never stopped to think about how quickly the trajectory of life had changed.  My entire adult life &#8212; including college &#8212; had been occupied by challenging jobs that were full of outlets for creativity and even humor (like constructing a giant pair of women’s panties for a <a href="http://www.hospitalitynet.org/news/4017850.html" target="_blank">street theater action on Michigan Avenue,</a>  or orchestrating this <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zoX2PL-DTEA" target="_blank">Billion Dollar Bake Sale</a> in the state capitol).</p>
<p>I was used to sharing my days (and many evenings) with smart, passionate, funny adults.  And now they were shared with stinky, whiny, endlessly needy children.  I did get another job, but one that allowed me to stay home with the second baby.</p>
<p>Scott managed to keep up his gaming and other hobbies, and I’m not sure he understood my hunger to just DO NOTHING every night after the kids went down.  I tried to write, but it went nowhere.  Meanwhile, as Scott got more serious about his comics, we designated one or two nights a week for him to do nothing but draw. I <a href="http://kingcrowcomics.blogspot.com/2012/05/joy-of-supportive-wiferoad-to-cake-part.html">supported him wholeheartedly</a>, but inside I was feeling lonely and stuck.</p>
<div id="attachment_509" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 309px"><a href="http://projectophile.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/picture-690.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-509   " alt="Picture 690" src="http://projectophile.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/picture-690.jpg?w=299&#038;h=450" width="299" height="450" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Scott&#8217;s first comic expo. As you can see, I&#8217;m dying inside from lack of intellectual stimulation.</p></div>
<p style="text-align:left;">After a few months of self-pity, I stared hard at a list of projects that I could never find the time to finish.  Nothing big;  just little projects around the house, stuff that I could never get done when the kids were awake because they involved needles or power tools or toxic fumes.  Stuff that would make our daily lives just a little bit more beautiful.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Then I used Scott&#8217;s drawing nights to actually finish my projects.  And it felt really good. So I started a blog and promised to update it once a week, to give myself a false sense of accountability (and also because I was jealous that Scott had a blog and I didn’t).</p>
<p>And then &#8212; suddenly &#8212; I had something to write about.  And remembered how much I loved writing, and making beautiful things.  And maybe, how much I loved my husband.</p>
<p>Thank you, STUDIO NIGHT!</p>
<p><span style="color:#ff00ff;"><em>“I’ve looked around enough to know that you’re the one I want to go through time with.”</em></span></p>
<div id="attachment_507" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 384px"><a href="http://projectophile.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/jim-on-stool.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-507" alt="Jim on stool" src="http://projectophile.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/jim-on-stool-e1365004710664.jpg?w=374&#038;h=378" width="374" height="378" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Thanks, Jim!</p></div>
<p><strong><em> *We&#8217;ve never done any of these things.</em> </strong></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/514/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/514/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=514&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://projectophile.wordpress.com/2013/04/03/how-studio-night-saved-my-marriage/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>25</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/1b08a68f35bf8af3ef2cba8f1cd73691?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cfauke</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://projectophile.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/jimcroce.jpg?w=584" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jimcroce</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://projectophile.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/whatdidijustdo.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">WHATDIDIJUSTDO</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://projectophile.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/picture-1143.jpg?w=584" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Picture 1143</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://projectophile.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/215772_1015440498649_8312_n.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">See why I married him?</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://projectophile.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/img_2985.jpg?w=584" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_2985</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://projectophile.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/picture-690.jpg?w=584" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Picture 690</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://projectophile.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/jim-on-stool-e1365004710664.jpg?w=584" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Jim on stool</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Documenting Syria</title>
		<link>http://russellchapman.wordpress.com/2013/04/03/documenting-syria/</link>
		<comments>http://russellchapman.wordpress.com/2013/04/03/documenting-syria/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 08:27:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Russell Chapman</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[exhibition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[revolution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Syria]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aleppo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fsa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[refugee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[war]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://russellchapman.wordpress.com/?p=721</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I have just spent a month in Syria looking at the war in order to understand why this war is happening. At the moment I am in the process of writing about my experience. I had the opportunity to talk to many people from political, military and humanitarian wings of the new Syrian opposition. My [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=721&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I have just spent a month in Syria looking at the war in order to understand why this war is happening. At the moment I am in the process of writing about my experience. I had the opportunity to talk to many people from political, military and humanitarian wings of the new Syrian opposition. My intention is to give as clear a description of what I found as possible. With that, I also took many photos of what I saw and they form a chronological record of my time in this fascinating country. After two years of war I find the people very resilient and resourceful. What really amazed me was the children- how they deal with the war really encapsulates the spirit and determination of this people.</p>
<p>I will be making exhibitions of my pictures from Syria that form a narrative to the human side of what is a very difficult situation for so many people. Here in this post are a very small number of images that give a taste of what I will show later.</p>
<div id="attachment_558" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 594px"><a href="http://russellchapman.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/dsc_1393.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-558" title="Children in the Bab Al Salam refugee camp" alt="" src="http://russellchapman.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/dsc_1393.jpg?w=584&#038;h=355" width="584" height="355" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Children in the Bab Al Salam refugee camp</p></div>
<div id="attachment_571" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 594px"><a href="http://russellchapman.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/dsc_1455.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-571 " title="Azaz, graveyard of the tanks" alt="The first major battle win by the FSA" src="http://russellchapman.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/dsc_1455.jpg?w=584&#038;h=430" width="584" height="430" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Azaz, graveyard of the tanks. The first major battle win by the FSA</p></div>
<div id="attachment_587" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 594px"><a href="http://russellchapman.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/dsc_1568.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-587" alt="This boy was injured by shrapnel. His father is rushing him to a field hospital" src="http://russellchapman.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/dsc_1568.jpg?w=584&#038;h=437" width="584" height="437" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">This boy was injured by shrapnel. His father is rushing him to a field hospital</p></div>
<div id="attachment_635" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 594px"><a href="http://russellchapman.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/dsc_1677.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-635" alt="I was across the road when a cannon shell hit this apartment building. Fortunately nobody was hurt" src="http://russellchapman.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/dsc_1677.jpg?w=584&#038;h=389" width="584" height="389" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">I was across the road when a cannon shell hit this apartment building. Fortunately nobody was hurt</p></div>
<div id="attachment_641" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 594px"><a href="http://russellchapman.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/dsc_1987.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-641" title="FSA fighters. Front-line Aleppo" alt="" src="http://russellchapman.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/dsc_1987.jpg?w=584&#038;h=470" width="584" height="470" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">FSA fighters. Front-line Aleppo</p></div>
<div id="attachment_675" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 594px"><a href="http://russellchapman.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/dsc_1660.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-675" alt="I had to get into a sniper position to get this photo. Was by far my riskiest shot" src="http://russellchapman.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/dsc_1660.jpg?w=584&#038;h=389" width="584" height="389" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">I had to get into a sniper position to get this photo. Was by far my riskiest shot</p></div>
<div id="attachment_718" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 594px"><a href="http://russellchapman.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/dsc_2547.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-718" alt="They have no international help. They build shelters with what they can find" src="http://russellchapman.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/dsc_2547.jpg?w=584&#038;h=413" width="584" height="413" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">They have no international help. They build shelters with what they can find</p></div>
<span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='640' height='390' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/_VVzq6W_Vr0?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/721/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/721/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=721&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://russellchapman.wordpress.com/2013/04/03/documenting-syria/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>25</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/e7f3018d35d5f9fb4b6d6b0ced1a1521?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">russellchapman</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://russellchapman.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/dsc_1393.jpg?w=584" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Children in the Bab Al Salam refugee camp</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://russellchapman.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/dsc_1455.jpg?w=584" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Azaz, graveyard of the tanks</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://russellchapman.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/dsc_1568.jpg?w=584" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">This boy was injured by shrapnel. His father is rushing him to a field hospital</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://russellchapman.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/dsc_1677.jpg?w=584" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">I was across the road when a cannon shell hit this apartment building. Fortunately nobody was hurt</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://russellchapman.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/dsc_1987.jpg?w=584" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">FSA fighters. Front-line Aleppo</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://russellchapman.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/dsc_1660.jpg?w=584" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">I had to get into a sniper position to get this photo. Was by far my riskiest shot</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://russellchapman.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/dsc_2547.jpg?w=584" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">They have no international help. They build shelters with what they can find</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>From Tolstoy to Twitter</title>
		<link>http://katekatharina.com/2013/03/24/from-tolstoy-to-twitter/</link>
		<comments>http://katekatharina.com/2013/03/24/from-tolstoy-to-twitter/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 11:19:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Kate Katharina</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Edinburgh]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kate Ferguson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Modern Fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virginia Woolf]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://katekatharina.com/?p=3012</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Edinburgh is just the place for thrifty, book-loving odd-balls. Many areas, like Bruntsfield, Marchmont and Waverly sound like settings that Jane Austen has fabricated. There is even a Bingham Park and, while I&#8217;ve yet to come across a Darcy Drive or a Wickham Way, it&#8217;s only a matter of time before mindful town planners restore [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3012&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Edinburgh is just the place for thrifty, book-loving odd-balls. </p>
<p>Many areas, like <em>Bruntsfield</em>, <em>Marchmont</em> and <em>Waverly</em> sound like settings that Jane Austen has fabricated. </p>
<p>There is even a <em>Bingham</em> Park and, while I&#8217;ve yet to come across a <em>Darcy</em> Drive or a <em>Wickham</em> Way, it&#8217;s only a matter of time before mindful town planners restore the literary balance.</p>
<p>I suspect the city was designed by a brilliant, absent-minded professor of literature, who approached the task like the writing of an essay.</p>
<p>There are examples of sublime beauty, like the Balmoral hotel, the Walter Scott monument and of course Edinburgh castle, but they are clumsily linked by several hills, which pepper the city indiscriminately. The effect is similar to the reward felt by a reader who huffs and puffs their way through stodgy prose, wondering where it is all going, only to stumble suddenly on something quite profound.<div id="attachment_3031" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://katekatharinaferguson.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/dsc03714.jpg"><img src="http://katekatharinaferguson.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/dsc03714.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" alt="Edinburgh" width="300" height="225" class="size-medium wp-image-3031" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Edinburgh</p></div></p>
<p>On Thursday, I stumbled across the<a href="http://www.stjohnbookshop.co.uk/"> St John&#8217;s charity bookshop</a> in Stockbridge. A poster in the window said &#8220;Clearance! Everything 50 pence&#8221; and I was inside as fast as my little legs could carry me. </p>
<p>It was cluttered and reassuringly musty. Bookish types sporting oversized anoraks and tufty hair browsed stealthily, building discerning piles of poetry, murder mysteries and natural history.</p>
<p>While I prowled the store, several dismayed customers asked the elderly couple behind the counter <em>why</em> <strong>everything must go.</strong> </p>
<p>&#8220;We haven&#8217;t got enough volunteers to keep it going,&#8221; said the man. </p>
<p>&#8220;Now where am I going to go for my books?&#8221; asked one lady and sighed. &#8220;If only I&#8217;d known, I would&#8217;ve given up a few hours,&#8221; said an English man, who blinked a lot and bought the collected works of Oscar Wilde.</p>
<p>&#8220;Well, get stocking up,&#8221; said the old lady. &#8220;Anything that isn&#8217;t sold will go into recycling.&#8221;</p>
<p>I didn&#8217;t need to be told twice. Some of the titles I had been perusing were so promising that the thought of them condemned to shredding alongside household bills and letters from the bank sent a shiver coursing down my spine. </p>
<p>I was tragically limited by the confines (56 x 45 x 25cm including wheels) of my hand baggage allowance. Nevertheless, I managed to add six books to my collection. It only set me back £3, which is about the cost of a glossy magazine offering to make me beautiful and thin. </p>
<p>I am now the proud owner of: <em>The Personality of Animals</em> by the appropriately named H Munro Fox, <em>The Childhood of Animals</em> by Sir Peter Chalmers Mitchell, <em>Know Your Own IQ</em> by  H.J. Eyesenck, <em>The Common Reader</em> by Virginia Woolf, <em>The Hill of Devi</em> by E.M. Forster and most promisingly of all: <em>The Intelligent Woman&#8217;s Guide to Socialism, Capitalism, Sovietism and Fascism Volume 2</em> by Bernard Shaw.</p>
<p>I opened the most humble-sounding of them, Virginia Woolf&#8217;s <em>The Common Reader</em> on the plane earlier. I kept it open on the bus and then on the underground and even brought it to bed with me.<div id="attachment_3032" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 242px"><a href="http://katekatharinaferguson.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/roger_fry_-_virginia_woolf.jpg"><img src="http://katekatharinaferguson.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/roger_fry_-_virginia_woolf.jpg?w=232&#038;h=300" alt="Roger Fry&#039;s painting of Virginia Woolf Image source: http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Roger_Fry_-_Virginia_Woolf.jpg" width="232" height="300" class="size-medium wp-image-3032" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Roger Fry&#8217;s painting of Virginia Woolf Image source: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Roger_Fry_-_Virginia_Woolf.jpg" rel="nofollow">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Roger_Fry_-_Virginia_Woolf.jpg</a></p></div> </p>
<p>We travelled well together. Ms Woolf seemed to understand the dilemmas of contemporary blogging as early as 1925.</p>
<p>In her chapter &#8220;Modern Fiction,&#8221; she asks what about and why and <em>how</em> we should be writing. Baffling questions that the amateur blogger faces every day.</p>
<p>Sometimes I steal <a href="http://katekatharina.com/2013/03/07/frau-bienkowski-and-the-irish-convent/" title="Frau Bienkowski and the Irish&nbsp;Convent">snatches of conversations I&#8217;ve had</a> and slap them onto the blogosphere. Other times I talk about <a href="http://katekatharina.com/2013/02/14/on-love/" title="On&nbsp;Love">love</a> or <a href="http://katekatharina.com/2013/02/24/meat/" title="Meat">meat</a> or <a href="http://katekatharina.com/2013/02/01/the-noisy-peeing-girl-and-the-sexy-reporter/" title="The Noisy Peeing Girl and The Sexy&nbsp;Reporter">peeing audibly</a>. </p>
<p>Occasionally I think about weighty things like politics or God and think I should write about these things too, yet I can find nothing more to say.  </p>
<p>And then there are the times I dream of invention. I wonder whether my paltry life experience could ever be transformed and trapped within the dusty covers of a big fat book. </p>
<p>It&#8217;s worth remembering that unless you&#8217;re an academic, Woolf&#8217;s chapter title doesn&#8217;t age well. &#8220;Modern fiction&#8221; is by nature a relative term. But what she says about the dilemmas of writing may apply to anything from Tolstoy to Twitter. She asks us to: </p>
<blockquote><p>Examine for a moment an ordinary mind on an ordinary day. The mind receives a myriad impressions — trivial, fantastic, evanescent, or engraved with the sharpness of steel. From all sides they come, an incessant shower of innumerable atoms; and as they fall, as they shape themselves into the life of Monday or Tuesday, the accent falls differently from of old; the moment of importance came not here but there; so that, if a writer were a free man and not a slave, if he could write what he chose, not what he must, if he could base his work upon his own feeling and not upon convention, there would be no plot, no comedy, no tragedy, no love interest or catastrophe in the accepted style, and perhaps not a single button sewn on as the Bond Street tailors would have it. Life is not a series of gig lamps symmetrically arranged; life is a luminous halo, a semi-transparent envelope surrounding us from the beginning of consciousness to the end.</p></blockquote>
<p>Sometimes I get stuck inside the semi-transparent envelope. I know I&#8217;m there when words fail me, or I lose the desire to write. It takes a hilly city, with rough cobble-stoned streets, place names that make me feel like I am Elizabeth Bennet and charitable  book-sellers to break the seal.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3012/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3012/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3012&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://katekatharina.com/2013/03/24/from-tolstoy-to-twitter/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>48</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/de5c908b3ac294989f3bf402faf16aa1?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">katekatharinaferguson</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://katekatharinaferguson.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/dsc03714.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Edinburgh</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://katekatharinaferguson.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/roger_fry_-_virginia_woolf.jpg?w=232" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Roger Fry&#039;s painting of Virginia Woolf Image source: http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Roger_Fry_-_Virginia_Woolf.jpg</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Roger Ebert, RIP</title>
		<link>http://whatever.scalzi.com/2013/04/04/roger-ebert-rip/</link>
		<comments>http://whatever.scalzi.com/2013/04/04/roger-ebert-rip/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 20:51:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>John Scalzi</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://whatever.scalzi.com/?p=21515</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There is a hole that can&#8217;t be filled. One of the greats has left us. Roger Ebert has passed away at the age of 70. suntm.es/Z4EIOF — Suntimes (@Suntimes) April 4, 2013 I can&#8217;t say that I ever spoke to Roger Ebert, but I can say I was once in the same room with him [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=21515&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p>There is a hole that can&#8217;t be filled. One of the greats has left us. Roger Ebert has passed away at the age of 70. <a title="http://suntm.es/Z4EIOF" href="http://t.co/FY4Kb9BUdn">suntm.es/Z4EIOF</a></p>
<p>— Suntimes (@Suntimes) <a href="https://twitter.com/Suntimes/status/319896006147854336">April 4, 2013</a></p></blockquote>
<p><strong>I can&#8217;t say that I ever spoke to Roger Ebert,</strong> but I can say I was once in the same room with him &#8212; specifically, the critics&#8217; screening room in Chicago, where as the entertainment editor for my college newspaper I watched a terrible movie called <em>Farewell to the King</em>, and he and Gene Siskel were there as well, sitting, if I remember correctly, in the back of the little theater. Other critics were snarking and catcalling the screen (I mentioned it wasn&#8217;t a very good film), and either Siskel or Ebert (it was dark and I was facing the screen) told them to shut it. They shut it. After the movie was done I rode down in the elevator with him. And that was my brush with greatness, film critic style.</p>
<p>For all that I consider Ebert to be one of my most important writing teachers. He was my teacher in a real and practical sense &#8212; I was hired at age 22 to be a newspaper film critic, with very little direct practical experience in film criticism (not withstanding <em>Farewell to the King</em>, I mostly reviewed music for my college paper). I was hired in May of 1991, but wouldn&#8217;t start until September, which left me the summer to get up to speed. I did it by watching three classic movies a night (to the delight of my then-roommates), and by buying every single review book Roger Ebert had out and reading every single review in them.</p>
<p>He was a great teacher. He was passionate about film &#8212; not just <em>knowledgeable </em>about films and directors and actors, but in love with the form, in a way that came through in every review. Even when a movie was bad, you could tell that at least part of the reason Ebert was annoyed was because the film failed its medium, which could achieve amazing things. But as passionate as he was about film, he wasn&#8217;t <em>precious</em> about it. Ebert loved film, but what I think he loved most of all was the fact that it entertained him so. He loved being entertained, and he loved telling people, in language which was direct and to the point (he worked for the <em>Sun-Times</em>, the blue collar paper in town) what about the films was so entertaining. What he taught me about film criticism is that film criticism isn&#8217;t about showing off what you know about film, it was about sharing what made you love film.</p>
<p>I saw how much Roger Ebert loved film that summer, through his reviews and his words. By the end of the summer, I loved film too. And I wanted to do what he did: Share that love and make people excited about going to the movies, sitting there with their popcorn, waiting to be entertained in the way only film can entertain you.</p>
<p>I left newspaper film criticism &#8212; not entirely voluntarily &#8212; but even after I left that grind I still loved writing about film and went back to it when I could. I wrote freelance reviews for newspapers, magazines and online sites; I&#8217;ve published two books about film. Every year I make predictions about the Oscars here on the site. And I can tell you (roughly) the domestic box office of just about every studio film since 1991. All of that flows back to sitting there with Roger Ebert&#8217;s words, catching the film bug from him. There are other great film critics, of course (I also have a soft spot for Pauline Kael, which is not entirely surprising), but Ebert was the one I related to the most, and learned the most from.</p>
<p>In these later years and after everything that he&#8217;d been through with cancer and with losing the ability to physically speak, I read and was contemplative about the essays and pieces he put up on his Web site. Much of that had nothing to do with film criticism, but was a matter of him writing&#8230; well, whatever. Which meant it was something I could identify with to a significant degree, since that is what I do here. It would be foolish to say that Ebert losing his physical voice freed him to find his voice elsewhere. What I think may be more accurate was that losing his physical voice reminded Ebert that he still had things he wanted to say before he ran out of time to say them.</p>
<p>His Web essays have a sharp, bright but autumnal quality to them; the leaves were still on the trees but the colors were changing and the snap was in the air. It seemed to me Ebert wrote them with the joy of living while there is still life left. I loved these essays but they also made me sad. I knew as a reader they couldn&#8217;t last. And of course they didn&#8217;t.</p>
<p>I had always meant to send Ebert a copy of <em>Old Man&#8217;s War</em>, for no other reason than as a token of appreciation. I knew he was a science fiction geek through and through (he had a penchant for giving science fiction films an extra star if they were especially groovy in the departments of effects and atmosphere). I wanted to sign the book to him and let him know how much his work meant to me &#8212; and for him to have the experience of the book before the movie, whenever that might be. I tried getting in touch with one of his editors at the <em>Sun-Times</em>, who I used to freelance for in college, to get it to him, but never heard back from her. Later it would turn out he and I had the same film/tv agent, who offered to forward on the book for me. I kept meaning to send off the book. I never did. I regret it now.</p>
<p>Although he can&#8217;t know it now, I still think it&#8217;s worth saying: Thank you, Roger Ebert, for being my teacher and for being such a good writer, critic and observer of the world. You made a difference in my life, and it is richer for having your words in it.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/21515/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/21515/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=21515&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://whatever.scalzi.com/2013/04/04/roger-ebert-rip/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>62</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/562d1c41cb05b4dd35650fe1c110bd63?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=R" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">scalzi</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Food Is Beyond &#8220;Good&#8221; and &#8220;Evil&#8221;</title>
		<link>http://fitisafeministissue.wordpress.com/2013/03/26/why-food-is-beyond-good-and-evil/</link>
		<comments>http://fitisafeministissue.wordpress.com/2013/03/26/why-food-is-beyond-good-and-evil/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 12:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Tracy I</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[diets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[overeating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weight loss]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moderation]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fitisafeministissue.wordpress.com/?p=2970</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Recently, in response to a comment I made about the calories in fruit juice, a friend said to me that fruit juice is &#8220;evil.&#8221; I am a philosopher who does a lot of ethics. So &#8220;evil&#8221; means something quite severe to me. Hitler and Pol Pot were evil.  Fruit juice, not so much. I checked [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2970&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://fitisafeministissue.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/orange-juice.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-3132" alt="Orange-Juice" src="http://fitisafeministissue.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/orange-juice.jpg?w=300&#038;h=187" width="300" height="187" /></a>Recently, in response to a comment I made about the calories in fruit juice, a friend said to me that fruit juice is &#8220;evil.&#8221; I am a philosopher who does a lot of ethics. So &#8220;evil&#8221; means something quite severe to me. Hitler and Pol Pot were evil.  Fruit juice, not so much.</p>
<p>I checked back with my friend. No, he didn&#8217;t mean it was literally evil. Just that it&#8217;s as bad as a can of Coke.  Still pretty bad, if not downright evil. It&#8217;s a &#8220;sometimes&#8221; food, not an everyday food. Other anti-juice people jumped in to clarify further. Juice is really, really bad FOR you. Harley Pasternak demonized it the other day in his talk too.  He said that a cup and half of OJ has 240 calories. That&#8217;s not quite right, since a cup has 112 calories.</p>
<p>But I don&#8217;t want to quibble about orange juice in particular. It&#8217;s this whole notion of good foods and bad foods that really gets under my skin. Very few foods, eaten in moderate quantities, are actually bad for you. I ate a big and delicious piece of vegan chocolate cake yesterday.  I don&#8217;t believe it was in the least bad for me. Why? Because I don&#8217;t eat cake every day. I eat it about once or twice a month.</p>
<p>I can&#8217;t trace the quote exactly, but a long time ago I read a great response by George Cohon of McDonald&#8217;s, to the claim that McDonald&#8217;s food was &#8220;bad for you.&#8221; He said something like that McDonald&#8217;s never said you should eat its food three meals a day, seven days a week.  I hesitate to agree with him (because McDonald&#8217;s is problematic in other ways, in my view), but I agree. McDonald&#8217;s and orange juice, chocolate cake and potato chips&#8230;all of these can be part of a healthy diet without doing damage to the person who ingests them.</p>
<p>Moralizing food by calling some of it &#8220;bad&#8221; and some of it &#8220;good&#8221; gives the false impression that foods in themselves have moral qualities. It isn&#8217;t a huge jump, and people make this jump all the time, to the claim that people who eat &#8220;good&#8221; foods in the &#8220;right&#8221; amounts are virtuous and people who do not are bad.</p>
<p>We frequently think of chocolate cake as &#8220;sinfully delicious&#8221; and &#8220;decadent.&#8221;  I&#8217;ve spoken to many a dieter who said, not that they had a good week, but that they were &#8220;good&#8221; that week.  If they wandered off the plan by eating something they weren&#8217;t supposed to, they were &#8220;bad&#8221; that week.  Some foods are considered &#8220;guilty pleasures.&#8221;</p>
<p>One of my favorite parts of both the  <a title="Intuitive Eating: What It Is and Why I Love It!" href="http://fitisafeministissue.wordpress.com/2013/02/12/intuitive-eating-what-it-is-and-why-i-love-it/">intuitive eating approach</a> and the <a title="Overcoming Overeating: Overview, Review, and Update" href="http://fitisafeministissue.wordpress.com/2013/01/22/overcoming-overeating-not-for-everyone/">the demand feeding approach to food </a>is that they both tell us to &#8220;legalize&#8221; all foods.  Carrot sticks are as legal as carrot cake, neither better nor worse than the other. I can already hear the rumblings in the comments.  &#8220;But carrot sticks are better for you than carrot cake!&#8221;  I can even hear those who would jump in against carrot sticks because they have a higher sugar content than celery sticks.</p>
<p>The whole thing brings me back to the idea of moderation, which <a title="Experiments in moderation" href="http://fitisafeministissue.wordpress.com/2013/03/20/experiments-in-moderation/" target="_blank">Sam wrote about </a>in such a lovely way recently.  We can live life by strict rules and have all sorts of forbidden foods on a black list if we like.  But forbidden foods are, for many of us, more attractive for being forbidden.</p>
<p>I know that when I finally truly legalized all foods, french fries, which I&#8217;d considered my favorite food for all of my life, suddenly lost their appeal. They&#8217;re okay, and I do enjoy them from time to time. But are they my favorite foods? No. If I had a choice of giving up fries for the rest of my life or giving up mangoes for the rest of my life, I&#8217;d give up the fries. And not because they&#8217;re &#8220;bad&#8221; or even &#8220;bad for me,&#8221; but because I simply love a good fresh mango.</p>
<p>The food police are those people who like to jump in and tell you about the evil foods that are bad for you and that you should avoid. I&#8217;m not interested in what they have to say.  I am extremely well informed about nutrition and used to be able to rhyme off all sorts of fun facts about countless foods. I wrote them down every day and <a title="Tracking and the Panopticon" href="http://fitisafeministissue.wordpress.com/2012/09/06/tracking-and-the-panopticon/">kept meticulous count</a>. I avoided fruit juice and all caloric drinks so as not to waste the stingily parceled out grams of this or that.  Like so many people, I felt so incredibly virtuous when I stuck with it, often for months and even years at a time.</p>
<p>I convinced myself, as I have heard so many others do, that I just <em>loved</em> this way of eating. It was <em>so great! </em>And I was <em>so good!</em> Meanwhile, I felt deprived, especially around celebrations and special occasions, which are enhanced by taking a meal together.  I had my false sense of virtue, but it wasn&#8217;t much fun.</p>
<p>I have also witnessed the effect of &#8220;virtuous&#8221; eating on others who were not so virtuous but who thought they should be. People would apologize for themselves for eating. &#8220;I shouldn&#8217;t be having this, but&#8230;&#8221;  That is always a preamble to the next day&#8217;s self-flagellation, &#8220;I was so <em>bad</em> at my daughter&#8217;s wedding yesterday.&#8221;   Or this one, &#8220;I&#8217;ll just take a sliver.&#8221;  When I was a young adult, my mother and I polished off close to whole banana loaf over the course of an evening by taking little slivers.  Even today I look back and think I should have just cut off a good sized slice, slathered it with butter, sat down with it, and enjoyed it. Instead, I sneaked into the kitchen a few times and shaved off inadequate pieces that left me wanting more.</p>
<p>When we moralize foods into good, bad, evil even, we deny ourselves permission and set ourselves up not just as failures, but as <em>moral failures.</em></p>
<p>If the foods that made people feel so bad weren&#8217;t forbidden or &#8220;sinful&#8221; in the first place, they&#8217;d be less attractive and people would be less likely to eat more of them than is comfortable.</p>
<p>Are there any foods that, for health reasons, we simply should not eat EVER, that even in tiny amounts are &#8220;evil&#8221;? For some people, there are &#8220;trigger&#8221; foods that they simply cannot moderate.  I will have more to say about that in <a title="Moderation Won’t Work If You’re Addicted, but Are You Sure You’re Addicted?" href="http://fitisafeministissue.wordpress.com/2013/03/28/moderation-wont-work-if-youre-addicted-but-are-you-sure-youre-addicted/" target="_blank">another post</a>. And of course, some people are allergic to things that will kill them if they eat them. And as a vegan I am keenly aware of social, moral and political reasons for avoiding certain foods.</p>
<p>But those foods aside, I&#8217;m not sure if there are any foods that should never, ever, under any circumstances, be eaten because of our health. And if there are, fruit juice is not among them.</p>
<p>Some other posts about food, diets, and moderation:</p>
<p><a title="Three Amazing Rants about Food, Nutrition, and Weight Loss" href="http://fitisafeministissue.wordpress.com/2012/12/05/three-amazing-rants-about-food-nutrition-and-weight-loss/" target="_blank">Three Amazing Rants about Food, Nutrition, and Weight Loss</a></p>
<p><a title="Metabolic Health Is a Feminist Issue" href="http://fitisafeministissue.wordpress.com/2013/02/28/metaboolic-health-is-a-feminist-issue/" target="_blank">Metabolic Health Is a Feminist Issue</a></p>
<p><a title="Raspberry Ketone, Pure Green Coffee Extract, Garcinia Cambogia, Weight Loss, and the Fallacy of Appealing to Authority" href="http://fitisafeministissue.wordpress.com/2013/01/24/raspberry-ketone-pure-green-coffee-extract-garcinia-cambogia-weight-loss-and-the-fallacy-of-appealing-to-authority/" target="_blank">Raspberry Ketone, Pure Green Coffee Extract, Garcinia Cambogia, and the Fallacy of the Appeal to Authority</a></p>
<p><a title="Why Sports Nutrition Counselling Is Not for Me (in the Long Run)" href="http://fitisafeministissue.wordpress.com/2012/12/17/why-sports-nutrition-counselling-is-not-for-me-in-the-long-run/" target="_blank">Why Sports Nutrition Counseling Is Not for Me</a></p>
<p><a title="Moderation Versus All or Nothing" href="http://fitisafeministissue.wordpress.com/2012/10/07/moderation-versus-all-or-nothing/" target="_blank">Moderation versus All or Nothing</a></p>
<p>[photo credit: <a href="http://good-wallpapers.com/food/23241" target="_blank">Good-Wallpapers</a>]</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2970/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2970/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2970&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://fitisafeministissue.wordpress.com/2013/03/26/why-food-is-beyond-good-and-evil/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>58</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/1a0fefa7684a6a097e71c9bd3ebc6a72?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">TI</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://fitisafeministissue.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/orange-juice.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Orange-Juice</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
