<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 21:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Random Chance and a Writer’s Success</title>
		<link>http://richardlevesqueauthor.wordpress.com/2013/04/01/how-much-does-random-chance-account-for-a-writers-success/</link>
		<comments>http://richardlevesqueauthor.wordpress.com/2013/04/01/how-much-does-random-chance-account-for-a-writers-success/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 12:24:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>richardlevesqueauthor</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[e-books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Indie Publishing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kindle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amazon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Take Back Tomorrow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twilight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Unfinished Business]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://richardlevesqueauthor.wordpress.com/?p=722</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I read a lot posts about marketing and selling books. For the most part, they say the same thing. To succeed, a writer (indie or otherwise) needs to: Blog Have a website or &#8220;landing page&#8221; for his/her book Use social media (Facebook, Twitter, Google+, etc.) Develop a &#8220;platform&#8221; Build connections with a community of readers [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=722&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://richardlevesqueauthor.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/800px-weirdtalesv36n1pg045_casino_suicide.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-729" alt="800px-WeirdTalesv36n1pg045_Casino_Suicide" src="http://richardlevesqueauthor.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/800px-weirdtalesv36n1pg045_casino_suicide.png?w=500&#038;h=311" width="500" height="311" /></a>I read a lot posts about marketing and selling books. For the most part, they say the same thing. To succeed, a writer (indie or otherwise) needs to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Blog</li>
<li>Have a website or &#8220;landing page&#8221; for his/her book</li>
<li>Use social media (Facebook, Twitter, Google+, etc.)</li>
<li>Develop a &#8220;platform&#8221;</li>
<li>Build connections with a community of readers</li>
<li>Develop an email list/newsletter</li>
<li>Have an amazing book, a professional cover, and a catchy blurb</li>
<li>Make smart use of sales tactics like price points and free Kindle days</li>
<li>Never, never, never, never give up</li>
</ul>
<p>I&#8217;ve been wondering, though, if one more thing shouldn&#8217;t be added to the list: To succeed, a writer needs to be really lucky.</p>
<p>I can hear the howls now: Luck has nothing to do with it! It&#8217;s all about talent and perseverance and building a community of readers&#8230;</p>
<p>True. It&#8217;s hard to imagine success without those things, but I still think a measure of luck has something to do with it, at least in some cases.</p>
<p>And let me add right away that I&#8217;m not blaming my shortcomings as a writer on my lack of luck. And I&#8217;m not bitching about other people being luckier than me. I place most of the blame for my shortcomings on the fact that I&#8217;m a novice marketer, trying to learn the ropes as I go after having spent the last thirty-plus years learning my craft and living with the illusion that I&#8217;d eventually land a deal with a publisher who&#8217;d do all that marketing for me.</p>
<p>For the most part, I&#8217;ve been trying to do all those things in the bullet points above, some better than others. Success hasn&#8217;t exactly been forthcoming, but it depends on how one measures success. To keep from failing at that last bullet point, I measure success in terms of just <em>having</em> books that are out there and having had <em>some</em> readers find them through my efforts (directly or indirectly) and be entertained by my storytelling. If I measured success in the hundreds of dollars or in averaging one sale per day in an average month, then the measurement would fall short. I&#8217;m not there yet. But I can live with it.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">I&#8217;m just finishing a week of free promos for my books after having launched the second in my Ace Stubble series, <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Unfinished-Business-Ace-Stubble-ebook/dp/B00C02KRFY" target="_blank"><em>Unfinished Business</em></a>. I noticed that on the days when <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Take-Back-Tomorrow-ebook/dp/B0071DMIDQ" target="_blank"><em>Take Back Tomorrow</em></a> was free, there were a lot of downloads (68) through the German arm of Amazon. Out of curiosity, I did a Google search and found that a German free-book-promo site had picked up the listing for my book and featured it; so there are 68 English-speaking German readers with my book in their Kindles, and a handful of them are likely to read it.<a href="http://richardlevesqueauthor.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screen-shot-2013-03-31-at-6-19-57-pm.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-730" alt="Screen shot 2013-03-31 at 6.19.57 PM" src="http://richardlevesqueauthor.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screen-shot-2013-03-31-at-6-19-57-pm.png?w=500&#038;h=218" width="500" height="218" /></a></p>
<p>Those are 68 (potential) readers I hooked up with strictly by chance. Yes, the people who say you make your own luck will argue that I put myself out there and thought positively and created the opportunity by making the book free in the first place. But so did several thousand other indie writers on the same day. The people who run that German site picked my book out of thousands and featured it without any other input from me. Maybe they liked the cover, or the selections from book reviews I included in my blog post about the free day. And maybe if I&#8217;d listed the book on a different day, the site administrators would have been in a different mood or had their eye caught by a different book. And so it goes.</p>
<p>On other free days, I&#8217;ve had other promo sites feature my books, resulting in thousands of free downloads. And on still other days those same books (with the same covers and blurbs and the same outreach on my part to the promo sites) have gone unnoticed, resulting in a couple hundred downloads instead.</p>
<p>It strikes me as rather random. As do other aspects of success.</p>
<p>I was reading another indie writer&#8217;s blog where he was analyzing the wild but temporary success he had on Amazon after his novel was featured in an Amazon-generated list of recommended books; his was the only indie book on the list, and he suddenly found himself with sales comparable to the pros his book was rubbing elbows with. Upon investigating, the writer discovered that his book had been included in the list because it looked so good, so professionally put together, that the Amazon editors had assumed this self-published book had come from a small press. While the author did a fantastic job of designing and marketing his book, the fact that it got noticed by these Amazon editors and recommended on a list of professionally designed books was, really, just a matter of luck&#8211;something the author was quick to acknowledge.<a href="http://richardlevesqueauthor.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/1926whybeunlucky.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-731" alt="1926WhyBeUnlucky" src="http://richardlevesqueauthor.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/1926whybeunlucky.jpg?w=324&#038;h=211" width="324" height="211" /></a></p>
<p>Why that book and not one of the other thousands of solidly designed indies, or even other professionally published books? Random chance maybe? The editors in a particular mood on a particular day and having some indefinable thing catch their eye that on another day would have slipped right past?</p>
<p>I don&#8217;t know the answer, but it does seem to me that random chance has something to do with the reason some writers shoulder ahead of others who are equally good, and oftentimes even better. And those better books never get noticed.</p>
<p>The same probably holds true in traditional publishing where one skilled writer gets picked up by an agent or editor on a given day while an equally skilled writer gets rejected&#8211;partly because the first one was in the right place at the right time.</p>
<p>Imagine the previously unpublished author of a teen vampire romance whose query comes up in an agent&#8217;s queue the same week that the first <em>Twilight</em> book shoots into the literary stratosphere. The agent snaps the book up and is pitching it to publishers in a heartbeat while the other queries in the queue&#8211;all by equally unknown writers, some with more talent and some with less than the author of the <em>Twilight</em> clone&#8211;get rejections because the agent can take on only so many new clients.</p>
<p>Surely there are books that deserve rejection, but there are others that, in a different week, would have outshone the book that got signed. Does being lucky guarantee this hypothetical author success? Not at all. But it gives that writer a hell of a better shot at it than the others who go back to the slush pile.</p>
<p>I don&#8217;t mean to sound defeatist or to say it&#8217;s <em>all</em> about chance. This isn&#8217;t sour grapes (I don&#8217;t have a bestseller because I never got lucky, etc.). No, talent and marketing and skill and savvy all help put the writer in a position where the odds are better. But it really does seem to me that, at least in some cases, luck is as much a factor as talent.</p>
<p>And in some cases, more.</p>
<p>No one seems to talk about it, though. Maybe because it&#8217;s something that can&#8217;t be taught&#8211;or sold&#8211;on a website.</p>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=722&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://richardlevesqueauthor.wordpress.com/2013/04/01/how-much-does-random-chance-account-for-a-writers-success/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>42</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/786e346bbb1b43413c217d2b65d5aad1?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">richardlevesqueauthor</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://richardlevesqueauthor.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/800px-weirdtalesv36n1pg045_casino_suicide.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">800px-WeirdTalesv36n1pg045_Casino_Suicide</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://richardlevesqueauthor.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screen-shot-2013-03-31-at-6-19-57-pm.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen shot 2013-03-31 at 6.19.57 PM</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://richardlevesqueauthor.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/1926whybeunlucky.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">1926WhyBeUnlucky</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>New Doctor Who</title>
		<link>http://thingsmychildrensaid.wordpress.com/2013/04/02/new-doctor-who/</link>
		<comments>http://thingsmychildrensaid.wordpress.com/2013/04/02/new-doctor-who/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 13:21:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>reverend61</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Autism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Doctor Who]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[asd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autistic spectrum disorder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[doctor who]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fatherhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pigsaw]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[world autism awareness day]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thingsmychildrensaid.wordpress.com/?p=2349</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[You may well know this, but April 2nd marks World Autism Awareness Day. Buildings and backdrops will be illuminated in blue to mark the occasion. There will be a bunch of articles in the papers, next to the reactionary studies about how the condition is caused by road fumes. Even the day itself is loaded [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2349&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://thingsmychildrensaid.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/blue.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-2351" alt="blue" src="http://thingsmychildrensaid.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/blue.jpg?w=584&#038;h=328" width="584" height="328" /></a></p>
<p>You may well know this, but April 2nd marks <a href="http://www.autismspeaks.org/what-autism/world-autism-awareness-day" target="_blank">World Autism Awareness Day</a>. Buildings and backdrops will be illuminated in blue to mark the occasion. There will be a bunch of articles in the papers, next to the <a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/science/science-news/9703255/Traffic-fumes-linked-to-autism.html" target="_blank">reactionary studies about how the condition is caused by road fumes</a>. Even the day itself is loaded with preconceptions, advocated as it is by <em>Autism Speaks</em>, a foundation which appears to look upon autism as a disease to be cured, rather than a condition to be accepted.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m ambivalent about it &#8211; there are days I wish Thomas could be fixed, but if he was, he would no longer be Thomas. I know too little about the scientific specifics of autism to know what&#8217;s best, but perhaps it&#8217;s better to have a day that&#8217;s created for slightly murky intentions but that you can use to your advantage. Whichever side your bread is buttered, there is much work to do: <a href="http://www.mysonsnotrainman.com/" target="_blank">clarifying misconceptions</a>, challenging prejudice and fighting for support.</p>
<p>But in our quiet part of Oxfordshire &#8211; for now, at least &#8211; the battle for acceptance is won. I have been overwhelmed by the grace and love that have surrounded Thomas in the past year and a half as a bunch of us figured out what was wrong and how we could set about fixing it. Nick Hornby, in the closing chapters of<em> About A Boy</em>, has his deuteragonist explain that in any monogamous relationship, &#8220;you need backup&#8221;. The same applies for families, and the backup we have here &#8211; from friends, family, and indeed from the system &#8211; is to be cherished and appreciated. We would not be where we are today without it.</p>
<p>This time last year I wrote a piece on <a href="http://thingsmychildrensaid.wordpress.com/2012/04/02/the-boy-in-the-bubble/" target="_blank">what it was like being the parent of a child with autism</a>. I stand by everything I said then. But this year I felt it prudent to let Thomas have a say. Except we&#8217;re not at the stage &#8211; not yet &#8211; where we can really ask Thomas about what&#8217;s going on in his head, and instead we are left with the breadcrumbs of his behaviour, where the things he says and does help form a composite. Or at least a sort of composite. You must be cautious, you see, when you are dealing with this, in order to make sure that the condition does not become the child. Because it is not everything he does and it does not define everything he is.</p>
<p>Still &#8211; until we have a hard and fast scientific principle for filtering the neurotypical from the &#8216;other&#8217;, we have nothing but warning signs discerned from books, observed patterns of behaviour, and gut instinct. Oh, and this, which is something Thomas dictated to his mother back in January, reproduced as is. They call it <em>New Doctor Who.</em></p>
<p><strong>Episode 1. The Broken Console.</strong></p>
<p>First I saw a broken console in my time machine. So I goed off to find the missing parts. I goed to the land of dinosaurs and had a piece of meat and a potion so I gave it to the dinosaur and then the dinosaur was fast asleep. And then inside some dinosaur eggs I found a dinosaur tooth. And then I found a time machine piece. I put it into the console and then I goed to a garden centre. I gave the dinosaur tooth to somebody who looks like a knight. I telled two things about the dinosaur tooth. Then he gave me a gem. Next I goed to Egypt. I had a box of matches and then a metal rod. I found the first broken stone then the second piece. I put it in the middle and then the broken stone was fixed. It helped me do the pattern right to open the coffin. Inside the coffin I saw a mummy and the time machine piece and I got it by giving the mummy the gem. I goed back to my time machine and put the time machine piece in the console. Then I goed to the lab and I opened a cupboard and inside was a heart. I put the heart inside a monster&#8217;s tummy. Then I found a brain. I put the brain into the monster&#8217;s head. Then I tried a machine. I pushed the lever then I made the monster alive. After that I found another time machine piece and I put it into the console. I digged up a plant a bit like a pineapple and gave it to a man then he gave me some spinach. I gave the spinach to myself and then I touched the sword and then the sword got out of the rock. Then I saw somebody. Her name was called Merlin. She gave me a time machine piece and I put it into the console. Then the console was fixed so I goed to a treasure island and then I said &#8220;Hurm this doesn&#8217;t look like home.&#8221; Then I was strapped up in pirate ship but I managed to get out with the sword and then I gave the pirate the sword then he climbed up the mast. Then I found everything I needed and then I made the cannon ball hit the mast, I made the pirate go into the sea. Then I goed back to my time machine. The End.</p>
<p><strong>Episode 2. The Fixed Console</strong>.</p>
<p>First I was on the pirate&#8217;s desert island. Then I saw my time machine. And then I said &#8220;Somebody&#8217;s been messing with my time machine! How do I get in?&#8221; I could only go to a prison and then I found some oil. I filled it up in some bolts. Then I used the screwdriver to turn them. Then I moved the panel and inside was a circuit board. I put it in my time machine and then there were new places to go. I goed to all of them, then I got to my HQ. The End.</p>
<p><strong>Episode 3. The Great Boss Cube.</strong></p>
<p>I was walking along a path when I was in a silver house. It was cold in there but a bad guy cube rolled me up with his attacks. His attacks was fire. He was trying to defeat me. But I defeated him. The End.</p>
<p><strong>Episode 4. The Family met Saw.</strong></p>
<p>I was trapped inside a house with falling marshmallows. There were 100 and thousand of them. After that I found a TV. I wanted to watch TV so I turned it on. On there was a good guy Saw. He told me what he did. And then he did a very special job. He put blood on the bad guy Saw and removed the locks off the doors, then we could get out. Next Saw goed home, and I goed home. The End.</p>
<p>&#8212;</p>
<p>There are multiple readings of the above. On one level it&#8217;s a juxtaposition of his obsession with <em>Doctor Who</em> &#8211; an obsession I&#8217;ve <a href="http://thingsmychildrensaid.wordpress.com/2012/12/21/time-to-move-on/" target="_blank">written about elsewhere</a> &#8211; and the <a href="http://www.inkagames.com/j_categorias.php?lang=en&amp;inicio=0&amp;codcategoria=8" target="_blank">Pigsaw adventure games</a> with which he is currently fascinated, and which I reluctantly let him play on the grounds that they seem harmless enough (and I have checked, honest). On another level&#8230;well, perhaps there is no other level. With Thomas, you can never be quite sure. But you know there&#8217;s always something going on beneath the surface. And that always makes it fun.</p>
<p><a href="http://thingsmychildrensaid.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/thomas_who_1.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2350" alt="Thomas_Who_1" src="http://thingsmychildrensaid.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/thomas_who_1.jpg?w=584&#038;h=389" width="584" height="389" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2349/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2349/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2349&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thingsmychildrensaid.wordpress.com/2013/04/02/new-doctor-who/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>16</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f1a246c38145787cc96799e57148f503?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">reverend61</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thingsmychildrensaid.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/blue.jpg?w=584" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">blue</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thingsmychildrensaid.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/thomas_who_1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Thomas_Who_1</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sawdust Never Looked So Good</title>
		<link>http://honduranhiatus.wordpress.com/2013/03/31/sawdust-never-looked-so-good/</link>
		<comments>http://honduranhiatus.wordpress.com/2013/03/31/sawdust-never-looked-so-good/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 04:16:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>honduranhiatus</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alfombras]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Comayagua]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Day trip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Easter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gallery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Good Friday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Honduras]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sawdust]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Semana Santa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tradition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://honduranhiatus.wordpress.com/?p=829</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Art, colour and passion aren&#8217;t words I would normally associate with sawdust. However that was before I visited Comayagua during Semana Santa. This year the Easter tradition of creating beautiful sawdust alfombras (rugs) through the main streets of Comayagua celebrated its 50th anniversary. The alfombras are made by families, community organisations and church groups. They [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=829&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Art, colour and passion aren&#8217;t words I would normally associate with sawdust. However that was before I visited Comayagua during Semana Santa.</p>
<p>This year the Easter tradition of creating beautiful sawdust <em>alfombras</em> (rugs) through the main streets of Comayagua celebrated its 50th anniversary. The <em>alfombras</em> are made by families, community organisations and church groups.</p>
<p>They work through the wee small hours of the morning, before the sun rises on Good Friday, to complete their masterpieces. By 9am hoards of locals and tourists alike descend on the town to view their spectacular efforts.</p>
<p>I couldn&#8217;t pick out just one or two photos to share with you, so I decided to make a whole gallery. If you click on each image you&#8217;ll be able to read a brief caption.</p>

<a href='http://honduranhiatus.wordpress.com/2013/03/31/sawdust-never-looked-so-good/image-23/' title='Finishing touches'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="834" data-orig-file="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image18.jpg" data-orig-size="3264,2448" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="Finishing touches" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image18.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image18.jpg?w=1024" width="150" height="112" src="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image18.jpg?w=150&#038;h=112" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="Making the finishing touches on an alfombra. You can see some of the stencils used in the background." /></a>
<a href='http://honduranhiatus.wordpress.com/2013/03/31/sawdust-never-looked-so-good/image-35/' title='Colourful sawdust'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="846" data-orig-file="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image30.jpg" data-orig-size="2448,3264" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="Colourful sawdust" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image30.jpg?w=225" data-large-file="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image30.jpg?w=768" width="112" height="150" src="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image30.jpg?w=112&#038;h=150" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="Bags of colourful sawdust ready to be used." /></a>
<a href='http://honduranhiatus.wordpress.com/2013/03/31/sawdust-never-looked-so-good/image-36/' title='Puzzle'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="849" data-orig-file="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image31.jpg" data-orig-size="2448,3264" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="Puzzle" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image31.jpg?w=225" data-large-file="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image31.jpg?w=768" width="112" height="150" src="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image31.jpg?w=112&#038;h=150" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="Adding the final piece of the puzzle." /></a>
<a href='http://honduranhiatus.wordpress.com/2013/03/31/sawdust-never-looked-so-good/image-30/' title='Watering the rugs'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="841" data-orig-file="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image25.jpg" data-orig-size="2448,3264" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="Watering the rugs" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image25.jpg?w=225" data-large-file="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image25.jpg?w=768" width="112" height="150" src="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image25.jpg?w=112&#038;h=150" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="Pesticide sprayers (filled with water) are used to dampen the alfombras so they don&#039;t blow away." /></a>
<a href='http://honduranhiatus.wordpress.com/2013/03/31/sawdust-never-looked-so-good/image-33/' title='Ladders'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="844" data-orig-file="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image28.jpg" data-orig-size="2448,3264" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="Ladders" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image28.jpg?w=225" data-large-file="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image28.jpg?w=768" width="112" height="150" src="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image28.jpg?w=112&#038;h=150" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="Many alfombras have ladders next to them you can climb to take photos." /></a>
<a href='http://honduranhiatus.wordpress.com/2013/03/31/sawdust-never-looked-so-good/image-34/' title='View from the top'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="845" data-orig-file="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image29.jpg" data-orig-size="2448,3264" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="View from the top" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image29.jpg?w=225" data-large-file="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image29.jpg?w=768" width="112" height="150" src="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image29.jpg?w=112&#038;h=150" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="A photo of an alfombra taken from one of the ladders." /></a>
<a href='http://honduranhiatus.wordpress.com/2013/03/31/sawdust-never-looked-so-good/image-26/' title='Floral alfombra'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="837" data-orig-file="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image21.jpg" data-orig-size="3264,2448" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="Floral alfombra" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image21.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image21.jpg?w=1024" width="150" height="112" src="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image21.jpg?w=150&#038;h=112" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="A floral alfombra viewed from a slightly different angle." /></a>
<a href='http://honduranhiatus.wordpress.com/2013/03/31/sawdust-never-looked-so-good/image-32/' title='Angelic cuteness'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="843" data-orig-file="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image27.jpg" data-orig-size="2448,3264" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="Angelic cuteness" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image27.jpg?w=225" data-large-file="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image27.jpg?w=768" width="112" height="150" src="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image27.jpg?w=112&#038;h=150" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="For a few hours the main streets of Comayagua are transformed by bright colours and intricately designed alfombras." /></a>
<a href='http://honduranhiatus.wordpress.com/2013/03/31/sawdust-never-looked-so-good/image-27/' title='Amazing artwork'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="838" data-orig-file="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image22.jpg" data-orig-size="2448,3264" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="Amazing artwork" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image22.jpg?w=225" data-large-file="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image22.jpg?w=768" width="112" height="150" src="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image22.jpg?w=112&#038;h=150" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="Some of the alfombras also use seeds, grains, rice and coffee beans to create their amazing artwork." /></a>
<a href='http://honduranhiatus.wordpress.com/2013/03/31/sawdust-never-looked-so-good/image-29/' title='Popcorn sheep!'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="840" data-orig-file="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image24.jpg" data-orig-size="2448,3264" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="Popcorn sheep!" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image24.jpg?w=225" data-large-file="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image24.jpg?w=768" width="112" height="150" src="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image24.jpg?w=112&#038;h=150" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="This little sheep is made from popcorn!" /></a>
<a href='http://honduranhiatus.wordpress.com/2013/03/31/sawdust-never-looked-so-good/image-31/' title='Egg-cellent'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="842" data-orig-file="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image26.jpg" data-orig-size="3264,2448" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="Egg-cellent" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image26.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image26.jpg?w=1024" width="150" height="112" src="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image26.jpg?w=150&#038;h=112" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="Even eggs can be used to create alfombra artwork." /></a>
<a href='http://honduranhiatus.wordpress.com/2013/03/31/sawdust-never-looked-so-good/image-38/' title='Capsicums'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="851" data-orig-file="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image33.jpg" data-orig-size="3264,2448" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="Capsicums" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image33.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image33.jpg?w=1024" width="150" height="112" src="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image33.jpg?w=150&#038;h=112" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="I also spotted some capsicums used to accent one alfombra&#039;s border." /></a>
<a href='http://honduranhiatus.wordpress.com/2013/03/31/sawdust-never-looked-so-good/image-37/' title='Comayagua crowds'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="850" data-orig-file="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image32.jpg" data-orig-size="2448,3264" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="Comayagua crowds" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image32.jpg?w=225" data-large-file="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image32.jpg?w=768" width="112" height="150" src="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image32.jpg?w=112&#038;h=150" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="Thousands of tourists roam the colonial streets of Comayagua each year to admire the alfombras before they disappear." /></a>
<a href='http://honduranhiatus.wordpress.com/2013/03/31/sawdust-never-looked-so-good/image-24/' title='Viacrucis procession'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="835" data-orig-file="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image19.jpg" data-orig-size="3264,2448" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="Viacrucis procession" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image19.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image19.jpg?w=1024" width="150" height="112" src="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image19.jpg?w=150&#038;h=112" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="The religious procession that takes the same pathway as the alfombras." /></a>
<a href='http://honduranhiatus.wordpress.com/2013/03/31/sawdust-never-looked-so-good/image-25/' title='Aftermath'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="836" data-orig-file="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image20.jpg" data-orig-size="2448,3264" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="Aftermath" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image20.jpg?w=225" data-large-file="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image20.jpg?w=768" width="112" height="150" src="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image20.jpg?w=112&#038;h=150" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="After the procession has passed the alfombras are smooshed into a colourful mess." /></a>

<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>It was a great day (although stinking hot) and I really enjoyed wandering the streets and admiring the creative and colourful <em>alfombras</em>. We went to another town for lunch, and by the time we returned to Comayagua all the sawdust had been swept up and cleared away.</p>
<p>To me, it made the whole day feel a little magical, and that the sawdust was akin to fairy dust. Rather than imagining Tinkerbell and co.&#8217;s involvement, I probably should have been reflecting on more religious themes, but I have always been prone to flights of fancy.</p>
<p>Although I don&#8217;t think you need to be religious to appreciate the time, effort and artistry that went into each <em>alfombra</em>. They were an impressive sight and I&#8217;m thrilled we were able to visit Comayagua during this special time.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/829/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/829/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=829&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://honduranhiatus.wordpress.com/2013/03/31/sawdust-never-looked-so-good/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>32</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/5284c7ae6ce06036cd44e8380206c97e?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">honduranhiatus</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image18.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Making the finishing touches on an alfombra. You can see some of the stencils used in the background.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image30.jpg?w=112" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Bags of colourful sawdust ready to be used.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image31.jpg?w=112" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Adding the final piece of the puzzle.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image25.jpg?w=112" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Pesticide sprayers (filled with water) are used to dampen the alfombras so they don&#039;t blow away.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image28.jpg?w=112" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Many alfombras have ladders next to them you can climb to take photos.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image29.jpg?w=112" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">A photo of an alfombra taken from one of the ladders.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image21.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">A floral alfombra viewed from a slightly different angle.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image27.jpg?w=112" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">For a few hours the main streets of Comayagua are transformed by bright colours and intricately designed alfombras.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image22.jpg?w=112" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Some of the alfombras also use seeds, grains, rice and coffee beans to create their amazing artwork.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image24.jpg?w=112" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">This little sheep is made from popcorn!</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image26.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Even eggs can be used to create alfombra artwork.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image33.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">I also spotted some capsicums used to accent one alfombra&#039;s border.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image32.jpg?w=112" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Thousands of tourists roam the colonial streets of Comayagua each year to admire the alfombras before they disappear.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image19.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The religious procession that takes the same pathway as the alfombras.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://honduranhiatus.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image20.jpg?w=112" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">After the procession has passed the alfombras are smooshed into a colourful mess.</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Evidence of Things Not Seen</title>
		<link>http://caramichelestrickland.wordpress.com/2013/04/01/the-evidence-of-things-not-seen/</link>
		<comments>http://caramichelestrickland.wordpress.com/2013/04/01/the-evidence-of-things-not-seen/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 13:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>misscaramichele</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[God]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[musings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[#1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[basketball]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Go Zags]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gonzaga University]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hebrews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hebrews 11:1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[March Madness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sports metaphor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zags]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://caramichelestrickland.wordpress.com/?p=1485</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Going into the madness of March, my little city had a feather in its&#8217; cap: a number one seed. I&#8217;ve been used to thinking of Gonzaga University as a tier three law school (which is it), but this winter and early spring, it has also been a basketball force to be reckoned with. I&#8217;ve been [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1485&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://caramichelestrickland.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/uspw_7064260_crop_exact.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-1486" alt="zags #1" src="http://caramichelestrickland.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/uspw_7064260_crop_exact.jpg?w=529&#038;h=358" width="529" height="358" /></a></p>
<p>Going into the madness of March, my little city had a feather in its&#8217; cap: a number one seed.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve been used to thinking of Gonzaga University as a tier three law school (which is it), but this winter and early spring, it has also been a basketball force to be reckoned with.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve been slowly getting my feet wet in the sports world, not pushing myself too hard. Basketball is hard for me, I can&#8217;t tell which shots are worth more points, and I&#8217;m distracted by the squeakiness of the players&#8217; shoes. As February came to a close, I would have had to have been living under a rock to not be aware of how great Gonzaga (or the Zags, as we affectionately refer to them) was doing.</p>
<p>It was contagious.</p>
<p>When I bought my car, it came with a Gonzaga decal which is located (unfortunately) right over the rear defrost strips on my window. Even though I have no affiliation with Gonzaga, it sure looks like I do. During this time, I got a lot of nods, thumbs up and &#8220;Go Zags!&#8221;</p>
<p>Everywhere I went, people were wearing Zags gear. Facebook was covered with news about each game (from a wide range of people). The local newspaper sent out &#8220;Go Zags&#8221; signs and people had them up in their windows, or on their front doors. Businesses used their signs to wish the Zags good luck.</p>
<p>I began to follow the games. I got excited and started talking about it with people, because it&#8217;s exciting to be number one, especially for a town that has no major league sports teams. The Zags are our boys.</p>
<p>My copy of Sports Illustrated came, complete with a front page picture of the Zags (some of you are trying to figure out if you read that sentence about me getting Sports Illustrated correctly, yes, yes you did).</p>
<p><a href="http://caramichelestrickland.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/si_gonzaga-450x600.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1487" alt="si_gonzaga" src="http://caramichelestrickland.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/si_gonzaga-450x600.jpg?w=450&#038;h=600" width="450" height="600" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Then, we played a game against Wichita. After work, I went to a sports bar to watch the game with my dad. It was close, too close, and we were behind too often. As it happened, we were behind at the crucial moment: when the game ended.</p>
<p>Stunned, we, the fans, left the bar. In an instant, our number one team had been asked to step out of the dance. What would we do now? What would we talk about? For weeks we had been stopping people in #1 t-shirts and Zag hoodies in grocery stores to crow triumphantly. All this success had created a community.</p>
<p>This is my first real March Madness, and I waited to see what would happen next.</p>
<p>After a while, I noticed that the signs were still in my neighbors&#8217; windows, the local businesses had not removed their tributes and well wishes, people still wore their Gonzaga gear. It reminded me, a little, of the way that Christmas lights stay up, long after Christmas is over. Eventually, those lights will be forward thinking, something you don&#8217;t have to hang like everyone else does in the midst of falling snow.</p>
<p>I am still learning about what it means to be a sports fan, and this March has taught me something about that, and about faith. The signs, the gear, the stickers and deposit checks written for season tickets are an investment: they are an expression of faith. Gonzaga will not play basketball more this season, but they will play next season. Our time is not right now, but it will come.</p>
<p>I think that this is another thing that I, as a Christian, can learn from the world of sports. Sometimes, things do not look good: they end, they change, they fail. Sometimes I take this to heart. I forget to keep wearing my faith, the evidence of things unseen, even in the face of present defeat.</p>
<p><a href="http://caramichelestrickland.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/go-zags-1920x1600.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-1489" alt="go-zags" src="http://caramichelestrickland.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/go-zags-1920x1600.jpg?w=529&#038;h=440" width="529" height="440" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://caramichelestrickland.wordpress.com/category/god/'>God</a>, <a href='http://caramichelestrickland.wordpress.com/category/life/'>life</a>, <a href='http://caramichelestrickland.wordpress.com/category/musings/'>musings</a>, <a href='http://caramichelestrickland.wordpress.com/category/sports/'>sports</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1485/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1485/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1485&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://caramichelestrickland.wordpress.com/2013/04/01/the-evidence-of-things-not-seen/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/33f60782991f3f385527d49ed9d981b7?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F0.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">misscaramichele</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://caramichelestrickland.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/uspw_7064260_crop_exact.jpg?w=529" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">zags #1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://caramichelestrickland.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/si_gonzaga-450x600.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">si_gonzaga</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://caramichelestrickland.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/go-zags-1920x1600.jpg?w=529" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">go-zags</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Kevin Ware Injury in the Twitter World</title>
		<link>http://irrelephantjournalism.wordpress.com/2013/04/01/the-kevin-ware-injury-in-the-twitter-world/</link>
		<comments>http://irrelephantjournalism.wordpress.com/2013/04/01/the-kevin-ware-injury-in-the-twitter-world/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 15:38:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>rdl24</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Journalism And Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sports & Twitter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Basketball]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Final Four]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gruesome]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Injury]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kevin Ware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marcus Lattimore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://irrelephantjournalism.wordpress.com/?p=2265</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In the midst of Louisville&#8217;s 85-63, Final Four clinching victory over the Duke Blue Devils on Sunday, Cardinal sophomore Kevin Ware suffered quite possibly the most gruesome leg injury in the history of competitive sports. The screenshot seen below shows the full extent of his injury (WARNING &#8211; EXTREMELY GRAPHIC). Ware suffered a compound fracture [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2265&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://irrelephantjournalism.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/kevin-ware-post.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image" id="i-2268" alt="Image" src="http://irrelephantjournalism.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/kevin-ware-post.jpg?w=487" /></a></p>
<p>In the midst of Louisville&#8217;s <a href="http://scores.espn.go.com/ncb/recap?gameId=330900097" target="_blank">85-63, Final Four clinching victory</a> over the Duke Blue Devils on Sunday, Cardinal sophomore Kevin Ware suffered quite possibly <a href="http://deadspin.com/kevin-ware-suffered-maybe-the-most-gruesome-injury-in-t-464789219" target="_blank">the most gruesome leg injury</a> in the history of competitive sports.</p>
<p>The screenshot seen below shows the full extent of his injury (WARNING &#8211; EXTREMELY GRAPHIC). Ware suffered a compound fracture &#8211; also known as an open fracture &#8211; which occurs when there is a break in the skin surrounding a broken bone. In Ware&#8217;s case, the bone was literally protruding through the skin.</p>
<p><a href="http://irrelephantjournalism.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/sports-gruesome-injuries-kevin-ware.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image" id="i-2276" alt="Image" src="http://irrelephantjournalism.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/sports-gruesome-injuries-kevin-ware.jpg?w=487" /></a></p>
<p>While this is nonetheless a horrific and tragic event for the young man, the issue immediately surrounding the injury was not how the injury would impact Ware&#8217;s career or if Louisville could beat Duke.</p>
<p>But instead, the overriding topic of discussion was: should the injury &#8211; in the 24/7 news cycle, internet era &#8211; be shown and looped continuously for everyone to see.</p>
<p>Almost instantly, following the injury, a massive debate started to arise on Twitter over CBS&#8217; coverage.</p>
<p>The network replayed video of the injury once or twice when it initially occurred, but they eventually (and correctly) opted to show reaction shots from Ware&#8217;s teammates and Duke opponents instead.</p>
<p>But ultimately, did CBS handle it correctly?</p>
<p>Richard Deitsch of Sports Illustrated believes so, disagreeing with ESPN&#8217;s Bill Simmons on how the coverage was handled.</p>
<p><a href="http://irrelephantjournalism.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/screen-shot-2013-04-01-at-10-07-39-am.png"><img class="size-full wp-image" id="i-2286" alt="Image" src="http://irrelephantjournalism.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/screen-shot-2013-04-01-at-10-07-39-am.png?w=487" /></a></p>
<p>From there, the talk on Twitter spilled over to whether or not the injury should be made into <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Graphics_Interchange_Format" target="_blank">a GIF</a> and linked and shared for everyone to see.</p>
<p>SB Nation, the go-to site for sports GIFs, respectfully declined to make a GIF of the injury tweeting this instead.</p>
<p><a href="http://irrelephantjournalism.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/screen-shot-2013-04-01-at-10-11-26-am.png"><img class="size-full wp-image" id="i-2293" alt="Image" src="http://irrelephantjournalism.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/screen-shot-2013-04-01-at-10-11-26-am.png?w=487" /></a></p>
<p>Instead of showing the actual injury, SB Nation rounded up GIFs of <a href="http://www.sbnation.com/college-basketball/2013/3/31/4168112/kevin-ware-suffers-awful-injury-teammates-react-emotionally" target="_blank">of reaction shots</a> of the Louisville and Duke players.</p>
<p>All told, the way in which the &#8220;internet community&#8221; handled the injury, in terms of choosing a compassionate, sympathetic approach as opposed to a schadenfreude, voyeuristic approach couldn&#8217;t have been better.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/monkeysee/2013/04/01/175905224/viewer-discretion-deciding-when-to-look-away?" target="_blank">Some agree</a> while others <a href="http://www.sportsonearth.com/article/43585894/" target="_blank">do not.</a></p>
<p>However, to me, discretion was certainly the better part of valor for both CBS and ESPN, as well as the Twitter community. Injuries like this <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sTEUD8if1wY" target="_blank">have happened before</a>. Just because one has the means and technology to watch it and distribute it on a continuous loop doesn&#8217;t mean one should.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s hope that as we move forward, this is the rule and not the exception.</p>
<p><a href="http://irrelephantjournalism.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/article-ware-0331.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image" id="i-2312" alt="Image" src="http://irrelephantjournalism.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/article-ware-0331.jpg?w=487" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2265/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2265/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2265&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://irrelephantjournalism.wordpress.com/2013/04/01/the-kevin-ware-injury-in-the-twitter-world/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/e2a9e09e00d9abbdac8b9fb062c80da9?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">rdl24</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://irrelephantjournalism.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/kevin-ware-post.jpg?w=487" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://irrelephantjournalism.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/sports-gruesome-injuries-kevin-ware.jpg?w=487" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://irrelephantjournalism.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/screen-shot-2013-04-01-at-10-07-39-am.png?w=487" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://irrelephantjournalism.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/screen-shot-2013-04-01-at-10-11-26-am.png?w=487" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://irrelephantjournalism.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/article-ware-0331.jpg?w=487" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Impressionism, Fashion, and Modernity</title>
		<link>http://pretemoiparis.com/2013/03/31/impressionism-fashion-and-modernity/</link>
		<comments>http://pretemoiparis.com/2013/03/31/impressionism-fashion-and-modernity/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 17:05:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>pretemoiparis</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exposition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[French culture abroad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Museums/Expos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Art and fashion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Frank Cierpial]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Impressionism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Impressionist expo in NYC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[monet]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://pretemoiparis.com/?p=6164</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Post by Frank Cierpial Paris has always been a city loved by artists. How can it not be? Paris is beautiful twenty four hours a day in every light. In Paris, art is everywhere. From every building to every café crème, beauty is a big part of life in Paris. New York is the opposite. [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=6164&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://pretemoiparis.com/2013/03/31/impressionism-fashion-and-modernity/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/d06aee710dcbbf22fa64960b1fd9f7c6?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F1.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">pretemoiparis</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://pretemoiparis.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/576228_268547019921309_940241069_n-e1361105428517.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Frank Cierpial</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://www.metmuseum.org/~/media/Images/Visit/Plan%20Your%20Visit/getting_here.ashx?mw=495" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://pretemoiparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screenshot-from-2013-04-01-215811.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2013-04-01 21:58:11</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://pretemoiparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/123.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Women in the Garden - Claude Monet</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://pretemoiparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/456.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">456</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://pretemoiparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/789.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">789</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://pretemoiparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/91011.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">91011</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://pretemoiparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/121314.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">121314</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ethics vs. Art</title>
		<link>http://factorydiaries.com.au/2013/03/31/ponder-this-ethics-vs-art/</link>
		<comments>http://factorydiaries.com.au/2013/03/31/ponder-this-ethics-vs-art/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 04:35:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Factory Diaries</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ponder This]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://factorydiaries.com.au/?p=750</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Ok, so let&#8217;s nip this in the bud straight off the bat: I HATE HAVING THIS ARGUMENT! Seriously, there is nothing that irks me more than having a &#8220;what is art?&#8221; debate. Especially if it involves having it with a pompous, Art History Major who never really could leave the romantic gore of the Renaissance period [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=750&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ok, so let&#8217;s nip this in the bud straight off the bat: I HATE HAVING THIS ARGUMENT! Seriously, there is nothing that irks me more than having a &#8220;what is art?&#8221; debate. Especially if it involves having it with a pompous, Art History Major who never really could leave the romantic gore of the Renaissance period behind. Although I am an artist and a complete art enthusiast, I really couldn&#8217;t give two fracks about how people define art. It isn&#8217;t important. Your opinion<span style="color:#ff0000;"> <span style="color:#000000;">of an artwork</span></span> in no way alters my own. While I am completely open to listening to it and perhaps even learning from it, at the end of the day just because you don&#8217;t view something as art it doesn&#8217;t mean that I don&#8217;t. That being said, I get very lost and conflicted when an ethical issue comes into play. I am torn between my stance on &#8216;you can&#8217;t define art!&#8217; and my moral code.</p>
<p>Let me explain.</p>
<p>During my hours and hours and hours (I need a life) of artistic internet scrolling and essay reading, I have stumbled across a few people talking about the Holocaust. (Bet ya didn&#8217;t see that one coming!). While reading these articles I had two horrible experiences.; the first one being that the art community suddenly sickened me a little. It made me queasy, uncomfortable and very, very sad.</p>
<p>Let me explain a little further.</p>
<p>In 2001, a French historian and philosopher by the name of Georges Didi-Huberman presented an exhibition entitled<em> Four Pieces of Film Snatched from Hell. </em>The exhibition featured four photographs that were miraculously smuggled out of Auschwitz by members of the Jewish Sonderkommando. For those who aren&#8217;t familiar, the Jewish Sonderkommando were Jewish prisoners held in Death Camps, forced on the threat of their own deaths to aid in the disposal of bodies from the gas chambers (for more information and perhaps a greater understanding you can read this <a href="http://books.google.com.au/books?id=mub823JQrdUC&amp;pg=PA501&amp;dq=Sonderkommandos+Auschwitz+451&amp;num=100&amp;client=firefox-a&amp;cd=2&amp;redir_esc=y#v=onepage&amp;q=451&amp;f=false">free ebook</a>). The Sonderkommando took photographs at the risk of their own lives in the hopes of one day informing people of what was really happening in the Death Camps.</p>
<p>I have to take a moment here to really commend some of the members of the art community who have debated this issue of ethics on their websites and blogs, for not casually posting the photos on their pages. If you are intrigued enough to want to see the photos for yourself (and by all accounts this is your right) you can easily find the images by searching the exhibit. Personally, I did not feel comfortable reposting these images on Factory Diaries as they depict the torture and death of innocent people. This may be an issue of censorship but this is my site, so suck it <img src='http://s1.wp.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif' alt=';)' class='wp-smiley' /> </p>
<p>Ok ,so now that I have caught you up to speed on what I am talking about it, let us get to the bottom of why.</p>
<p>While I believe that the photographs taken by the Sonderkommando should be seen and are very important in attempting to understand exactly what happened in a horrifying period in world history, I could not be more disgusted at the thought of an art gallery displaying these images. The idea of the gallery owners throwing a big, fancy opening night, serving champagne and having the patrons stare at the evil in front of them. The idea that instead of learning, feeling and experiencing the horror depicted in the photographs, they instead debate whether or not these images should be considered art.</p>
<p>ARE YOU SERIOUS?!</p>
<p>My immediate reaction to this concept was no. NO NO NO NO NO. This is not art. It was never intended to be art and the idea that anyone could look at those images and see them as art was disturbing to me (queue horrible experience number 2 when I realise I have in fact drawn my own line on what is and isn&#8217;t art).</p>
<p>But, I am almost alone in this opinion, and that realisation almost broke my heart.</p>
<p>While studies have shown that the majority of people who view these photographs can see why those of Jewish decent would be upset by these images being displayed as art, most people agree that art has no bounds and nothing is exempt from art&#8217;s reach.</p>
<p>Again, ARE YOU SERIOUS?!</p>
<p>Quite frankly it is my right as a human being, not as a descendant of the Jewish faith, to be appalled by these images being considered art. When those same people, who viewed these photographs as art, were asked if they would be upset if a photograph of one of their family members&#8217; deaths was being displayed as art  they said yes, but accepted that it is now a part of life and that this could indeed happen.</p>
<p>Um. WHAT?!</p>
<p>Part of life? I don&#8217;t know what version of The Lion King you saw as a kid but I don&#8217;t remember Mufasa explaining that the death and torture of thousands of innocent people could be used for your visual enjoyment.</p>
<p>On the other side of this argument sits people who believe that this exhibit is no different than the Holocaust being depicted in film or literature, and that Death Camps are now &#8216;tourist attractions&#8217;. Forgive me, but I have to wholeheartedly disagree. Firstly, have you ever visited a Death Camp? I have. Let me tell you, there is nothing &#8216;touristy&#8217; about them. For the most part they are run by volunteers and every single person who visits them is there to learn. No one is there for a good time. Secondly, there is a huge difference between a film or literary interpretation/representation of the Holocaust and actual photographs taken, at the risk of losing lives, in order to hopefully inform people of what actually happened in Auschwitz. An interpretation of events is remarkably different to a visual recording of people losing their lives.</p>
<p>It took a lot for me to admit that, on some level, I clearly do have a strong stance on the issue of &#8216;what is art?&#8217;. My saving grace is that I find myself drawing this line as a compassionate and moral human being and not as a snooty art snob. So, as I sit here typing I am fully aware that art CAN have no bounds and doesn&#8217;t HAVE to be restricted by any kind of moral code&#8230; But I am starting to wonder if it SHOULD be.</p>
<p>What do you think?</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/750/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/750/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=750&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://factorydiaries.com.au/2013/03/31/ponder-this-ethics-vs-art/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>27</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://factorydiariesblog.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/ethics.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://factorydiariesblog.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/ethics.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ETHICS</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/fff03d7dc7eab8c56aca19232ff2644a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">factorydiariesblog</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Superheroine Spotlight: Wonder Woman</title>
		<link>http://journeyintoawesome.wordpress.com/2013/03/31/womens-history-month-superheroine-spotlight-wonder-woman/</link>
		<comments>http://journeyintoawesome.wordpress.com/2013/03/31/womens-history-month-superheroine-spotlight-wonder-woman/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 02:30:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Daniel Amrhein</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Comics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Women in Comics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comic books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DC comics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diversity in comics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[female comic book characters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[feminism in comics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gender in comics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gender studies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Justice League]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sexism in comics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sociology in comics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[superheroines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women in comics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[womens studies]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://journeyintoawesome.wordpress.com/?p=2085</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Today, the last day of Women&#8217;s History Month, I&#8217;d like to take a closer look at the most influential and recognizable superheroine in comics, Wonder Woman. She may not be the the first comic book superheroine or even the first heroine to star in her own comic, but you can&#8217;t deny the impact that Wonder Woman has had [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2085&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://journeyintoawesome.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/wonder_woman_1_1942.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-2362" style="border:5px solid black;margin:10px;" alt="Wonder Woman #1 (summer of 1942)" src="http://journeyintoawesome.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/wonder_woman_1_1942.jpg?w=220&#038;h=300" width="220" height="300" /></a>Today, the last day of <a title="Superheroines for Women’s History Month" href="http://journeyintoawesome.wordpress.com/2013/03/01/superheroines-for-womens-history-month/" target="_blank">Women&#8217;s History Month</a>, I&#8217;d like to take a closer look at the most influential and recognizable superheroine in comics, Wonder Woman.</p>
<p>She may not be the <a title="Women’s History Month Superheroine Spotlight: Olga Mesmer, Fantomah, and Woman in Red" href="http://journeyintoawesome.wordpress.com/2013/03/11/womens-history-month-superheroine-spotlight-olga-mesmer-fantomah-and-woman-in-red/" target="_blank">the first comic book superheroine</a> or even the<a title="Women’s History Month Superheroine Spotlight: Sheena, Queen of the Jungle" href="http://journeyintoawesome.wordpress.com/2013/03/04/womens-history-month-superheroine-spotlight-sheena-queen-of-the-jungle/" target="_blank"> first heroine to star in her own comic</a>, but you can&#8217;t deny the impact that Wonder Woman has had on the history of comics and on our cultural as a whole.</p>
<p>As a character with strong feminist roots, Wonder Woman has certainly seen her share of ups and downs throughout her publication.<span id="more-2085"></span></p>
<p>Created by Dr. William Moulton Marston and his wife Elizabeth Holloway Marston, Wonder Woman first appeared in an 8-page story in <em>All Star Comics</em> #8 (December 1941) and would later go on to star in her own title in the summer of 1942.</p>
<p>Dr. Marston was a Harvard-trained psychologist and the inventor of the polygraph (a legacy that&#8217;s clearly reflected in Wonder Woman&#8217;s Lasso of Truth). <a title="CBLDF - Tales From the Code: Whatever Happened to the Amazing Amazon–Wonder Woman Bound by Censorship" href="http://cbldf.org/2012/10/tales-from-the-code-whatever-happened-to-the-amazing-amazon-wonder-woman-bound-by-censorship/" target="_blank">He was also a staunch feminist</a>. However, instead of advocating for an equal society, Marton championed a matriarchy in which women would use their femininity to control and dominate men (who he regarded as inherently more violent and greedy).</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://journeyintoawesome.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/ares_aphrodite_wonder_woman_1.png"><img class="wp-image-2366 alignnone" style="border:5px solid black;margin:10px;" alt="Ares and Aphrodite argue in Wonder Woman (1942) #1" src="http://journeyintoawesome.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/ares_aphrodite_wonder_woman_1.png?w=450&#038;h=299" width="450" height="299" /></a></p>
<p>Obviously, this belief is problematic because placing women on a pedestal is still a form of objectification.</p>
<p><a href="http://journeyintoawesome.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/diana_gets_costume_wonder_woman_1.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-2356" style="border:5px solid black;margin:10px;" alt="Steriotypes about women in Wonder Woman #1 (1942)" src="http://journeyintoawesome.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/diana_gets_costume_wonder_woman_1.jpg?w=210&#038;h=292" width="210" height="292" /></a>As a member of the DC Editorial Advisory Board, Marston came to realize a severe lack of female characters and role models in comics. To remedy this, he created the character of Wonder Woman, loosely based on his wife Elizabeth Marston and Olive Byrne, a live-in student who was involved in a polyamorous relationship with the Marstons.</p>
<p>Marston&#8217;s belief of woman&#8217;s superiority and his obsession with bondage and the master/slave relationship would both become central theme&#8217;s of early Wonder Woman stories. These stories also contain a surprising amount of stereotypes about women.</p>
<p><a href="http://journeyintoawesome.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/all-star_comics_wonder_woman_jsa_secretary.png"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-2355" style="border:5px solid black;margin:10px;" alt="Wonder Woman becomes the JSA's secretary" src="http://journeyintoawesome.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/all-star_comics_wonder_woman_jsa_secretary.png?w=180&#038;h=300" width="180" height="300" /></a>Despite these issues, Wonder Woman&#8217;s empowering message and uniqueness helped the heroine to quickly find a market. That&#8217;s why it&#8217;s not surprising that the decision was made to give Wonder Woman a place on the JSA. Sadly, <a title="Strained Circumstances- Wonder Woman: Secretary Of The Justice Society Of America" href="http://thanley.wordpress.com/2012/06/25/wonder-woman-secretary-of-the-justice-society-of-america/" target="_blank">she was only bestowed the &#8220;honor&#8221; of becoming their secretary</a>.</p>
<p>This insult is only compounded by the fact that she was physically more powerful than the other JSA members. Not to mention that her book was actually selling better than those of the male JSAers.</p>
<p>But, with Marston’s death in 1947, Wonder Woman would soon lost sight of her feminist roots completely.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://journeyintoawesome.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/all-star_comics_role_call.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-2354" style="border:5px solid black;margin:10px;" alt="Wonder Woman listed at the JSA's secretary" src="http://journeyintoawesome.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/all-star_comics_role_call.jpg?w=450&#038;h=157" width="450" height="157" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://journeyintoawesome.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/sensation_comics_9_romance_wonder_woman_comic.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-2358" style="border:5px solid black;margin:10px;" alt="Steve Trevor carrying Wonder Woman" src="http://journeyintoawesome.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/sensation_comics_9_romance_wonder_woman_comic.jpg?w=212&#038;h=300" width="212" height="300" /></a>With women leaving the factories and no Nazis to fight, the publisher decided that it was the perfect time to reboot Wonder Woman as the star of a romance comic. Gone was the strong, feminist Diana of the early &#8217;40s. Instead, fans were left with a Wonder Woman who liked to be princess-carried across shallow streams.</p>
<p>Of course, this was not the only radical transformation the character would undergo. The late 1960 saw the rise of  the &#8220;Mod Girl Wonder Woman&#8221; when Dinan gave up her powers, opened a mod boutique, and gained a male mentor and slew of new love interests.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://journeyintoawesome.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/wonder_woman_ad.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-2360" style="border:5px solid black;margin:10px;" alt="The New Mod Wonder Woman" src="http://journeyintoawesome.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/wonder_woman_ad.jpg?w=450&#038;h=233" width="450" height="233" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Feminist icon <a title="Comic Book Movie - Myth Understood: Wonder Woman: Feminist icon or Exploitative Fantasy?" href="http://www.comicbookmovie.com/fansites/betaraysyr/news/?a=66698" target="_blank">Gloria Steinem was not too happy about about this</a>, but she&#8217;s hardly alone in her disdain.</p>
<p><a href="http://journeyintoawesome.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/wonder_woman_178.jpg"><img class="alignleft  wp-image-2359" style="border:5px solid black;margin:10px;" alt="&quot;Mod Girl Wonder Woman&quot; " src="http://journeyintoawesome.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/wonder_woman_178.jpg?w=198&#038;h=300" width="198" height="300" /></a>As <a title="Bitch Magazine - Female Bonding" href="http://bitchmagazine.org/article/female-bonding" target="_blank">KL Pereira puts it</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;the new Wonder Woman was a caricature, a weak figure with no personality or wit. Denied her erotic and feminist history, she became a virginal, domesticated figure whose goal of fighting injustice was abandoned for marriage and shopping&#8230; Diana Prince is stripped of her superpowers to become a mortal woman. One glance at the cover’s embellished print and fashionably mod Diana&#8230; says everything about the story that awaits readers inside: a veritable cacophony of hatboxes, shoes, and fashionable outfits. The most important thing about this Wonder Woman, it seemed, was the way she looked.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Like so many other female comic characters, Wonder Woman&#8217;s publication history is fraught with well-meaning mistakes, carelessness, and down right sexism. <em>However</em>, Wonder Woman perseveres.</p>
<p><a title="Wonder Women! The Untold Story of American Superheroines" href="http://journeyintoawesome.wordpress.com/2012/04/30/wonder-women-the-untold-story-of-american-superheroines/" target="_blank">Her cultural importance</a> is unrivaled by other superheroines and she is just as important today as she was when she was created more than seven decades ago.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><a href="http://journeyintoawesome.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/wonder-woman-new-52.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-2399" style="border:5px solid black;margin:10px;" alt="Wonder Woman #1 DC Comic's New 52" src="http://journeyintoawesome.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/wonder-woman-new-52.jpg?w=450&#038;h=197" width="450" height="197" /></a>Comment and share your favorite incarnation of Wonder Woman!</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2085/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2085/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2085&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://journeyintoawesome.wordpress.com/2013/03/31/womens-history-month-superheroine-spotlight-wonder-woman/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>24</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c760ca82740c911445aeb7ea784baa90?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=R" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">journeyintoawesome</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://journeyintoawesome.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/wonder_woman_1_1942.jpg?w=220" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Wonder Woman #1 (summer of 1942)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://journeyintoawesome.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/ares_aphrodite_wonder_woman_1.png?w=500" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ares and Aphrodite argue in Wonder Woman (1942) #1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://journeyintoawesome.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/diana_gets_costume_wonder_woman_1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Steriotypes about women in Wonder Woman #1 (1942)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://journeyintoawesome.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/all-star_comics_wonder_woman_jsa_secretary.png?w=180" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Wonder Woman becomes the JSA&#039;s secretary</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://journeyintoawesome.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/all-star_comics_role_call.jpg?w=500" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Wonder Woman listed at the JSA&#039;s secretary</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://journeyintoawesome.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/sensation_comics_9_romance_wonder_woman_comic.jpg?w=212" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Steve Trevor carrying Wonder Woman</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://journeyintoawesome.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/wonder_woman_ad.jpg?w=500" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The New Mod Wonder Woman</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://journeyintoawesome.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/wonder_woman_178.jpg?w=198" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">&#34;Mod Girl Wonder Woman&#34; </media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://journeyintoawesome.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/wonder-woman-new-52.jpg?w=500" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Wonder Woman #1 DC Comic&#039;s New 52</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Into the Sunset</title>
		<link>http://surroundedbyimbeciles.wordpress.com/2013/04/01/into-the-sunset/</link>
		<comments>http://surroundedbyimbeciles.wordpress.com/2013/04/01/into-the-sunset/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 04:40:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Rick</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Batman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Clint Eastwood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cowboys and Aliens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Don Johnson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Harley Davidson and the Marlboro Man]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[John Wayne]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mickey Rourke]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pale Rider]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the Bad and the Ugly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Dark Knight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Good]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Outlaw Josey Wales]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Searchers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Westerns]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://surroundedbyimbeciles.wordpress.com/?p=3285</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s a cliché of the western movie genre. The hero has lived through some adventure, and, when it&#8217;s over, he gets on his horse and rides into the sunset. I have watched that scene dozens of times, and it fascinates me every time. What happens when they disappear over the horizon? What happens after the &#8220;The [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3285&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s a cliché of the western movie genre. The hero has lived through some adventure, and, when it&#8217;s over, he gets on his horse and rides into the sunset. I have watched that scene dozens of times, and it fascinates me every time.</p>
<p>What happens when they disappear over the horizon? What happens after the &#8220;The End&#8221; placard covers the screen? Does the hero take time off before finding another adventure? Does he die of wounds suffered during the movie? Does he live happily ever after in some frontier town?</p>
<p>All of those questions go through my mind because I have to know the rest of the story. It doesn&#8217;t matter how bad the movie is. I still want to know what happens after the credits roll. However, something else goes through my mind, as well. The &#8220;into the sunset&#8221; scene isn&#8217;t always the same.</p>
<p>One of the greatest &#8220;into the sunset&#8221; scenes doesn&#8217;t even have a horse. In <em>The Searchers</em>, Ethan Edwards spends years attempting to rescue his niece from her Comanche captors. When he returns with her, everyone goes into the house except for him. He turns and <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1aHf7VdOpsE">walks into the desert</a> as the door closes behind him.<a href="http://surroundedbyimbeciles.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/the-searchers.png"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-3287" alt="The Searchers" src="http://surroundedbyimbeciles.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/the-searchers.png?w=300&#038;h=164" width="300" height="164" /></a></p>
<p>Where did Edwards go? Did he leave because most of his family was dead? Did he wander because there was no purpose in his life? All of the wars were over. Or, did he think back over the past years before turning around and coming back?</p>
<p>John Wayne walked away in <em>The Searchers</em>, but Clint Eastwood could be the king of &#8220;into the sunset&#8221; rides. In <em>The Outlaw Josey Wales</em>, he is bleeding as he rides away. Does he live? If so, then does he go back to the friends that he has gained throughout the movie? Or, does he disappear from history?</p>
<p>Sometimes, he completely disappears because we really don&#8217;t know what he is. In <em>Pale Rider</em>, Eastwood evaporates from the scene. Is he some kind of spirit or is he just a mysterious gunman?</p>
<p>Those were great, but my favorite Eastwood ending comes from <em>The Good, the Bad and the Ugly</em>. Blondie leaves Tuco with a noose around his neck and gold at his feet. After an impossible rifle shot to save Tuco, <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bIhqi0kVxDQ">Blondie rides away</a> to one of the greatest movie scores of all time.</p>
<p>A more recent western has an &#8220;into the sunset&#8221; scene at the end. The difference is the adventure that precedes it. In <em>Cowboys and Aliens</em>, James Bond defeats aliens with the help of Indiana Jones. Oh, Boyd Crowder helps out, too. This time the hero is truly a loner. His wife is dead. His alien love interest is dead. He is considered dead. Heck, the dog doesn&#8217;t even go with him. In this one, the hero probably went somewhere and cried.</p>
<p>The cool thing about &#8220;into the sunset&#8221; scenes is that they are no longer reserved for westerns only. Remember what happened at the end of <em>The Dark Knight</em>? He agrees to be the fall guy and live life as a villain. Then, he hops on his jacked out motorcycle and <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jAj20UOc3DE">rides into a tunnel</a>. There is no sunset, but there is a cool speech and some kind of light up ahead. I hope it&#8217;s not a train.<a href="http://surroundedbyimbeciles.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/the-dark-knight.png"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-3291" alt="The Dark Knight" src="http://surroundedbyimbeciles.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/the-dark-knight.png?w=300&#038;h=123" width="300" height="123" /></a></p>
<p>Everybody knows what happened to him after that because we have sequels now. There should not have been a sequel to this one. Wondering what happened to Batman was a lot better than knowing that he faked his death and ended up with Catwoman.</p>
<p>Ok, so John Wayne, Clint Eastwood, James Bond and Batman all have had great scenes to end movies. However my favorite &#8220;into the sunset&#8221; scene comes from a movie that isn&#8217;t very good. At the end of <em>Harley Davidson and the Marlboro Man</em>, Don Johnson, as Marlboro, goes back to his roots and enters a rodeo. At the same time, Mickey Rourke, as Harley, <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qW64tq30egw">rides his motorcycle</a> into the sunset with an 80s vixen on the back and Black Eyed Susan playing in the background.<a href="http://surroundedbyimbeciles.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/harley-ending.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3294" alt="Harley Ending" src="http://surroundedbyimbeciles.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/harley-ending.png?w=299&#038;h=168" width="299" height="168" /></a></p>
<p>Why is that my favorite? Because it&#8217;s the only one that seems like a happy ending. He&#8217;s not alone. He&#8217;s not wounded. And, there is no doubt that something good is going to happen further down the road.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3285/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3285/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3285&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://surroundedbyimbeciles.wordpress.com/2013/04/01/into-the-sunset/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>52</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a92db7a1e140c51397348f4fda8dcea6?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lealco74</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://surroundedbyimbeciles.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/the-searchers.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The Searchers</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://surroundedbyimbeciles.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/the-dark-knight.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The Dark Knight</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://surroundedbyimbeciles.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/harley-ending.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Harley Ending</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Biological Basis of Orchestra Seating</title>
		<link>http://brainsidea.wordpress.com/2013/03/28/the-biological-basis-of-orchestra-seating/</link>
		<comments>http://brainsidea.wordpress.com/2013/03/28/the-biological-basis-of-orchestra-seating/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 21:36:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Richard Kunert</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Brain quirks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cognitive Science Applications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Home Replications]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Richard Kunert]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diana Deutsch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Musician]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Orchestra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Primary auditory cortex]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stringed]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brainsidea.wordpress.com/?p=1176</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Many cultural conventions appear like the result of historical accidents. The QWERTY – keyboard is a typical example: the technical requirements of early typewriters still determine the computer keyboard that I write this text on, even though by now technical advances would allow for a far more efficient design. Some culturally accepted oddities, however, appear [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1176&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h4 style="padding-left:30px;"><strong>Many cultural conventions appear like the result of historical accidents. The QWERTY – keyboard is a typical example: the technical requirements of early typewriters still determine the computer keyboard that I write this text on, even though by now technical advances would allow for a far more efficient design. Some culturally accepted oddities, however, appear to reflect the biological requirements of human beings. The way musicians are seated in an orchestra is one such case, but the listener is, surprisingly, not the beneficiary.</strong></h4>
<h5 style="padding-left:30px;"></h5>
<h5 style="padding-left:30px;">When one goes to a concert one typically sees a seating somewhat like the one below: strings in the front, then woodwinds further back, then brass. What is less obvious is that, in general, higher pitched instruments are seated on the left and lower pitched instruments on the right. The strings show this pattern perfectly: from left to right one sees violins, violas, cellos and then basses. Choirs show the same pattern: higher voices (soprano and tenor) stand left of the lower voices (alt and basses). Why is that?</h5>
<p><span style="color:#ffffff;">.</span></p>
<h5 style="padding-left:30px;"></h5>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 490px"><a href="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/e/e1/Symfonieorkest_Nijmegen.jpg"><img class=" " alt="orchestra; seating arrangement; Nijmegen; Nijmegen studenten orkest" src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/e/e1/Symfonieorkest_Nijmegen.jpg" width="480" height="289" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">An orchestra I have personally performed with.</p></div>
<h5 style="padding-left:30px;"></h5>
<h5 style="padding-left:30px;"><span style="color:#ffffff;">.</span></h5>
<h5 style="padding-left:30px;">It turns out that this is not a historical accident but instead a biological requirement. Diana Deutsch has used a series of audio illusions which all showed a curious pattern: when you present two series of tones each to one ear, you have the illusion that the high tones are being played to your right ear and the low ones to the left ear. In case you don’t believe me, listen to this illustration of Deutsch’s scale illusion:</h5>
<h5 style="padding-left:30px;"><span style="color:#ffffff;">.</span></h5>
<h5 style="padding-left:30px;"><span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='640' height='390' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/C5xLOfUzM4M?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span></h5>
<h5 style="padding-left:30px;"><span style="color:#ffffff;">.</span></h5>
<h5 style="padding-left:30px;">Apparently, there is a right ear advantage for high tones. So, seating the higher instruments on the left side (as seen on the photo) makes complete sense as this way musicians on stage tend to hear higher tones coming from their right. However, from the point of view of the audience this is actually a really bad idea as their right ear advantage is not taken into account. It turns out that orchestra seating arrangements are not favouring the hearing of the audience or the conductor but instead the musicians!</h5>
<h5 style="padding-left:30px;"></h5>
<h5 style="padding-left:30px;">The right ear advantage for high tones is even mirrored in musicians’ brains. We know that the right ear projects mostly to the left auditory cortex and vice versa for the left ear. So, one would expect that people who play high instruments have trained their right ear / left auditory cortex the most when they practiced their craft. These training effects should be mirrored in differences in cortex size. This would mean that people sitting on the left in an orchestra have bigger left auditory cortices. In a fascinating article Schneider and colleagues showed that by and large this is the case: professional musicians who play high instruments or instruments with a sharp attack (e.g., percussionists, piano players) tend to have greater left auditory cortices than right auditory cortices. Their figure says is all.</h5>
<h5 style="padding-left:30px;"><span style="color:#ffffff;">.</span></h5>
<div id="attachment_1177" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 779px"><a href="http://brainsidea.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/brain_orchestra_seating.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1177" alt="Schneider; orchestra; seating; brain; Heschl's gyrus; primary auditory cortex; cortical size" src="http://brainsidea.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/brain_orchestra_seating.jpg?w=769&#038;h=602" width="769" height="602" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">How the brains are seated in an orchestra.</p></div>
<h5 style="padding-left:30px;"><span style="color:#ffffff;">.</span></h5>
<h5 style="padding-left:30px;">The orchestra seating arrangement mirrors not only the listening biases of most human ears but on top of that the brain differences between musicians. By and large, the orchestra is organised according to biological principles. Thus, not all cultural conventions – like the seemingly arbitrary seating arrangement of orchestras – have their roots in historical accidents. Cultural oddities are sometimes merely down to biology.</h5>
<p>&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;-<br />
<span class="Z3988" title="ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Ajournal&amp;rft.jtitle=The+Psychology+of+Music%2C+Second+Edition&amp;rft_id=info%3Adoi%2F10.1016%2FB978-012213564-4%2F50010-X&amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fresearchblogging.org&amp;rft.atitle=Grouping+Mechanisms+in+Music&amp;rft.issn=&amp;rft.date=1999&amp;rft.volume=&amp;rft.issue=&amp;rft.spage=299&amp;rft.epage=348&amp;rft.artnum=&amp;rft.au=Deutsch%2C+D.&amp;rfe_dat=bpr3.included=1;bpr3.tags=Psychology%2CSocial+Science%2CCognitive+Psychology%2C+Sensation+and+Perception">Deutsch, D. (1999). Grouping Mechanisms in Music <span style="font-style:italic;">The Psychology of Music, Second Edition</span>, 299-348 DOI: <a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/B978-012213564-4/50010-X" rev="review">10.1016/B978-012213564-4/50010-X</a></span></p>
<p><span class="Z3988" title="ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Ajournal&amp;rft.jtitle=Annals+of+the+New+York+Academy+of+Sciences&amp;rft_id=info%3Apmid%2F16597790&amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fresearchblogging.org&amp;rft.atitle=Structural%2C+functional%2C+and+perceptual+differences+in+Heschl%27s+gyrus+and+musical+instrument+preference.&amp;rft.issn=0077-8923&amp;rft.date=2005&amp;rft.volume=1060&amp;rft.issue=&amp;rft.spage=387&amp;rft.epage=94&amp;rft.artnum=&amp;rft.au=Schneider+P&amp;rft.au=Sluming+V&amp;rft.au=Roberts+N&amp;rft.au=Bleeck+S&amp;rft.au=Rupp+A&amp;rfe_dat=bpr3.included=1;bpr3.tags=Psychology%2CNeuroscience%2CSensation+and+Perception%2C+Cognitive+Psychology%2C+Cognitive+Neuroscience">Schneider P, Sluming V, Roberts N, Bleeck S, &amp; Rupp A (2005). Structural, functional, and perceptual differences in Heschl&#8217;s gyrus and musical instrument preference. <span style="font-style:italic;">Annals of the New York Academy of Sciences, 1060</span>, 387-94 PMID: <a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/16597790" rev="review">16597790</a></span></p>
<p>&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;-</p>
<p>Figures:</p>
<p>1) Nederlands: Symfonieorkest Nijmegen in de grote zaal van de Vereeniging, The SON photo library, via wikimedia</p>
<p>2) as found in Schneider et al., 2005, p. 392</p>
<p><span style="float:left;padding:5px;"><a href="http://www.researchblogging.org"><img style="border:0;" alt="ResearchBlogging.org" src="http://www.researchblogging.org/public/citation_icons/rb2_large_gray.png" /></a></span></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1176/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1176/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1176&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://brainsidea.wordpress.com/2013/03/28/the-biological-basis-of-orchestra-seating/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>26</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/606c314028be8470c2f0b705066e4250?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">brainsidea</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/e/e1/Symfonieorkest_Nijmegen.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">orchestra; seating arrangement; Nijmegen; Nijmegen studenten orkest</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://brainsidea.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/brain_orchestra_seating.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Schneider; orchestra; seating; brain; Heschl&#039;s gyrus; primary auditory cortex; cortical size</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://www.researchblogging.org/public/citation_icons/rb2_large_gray.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ResearchBlogging.org</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
