<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2013 21:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Flightless</title>
		<link>http://thewordsisaw.wordpress.com/2013/02/21/flightless/</link>
		<comments>http://thewordsisaw.wordpress.com/2013/02/21/flightless/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2013 07:05:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>The Words I Saw</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Short stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[short story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poverty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hunger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Words I Saw]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thewordsisaw.wordpress.com/?p=1201</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I remember watching them high up in the sky, so high I had to squint my eyes. I remember Papa taking me to the falls where they would dive with the water, quickly lost to the mist-filled canyon beneath us. I remember the evenings sat on Mama’s lap, outside our brick home, listening to them [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1201&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I remember watching them high up in the sky, so high I had to squint my eyes. I remember Papa taking me to the falls where they would dive with the water, quickly lost to the mist-filled canyon beneath us. I remember the evenings sat on Mama’s lap, outside our brick home, listening to them sing to the stars and me. That’s how I want to remember them, and not as this small pile of bones, with their flesh lost to the red arid-soil before me.</p>
<p><i>Bones are all that remain of the starved</i>, Papa once told me. <i>But we live off them; they feed us Daya, because the sugar company needs them to bleach their cane</i>. I look at my rice sac, thinking back to Papa’s words, haunting me. <i>But they’re just bones in the end; like all of us, aren’t they?</i> I want to say to him.</p>
<p>I dust it clean and pinch the tiny breastbone between my fingers, before dropping it into my sac. It clinks like a note I had once played on a long wooden instrument at school. I had hit it with a stick, the instrument, and it sounded just like tapping two bones together. I peer inside against the smell. Not many of them are birds; they’re too big to be birds, too big to be animal.</p>
<p>It’s almost as tall as me now, and too heavy to lift, but if I drag it then my sac slides easy enough over the land, causing a red mist to rise up behind me. I pull as the rough hemp cuts into my shoulder. I squint against the pain as I mimic the sound of that musical note I had once played.</p>
<p align="center">*</p>
<p>‘Mama,’ I call out after arriving at our tent home. ‘Mama, I found lots Mama!’</p>
<p>But Mama doesn’t respond. I tie my sac tightly shut, and turn to see the amber sky deepening over the village. Sand is lifted by the rising winds of dusk, causing everything to shimmer beneath the descending darkness. I see him, leaning against the canvas walls of my neighbour’s home, staring at me and my sac. I want to take it inside, but Mama says we live with Death close enough already, without inviting it into our homes as well. So I push my sac up against the tent, turning to see that the man I don’t know has gone. I open the flap and walk inside.</p>
<p>‘Mama,’ I say running to lower myself into her arms. ‘What’s wrong, why are you crying?’</p>
<p>The blanket I had placed over her before leaving in the morning to collect had barely moved. She remains lying on the floor, with my baby brother asleep by her side.</p>
<p>‘Oh Daya, my sweet girl, Mama is not well today.’</p>
<p>She then begins violently coughing. I hold her tightly in my arms.</p>
<p>‘It’s OK Mama; I collected half a sac today. The sugar men will give us twenty cents for half a sac. We will eat tomorrow.’</p>
<p>‘Tomorrow,’ she says before closing her eyes.</p>
<p>I stand and walk around Mama to kiss Rudo on the head. He was born in the village and never saw our brick home, or Papa. When I’m not collecting then I tell Rudo about our life before; I tell him about Papa. I miss Papa. I felt safe when he was alive, as he could collect much better than me.</p>
<p>I pull my dusty clothes off and place them in one corner for tomorrow, as Mama’s wheezing breath fills the growing silence of the night. I light our only candle to get ready for bed, shadows dance around me in its flickering light. After putting on one of Papa’s old blue t-shirts, which falls all the way to my shins, I cross to the door to tie it shut. But first, I peer out to see my sac, illuminated under the glare of the moon. I briefly look up to see a world of stars above me.</p>
<p>‘Please God,’ I whisper.</p>
<p>Turning, I blow out the candle and find Mama’s side in the darkness. I lie pressed up against her and close my eyes, listening to her breath in order to drown out the hunger that’s constantly punching me in my belly.</p>
<p align="center">*</p>
<p>‘Papa was a great man,’ I tell Rudo, as he sits chewing his fingers on my lap. ‘We were never hungry when Papa was alive; he was a wise man and could make bird traps out of sticky berries. Mama would then pluck the Dusky Larks, roast them, and then we would sit just here,’ I tap the earth beneath us, ‘in a circle, laughing and eating larks. Yes, Papa was a great man Rudo, but,’ I look at Mama drifting between her delusions and dreams, ‘Death took him from us.’</p>
<p>Rudo giggles and climbs up my chest to begin chewing my nose.</p>
<p>‘<i>Mira</i> Baby,’ <i>stop </i>I say, ‘it’s sticky,’ I add, laughing and hugging him tightly.</p>
<p>I like my mornings with Rudo. Before Mama wakes I sit and play with him. I let myself be nine again. But once Mama is up I must start work again, because if I don’t try and find food, if I don’t care for us, then no one will.</p>
<p>After placing Rudo on the edge of Mama’s frayed blanket, I pull Papa’s t-shirt up over my head and quickly run from the morning chill to the corner of the tent. My work clothes scratch against my skin from all the dirt trapped inside them. The river is a morning away, so I can only wash them once a week. I pick up the broom, which stands taller than me, and fill the dawn silence with the shiver of bristles sweeping dust. Rudo begins scratching at the ground. I work around him, laughing as he crawls after the brush-head at my feet.</p>
<p>When I sweep I think about our brick home, and how tidy Mama used to keep it, and how Mama and Papa both wailed on their knees, crying out to God, when the bad men came and bulldozed it. I sweep and see a sea of us, lost in our own country, all walking together to this: I sweep a pile of dust to the door and, after opening it, force a small grey cloud outside into the face of the rising sun.</p>
<p>The engine of a truck hums in the horizon. I smile, now knowing that for at least today and tomorrow we will not die, for twenty cents will buy enough maize to feed us.</p>
<p>‘Mama,’ I call. ‘The sugar men are here.’</p>
<p>Rudo claps his hands together before patting Mama on the head. She fights to wake but her dreams are too safe to leave. Gazing back outside, I watch people beginning to exit their tents around me, carrying their sacs to the truck which hoots its horn. Two men step out and begin assessing the sacs, before tossing them on the back of the truck and handing out coins. I look down at my own sac, but it is gone.</p>
<p>‘No!’ I cry. ‘My bones, my bones have been stolen!’</p>
<p>My mouth is filled by a desperate saltiness, as my tears crash from the brink of my lip. I turn to look back at Mama and Rudo, who has also fallen asleep beside her, with his bulging belly rising and falling beneath his tiny ribs. I run.</p>
<p>‘<i>Pamusoro</i>, <i>pamusoro</i>,’ <i>excuse-me </i>I say, pulling at the jacket of the man who is giving out coins. ‘My sac was stolen but I collected half, please give me twenty cents to feed my family.’</p>
<p>He raises the clipboard in his hand and slaps me around the face with it, hard enough to knock me to the ground.</p>
<p>‘No bones, no money,’ he hisses, before kicking the dusty soil over me.</p>
<p>‘But I will get you half a sac next time; just give me twenty cents for today. My Mama and baby brother are starving. I’m starving, please.’</p>
<p>He raises the clipboard high above my head, as I scramble away between the legs of my neighbours.</p>
<p align="center">*</p>
<p>The soil crumbles as I dig down, sifting amongst the rubbish buried within it. I lift my hoe to try again, but my empty stomach feels as though it might collapse under the strain. The hoe drops to the ground, as I bring my hand to my belly to soothe it, with my vision misted by the sun’s hot rays.</p>
<p>‘Papa,’ I say, ‘I can’t dig Papa, my hunger eats me.’</p>
<p>Papa looks up at me and smiles, as he avidly turns over the soil picking up bone after bone.</p>
<p>‘We dig to eat, Daya; the sugar company will reward us for our hard work.’</p>
<p>I lean over and collect my hoe, seeing a partially covered bone beside its stone-scratched metal head. I scrap it free with my fingers, and tap it against the hoe’s wooden handle. It makes the right note so I stumble to the white sac and drop it inside.</p>
<p>‘But Papa,’ I say again, turning back to the shrunken man, with his blue t-shirt hanging loser each day, ‘I don’t want to scavenge anymore; the other girls laugh at me Papa.’</p>
<p>He forces his hoe into the ground and pushes his curved spine up straight as he turns to face me; his breaths falter as he fills his lungs with the sticky-air.</p>
<p>‘It’s not scavenging Daya,’ he says, looking out across the rubbish heap we’re stood upon, lifting us high up into the cloudless sky. ‘We dig to survive, and there’s nothing wrong about surviving.’ Papa lifts his hoe before breaking though the heap’s crust, releasing the potency of poverty further more. ‘There’s nothing wrong in survival Daya, and never let anyone tell you otherwise – understand?’</p>
<p>‘Yes Papa,’ I reply, but my words are cast astray on the breeze, lost with my dreams.</p>
<p>I sigh and turn to my sac, with them rattling inside as I shake it. I begin to drag it behind me, stopping to look for Papa once more, but my vision clears with the setting sun, and Papa is gone. I often cry while I’m out on the heap, as it’s the one place where I’m always alone.</p>
<p align="center">*</p>
<p>I don’t know what it’s like elsewhere in the world, but here, in my village, suffering seems to find its way into all of us.</p>
<p>‘<i>Mhoro</i>!’ I call out, pushing the air in the top of my sac downwards to make it bulge at the bottom.</p>
<p>A flickering light seeps beneath the walls of the tent, licking at the darkness by my feet.</p>
<p>‘Hello,’ I call again. ‘Mother Amadika, <i>mhoro</i>, it’s me – Daya.’</p>
<p>The flap drops and I am bathed in light, blinded, and unable to find the eyes of the black silhouette before me.</p>
<p>‘What is it child?’</p>
<p>My vision adjusts to see the vibrant colours of her dress, tainted by hardship and sweat.</p>
<p>‘Mother Amadika, please take these bones I have collected, and all for a little bit of maize.’</p>
<p>Her towering figure and heavy breasts fall forwards as she lifts the sac, assessing its value, before carrying it inside.</p>
<p>‘I have little maize to give,’ she says, no louder than a whisper.</p>
<p>I follow her into the tent; a small fire warms a pot in one corner, with the flames ravaging the air around them. Mother Amadika lifts a small tin bowl and lowers herself beside the pot, scraping at the contents with a metal spoon. I turn to the sound of the wheezing man, lying along the far canvas wall – his body shaking with fever.</p>
<p>‘I can give no more.’</p>
<p>Mother Amadika places the bowl into my outstretched hand, too hot to hold on its bottom. I look at the few spoonfuls of porridge; there’s barely enough to feed Rudo, let alone Mama and me.</p>
<p>‘<i>Ndatenda</i> Mother Amadika,’ <i>thank you </i>I say stepping away.</p>
<p>I stop at the entrance, trapped by my thoughts. I turn and face Mother Amadika, whose curly her hair is cut short like mine.</p>
<p>‘He’s dying, isn’t he?’ I ask, pointing at her son, now lying still with his eyes wide-open – searching.</p>
<p>She walks towards me and places her heavy hand on my shoulder.</p>
<p>‘We’re all dying Daya, but,’ her sadness clenches me tighter, ‘some of us are freed from this life much sooner than others.’ She lets my shoulder go and lifts the flap, covering me in shadow. ‘Now run home child. Don’t get caught with that maize in your hands.’</p>
<p>‘I won’t Mother Amadika, <i>ndatenda</i>.’</p>
<p>I hug the warm bowl close to my chest and run quickly, skipping over the black festering puddles.</p>
<p align="center">*</p>
<p>I hear his cries from far away.</p>
<p>‘Rudo!’ I call, running quicker towards our home. ‘I’m coming Rudo!’</p>
<p>I dash towards the full moon that hangs like a beacon, directing me towards the village’s end, while dodging the shadows calling out to me to sit with them, to keep them company just for tonight.</p>
<p>‘Rudo,’ I shout, tearing at the door shielding his screams inside.</p>
<p>I enter our home and edge my way through the darkness, placing the bowl of maize on the floor, before collecting Rudo in my arms.</p>
<p>‘It’s OK Baby, I’m here.’</p>
<p>His screams fade as he digs his head into my neck, clenching me tighter.</p>
<p>‘Mama,’ I say, lowering to find her hand in the darkness; it’s as cold as a pebble exposed to a winter’s night. ‘Mama?’ I say again.</p>
<p>I place Rudo back on the floor; his sniffles are accompanied by my scrambling to light our candle. The match sparks and I meet it with the blackened wick, before the tent is given a shimmering light. I slowly walk back to Mama and lean over her; her eyes peer right through me. I fall with my tears to her side, and hold her before kissing her cheek. I push back her hair, and see that her pain has now left her. I wish her goodnight.</p>
<p>‘<i>Urare zvakanakat</i> Mama,’ I whisper, pulling the blanket up to cover her face, ‘kiss Papa for me.’</p>
<p>I look over Mama at Rudo; his little hands and parting smile are covered in sticky porridge. Moonbeams fight their way through the many holes in our canvass walls, creating a pattern of stars in the black universe behind him.</p>
<p>‘It’s just us now Baby,’ I say.</p>
<p align="center">*</p>
<p>The soil trickles between my fingers, before I smooth it with my palm as Rudo plays with two sticks beside me.</p>
<p>‘We’ll be OK now Rudo,’ I say to him, taking the sticks before tying them into a small cross with some string. ‘Now Papa can take care of Mama, and I will be able to feed us better.’</p>
<p>Rudo reaches out for the cross, but I place it into the centre of the newly turned soil.</p>
<p>‘Come Baby.’</p>
<p>I stand and pull him up into my arms. Stumbling, I begin to walk away but I’m soon drawn towards a small slope, and the sound of scraping being carried up it on the morning breeze. I wait with the moment; familiar with the noise of collecting; familiar with Death’s song. A man, the stranger, staggers up the horizon before me, with my white rice sac sliding over the land behind him. I look down at Mama, hidden beneath the red arid soil. I lean over with Rudo still in my arms and pull out the cross. <i>May they never find her,</i> I say silently.</p>
<p>I hold Rudo and head towards our tent home; humming in his ear like Papa would once do to me. But he points at something over my shoulder and burbles the word, <i>Mama. </i>I smile with Rudo’s first word, but I turn as he says <i>Mama</i> once again.</p>
<p>There, pecking at the soil above Mama’s grave, is a small bird so white, I imagine the feathers of an angel could not fall any purer. I stand and stare, before watching the bird, and Mama, fly away.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">© Matthew Small 2013</p>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1201&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thewordsisaw.wordpress.com/2013/02/21/flightless/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/add687650d7be120e6790e8271541dc4?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">thewordsisaw</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>It&#8217;s Not Just a Cat Toy</title>
		<link>http://lynnsimon.wordpress.com/2013/02/18/its-not-just-a-cat-toy/</link>
		<comments>http://lynnsimon.wordpress.com/2013/02/18/its-not-just-a-cat-toy/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2013 04:17:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>lynnsimon</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[cats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[paper project]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photoshop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPchallenge]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://lynnsimon.wordpress.com/?p=769</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[If he&#8217;s honest with himself, the cat will admit that this toilet paper tube is now 100% more entertaining than it was when he first started playing with it. (When it was still just a tube. That&#8217;s so boring. We can do better than that.) I made that spiraling dangly thing just for him. Is [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=769&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If he&#8217;s honest with himself, the cat will admit that this toilet paper tube is now 100% more entertaining than it was when he first started playing with it. (When it was still just a tube. That&#8217;s so boring. We can do better than that.)</p>
<p><a href="http://lynnsimon.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/cattoy.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-770" alt="cattoy" src="http://lynnsimon.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/cattoy.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>I made that spiraling dangly thing just for him. Is he grateful? Not that I can tell.</p>
<p>The above photograph was bad from the start (poor lighting), and I over-brightened and over-sharpened it in Photoshop, just to make it somewhat viewable. Anyway, it&#8217;s still a bad photo, but something about it started to intrigue me. I liked the shapes, and the shadow of the spiral.</p>
<p>I decided to mess around with Photoshop filters. The Cutout filter yielded this&#8230;</p>
<p><a href="http://lynnsimon.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/cattoy1.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-771" alt="cattoy1" src="http://lynnsimon.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/cattoy1.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>&#8230;which was kind of interesting, but not enough on its own. I took the Cutout file and copied it into a file with the original photo. With the Cutout on a layer above the original, and the Blending mode set to Multiply, I ended up with this:</p>
<p><a href="http://lynnsimon.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/cattoy2.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-773" alt="cattoy2" src="http://lynnsimon.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/cattoy2.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>Which is an improvement on the original, I think. The same file, but with the Blending Mode set to Exclusion results in this:</p>
<p><a href="http://lynnsimon.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/cattoy3.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-774" alt="cattoy3" src="http://lynnsimon.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/cattoy3.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>Cool!</p>
<p>Returning to the original photo, I used a filter that I have <strong><em>never</em> </strong>had any success with. The Stained Glass filter. Always a disaster. So, why even bother trying it? That&#8217;s the triumph of hope over experience. And&#8230;</p>
<p><a href="http://lynnsimon.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/cattoy4.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-775" alt="cattoy4" src="http://lynnsimon.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/cattoy4.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>OMG! I really kind of love that!</p>
<p>Every time I use Photoshop filters I hear voices in my head, the clamor of professionals saying, <em><strong>Take a competent picture to begin with! Filters are</strong><strong> cheating!</strong></em> And I get what they&#8217;re saying. I really do.</p>
<p>On the other hand, this started out as a toilet paper tube. You know?</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/769/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/769/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=769&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://lynnsimon.wordpress.com/2013/02/18/its-not-just-a-cat-toy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://lynnsimon.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/cattoy2.jpg?w=108" />
		<media:content url="http://lynnsimon.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/cattoy2.jpg?w=108" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cattoy2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/493ffbc98a5251a54ac04a2e90994bc9?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lynnsimon</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lynnsimon.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/cattoy.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cattoy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lynnsimon.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/cattoy1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cattoy1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lynnsimon.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/cattoy2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cattoy2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lynnsimon.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/cattoy3.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cattoy3</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lynnsimon.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/cattoy4.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cattoy4</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Of Trying to Say Clear of the Witch-Hunt</title>
		<link>http://roobo69.wordpress.com/2013/02/20/dp-challenge-of-trying-to-stay-clear-of-the-witch-hunt/</link>
		<comments>http://roobo69.wordpress.com/2013/02/20/dp-challenge-of-trying-to-stay-clear-of-the-witch-hunt/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2013 11:24:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Robin</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Real Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weekly Writing Challenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DP Challenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oscar Pistorius]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[South Africa]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://roobo69.wordpress.com/?p=9132</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I went to bed last night more than a little irritated and, to be honest, sad. Since last week Thursday South Africa has been gripped by the story that Paralympic hero Oscar Pistorius shot and killed his girlfriend, Reeva Steenkamp, on Valentine&#8217;s Day. The &#8220;Twittersphere&#8221; and other social media is clogged with conspiracy theories, the [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=9132&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://roobo69.wordpress.com/2013/02/20/dp-challenge-of-trying-to-stay-clear-of-the-witch-hunt/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://roobo69.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/burning-13.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://roobo69.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/burning-13.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Witch-hunt</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/96dc369d92334b82ccc156c51a054bc7?s=96&#38;d=retro&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">roobo</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://roobo69.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/pistorius-400-heats841.jpg?w=547" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">South Africa&#039;s Oscar Pistorius competes during the men&#039;s 400m heats at the London 2012 Olympic Games. (Pic: REUTERS/Phil Noble)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://roobo69.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/oscar-pistorius-1709296.jpg?w=547" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Oscar Pistorius leaves the Boschkop police station, Pretoria, after his arrest for the murder of his girlfriend Reeva Steenkamp (AP)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://roobo69.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/oscar-pistorius-6_2480644b.jpg?w=547" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Reeva Steenkamp and Oscar Pistorius, left &#38; Oscar Pistorius on the track, right</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://roobo69.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/oscar19feb.jpg?w=356" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Oscar Pretorius sobs at his bail hearing</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>You Can Thank Me Later</title>
		<link>http://joyandwoe.wordpress.com/2013/02/19/you-can-thank-me-later/</link>
		<comments>http://joyandwoe.wordpress.com/2013/02/19/you-can-thank-me-later/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2013 03:51:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jeni</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPchallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flowchart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gifts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[holidays]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mother's day]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joyandwoe.wordpress.com/?p=1994</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I know we're months away from the 2013 edition -- May 12, take note! -- but I want to give readers ample time to consider the handy-dandy flowchart I've compiled, which neatly answers the question: <b>Should you buy the mother of your child/ren a Mother's Day present?</b><img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1994&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I have some fairly well-entrenched views when it comes to Mother&#8217;s Day, as in <a href="http://joyandwoe.wordpress.com/2012/05/08/mothers-day-2012-all-systems-go/" target="_blank">it should be celebrated</a>, and <a href="http://joyandwoe.wordpress.com/2012/05/14/motherfarmers/" target="_blank">let&#8217;s please be polite about it</a>.</p>
<p>And I know we&#8217;re months away from the 2013 edition &#8212; May 12, take note! &#8212; but I want to give readers ample time to consider the handy-dandy flowchart I&#8217;ve compiled, which neatly answers the question: <strong>Should you buy the mother of your child/ren a Mother&#8217;s Day present?</strong></p>
<p><a href="http://joyandwoe.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/mothers_day_flowchart1.png"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1997" title="Still not sure? BUY HER A GIFT." alt="mothers_day_flowchart" src="http://joyandwoe.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/mothers_day_flowchart1.png?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>This post brought to you in honour of all mothers everywhere, and this week&#8217;s writing challenge, <a href="http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2013/02/18/writing-challenge-image-vs-text/" target="_blank">image vs. text</a>.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1994/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1994/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1994&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://joyandwoe.wordpress.com/2013/02/19/you-can-thank-me-later/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>46</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/3edd4561c58c76a349c015970dcd4f38?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">joyandwoe</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://joyandwoe.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/mothers_day_flowchart1.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Still not sure? BUY HER A GIFT.</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Process as a Russian Doll</title>
		<link>http://breathofgreenair.wordpress.com/2013/02/19/process-as-a-russian-doll/</link>
		<comments>http://breathofgreenair.wordpress.com/2013/02/19/process-as-a-russian-doll/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2013 09:52:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>greenmackenzie</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[change]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mindfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nature photo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spiritual]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life and death]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[postaday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[symbolism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trees]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://breathofgreenair.wordpress.com/?p=1396</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Deep in the oak woods, something stirs. Tiny creaks and crackles fill the spaces between the air with gossamer wisps of sound.The sap hidden beneath the crusty crackled skin of bark begins its upwards journey towards the wooden finger tips of the trees. The earth turns back towards the sun, and the unstoppable yearly process [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1396&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_1457" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 650px"><a href="http://breathofgreenair.wordpress.com/2013/02/19/process-as-a-russian-doll/20130219-094111-jpg/" rel="attachment wp-att-1457"><img class="size-large wp-image-1457" alt="Spring stirred oaks" src="http://breathofgreenair.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/20130219-094111.jpg?w=640&#038;h=426" width="640" height="426" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Spring stirred oaks dancing</p></div>
<p>Deep in the oak woods, something stirs. Tiny creaks and crackles fill the spaces between the air with gossamer wisps of sound.The sap hidden beneath the crusty crackled skin of bark begins its upwards journey towards the wooden finger tips of the trees. The earth turns back towards the sun, and the unstoppable yearly process of growth and decay, turns the trees out of winter and into spring. But look a little deeper and this grand yearly cycle is nestled like a Russian doll within far greater, longer cycles of process and change.</p>
<div id="attachment_1448" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 436px"><a href="http://breathofgreenair.wordpress.com/2013/02/19/process-as-a-russian-doll/20130219-092119-jpg/" rel="attachment wp-att-1448"><img class="size-large wp-image-1448" alt="Viking warrior bares belly" src="http://breathofgreenair.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/20130219-092119.jpg?w=426&#038;h=640" width="426" height="640" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Viking warrior bares belly</p></div>
<p>Lightening is drawn inevitably, like a tragic star struck lover, towards the heartwood of oak. The bleached lightening struck branches gleam like bones, revealing the first step in the big process of decay from life.</p>
<div id="attachment_1454" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 436px"><a href="http://breathofgreenair.wordpress.com/2013/02/19/process-as-a-russian-doll/20130219-093952-jpg/" rel="attachment wp-att-1454"><img class="size-large wp-image-1454" alt="Broken limb" src="http://breathofgreenair.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/20130219-093952.jpg?w=426&#038;h=640" width="426" height="640" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Broken limb, fallen dancer</p></div>
<p>Weakened by the heaven sent fury, the ground is littered with the fallen carcasses of limbs once swaying in the summer breeze, reaching towards the sky.</p>
<div id="attachment_1450" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 650px"><a href="http://breathofgreenair.wordpress.com/2013/02/19/process-as-a-russian-doll/20130219-092531-jpg/" rel="attachment wp-att-1450"><img class="size-large wp-image-1450" alt="Rope twist in wood" src="http://breathofgreenair.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/20130219-092531.jpg?w=640&#038;h=426" width="640" height="426" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Rope twist in wood</p></div>
<p>The contact with the earth sets off the next stage in the process of decay. The bark falls like flesh, and the grain in the wood is chiseled out by millions of tiny organisms, unseen by human eye. The wood is re-clothed with moss, fungi and lichen, as its structure softens further, releasing its hard held form back into the soft earth.</p>
<div id="attachment_1451" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 650px"><a href="http://breathofgreenair.wordpress.com/2013/02/19/process-as-a-russian-doll/20130219-092631-jpg/" rel="attachment wp-att-1451"><img class="size-large wp-image-1451" alt="Wood to earth - new hope" src="http://breathofgreenair.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/20130219-092631.jpg?w=640&#038;h=488" width="640" height="488" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Wood to earth &#8211; new hope</p></div>
<p>In the end, the strength of the tree dissolves into soil, and tiny acorns are nourished by its soft life giving blanket.  Change and process are hidden all around us in unseen layers within layers, if only we have the eyes to see. The stately process has come full circle, and the earth breathes out, into growth, and into the next layer of the Russian doll of life.</p>
<p>To see more ideas of process decribed with pictures and words visit <a href="http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2013/02/18/writing-challenge-image-vs-text/">the weekly challenge</a></p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://breathofgreenair.wordpress.com/category/art/'>art</a>, <a href='http://breathofgreenair.wordpress.com/category/change/'>change</a>, <a href='http://breathofgreenair.wordpress.com/category/mindfulness/'>mindfulness</a>, <a href='http://breathofgreenair.wordpress.com/category/nature-photo/'>nature photo</a>, <a href='http://breathofgreenair.wordpress.com/category/photos/'>photos</a>, <a href='http://breathofgreenair.wordpress.com/category/spiritual/'>spiritual</a> Tagged: <a href='http://breathofgreenair.wordpress.com/tag/change/'>change</a>, <a href='http://breathofgreenair.wordpress.com/tag/life/'>life</a>, <a href='http://breathofgreenair.wordpress.com/tag/life-and-death/'>life and death</a>, <a href='http://breathofgreenair.wordpress.com/tag/mindfulness/'>mindfulness</a>, <a href='http://breathofgreenair.wordpress.com/tag/nature/'>nature</a>, <a href='http://breathofgreenair.wordpress.com/tag/photography/'>photography</a>, <a href='http://breathofgreenair.wordpress.com/tag/postaday/'>postaday</a>, <a href='http://breathofgreenair.wordpress.com/tag/spiritual/'>spiritual</a>, <a href='http://breathofgreenair.wordpress.com/tag/symbolism/'>symbolism</a>, <a href='http://breathofgreenair.wordpress.com/tag/trees/'>trees</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1396/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1396/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1396/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1396/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1396/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1396/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1396/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1396/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1396/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1396/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1396/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1396/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1396/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1396/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1396&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://breathofgreenair.wordpress.com/2013/02/19/process-as-a-russian-doll/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>31</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/af918af9a93f5eac00b76910574f652c?s=96&#38;d=wavatar&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">greenmackenzie</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://breathofgreenair.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/20130219-094111.jpg?w=640" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Spring stirred oaks</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://breathofgreenair.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/20130219-092119.jpg?w=426" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Viking warrior bares belly</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://breathofgreenair.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/20130219-093952.jpg?w=426" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Broken limb</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://breathofgreenair.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/20130219-092531.jpg?w=640" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Rope twist in wood</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://breathofgreenair.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/20130219-092631.jpg?w=640" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Wood to earth - new hope</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Bridal Diet Makes Me Hungry (for Vengeance)</title>
		<link>http://confederacyofspinsters.com/2013/02/19/the-bridal-diet-makes-me-hungry-for-vengeance/</link>
		<comments>http://confederacyofspinsters.com/2013/02/19/the-bridal-diet-makes-me-hungry-for-vengeance/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2013 18:44:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Grace</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[A Spinster Gets Married]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Feminism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weddings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://confederacyofspinsters.com/?p=1040</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There is great danger ahead. The bridal magazines warn of it and dress clerks speak of it in hushed, panicky tones, as though the barest mention can summon its cream-filled wrath. It is the monster they call fat and it&#8217;s the quickest way to ruin a wedding. I know what you&#8217;re thinking. But, Grace, I&#8217;m [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1040&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://confederacyofspinsters.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/wedding-diet-500x485.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-1041" alt="Wedding-Diet-500x485" src="http://confederacyofspinsters.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/wedding-diet-500x485.jpg?w=258&#038;h=250" width="258" height="250" /></a>There is great danger ahead. The bridal magazines warn of it and dress clerks speak of it in hushed, panicky tones, as though the barest mention can summon its cream-filled wrath. It is the monster they call fat and it&#8217;s the quickest way to ruin a wedding.</p>
<p>I know what you&#8217;re thinking. <em>But, Grace, I&#8217;m happy with my size! Dr. Swoodilypooper fell in love with me just as I am, so why change now</em>? Don&#8217;t ask me, dearest. Personally, I think you&#8217;re the bee&#8217;s knees and should stay as you are, but I do not make the wedding rules. If I did, there would be more elephant rides. Unfortunately, the wedding industry is against fun<em> and</em> your body. You are a bride, so you should lose weight. It&#8217;s in all the literature!</p>
<p>As soon as you get Facebook engaged, that paramount sign of commitment, you&#8217;re inundated with wedding ads. Photographers, venues, and DJs all want <del>your money</del> to help with your special day. None, however, seem more concerned than the personal trainers. <em>Look perfect on your special day,</em> they promise. <em>Don&#8217;t you want to be a shiny, happy wedding princess</em>? Well, princesses aren&#8217;t a size 12, so join a boot camp, fatty fatpants. A true bride prepares for her wedding like it&#8217;s a <em>war</em>. Death to the thunder thighs!</p>
<p>No matter the bride, improvements are necessary. Sure, you may already be a size 2, but are you a toned size 2? Worse, do you have a bit of cellulite, that natural way female fat is stored? Disgusting! Stop eating this instant. You&#8217;re going to be <em>in pictures</em>, darling. They&#8217;re worth a 1000 words, 999 of which could be variants of &#8220;chunky apple pie face.&#8221; You don&#8217;t want your grandchildren thinking you looked like a lace-cased sausage, do you? They won&#8217;t love you anymore! You are a woman, darling, and women are delicate flowers. Just because you&#8217;ve fooled a man into thinking your body is sex incarnate, doesn&#8217;t make it acceptable.</p>
<p>As a bride, you have certain responsibilities. Chief among them is looking conventionally beautiful. You only get this one day<em> ever</em> to be happy, so make it count. Heaven forbid your guests leave chatting about the great food and lively conversation! If they&#8217;re not complimenting your spindly collarbone, you have failed. And if you fail at being a bride? Barbie comes to life, knocks in your door with a magenta battering ram, and revokes your woman card. Then, who will do your husband&#8217;s laundry? Get dieting now, or else&#8230;</p>
<p>Or, call me crazy, you could find a dress that makes you happy and sashay up to the alter as the person you are. Shock your guests and &#8211; <em>gasp!</em> &#8211; look like the you they already love. It&#8217;s one thing to want to feel better or combat health problems, but why exactly are we dieting ourselves down to an unmaintainable size for one party? Your wedding photos don&#8217;t actually follow you around, shadow-like, for all your days. Despite what the magazines tell you, you are <em>not</em> your dress size. Not this day, not ever. You are your career, your friends, your perfectly twee impression of Zooey Deschanel. You are not a bride, you are a <em>person</em>.</p>
<p style="text-align:right;">- Grace</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1040/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1040/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1040&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://confederacyofspinsters.com/2013/02/19/the-bridal-diet-makes-me-hungry-for-vengeance/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>61</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a062143ac00603a027b38c6883c28bef?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">confederacyofspinsters</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://confederacyofspinsters.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/wedding-diet-500x485.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Wedding-Diet-500x485</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mapping the Human Brain</title>
		<link>http://manicmuses.wordpress.com/2013/02/21/mapping-the-human-brain/</link>
		<comments>http://manicmuses.wordpress.com/2013/02/21/mapping-the-human-brain/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2013 14:25:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>ManicMuses</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Bipolar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mental Illness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scientific Research]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://manicmuses.wordpress.com/?p=1140</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[During his last State of the Union address, US President Barack Obama briefly touched on the idea of the US Federal Government funding a program for a Brain Activity Map (BAM).  Basically, signals sent by every brain cell would be recorded so we can better understand the circuitry of human thoughts, feelings and emotions. (1)  The implications [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1140&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://manicmuses.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/brain-e1295289750891.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-144" alt="Brain" src="http://manicmuses.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/brain-e1295289750891.jpg?w=225&#038;h=300" width="225" height="300" /></a>During his last State of the Union address, US President Barack Obama briefly touched on the idea of the US Federal Government funding a program for a <a title="Brain Activity Map Project" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brain_Activity_Map_Project" target="_blank">Brain Activity Map (BAM)</a>.  Basically, signals sent by every brain cell would be recorded so we can better understand the circuitry of human thoughts, feelings and emotions. (1)  The implications of successfully completing a project like this are enormous &#8211; from advances in everything from medicine to <a class="zem_slink" title="Artificial intelligence" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Artificial_intelligence" target="_blank" rel="wikipedia">artificial intelligence (AI)</a>. The project is, supposedly, the next logical scientific progression for the US after the strides we made in cancer research in the 70&#8242;s and the <a class="zem_slink" title="Human Genome Project" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Human_Genome_Project" target="_blank" rel="wikipedia">human genome project</a> of the 90&#8242;s.</p>
<p>Of course, instead of the President selling this program with examples of potential benefits to mankind, the message immediately became about the positive economic impact a program of BAM&#8217;s magnitude could have.  For example, for every dollar spent on the human genome project (on which BAM would be modeled) it, “returned $140 to our economy.” .</p>
<blockquote><p>With some $3.8 billion spent over 13 years, the resulting gene-based boon turned out to be $796 billion in new jobs, medical treatments, increased salaries and other benefits, according to a 2011 analysis conducted for the federal government.</p></blockquote>
<p>Scientists on the BAM project are hoping for a similar investment from the Feds and an even bigger ROI (return on investment) for BAM.</p>
<p>What was unfortunately not explored by Obama during SOTU is the obvious hope those of us with mental illness or any brain disorder have about a such an initiative.  Perhaps if we can understand the circuitry of the brain, there will be better diagnostics, treatment &#8211; and dare we hope &#8211; maybe a cure &#8211; for brain illnesses such as depression, bipolar disorder and schizophrenia.  Alzheimer&#8217;s patients could also reap huge benefits.</p>
<p>After my initial spark of hopefulness faded, it took my medicated brain (I have Bipolar I) a few minutes to process why my gut is telling me this may not be the best way to go.</p>
<p>Before I &#8216;retired&#8217; to move across the planet and sporadically write a blog, I was an IT Geek in a pretty nifty industry.  So, after blowing the med fog to the side of my brain, the first coherent thought I had was, &#8220;Is the present technology anywhere near up to the task?&#8221;</p>
<p>After doing just a bit of digging, clearly the answer is, &#8220;no.&#8221; One piece of tech  needed is the brain imaging tools that would allow scientists to observe cell recruitment functions at the low level necessary to observe circuits firing off feelings, memories, etc.  It still needs to be devised.  That&#8217;s a pretty tall order, and a pretty expensive one.  Then there are the systems and software necessary to store, interpret and model the data.  Those are probably in the works in some form or another, but I couldn&#8217;t find any evidence that&#8217;s truly the case.  It&#8217;s not that these technological components can&#8217;t be developed.  We have some of the best engineers on the planet in the good ol&#8217; USA.  But, Obama is right.  In the end, it&#8217;s all about the money.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, there&#8217;s little hope that funding for this project will be approved in March when Congress votes on the 2014 budget. Since Congress couldn&#8217;t see their way clear to quickly approve disaster relief for the victims of Superstorm Sandy without arguing over pork and a whole lot of other BS. it&#8217;s unlikely a bold scientific undertaking is going to get any cash, especially in this time of austerity and the House being led by the GOP.  Should BAM be approved, under one funding scenario, It&#8217;s estimated that 750 labs across the US will lose their grants for other projects. Here&#8217;s where the project loses me. Killing off scientific diversity is something I can&#8217;t ascribe to.</p>
<p>But wouldn&#8217;t it be great if the wheels were already set in motion for a project that would tackle brain mapping so that everything from better understanding of physical and mental illness to advances in AI would be a byproduct?</p>
<p>Wait &#8211; there just might be a way we can still look forward to a day when those of us with faulty circuitry can stroll into a Radio Shack for a replacement model.</p>
<p><a title="The Human Brain Project" href="http://www.humanbrainproject.eu/index.html" target="_blank">The Human Brain Project</a> is a one billion Euro effort being coordinated by Switzerland and has a somewhat similar goal to what the US is proposing:</p>
<blockquote><p><em>The goal of the Human Brain Project is to pull together all our existing knowledge about the human brain and to reconstruct the brain, piece by piece, in supercomputer-based models and simulations. The models offer the prospect of a new understanding of the</em> <em>human brain</em> <em id="__mceDel" style="line-height:1.6;"><em id="__mceDel"><em id="__mceDel"><em id="__mceDel">and its diseases and of completely new computing and robotic technologies. On January 28, </em></em></em></em><em id="__mceDel" style="line-height:1.6;"><em id="__mceDel"><em id="__mceDel"><em id="__mceDel"><em id="__mceDel">the <a class="zem_slink" title="European Commission" href="http://maps.google.com/maps?ll=50.8436111111,4.38277777778&amp;spn=0.01,0.01&amp;q=50.8436111111,4.38277777778 (European%20Commission)&amp;t=h" target="_blank" rel="geolocation">European Commission</a> supported this vision, announcing that it has selected the HBP as </em></em></em></em></em><em id="__mceDel" style="line-height:1.6;"><em id="__mceDel"><em id="__mceDel"><em id="__mceDel"><em id="__mceDel"><em id="__mceDel">one of two projects to be funded through the new FET Flagship Program.</em></em></em></em></em></em></p></blockquote>
<p>It appears funding is already in place, ramp up is beginning this year and one goal of the program is to create e <a title="CERN" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cern" target="_blank">CERN</a> for the brain.  True, the HBT project is not promising the level of granularity BAM would like to achieve, but you have to admit, the EU is already leaps and bounds ahead in actually beginning their brain program.  The HBT goal seems more attainable as well.  If the US Congress can&#8217;t see its way clear to fund BAM, why not begin with assembling all available data on the brain first, and then advance to examining the minutia of brain circuitry and function at a later date?</p>
<p>Overall, this is an exciting time in brain research.  We have some of the best minds (pun intended) on both sides of the world innovating to better understand the most complex organ in the human body.  We are on the verge of creating the technology to do so, and who knows what other purposes that tech could be applied to in the end.  Most importantly, think (pun intended) about how the quality of human life could be improved by better understanding our own brain.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s pretend for one moment that the US Congress does approve funding for BAM and its full steam ahead in the US.  I would really love to see this happen.</p>
<p>Maybe brain research could be the new Friendly Space Race.  The US vs the EU (instead of Russia) and the new territory to be charted instead of the moon is the human brain.  A bit of competition is good, right?  It keeps everyone on their toes and the wheels in motion.  Even if the end goals for BAM and HBP aren&#8217;t the exactly the same, having two active brain understanding projects can only turn out to be beneficial in the end.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration:underline;"><strong>Resources:</strong></span></p>
<p><a title="Brain Map: President Obama Proposes First Detailed Guide of Human Brain Function  Read more: http://healthland.time.com/2013/02/19/brain-map-president-obama-proposes-first-detailed-guide-of-human-brain-function/#ixzz2LXdaSY4k" href="http://healthland.time.com/2013/02/19/brain-map-president-obama-proposes-first-detailed-guide-of-human-brain-function/#ixzz2LXdaSY4k" target="_blank">Brain Map: President Obama Proposes First Detailed Guide of Human Brain Function</a></p>
<p><a title="Researchers debate wisdom of brain-mapping initiative" href="http://www.usatoday.com/story/tech/sciencefair/2013/02/20/brain-map-project-questioned/1932987/" target="_blank">Researchers debate wisdom of brain-mapping initiative</a></p>
<p><a title="Human Brain Project" href="http://www.humanbrainproject.eu/index.html" target="_blank">HBP &#8211; Human Brain Project</a></p>
<p>1) Nerdier explanation of the BAM project from Wikipedia:</p>
<blockquote><p>By using new non-invasive methods of <a title="Electrophysiology" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Electrophysiology">electrophysiology</a> derived from <a title="Nanotechnology" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nanotechnology">nanotechnology</a>, in which synthetic <a title="DNA" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DNA">DNA</a> molecules will be used to store and report the sensed activity of single neurons, and combining them with methods of <a title="Neuroimaging" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neuroimaging">neuroimaging</a>and <a title="Neuroanatomy" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neuroanatomy">neuroanatomy</a>, participating scientists hope to map activity of each of the approximately 100 billion neurons in the human brain</p></blockquote>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://manicmuses.wordpress.com/category/mental-illness-2/bipolar-mental-illness/'>Bipolar</a>, <a href='http://manicmuses.wordpress.com/category/mental-illness-2/'>Mental Illness</a>, <a href='http://manicmuses.wordpress.com/category/mental-illness-2/scientific-research/'>Scientific Research</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1140/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1140/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1140&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://manicmuses.wordpress.com/2013/02/21/mapping-the-human-brain/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>15</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/5fb28d65c0559864b90e9a079aaba9a2?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">manicmuses</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://manicmuses.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/brain-e1295289750891.jpg?w=225" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Brain</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Evolution of a Canadian Muslim</title>
		<link>http://thecanadianmuslim.wordpress.com/2013/02/20/evolution-of-a-canadian-muslim/</link>
		<comments>http://thecanadianmuslim.wordpress.com/2013/02/20/evolution-of-a-canadian-muslim/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2013 07:15:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>thecanadianmuslim08</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beard in Islam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canadian Muslim]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Evolution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[islam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MSA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Muslim]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thecanadianmuslim.wordpress.com/?p=70</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Imagine for a second, that you walk into a Masjid for Salah, and the people look at you with a surprised look as though you are not supposed to be there. Imagine that you show up to an MSA event for the first time, and one of the brothers approaches you to give YOU dawah. [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=70&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://thecanadianmuslim.wordpress.com/2013/02/20/evolution-of-a-canadian-muslim/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/2f0684454b15fa0ffd2ba6636206c75a?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F2.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">thecanadianmuslim08</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Defense of Banksy</title>
		<link>http://abetterwhirlpool.wordpress.com/2013/02/20/banksy/</link>
		<comments>http://abetterwhirlpool.wordpress.com/2013/02/20/banksy/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2013 18:38:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Art</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Aesthetics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Banksy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jonathan Jones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Street Art]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://abetterwhirlpool.wordpress.com/?p=435</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Once again, I feel compelled to address some claims made by the art critic Jonathan Jones at The Guardian.  This time, Jones has written a piece attacking Banksy.  This in itself is not the problem.  The problem is that the attack makes very little sense under close examination. Here is the crux of Jones’s argument: [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=435&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://www.tate.org.uk/art/artworks/johns-dancers-on-a-plane-t03242" target="_blank"><img class="wp-image-436 aligncenter" title="Dancers on a Plane by Jasper Johns" alt="Dancers on a Plane by Jasper Johns" src="http://abetterwhirlpool.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/dancers-on-a-plane.jpg?w=195&#038;h=240" width="195" height="240" /></a></p>
<p>Once again, I feel compelled to address some claims made by the art critic Jonathan Jones at <i>The Guardian</i>.  This time, Jones has written <a title="Banksy: overrated purveyor of art-lite" href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/artanddesign/jonathanjonesblog/2013/feb/19/banksy-overrated-art" target="_blank">a piece attacking Banksy</a>.  This in itself is not the problem.  The problem is that the attack makes very little sense under close examination.</p>
<p>Here is the crux of Jones’s argument:</p>
<blockquote><p>Some art can exist just as well in silence and obscurity as on the pages of newspapers. The Mona Lisa is always being talked about, but even if no one ever again concocted a headline about this roughly 510-year-old painting it would still be as great. The same is true of real modern art. A Jasper Johns painting of a network of diagonal marks surrounded by cutlery stuck to the frame, called Dancers On a Plane – currently in an exhibition at the Barbican – was just as real, vital and profound when it was hidden away in the Tate stores as it is under the gallery lights. Johns does not need fame to be an artist; he does not even need an audience. He just <em>is</em> an artist, and would be if no one knew about him. Banksy is not an artist in that authentic way.</p></blockquote>
<p>I strongly disagree that art can exist in a vacuum; I think it needs an audience to be art.  Thus, I cannot fathom the absurdity in the statement that Jasper Johns “does not even need an audience” to be an artist.  How does that work exactly?  It doesn’t.  Jones is simply presupposing a metaphysical reality in which art possesses inherent value independent of humans.  This presupposition, being fictional, remains unsupported.  How can a work remain profound if no one is around to bestow the value of profundity upon it?  And does it not take a human mind to transform Jasper Johns’s “network of diagonal marks surrounded by cutlery stuck to the frame” into a cohesive whole?  Truly, then, one cannot dismiss Banksy on the grounds that his work demands an audience.  All art does.</p>
<p>Another problem that I have with Jones’s argument is that he takes the properties that make Banksy aesthetically interesting to most people and transforms them into Banksy’s aesthetic shortcomings:</p>
<blockquote><p>Banksy, as an artist, stops existing when there is no news about him. Right now he is a story once again, because a &#8220;mural&#8221; by him (street art and graffiti no longer suffice to describe his pricey works) has been removed from a wall and put up for auction. Next week the story will be forgotten, and so will Banksy – until the next time he becomes a headline.</p></blockquote>
<p>Part of Banksy’s “art” is in the impermanence of his pieces and in the confrontational nature of his “murals” that are designed to disrupt people from their daily routines to make them stop and notice something, to see things differently.  Perhaps comparisons to static pieces like the <i>Mona Lisa</i> are not the best means to understand performance-based work of this nature (though I admit that because the art market has laid claim to Banksy, such comparisons are not necessarily off base, either).</p>
<p>But “street art” is hardly the first recognized art form to be temporary and confrontational in the manner adopted by Banksy. And why does Jones consider fame and branding as faults or weaknesses of the artist?  These attributes were obviously as essential in solidifying the legacies of the artists whom Jones admires as they were in elevating Banksy above his peers.</p>
<p>Jones claims that he wants “art that is physically and intellectually and emotionally real.”  Unfortunately for him, as his blog on Banksy makes clear, he seems to have no idea what that even means.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/435/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/435/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=435&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://abetterwhirlpool.wordpress.com/2013/02/20/banksy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>32</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f5d6d9e4efd4a8b891f4bfbda354b869?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">abetterwhirlpool</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://abetterwhirlpool.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/dancers-on-a-plane.jpg?w=244" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Dancers on a Plane by Jasper Johns</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Letter I Can\&#8217;t Bring Myself To Send</title>
		<link>http://pennygetslucky.wordpress.com/2013/02/15/the-letter-im-afraid-to-send/</link>
		<comments>http://pennygetslucky.wordpress.com/2013/02/15/the-letter-im-afraid-to-send/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 16:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>pennyposh</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Penny's History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sex and Sexuality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social Justice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[acceptance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[being bi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coming out]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[I do what I want]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parents]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[religion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Seriously dating girls is awesome]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sexuality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tolerance]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://pennygetslucky.wordpress.com/?p=259</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Dad: I’ve had some time to think about the things you said to me, the day I told you I was bisexual. I’ve thought about what it means, and what you believe, and where I fit into that picture. I’ve come to a decision. I assume by now you’ve shared the news with Mom, if [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=259&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://pennygetslucky.wordpress.com/2013/02/15/the-letter-im-afraid-to-send/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>63</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/403f60e7f2f2dd6f1a5a644c75ef2806?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">pennyposh</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
