<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2012 01:02:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>US Army: Captain America, Space Marines, or the Clone Wars?</title>
		<link>http://arkangelwinter.wordpress.com/2012/08/14/us-army-captain-america-space-marines-or-the-clone-wars/</link>
		<comments>http://arkangelwinter.wordpress.com/2012/08/14/us-army-captain-america-space-marines-or-the-clone-wars/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2012 18:28:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Joshua Snow</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RPG]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://arkangelwinter.wordpress.com/?p=13</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#160; &#160; &#160; &#160; Recently, DARPA announced a plan to create genetically-modified shock troopers for the United States military. Let that sink in a moment, pal. Done? These new super-troops are projected to run faster than Usain Bolt, go without food and sleep for days, outlift Olympic weightlifters, and possibly regrow lost limbs. Like a [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=13&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://arkangelwinter.wordpress.com/2012/08/14/us-army-captain-america-space-marines-or-the-clone-wars/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/087976afec825b1dee022fa20c3d001f?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F0.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">arkangelwinter</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://images.wikia.com/halo/images/8/8c/Halo_Character_Spartan_Render.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">spartan</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://www.freestockphotos.biz/pictures/10/10260/stormtrooper.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">waving 501st</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://i.annihil.us/u/prod/marvel//universe3zx/images/thumb/0/0d/MikeFichera--Cap-Classic-red-white-blue.jpg/180px-MikeFichera--Cap-Classic-red-white-blue.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Captain America </media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://i.istockimg.com/file_thumbview_approve/4346085/2/stock-photo-4346085-seedy-motel.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Seedy motel</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Once Upon a Time</title>
		<link>http://strangedavid.wordpress.com/2012/08/12/once-upon-a-time/</link>
		<comments>http://strangedavid.wordpress.com/2012/08/12/once-upon-a-time/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2012 23:23:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>strangedavid</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fatherhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thinky Thoughts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fatherhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thinky thoughts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal history]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Grandma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Grandpa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sunflowers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weeping willow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[willow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[willow trees]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fairy tale]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fairy tales]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[junebug]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dementia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alzheimer's]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[renewal]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://strangedavid.wordpress.com/?p=606</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[My next-door neighbor has a small weeping willow tree in her backyard. A neighbor across the housing edition&#8217;s common space has sunflowers. That&#8217;s what inspired this post. &#160; &#160; &#160; &#160; &#160; &#160; &#160; &#160; &#160; &#160; &#160; When I was a kid, my mother&#8217;s parents had a house in Chittenango, New York. I remember [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=606&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>My next-door neighbor has a small weeping willow tree in her backyard. A neighbor across the housing edition&#8217;s common space has sunflowers. That&#8217;s what inspired this post. </em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div id="attachment_619" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 484px"><a href="http://strangedavid.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/willow1.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-619" title="Willow Tree" src="http://strangedavid.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/willow1.jpg" alt="Willow Tree" width="474" height="377" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Magic.</p></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>When I was a kid, my mother&#8217;s parents had a house in Chittenango, New York. I remember a lot of things about the house, but some of my favorite memories have to do with the yard. For one thing, I remember that my grandfather had a small garden. I don&#8217;t remember what he grew, other than tomatoes and sunflowers. He was the only person I knew who specifically grew sunflowers, and I absolutely loved them. I don&#8217;t know that I ever actually <em>touched</em> them, or even wanted to go too close to them. I wasn&#8217;t specifically avoiding them, of course, because I thought they were fantastic&#8230; but I think somehow, even as a kid, I knew that I just might like the <em>idea</em> of them more than the <em>reality</em> of them. I still don&#8217;t know anything about growing them; I don&#8217;t know how their stems feel against the palms of my hands, or if they have a noticeable smell, or what sort of work you have to do in order to keep them alive. I just loved that my grandfather had flowers that were so much bigger and more intense than any flowers in the yards of anyone else that I knew. They were flowers out of fairy tales, as far as I was concerned.</p>
<p>They also had a weeping willow tree, with a homemade swing hanging from it. The swing was great &#8212; of course, all swings are pretty great &#8212; but I loved the tree. Just like with the sunflowers, I didn&#8217;t know anyone else who had a weeping willow. I remember being heartbroken when they cut it down, and by then I think I might have been a teenager already. But when it was around, I loved playing by it, swinging from it, even just looking out the small window by the table in the kitchen and seeing it there, branches flowing with the breeze like it was underwater.</p>
<p>In my memories from childhood, the sunflowers and the willow tree were so incredibly huge. I know, obviously, that some of that is just perspective. I&#8217;ve seen plenty of sunflowers and I know that they don&#8217;t grow as big as I remember Grandpa&#8217;s sunflowers growing. The willow tree &#8212; well, that I don&#8217;t know. Some of those get pretty gigantic. But to me, as a kid, it was the biggest tree that ever grew outside a forest. There was something about it that was almost magical. Like the sunflowers, it felt as if it were from a fairy tale.</p>
<p>After my grandmother had passed away, when it became clear that my grandfather was no longer going to be able to live on his own in that house, I visited one last time to &#8220;claim&#8221; some things that he wasn&#8217;t going to need. The emotions of that day were powerful; I think I grieved for my grandmother in a way that I hadn&#8217;t even done at her funeral. Some of the items I claimed were ones that I had fond, specific memories of &#8212; such as the board game &#8220;Careers&#8221; that I remembered playing with my cousins and siblings time and time again. Others were items I had never actually played with or held before, but that I had secretly built stories around &#8212; such as a hand-sized Model T that seemed to be made out of scrap hardware pieces like washers and nuts. I couldn&#8217;t even really remember the stories I had dreamed up about it, but in the shadows of my memory it had meaning and importance.</p>
<p>I remember going to the window that looked out at the yard. I remembered how I occasionally used to sit there, forcing myself to eat the slices of banana Grandma had put into my cereal because if I could just get through the banana, there would be a molasses cookie after breakfast. I remembered how it was seated at that small table that I had first seen a junebug, and how it had scared me with its size &#8212; a giant bug that was, like so many other things at Grandma and Grandpa&#8217;s house, from a fairy tale. I remember Grandpa flicking the screen and the junebug arcing away from the window, only starting to fly when it was halfway to the ground. Grandpa was a minor hero that day.</p>
<p>I looked out at the yard. There was no garden, of course, although sometimes in my memories of that day I see heat-tired, somewhat scraggly remnants of sunflowers that just couldn&#8217;t make it without Grandpa&#8217;s attention. I have no idea if this memory is real or something symbolic my mind has created. And the willow was long gone. And the hill that led up to the neighbor&#8217;s yard seemed so small compared to my memories from childhood.</p>
<p>Grandma was gone. Grandpa was clearly going. And the fairy tales were over.</p>
<p>Grandpa suffered from a long, lingering dementia &#8212; almost definitely Alzheimer&#8217;s, although if I understand correctly they can&#8217;t technically diagnose that with 100% certainty until an autopsy, and I doubt there was any point in doing that for Grandpa when he passed away. At various times, he would answer questions about what he had done that day with brief explanations of how he had milked the cows (something he probably hadn&#8217;t done since the forties or even the thirties). He didn&#8217;t remember that his siblings and friends and his wife had already passed on; instead, he remembered (or imagined) conversations they had &#8220;just had.&#8221; It was terribly confusing and sometimes terrifying for him, although I am certain that it was more painful for us. Sometimes, I think that what he was remembering was something that really happened; sometimes, I think he was reinterpreting his own secret fairy tales.</p>
<p>It would be unrealistic to say that I &#8220;grew up&#8221; that day, feeling that the fairy tales were gone. I was old enough by that point that I&#8217;d experienced plenty of disappointments and realistic setbacks in my life. But it still felt like a loss. The memories were so big and wide, and the reality was so small and faded.</p>
<p>&#8230;But I have a daughter now. A daughter who is going to grow up with a small weeping willow tree in the neighbor&#8217;s yard, and sunflowers across the way. I don&#8217;t know if those are necessarily going to be part of her fairy tales; maybe she&#8217;ll latch on to something else entirely that makes her happy simply for the reason that they&#8217;re bigger, or prettier, or more <em>something</em> than everything else she knows.</p>
<p>She has the wonder &#8212; already, at seven and a half months old &#8212; that all children should be blessed to have. And as I&#8217;m starting to see things through her eyes (that dog is <em>so exciting!</em> that plum looks <em>amazing!</em> Daddy, look at your <em>hands! </em>Have you <em>seen</em> them? <em>Look at them!</em>)&#8230; or maybe as I start to imagine how she sees things&#8230; I&#8217;m discovering the fairy tales aren&#8217;t gone. I just stopped reading them.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/606/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/606/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=606&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://strangedavid.wordpress.com/2012/08/12/once-upon-a-time/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/56f2b76b6742e9d006f9b9ed00e3d10c?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">strangedavid</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://strangedavid.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/willow1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Willow Tree</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Op the rigging</title>
		<link>http://yearofrandomreading.wordpress.com/2012/08/14/op-the-rigging/</link>
		<comments>http://yearofrandomreading.wordpress.com/2012/08/14/op-the-rigging/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2012 16:57:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Kate</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eric Newby]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://yearofrandomreading.wordpress.com/?p=460</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[THE LAST GRAIN RACE, by Eric Newby, published in 1956 Bookcase 10, shelf 9, book 3 What a winner, getting this &#8211; one of my all-time favourite travel books. One of my all-time favourite books, in fact. And in this case I am including the actual, physical book in my remark, because this is a [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=460&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>THE LAST GRAIN RACE</strong>, by Eric Newby, published in 1956</p>
<p><em>Bookcase 10, shelf 9, book 3</em></p>
<p><img class="alignleft  wp-image-462" title="book" src="http://yearofrandomreading.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/img_2240.jpg?w=150&h=200" alt="" width="150" height="200" />What a winner, getting this &#8211; one of my all-time favourite travel books. One of my all-time favourite <em>books</em>, in fact. And in this case I am including the actual, physical book in my remark, because this is a first edition I found several years ago at a book fair when I was on holiday on the north Norfolk coast. It replaced a Picador paperback which had been read so often that it fell apart (not always that difficult with some of those white-spined Picador titles, mind).</p>
<p>I remember once hearing <em>The Last Grain Race</em> being discussed on Radio 4, and somebody dismissed it as &#8216;very much a bloke&#8217;s book&#8217;. Rubbish. I am most definitely not a bloke, and I adore it, so perhaps I should explain why instead of simply repeating the fact that it&#8217;s a wonderful read.</p>
<p>A large part of its appeal is down to Eric Newby&#8217;s attitude and the sheer style and class of his writing, writing which is never over the top or remotely purple, writing which nonetheless conveys the wonder of the world, whether that is rounding Cape Horn on one of the last grain clippers here, hiding from Nazis in Italy (<em>Love and War in the Appenines</em>) or trekking through Nuristan with a maniac friend (<em>A Short Walk in the Hindu Kush</em>). Lest anyone who doesn&#8217;t know Eric Newby assume he was a cross between James Bond and Richard Hannay, I&#8217;ll add that he is equally evocative describing his youth in Barnes or his work in the post-war rag trade (<em>Something Wholesale</em>). And of course he is also self-depreciating (the classic anecdote is one from <em>Hindu Kush</em>, where he and his companion encounter that legendary traveller Wilfrid Thesiger. They blew up their inflatable matresses at night, getting a predictable reaction from the Great Man: &#8216;God, you must be a couple of pansies&#8217;&#8230;) and immensely funny.</p>
<p><em>The Last Grain Race</em> is the story of his voyage around the world as a young apprentice on board <em>Moshulu</em>, one of the last of the great windjammers, in 1938-9.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><img class="wp-image-463 aligncenter" title="Moshulu" src="http://yearofrandomreading.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/img_2242.jpg?w=467&h=266" alt="" width="467" height="266" /></p>
<p>(<em>Moshulu</em>, incidentally, has a brief role in <em>Godfather II</em>, where she carries the young Vito Corleone to America &#8211; watch out for it, as it gives an idea of the scale of these huge but lightly crewed grain ships.)</p>
<p>Newby had always been tempted by the sea and finally gave in to romanticism, bad influences (Mountstewart, an elderly friend and possibly certifiable lunatic), heredity (his father &#8216;had once tried to run away to sea and been brought back from Millwall in a hackney cab&#8217;) and the growing realisation that this was an opportunity which was about to disappear from the oceans of the world for ever. He kept a meticulous record during the voyage, as well as writing letters and taking many remarkable photographs, all of which enabled him to write <em>Grain Race</em> so evocatively nearly 20 years later.</p>
<p><img class="alignleft  wp-image-469" title="newby" src="http://yearofrandomreading.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/img_22451.jpg?w=200&h=145" alt="" width="200" height="145" />After a laborious attempt to locate a caribou-skin sleeping bag &#8211; &#8216;it took up a great deal of time which I could have spent more profitably in eating&#8217; &#8211; which he had become convinced was necessary (the salesman: &#8216;The last one gave the man who slept in it anthrax&#8217;), and lugging the second-hand Louis Vuitton trunk found in a lost property shop, Newby set off for Belfast, <em>Moshulu </em>and &#8211; eventually &#8211; the Southern Ocean. All in all, for a voyage of some 30,000 miles.</p>
<p>The ship finally left the unappealing docks of pre-war Belfast on 18 October, and EN began a steep learning curve in everything from getting on with his variously eccentric shipmates to climbing the rigging in all situations (above a dock, in a storm, when someone is throwing up on your head), to what happens if you lose a hammer over the side and how bad a dead dog smells when you excavate it from the ballast four months after the Belfast stevedores have amusingly placed it there.</p>
<p><img class="alignright  wp-image-474" title="aloft" src="http://yearofrandomreading.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/img_2246.jpg?w=200&h=165" alt="" width="200" height="165" />There is a lot of detail about the organization of a sailing ship, but it can easily be skipped; in fact, Newby tells readers where to jump to at one point if they don&#8217;t want to follow his &#8216;technical interlude&#8217;. Even without reading that, though, you inevitably pick up a lot of vicarious knowledge &#8211; how slippery the ratlines could be, and how dangerous; how to clean the revolting heads; how to set a course in Swedish, the working language of the ship.</p>
<p>And so the outward journey to Australia continues, Moshulu crossing the equator (with a horrible initiation ceremony for those who had not done so before, including EN) about a month after sailing.There is some wonderful writing about the sea, evocative in the extreme:</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><em>&#8216;On Christmas morning the weather was cold and brilliant. Big following seas were charging up astern in endless succession. They surged beneath the ship, bearing her up, filling the air with whistling spray as their great heads tore out from under and ahead to leave her in a trough as black and polished as basalt except where, under the stern post, the angle of the rudder made the water bubble jade-green, as from a spring. From the mizzen yardarm, where I hung festooned with photographic apparatus, I could see the whole midships…&#8217;</em></p>
<p><img class="alignleft  wp-image-475" title="book" src="http://yearofrandomreading.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/img_2244.jpg?w=200&h=165" alt="" width="200" height="165" />Now is the time to mention the photographs &#8211; the extraordinary photographs. They are so good, and so comparatively rare, documenting life on a windjammer, that at least one commentator has described them as the most important aspect of Eric Newby&#8217;s work. They are indeed excellent, and in my edition are reproduced particularly well. In fact a book entirely devoted to them was published in 1999 &#8211; <em>Learning the Ropes</em>.</p>
<p>The ship arrived in Australia in early January, loaded and left in March 1939, and arrived back at Queenstown (now Cobh) in June, 91 days out. <em>Moshulu</em> was the winner of the &#8217;39 grain race. But this was just before the outbreak of war and everything was to change, and change extremely fast, just as EN had anticipated. One of the other ships in the race, the <em>Olivebank</em>, hit a German mine in early September, but <em>Moshulu</em> herself survived, and is now &#8211; wait for it &#8211; a floating restaurant. And occasional film location.</p>
<p>Throughout <em>The Last Grain Race</em>, as with his other books, Eric Newby&#8217;s essentially genial and humane personality comes through. Yes, he&#8217;s a romantic, but he finds that characteristic amusing and gently pokes fun at his younger self (as in the affair of the wretched sleeping bag). He genuinely<em> likes</em> people and finds them interesting &#8211; and that&#8217;s not something you can say for every travel writer, or indeed every writer. There&#8217;s no need to explain away undesirable attitudes as being &#8216;common at the time&#8217; or &#8216;simply reflecting the times in which the book was written&#8217; because there aren&#8217;t any such attitudes in evidence. Having met the man himself when I was a baby bookseller, I can testify to his genuine <em>niceness</em> &#8211; an often under-esteemed quality.</p>
<p>A wonderful book, and a wonderful author.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-477" title="grain race" src="http://yearofrandomreading.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/img_2243.jpg?w=467&h=349" alt="" width="467" height="349" /></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/460/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/460/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=460&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://yearofrandomreading.wordpress.com/2012/08/14/op-the-rigging/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/97b2f9a0fee6db31c4d06c7ad43e3ed1?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">yearofrandomreading</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://yearofrandomreading.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/img_2240.jpg?w=104" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">book</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://yearofrandomreading.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/img_2242.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Moshulu</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://yearofrandomreading.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/img_22451.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">newby</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://yearofrandomreading.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/img_2246.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">aloft</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://yearofrandomreading.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/img_2244.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">book</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://yearofrandomreading.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/img_2243.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">grain race</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>My New Art Wall</title>
		<link>http://destashio.wordpress.com/2012/08/04/my-new-art-wall/</link>
		<comments>http://destashio.wordpress.com/2012/08/04/my-new-art-wall/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2012 04:33:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>kjpaints</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Accessories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[collecting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Etsy shop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Happy Me]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[home]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[paint chips]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://destashio.wordpress.com/?p=182</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I painted my living room last Fall and purposely left one wall empty, (by empty I mean that there is nothing hanging on the wall, it&#8217;s obviously not empty, but full of flowers and swirls, I get it) because I wanted to have an art wall. I had collected pieces and had a unique idea [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=182&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://destashio.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_2292_edited-2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-183" title="IMG_2292_edited-2" src="http://destashio.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_2292_edited-2.jpg?w=1024&h=715" alt="" width="1024" height="715" /></a>I painted my living room last Fall and purposely left one wall empty, (by empty I mean that there is nothing hanging on the wall, it&#8217;s obviously not empty, but full of flowers and swirls, I get it) because I wanted to have an art wall. I had collected pieces and had a unique idea of how to display them, and this weekend I finally did it.</p>
<p><a href="http://destashio.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_2293_edited-2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-184" title="IMG_2293_edited-2" src="http://destashio.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_2293_edited-2.jpg?w=1024&h=677" alt="" width="1024" height="677" /></a>Super cool, right?! So the ledges are made out of the wood pieces that make up a barrel.  I had a half barrel that fell apart last fall and I&#8217;ve been trying to use the pieces, so there you go. Now I&#8217;ll break down the pieces in my collection&#8230;&#8230;</p>
<p><a href="http://destashio.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_2297_edited-11.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-188" title="IMG_2297_edited-1" src="http://destashio.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_2297_edited-11.jpg?w=1024&h=768" alt="" width="1024" height="768" /></a>I have a thing for crows, just a warning. This is a photograph taken by my friend <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/bitterbetty/">Dana Wilkerson</a>. I mounted it on a counter top sample I made for a client. It&#8217;s been sitting in the studio with no purpose. I framed the photo with four rusted metal filigree corners I bought this spring at a Paris flea market. (Don&#8217;t you hate it when people just drop in to conversation that they&#8217;ve shopped at a Paris flea market? Makes you want to stab them in the head with your boring Wal-Mart fork). I absolutely love the combination of materials. I think it shows off the photo perfectly. And it&#8217;s an awesome photo.</p>
<p><a href="http://destashio.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_2298_edited-21.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-189" title="IMG_2298_edited-2" src="http://destashio.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_2298_edited-21.jpg?w=1024&h=768" alt="" width="1024" height="768" /></a>This is just a piece I made out of paint chips for fun.</p>
<p><a href="http://destashio.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_2299_edited-1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-187" title="IMG_2299_edited-1" src="http://destashio.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_2299_edited-1.jpg?w=939&h=1024" alt="" width="939" height="1024" /></a>This is a piece I painted that is also for sale in<a href="https://www.etsy.com/listing/78875653/original-painting-light-wishes"> my Etsy shop</a>. I love the little fat blue bird in the corner.</p>
<p><a href="http://destashio.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_2300_edited-1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-190" title="IMG_2300_edited-1" src="http://destashio.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_2300_edited-1.jpg?w=1024&h=768" alt="" width="1024" height="768" /></a>This is another fantastic crow photo by my friend <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/bitterbetty/">Dana Wilkerson</a>. It&#8217;s super spooky looking and I love it. The old frame is beat up, but it was given to me by a friend who told me it had survived the fires here in San Diego even when his house didn&#8217;t. I love it&#8217;s gothic flavor and the subtle smell of mesquite.</p>
<p><a href="http://destashio.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_2301_edited-1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-193" title="IMG_2301_edited-1" src="http://destashio.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_2301_edited-1.jpg?w=1024&h=768" alt="" width="1024" height="768" /></a>This is a brass/cloisonne style dish that I found at a thrift store and fell in love with. Every home needs at least one unicorn, right?</p>
<p><a href="http://destashio.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_2302_edited-1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-192" title="IMG_2302_edited-1" src="http://destashio.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_2302_edited-1.jpg?w=1024&h=819" alt="" width="1024" height="819" /></a>This is a painting my husband bought for my mother when he was in the Middle East. Unfortunately, she died the night he came home, so she never saw it. It reminds me of their relationship and how special it was. He said it was painted by a street artist. My mom would have loved it.</p>
<p><a href="http://destashio.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_2303_edited-1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-194" title="IMG_2303_edited-1" src="http://destashio.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_2303_edited-1.jpg?w=1024&h=768" alt="" width="1024" height="768" /></a>This is a print I bought at a craft fair from a <a href="http://www.zuill.us/illustration/?page_id=111">local artist</a> who shares my dark sense of humor. It&#8217;s titled &#8220;Bo Peep and Eric.&#8221; Bo Peep&#8217;s evil face just kills me.</p>
<p><a href="http://destashio.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_2305_edited-1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-195" title="IMG_2305_edited-1" src="http://destashio.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_2305_edited-1.jpg?w=768&h=1024" alt="" width="768" height="1024" /></a>These are metal letter stencils that I bought at a Paris flea market (there she goes again, why hasn&#8217;t anyone stabbed her?). I put scrapbook paper behind them to highlight the letters. Simple.</p>
<p><a href="http://destashio.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_2295_edited-1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-196" title="IMG_2295_edited-1" src="http://destashio.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_2295_edited-1.jpg?w=1024&h=768" alt="" width="1024" height="768" /></a>So there&#8217;s my new art wall. There&#8217;s room for more and it&#8217;s definitely open to change as I find new pieces. I love it!</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://destashio.wordpress.com/category/accessories/'>Accessories</a>, <a href='http://destashio.wordpress.com/category/art/'>Art</a>, <a href='http://destashio.wordpress.com/category/family/'>Family</a> Tagged: <a href='http://destashio.wordpress.com/tag/collecting/'>collecting</a>, <a href='http://destashio.wordpress.com/tag/etsy-shop/'>Etsy shop</a>, <a href='http://destashio.wordpress.com/tag/happy-me/'>Happy Me</a>, <a href='http://destashio.wordpress.com/tag/home/'>home</a>, <a href='http://destashio.wordpress.com/tag/paint-chips/'>paint chips</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/182/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/182/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=182&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://destashio.wordpress.com/2012/08/04/my-new-art-wall/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>30</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/1d15345745268995f22e544aec1f07d8?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">kjpaints</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://destashio.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_2292_edited-2.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_2292_edited-2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://destashio.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_2293_edited-2.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_2293_edited-2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://destashio.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_2297_edited-11.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_2297_edited-1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://destashio.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_2298_edited-21.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_2298_edited-2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://destashio.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_2299_edited-1.jpg?w=939" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_2299_edited-1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://destashio.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_2300_edited-1.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_2300_edited-1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://destashio.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_2301_edited-1.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_2301_edited-1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://destashio.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_2302_edited-1.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_2302_edited-1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://destashio.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_2303_edited-1.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_2303_edited-1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://destashio.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_2305_edited-1.jpg?w=768" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_2305_edited-1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://destashio.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_2295_edited-1.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_2295_edited-1</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Sense of Community in the Arts</title>
		<link>http://tuxedorevoltblog.wordpress.com/2012/08/08/a-sense-of-community-in-the-arts/</link>
		<comments>http://tuxedorevoltblog.wordpress.com/2012/08/08/a-sense-of-community-in-the-arts/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2012 02:22:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tuxedorevoltblog</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advocacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Inspiration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Performance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[performance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Performing arts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sense of community]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tuxedorevoltblog.wordpress.com/?p=284</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#160; &#160; &#160; &#160; &#160; &#160; &#160; There is a natural phenomenon within the arts community where artists generally only interact with similar artists—painters talk to painters, dancers talk to dancers, musicians to musicians and so on.  But why is this so?  I think that branching out and seeking inspiration from a variety of resources [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=284&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 250px"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/22498907@N02/2595051813" target="_blank"><img class="zemanta-img-inserted zemanta-img-configured" title="communities already exist" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3143/2595051813_c4bba49555_m.jpg" alt="communities already exist" width="240" height="160" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">communities already exist (Photo credit: Will Lion)</p></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>There is a natural phenomenon within the arts community where artists generally only interact with similar artists—painters talk to painters, dancers talk to dancers, musicians to musicians and so on.  But why is this so?  I think that branching out and seeking inspiration from a variety of resources is key to creating highly original work.</p>
<p>Of course, there are the obvious reasons: similar lifestyles, similar challenges, and similar pools of knowledge from which to share. On some levels, I get it. As a performing musician who has spent the past seven years steeped in music school and conservatory, I understand why we gravitate to others like ourselves.  However, I wonder if in some way that this may be hurting us or stifling our creativity? When musicians or any other kind of similar performers spend so much time around each other, how much truly original work can be generated?</p>
<p>For example, when only musicians hang out together, both professionally and socially, the strongest source of input into their artistic lives may only be other musicians. In fact, it gets more narrowly defined than that.  It is my experience that horn players stick together, violinists stick together, woodwinds, low brass, etc.  It is really common. Sure there will always be exceptions to the rule, and this is not an absolute truth (very few things are). <em> </em>But what is important here is to realize that this is the case in many performing arts settings.  I call this social condition, <em>cultural insulation.</em></p>
<p>Why is this a negative thing?  Well, for a while it is actually not a negative influence. When performers are first to learning their craft, it is good to be around others learning the same thing. According to constructivist theories on learning, a process called scaffolding takes place where the learner joins together bits and pieces of information from various sources to make a mental construct about the subject being learned.  For an (elementary) example, if I learn from Joe that I need soil to grow plants, and I learn from Jane that I need to water my plants, I have then learned that plants need both soil and water to grow.   The problem with cultural insulation is that once we have a working body of knowledge, we have problems when it comes time to stop modeling others and make our own artistic decisions.</p>
<p>Throughout my time in conservatory, I saw time and time again hordes of talented young musicians all striving to be better than each other. Something you would expect to see in a conservatory right? The problem was, that because they were all mostly influenced by each other in this microcosm-music-society, the performances were all incredibly similar, reaching an almost homogenous level.  It was literally recital after recital of <em>exactly the same thing. </em>This sort of problem has been going on for decades in music schools, and I will bet that it similar in other performing institutions.</p>
<p>PERFORMING ARTISTS NEED TO MIX AND MINGLE WITH OTHER ARTISTS FROM DIFFERENT GENRES.</p>
<p>Once we know a good deal about the mechanics and technique of our performance area, then we should start thinking about how to use the tools we have learned to create original and inspiring performances.  This is key to the originality in the live performance.</p>
<p>Over the course of this blog, I’ll dig more deeply into why this is important for growth in our artistry. This is important for non-performing artists as well as it helps to create a richness and fullness in life.</p>
<p>There is so much out there for us to learn and enrich our lives and art by. I’ll help you think of creative ways to meet others, to invigorate your performances with new material and to make your life more well rounded by constantly absorbing ideas from the world around you.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Stay tuned,</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>John-Morgan</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/284/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/284/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=284&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tuxedorevoltblog.wordpress.com/2012/08/08/a-sense-of-community-in-the-arts/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		<georss:point>40.714353 -74.005973</georss:point>
		<geo:lat>40.714353</geo:lat>
		<geo:long>-74.005973</geo:long>
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/581dd948fef628d18a57eab147dfe6ee?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F2.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tuxedorevoltblog</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3143/2595051813_c4bba49555_m.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">communities already exist</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Limericks of Street Art</title>
		<link>http://whatisthecity.wordpress.com/2012/08/14/limericks-of-street-art/</link>
		<comments>http://whatisthecity.wordpress.com/2012/08/14/limericks-of-street-art/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2012 07:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>kasprzyszak</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[What is the City?]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Limericks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Street art]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://whatisthecity.wordpress.com/?p=33</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[With sights, there is a part Which argues that it is quite smart. It expresses issues It reaches for tissues It is, of course, Street Art. The artists show their passion By creating the city&#8217;s fashion. They spray and paint; or is it &#8220;taint&#8221;? Because some think that they lack compassion. The government wants it [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=33&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://whatisthecity.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/767409-melbourne-street-art.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image aligncenter" src="http://whatisthecity.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/767409-melbourne-street-art.jpg?w=487" alt="Image" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">With sights, there is a part<br />
Which argues that it is quite smart.<br />
It expresses issues<br />
It reaches for tissues<br />
It is, of course, Street Art.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">The artists show their passion<br />
By creating the city&#8217;s fashion.<br />
They spray and paint;<br />
or is it &#8220;taint&#8221;?<br />
Because some think that they lack compassion.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">The government wants it clean<br />
Because they think its obscene.<br />
They clean the grime<br />
It takes some time<br />
They don&#8217;t want to be seen as mean.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">So the graffiti gets taken down<br />
And the artists give some frowns.<br />
It&#8217;s like, c&#8217;mon<br />
It goes on and on;<br />
This endless routine of clowns.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">Street art, in its physical form, can be great.<br />
But behind it all, it&#8217;s one long debate.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">Between artists and authority that cannot agree<br />
An endless and repetitive struggle for eternity.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/33/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/33/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=33&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://whatisthecity.wordpress.com/2012/08/14/limericks-of-street-art/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/53ed3a40a1297eca1a90c4036a526734?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">kasprzyszak</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://whatisthecity.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/767409-melbourne-street-art.jpg?w=487" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>In Which Elena Goes to the Bank: A Pilgrimage in 3 Acts.</title>
		<link>http://elenainenglish.wordpress.com/2012/08/13/in-which-elena-goes-to-the-bank-a-pilgrimage-in-3-acts/</link>
		<comments>http://elenainenglish.wordpress.com/2012/08/13/in-which-elena-goes-to-the-bank-a-pilgrimage-in-3-acts/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2012 23:41:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Elena Fultz</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Real life...whatever that means...]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adventures in a Big City]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drivethru]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Driving without a GPS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Frustration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Getting Lost]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internal gps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Maps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pneumatic Tubes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rush hour traffic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://elenainenglish.wordpress.com/?p=941</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Today I went to the bank. In the small town where I grew up, this statement would mean a simple thing, even a pleasant bike trip through blocks of houses on the main drag. I might have to wait for two or three stoplights while the rush hour traffic (ten cars) speeds through. Or I [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=941&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today I went to the bank.</p>
<p>In the small town where I grew up, this statement would mean a simple thing, even a pleasant bike trip through blocks of houses on the main drag. I might have to wait for two or three stoplights while the rush hour traffic (ten cars) speeds through. Or I could take the trail overlooking the glittering lake and avoid traffic altogether<em>. </em>Ah, blissful summer of bike rides through town.</p>
<p>But banks, I am learning, are not simple in a city. Please, join me for: <em>Elena Goes to the Bank: A Pilgrimage in 3 Acts</em><em>. </em>That should really be <em>3 months, </em>starting with</p>
<p><strong>June.</strong></p>
<p>I find I need to cash a check.</p>
<p>I attempt to Google search for the nearest location of my bank, since the Big City is not something you &#8220;spin through&#8221;. (If only things were labeled like toy towns: &#8220;The Hospital&#8221;&#8211;&#8221;The Library&#8221;&#8211;&#8221;The Toy Store.&#8221; Because, you know, there&#8217;s only one of each.) The little blurp on the internet map shows that there&#8217;s one right by me. Your Personal Bank! Mere minutes away! Even on foot! It even gives times they&#8217;re open.</p>
<p>But I am smarter than the bank. I drive to this location, carefully, and my suspicions are confirmed. This bank is new and <em>under construction</em>. Like, it has no walls. I can see straight through all the steel frames to the heavy machinery on the other side. The whole thing is one big drivethru. Maybe they&#8217;re hoping I&#8217;ll stop by (during open hours) and toss my money toward them. Hah.</p>
<p>So I drive to the next nearest location: life is not easy, sans GPS. There is Summer Construction. Suddenly one-way signs are popping up like Whac-a-Moles and I&#8217;m going <em>all the wrong ways</em> and then suddenly I&#8217;m on the university campus. Surprise! There are students on the crosswalks wearing shoes that are so high-heeled I&#8217;m surprised they&#8217;re still vertical. There are students biking everywhere. There are flashing signs vying for everyone&#8217;s attention, which of course no one is looking at. The the stoplight decides to take a nap. My internal GPS is calmly announcing to me: &#8220;Searching for satellite. Searching for satellite.&#8221; Your Personal Bank is not supposed to be located on the university campus.</p>
<p>Finally I arrive at the bank, after multiple, multiple turnarounds in rush hour. The line is out the door; they&#8217;re closing in half an hour. The woman ahead of me gets too impatient and leaves. I can see her through the bank windows using the drivethru. So now it&#8217;s just five people ahead of me. I have a conversation to pass the time:</p>
<div id="attachment_996" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 173px"><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Bank_pneumatic_tubes.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-996" title="Bank_pneumatic_tubes" src="http://elenainenglish.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/bank_pneumatic_tubes.jpeg?w=163&h=300" alt="" width="163" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">&#8220;Pneumatic Tubes,&#8221; it turns out they&#8217;re called. Used for sending things to the mother ship. (Click for credit.)</p></div>
<p>Me: There&#8217;s something funny about people sticking their money in little tubes, and it going up all by itself into the bank. It&#8217;s so&#8230;<em>space age.</em>&#8220;</p>
<p>College-age girl behind me: Haha!</p>
<p>Me: [encouraged] It&#8217;s just so cool! I mean, a tube sucks up the little container&#8211;how does it do that? Does it have something attached to it? Who <em>thinks</em> of stuff like this?</p>
<p>College-age girl behind me: &#8230;[long pause]</p>
<p>Me: Clearly I don&#8217;t get out much.</p>
<p>Then she really laughs, and it&#8217;s a big beautiful laugh, and I laugh too, and we both sound like we haven&#8217;t laughed all day, which is at least true of me. And I am reminded again that she is a person, not just a crabby driver refusing to let me merge, and not just a stupid internet employee sending me to non-existent banks. She&#8217;s just a person, and we&#8217;re waiting in line like good people in a big city do.</p>
<p>Big cities. There&#8217;s nothing so bad about them&#8230;there&#8217;s just so much <em>more</em> of them.</p>
<p>I burn up another 45 minutes and all of my warm fuzzy just trying to get home. <em>More of them</em>, my foot.</p>
<p>Stay tuned (oh, <em>stay tuned</em>) for part 2.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/941/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/941/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=941&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://elenainenglish.wordpress.com/2012/08/13/in-which-elena-goes-to-the-bank-a-pilgrimage-in-3-acts/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/26c23edac48757a0c93ee3c06abb3bd8?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">elenafultz</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://elenainenglish.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/bank_pneumatic_tubes.jpeg?w=163" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Bank_pneumatic_tubes</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Bottle Test</title>
		<link>http://nevalalee.wordpress.com/2012/08/14/the-bottle-test/</link>
		<comments>http://nevalalee.wordpress.com/2012/08/14/the-bottle-test/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2012 15:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>nevalalee</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breaking Bad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Glee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mad Men]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The X-Files]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nevalalee.wordpress.com/?p=13074</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Earlier this year, while watching the entire run of Breaking Bad for the first time, I finally saw &#8220;Fly,&#8221; which is generally considered to be one of the show&#8217;s definitive episodes. It takes place almost entirely in the secret meth lab, as Walt and Jesse go to increasingly elaborate—and dangerous—lengths to kill a pesky fly [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=13074&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://nevalalee.wordpress.com/2012/08/14/the-bottle-test/breaking-bad-fly/" rel="attachment wp-att-13075"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-13075" title="The Breaking Bad episode &quot;Fly&quot;" src="http://nevalalee.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/breaking-bad-fly.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="237" /></a></p>
<p>Earlier this year, while watching the entire run of <a title="Vince Gilligan and the dark genius of Breaking Bad" href="http://nevalalee.wordpress.com/2012/08/10/vince-gilligan-and-the-dark-genius-of-breaking-bad/"><em>Breaking Bad</em></a> for the first time, I finally saw <a href="http://www.avclub.com/articles/fly,41430/">&#8220;Fly,&#8221;</a> which is generally considered to be one of the show&#8217;s definitive episodes. It takes place almost entirely in the secret meth lab, as Walt and Jesse go to increasingly elaborate—and dangerous—lengths to kill a pesky fly that ends up symbolizing everything that has gone wrong with both of their lives. And while the conceit was divisive at time, I think it&#8217;s easily one of the strongest episodes of the series, and more riveting than many of the show&#8217;s busier, more conventionally plotted installments. Part of this is because it focuses squarely on its two most compelling characters, without the digressions to relatively weaker players like Skyler or Marie who tend to sap the momentum. But it&#8217;s also a reflection of the inherent strength of one of the most fascinating conventions of episodic television, a form of storytelling that, at its best, offers us nothing less than a distilled version of the shows we love: the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bottle_episode">bottle episode</a>.</p>
<p>A bottle episode, as viewers of the <a href="http://www.avclub.com/articles/cooperative-calligraphy,47383/">&#8220;Cooperative Calligraphy&#8221;</a> episode of <a title="What would the Community think?" href="http://nevalalee.wordpress.com/2012/03/22/what-would-the-community-think/"><em>Community</em></a> or the nerds on <a href="http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/BottleEpisode">TV Tropes</a> already know, is an episode of a television series that takes place mostly on one set, and often with only the show&#8217;s regular cast. Bottle episodes are usually a budgetary measure, born out of a need to save time or money, but as is often the case when constraints are imposed, the results can be remarkable. My own favorite example is the <a title="Learning from the masters: Darin Morgan and The X-Files" href="http://nevalalee.wordpress.com/2011/04/01/learning-from-the-masters-darin-morgan-and-the-x-files/"><em>X-Files</em></a> episode <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ice_%28The_X-Files%29">&#8220;Ice,&#8221;</a> which, aside from a couple of establishing scenes, takes place entirely in an abandoned research base in Alaska. The result seems designed to economize in more ways than one—the plot is essentially an extended riff on <em>The Thing</em>—but it&#8217;s also the first great episode of the series, and one of the best the show ever did. It established the fact that the show&#8217;s true strengths had nothing to do with elaborate conspiracies or special effects, but with the ingenious working out of tense, surprising premises. And it&#8217;s no accident that the show&#8217;s storytelling became immediately more confident after &#8220;Ice&#8221; established what the series could really do.</p>
<p><a href="http://nevalalee.wordpress.com/2012/08/14/the-bottle-test/x-files-ice/" rel="attachment wp-att-13076"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-13076" title="The X-Files episode &quot;Ice&quot;" src="http://nevalalee.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/x-files-ice.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a></p>
<p>In fact, the more I think about it, the more I&#8217;d argue that the ability to deliver a great bottle episode is a measure of a show&#8217;s quality. Only a show with supreme confidence in its cast, its premise, the technical qualities of its writing and direction, and a willingness to embrace constraint and simplicity can pull off an episode like this. And if we apply this hypothetical test to an actual show, the resulting thought experiment tells us a lot about the series in question. It&#8217;s hard to imagine a show like <a title="Farewell to Glee" href="http://nevalalee.wordpress.com/2012/05/17/farewell-to-glee/"><em>Glee</em></a>, for instance, with its obsession with burning through ideas and plotlines as quickly as possible, generating the necessary focus to keep its primary cast in a room for forty minutes while still keeping our attention. (<a href="http://www.avclub.com/articles/blame-it-on-the-alcohol,52122/">&#8220;Blame It On the Alcohol&#8221;</a> is a great example of a potentially promising bottle episode that chickens out halfway through.) Conversely, while <a title="The fractal brilliance of Mad Men" href="http://nevalalee.wordpress.com/2012/03/27/the-fractal-brilliance-of-mad-men/"><em>Mad Men</em></a> has never done a true bottle episode—<a href="http://www.avclub.com/articles/the-suitcase,44857/">&#8220;The Suitcase&#8221;</a> probably comes closest—the prospect of keeping these characters in a single location is undeniably enticing.</p>
<p>Which only demonstrates that part of the appeal of the bottle episode is that it&#8217;s really an allegory for the act of making television itself. Any television series, after all, really amounts to a bottle episode being played out in real life over the course of many seasons: it involves a group of actors, writers, and other professionals thrown together on a few standing sets, often without a lot of advance preparation, so that it&#8217;s anyone&#8217;s guess what will come next. This is especially true of comedy, in which the dynamics present in the pilot will often evolve in ways that nobody could have anticipated at the time: a secondary character will turn into a <a href="http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/BreakoutCharacter">breakout star</a>, supporting players will fall flat or rise to the occasion, and <a title="Bridesmaids, Metcalfe’s Law, and the power of ensembles" href="http://nevalalee.wordpress.com/2011/05/25/bridesmaids-metcalfes-law-and-the-power-of-ensembles/">unusual pairings and combinations</a> will arise under the endless pressure of producing new stories. The more interesting the ensuing collisions, the better the show will be. And none of this would happen if the process weren&#8217;t already taking place in a bottle—and unfolding before our eyes.</p>
<p><em>Note: If this is your first time here, please take a moment to visit my <a title="About me" href="http://nevalalee.wordpress.com/about/">author page</a> and learn a bit about my novel </em><a href="http://www.amazon.com/The-Icon-Thief-Alec-Nevala-Lee/dp/0451236203">The Icon Thief</a><em>.</em></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/13074/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/13074/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=13074&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://nevalalee.wordpress.com/2012/08/14/the-bottle-test/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>15</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a86a6b77ede854a68ec81fa62c7a80eb?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">nevalalee</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nevalalee.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/breaking-bad-fly.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The Breaking Bad episode &#34;Fly&#34;</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nevalalee.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/x-files-ice.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The X-Files episode &#34;Ice&#34;</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Paypal: Romance Meets Finance (Just Buy It)</title>
		<link>http://toddgarlington.wordpress.com/2012/08/13/paypal-culture-commentary-2/</link>
		<comments>http://toddgarlington.wordpress.com/2012/08/13/paypal-culture-commentary-2/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2012 03:34:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Todd Garlington</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advertising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Consumerism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Psychology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Romance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Capitalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Paypal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Survival of the fittest]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://toddgarlington.wordpress.com/?p=159</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Advertising’s love affair with romance goes way back, perhaps to the birth of advertising itself.  People never seem to tire of images that portray intimacy in connection with the act of purchasing.  A recent ad by Paypal seems innocuous enough: a girl wearing a heart-shaped pendant kisses a young man in a suit.  Our eyes [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=159&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://toddgarlington.wordpress.com/2012/08/13/paypal-culture-commentary-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://toddgarlington.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/paypal-necklace-selected-privacy-protected.jpeg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://toddgarlington.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/paypal-necklace-selected-privacy-protected.jpeg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Paypal: Romance Meets Finance</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c77f6daab53160152354740a253e4316?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">toddgarlington</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://toddgarlington.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/paypal-necklace-selected-privacy-protected.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Paypal: Romance Meets Finance</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Does Social Networking Make Us Narcissists?</title>
		<link>http://katherinetoms.wordpress.com/2012/08/13/does-social-networking-make-us-narcissists/</link>
		<comments>http://katherinetoms.wordpress.com/2012/08/13/does-social-networking-make-us-narcissists/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2012 03:40:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Katherine Toms</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consumerism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creativity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gender]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[authenticity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Higher Unlearning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[identity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jeff Perera]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Luka Magnotta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[narcissism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nina Arsenault]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social networking]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://katherinetoms.wordpress.com/?p=1154</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I think Nina Arsenault is an incredible artist. [Heads up, her website has some NSFW content.] She explores and deconstructs the concept of &#8220;personhood&#8221; with such ferocity, it&#8217;s completely breathtaking. I recently read an interview with Nina Arsenault about her ties with serial killer Luka Magnotta. (Thanks Jeff Perera at Higher Unlearning for sharing the [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1154&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://katherinetoms.wordpress.com/2012/08/13/does-social-networking-make-us-narcissists/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>60</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/b50eed04a1d0c0cc735fbfc0f1299def?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=R" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">katherinetoms</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://katherinetoms.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/nina_mannequins.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Nina Arsenault - Mannequin (2007)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://katherinetoms.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/venetian-masks.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Venetian Masks</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://katherinetoms.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/nina_plasticsurgery.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Nina Arsenault - Ordinary Day, Extraordinary Girl (2007)</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>