<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 20:06:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Protest:  Egypt, France, Venezuela</title>
		<link>http://zoetropic.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/protest-egypt-france-venezuela/</link>
		<comments>http://zoetropic.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/protest-egypt-france-venezuela/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 19:08:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>zoetropic</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Personal Essays]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cultural Comparisons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture Clash]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Civil War]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Current events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Egypt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Libya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[March]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Middle East]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Protest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Revolution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[South America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[students]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thoughts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Unrest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venezuela]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[violence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://zoetropic.wordpress.com/?p=1469</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Like many, I have been captivated by the news and images coming from the Middle East over the last month or two.  It has been fascinating to watch the virus of vocalized dissatisfaction spread from city to city, region to region, country to country.  I say with a bit of shame and awe, it took [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=1469&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Like many, I have been captivated by the news and images coming from the Middle East over the last month or two.  It has been fascinating to watch the virus of vocalized dissatisfaction spread from city to city, region to region, country to country.  I say with a bit of shame and awe, it took me completely by surprise.  I never had the thought in my head that things in that region might change so dramatically over such a short period of time.</p>
<p>I was on the phone with my father about two weeks ago, just after Mubarak finally resigned, and we were talking about Egypt.  He chuckled and said, &#8220;I bet you are half glad to be somewhere else, but half really wish you were there right now.&#8221;</p>
<p>It’s true.  It must have been a sublime three weeks in Egypt – at times frightening and disheartening and at other time intoxicating.  Only someone who has actually lived through a revolution could really understand what it was like to be there, to experience the swell of energy that doesn’t just recede but breaks with enough force to create true change.</p>
<p>And while of course I am grateful to be in a safe and democratic country, I also am left so curious as to what it has really been like for people living through these tumultuous weeks. I try to imagine the feelings pulsing through the cities as things move up and down and back and forth, drama after drama unraveling.  I try to imagine the surge in will and determination that leads people into the streets day after day.  I try to imagine how frightened and impotent people must feel as their governments use harsher and harsher methods to control the protests and stifle the descent, as people&#8217;s capacity to communicate with the outside world diminishes or ends altogether, as people are killed. I try to imagine the moments of defiance, of hope, of fear, of exaltation, and then (at least in the case of Tunisia and Egypt) of euphoria.</p>
<p>But the truth is I can&#8217;t.  I do not know what it feels like to be so oppressed and to have so much at stake, nor have I ever been anywhere at the precise moment of the emergence of momentous change.</p>
<p>The closest I’ve come perhaps was being in New York on 9/11 or Paris when France won the World Cup in 1998.</p>
<div id="attachment_1474" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 365px"><a href="http://zoetropic.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/paris-98-world-cup-win.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1474" title="Champs-elysees World Cup Win" src="http://zoetropic.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/paris-98-world-cup-win.jpg?w=355&#038;h=512" alt="" width="355" height="512" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Thousands of people fill the Champs-Elysees in Paris on July 13th, 1998, as they wait for the French national soccer team.  The French beat Brazil 3-0 in the World Cup final on July 12th. AFP photo by Gabriel Bouys.</p></div>
<p>In both cases I was part of an entire population brought together with a common feeling.  There was a sense of complete shared experience, in shock and tragedy in one circumstance, and celebration and pride in the other.</p>
<p>But these situations were so different because they were the experience of living through something that happens to a community, rather than something that a community makes happen.</p>
<p>How is it that things can go on one way for so very many years and then suddenly, over the period of a handful of days, change completely?  What is it that comes together to make that moment so different than all the moments that came before? What makes the perfect balance of specific factors that combine in a chemical reaction that cannot be reversed?</p>
<p>I guess what I wonder is how that moment, the moment on the way to change really happening, the moment just before the tipping point, FEELS to the people inside it, creating it?  When you are in the middle of it, part of it, riding the flow of it, do you have a sense of what is happening?  Do you feel as you act, as you watch, as you listen, that something is really happening, that you are in the middle of history in the making?  Is there a consciousness to it, or is it more raw and blind than that?  Do you act because you can imagine your actions having a positive outcome, because you can feel deeply that all of it is going somewhere, that there could be a breaking point right there in front of you?  Do you know somehow deep inside?  Or  is there a need to move and act, not because you feel the outcome, but just because you and those around you must, because you are carried along by an energy, a wave, a swell that must break some way or other for better or for worse?</p>
<p>Ostensibly I currently live in a country of protest; I would guess that the French strike more than any other nationality in the world.  As I said I have never been in a country during a period of true upheaval and dramatic change – but I think I can safely say that I believe that THIS is what it feels like to be in a country that is NOT on the verge of revolution.  THIS is what it feels like to be in a place that is not changing dramatically anytime soon.</p>
<p>In France, strikes happen all the time for one reason or another.  But every now and then (<span style="text-decoration:underline;"><em><a href="http://zoetropic.wordpress.com/2010/10/12/a_good_day_for_a_strike/"><span style="color:#ffff99;">like much of last Fall</span></a></em></span>)<strong> </strong>they will get really serious.  And the results? Flights will be cancelled, trains will be held up, roads will be blockaded.  There might be some shortages of fuel, maybe less fresh produce available in the grocery stores.  And if things get REALLY bad, garbage won’t be collected for a while.  People will get irritated, inconvenienced, and the government will get mildly perturbed, wondering how much it will cost them this time.</p>
<p>There is something so traditional about French strikes, like national clockwork.  It is not really progressive at all; the people march less to change things, as much as to keep them how they already are or to make them ever so slightly more agreeable.</p>
<p>The French government constantly must weigh every choice and decide if it is important enough to face the consequences of upsetting the people.  While on the one hand this is obviously a far superior system than a dictatorship, it also limits the government’s capacity to make any long-term choices that may be for the ultimate good of the country but might also, in the short term, inconvenience people or cause them some small discomforts.</p>
<span style="text-align:center; display: block;"><a href="http://zoetropic.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/protest-egypt-france-venezuela/"><img src="http://img.youtube.com/vi/zppIwQ-Kuik/2.jpg" alt="" /></a></span>
<p>While I think France does a lot of things really well, what I object to is how many people take it all for granted and are still dissatisfied, and don&#8217;t seem to recognize that sometimes small sacrifices are essential to the greater good and to a better future.  They protest, they complain, they show their anger, not with courage and idealism and a desire to start fresh, but a kind of pessimism.  They seem to be saying, &#8220;it&#8217;s still not good enough and it&#8217;s only going to get worse.&#8221;</p>
<p>Occasionally there is a different sort of protest here &#8211; a more sudden, explosive, destructive sort, where young men run around setting things on fire, breaking things and acting generally angry and disruptive. It&#8217;s usually disaffected young men from immigrant communities – they may be French, but are treated like ‘the other’, unaccepted and undervalued. These young people are angry – but as of yet it has always proven to be a somewhat directionless and vague anger, a kind of lashing out without any real goal apart from expressing rage.</p>
<p>Someday if this anger were to be channeled into real ideas about the changes that could be and should be in France in terms of multiculturalism, in terms of immigrant rights, in terms of religious rights, in terms of actually confronting the racism in France, well perhaps there could be a kind of revolution.</p>
<p>What would it be like if the immigrant community here really found a voice and found common ground and decided what they were fighting for?  It could be very powerful. But the people who currently feel disenfranchised and disaffected are not anywhere close to that.  They do not quite seem ready to find a common voice in order to verbalize what they want changed.</p>
<p>Apart from the immigrant community however most people in France don&#8217;t have a whole lot to complain about, although they relish doing so.   France currently feels like an arthritic sort of country &#8211; you just can&#8217;t expect it to move much or very quickly anymore. France of today is going to be a lot like France tomorrow and France next month and France next year.  But Egypt?  Tunisia? Libya?  What shape will they take in 5 years, one year, even one month? We can only guess.  I guess it’s precisely that – the numerous possibilities, both good and bad, that is what is both exciting and frightening about countries in flux.</p>
<p>This perhaps is what drew me to Venezuela.  I think I wanted to go somewhere in the throes of change – somewhere that wasn’t predictable, somewhere where something dramatic might happen.</p>
<div id="attachment_1484" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 507px"><a href="http://zoetropic.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/october18-023_2.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1484" title="Plaza de La Revolución" src="http://zoetropic.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/october18-023_2.jpg?w=497&#038;h=329" alt="" width="497" height="329" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">A Plaza in Caracas, Venezuela</p></div>
<p>I went to Venezuela in the months leading up to the presidential elections &#8211; what would become a second win for Hugo Chavez.  I think a lot of foreigners went to Venezuela at that time with a kind of “if shit is going to go down, I want to be there” attitude, expecting some kind of fireworks or intrigue during the elections.   I think I felt a little of that myself.</p>
<p><a href="http://zoetropic.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_2450.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1486" title="IMG_2450" src="http://zoetropic.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_2450.jpg?w=480&#038;h=640" alt="" width="480" height="640" /></a></p>
<p>It turns out they were pretty normal, above the board elections.  Chavez won fair and square, his popularity at that time still very, very high.</p>
<p>At this point the opposition marches were still mostly composed of the upper-middle class, strolling through the streets of Caracas wearing their sunglasses and polo shirts, and delicately waving their flags.</p>
<p><a href="http://zoetropic.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_2369.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1488" title="IMG_2369" src="http://zoetropic.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_2369.jpg?w=497&#038;h=372" alt="" width="497" height="372" /></a></p>
<p>These seemed more marches to show disdain than anything else, and greatly contrasted with the fervor of a Chavez march &#8211; which was more like a big party &#8211; everyone eating and drinking and clapping and singing and chanting and smiling and laughing.</p>
<p><a href="http://zoetropic.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_24452.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1492" title="IMG_2445" src="http://zoetropic.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_24452.jpg?w=480&#038;h=500" alt="" width="480" height="500" /></a></p>
<p>But over the last few years there’s been a big shift as younger, more genuinely middle class people have gotten involved, particularly students.  A lot of these people never could feel part of the stodgy, old-fashioned opposition, whose only talking point seemed to be &#8220;no more Chavez,&#8221; and yet had either become disillusioned with Chavez or had never supported him in the first place.  This group became angrier, more vocal, more political, more idealistic, and more aggressive.</p>
<p>Thus the nature of the opposition marches has changed. They have became more angry and violent.  Clashes between students and the police have become the norm.</p>
<p><a href="http://zoetropic.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_2949_21.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1494" title="IMG_2949_2" src="http://zoetropic.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_2949_21.jpg?w=497&#038;h=305" alt="" width="497" height="305" /></a></p>
<p>On protest days, during my last year in Venezuela, you could hear the sound of rubber bullets and smell the tear gas from my window.</p>
<span style="text-align:center; display: block;"><a href="http://zoetropic.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/protest-egypt-france-venezuela/"><img src="http://img.youtube.com/vi/hSSAdGQSljg/2.jpg" alt="" /></a></span>
<p>I left Venezuela two years ago – but even then I felt a mounting energy, like we were all sitting on a powder keg, and like every day a bit of gunpowder was added to it.  All that potential energy might remain dormant, or it might someday, given a spark of some kind, explode.</p>
<p>But the energy I felt there wasn&#8217;t the mounting energy of revolution like in Egypt in which a government is cast aside by surging will of the majority of the people.  It was a much more muddled chaotic energy.  The risk I felt there was not so much that the people would rise up against the government but that &#8211; given the right series of events that might give a light to the fuse &#8211; the people would rise up in violence against each other.</p>
<p>There is a deep divide in Venezuela between those that support the government and those that do not (currently estimated to be roughly 50/50) that is more and more entrenched every day.  While the opposition is certainly gaining in power and influence, President Chavez has a very large, loyal, and passionate base.</p>
<span style="text-align:center; display: block;"><a href="http://zoetropic.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/protest-egypt-france-venezuela/"><img src="http://img.youtube.com/vi/yIX_B2Oqx-o/2.jpg" alt="" /></a></span>
<p>Increasing hatred is felt by each side for the other; the differences between these two groups have become much more important to them in general than the many cultural values that they share.</p>
<p>Meanwhile many Venezuelans are armed now with both legal and illegal weapons.  Violence is already deeply problematic, Caracas having one of the highest homicide rates of any city in the world.</p>
<p>And life is difficult, stressful and frustrating for many people throughout the country.</p>
<p>What might happen if that hatred and frustration is ignited?  If things were to get truly out of control, the fear I feel in the case of Venezuela, is that it might not be Egypt so much as Libya or Sudan &#8211; not a case of revolution so much as a potential civil war.  But I hope the feeling I had there was wrong.  And I hope we never have the opportunity to find out.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1469/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1469/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1469/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1469/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1469/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1469/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1469/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1469/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1469/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1469/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1469/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1469/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1469/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1469/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=1469&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://zoetropic.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/protest-egypt-france-venezuela/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/568153117dd35a2012e060028e6b5c84?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">zoetropic</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://zoetropic.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/paris-98-world-cup-win.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Champs-elysees World Cup Win</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://zoetropic.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/october18-023_2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Plaza de La Revolución</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://zoetropic.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_2450.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_2450</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://zoetropic.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_2369.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_2369</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://zoetropic.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_24452.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_2445</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://zoetropic.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_2949_21.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_2949_2</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Human Spirit</title>
		<link>http://mmauchline.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/the-human-spirit/</link>
		<comments>http://mmauchline.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/the-human-spirit/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 19:43:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>M Mauchline</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christchurch earthquake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christchurch moment of silence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kiwi resilience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New Zealand character]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the human spirit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unrest in North Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unrest in the Middle East]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mmauchline.wordpress.com/?p=500</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Today, the balancing act that is life, highlighted by poignant examples of the strength, and resilience of the human spirit, is happening on opposite ends of our earth. The people of North Africa and the Middle East continue to mass, and protest for basic democratic reforms that I take for granted. Beginning with the action [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=500&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_501" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 650px"><a href="http://mmauchline.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/tomatoes-crawford-market-bombay-india.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-501 " title="Tomatoes Crawford Market Bombay India" src="http://mmauchline.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/tomatoes-crawford-market-bombay-india.jpg?w=640&#038;h=966" alt="" width="640" height="966" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Tomato vendor in the old Crawford Market, Mumbai, India.</p></div>
<p>Today, the balancing act that is life, highlighted by poignant examples of the strength, and resilience of the human spirit, is happening on opposite ends of our earth.</p>
<p>The people of North Africa and the Middle East continue to mass, and protest for basic democratic reforms that I take for granted. Beginning with the action of Tunisian fruit vendor Mohamed Bouazizi setting himself alight in early January, the domino effect of popular protest movements has taken down entrenched regimes in both Tunisia and Egypt, and currently has another multi-decade old despot in Libya hanging from the precipice. All of North Africa from Morocco to Sudan have felt the tremors, and governments from Lebanon, Syria and Jordan, all the way to Gulf states like Bahrain, Yemen and Oman are having to deal with the aftershocks fomented by their own people. Today, hundreds of thousands of protesters are reported to be in the streets of Yemen alone.</p>
<p>These people are fighting against worsening economic conditions, corruption and political repression. A half world away, the people of Christchurch New Zealand, beneficiaries of a democratic system designed to protect its people from all of the above, observed two minutes of silence for those killed in a devastating earthquake at 12:51 p.m. local time, exactly one week ago. Jack hammers and rescue efforts ceased for the first time in seven days, traffic came to a halt, residents emptied into the streets, joined together while pondering the ground and the sky, as church bells rang, and for all intensive purposes Christchurch came to a standstill.</p>
<p>The little island nation of New Zealand has always impressed me. &#8220;Aotearoa&#8221;, the land of the long white cloud, as it is referred to by the Maori indigenous people, has always managed to punch above its weight class with regards to managing its affairs in a progressive and democratic manner. New Zealand isn&#8217;t perfect. But, this isolated island nation with a population less than the Greater Toronto Area, has always managed to keep its domestic house in order, whether it be social programs, indigenous people&#8217;s issues, or the environment. New Zealanders&#8217; energy and joie de vivre was not only epitomized in their physical pursuits, because, after all, this was the home Sir Edmund Hillary, incredible multi-day hikes, ocean paddles, and the out-of-body experience of bungy jumping. But, it is the nation of taking things one step further, of seeing how many physical activities they can string together to quench a constantly increasing thirst for challenge. New Zealand is the birthplace of epic multi-sport adventures  races such as the Southern Traverse, and the Speight&#8217;s Coast to Coast.</p>
<p>On February 22, 2011, the physical embodiment of  their democracy came crashing down around the 350,000 residents of Christchurch,  leaving hundreds dead and leveling, or severely damaging many of the city centre&#8217;s most recognizable buildings, including the iconic Christchurch Cathedral. According to engineers, roughly one-third of all the buildings in central Christchurch will need to be demolished.</p>
<p>I think about my Kiwi friends, former work colleagues, as well as individuals I&#8217;ve met in far-flung corners of the world. I think of the Blenheim-based, rudy-hued river guide Peter Bruce, a.k.a. Wild Wally, the young Christchurch couple whom I shared a game of Yahtzee with in the spartan Mountain Refuge Hotel in Sust, Northern Pakistan, and the wandering, hotel-working couple Andrea and I met in a wind-swept campground while bicycle touring on the outskirts of Spain&#8217;s Cabo de Gata &#8211; Nijar Natural Park.</p>
<p>Christchurch will rebuild. I am sure of that. I am also confident that the fight for basic human rights in all parts of the world will succeed. It may not all happen in my lifetime. But, it will succeed because, despite all our failings, our greatest resource and attribute is the thing that authoritarian regimes and natural disasters cannot take away, the strength and resilience of our human spirit.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/500/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/500/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/500/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/500/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/500/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/500/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/500/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/500/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/500/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/500/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/500/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/500/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/500/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/500/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=500&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://mmauchline.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/the-human-spirit/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/a7d58ef93e4c9f860fc2ad5ed435e45e?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mmauchline</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mmauchline.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/tomatoes-crawford-market-bombay-india.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Tomatoes Crawford Market Bombay India</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>“I’m Too Sexy” #27</title>
		<link>http://myparentsarecrazierthanyours.com/2011/03/01/%e2%80%9ci%e2%80%99m-too-sexy%e2%80%9d-27/</link>
		<comments>http://myparentsarecrazierthanyours.com/2011/03/01/%e2%80%9ci%e2%80%99m-too-sexy%e2%80%9d-27/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 15:35:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>My Parents Are Crazier Than Yours</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Confidence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Depression]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Inspiration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[My Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Positivity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Postaday2011]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Self-Help]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sexy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Single Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Unemployment]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://myparentsarecrazierthanyours.com/?p=145</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[You wouldn’t think that being 40, unemployed, and forced to live with your nut-job parents would provide any opportunity to feel your innate sexiness… But let me tell you, I am learning a thing or two about how life works and the miraculous surprises around every corner if you are just willing to put down [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=145&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://myparentsarecrazierthanyours.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_0250.gif"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-146" title="IMG_0250" src="http://myparentsarecrazierthanyours.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_0250.gif?w=200&#038;h=300" alt="" width="200" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>You wouldn’t think that being 40, unemployed, and forced to live with your nut-job parents would provide any opportunity to feel your innate sexiness… But let me tell you, I am learning a thing or two about how life works and the miraculous surprises around every corner if you are just willing to put down your negativity and doubt for one second.</p>
<p>Maybe you already know that your experience of life is almost wholly determined by your attitude and the filter through which you see things.  I can say that life is just plain shitty sometimes.  But, when you open a smidgeon to the possibility of life and its adventures – IF you are willing to get out of bed and say <em>Bring it on, </em>then my friends, good times will roll.</p>
<p>The weather was gray and damp yesterday.  I was almost paralyzed by my thoughts of being condemned to a lifetime with silverware stealing, coupon scamming, incessantly arguing parents who would <em>never</em> get me.  I lay there, wrapped up in my brother’s old Thundercats comforter.  You could say I was curled up with my lifelong companion, the melancholy that doesn’t go away despite how nicely you ask.  I had no desire to do anything.  Life or any effort to live it seemed futile.  So, when Rob called me to see if I wanted to go to the old Printer’s Devil Bar downtown with him and his cousin, I surprised myself by saying, “What time should I be ready?”</p>
<p>No expectations for anything good, bad or otherwise, I took a shower (I know, can you believe it?) and got myself out there.  Two apple martinis in, and my mojo kicks in.  I’ve got so much of it, it’s coming out my ears.  I start talking to two guys <em>much younger </em>than me in those button-down shirts New Jersey and Long Island boys are notorious for wearing.  I treat them like I’m way too valuable for them.  So, of course they want to buy me a drink.  In one coup d’etat moment after another, I’m getting free drinks, attention, questions about myself, you name it.  I interrupt them to say, “Boys, forgive me.  There’s only one of me to go around.”  And I move on. </p>
<p>As I pass the guitar-wielding singer at the mic in between songs, I lean in and say, “Sing some Jane’s Addiction, will ya?” </p>
<p>At one point, I catch my reflection in the bar’s mirror and I like what I see.  When’s the last time <em>that</em> happened?</p>
<p>I’m talking to another group of single guys. One of them says to me, “Those are some great heels.”  I say, “Tell me something I don’t know.” I notice a few girls on the other side of the bar looking at me.  Don’t hate, AP-PRE-CI-ATE, ladies. </p>
<p>The singer is crooning “Jane Says,” when he suddenly stops mid-verse, and the only thing you hear in the bar is me singing. Everyone cheers.  I feel like I’m in a Stella Artois commercial where a nobody character rises to stardom in a nowhere bar.  It may not be &#8221;healthy&#8221; to say drinking is a good thing, but babies, apple martinis are good to me.</p>
<p>On the way home, Rob and his cousin talked in the front seat.  I sat in the back, my face pressed against the drizzly window.  <em>To think I almost didn’t go out.</em>  Those boys would have never had the opportunity to meet me.  But seriously, I would have missed out on the fun…and learning this great lesson.  It’s not the depression you have to fight &#8211; but letting yourself be crippled by it.</p>
<p>Everyone has a right to feel sexy.  Single or not.  Unemployed or not.  Living with maniacs, or all by your lonesome.  Lots of money in the bank or not a penny.  It’s an inside job.  And <em>this</em> is the neatly wrapped gift that life place in my lap for simply saying YES <em>despite my depression.</em> </p>
<p>Rob finally pulled up in my driveway and asked if we’d all like to do this again on Friday night.  “What time should I be ready?” I asked.  I started to walk away – but turned back quickly.  Rob rolled his window down. </p>
<p>“Next time I’m getting digits,” I said before sashaying to the house.</p>
<p>I got in the house and ran up the stairs the way I always ran up the stairs as a kid because I was afraid there was a monster at my heels.  In my room where I left my phone, I saw there was a text message from my ex.  The one who so easily broke my heart.  It said, “Hi.  How are you?”</p>
<p>I deleted it.</p>
<p>I picked up Vito’s paws, got down on my knees and slow danced with him while singing Frank Sinatra.</p>
<p><em>…Someday when I’m awfully low,</em></p>
<p><em>When the world is cold</em></p>
<p><em>I will feel a glow just thinking of you…</em></p>
<p><em>And the way you look tonight…</em></p>
<p>Would you believe me if I told you that Vito put his big head on my shoulder?  I love my dog.  He’s got mojo, too.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/145/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/145/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/145/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/145/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/145/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/145/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/145/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/145/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/145/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/145/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/145/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/145/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/145/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/145/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=145&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://myparentsarecrazierthanyours.com/2011/03/01/%e2%80%9ci%e2%80%99m-too-sexy%e2%80%9d-27/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/f2dca70add42f4778a4d899e582835e3?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mypacty</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://myparentsarecrazierthanyours.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_0250.gif?w=200" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0250</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Meaning of &#8220;Now&#8221; in South Africa</title>
		<link>http://fellowsblog.kiva.org/2011/03/01/the-meaning-of-now-in-south-africa/</link>
		<comments>http://fellowsblog.kiva.org/2011/03/01/the-meaning-of-now-in-south-africa/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 18:21:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Alexis Ditkowsky</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogsherpa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[South Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Womens Development Businesses (WDB)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[KF14 (Kiva Fellows 14th Class)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kiva]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kiva Fellows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pictures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alexis Ditkowsky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogsherpa South Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sodwana Bay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Phrases]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Words]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[howzit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[just now]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shame]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pleasure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tea]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fellowsblog.kiva.org/?p=25324</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[By Alexis Ditkowsky, KF14, South Africa

<a href="http://kivafellows.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/picture-207.png"><img src="http://kivafellows.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/picture-207.png?w=300" alt="" title="tea_biscuits_southafrica" width="300" height="200" class="size-medium wp-image-25325" /></a>

In addition to the popular phrases "howzit?" (short for "how's it going?"), "pleasure" (in place of "you're welcome"), and "ach, shame" (which can emphasize just about anything from appreciation for an adorably cute dog to disappointment over your cricket team losing to acting as a general conversation filler), you'll hear a lot of "just now" while traveling or living in South Africa.<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=25324&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>By Alexis Ditkowsky, KF14, South Africa</p>
<div id="attachment_25325" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://kivafellows.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/picture-207.png"><img src="http://kivafellows.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/picture-207.png?w=300&#038;h=200" alt="" title="tea_biscuits_southafrica" width="300" height="200" class="size-medium wp-image-25325" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Learning the meaning of &quot;just now&quot; over tea on a previous trip to South Africa</p></div>
<p>In addition to the popular phrases &#8220;howzit?&#8221; (short for &#8220;how&#8217;s it going?&#8221;), &#8220;pleasure&#8221; (in place of &#8220;you&#8217;re welcome&#8221;), and &#8220;ach, shame&#8221; (which can emphasize just about anything from appreciation for an adorably cute dog to disappointment over your cricket team losing to acting as a general conversation filler), you&#8217;ll hear a lot of &#8220;just now&#8221; while traveling or living in South Africa.</p>
<p>&#8220;Just now&#8221; takes some getting used to for us Americans. The first time I finally understood the meaning of &#8220;just now&#8221; went something like this:</p>
<p>I was making tea and asked my husband&#8217;s five year-old cousin if he&#8217;d like some. &#8220;Just now&#8221; he said. So I quickly made some tea, brought him a cup, and couldn&#8217;t figure out why he so was surprised to see me and so disinterested in his cup of tea. &#8220;I wanted it &#8216;Just now&#8217;,&#8221; he said. &#8220;Right,&#8221; I replied. &#8220;And I <em>just</em> brought it to you&#8230;.&#8221; Fortunately, his mother intervened and informed me that &#8220;just now&#8221; doesn&#8217;t mean &#8220;right now&#8221;, nor does it mean &#8220;just a moment ago&#8221;. It actually means &#8220;perhaps in a bit&#8221; or &#8220;I&#8217;m not really interested but I&#8217;m going to put you off gently&#8221; or &#8220;yeah, that&#8217;s a nice idea &#8211; let&#8217;s leave it at that&#8221;. It&#8217;s a very non-committal phrase.</p>
<p>Okay, so what about &#8220;now&#8221;? As I soon found out, &#8220;now&#8221; also has its vagaries. &#8220;Now&#8221; doesn&#8217;t necessarily mean &#8220;at this moment&#8221; (although it&#8217;s typically a little more definite than &#8220;just now&#8221;). If I had to guess based on my experience so far, &#8220;now&#8221; still puts the action at least five minutes into the future and possibly much longer depending on what else comes up in the meantime.</p>
<p>Fortunately, though, there&#8217;s a perfect phrase for my personality and that&#8217;s &#8220;now, now, now.&#8221; I can be a bit &#8220;now, now, now&#8221; when I&#8217;m at work in the States and it&#8217;s been a real effort for me to try to tone it down to the level of &#8220;now&#8221; or even &#8220;just now&#8221; when working with my colleagues in South Africa. So far, I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;m succeeding but I&#8217;m not sure I want to be either. I&#8217;m already one month into my Kiva Fellowship and there&#8217;s a lot I&#8217;d like to accomplish before I hit the road again. So if ever there was a perfect time for &#8220;now, now, now&#8221;, this might be it.</p>
<p><strong><em>Alexis Ditkowsky (KF14) works with Women&#8217;s Development Businesses in KwaZulu-Natal, South Africa. Check out WDB&#8217;s <a href="http://www.kiva.org/team/friends_of_womens_development_businesses" target="_blank">lending team</a> and stay tuned for new loans on their <a href="http://partners.kiva.org/lend?partner_id=178&amp;status=fundRaising&amp;sortBy=Most+Recent" target="_blank">lending page</a>.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em><strong>Previous posts by Alexis Ditkowsky:</strong><br />
<a href="http://fellowsblog.kiva.org/2011/02/28/update-from-the-field-videos-epic-commutes-going-beyond-microfinance/" target="_blank">Update from the Field: Videos, Epic Commutes + Going Beyond Microfinance</a><br />
<a href="http://fellowsblog.kiva.org/2011/02/21/last-week-in-the-field-christmas-trekking-adversity-good-company/" target="_blank">Last Week in the Field: “Christmas”, Trekking, Adversity + Good Company</a><br />
<a href="http://fellowsblog.kiva.org/2011/02/17/next-steps-for-kivas-partner-in-south-africa/" target="_blank">Next Steps for Kiva’s Partner in South Africa</a><br />
<a href="http://fellowsblog.kiva.org/2011/02/14/first-borrower-visit-take-350/" target="_blank">First Borrower Visit (Take 350+)</a><br />
<a href="http://fellowsblog.kiva.org/2011/02/03/a-hand-delivered-kiva-fellow/" target="_blank">A Hand-Delivered Kiva Fellow</a><br />
<a href="http://fellowsblog.kiva.org/2011/01/18/drawings-from-training-and-greetings-from-boston/" target="_blank">Drawings from Training and Greetings from Boston</a></em></strong></p>
<div id="attachment_25326" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://kivafellows.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/picture-209.png"><img src="http://kivafellows.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/picture-209.png?w=300&#038;h=199" alt="" title="Sodwana_Bay" width="300" height="199" class="size-medium wp-image-25326" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Working on the concept of &quot;just now&quot; over the weekend in Sodwana Bay</p></div>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://fellowsblog.kiva.org/category/countries/africa/'>Africa</a>, <a href='http://fellowsblog.kiva.org/category/blogsherpa/'>blogsherpa</a>, <a href='http://fellowsblog.kiva.org/category/all/kf14-kiva-fellows-14th-class/'>KF14 (Kiva Fellows 14th Class)</a>, <a href='http://fellowsblog.kiva.org/category/countries/africa/south-africa/'>South Africa</a>, <a href='http://fellowsblog.kiva.org/category/kiva-field-partners/womens-development-businesses-wdb/'>Womens Development Businesses (WDB)</a> Tagged: <a href='http://fellowsblog.kiva.org/tag/africa/'>Africa</a>, <a href='http://fellowsblog.kiva.org/tag/alexis-ditkowsky/'>Alexis Ditkowsky</a>, <a href='http://fellowsblog.kiva.org/tag/blogsherpa/'>blogsherpa</a>, <a href='http://fellowsblog.kiva.org/tag/blogsherpa-south-africa/'>blogsherpa South Africa</a>, <a href='http://fellowsblog.kiva.org/tag/culture/'>culture</a>, <a href='http://fellowsblog.kiva.org/tag/howzit/'>howzit</a>, <a href='http://fellowsblog.kiva.org/tag/just-now/'>just now</a>, <a href='http://fellowsblog.kiva.org/tag/kiva/'>Kiva</a>, <a href='http://fellowsblog.kiva.org/tag/kiva-fellows/'>Kiva Fellows</a>, <a href='http://fellowsblog.kiva.org/tag/photos/'>photos</a>, <a href='http://fellowsblog.kiva.org/tag/phrases/'>Phrases</a>, <a href='http://fellowsblog.kiva.org/tag/pictures/'>pictures</a>, <a href='http://fellowsblog.kiva.org/tag/pleasure/'>pleasure</a>, <a href='http://fellowsblog.kiva.org/tag/shame/'>shame</a>, <a href='http://fellowsblog.kiva.org/tag/sodwana-bay/'>Sodwana Bay</a>, <a href='http://fellowsblog.kiva.org/tag/south-africa/'>South Africa</a>, <a href='http://fellowsblog.kiva.org/tag/tea/'>Tea</a>, <a href='http://fellowsblog.kiva.org/tag/travel/'>Travel</a>, <a href='http://fellowsblog.kiva.org/tag/words/'>Words</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/25324/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/25324/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/25324/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/25324/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/25324/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/25324/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/25324/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/25324/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/25324/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/25324/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/25324/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/25324/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/25324/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/25324/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=25324&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://fellowsblog.kiva.org/2011/03/01/the-meaning-of-now-in-south-africa/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>12</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">aditkowsky</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://kivafellows.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/picture-207.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tea_biscuits_southafrica</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://kivafellows.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/picture-209.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Sodwana_Bay</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Playing for a better world</title>
		<link>http://francescociriaci.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/playing-for-a-better-world/</link>
		<comments>http://francescociriaci.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/playing-for-a-better-world/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 11:13:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Francesco Ciriaci</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Better Software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gamification]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mmorpg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[motivation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NGO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social-software]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://francescociriaci.wordpress.com/?p=260</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Can we imagine millions of people spending huge amount of spare time enjoying the delights of world-changing achievements? Here is an idea for a Facebook extention based on the concepts of serious gaming and gamification / gameful design, aimed to engage people worldwide.  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=260&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Foreword: a few things worth a lot of attention</h2>
<p>This post is about an <strong>idea</strong> that came some time ago and that I&#8217;d like to share; before  getting to the point there are a few concepts I&#8217;d like to introduce. I&#8217;m writing this post mostly for myself and my friends, but I hope if it can inspire people to dig into the concepts I bring here, if they are new to them, and enjoy the very early stage of a crazy idea (yes, yes, another one).</p>
<h3>Videogames matter! (confession of a videogames addict)</h3>
<p><a href="http://francescociriaci.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/ulunntha-runetotem-trone.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-305" title="ulunntha-runetotem-trone" src="http://francescociriaci.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/ulunntha-runetotem-trone.jpg?w=300&#038;h=168" alt="one of my pg in wow" width="300" height="168" /></a>I&#8217;ve grown up with video-games since they exists. I&#8217;ve been playing a lot,  too much. Beside the fun, I&#8217;ve always tried to study them, evaluate, analyse and enjoyed a lot of discussions about them with a couple of friends, passionate as I am. World of Warcraft has been my second life for several years now, an unbelivable source for learning and the ultimate time-sink.  Videogames are, at the same time, bliss and a curse.</p>
<p>No matter if you are a videogame addic, if you never understood them or if  you and never played or hate them: videogames is not something that can be ignored. (I suggest reading the book <a title="Fun Inc. book" href="http://tomchatfield.net/my-book-fun-inc/">Fun Inc.: Why games are the 21st Century&#8217;s most serious business</a> by Tom Chatfield, for an introduction to the role of videogames in our present and future).</p>
<h3>More than fun</h3>
<p>Then something I would have never imagined started to make his way into these discussions with friends and colleagues: gaming can be used with different purposes than &#8220;fun&#8221;! About two years ago we started imagining several possibilities to engage people in real world  using &#8220;games&#8221; and game techniques. The original idea came from looking at the emerging social gaming, especially on Facebook, and analysing some of the best in leveraging the network of friends, creating a new wave of time-sinks and ultimately a lot of fun and some little good.</p>
<p>Since then we discovered <a title="Games for Change" href="http://www.gamesforchange.org/">Games for Change</a>: a multitute of innovative and often very experimental games aimed to change the world for the better: in education, training, democracy, politics, climate change, etc. etc. We have been inspired by <a title="Jane McGonigal" href="http://janemcgonigal.com/">Jane&#8217;s talks and articles</a>, and we&#8217;ve been studing and working to be able to bring this passion into our professional future.</p>
<p><em><strong>Good changes can be brough to the world leveraging the little gamer that is inside each one of us&#8230; with a Purpose.</strong></em></p>
<h3>Gaming as an interface</h3>
<p>The last important concept I need to introduce is that games can teach us a lot on how to design powerful engaging applications and tools. Learning from psycology, motivational design or BJ Foggs work on behavioural changes, the message seems always to be that what some game developers is very relevant and meaningful for application design.</p>
<p>The phenomenon is hyped as gamification: &#8220;<em>Gamification is the use of game play mechanics for non-game applications, particularly consumer-oriented web and mobile sites, in order to encourage people to adopt the applications. It also strives to encourage users to engage in desired behaviors in connection with the applications&#8221; </em>from <a title="Gamification definition - Wikipedia" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gamification">Wikipedia</a>.</p>
<p>In other words Gamification is the concept that basic elements that make games fun and engaging can be applied to things that typically aren&#8217;t considered a game, to bring real-life changes and behaviours (see also <a title="Gamification Encyclopedia" href="http://gamification.org/wiki/Encyclopedia">The Gamification Encyclopedia</a>): nice examples are <a title="Foursquare" href="http://foursquare.com/">Foursquare</a>, Wii Fit, <a title="Jinx" href="http://www.jinx.com/">Jinx</a> and &#8230;</p>
<p>But, as some of my friends, working in psycology put it: gamification focuses on using <strong><em>gaming as an interface. </em></strong>The approach is definitively much more than only badges, points and achivements. All literature on the topic dates 2010 or 2011, the very term &#8220;gamification&#8221; is too recent (and ugly) to describe the concept and the approach new and not mature at all; there is too much hype about it and a lot of promeses about it that will not be fullfilled.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m not sure what will be the true role and evolutions of the concept but I&#8217;m firmly convinced that yes, &#8220;gaming&#8221; can be used as a paradigm to design new powerful applications. In paricular observing the latest developments in MMORPGs, gaming platforms, and &#8220;social gaming&#8221; (Zynga, etc.) there is a LOT to learn.</p>
<p>This very week at the Game Developers Conference in San Francisco gamification enthusiasts and traditional videogame designers are meeting and joyfully fighting (<a title="GDC Gamification Debate!" href="http://schedule.gdconf.com/session/12301">The Great Gamification Debate!</a>).</p>
<h2>&#8220;Better World&#8221; project</h2>
<p>So here is the idea, crazy and worth pursuing: build an environment to match resources (time, ideas, money, skills, etc) needed by NGOs and resources availables in the world (from all people) in a huge games-like experience aimed to changing the world.</p>
<p>The idea came while working on Miomood (a startup on mood tracking&amp;sharing): to build an application, a Facebook application or Facebook &#8220;extention&#8221; that would help engage users in quests, missions, &#8220;call to arms&#8221; and battles&#8230; in the real world. The application would make it easy for NGOs to develop it&#8217;s social mission (whatever it is) using the Social Network.</p>
<p>The pain it addresses: activism, social engagement, volunteering, lobbying, etc. are quite painful, hard and complex activities for most of the people: the result is that there are millions of &#8220;sleeping activists&#8221;, marginally-engaged people, lost volunteers-to-be. Becase these issues are complex, the contest is complex, true engagement expensive and time consuming.<br />
The good news is that social engagement seems to be very important in the &#8220;personal network&#8221; of a person, as it relates to &#8220;shared values&#8221;, moreover, a lot is about &#8220;education&#8221; and &#8220;information&#8221; and gaming is excellent at both training and forming.</p>
<div id="attachment_320" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 310px"><a title="Io Senza Frontiere" href="http://www.iosenzafrontiere.it/"><img class="size-medium wp-image-320" title="Iosenzafrontiere-home" src="http://francescociriaci.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/iosenzafrontiere-home.png?w=300&#038;h=219" alt="io senza frontiere scheenshot" width="300" height="219" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Game-like Facebook application by MSF Italia</p></div>
<p>The opportunity it delivers: move huge amounts of spare-time, game-time (&amp; cognitive surplus) into changing the world for real.<br />
NGOs  would &#8220;create&#8221; the content in a guided, simple, clear format: the same way they manage a Facebook page they would be able to add a &#8220;Quest&#8221; or a &#8220;Mission&#8221; or an &#8220;Action&#8221;. Title, difficulty, location, requirements, goals&#8230; storyline. NGOs would need to well design their contents, their messages and stories, but will not have to develop any mechanic, user interface or web platform.</p>
<p>A <em>world-changer</em>, the user, the player would join the &#8220;call&#8221;. The identity of the &#8220;world-changer&#8221; would be his/her real identity, enriched and customized with special skills and abilities, experience, place visited, language spoken, etc. The world-changer answering the call would need the help of his/her friends very often to complete the Quest, the Mission or the action. She/he would along the way socialize with others, maybe even people of distant countries. Along the way discover new and more complex ways of interacting. And be rewarded.</p>
<p>Here is an overview of the main motivational drivers that should be considered the design:</p>
<p><strong>1) Achievement</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Advancement (points, badges, medals, titles, stats, experience, talents, &#8230;) example: &#8220;green points&#8221;</li>
<li>Mechanics (how to spend points, talents, get rewards, &#8230;)</li>
<li>Competition (there can be good competition too, even in social engagement) example: &#8220;world-travelling ladders&#8221;</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>2) Social</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Socializing (within the personal network and beyond) example: exchanging messages with the volunteers in Haiti.</li>
<li>Relationship (everywhere is the design!)</li>
<li>Teamwork (everywhere is the design!)</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>3) Immertion</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Discovery (new people, new problems, new landscapes, both local or very distant)</li>
<li>Role-Playing (world-changer would be taken into being THE BEST possible themselves, right?)</li>
<li>Customization (background, avatar, objects carried, t-shirts weared, photo uploaded, &#8230;)</li>
<li>Escapism (very different from a MMORPG, not sure how it fits, right now)</li>
</ul>
<p>I&#8217;m sure someone have more than enough imagination to &#8220;see&#8221; how such a project could look like.</p>
<p>It is worth noting that Facebook is already evolving to support some of these needs, expanding our &#8220;online self&#8221;. Moreover such platform is not only about game mechanics, badges or points, but an evolving system to allow the design of rewarding and joyful experiences when acting in changing the world!</p>
<p>Key design challenges: simplicity, cleanness, avoid transforming serious things in a game (but &#8220;play&#8221; for real changes!), avoid retoric, avoid frustration when approaching real-world problems as complex as hunger, poverty, etc. and reach the MAXIMUM number of people (get the &#8220;marginal&#8221; engagement of millions).<br />
A lesson we have all to learn again from WOW: it has brought to a MMORPG millions of people that where not even gamers before! Now popular games such Zynga products and loads of online and social games are expanding this territory. <em><strong>I feel it is the right time to expand into more massive &#8220;serious&#8221; gaming.</strong></em></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/260/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/260/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/260/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/260/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/260/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/260/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/260/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/260/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/260/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/260/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/260/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/260/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/260/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/260/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=260&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://francescociriaci.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/playing-for-a-better-world/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>32</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/aea71c9f7d1c19e66a1c0ea00cd00956?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">francescociriaci</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://francescociriaci.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/ulunntha-runetotem-trone.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ulunntha-runetotem-trone</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://francescociriaci.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/iosenzafrontiere-home.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Iosenzafrontiere-home</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>I wouldn&#8217;t have it any other way BUT..</title>
		<link>http://mostlyyummymummy.com/2011/03/01/i-wouldnt-have-it-any-other-way-but/</link>
		<comments>http://mostlyyummymummy.com/2011/03/01/i-wouldnt-have-it-any-other-way-but/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 12:38:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>(mostly) yummy mummy</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[baby]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[babysitting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[child]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[childcare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daddy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[home]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[housework]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mostly yummy mummy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mummy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SAHM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stay at home mummy]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mostlyyummymummy.com/?p=1719</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I really don&#8217;t want this to misconstrued as a moaning post, so I should start up by saying that I love my big family to bits and really wouldn&#8217;t have it any other way.. But.. And there had to be a but.. Sometimes, it really is hard work! Don&#8217;t get me wrong, I never expected it [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=1719&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I really don&#8217;t want this to misconstrued as a moaning post, so I should start up by saying that I love my big family to bits and <em>really</em> wouldn&#8217;t have it any other way..</p>
<p>But..</p>
<p>And there had to be a but..</p>
<p>Sometimes, it really is hard work!</p>
<p>Don&#8217;t get me wrong, I never expected it to be anything but and I truly wouldn&#8217;t have it any other way. When you have a brood of four, so many people say &#8220;Oh, I don&#8217;t know how you manage with that many children blah blah blah..&#8221; And for the most part, you just brush it off and play it down. But then on the not so good days, and I don&#8217;t believe anyone doesn&#8217;t have <em>those</em> days, I sit down and think &#8220;No, I don&#8217;t know how I manage either..&#8221;</p>
<p><img class="alignright" src="http://t0.gstatic.com/images?q=tbn:ANd9GcRRHLsx7v6xpIw9CxoQTmyTbIJpvDg0GqPcvuVWEy6VfZwFMPRn1A" alt="" width="198" height="201" />Some days, it truly feels like I scrape through by the skin of my teeth rather than actually manage. But I&#8217;m sure many could say the same whether they have one child or a dozen, right?</p>
<p>I love school holidays. Not just because of the lazier mornings (let&#8217;s face it, having four children means that it can never be truly lazy but not having the rush of the school run certainly makes it easier.) But I love having them all at home. I love spending time together. Although when you are trying to entertain children with such huge age differences, there are always going to be fall-outs. There is nothing like the clash of toddler temper tantrums with the pre-teen hormonal screaming matches. It sounds like a madhouse, and sometimes, it really is just that! I sometimes think that half term comes along to keep those broody feelings at bay because four children really <em>is</em> enough! Not that I am completely convinced of that. But I guess that is another rambling post for another day..</p>
<p>I don&#8217;t get any help as such when it comes to babysitting etc, my family aren&#8217;t too forthcoming on that front I&#8217;m afraid. So for the most part, it is just the six of us. With me being the stay at home parent of course the main brunt of the childcare naturally falls on me and for the most part, I am so run off my feet that I don&#8217;t have time to give it a second thought as to just how hard it can be. But there are times when it all just feels pretty relentless. My youngest two still don&#8217;t always sleep through the night which is physically exhausting! I can count the number of full nights sleep I&#8217;ve had in the last five years on one hand, I swear! For the most part, you just get on with it of course, but on other days, those not so good days, I could just crawl up and sleep for a week in the constantly overflowing laundry basket.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s my next point. The housework. I am far from being a perfect housewife, trust me! But trying to keep the house tidy when you are surrounded by little people who are intent on turning it upside down is just never-ending! I seem to spend my days taking everything upstairs that should be downstairs, and downstairs what should be upstairs. Between the four of them (and sometimes Daddy can be just as bad..) they literally turn the house upside down on a daily basis. And I put it back together again. Of course, only the things that you <em>haven&#8217;t</em> done get noticed, not the other hundred things that you <em>have</em> done. And I am the only person who ever knows where anything is. Or can stack the dishwasher properly. Or feed the cat. Or can put laundry in the basket not in a pile at the side of the basket. Or replenish empty toilet rolls. You get the picture.</p>
<p>But do you know what? I am thankful that I have more good days than not so good. The good days help you to get through the not so good days. I really do mean it when I say that.</p>
<p>I wouldn&#8217;t change a thing.</p>
<p>Sometimes I can&#8217;t believe just how lucky I am to have my lovely brood.*</p>
<p>*Cue cheesy music. Sick bags are available upon request.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1719/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1719/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1719/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1719/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1719/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1719/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1719/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1719/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1719/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1719/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1719/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1719/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1719/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1719/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=1719&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://mostlyyummymummy.com/2011/03/01/i-wouldnt-have-it-any-other-way-but/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>46</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/48d4c20b70eba7157fe48fb9a6766b72?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">YummyNo1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://t0.gstatic.com/images?q=tbn:ANd9GcRRHLsx7v6xpIw9CxoQTmyTbIJpvDg0GqPcvuVWEy6VfZwFMPRn1A" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Moroccan meatballs for a chilly winter&#8217;s day</title>
		<link>http://cupcakejunky.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/moroccan-meatballs-for-a-chilly-winters-day/</link>
		<comments>http://cupcakejunky.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/moroccan-meatballs-for-a-chilly-winters-day/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 11:07:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>cupcakejunky</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bohemia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Comfort Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Leon Restaurants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Meatballs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Moroccan Meatballs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spitalfields]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spitalfields Market]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cupcakejunky.wordpress.com/?p=408</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve discovered a healthy fast food restaurant, Leon, which was under my nose the whole time. I&#8217;m now addicted to their meatball lunchbox with consists of meatballs, a tomato sauce, brown rice, a few seeds and some aioli. It&#8217;s pure comfort food. When I can, I go to Leon in Spitalfields Market, London. Further down [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=408&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://cupcakejunky.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/moroccan-meatballs-for-a-chilly-winters-day/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>33</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/8d5a114c96a6370ee9128f43c899e016?s=96&#38;d=monsterid&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cupcakejunky</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cupcakejunky.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/leon3.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Leon3</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cupcakejunky.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/leon.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Leon</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cupcakejunky.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/leon2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Leon2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cupcakejunky.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/leon4.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Leon4</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cupcakejunky.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/moroccan-meatballs.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Moroccan meatballs</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cupcakejunky.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/moroccan-meatball-tagine1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Moroccan meatball</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cupcakejunky.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/spitalfields-rabbits.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Spitalfields Rabbits</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cupcakejunky.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/spitalfields-goat.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Spitalfields Goat</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Well, I Told You He Bites</title>
		<link>http://play101.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/well-i-told-you-he-bites/</link>
		<comments>http://play101.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/well-i-told-you-he-bites/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 12:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>happykidshappymom</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Parenting and Play]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bite]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[carnivore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dinosaur]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[postaday2011]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://play101.wordpress.com/?p=590</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As I watch the baby dimples fade from the back of my son&#8217;s hand, I see him growing up in other ways too. Playing with dinosaurs used to mean grouping like ones together, and having them stomp around. Now, he can name anything from a Brachiosaurus to a Cretoxyrhina. And more, he knows which ones [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=590&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://play101.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/well-i-told-you-he-bites/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>29</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/5b1f2b30e81b5e9640314bbfdbf25837?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">happykidshappymom</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://play101.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/img_0647-medium-web-view-copy.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0647 Medium Web view - Copy</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Feeding wild monkeys in Uganda.</title>
		<link>http://tonyalatorre.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/feeding-wild-monkeys-in-uganda/</link>
		<comments>http://tonyalatorre.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/feeding-wild-monkeys-in-uganda/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 12:28:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tonyalatorre</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[adoption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gardening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flowers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[monkeys]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[orphans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uganda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wild animals]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tonyalatorre.wordpress.com/?p=5388</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Yesterday was fresh with Spring. Redbud trees are a stunning purple, and the pears are pearly white. The grass is coming back and my roses are covered with fresh red leaves. Under a cloudless blue sky with a fresh wind wrapping around us and lifting skirts I closed my eyes, took a deep breath and believed I was [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=5388&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday was fresh with Spring. Redbud trees are a stunning purple, and the pears are pearly white. The grass is coming back and my roses are covered with fresh red leaves. Under a cloudless blue sky with a fresh wind wrapping around us and lifting skirts <strong><em>I closed my eyes, took a deep breath and believed I was back in Uganda.</em></strong> We enjoyed endless days exactly like this, so many we became bothered from squinting at the perfect sky. This is the weather that enters the muscles and makes them move. It wasn’t just me. I saw more joggers than ever in the neighborhood, young teens grouped around the lake and even Lucy darted with her toys in the back yard. Jack spontaneously needed to jump rope and jog around the lake. He thinks this will make his muscles look like his brothers. Everyone has muscles now except for him. He feels left out. And being the boy he is, he just went right to work doing something about it. He tells me, &#8220;I think I am starting puberty now.&#8221; I have to remind him not until he passes twelve. I had no idea he would then do as many pushups as he could to fix what he saw as a problem and hasten the onset.<a rel="attachment wp-att-5389" href="http://tonyalatorre.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/feeding-wild-monkeys-in-uganda/dsc_6973/"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5389" title="botanical gardens in uganda" src="http://tonyalatorre.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_6973.jpg?w=500&#038;h=332" alt="" width="500" height="332" /></a></p>
<p>We enjoyed a day just like this one in Uganda on a Saturday. We drove to the botanical gardens in Entebbe to take a break from the city smog, noisy bodas and busy bodies<strong><em>. I was curious to know how a botanical garden would look in Uganda.</em></strong> As an avid gardener who has grown plants in every planting zone I loved identifying and recognizing plants I have grown.  I was thrilled though to see specimens I have never seen before. New discoveries hint that there’s always more to learn, and that revs my engines.</p>
<p><a rel="attachment wp-att-5402" href="http://tonyalatorre.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/feeding-wild-monkeys-in-uganda/dsc_7175/"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5402" title="clusters of flowers" src="http://tonyalatorre.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_7175.jpg?w=500&#038;h=752" alt="" width="500" height="752" /></a></p>
<div id="attachment_5390" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a rel="attachment wp-att-5390" href="http://tonyalatorre.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/feeding-wild-monkeys-in-uganda/dsc_6964/"><img class="size-full wp-image-5390" title="mom in gardens" src="http://tonyalatorre.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_6964.jpg?w=500&#038;h=332" alt="" width="500" height="332" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">My mom walking in the gardens.</p></div>
<p>I thought we would park and spend the day walking in the fresh air. I needed to walk in the fresh air that day. But <strong><em>these gardens were strung with a winding road, dappled with enormous flowering trees, and wide open landscapes of natural beauty,</em></strong> not master planned garden beds. So we drove. But not to be deterred we took it like a safari for plants, opened the top and stuck out our white heads. There were Ugandans who appeared to live nearby as they were hauling wares on their heads, children were playing, and women were doing laundry. We stopped for a man with a wide basket on his head selling packaged nuts. We were hungry and there he was the mobile convenience store.<a rel="attachment wp-att-5391" href="http://tonyalatorre.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/feeding-wild-monkeys-in-uganda/dsc_6971/"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5391" title="peanut seller" src="http://tonyalatorre.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_6971.jpg?w=500&#038;h=752" alt="" width="500" height="752" /></a></p>
<p>We knew there was a group of monkeys who lived in the park, so we came prepared to feed them. The day before, we walked to the market and bought  mini bananas and a loaf of bread so we could have the pleasure of wasting good food on wild beasts. I was embarrassed to tell Julie, the house manager and my friend, that the abundance of bananas were for feeding monkeys. That’s wasteful, and she’s the supreme “waste not want not” of my friends there. But we are American and we indulge our fantasies.<a rel="attachment wp-att-5392" href="http://tonyalatorre.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/feeding-wild-monkeys-in-uganda/dsc_6981/"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5392" title="monkey" src="http://tonyalatorre.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_6981.jpg?w=500&#038;h=752" alt="" width="500" height="752" /></a></p>
<p><strong><em>Eventually our driver approached the grove of trees where the monkeys stalk people for food.</em></strong> In a bossy tone Edde told us to get down, and close the windows. It was urgent and so we hustled. I soon saw why as monkeys were climbing all over our van within minutes of his orders. He stopped in the road and we all got out. Monkeys began to come out of the trees in family groups, clustered at the edge of the road making decisions about the newcomers, us. There had to be at least fifty of them. <strong><em>They were aggressive little creatures coming right up to us for the banana and if we were not quick enough in the offering they snatched it out of our hands.</em></strong>The mother in me was concerned. This was wild behavior, and my babies could be in danger. But we were having so much fun, I tried not to measure the risk, but it never left my mind especially when Edde told me they carry rabies. Great. I made the kids hustle away when some of the adolescent monkeys were fighting over our bananas. I photographed the whole time as Edde demonstrated for us how to get the monkeys to perform with leaps for their bananas. The boys and Emily took turns holding the banana over their head so the little beasts could demonstrate for us how high they could jump. <strong><em>We laughed so hard with the exhilarating fun of a wild encounter.</em></strong>When we were almost out of bananas the kids urged me to try. I was afraid. But I also wanted to know what it felt like to be approached by a monkey. Really, I wished they were nice so I could hold one on my hip like a baby, but there was no way I would let these beasts get that close to me. I found a mama with a baby clinging to her middle and I fed her. The other monkeys wanted what she was getting and their irritation made me nervous. But the thrill of having her jump for my banana and take it out of my hand was quite satisfying. I had never fed a wild monkey before!</p>
<div id="attachment_5395" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a rel="attachment wp-att-5395" href="http://tonyalatorre.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/feeding-wild-monkeys-in-uganda/dsc_7088/"><img class="size-full wp-image-5395" title="tonya feeding monkey" src="http://tonyalatorre.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_7088.jpg?w=500&#038;h=752" alt="" width="500" height="752" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Great shot Emily!</p></div>
<p>We should have been smarter when we were out of food and just scramble into the van and drive away. But I was distracted because there were a pitiful looking group of children dressed in tatters watching “the mzungus waste good food on the animals” so I got some blowpops and walked up the bank to where they were sitting so I could give them a treat. One of the more aggressive monkeys chased me and grabbed at my ankle with his claw as I made my way to the children. I had to act like a gorilla to get it to leave me alone. Edde came after them with a stick. I gave the treats to the kids and yelled to mine, “get in the car now!”  And we got out of there.<a rel="attachment wp-att-5397" href="http://tonyalatorre.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/feeding-wild-monkeys-in-uganda/dsc_7045/"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5397" title="the watching children" src="http://tonyalatorre.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_7045.jpg?w=500&#038;h=332" alt="" width="500" height="332" /></a></p>
<p> I thought what a stupid risk we took to have fun.  And I thanked God that no one got bit. It really was a highlight of fun, but now that I’m wiser about the situation I can’t say I would do it again. The risk was too great.<a rel="attachment wp-att-5396" href="http://tonyalatorre.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/feeding-wild-monkeys-in-uganda/dsc_7080/"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5396" title="biting beasts" src="http://tonyalatorre.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_7080.jpg?w=500&#038;h=332" alt="" width="500" height="332" /></a></p>
<p><a rel="attachment wp-att-5398" href="http://tonyalatorre.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/feeding-wild-monkeys-in-uganda/dsc_7040/"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5398" title="mama monkey" src="http://tonyalatorre.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_7040.jpg?w=500&#038;h=752" alt="" width="500" height="752" /></a></p>
<p>We drove off deeper into the gardens to where the waters of Lake Victoria lapped the shore. We got out and enjoyed a leisurely hour lying around watching people drop to their drawers and go for a swim. We couldn’t help but notice the bulging muscles on the teenagers. Our high schoolers at home would be tortured with envy. Our kids waded into the water and Kira was thrilled as Emily dipped her feet in to the cold.<a rel="attachment wp-att-5399" href="http://tonyalatorre.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/feeding-wild-monkeys-in-uganda/dsc_7127/"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5399" title="in the lake" src="http://tonyalatorre.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_7127.jpg?w=500&#038;h=332" alt="" width="500" height="332" /></a></p>
<p>The children we served lollis to appeared and hung around. They were swinging from the trees and watching us. One of them held out their hand and asked for money and said, “we are orphans”. Somehow I didn’t believe them. I said, “you don’t have parents?” They dropped their heads, and admitted they had parents. I felt like such a target. And I don’t like to be lied to or to have my heart strings strangled for an untruth. I was disappointed. Hunger and extreme poverty will cause them to say anything to get their needs met. I gave them the Pringles can we were leisurely eating from and they skipped away. I felt a little sad because there is so much need in so many people in this country. I just have to trust God to put the ones He wants me to touch in my path and know he will send more, and believe He is their provider.<strong><em> I just can’t bear to see a child suffer from hunger.<a rel="attachment wp-att-5400" href="http://tonyalatorre.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/feeding-wild-monkeys-in-uganda/dsc_7169-2/"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5400" title="park view" src="http://tonyalatorre.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_7169.jpg?w=500&#038;h=332" alt="" width="500" height="332" /></a></em></strong></p>
<p>So as  I sat under the same sky on the other side of the world from Uganda watching the teenagers on the bank of our lake in the backyard cluster in the same social way the children in Uganda did on the banks of Lake Victoria I sighed<strong><em>. I now live in two places that couldn’t be more different, and yet in many ways are just the same. Kids here have a different kind of unmet hunger, and a lollipop won’t make them smile.<a rel="attachment wp-att-5401" href="http://tonyalatorre.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/feeding-wild-monkeys-in-uganda/dsc_7176/"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5401" title="an unidentified flower" src="http://tonyalatorre.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_7176.jpg?w=500&#038;h=332" alt="" width="500" height="332" /></a></em></strong></p>
<div id="attachment_5394" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a rel="attachment wp-att-5394" href="http://tonyalatorre.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/feeding-wild-monkeys-in-uganda/dsc_7006/"><img class="size-full wp-image-5394" title="feeding time" src="http://tonyalatorre.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_7006.jpg?w=500&#038;h=332" alt="" width="500" height="332" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Notice Kevin was way out of the picture. he&#039;s more cautious than the rest of us. That makes him smarter.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_5393" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a rel="attachment wp-att-5393" href="http://tonyalatorre.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/feeding-wild-monkeys-in-uganda/dsc_6991/"><img class="size-full wp-image-5393" title="jack and monkey" src="http://tonyalatorre.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_6991.jpg?w=500&#038;h=332" alt="" width="500" height="332" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Yikes!</p></div>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5388/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5388/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5388/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5388/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5388/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5388/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5388/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5388/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5388/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5388/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5388/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5388/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5388/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5388/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=5388&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tonyalatorre.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/feeding-wild-monkeys-in-uganda/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>25</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/d5fa68d888d03d05880c90c415437f5b?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tonyalatorre</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tonyalatorre.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_6973.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">botanical gardens in uganda</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tonyalatorre.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_7175.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">clusters of flowers</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tonyalatorre.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_6964.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mom in gardens</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tonyalatorre.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_6971.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">peanut seller</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tonyalatorre.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_6981.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">monkey</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tonyalatorre.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_7088.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tonya feeding monkey</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tonyalatorre.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_7045.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">the watching children</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tonyalatorre.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_7080.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">biting beasts</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tonyalatorre.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_7040.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mama monkey</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tonyalatorre.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_7127.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">in the lake</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tonyalatorre.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_7169.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">park view</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tonyalatorre.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_7176.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">an unidentified flower</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tonyalatorre.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_7006.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">feeding time</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tonyalatorre.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_6991.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jack and monkey</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Freshly Pressed</title>
		<link>http://justhugo.com/2011/03/01/freshly-pressed/</link>
		<comments>http://justhugo.com/2011/03/01/freshly-pressed/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 03:25:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Hugo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Log]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tattoo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WordPress]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://justhugo.com/?p=58</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Today was an exciting day! I just flew back from NYC, where I&#8217;ve been hanging out for a week to meet with my team mates (Team Social FTW). After some well deserved sleep, I headed out to Queen of Hearts tattoo parlor for an appointment with my favorite tattoo artist &#8211; Pedro Mascarenhas (yeah&#8230; flash [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=58&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today was an exciting day!</p>
<p>I just flew back from NYC, where I&#8217;ve been hanging out for a week to meet with my team mates (Team Social FTW). After some well deserved sleep, I headed out to Queen of Hearts tattoo parlor for an appointment with my favorite tattoo artist &#8211; <a title="Tattoos by Pedro" href="http://www.tattoosbypedro.org/" target="_blank">Pedro Mascarenhas</a> (yeah&#8230; flash website&#8230; I know&#8230;)- to get some fresh ink in me.</p>
<p><span id="more-58"></span></p>
<p>As most of you know, I&#8217;ve been a WordPress enthusiast for quite some time (2005-ish). <a title="WordPress.org" href="http://wordpress.org" target="_blank">WordPress</a>, as a platform and community, has been a very important part of who I am today as a web designer and as a person. Therefore, getting a WordPress related tattoo makes perfect sense.</p>
<p>The decision to tattoo something WordPress related is not necessarily because of my new job at Automattic, although it kinda served as a catalyst - the icing on the cake &#8211; for me to go through with it!</p>
<p>So I got, not one, but two WordPress related tattoos! Check it out:</p>
<p><a href="http://hugobaeta.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/wpdotme.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-61" title="WordPress dot me" src="http://hugobaeta.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/wpdotme.jpg?w=640&#038;h=395" alt="" width="640" height="395" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://hugobaeta.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/codeispoetry.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-60" title="Code is Poetry" src="http://hugobaeta.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/codeispoetry.jpg?w=640&#038;h=395" alt="" width="640" height="395" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://hugobaeta.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/codeispoetry_closeup.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-59" title="Code is Poetry (close-up)" src="http://hugobaeta.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/codeispoetry_closeup.jpg?w=640&#038;h=395" alt="" width="640" height="395" /></a></p>
<p>It&#8217;s funny I&#8217;m getting these in real ink. It feels like a full-circle moment here. Once, not so long ago, <a title="Jim Doran" href="http://jimdoran.net/" target="_blank">a dear friend</a> got me to place a fake <a title="Wordpress Tattoo: Hugo Baeta (on Flickr)" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/spazticus/2769034548/" target="_blank">WordPress tattoo on my arm</a> (the other one, where I have a Mr.WannaB name tattooed already) in WordCamp SF 2008 &#8211; I bet he&#8217;s proud of me now!!! <img src='http://s1.wp.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif' alt=';)' class='wp-smiley' /> </p>
<p>I also did a small movie clip of the experience (too bad I only remembered my iPhone does that when we were finishing the second part). Loud tattoo machine noise ahead&#8230;</p>
<div id="x-video-0" class="video-player" style="width:400;height:224">
<embed id="video0" src="http://s0.videopress.com/player.swf?v=1.02&amp;guid=tBm7Q7iV" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="400" height="224" title="Freshly Pressed" wmode="transparent" seamlesstabbing="true" allowfullscreen="true" allowscriptaccess="always" overstretch="true"></embed></div>
<p>I&#8217;m really proud of these tattoos. Hope y&#8217;all like it too!</p>
<p>Peace and Love <img src='http://s1.wp.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif' alt=';)' class='wp-smiley' /> </p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/58/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/58/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/58/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/58/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/58/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/58/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/58/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/58/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/58/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/58/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/58/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/58/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/58/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/58/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=58&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" /><div><a href="http://justhugo.com/2011/03/01/freshly-pressed/"><img alt="Freshly Pressed" src="http://videos.videopress.com/tBm7Q7iV/freshlypressed_scruberthumbnail_1.jpg" width="160" height="120" /></a></div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://justhugo.com/2011/03/01/freshly-pressed/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>60</slash:comments>
	<enclosure url="http://videos.videopress.com/tBm7Q7iV/freshlypressed_dvd.mp4" length="2347008" type="video/mp4" />

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/99ab7c018336a3263f8f78bedc2d6500?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F1.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">hugobaeta</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hugobaeta.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/wpdotme.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">WordPress dot me</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hugobaeta.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/codeispoetry.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Code is Poetry</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hugobaeta.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/codeispoetry_closeup.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Code is Poetry (close-up)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:group>
			<media:content url="http://videos.videopress.com/tBm7Q7iV/freshlypressed_dvd.mp4" fileSize="2347008" type="video/mp4" medium="video" bitrate="1528" isDefault="true" duration="12" width="640" height="360" />

			<media:content url="http://videos.videopress.com/tBm7Q7iV/freshlypressed_std.mp4" fileSize="1222656" type="video/mp4" medium="video" bitrate="796" isDefault="false" duration="12" width="400" height="224" />

			<media:content url="http://videos.videopress.com/tBm7Q7iV/freshlypressed_fmt1.ogv" fileSize="1222656" type="video/ogg" medium="video" bitrate="796" isDefault="false" duration="12" width="400" height="224" />

			<media:rating scheme="urn:mpaa">pg-13</media:rating>
			<media:title type="plain">Freshly Pressed</media:title>
			<media:thumbnail url="http://videos.videopress.com/tBm7Q7iV/freshlypressed_scruberthumbnail_1.jpg" width="256" height="144" />
			<media:player url="http://s0.videopress.com/player.swf?v=1.02&#038;guid=tBm7Q7iV" width="400" height="225" />
		</media:group>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>