<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 21:02:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>My Mind Is My Battlefield</title>
		<link>http://dontforgettofeedthebaby.com/2013/03/06/my-mind-is-my-battlefield/</link>
		<comments>http://dontforgettofeedthebaby.com/2013/03/06/my-mind-is-my-battlefield/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2013 15:30:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Kathy V.</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mental Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[depression]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mental health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parenting community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[them's fighting words]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dontforgettofeedthebaby.com/?p=1887</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This is as true in everyday life as it is in battle: we are given one life and the decision is ours whether to wait for circumstances to make up our mind, or whether to act, and in acting, to live. ~ Omar N. Bradley Depression is an issue that has been getting a great [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1887&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>This is as true in everyday life as it is in battle: we are given one life and the decision is ours whether to wait for circumstances to make up our mind, or whether to act, and in acting, to live. ~ Omar N. Bradley</em></p>
<p>Depression is an issue that has been getting a great deal of press lately, particularly in the parenting community. The Parenting Magazine article <a href="http://www.parenting.com/article/xanax" target="_blank">Xanax Makes Me A Better Mom</a> shows just how pervasive and controversial this issue is: according to the article, parents are more than twice as likely as non-parents to experience depression, and the comments section illustrates just exactly how harsh and judgmental people can be about it &#8212; whether you&#8217;re taking pills or not, whether you&#8217;re in therapy or not, as soon as you use the word &#8216;depression&#8217; someone stands ready to condemn you for something.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve been depressed for my entire life. When I was 24, I first heard the word <a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmedhealth/PMH0001916/" target="_blank">dysthymia</a>: chronic, mild depression that lasts for years. It was a diagnosis which has made me view my entire dry, pessimistic personality as suspect. I&#8217;ve suffered repeated bouts of <a href="http://www.webmd.com/depression/double-depression" target="_blank">double depression</a> as well &#8212; dysthymia paired with an episode of major depression. It makes for a thick psychiatric folder and a lifelong struggle to feel even the most basic joys.</p>
<div id="attachment_1899" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://dontforgettofeedthebaby.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/depressed-woman.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1899" alt="Photo courtesy of sxc.hu" src="http://dontforgettofeedthebaby.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/depressed-woman.jpg?w=300&#038;h=208" width="300" height="208" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Photo courtesy of sxc.hu</p></div>
<p>I took medications (many, many medications) for five years. I&#8217;ve been in therapy with psychiatrists, psychologists, clinical social workers, and counselors for eleven. I&#8217;ve used all the conventional methods to treat depression, from SSRIs to Cognitive Behavioral Therapy. I know what works for me and what doesn&#8217;t.</p>
<p>Last summer, I went once more into a deep depression. Years of therapy had given me tools that helped me to deal with my dysthymia, and I had been functioning quite well without drugs for years. The scary thing about this depression, beyond the fact that my own mind was once more threatening my life and happiness, is that this time I&#8217;m a mom.</p>
<p>I have a son. I have to raise this child. I have to get up early every morning, put his needs before my own, and provide him with a safe, healthy environment. More than that, I have to teach him how to live in the world. How can I do that, if I&#8217;m mired in pain? How can I teach him to love life if I&#8217;m thinking of taking my own?</p>
<p><a href="http://dontforgettofeedthebaby.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/baby-face_edited-1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-1902" alt="Baby face_edited-1" src="http://dontforgettofeedthebaby.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/baby-face_edited-1.jpg?w=500&#038;h=363" width="500" height="363" /></a></p>
<p>My son, just by existing, has raised the stakes on my healing process. <em>I MUST GET BETTER.</em> For his sake, for my sake, for the sakes of all the people with whom I come into contact. I cannot refuse to do the things that I have to do to get better, not out of fear or shame or any other emotion that may weigh me down.</p>
<p>A recent <a href="http://www.inthepowderroom.com/read/me-time/2013-02-we-are-only-as-sick-as-our-secrets.html" target="_blank">article by The Bearded Iris</a> was titled &#8220;We Are Only As Sick As Our Secrets&#8221;. It&#8217;s a saying which is common theme in therapy. Being open about our pain, about the reasons behind our pain, alleviates that pain. It allows us to live more fully in our skins and to have more honest relationships with people. Though it may be hard and frightening, talking about our inner fears, hurts, and suppressed angers is a necessary part of healing.</p>
<p>Though it&#8217;s hard, I&#8217;ve been working to come to grips with my past &#8212; to expose my pain to fresh air and sunlight. Therapy has taught me a great deal about myself, about the things that made me the way I am, and about what I need to do to become the kind of person that I want to be.</p>
<p>When it becomes too hard, when it hurts too much and I face too much judgment and condemnation from my loved ones (who would be very happy to see me medicate the pain away, in spite of the fact that I know that drugs are only a superficial panacea for me), I think of my little son.</p>
<p>I think of him at seventy, or eighty, or ninety. I think of him telling his grandchildren about his life, and that of his parents. I think of him telling them about me.</p>
<p>If I give up, if I choose not to do the hard work of grappling with my pain, his story will be one of his own pain. It will be a story of feeling disconnected from his mother, of watching her shrivel into herself until she was completely unable to function. It may be a story of losing her altogether, and the terrible toll that had on the rest of his young life. I can&#8217;t bear to think of that.</p>
<p>If I don&#8217;t give up, if I do what needs to be done to face my demons and stand up for my own mental health, I can hope that his story will be one of pride and admiration. It will be a story of a strong, courageous woman who did not let life, stigma, condemnation, or her own mind keep her down. A woman who fought for what she loved and who raised him with the courage to do the same.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s the story I want to leave my son with. That&#8217;s the woman, the mother, that I want to be.</p>
<p>So the fight continues.</p>
<p><a href="http://dontforgettofeedthebaby.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/battle_of_barnet.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-1893" alt="Battle_of_barnet" src="http://dontforgettofeedthebaby.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/battle_of_barnet.jpg?w=243&#038;h=300" width="243" height="300" /></a></p>
<p><em>If you find yourself relating to me a little too closely, or you know someone who would, there&#8217;s lots of help available. Please don&#8217;t suffer in silence. Seek help. A basic Google search for &#8220;depression help&#8221; turns up an unbelievable <a href="http://www.google.com/#hl=en&amp;sugexp=les%3B&amp;gs_rn=5&amp;gs_ri=psy-ab&amp;cp=12&amp;gs_id=6b&amp;xhr=t&amp;q=depression+help&amp;es_nrs=true&amp;pf=p&amp;output=search&amp;sclient=psy-ab&amp;oq=depression+h&amp;gs_l=&amp;pbx=1&amp;bav=on.2,or.r_gc.r_pw.r_qf.&amp;bvm=bv.43148975,d.dmQ&amp;fp=e8eb7b2769946688&amp;biw=1920&amp;bih=1015" target="_blank">240,000,000 results</a>. You owe it to yourself, and even more importantly to your children, to get treatment.</em></p>
<p><strong><em>Let&#8217;s make sure that all our children have truly inspiring stories to tell of us.</em></strong></p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://dontforgettofeedthebaby.com/category/family/'>Family</a>, <a href='http://dontforgettofeedthebaby.com/category/mental-health-2/'>Mental Health</a>, <a href='http://dontforgettofeedthebaby.com/category/uncategorized/'>Uncategorized</a> Tagged: <a href='http://dontforgettofeedthebaby.com/tag/depression/'>depression</a>, <a href='http://dontforgettofeedthebaby.com/tag/mental-health/'>mental health</a>, <a href='http://dontforgettofeedthebaby.com/tag/parenting/'>parenting</a>, <a href='http://dontforgettofeedthebaby.com/tag/parenting-community/'>parenting community</a>, <a href='http://dontforgettofeedthebaby.com/tag/thems-fighting-words/'>them's fighting words</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1887/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1887/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1887&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://dontforgettofeedthebaby.com/2013/03/06/my-mind-is-my-battlefield/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>82</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/208729b6abd0e082589468c99eab2957?s=96&#38;d=monsterid&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">varyka</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dontforgettofeedthebaby.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/depressed-woman.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Photo courtesy of sxc.hu</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dontforgettofeedthebaby.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/baby-face_edited-1.jpg?w=500" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Baby face_edited-1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dontforgettofeedthebaby.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/battle_of_barnet.jpg?w=243" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Battle_of_barnet</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>When the Future Comes, What Are We All Going to Do With It?</title>
		<link>http://orkinpod.wordpress.com/2013/02/27/when-the-future-comes-what-are-we-all-going-to-do/</link>
		<comments>http://orkinpod.wordpress.com/2013/02/27/when-the-future-comes-what-are-we-all-going-to-do/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2013 03:19:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>orkinpod</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[the economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[What do I know?]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mechanization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[neoliberalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the future]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://orkinpod.wordpress.com/?p=58</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Last week I wrote about whether or not we really needed economic growth, and I claimed that the central problems facing our economy and our society were not about the size, scale, or growth of our economy, but rather about some deeper, undisclosed set of problems. This week I am trying, haphazardly and tentatively, to [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=58&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last <a href="http://orkinpod.wordpress.com/2013/02/20/do-we-need-economic-growth/">week</a> I wrote about whether or not we really needed economic growth, and I claimed that the central problems facing our economy and our society were not about the size, scale, or growth of our economy, but rather about some deeper, undisclosed set of problems. This week I am trying, haphazardly and tentatively, to work through what those problems might look like. Also to predict the future.</p>
<div id="attachment_59" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 333px"><a href="http://orkinpod.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/astounding-sf-sep-1952.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-59  " alt="For example, an economist looking at the big picture might ask why splitting the atom hasn't unlocked the key to our glorious communist future?" src="http://orkinpod.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/astounding-sf-sep-1952.jpg?w=323&#038;h=461" width="323" height="461" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">For example, an economist looking at the big picture might ask why splitting the atom hasn&#8217;t unlocked the key to our glorious communist future?</p></div>
<p>One of the things that bothers me about economics—both in its academic guise as a social science discipline and its neoliberal political guise as a quasi-religious faith in which bankers and CEOs serve as high priests—is its general failure to talk about what it’s <i>for.</i> Historians have a whole subfield, historiography, dedicated to how and why we write history. But because the economy is so self-evidently important to the fabric of our society, economists get a kind of pass. Economics is important because the economy is important. But what is the point of the economy, anyway? Is it possible to <i>not </i>have an economy? If the answer is no, than what is it about the concept of an “economy” that makes it an inevitable feature of human society? Why is the discipline of economics structured the way it is? Of course, those questions are scary because they lead to even harder questions about why the economy <i>itself</i> is structured the way it is.</p>
<p>I’m not saying I have answers to these questions. Still, it seems like economists, policy makers, and politicians love to fight over the <i>hows—</i>how does the economy run, how does it work, and the most specific whys: why this policy, why that policy—but are terrified to confront big picture questions: why is our economy arranged the way it is arranged, what is it accomplishing for who, and would we set it up that way again if we had to start over?</p>
<p>Even within the constrained context of neoliberal thought, economists, politicians, and business elites seem unwilling to ask even the most obvious of difficult questions. (Note: I define neoliberalism very broadly, and somewhat reflexively, as our society’s governing consensus with regard to global capital, sovereignty, and power-structures.)</p>
<p><span id="more-58"></span></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><b>In Which I Seem like I Will Get to the Point, but Don&#8217;t</b></p>
<div id="attachment_60" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 320px"><a href="http://orkinpod.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/science-fiction-cover-1934-granger.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-60 " alt="science-fiction-cover-1934-granger" src="http://orkinpod.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/science-fiction-cover-1934-granger.jpg?w=310&#038;h=448" width="310" height="448" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">One might go so far as to say that neoliberalism itself is <em>The Mightiest Machine!</em></p></div>
<p><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height:24px;font-size:16px;">This blog post is about the central problems facing Western style capitalism within the terms that neoliberalism has set for itself.  That means I’m disregarding global warming, which neoliberalism has sidelined, since it obviously has nothing to do with free trade or markets (with the exception of various weak-willed efforts to promote cap-and-trade, a market based solution to a problem that only a true ideologue would see as about markets.) Global warming is fundamentally not saleable, scalable, tradeable, or commodifiable—you can’t package and sell a disruption to the balance of nature any more than you can package and sell an earthquake. </span></p>
<p>I’m also not talking about structural violence or civil crisis such as mass-incarceration, colonialism, or the military industrial complex. These are all things that neoliberals have basically accepted as natural and inevitable features of the world, either due to a dramatic failure of imagination, or because they have a personal stake in those institutions and power structures.</p>
<p>Setting all of the violence and senselessness of modernity aside, what remains so hard to understand is why our nation’s elites, and the economists that serve as their high priests, refuse to confront what appears to me to be the central problem facing the global economy, even on their own narrow terms.</p>
<p align="center"><b>In Which I Start to Get to the Point, Finally</b></p>
<div id="attachment_65" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 210px"><a href="http://orkinpod.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/davidbrooks200.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-65 " alt="DavidBrooks200" src="http://orkinpod.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/davidbrooks200.jpg?w=200&#038;h=252" width="200" height="252" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">This is actually what I look like.</p></div>
<p>With all the panache of a young David Brooks, I have dubbed this problem the “making things” problem. What is the making things problem?  In the distant past, most people made a living by growing food.  This, after all, was what you needed to do if you wanted to wake up tomorrow morning and eat breakfast. Food production was centered around local communities, within which food and labor were generally distributed among neighbors and family members.</p>
<p>Mind you, I don’t mean to make this out as a perfect system, or some kind of pre-industrial paradise.  For one thing, there was no television, and I really like television. And because you relied on your immediate community for everything you needed, a natural disaster like a drought could do in your whole family. This was not some better, more natural way—it was just the basic, essential way that was. People grew food, interacted closely with the land, and relied on their immediate community for support when necessary.</p>
<p>Upon this model rested feudal systems, tribal systems, city states, proto-nation states, empires, religious hierarchies, trade caravans, social classes, gender roles, laws, and rules—goods were distributed all around the world (albeit very slowly). So I am not trying to say things were simple. But it was a very, very different kind of economy than what we got after the second industrial revolution.</p>
<p>What we got was a <i>making-things</i> economy. Farmers had become so productive that most people didn’t need to farm anymore. To a few people, it probably seemed stupid to farm when other farmers were making plenty of food. Most people, though, probably liked farming, or at least knew no other way. They stopped farming when other people decided it was stupid for them to be farming, and kicked them off their land (read: enclosure in England, read also: free trade agreements that make small-scale farming uneconomical for poor countries by insisting, in the name of “fairness,” that they trade on an equal footing with rich countries—which incidentally, became rich colonies by colonizing the poor countries oh…less than a century ago, but I’m not even going to go there).</p>
<p>Anyways, the economy we created was one in which people made shit. In exchange for making shit, citizens of wealthy countries got food, shelter, recreation, and healthcare (money made this trade easier, but it was not what they were getting, nor what they needed—it was and remains no more than the highly useful medium of exchange standing between ten hours in a factory and dinner on the table at the end of ten hours in a factory.)</p>
<p>Building the economy around making shit made sense, because a) we got more shit, and god knows people love their plastic crap, b) it came mixed in with modern education, sanitation, electricity, healthcare, and participatory democracy in a bundle of changes which almost certainly could not have been unbundled, and c) every (white, male, able) body who was willing to work their asses off got a half-way decent life for themselves, or at least their children—at least after they fought for said privilege and organized themselves into unions.</p>
<div id="attachment_61" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 352px"><a href="http://orkinpod.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/tops_in_science_fiction_1953spr_v1_n1.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-61  " alt="" src="http://orkinpod.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/tops_in_science_fiction_1953spr_v1_n1.jpg?w=342&#038;h=503" width="342" height="503" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Obviously, I&#8217;m referring to those science fiction writers who weren&#8217;t busy imagining the richly literary encounters between buxom ladies and tentacled space worms&#8230;</p></div>
<p>But now, something fundamental is changing. The science fiction writers of the mid 20<sup>th</sup> century predicted this change. In fact, many believed it was eminent. Perhaps, in a sad twist of fate, this is one reason it is so neglected by more “serious” people now. In 2013, we don’t really need <i>people </i>to make shit anymore, because we have robots that can make shit.</p>
<p>A lot of liberals and neoliberals and people in general don’t see this happening—what they think has happened is that manufacturing has moved overseas because of free trade agreements and globalization. And that <i>has </i>happened, and it wasn’t inevitable, and it wasn’t necessarily a good idea. But so far as I can tell, this overseas shift of manufacturing from places like Michigan to places like Bangladesh is a sort of giant global-history <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Macguffin">MacGuffin</a>.</p>
<p>It’s true that workers who don’t have rights, fair wages, environmental restrictions providing them with clean water and air, modern economies providing them with access to credit, and decent housing and healthcare, can make a T-shirt (or an iphone) a hell of a lot cheaper than a North American can. But people seem to believe that manufacturing will work in these countries the same way it worked in the United States—worker’s rights will improve, things will get better, the country will develop, wealth will be generated, and the third world will eventually rise to be like the first world, while the first world will by then be far ahead due to its mysterious “knowledge-based” economy.<i></i></p>
<p>I don’t think it will work that way. Cheap labor in poor countries under miserable conditions may be cheaper than hiring American workers. It may also be cheaper than robots and total mechanization. But, as the mechanization and modernization of manufacturing in America has demonstrated, manufacturing will never again lead to good jobs under a free market system, because only by mistreating workers can humans compete with machines. When the workers get restless, as they have at Foxconn, to take one example, corporations will not only improve conditions (as Foxconn may or may not be doing)—they will also make plans to replace most of their human employees with humanoid robots (as Foxconn is <a href="http://www.theverge.com/2012/12/11/3753856/foxconn-shenzhen-factory-automation-manufacturing-US-expansion">definitely</a> doing.)</p>
<p>To me, this begs a rather large question—the one that everybody is ignoring. When the future arrives (and I believe that it is very, very close), and machines can supply all the <i>things </i>that humans could possibly ever want, what is everybody going to<i> do?  </i></p>
<p>Mechanization does not have to be a curse. The coming robot revolution, and I truly believe it will be a robot revolution in something very close to the 1950s pulp-fiction sense, should be a blessing. It should mean wealth, leisure, freedom, and dignity for ever more human beings—eventually all human beings.  It should free us to pursue the things we truly love, like art, like love, like family, in place of the things we tolerate, like working in factories and office towers. This is the question that I see glaring back at me when I try to think about the problems facing our economy taken on it’s own terms—discounting humanitarianism, ecology, and structural violence—just money, trade, and straightforward metrics, just like the neoliberals like it.</p>
<p>I wonder whether or not we need leaders and thinkers who can figure out a long term plan for the future, and who have the courage to start implementing it. This is what the corporations, futurists, and government workers who spent the Great Depression <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Futurama_(New_York_World%27s_Fair)">planning in detail</a> for the highways, suburbs, and consumer goods they were going to start making in the post-war era did. Or do we need some kind of grass-roots response? An insurrection, or a movement?</p>
<div id="attachment_62" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 326px"><a href="http://orkinpod.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/if-science-fiction-magazine-1953-cover.jpg"><img class="wp-image-62 " alt="if-science-fiction-magazine-1953-cover" src="http://orkinpod.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/if-science-fiction-magazine-1953-cover.jpg?w=316&#038;h=448" width="316" height="448" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">This is an astoundingly literal depiction of the future I imagine in the last paragraph.</p></div>
<p>Our generation is not going to look like the Baby Boomer generation part 2—that ship has already sailed. And I doubt that it will be a future in which steady technological advance provides jobs enough for all—we can’t all design the next iPhone, although in the 20<sup>th</sup>-century-model economy we might have all helped to build them. Maybe the future will include tariff barriers that help people stick with the jobs they have now while the world figures out what’s coming next, rather than throwing millions of peoples into slums in the name of “globalization” and capitalist progress—but I’m not counting on it.</p>
<p>And maybe the robot revolution will mean that people, secure in their computer and machine-supported ability to have all the cool shit they can imagine, will go back to farming and crafts work and other traditional human occupations—not because they have to, but because they want to?</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/58/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/58/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=58&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://orkinpod.wordpress.com/2013/02/27/when-the-future-comes-what-are-we-all-going-to-do/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/15502c832808271a3cc0e454a5424d4f?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">orkinpod</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://orkinpod.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/astounding-sf-sep-1952.jpg?w=449" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">For example, an economist looking at the big picture might ask why splitting the atom hasn&#039;t unlocked the key to our glorious communist future?</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://orkinpod.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/science-fiction-cover-1934-granger.jpg?w=443" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">science-fiction-cover-1934-granger</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://orkinpod.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/davidbrooks200.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DavidBrooks200</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://orkinpod.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/tops_in_science_fiction_1953spr_v1_n1.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://orkinpod.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/if-science-fiction-magazine-1953-cover.jpg?w=452" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">if-science-fiction-magazine-1953-cover</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Working from Home</title>
		<link>http://spryfox.com/2013/03/04/working-from-home-comic/</link>
		<comments>http://spryfox.com/2013/03/04/working-from-home-comic/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2013 02:31:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>David (aka Chedd)</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Comics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://spryfox.com/?p=4376</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[PS. This is hopefully the first of many comics by our ultra-talented artist, BrentK.<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4376&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://spryfoxsite.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/sf_comic_working-from-home.jpg"><img src="http://spryfoxsite.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/sf_comic_working-from-home.jpg?w=650&#038;h=1341" alt="SF_Comic_Working-from-home" width="650" height="1341" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4377" /></a></p>
<p>PS. This is hopefully the first of many comics by our ultra-talented artist, BrentK. <img src='http://s0.wp.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif' alt=':-)' class='wp-smiley' /> </p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4376/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4376/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4376&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://spryfox.com/2013/03/04/working-from-home-comic/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>25</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/7ce95b2e3db672ee76ca57fd7a422337?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">djedery</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://spryfoxsite.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/sf_comic_working-from-home.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">SF_Comic_Working-from-home</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Can Universities Be The Future Home of Environmental Journalism?</title>
		<link>http://legalplanet.wordpress.com/2013/03/05/can-universities-be-the-future-home-of-environmental-journalism/</link>
		<comments>http://legalplanet.wordpress.com/2013/03/05/can-universities-be-the-future-home-of-environmental-journalism/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2013 21:44:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jonathan Zasloff</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Academia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Literature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[elizabeth kolbert]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hechinger Report]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Investigative Reporting Workshop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New England Center for Investigative Reporting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York Times]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reporting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Schuster Institute]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://legalplanet.wordpress.com/?p=20097</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Consider me somewhat skeptical of the arguments, well-presented by Jayni, that The New York Times&#8217; killing of the Green blog will somehow enhance the paper&#8217;s environmental coverage.  It reminds me a little of the attempts of law schools to teach ethics not with a specific class but with the suffusion method: it&#8217;s an easy way [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=20097&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Consider me somewhat skeptical of the arguments, <a href="http://legalplanet.wordpress.com/2013/03/04/new-york-times-says-farewell-to-green-blog-and-environment-desk/" target="_blank">well-presented by Jayni</a>, that <em>The New York Times&#8217;</em> killing of the Green blog will somehow enhance the paper&#8217;s environmental coverage.  It reminds me a little of the attempts of law schools to teach ethics not with a specific class but with the suffusion method: it&#8217;s an easy way to avoid doing what you don&#8217;t want to do.  And there are grounds for a strong suspicion as to why the Times no longer wants to run the blog or pay the reporters to cover these issues: there isn&#8217;t any money in it.  As Jayni observes, the paper is happy to run blogs on the Red Carpet and automobiles.</p>
<p>This isn&#8217;t pure cheapness on the Times&#8217; part.  Even the nation&#8217;s Paper of Record is staring at its own fiscal cliff.  Consider the following graph, <a href="https://www.techdirt.com/articles/20120916/14454920395/newspaper-ad-revenue-fell-off-quite-cliff-now-par-with-1950-revenue.shtml" target="_blank">assembled by economics professor Mark Perry</a>:</p>
<p><a href="http://legalplanet.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/newspaper-ad-declines.png"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-20099" alt="Newspaper ad declines" src="http://legalplanet.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/newspaper-ad-declines.png?w=600&#038;h=403" width="600" height="403" /></a></p>
<p>Media critic Jay Rosen points out that the advertising peak came when blogging software became available, but I don&#8217;t think that that is it.  It&#8217;s that the internet so vastly expanded the media universe that the advertising money has so many other places to go.</p>
<p>This collapse in newspaper sustainability should really worry anyone committed to democracy: simply put, newspapers generate information necessary to governance and progress (however you want to define the latter term).  Without them, meaningful public participation is really impossible. </p>
<p>What to do?  Many have proposed that newspapers &#8212; which are generally for-profit entities &#8212; <a href="http://www.ojr.org/p1627/" target="_blank">should start seeking philanthropic dollars</a>.  That&#8217;s tricky, because it is hard for foundations to give grants to for-profits.  In any event, the green shoots (so to speak) of strong non-profit journalism are emerging, with entities such as ProPublica, the Center for Public Integrity, or the Pulitzer Center on Crisis Reporting.  It seems to me, however, that one is looking for the natural locus of unifying philanthropic dollars with serious journalism, there is one place to go: the university.</p>
<p>In many ways, serious journalism and serious scholarship are two sides of the same coin.  They both exist to produce knowledge.  To say this in an academic audience is akin to heresy: if a stuck-up academic wants to insult someone, he or she will call their efforts &#8220;journalism.&#8221;  And of course there are differences.  Academic scholarship will try to put information in a theoretical framework that can explain and predict events and advance new hypotheses.  Journalism generally doesn&#8217;t do that; it is generally more at home in the relentless acquisition of facts (when it is doing its job, of course).</p>
<p>But one can easily over-emphasize these differences, and most academics do, because of the need to justify our position and professional prestige.  Many scholarly articles &#8212; particularly from law professors &#8212; rely heavily on journalistic accounts of the world.  To the extent that we are assembling our own facts, we really <em>are</em> doing journalism &#8212; <em>and there is nothing whatever wrong with that.</em> Think of scholars such as Sudhir Venkatesh, Elijah Anderson, or Theda Skocpol as outstanding instances.  Conversely, the best journalism takes a theoretically informed approach and then tries to identify broader patterns and causal connections that mere fact-gathering will not reveal.  Nicholas Lemann, Elizabeth Kolbert, and James Fallows come to mind as outstanding examples.</p>
<p>Journalism embedded within a university not only dovetails nicely with the scholarly mission but also has some promise for creating better journalism and better scholarship.  By working together, academics can generate a set of good questions that need to be answered in order to understand social reality, and journalists can provide the sort of rich factual basis to determine whether these theories have purchase as well as generating new theoretical questions.  Nowhere would this work better in my view than in the environmental field, which often involves complex scientific questions but meta-question about what the science actually <em>means.</em></p>
<p>Already, some universities are beginning to pioneer the new approach.  There&#8217;s the <a href="http://necir-bu.org/" target="_blank">New England Center for Investigative Reporting at Boston University</a>, Chuck Lewis&#8217;s <a href="http://investigativereportingworkshop.org/" target="_blank">Investigative Reporting Workshop at American University</a>, and the <a href="http://www.brandeis.edu/investigate/" target="_blank">Schuster Institute </a>at Brandeis.  In education journalism, Columbia houses the <a href="http://hechingerreport.org/" target="_blank">Hechinger Report</a>, which is a sort of pro publica for schools coverage.</p>
<p>The Times&#8217; decision to de-emphasize environmental coverage is just the sort of prod to bring this new thinking to environmental centers in universities.  The old expression about the weather is that everyone complains about it but no one does anything about it.  The same must be said for reporting on the environment.  And that is even more true because so much environmental reporting is now <em>about</em> the weather.  The time is now to get out of the box and embrace the new challenges posed by the radical restructuring of American journalism.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/20097/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/20097/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=20097&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://legalplanet.wordpress.com/2013/03/05/can-universities-be-the-future-home-of-environmental-journalism/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/3f5cbd506d7f2d59b645da80099e23c0?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jzasloff</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://legalplanet.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/newspaper-ad-declines.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Newspaper ad declines</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Now vs. Now</title>
		<link>http://findingravity.com/2013/03/02/now-vs-now-vs-now/</link>
		<comments>http://findingravity.com/2013/03/02/now-vs-now-vs-now/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 03:41:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>findingravity</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://findingravity.com/?p=2153</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A few days ago at work, I lead a creative jam session where we discussed how being present can make you more creative, and it can also make you a more positive person overall. If you aren’t comparing yourself to where you’ve been, or where you you’d rather be, or how much better you could [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2153&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://findingravity.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/empireyoga.jpg"><img src="http://findingravity.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/empireyoga.jpg?w=285&#038;h=400" alt="empireyoga" width="285" height="400" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2154" /></a></p>
<p>A few days ago at work, I lead a creative jam session where we discussed how being present can make you more creative, and it can also make you a more positive person overall. If you aren’t comparing yourself to where you’ve been, or where you you’d rather be, or how much better you could be than the person across from you, then you’re putting that energy into your creative projects right now.<br />
<br />
That’s what matters, right?<br />
<br />
Right now.<br />
<br />
These words trickled out of my mouth so easily, you would have thought I was a pro at living in the now and appreciating life, moment to moment. This weekend, I thought I would test out my creative beliefs by putting them into practice. On this breezy Brooklyn Saturday, I attended a Yoga class for the first time in over a year.<br />
<br />
Walking into a yoga class after a year of not practicing was harder mentally, physically, and emotionally, than walking into a yoga class two years ago for the very first time.<br />
<br />
Two years ago, I strutted confidently into a yoga studio in my hometown. I had no obligations to myself, other than to simply try something new. It was like trying Thai for the first time, believing that I could be cultured and interesting if I sat in a Thai restaurant and pretended to know what I was ordering.<br />
<br />
Still, I stretched, focused on my breath because that’s what my instructor told me to do, and twisted into positions I had never tried before, all for the excitement of trying this newfound thing. When I left the studio, I knew I would be back. Month after month I formed a unique relationship with my mind, and Yoga became something that made me appreciate my thoughts and feelings in the present moment.<br />
<br />
I did not share that sentiment walking into yoga today.<br />
<br />
If I’m being completely honest, I judged myself, incredibly, during each and every moment. I judged myself because I knew that a year ago I was melting into poses that I could not even wrap my mind around today. I judged myself for assuming that my yoga teacher was judging me. <i>How silly</i>, I thought, <i>yoga teachers aren’t judgmental creatures. </i>I judged myself because the eighty-year-old woman effortlessly lifted into a headstand, and no matter how hard I kicked, my feet fell back to the ground.<br />
<br />
I know, Judgy McJudgerson.<br />
<br />
My yoga teacher would say, “Try your best to flatten your heels…”<br />
And in my head I was shouting, “No….Flatten YOUR heels, dude!”<br />
<br />
It was horribly frustrating, and internally embarrassing.<br />
<br />
I say internally because nobody else could tell that I was tearing myself down, pose by pose, in a practice that used to lift me up.<br />
<br />
Then, something kind of cool happened. During the last 10 minutes of class, our yoga teacher gave a talk about the misconception of allowing ourselves to think we must always achieve the impossible. That sometimes, thinking that we have to achieve the impossible can make the possible seem unattainable. That perhaps it’s not about what’s impossible, but more, what’s workable.  If we focus on what is workable during our poses, then we begin to direct our attention to what we are working with, and allowing that to be good enough.<br />
<br />
It doesn’t mean that we aren’t trying to better ourselves, it just means that we are accepting ourselves in the present moment.  If we can focus on what is workable in our lives, with our creativity, with our current states, with our capabilities, then we can begin to assess where we can develop those things.<br />
<br />
Instead of wishing you could do a hand stand, acknowledge that whatever brought you to your mat was a strong enough force to work with. Instead of wishing you could write the next famous screen play, believe that writing words down that may be read only by you is brave and inspiring in itself. Instead of chasing after somebody else&#8217;s accomplishments, say everything wonderful you&#8217;ve attained by yourself out loud, and let the sound of your own voice be affirmation that you are here.<br />
<br />
Now.<br />
In this moment.<br />
<br />
<a href="http://s1146.beta.photobucket.com/user/findingravity/media/signiture.jpg.html" target="_blank"><img src="http://i1146.photobucket.com/albums/o531/findingravity/signiture.jpg" border="0" alt=" photo signiture.jpg" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2153/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2153/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2153&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://findingravity.com/2013/03/02/now-vs-now-vs-now/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>44</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/6c73f160c98124b251242171071335e2?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">findingravity</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://findingravity.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/empireyoga.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">empireyoga</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://i1146.photobucket.com/albums/o531/findingravity/signiture.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html"> photo signiture.jpg</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Quoth the Raven . . .</title>
		<link>http://wendylovesjesus.wordpress.com/2013/03/05/quoth-the-raven/</link>
		<comments>http://wendylovesjesus.wordpress.com/2013/03/05/quoth-the-raven/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2013 21:29:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Wendy Brydge</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Art & Artists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Edgar Allan Poe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Essay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Literature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Philosophy of Composition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Raven]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://wendylovesjesus.wordpress.com/?p=843</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Dénouement:  the final outcome of the main dramatic complication in a literary work; the outcome of a complex sequence of events; the end result Nothing is more clear than that every plot, worth the name, must be elaborated to its dénouement before any thing be attempted with the pen. It is only with the dénouement [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=843&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><i>Dénouement:  </i>the final outcome of the main dramatic complication in a literary work; the outcome of a complex sequence of events; the end result</p>
<blockquote><p>Nothing is more clear than that every plot, worth the name, must be elaborated to its dénouement before any thing be attempted with the pen. It is only with the dénouement constantly in view that we can give a plot its indispensable air of consequence, or causation, by making the incidents, and especially the tone at all points, tend to the development of the intention.</p></blockquote>
<p><a href="http://wendylovesjesus.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/edgar-allan-poe-portrait.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-864 aligncenter" alt="Edgar Allan Poe - Portrait" src="http://wendylovesjesus.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/edgar-allan-poe-portrait.jpg?w=239&#038;h=300" width="239" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>In 1846, a year after “<a title="Once Upon a Midnight Dreary" href="http://wendylovesjesus.wordpress.com/2013/01/29/once-upon-a-midnight-dreary/" target="_blank">The Raven</a>” was published, Edgar Allan Poe wrote “The Philosophy of Composition”, a prose essay explaining his famous poem. A friend and former employer of Poe&#8217;s, George Rex Graham (who had declined to be the first to print “The Raven” &#8212; a poem he didn&#8217;t like &#8212; the previous year), would publish the essay in his April issue of Graham&#8217;s American Monthly Magazine of Literature and Art.</p>
<p>There are some critics who contend that Poe&#8217;s essay is purely fictitious, meant to be nothing more than a piece of imaginative writing instead of a serious examination of his haunting poem. In my opinion, this idea is absolutely ludicrous. “The Philosophy of Composition” is a remarkable piece of literature revealing Poe&#8217;s carefully thought-out process of writing. It is an invaluable tool to writers, both professional and amateur alike. Why this essay isn&#8217;t a mandatory study in every high school English class in the world is beyond me.<span id="more-843"></span></p>
<p>Poe is quick to point out that many writers, poets in particular, are only too happy to have the reader believe <i>“that they compose by a species of fine frenzy — an ecstatic intuition —” </i>when in reality, as Poe will continue to describe in exquisite detail, that could not be further from the truth.</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8230; it will not be regarded as a breach of decorum on my part to show the modus operandi by which one of my own works was put together&#8230; It is my design to render it manifest that no one point in its composition is referrible either to accident or intuition &#8212; that the work proceeded, step by step, to its completion with the precision and rigid consequence of a mathematical problem.</p></blockquote>
<p>What I found most enlightening about Poe&#8217;s essay was seeing how his writing process was remarkably similar to the process I use when creating a painting. The birth of any work of art, be it a painting or a fine piece of literature, comes with much thought, consideration and careful planning.</p>
<p>The first step Poe takes in the writing of “The Raven” is determining the length of the poem. According to Poe, a poem should fall within <i>“the limit of a single sitting”</i>. Any literary work too long to be read in one sitting compromises the <i>“unity of impression”</i>. If it requires a second sitting to complete, then you risk losing the effectiveness of what you&#8217;ve written. As Poe puts it, <i>“&#8230;the whole being deprived, through the extremeness of its length, of the vastly important artistic element, totality, or unity, of effect.” </i></p>
<p>Considering a number of factors, Poe determines that an appropriate length for his poem will be around 100 lines (&#8220;The Raven&#8221; has 108) – long enough to tell a compelling story and maintain reader interest, but short enough that none of the author&#8217;s artistic nuances are lost, and you retain the effective flow of the piece.</p>
<p>For example, if you build up to an exciting climax but then the reader is delayed in reading it, all the work you did to build up to it was for nothing. You&#8217;ve lost the effectiveness of the moment. To get the biggest bang for your buck you need to read the piece as a whole, from start to finish, at one time, so that everything is fresh in your mind, and you&#8217;re in the moment when the moment comes.</p>
<p>Next Poe decides on the <i>province</i> of the poem, that is, the impression or effect to be conveyed and the tone it will take: <i>“Beauty is the sole legitimate province of the poem. Beauty of whatever kind, in its supreme development, invariably excites the sensitive soul to tears. Melancholy is thus the most legitimate of all the poetical tones.”</i></p>
<p>Even Poe&#8217;s choice of the word for the poem&#8217;s refrain &#8211; “Nevermore” spoken by a raven &#8211; is extremely well thought-out and complex. He chooses to vary the <i>application of the refrain</i> instead of varying the refrain itself. Instead of the refrain being different each time it&#8217;s used, when and where the refrain is spoken will vary; he must decide the <i>nature</i> of the refrain, its <i>length</i> and <i>character</i>; where to use it and how it will sound; THEN select a word embodying this sound in keeping with the tone of the poem. Finally, he settles on a pretext for the continuous use of the one word – why is the same word being used over and over again. Poe&#8217;s solution: have it spoken by a raven, <i>“the bird of ill omen”</i>.</p>
<p>At last we come to the most important part of the planning process&#8230; what is the poem&#8217;s <i>topic</i>?</p>
<blockquote><p>Of all the melancholy topics, what, according to the universal understanding of mankind, is the most melancholy? Death &#8212; was the obvious reply. And when is this most melancholy of topics most poetical? When it most closely allies itself to Beauty: the death, then, of a beautiful woman is, unquestionably, the most poetical topic in the world &#8212; and equally is it beyond doubt that the lips best suited for such topic are those of a bereaved lover.</p></blockquote>
<p>“<i>I had now to combine the two ideas, of a lover lamenting his deceased mistress and a Raven continuously repeating the word “Nevermore”&#8230;”</i> Here Poe concludes that the Raven will speak the refrain in answer to the queries of the lover. And now the building begins. The queries will begin as commonplace, the first of course is simply the man asking the bird its name. But each query will gradually becoming more serious until eventually the lover, expecting to hear the Raven&#8217;s answer of Nevermore, becomes delirious and half-crazed, asking the final question whose climax involves <i>“the utmost conceivable amount of sorrow and despair.”</i> For me, this is the magic moment.</p>
<blockquote><p>Here then the poem may be said to have its beginning &#8212; at the end, where all works of art should begin &#8212; for it was here, at this point of my preconsiderations, that I first put pen to paper in the composition of the stanza:</p></blockquote>
<p style="text-align:center;">&#8220;Prophet,&#8221; said I, &#8220;thing of evil! prophet still if bird or devil!</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">By that heaven that bends above us &#8212; by that God we both adore,</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">Tell this soul with sorrow laden, if within the distant Aidenn,</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">It shall clasp a sainted maiden whom the angels name Lenore &#8211;</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">Clasp a rare and radiant maiden whom the angels name Lenore.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">Quoth the raven, &#8220;Nevermore&#8221;.&#8221;</p>
<p>The very <b>first</b> thing that Poe writes is the climax or conclusion of the story. With the climax established, Poe explains how he could now better vary and graduate the seriousness and importance of the preceding queries of the lover, and in turn make certain that none of the previous stanzas would surpass the climactic one.</p>
<p>Poe continues on in his essay to describe every detail of the poem and how he came about making the choices he did. It is a fascinating journey into the mind of this incredible writer. Poe leaves nothing to chance. He even chooses a bust of Pallas for the Raven to perch upon for the effect of contrast between the light-coloured marble of the bust and the dark plumage of the bird.</p>
<p>When reading the poem, we can see the gradual change which comes over the lover. At first he is amused by the Raven, then his thoughts turn to the slightly fantastical, and finally he turns very serious. <i>“This revolution of thought, or fancy, on the lover’s part, is intended to induce a similar one on the part of the reader — to bring the mind into a proper frame for the dénouement.”</i></p>
<p>The dénouement or final outcome of the narrative is the Raven&#8217;s reply of “Nevermore” to the lover&#8217;s final demand if he shall meet his mistress in another world.</p>
<p>Poe&#8217;s process is so wonderfully refreshing because he really has thought of everything. The entire series of events is entirely plausible – a raven seeking shelter from the stormy night flies into a man&#8217;s house. The bird constantly repeats the only word that it has been taught, but that word <i>“finds immediate echo in the melancholy heart”</i> of the lover who is already wallowing in grief over the death of his beloved Lenore.</p>
<p>And he is impelled by <i>“the human thirst for self-torture.”</i> He keeps asking questions, knowing already what the Raven&#8217;s answer will be. Everything is plausible, Poe has kept both feet in reality. There is nothing supernatural about the occurrences in “The Raven”, and perhaps that is what makes the story so striking &#8212; the realness of the situation resonates with the reader, giving the poem soul.</p>
<p>Having stayed within the confines of reality, Poe ensures that the poem doesn&#8217;t lose its richness and artistic appeal.</p>
<p>“<i>I added the two concluding stanzas of the poem — their suggestiveness being thus made to pervade all the narrative which has preceded them. The under-current of meaning is rendered first apparent in the lines — </i></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">“Take thy beak from out <i>my heart,</i> and take thy form from off my door!”</p>
<p align="CENTER">Quoth the Raven “Nevermore!”</p>
<p><i>It will be observed that the words, “from out my heart,” involve the first metaphorical expression in the poem. They, with the answer, “Nevermore,” dispose the mind to seek a moral in all that has been previously narrated. The reader begins now to regard the Raven as emblematical — but it is not until the very last line of the very last stanza, that the intention of making him emblematical of <b>Mournful and Never-ending Remembrance </b>is permitted distinctly to be seen: </i></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">And the Raven, never flitting, still is sitting, still is sitting,</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">On the pallid bust of Pallas just above my chamber door;</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">And his eyes have all the seeming of a demon’s that is dreaming,</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">And the lamplight o’er him streaming throws his shadow on the floor;</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">And my soul <i>from out that shadow</i> that lies floating on the floor</p>
<p align="CENTER">Shall be lifted — nevermore.</p>
<p>I strongly urge you to ready Poe&#8217;s essay, <a href="http://www.eapoe.org/works/essays/philcomp.htm" target="_blank">The Philosophy of Composition</a>, for yourself. It is a veritable fountain of information, and it discusses even more than what I have highlighted here. It is a rare and exciting privilege to take a peek into the mind of a genius, to see how he thinks, to discover the method behind his madness. That is what Poe has given us with this extraordinary piece of literature &#8212; a chance to glimpse the master at work.</p>
<p>In all of his writings, from the first line to the last, Edgar Allan Poe truly captivates the imagination. His unmatched literary prowess spanned all topics. The same man that gave us the most beautiful of verses from &#8220;Annabel Lee&#8221;, <em>&#8220;But we loved with a love that was more than love&#8221;,</em> also gave us a taste of the torments of the Spanish Inquisition in &#8220;The Pit and the Pendulum&#8221;<em>. </em>We must stand idly by as a Prince loses the battle to protect himself from the Plague in &#8220;Masque of the Red Death&#8221;.</p>
<p>But it is in his most brilliant of works, &#8220;The Raven&#8221;, that Poe reaches his artistic peak. He lays bare a man&#8217;s soul, strips his sorrow naked, and illustrates the sad fact that we&#8217;re sometimes our own worst enemy.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/843/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/843/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=843&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://wendylovesjesus.wordpress.com/2013/03/05/quoth-the-raven/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>34</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/44dda5191de97fb3d1b6b0489ab1c2aa?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">wendybrydge</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://wendylovesjesus.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/edgar-allan-poe-portrait.jpg?w=239" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Edgar Allan Poe - Portrait</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Graffiti of Grace</title>
		<link>http://whimsygizmo.wordpress.com/2013/03/04/the-graffiti-of-grace/</link>
		<comments>http://whimsygizmo.wordpress.com/2013/03/04/the-graffiti-of-grace/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2013 04:57:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>whimsygizmo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://whimsygizmo.wordpress.com/?p=4261</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[You write it on doorposts and bridges and walls and inevitable falls and failings. You paint it in sunrise and sunset and across star-stung skies and in the tattoo of shadows. You stitch it into hearts, tiny etched mendings, sacred scars. It is radical and ridiculous and readily available and we forget and we cheapen [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4261&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><b><span style="color:#ffffff;"><a href="http://whimsygizmo.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/2011-02-25-at-16-21-12.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-4267" alt="2011-02-25 at 16-21-12" src="http://whimsygizmo.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/2011-02-25-at-16-21-12.jpg?w=640&#038;h=959" width="640" height="959" /></a></span></b></p>
<p>You write it on<br />
doorposts<br />
and bridges<br />
and walls<br />
and inevitable falls<br />
and failings.</p>
<p>You paint it in<br />
sunrise<br />
and sunset<br />
and across star-stung skies<br />
and in the tattoo<br />
of shadows.</p>
<p>You stitch it into<br />
hearts, tiny etched<br />
mendings,<br />
sacred scars.</p>
<p>It is<br />
radical<br />
and ridiculous<br />
and readily available<br />
and we forget<br />
and we cheapen it<br />
and we take it<br />
but forget<br />
to give it.</p>
<p>It is<br />
free<br />
and we’re found<br />
gently loosed and unbound;<br />
but we forsake it,<br />
and forget<br />
to live it.<br />
<span style="color:#ffffff;">&#8230;..</span></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4261/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4261/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4261&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://whimsygizmo.wordpress.com/2013/03/04/the-graffiti-of-grace/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>23</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/9bd1171cad141073819367ecd380c262?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">whimsygizmo</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://whimsygizmo.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/2011-02-25-at-16-21-12.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2011-02-25 at 16-21-12</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Reading Between the Lines</title>
		<link>http://geminigirlinarandomworld.com/2013/03/05/reading-between-the-lines-when-your-family-cares-enough-to-send-the-very-best/</link>
		<comments>http://geminigirlinarandomworld.com/2013/03/05/reading-between-the-lines-when-your-family-cares-enough-to-send-the-very-best/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2013 15:02:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Stacie Chadwick</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chores]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dakota Fanning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hallmark holidays]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iphone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ivy League]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kristen Stewart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nicole Richie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Schoolhouse Rock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Steve Jobs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tiger Woods]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://geminigirlinarandomworld.com/?p=2054</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Recently, I got this card from my husband and kids: On the surface, you could read this as, “You’re an awesome Mom/Wife/Food Sanitation Expert/Cleaning Lady!” Digging a little deeper though, there’s a hidden meaning behind each of their missives, one that involves birth order, timing, and various stages of psychological development. Allow me to explain. [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2054&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://geminigirlinarandomworld.com/2013/03/05/reading-between-the-lines-when-your-family-cares-enough-to-send-the-very-best/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>120</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/2d138b5407b77563b6ea99ab736369f5?s=96&#38;d=monsterid&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">staciechadwick</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://staciechadwick.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/photo-21.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">photo (21)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://staciechadwick.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_2201.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">This is Scot&#039;s mustache era, circa December 20 - December 31 2012. I love posting pics of him that he doesn&#039;t want any of his co-workers to see.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://staciechadwick.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_2344.jpg?w=225" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Taylor will probably kill me for posting this pic, but he had a bad attitude last Saturday night when I took him out for a special mother-son dinner so he can suck it.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://staciechadwick.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_1897.jpg?w=224" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">That&#039;s Grace teaching our dog to follow commands in Mandarin.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://staciechadwick.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_1153.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Word.</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Six Years Ago, I Was Dead</title>
		<link>http://therunawaymama.com/2013/03/05/six-years-ago-i-was-dead/</link>
		<comments>http://therunawaymama.com/2013/03/05/six-years-ago-i-was-dead/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2013 14:25:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>The Runaway Mama</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[anxiety]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[conversations to remember]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[death]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[molar pregnancy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[September 11th]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shopping]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://therunawaymama.com/?p=3059</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The other day, Dylan said to me, “Six years ago I was dead.”  We were at the gas station.  I was pumping gas, and Dylan and Riley were hanging out the window. I replied, “No, you weren’t dead.  You just weren’t born yet.” Then he said, “I was dead when I was in your belly.” [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3059&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:justify;">The other day, Dylan said to me, “Six years ago I was dead.”  We were at the gas station.  I was pumping gas, and Dylan and Riley were hanging out the window.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">I replied, “No, you weren’t dead.  You just weren’t born yet.”</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Then he said, “I was dead when I was in your belly.”</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">I replied, “No, you weren’t.  You were growing inside of me.”</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Then he said, “Look, I’m dead,” and his body went limp.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Then Riley said, “Look, I’m dead, too,” and he went limp next to his brother.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">“Neither of you are dead,” I said.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Then Dylan said, “Two years ago I was dead and now I’m back.”</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">After that zinger, I changed the subject.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">The ease with which my kids talk about, think about, and imitate death astounds me.  Equally surprising is the ease with which I talk about it with them.  Dylan has, on many occasions, asked me about death (thankfully he’s only had to mourn a fish so far), and I’ve had some <a href="http://therunawaymama.com/2011/12/25/merry-christmas-what-happens-when-you-die/" target="_blank">pretty darn good answers</a> (if I do say so myself).  The problem is that underneath my super cool, no big deal this-is-what-happens-when-you-die exterior, I’m a hot, flaming mess.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">You see, death is one thing.  Dying is another.  I don’t even like it when my boys go to birthday parties without me.  How am I supposed to die?  How am I supposed to be gone?  Forever?  Holy crap.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">I <i>don’t</i> know what happens after we die.  (Maybe Dylan <i>was</i> dead before he was born.)  Even more unsettling is that, if I’m being totally honest, the theory I consider to be the most likely is that nothing happens, which doesn’t leave me much to hang a hat on.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">So, how exactly does one prepare for the end?  For nothingness?  And as long as I’m on the subject, what’s my purpose and why am I here?</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Wait.  I’m sorry.  Do you think I have answers to these questions?  Ha!  If I contemplate for just a few seconds the notion that the earth is a speck of dust in an infinite universe, my chest tightens and I can’t catch my breath.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">I don’t like being out of control, which is why general anesthesia is so hard for me and why life’s lemons propel me to clean out closets and organize cabinets (or at least go shopping for these projects at the Container Store).  Every aspect of death – from how to when to where to why – is a crapshoot, so I can’t embrace it any more than I can Dylan going to sleepaway camp or – gulp – driving a car.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">I’ve lost my fair share of loved ones.  Their lives <i>and</i> deaths have not only given purpose to mine, but also amplified theirs.  I cherish the memories I have of them, the perspective they impart, the lessons they pass on, and the endless wisdom they share, even in death.   Whether I know it or not, my children and loved ones will have the same experience after I’m gone, which is a beautiful proposition, but it’s the “whether or not I know it” part with which I struggle.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">I don’t believe in anything enough to surrender to it.  After <a href="http://therunawaymama.com/2012/09/10/hills-are-no-big-deal-and-life-is-sweet/" target="_blank">9/11</a>, I desperately wanted to believe in something to make sense of why I was alive and others were dead, and I felt something eerily similar after my <a href="http://therunawaymama.com/2012/02/29/were-okay/" target="_blank">molar pregnancy</a>.  In the end, though, these tragedies didn’t give me faith; rather they made me keenly aware of what I don’t believe.  I don’t believe in fate, I don’t believe in a plan, and I don’t believe things happen for a reason, all of which make dying a tricky proposition.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">I certainly hope that by the time I’m an old lady – assuming I have the great fortune of growing old – I’ll have adopted a belief in something other than nothing or become exhausted enough with life to accept what does or doesn’t happen next.  In the meantime, I’ll obsess over the wrinkles developing in my cleavage (true story) and how my hands are starting to look like my mom’s (sorry mom), and I’ll live my life how I want my children to live theirs and how I want their children to live theirs and how I want their children’s children to live theirs.   <i>Chest tightening.  Can’t catch breath.  </i>And when overwhelming thoughts of death, nothingness, infinity, and my children’s children’s children take hold, I’ll do what I did after Dylan said, “Six years ago I was dead.”  I’ll change the subject.  Or, I’ll go to the Container Store.  (Ahh.)</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">p.s. Rest in peace, Uncle David.  Whether you know it or not, your lessons are coming fast and hard.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><a href="http://therunawaymama.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/park2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-3085" alt="watersunpark" src="http://therunawaymama.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/park2.jpg?w=300&#038;h=224" width="300" height="224" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3059/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3059/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3059&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://therunawaymama.com/2013/03/05/six-years-ago-i-was-dead/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>59</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/e1ab870008afab660923d7b504f77a92?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">therunawaymama</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://therunawaymama.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/park2.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">watersunpark</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Was The Irish Famine Genocide?</title>
		<link>http://robertnielsen21.wordpress.com/2013/03/05/was-the-irish-famine-genocide/</link>
		<comments>http://robertnielsen21.wordpress.com/2013/03/05/was-the-irish-famine-genocide/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2013 10:05:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Robert Nielsen</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Britain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Famine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Genocide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Great Famine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ireland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Irish Famine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Irish History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Irish Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Famine Plot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tim Pat Coogan]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://robertnielsen21.wordpress.com/?p=1184</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Some people claim that the Great Famine was an act of genocide committed by the British Empire against the Irish people. This theory is most popular among Irish-Americans (who strangely enough are more nationalist than people from Ireland) and on the internet, though it has little if any credence in Ireland. It has been booted [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1184&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.irishhistorylinks.net/History_Links/IrishFamineGenocide.html" target="_blank"><span style="color:#0000ff;">Some</span> </a><a href="http://thepressnet.com/2012/12/06/proving-the-irish-famine-was-genocide-by-the-british/" target="_blank"><span style="color:#0000ff;">people</span> </a>claim that the Great Famine was an act of genocide committed by the British Empire against the Irish people. This theory is most popular among <a href="http://www.irishcentral.com/story/news/periscope/proving-the-irish-famine-was-genocide-by-the-british----tim-pat-coogan-moves-famine-history-unto-a-new-plane-181984471.html" target="_blank"><span style="color:#0000ff;">Irish-Americans</span></a> (who strangely enough are more nationalist than people from Ireland) and on the <a href="http://www.eirefirst.com/archive/unit_6.html" target="_blank"><span style="color:#0000ff;">internet</span></a>, though it has little if any credence in Ireland. It has been booted out of <a href="http://enochered.wordpress.com/2011/02/05/the-famine-that-never-was/" target="_blank"><span style="color:#0000ff;">conspiracy theory</span></a> land after one of the most respected Irish historians; Tim Pat Coogan supported the allegation in his <a href="http://itsapoliticalworld.wordpress.com/2012/12/20/tim-pat-coogans-the-famine-plot-englands-genocidal-role-a-review/" target="_blank"><span style="color:#0000ff;">new</span> </a>book, <i><a href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/12729810-the-famine-plot" target="_blank"><span style="color:#0000ff;">The Famine Plot</span></a>.<span id="more-1184"></span></i></p>
<div id="attachment_591" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://robertnielsen21.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/fam_ejectment.gif"><img class="size-full wp-image-591" alt="An eviction - loss of house and land resulted in emigration or death" src="http://robertnielsen21.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/fam_ejectment.gif?w=500&#038;h=346" width="500" height="346" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">An eviction &#8211; loss of house and land resulted in emigration or death</p></div>
<p>The Great Famine (or Great Hunger as it is also known) was the most cataclysmic event in Irish history. Sparked by the failure of the potato crop (due to blight) it led to roughly one million deaths and roughly another million people to emigrate. Considering the pre-famine population was 8 million it was proportionally one of the worst famines in modern times. The population of Ireland has never reached that level again, making us one of the few (if not only) countries to have the same population that we did in 1820. It was the largest factor in the destruction of the Irish language and culture. It began a process of mass emigration that would drain the country of all vitality for the next 150 years as the best and brightest left.</p>
<p>The argument is that this famine was not a natural disaster but rather deliberate plan by the British authorities to destroy the Irish people. The famous 19<sup>th</sup> century Irish revolutionary John Mitchell famously said “God sent the blight, but the English sent the Famine.” What he meant was that despite the failure of the potato crop there was still enough food in the country to feed the population. Instead the cruel and greedy English exported the food leaving the Irish to starve. Reference is made to disgusting bigotry and anti-Irish prejudice in Britain at the time, particularly of the infamous <i>Punch</i> cartoons which compared the Irish to apes. The allegation is that the British deliberatively neglected the starving Irish in order to destroy them and clear the land.</p>
<div id="attachment_1185" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 505px"><a href="http://robertnielsen21.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/588486e.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1185" alt="The Famine Plot has reignited the claim that the Famine was an act of genocide by the British" src="http://robertnielsen21.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/588486e.jpg?w=495&#038;h=371" width="495" height="371" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The Famine Plot has reignited the claim that the Famine was an act of genocide by the British</p></div>
<p>The most controversial issue in Anglo-Irish affairs is the allegation that food was exported during the Famine. This was first claimed by Irish nationalists as a reason to end British rule and the Famine certainly put an end to the idea that Ireland would be a part of the United Kingdom for good. However, it is extraordinarily difficult to prove the claim true or false, and to my knowledge no one has. Records of exports simply weren’t kept or have since been lost. It is certainly true that some food was exported, but there is no way of knowing how much or if it would have prevented the Famine. Food was also imported, though again, it is unknown where this outweighed the food that was exported. The starving Irish had little money so merchants naturally (in their mind) sold it abroad where they could get a better price. Had a ban on exports been put in place, lives would have been saved, but how many is unknown.</p>
<p><span style="line-height:1.7;">Let’s take a moment to reflect on what genocide actually means. According to the United Nations Genocide Convention:</span></p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Any of the following acts committed with<strong> intent to destroy</strong>, in whole or in part, a national, ethnical, racial or religious  group, as such: killing members of the group; causing serious bodily or mental harm to members of the group; deliberately inflicting on the group conditions of life, calculated to bring about its physical destruction in whole or in part; imposing measures intended to prevent births within the group; [and] forcibly transferring children of the group to another group.&#8221; (emphasis added)</p></blockquote>
<p><span style="line-height:1.7;">The crucial question in whether or not it is genocide comes down to intent. Did the English government intend to destroy the Irish people? The answer is no. They were heartlessly negligent, but neglect is not the same as murder. There was never any plan to wipe out the Irish nor any actions that could be viewed as such. The government didn’t directly kill anyone nor did they deliberatively destroy any food. In fact the relief aid, pathetic as it was, does damage the genocide argument. After all, why would the government set up soup kitchens if it wanted the Irish to die?</span></p>
<p>It was not murder or genocide that killed so many, but neglect. The government believed in laissez-faire economics or what would now be called free market fundamentalism (<a href="http://robertnielsen21.wordpress.com/2012/08/25/laissez-faire-and-the-irish-great-famine/" target="_blank"><span style="color:#0000ff;">I have a post on the issue here</span></a>). They believed that the government should not interfere with the market or it would only make the situation worse. They believed (like many today) that aid to the Irish would only make them lazy and dependent on handouts. They believed Ireland was over-populated and welcomed emigration to America. There was certainly a lot of racism, but I believe the larger motivator was aristocratic disgust for the poor. The government didn’t believe that poor people should be helped no matter how desperate their situation or what their nationality was. This, and not some genocidal master plan, was why so little was done during the Famine.</p>
<p><em>(It is worth pointing out that <a href="http://www.drb.ie/blog/writers-and-artists/2013/02/25/was-the-famine-a-genocide-" target="_blank"><span style="color:#0000ff;">historians</span> </a>have <a href="http://www.irishtimes.com/newspaper/weekend/2013/0119/1224329030440.html" target="_blank"><span style="color:#0000ff;">criticised</span> </a>Coogan&#8217;s book. Having read it, I must agree that it lacks thoroughness and fails to back up its claim that the Famine was genocide. Little evidence is given and there are surprisingly few sources used.)</em></p>
<p>The Famine was the greatest calamity in Irish history. People needlessly died due to cold-hearted indifference and the elevation of the market above the lives of people. Nowhere near enough aid was given as prejudice won out over compassion. Lassiez faire turned into Leave them to die. But this was a crime of neglect, not genocide. There never was intent to destroy the Irish. Had the government really wanted to exterminate the Irish, they would have done more than let natural disasters run their course. The claims by Coogan and others, while passionate, simply do not have enough evidence to support themselves.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1184/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1184/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1184&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://robertnielsen21.wordpress.com/2013/03/05/was-the-irish-famine-genocide/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>37</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/b2ddcd530fd110bdf82945e8c5bc5664?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">rapn21</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://robertnielsen21.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/fam_ejectment.gif" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">An eviction - loss of house and land resulted in emigration or death</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://robertnielsen21.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/588486e.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The Famine Plot has reignited the claim that the Famine was an act of genocide by the British</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
