<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 21:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>68 Teams, 1 Dream: Why March Madness is Sheer Happiness</title>
		<link>http://sheridansshorts.com/2013/03/26/68-teams-1-dream-why-march-madness-is-sheer-happiness/</link>
		<comments>http://sheridansshorts.com/2013/03/26/68-teams-1-dream-why-march-madness-is-sheer-happiness/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 01:34:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>sheridad69</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Basketball]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[March Madness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NCAAM]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://sheridansshorts.com/?p=522</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[10 seconds left on the clock.  Tie ball game. 20,000 nervous fans, all on their feet, tensely await the start of the next play.  Hearts are pounding, palms are sweating, knees are shaking… this is the moment of truth.  After a long, hard-fought 39 minutes and 50 seconds of playing time, the game hangs in [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=522&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://sheridansshorts.com/2013/03/26/68-teams-1-dream-why-march-madness-is-sheer-happiness/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f3e5d90f98c62d304005dd1688e460d5?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sheridad69</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Love&#8217;s Leaver&#8217;s Lost</title>
		<link>http://boozeforthought.net/2013/03/19/loves-leavers-lost-2/</link>
		<comments>http://boozeforthought.net/2013/03/19/loves-leavers-lost-2/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 01:24:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Charles Hardwick</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Non-Fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cocktails]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lost and Found]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shakespeare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spirits]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://boozeforthought.net/?p=39</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Losing things can be a tremendous nuisance. There are the tangible losses that sting: a scarf, an umbrella or a cell phone. And the abstract losses: your innocence, your inhibitions, and perhaps, your self-respect as a result of several booze-induced bad decisions. Alone or accompanied, you wake up and wonder, “What was I thinking?” The [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=39&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Losing things can be a tremendous nuisance. There are the tangible losses that sting: a scarf, an umbrella or a cell phone. And the abstract losses: your innocence, your inhibitions, and perhaps, your self-respect as a result of several booze-induced bad decisions. Alone or accompanied, you wake up and wonder, “What was I thinking?” The bar is a place where you willfully go hoping to lose something intangible and perhaps unmentionable, while praying that your belongings and daily mentionables don’t tumble out of your purse or pocket along the way. After all, a hat or scarf can be replaced, but that favorite hat or scarf that you bought during that trip to Ireland, and all the memories associated with it, cannot. You walk through the door courting a kind of self-inflicted amnesia, and you do so at your peril. You wager on your future and the quality of your evening . Win big, lose small, and most of all, know when it’s time to go home.</p>
<p>The best bartenders know a lot about losses and gains. They recognize that the bar is a kind of casino where bets are placed; often by people who don’t even know what game they are playing.  In the abstract, you can win big in the form of closing a big business deal, or you can meet the love of your life. You can also come so painfully close to success with either that you will want to cry like a baby when it is suddenly snatched away from you.  We are the Croupier, the Pit Boss and Casino Manager all rolled into one. Things get lost or left behind, people spend far more than they intended to, and we dispassionately bear witness to all the comings and goings. When the item is something material, we store it, label it like an archivist and (usually) hope it gets back to it&#8217;s rightful owner. When it is something we covet however, this becomes more of a challenge. The woman whose shameless flirting seems to grow in direct proportion to her date’s lateness or dull conversation. The new iPad or digital camera someone left behind. These things can inspire no small amount of temptation. But I feel pretty secure in saying that our guilt at keeping an item from the lost and found directly corresponds to its material value. It is the cheap and mundane, the crass or comical things, neglected and easy to replace, that we consider fair game.</p>
<p>Take umbrellas for example. I haven’t bought an umbrella in twenty years. I’ve had all sorts come into my possession. At one point I counted an accumulated two dozen umbrellas in my apartment. I eventually gave most of them away and all but two I don’t have anymore. Why? Because I left them in a bar somewhere. Believe me, I am more likely to buy an Aston-Martin than I am to buy an umbrella.</p>
<p>I don’t smoke, but I have dozens of cigarette lighters. Bics and butanes, large, small, plastic, aluminum, I even have a $500 DuPont lighter that I probably should have sold on Ebay long ago. Scarves and jackets, a couple of amazing raincoats courtesy of the unclaimed lost and found bin; I could build a façade of accessories that would make Ian Fleming proud. But please don’t think me a thief or cold-blooded opportunist. In every one of these cases I have at least waited the requisite 2-4 weeks before taking possession of the orphaned items. I confess to being a bit of a calendar watcher on occasion, but at least as often, I have gone on the internet, or Facebook, and called credit card companies and told them to inform the card holder of their lost item.  Certainly, that lambs wool sweater feels far less itchy with a clear conscience.</p>
<p>Some things that get left behind are just plain weird. Opening a stranger&#8217;s bag can be akin to opening the prize packet inside a depraved box of Cracker Jacks. Someone once left a beautiful leather golf bag behind and upon opening it I discovered, among other things, a nice, but weathered dop kit that, along with the usual toiletries, contained a diabetics insulin testing kit and several syringes and medications. Worrying about the persons safety should they not get their meds, I scoured the bag for anything that might identify the owner, but to no avail. I was once haunted for months by a woman’s lost Korean passport with all sorts of difficult and complicated stamps and visas stapled in it. Try as I might, I couldn’t find her via the internet or any other source and she never called or returned for it. The documents are probably still in that office right now.</p>
<p>But it is the birthday parties that yield the most colorful left behinds. The half-consumed customized cakes, and tons of delicious designer pastries. Kooky balloons withering on their strings, the thoughtfully chosen oversized cards with scores of signatures that the drunken birthday celebrant completely forgot about. I once had a guy celebrate his birthday at my bar. Kinda hip looking in a Maroon 5 sort of way, he intended to move to a table but wound up having such a blast at the bar that he just stayed and reveled the night away as his friends continued to give him all sorts of various and sundry gifts. When he left, many of them were left behind in a bag (they were unwrapped) and a partial list included: an iPod Charger, a bottle of 1999 Dom Perignon, a bottle of K-Y warming lubricant, and an enormous 12” black dildo called “The Emperor.” I suspect the last item  may have explained his hesitancy in calling to retrieve them. We kept everything for quite a while until one day, the dildo mysteriously vanished along with a never-been-kissed Jehovah’s Witness cocktail waitress of ours. The timing may have been a coincidence, but at the end of the day, I’ll never know. I can only view it as the detritus of a night well enjoyed, that in some mysterious way, rippled outward and made a few lives better.</p>
<p>When the evening ends, the inventory of things lost and found can begin, and one hopes that they are only vague and ethereal. A few cares and inhibitions, perhaps a forgotten stop or two during your bar crawl.  This along with a few dollars and you can happily declare that you’ve at least broken even. If it’s a tooth or a pair of underwear, well, it still could’ve been worse. William Shakespeare must have just awakened after a long night out when he wrote, “Praising what is lost, makes the remembrance dear.”  Indeed. And if you’re lucky, we may just be holding on to it for you.</p>
<p><b>Cocktail Epilogue</b></p>
<p>The Casino Cocktail</p>
<p>2 parts Old Tom Gin</p>
<p>¼ part Maraschino liqueur</p>
<p>¼ part fresh lemon juice</p>
<p>2 dashes Orange bitters</p>
<p>Combine all ingredients along with ice in a cocktail shaker, shake vigorously and strain into a chilled cocktail glass. Garnish with a brandied Maraschino cherry.</p>
<p><i>Source: New Diners Club Drink Book, 1968, by Matty Simmons</i></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/39/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/39/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=39&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://boozeforthought.net/2013/03/19/loves-leavers-lost-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://boozeforthoughtdotnet.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/n503400088_1753798_3873.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://boozeforthoughtdotnet.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/n503400088_1753798_3873.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">n503400088_1753798_3873</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/3428b7315dc49b167a8e7ed2c464c988?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">charhard</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Seeing the City as Palimpset</title>
		<link>http://andthosewerethereasons.wordpress.com/2013/02/06/seeing-the-city-as-palimpsest-part-iii/</link>
		<comments>http://andthosewerethereasons.wordpress.com/2013/02/06/seeing-the-city-as-palimpsest-part-iii/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2013 03:51:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lucy</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[City life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Melbourne]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[street art]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://andthosewerethereasons.wordpress.com/?p=291</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The peeling paste-up ONE OF THE MOST POPULAR forms of street art in Melbourne is the paste-up: printed or drawn posters adhered to city walls with a wheat-based glue. The physical insubstantiality of paste-ups renders them particularly ephemeral — they do not have the ‘sticking power’ of paint — yet this also makes them particularly [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=291&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://andthosewerethereasons.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/brunswick.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-484" alt="brunswick" src="http://andthosewerethereasons.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/brunswick.jpg?w=525&#038;h=349" width="525" height="349" /></a> <a href="http://andthosewerethereasons.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/croydon1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-485" alt="croydon" src="http://andthosewerethereasons.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/croydon1.jpg?w=525&#038;h=350" width="525" height="350" /></a> <a href="http://andthosewerethereasons.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/miso-greeve-st1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-486" alt="miso-greeve-st" src="http://andthosewerethereasons.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/miso-greeve-st1.jpg?w=525&#038;h=406" width="525" height="406" /></a></p>
<h2 style="text-align:justify;">The peeling paste-up</h2>
<p style="text-align:justify;">ONE OF THE MOST POPULAR forms of street art in Melbourne is the paste-up: printed or drawn posters adhered to city walls with a wheat-based glue. The physical insubstantiality of paste-ups renders them particularly ephemeral — they do not have the ‘sticking power’ of paint — yet this also makes them particularly ‘active’ components of the city footprint. The effects of time and human interface are readily wrought upon their surface. Older paste-ups peel away from the walls on which they are stuck; new ones are pasted over them, perhaps in turn to be painted over by following artists, tagged by graffitists, or torn down by council cleaning teams. For artist Miso, the traces of the ‘life’ of the poster are part of its appeal as an art form:</p>
<blockquote><p>There is a certain excitement in nature and the city reclaiming that piece and the way people interact with it. Whether it is rained on, pipes drip onto it, moss grows on it, it’s tagged over, drunks piss on it, or it’s documented and archived and put into books or whatever happens, I really like that it has a life of its own.<a title="" href="#_ftn1">[1]</a></p></blockquote>
<p style="text-align:justify;">These actions leave physical traces on the site of the artwork. The city’s fabric is in constant flux; it is an organic, evanescent, growing surface.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Between pastings and as existing posters perish, paste-up sites come to resemble modern collages or a paper form of the archaeologist’s stratum; the suggestions of text and image become visible in part as the layers are torn away. The stratum represents a temporally condensed equivalent of the overlays of paint and wallpaper in a period home which, if peeled back, reveal the evolving decorative tastes and economic standing of subsequent generations of the building’s occupants. Like layered advertising posters, the sanctioned cousin of the illegal paste-up, their content discloses the concerns of the urban inhabitants, concerns often as ephemeral as the posters themselves: commodities, events, political agendas, values, aesthetics.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Also like advertising, the images are infinitely reproducible: constructed in a studio and able to be rapidly wheat-pasted to any wall, paste-ups (like stencil art) enable the artist to bombard the city with a repeatable message or to transport a particular look to different urban centres. Yet the impact of different sites, different natural patterns, and of different public interactions and responses will imbue each image with a unique lifespan and patina of aging.</p>
<div style="text-align:justify;">
<hr align="left" size="1" width="33%" />
<div>
<p><a title="" href="#_ftnref1">[1]</a> Interview with Miso in <i>Street Studio</i> by Alison Young, 167.</p>
</div>
</div>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/291/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/291/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=291&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://andthosewerethereasons.wordpress.com/2013/02/06/seeing-the-city-as-palimpsest-part-iii/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/b7c505b17f9391c11b86b23bd09ec4f7?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F2.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lucycwatson</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://andthosewerethereasons.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/brunswick.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">brunswick</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://andthosewerethereasons.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/croydon1.jpg?w=525" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">croydon</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://andthosewerethereasons.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/miso-greeve-st1.jpg?w=525" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">miso-greeve-st</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Oh, Flaneur</title>
		<link>http://mantisandme.com/2013/03/04/oh-flaneur/</link>
		<comments>http://mantisandme.com/2013/03/04/oh-flaneur/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2013 22:55:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>artemiswins</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Thoughts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[active]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[argentina]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Baudelaire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cyberflaneur]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flaneur]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[luck]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[perspective]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[purpose]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[society]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sociology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thoreau]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mantisandme.com/?p=315</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;d like to share a concept that I have grown to adore and utilize widely in my life. It&#8217;s an old French ideal, something probably upper-class and white and readily eyebrowed, but the art of the flaneur is a specific take on observation: Wikipedia says the word means something along the lines of &#8220;to stroll&#8221; or [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=315&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;d like to share a concept that I have grown to adore and utilize widely in my life.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s an old French ideal, something probably upper-class and white and readily eyebrowed, but the art of the <em>flaneur</em> is a specific take on observation: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fl%C3%A2neur">Wikipedia</a> says the word means something along the lines of &#8220;to stroll&#8221; or &#8220;saunter&#8221; or &#8220;loaf,&#8221; which alludes to that principle at the core of <em>flanerie</em>, which is to do nothing; to have no objective, no destination, no prerogative or goal in mind, except to observe in any way you might like the surroundings you encounter.</p>
<p>Historically, the <em>flaneur</em> has been important in some strains of academic thought including <a href="http://usj.sagepub.com/content/35/5-6/909.extract">urban modernization</a>, class conflict, and architecture. Important theoretic contributors include <a href="http://www.columbia.edu/itc/architecture/ockman/pdfs/dossier_4/Baudelaire.pdf">Charles Baudelaire</a>, <a href="http://tcs.sagepub.com/content/8/3/151.extract">Georg Simmel</a>, Susan Sontag, and <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=k4MhC5tcEv0">Nassim Nicholas Taleb</a>; of course there are lots of interesting learnings pent up in each of these contributions to the theme, but this being a blog and you having the Internet, I will let you explore ad libitum and I&#8217;ll proceed with what I&#8217;d actually like to write about.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone" alt="" src="http://blindflaneur.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/02/gustave_caillebotte_paris_street_rainy_day_1877_wiki.jpg" width="783" height="600" /></p>
<p>I have now begun my semester studying abroad. Except for when I&#8217;ve had to participate in program-scheduled activities (picking classes, orientation etc.) I have had a great many hours of entirely unstructured time. Like most humans I do often enjoy the company of others and so I have certainly been getting to know the other international students as well as my host family and an interesting handful of native Argentines. But when I wake up on Friday and Saturday and Sunday (literally, every day this weekend) with nothing that I <em>must do</em>, I think to myself, I&#8217;ve made it. I&#8217;m here, this is what I&#8217;ve been waiting for. Enter, the <em>flaneur</em>.</p>
<p>I am in love with the idea of eschewing purpose, first in any location, as it matters not <a href="http://books.google.com.ar/books?id=nG0VZOYd2m8C&amp;pg=PA69&amp;lpg=PA69&amp;dq=thoreau+journal+5+august+1851&amp;source=bl&amp;ots=Eh81-KBN1L&amp;sig=zDO2YDEfbWwN4W77nGt_1JMjs-w&amp;hl=en&amp;sa=X&amp;ei=Fw40UZm6Aoeo8QT9yoHAAQ&amp;sqi=2&amp;redir_esc=y#v=onepage&amp;q&amp;f=false">where you look but how</a>, but with even more gusto in some place new and fantastic. Not that I have any problem with having guiding purpose in your day or life, as you would be idle to be without it. But so often, our purpose lends us spectacular clarity upon our destination and utter blindness to anything that might be even a degree off-course.</p>
<p>There is a nice parable that illustrates this idea, in which a rich man leads a crowd of people to see that he had laid out a trail of dollar bills on a sidewalk stretching as far as the eye could see. Immediately the crowd swarms, racing and elbowing each other to pick them up first. When they arrive, breathless, at the end of the trail, the rich man points so as to lift their gaze ever so slightly, to see that he had also hung hundred dollar bills from the trees on either side of the sidewalk. In the distance, not yet far from the starting line, a single man had noticed the hanging money and was about to climb the fourth tree.</p>
<p>To be alone in a crowd; to be one with its ebbs and flows, its conflict and resolution; to notice and admire each grand story as it marches past, mysterious forever; invisible (unless someone else is watching me, and then let them). Baudelaire looked to be one with the crowd. I look to be one part of it. A tiny part, scarily small, or perhaps the world is scarily large, and I&#8217;m still normal-sized. Perhaps I am enamored with this concept of relativity, that suddenly I&#8217;m not so important; I tire of placing myself on such a false pedestal, like why should I care so much about myself? I can answer this question only evolutionarily, and perhaps economically as I will likely someday contribute some value back from where I&#8217;ve taken it. But ethically, I am an arbitrary prince, my value arbited by fickle luck. In my selfishness I am disgusted. But I digress..</p>
<p>Now, im not so idealistic as to suggest that all of you with your busy lives and money-trails should suddenly stop these activities and squat on city corners for hours each day. In my luxurious moment, I am able to begin and end the day without having accomplished a single goal, except to have observed, and that is a truly precious privilege. However, I also have lived the busy life, and this mindset has not only just occurred to me in these spare minutes. For it is that exactly: a mindset. Often I&#8217;ll set aside a time slot,- nothing outrageous, perhaps half an hour, during which time I&#8217;ll set the single goal of getting razors and body soap from the CVS nearby. Unless each of our days are so routinely unfortunate that each task forever bleeds into the next, I think we are generally able to allot a bit of extra time for oneself at strategic points in our days. To do what? To do nothing. For me, I have seen the most hideous and the most beautiful things in these times, the most banal and the most surprising. If you are so jaded to experience that you do not feel the attraction to this activity (or lack thereof), then you should read my <a href="http://mantisandme.com/2013/02/19/on-substitutes-and-glitter-bombs/">last post</a>, which explained slightly why I like to keep my eyes open.</p>
<p>An interesting adaptation of this concept is that of the <em>cyberflaneur</em>, in which this mindset of not being always-purposed is applied to our use of the Internet. Trends indicate that we increasingly use the Internet only functionally. In an <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2012/02/05/opinion/sunday/the-death-of-the-cyberflaneur.html?_r=2&amp;pagewanted=all&amp;">article</a> published in the New York Times last February, <a href="https://twitter.com/evgenymorozov">Evegny Morozov</a> commented that our increasing societal single-mindedness is reflected on the Internet:</p>
<blockquote><p>Something similar has happened to the Internet. Transcending its original playful identity, it’s no longer a place for strolling — it’s a place for getting things done. Hardly anyone “surfs” the Web anymore. The popularity of the “app paradigm,” whereby dedicated mobile and tablet applications help us accomplish what we want without ever opening the browser or visiting the rest of the Internet, has made cyberflânerie less likely. That so much of today’s online activity revolves around shopping — for virtual presents, for virtual pets, for virtual presents for virtual pets — hasn’t helped either. Strolling through Groupon isn’t as much fun as strolling through an arcade, online or off.</p></blockquote>
<p>(Side-question: is social media helping or hurting our discovery of interesting things? Morozov seems to think that it&#8217;s a distraction from our own perusing, but technosociologist <a href="https://twitter.com/techsoc">Zeynep Tufekci</a> <a href="http://technosociology.org/?p=693">doesn&#8217;t quite agree</a>; is there a &#8216;filter bubble&#8217;? Is seeing new and exciting articles from our friends on FB a new flaneurism, or is it the &#8216;daily me&#8217;?)</p>
<p>Again, not that I think we should all sit around flipping through page after page of Wikipedia or <a href="http://http://blogs.canoe.ca/moniquesmorningminute/reddit/why-reddit-can-be-awesome/">Reddit</a> or <a href="http://www.ted.com/talks/wingham_rowan_a_new_kind_of_job_market.html">TED</a>, but in actuality, I do! Everything in moderation, but these tools of modernity can connect us with troves of brilliance and creativity, information about history, art, all of the <a href="http://www.openculture.com/free_ebooks">academica</a> under the sun, etc.</p>
<p>Set parameters. Fifteen minutes. Forty-five. Don&#8217;t allow yourself to over or under-do it. If you get so wrapped up in a wikipedia binge that you only look up two hours later, the next time you might have ten minutes free, you&#8217;ll think &#8220;I don&#8217;t want to start, because then I won&#8217;t be able to stop.&#8221; Not that self moderation is easy for everyone, but give it your all..</p>
<p>Be an active observer of your world. Loaf both on the curb outside Starbucks and then again inside; sip your latte, but use their WIFI to read about the folks that might have a cure for <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-21651225">HIV in infants</a>. Follow your money trail, but look to the trees! You might see a monkey 8-] (or a mantis??)</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/315/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/315/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=315&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://mantisandme.com/2013/03/04/oh-flaneur/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/49137bdd7084413e912c134573477a56?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">artemiswins</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://blindflaneur.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/02/gustave_caillebotte_paris_street_rainy_day_1877_wiki.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Finally, Romantic Justice For Little Women&#8217;s Jo</title>
		<link>http://reliablyuncomfortable.com/2013/03/27/finally-romantic-justice-for-little-womens-jo/</link>
		<comments>http://reliablyuncomfortable.com/2013/03/27/finally-romantic-justice-for-little-womens-jo/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 06:01:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sandra Stephens</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Bird's Eye View]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Essays]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dorky fan fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[essay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jo March]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[little women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[louisa may alcott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marmee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[short fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[short stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unrequited love]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://reliablyuncomfortable.com/?p=698</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Though it may surprise many who assume they know me well, I am a romantic at heart; whether I was already that way before reading Little Women, or whether Ms. Alcott&#8217;s tome guided me to this trajectory I do not know. What I do know is, I still remember the exact day I read Little [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=698&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://reliablyuncomfortable.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/little-women.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image alignleft" id="i-1072" alt="Image" src="http://reliablyuncomfortable.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/little-women.jpg?w=293&#038;h=409" width="293" height="409" /></a>Though it may surprise many who assume they know me well, I am a romantic at heart; whether I was already that way before reading Little Women, or whether Ms. Alcott&#8217;s tome guided me to this trajectory I do not know.</p>
<p>What I do know is, I still remember the exact day I read Little Women for the first time. I was in seventh grade, just turned twelve.  I read the book sprawled on my orange and yellow and brown patchwork bedspread, or tilted back to a dangerous degree in the nubby yellow corduroy rocking chair, feet braced on the wobbly end table with reading lamp.</p>
<p>I read in Dad&#8217;s Lazy-Boy Recliner, after he had gone to bed, and sometimes on the top step of the basement steps, or the back porch if the concrete was warmed from the sun.  Often I read at night in bed, sometimes with a flashlight under the covers but more often propped up on my right elbow, the page illuminated by the streetlight shining in my bedroom window.</p>
<p>I immediately developed a love/hate relationship with that book.  I loved most of it, but I hated one specific part of it &#8211; a big part of it, a *central* part of it.</p>
<p>I often forget the names of the authors of books (o, irony), but in this case, I flipped to the frontispiece of the book to burn the name Louisa May Alcott forever into my memory, under the heading &#8220;On My Sh*t List Forever&#8221;.  Because how could any right thinking writer imagine characters like Laurie and Jo into being, and then keep them apart?  How? They were so clearly made for each other!</p>
<p>Yet instead of falling passionately into one another&#8217;s arms, and spending the next 50 years having crazy hot sex and arguments featuring flying crockery and raised voices and heaving bosoms and amused forbearance and  crazy hot make up sex, we the readers are asked to accept Jo&#8217;s &#8220;wisdom&#8221;, confirmed by Laurie&#8217;s out of touch geezer grandfather, that she and Laurie are too much alike to be truly happy together.</p>
<p>After Jo turns Laurie down he proves the depth of his love by the depth of his depression which everyone confuses with maturity and approves of.  Passion tamed by rejection, Laurie finds solace in the lowered expectations of a marriage with the beautiful but insipid Amy, (who always got what she wanted) while Jo gets stuck with crotchety old German Professor Baher, aka Grody Old Graybeard, much to the indignation of my 12 year old romantic&#8217;s heart.</p>
<p>Do not evoke the movie for me &#8211; the movie director, like every one else on the planet, loved Jo and wanted her to be with Laurie too, and so felt compelled to cast  young virile good looking Gabriel Byrne as the Professor, the better to rationalize that Jo did not get the short old gray end of the stick that Alcott dealt her.</p>
<p>So don&#8217;t tell me about the movie, b/c the movie is not reflecting who the Professor really was, the Professor that Alcott wrote about, who was old country Germanic and probably a little portly and I think even walked with a limp and smelled of moth balls&#8212; and was most assuredly NOT deserving of Jo and most of all he was NOT LAURIE.</p>
<p>Laurie and Jo were my introduction to unrequited love.  That same year I found Little Women in our home library, our teacher took us to see Romeo and Juliet at an afternoon matinee. The movie starred Olivia Wilde and Leonard Whiting, who were memorably young and beautiful and spoke in Shakespearean verse, which we noticed when we weren&#8217;t embarrassed to giggles by Leonard Whiting&#8217;s partial nude scene in which we saw his bare  bottom which my friends and I immediately dubbed a &#8220;Montague&#8221; (and which I privately noted with seventh grade surprise, was as smooth and hairless and pretty as a girl&#8217;s).</p>
<p>Of the two girls with ill-fated luck in love it was Jo&#8217;s story that I took most to heart.  Juliet&#8217;s story was tragic but she was beautiful and rich and privileged.  Her plight and fate were as unreal to me as her speech.</p>
<p>Jo, by contrast, was much more real to me. I fell in love with Jo not because she was a writer, but because she was so honest (which is what made her a good writer). The specific scene in which my love was born: when Jo cuts her hair and sells it in order to help out the family, which, with the father off to war, is near starvation. She falters before she does it, and then crushes her own vanity and does it anyway.</p>
<p>And when she hands the wad of cash over to her mother (Marmee dearest), and everyone wonders aloud how she came to have so much money, she pulls off her hat to reveal her shorn head, and her lovely (and somewhat vain and shallow) older sister Meg cries out &#8220;Oh, Jo!  Your one beauty!&#8221;  A sentiment that Jo tacitly agrees with but does not take to heart &#8211; a feat that seemed utterly impossible to my 12 year old self.</p>
<p>I loved Jo fiercely from that moment on (and hated Meg), and I never recovered when she turned down, for no good reason that I could see,  Laurie&#8217;s final impetuous request to love him, to marry him, and dance into eternity in some truly awesome silk ballgowns. I read the book over and over and Beth always wasted away, Amy always came infuriatingly into her own, and Jo never ends up with the one man that could have supported and nurtured her crazy writing talent so that it grew wild, covering their mansion with green vines and exotic tropical flowers and palm leaves big as a man&#8217;s head where birds the color of jewels spoke to startled visitors in the parlor.   Jo ends up with geriatric old Mr. Germanic Graybeard.</p>
<p>After one of my many re-readings of Little Women, and after learning of the dorky  but sometimes necessary practice of fan fiction, I immediately undertook to rewrite the ending (some wrongs just need to be (re)writed/righted), giving Jo the man she really wants, needs, and deserves.  I hope Miss Alcott isn&#8217;t turning over in her grave; rather, I hope she sitting up and clapping, glad that someone finally righted the grievous wrong she did  to Jo, Laurie, and Love itself.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;" align="center"><a href="http://reliablyuncomfortable.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/flourish1.jpg"><img class=" wp-image aligncenter" id="i-717" alt="Image" src="http://reliablyuncomfortable.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/flourish1.jpg?w=273&#038;h=88" width="273" height="88" /></a>Jo sat in the parlor, Laurie’s impassioned plea – could she, would she? in her hand.   Her heart was racing, and to calm herself she looked about with some satisfaction.  The parlor was dim; it was early evening, the quiet time before dinner preparations would begin.  She could hear Marmee humming over her sewing in the upstairs garret where the light was still clear.</p>
<p>A tinkling at the pianoforte brought a smile to her lips; dear Beth was composing again.  How good it was to see her recovering day by day!  The sickness that had cast its frightening gray pall over the household was receding like so much remembered fog.   Now the house was airy and light with music, and who better to author the tune of a happy, healthy future than Beth herself?  Jo relished this time – after the worst but with the best still to come.  She wanted to slow the days down and sip from them as if at some rich and aromatic cup.</p>
<p>“I suppose this is growing up,” she thought to herself.  “What we long for is suddenly here, and it is only then that we realize the beauty was in the journey as much as the destination.”</p>
<p>She looked again at the letter in her hand, the words themselves seeming to leap from the page with all of Laurie’s impetuous energy.   She had been sorely tempted to tell him that she was sorry, he would always be her dear Laurie but she decisively couldn’t, and wouldn’t.  The words of the old man had been ringing loudly in her ears – that she and Laurie were too much alike, and a household of peace could never be theirs.</p>
<p>But then the roses had begun to bloom again in Beth’s pale cheeks, a sight so shocking but at the same time welcome that Jo had spent the next several nights in the garret, unable to sleep, feverishly writing.  Marmee and Meg had gently given her space, assuming she was  simply scribbling away at another story that would provide the household with a turkey, perhaps, or a silk scarf for Marmee to wear to Easter Mass.</p>
<p>But for once, Jo was not scribbling a story. She was writing her thoughts down; she was, in fact, writing her thoughts into being.  It had started as a letter to Laurie and ended up a letter to herself, and in it she found many surprises, doors that opened with a creak and a groan, and not least of all, Love.</p>
<p>You and I are so much alike, she had begun, picturing her dear boy in Venice. She saw him quite clearly in her mind’s eye; his long-lashed eyes with their lazy regard that could flare in an instant to mischief, or (she thought with a tremor) passion.  She imagined him seated at a ball, his long legs, elegant in breeches, stretched carelessly before him while around him dazzlingly beautiful women circled him in their fine silks and puffed crinolines like anxious flowers.  She imagined the curly forelock springing free from his pomaded hair, a silent acknowledgement of her secret regard.</p>
<p>We are so much alike, she’d written. We are so much alike. And then the words came pouring forth, words she’d never dared think, words she didn’t know were even in her vocabulary, so passionate they were.</p>
<p>You, she wrote, savoring the word that had come to mean only one person.  You. You understand me as no other has ever understood me.  You alone have read my writing and understood the words as if you were reading them inscribed on my very heart.  You heard my characters cry for love and knew that they spoke in a voice that is mine, and with words that would be mine if only I had the courage to speak them.   You know that for me, to write is to breathe, and that the little notes I have sent you each day were tiny lifelines fluttering from my fingers to your window.  You have felt my heart pound when we dance, and pretended not to know that it was the nearness of your dear face, and not our exertions, that had me so flushed.  Laurie, we are so much alike, we are as one, you are my soul and my heart. I would be with you whatever the cost, however you wish. I care not for your riches, only be generous with your love.  My dear, my love, I do not fear poverty or age or  sickness when I think of a life with you; only silence. Let us pledge never to be silent with one another, but speak always in the language we have found together, the language of two souls in true understanding.</p>
<p>In a passion of impatience to know how you read these words, a torture of trembling that I have waited too long to know my own  heart,</p>
<p>I am yours, ever,</p>
<p>Jo</p>
<p>{There.  I feel much better now. }</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/698/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/698/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=698&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://reliablyuncomfortable.com/2013/03/27/finally-romantic-justice-for-little-womens-jo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>41</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/97c08d2f1a7b26865d90381c7d6c66a6?s=96&#38;d=monsterid&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">slstephens</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://reliablyuncomfortable.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/little-women.jpg?w=293" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://reliablyuncomfortable.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/flourish1.jpg?w=650" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Matzo Man</title>
		<link>http://amapofcalifornia.wordpress.com/2013/03/27/matzo-man/</link>
		<comments>http://amapofcalifornia.wordpress.com/2013/03/27/matzo-man/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 04:16:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>sinecostan</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jewish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Judaism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Passover]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://amapofcalifornia.wordpress.com/?p=251</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Matz-o, matz-o man, I want to be a matzo man . . . I remember my mother dancing in the kitchen while we sang Passover lyrics of our own invention to the tune of the Village People’s “Macho Man.” Matzah, the crunchy, unleavened cracker that we eat during Passover, gets a bad rap. We make [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=251&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://amapofcalifornia.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/matzah.jpg"><img src="http://amapofcalifornia.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/matzah.jpg?w=276&#038;h=183" alt="matzah" width="276" height="183" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-252" /></a><br />
                       <em>Matz-o, matz-o man, I want to be a matzo man . . .</em></p>
<p>I remember my mother dancing in the kitchen while we sang Passover lyrics of our own invention to the tune of the Village People’s “Macho Man.”</p>
<p>Matzah, the crunchy, unleavened cracker that we eat during Passover, gets a bad rap.  We make fun of “<em>Pesakh</em> bread,” we gripe and moan about having to eat it for eight days, about it causing us to gain weight, about ending up constipated.</p>
<p>But when it counts, matzah does get the respect that it deserves.  The English word “Passover” refers to the tenth and final plague that the Lord visited upon Pharaoh, king of Egypt, when he repeatedly reneged on his promise to emancipate the Jewish people from slavery.  While every Egyptian household had its dead, we were spared when the plague “passed over” Jewish homes.  In Hebrew, however, the word for Passover is <em>Pesakh</em>, which actually refers to the Paschal lamb that we were commanded to prepare and eat the night before our great escape from Egypt.  But in the liturgy, the holiday is referred to as <em>hag ha’matzot hazeh</em>, “the festival of matzah that we now celebrate.”  Thus, matzah is the very definition of the holiday.</p>
<p>When setting the Seder table on the first night of Passover in my parents’ home, the place of honor in the center of the table was always occupied by my grandmother’s <em>matzah tash</em>.  This was a white cloth matzah cover, composed of three compartments to contain the three sheets of matzah used during the service.  The outside of the <em>matzah tash</em> featured some of the most beautiful embroidery I have ever seen.  Bordered in purple grapes and green grape leaves, a large orange circle contained the Hebrew words, also rendered in orange, for each of the items on the ceremonial Seder plate.  Right next to Grandma’s <em>matzah tash</em> would be the Seder plate itself, featuring the symbolic burnt bone and burnt egg, as well as the crunchy celery, hot horseradish, Romaine lettuce and sweet <em>haroseth</em> that we eat during the Seder service.</p>
<p>Not only does the <em>matzah tash</em> protect the matzahs and prevent them from breaking into pieces and crumbs, but the white covering is a sign of purity and respect.  When the matzahs are removed from the <em>tash</em> during the Seder, it is something of a grand reveal, the centerpiece of the festival officially presented to our family and friends in attendance.  Then, of course, we get to eat the matzahs in all their crunchy glory.</p>
<p>Early in the ceremony, we break the middle matzah in two and, traditionally, the children at the table hide one half of it.  Later, when it is time to eat the missing piece of matzah, the adults pretend to search high and low for it, without trying too hard.  Shrieking with laughter at the adults’ “ineptitude,” the kids “ransom” the matzah for gifts or money.  In some families, considerable negotiation ensues.  This is followed by the second reveal of the evening, in which the kids remove the half matzah from its hiding place and the adults praise them for concealing it so well.</p>
<p>The combination of the respect we accord to matzah and the merriment we derive from it is nothing short of amazing.  It teaches us to place things in perspective, that it is possible for us to appropriately appreciate the gifts in our lives without taking ourselves too seriously.</p>
<p>It makes me proud to be a matz-o man.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/251/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/251/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=251&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://amapofcalifornia.wordpress.com/2013/03/27/matzo-man/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/efb7628b68f06f84c630062ca1b36266?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sinecostan</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://amapofcalifornia.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/matzah.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">matzah</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>One Minute Film School</title>
		<link>http://theuprightmonkey.wordpress.com/2013/03/26/one-minute-film-school/</link>
		<comments>http://theuprightmonkey.wordpress.com/2013/03/26/one-minute-film-school/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 06:32:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>theuprightmonkey</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[The Search for Truth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Filmmaking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Screenwriting]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://theuprightmonkey.wordpress.com/?p=233</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Today, I had a fella send me this message on LinkedIn: Hi Mr. Kandborg. My name is *****. I have a story idea that I would like to direct and was hoping if you would like to work with me. I been trying to get in touch with producers but have no luck. Please let [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=233&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://theuprightmonkey.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/stop-watch-1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-314" alt="Stop Watch 1" src="http://theuprightmonkey.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/stop-watch-1.jpg?w=275&#038;h=183" width="275" height="183" /></a><a href="http://theuprightmonkey.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/unmasking_jesse-scaturro-sculpture.jpg"><br />
</a>Today, I had a fella send me this message on LinkedIn:</p>
<p><em>Hi Mr. Kandborg. My name is *****. I have a story idea that I would like to direct and was hoping if you would like to work with me. I been trying to get in touch with producers but have no luck. Please let me know. </em></p>
<p>Typos aside (I certainly hope they&#8217;re typos), rather than dismiss the request out of hand as vague, incomplete and, well, odd, I decided to offer some suggestions since countless numbers of them were percolating in my head, unbidden. I&#8217;ve subsequently decided to post them here because I feel they may have some universal value to aspiring film makers everywhere.</p>
<p><i>Hi, *****. Sorry to hear that you&#8217;re having trouble getting in touch with producers. Maybe you aren&#8217;t being clear with what you&#8217;re looking for. You say you have an idea. Do you have a script? It&#8217;s unlikely that any established producer would be interested without one. As I like to say, having an idea for a movie is like having an idea for a painting. &#8220;Flowers!&#8221; Doesn&#8217;t mean much.</i></p>
<p><a href="http://theuprightmonkey.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/sunflowers-1888.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-316" alt="sunflowers-1888" src="http://theuprightmonkey.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/sunflowers-1888.jpg?w=122&#038;h=150" width="122" height="150" /></a></p>
<p><i><a href="http://theuprightmonkey.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/vs.png"><img class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-317" alt="vs" src="http://theuprightmonkey.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/vs.png?w=150&#038;h=150" width="150" height="150" /></a><a href="http://theuprightmonkey.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/bad-flower.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-318" alt="Bad Flower" src="http://theuprightmonkey.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/bad-flower.jpg?w=99&#038;h=150" width="99" height="150" /></a><br />
</i></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><i>If you don&#8217;t have a script, write one. </i></p>
<p><i>If you don&#8217;t know how, learn. </i></p>
<p><i>If you have no talent for writing, find someone who does. </i></p>
<p><i>If you have a script and no one wants to produce it (because really, why should they?), produce it yourself. </i></p>
<p><i>If you can&#8217;t raise a lot of money, make it for a little (I know of features that were made for $5,000). </i></p>
<p><i>If you can&#8217;t raise any, write something else, either something better, something cheaper or something shorter. Maybe all three.</i></p>
<p><i>If you want to direct a movie, direct a movie. It&#8217;s never been easier. </i></p>
<p><i>If you&#8217;ve already directed one, direct another. </i></p>
<p><i>If you&#8217;re any good, someone will notice, believe me. </i></p>
<p><i>If you&#8217;re not, please stop.</i></p>
<p><i>I hope this helps. Good luck. And remember: if you want to work in the circus, you&#8217;d better get used to crazy people, anxiety and the smell of shit. Embrace the shit.</i></p>
<p><em>All the best,</em></p>
<p><em>Mark</em></p>
<p><a href="http://theuprightmonkey.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/tiger.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-337" alt="Tiger" src="http://theuprightmonkey.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/tiger.jpg?w=580&#038;h=435" width="580" height="435" /></a></p>
<p>I&#8217;ve thought all of these things when confronted with the boundless (and borderline insane) blind enthusiasm of one aspiring filmmaker or another who has, usually inadvisably, appointed himself the next Tarantino simply because he really likes movies, even though he may not be able to articulate, like, <em>why</em>. But I&#8217;ve rarely said them. Partly because I&#8217;m fairly sure they don&#8217;t really want to hear any of it, but mostly because I can&#8217;t bear to see the dreams of a fellow human being, however misguided, recoil and disintegrate before my eyes like a vampire hit by a sunbeam.</p>
<p>And I find nothing kills a crazy dream faster than a brush with reality.</p>
<p>Which is why I like to keep mine tucked away safely in the dark. On the few occasions where I&#8217;ve found the courage, or more accurately the hubris, to actually ask for a reality check like my new friend *****, the subsequent slivers of light have mottled the surface of my fragile, sacred passenger just enough to render me mute, confused and ultimately, immobile.</p>
<p>So the surprise here is that my advice to ***** is really advice to myself.<a href="http://theuprightmonkey.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/m-fritz-lang-6250_5.jpg"><br />
</a></p>
<p><a href="http://theuprightmonkey.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/m-fritz-lang-6250_5.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-322" alt="M-fritz-lang-6250_5" src="http://theuprightmonkey.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/m-fritz-lang-6250_5.jpg?w=300&#038;h=226" width="300" height="226" /></a></p>
<p>Maybe this time I&#8217;ll have the wisdom to listen.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>[NOTE: If this or any of my previous posts have encouraged you to think a thought (or hear a Who) you might otherwise have not, go ahead and comment, share or subscribe. Go on...]</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/233/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/233/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=233&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://theuprightmonkey.wordpress.com/2013/03/26/one-minute-film-school/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/462a7de68ac18522697401d00a5e3814?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">theuprightmonkey</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theuprightmonkey.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/stop-watch-1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Stop Watch 1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theuprightmonkey.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/sunflowers-1888.jpg?w=122" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sunflowers-1888</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theuprightmonkey.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/vs.png?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">vs</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theuprightmonkey.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/bad-flower.jpg?w=99" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Bad Flower</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theuprightmonkey.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/tiger.jpg?w=580" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Tiger</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theuprightmonkey.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/m-fritz-lang-6250_5.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">M-fritz-lang-6250_5</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>You\&#8217;re Gonna Carry That Weight; Carry That Weight a Long Time</title>
		<link>http://lucysfootball.com/2013/03/23/youre-gonna-carry-that-weight-carry-that-weight-a-long-time/</link>
		<comments>http://lucysfootball.com/2013/03/23/youre-gonna-carry-that-weight-carry-that-weight-a-long-time/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 15:45:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>lucysfootball</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[angry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[childhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[famous people]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[I hate people]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[issues]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[judgments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kevin Smith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fat-shaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gender]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[men]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shame]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thin-shaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://lucysfootball.com/?p=7842</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I was a skinny kid. Photos of me from back then are all pigtails and smeary glasses and I&#8217;m usually covered in mud. And I&#8217;m sometimes brandishing things like frogs or buckets of mucky water, for whatever reason. I probably had a plan for those buckets. Maybe I was going to put the frog in [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=7842&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I was a skinny kid. Photos of me from back then are all pigtails and smeary glasses and I&#8217;m usually covered in mud. And I&#8217;m sometimes brandishing things like frogs or buckets of mucky water, for whatever reason. I probably had a plan for those buckets. Maybe I was going to put the frog in them. I don&#8217;t know.</p>
<p>Then puberty hit. You can&#8217;t fight science, people. I come from hearty peasant stock on both sides of my family. Dad&#8217;s side are all, in his words, &#8220;built like tops &#8211; big on the top, skinny on the bottom.&#8221; (I attempted to explain to him that&#8217;s not exactly how tops work, and also we don&#8217;t spin very well, but he was all &#8220;WE ARE LIKE TOPS!&#8221; so who am I to argue with him?) and my mom&#8217;s side are all built like the Goddess of Willendorf. Curvy doesn&#8217;t even begin to explain it. Genetics decided I needed a little of both, apparently.</p>
<p><a href="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/goddess.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7847" alt="" src="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/goddess.jpg?w=203&#038;h=248" width="203" height="248" /></a></p>
<p>Now, Dad had been heavy growing up, and teased about it mercilessly. He lost quite a bit of weight when he married my mother (who was, and remains, thin; she&#8217;s the only one in her family that is.) Dad saw that I was starting to gain weight and immediately feared that I was going to be teased about it at school.</p>
<p>His solution? Constantly watch everything I put in my mouth, tell me how disgusting being fat was, tell me I needed to be working out and/or being active every single minute of every single day, tell me I was never going to find anyone to love me if I was fat, and call me things like &#8220;elephant.&#8221; If I got upset about this, he was genuinely confused. &#8220;I just want you to be happy,&#8221; he&#8217;d say. &#8220;I just want you to be pretty and thin.&#8221;</p>
<p>Now, I don&#8217;t know what size you&#8217;re imagining me in high school, but if I remember correctly, I was about a size twelve. A twelve. I was probably around&#8230;oh, I don&#8217;t know. 140 pounds, maybe? 150? Just about the thinnest I&#8217;ve ever been in my adulthood, anyway. I certainly wasn&#8217;t fat. And I&#8217;m fairly tall. 5&#8217;8.</p>
<p>I WAS COMPLETELY NORMAL.</p>
<p>However, years and years of being told, by the person you love and admire most in the whole world, that you are ugly, fat and worthless, take their toll. My self-esteem, never overly good to begin with, wasn&#8217;t getting much better.</p>
<p><a href="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/fatshaming.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-7848" alt="" src="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/fatshaming.jpg?w=300&#038;h=139" width="300" height="139" /></a></p>
<p>Senior year, I was tired of being so ugly and fat (although I was neither &#8211; I look at photos of myself from that time and think &#8220;GOOD GRIEF, WHY DIDN&#8221;T YOU REALIZE HOW GORGEOUS YOU WERE?!?!&#8221;) and went on a crash diet. This diet was basically a bowl of cereal at breakfast and a can of Chinese vegetables at dinner. Sometimes some chicken. No lunch. This was what I ate every day for about 8 months. I worked out for hours at a time daily. I lost about fifty pounds. I could see my hipbones and my ribs and my cheekbones. My collarbones were so prominent I would sometimes accidentally bump them and leave bruises.</p>
<p>It was the first time my father ever told me I was beautiful. He followed it with &#8220;See? All you had to do was lose weight. I knew you were beautiful underneath that.&#8221;</p>
<p>I was starving. I had headaches constantly. I was tired all the time. But I was THIN. Boys were paying attention to me. One of my teachers told me, &#8220;Don&#8217;t you dare ever gain weight again. Don&#8217;t you DARE&#8221; which at the time I was all &#8220;Aw, nice!&#8221; and now, looking back, I&#8217;m all, &#8220;Um. CREEPSTER!&#8221;</p>
<p>I think you can see where this is going. Can anyone maintain that kind of diet and exercise regimen in the long-term? And not get scurvy? And not go CRAZY? I mean, I couldn&#8217;t eat ANYTHING. I was counting the calories in CORNSTARCH. I&#8217;m not even kidding you about this. This is not a way to live a life.</p>
<p>I gained the weight back over about a year. I felt terrible shame. I&#8217;d let everyone down. I was disgusting. I was ugly and fat again. I had no self-esteem; I didn&#8217;t like to go out in public, I didn&#8217;t like to go out with my friends, I didn&#8217;t date because who would have me? I drank a lot, though. Liquid courage, right? Mmm-hmm. Works every time, except when you start needing it for everything, ever. Like getting out of bed in the morning, or to get to sleep at night. Or for everything in between.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve fluctuated in weight ever since. Sometimes I&#8217;m heavier; sometimes I&#8217;m lighter. And here&#8217;s the thing; as I age, it matters less to me. I still don&#8217;t love what I see in the mirror every day; I still see photos of myself and think, &#8220;Good grief, that&#8217;s an unflattering photo.&#8221; I still have residual shame. I still think &#8220;If only I was thinner, life would be easier, in a million different ways.&#8221; But it&#8217;s not a daily thing. It&#8217;s not even all that often anymore.</p>
<p><a href="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/radicalidea.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7849" alt="" src="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/radicalidea.jpg?w=193&#038;h=261" width="193" height="261" /></a></p>
<p>And before you start to hate him, Dad understands, and has repeatedly apologized, for what he did when I was younger. I often think most of parenting is a fly-by-the-seat-of-your-pants affair. He really, truly thought he was doing the right thing. He thought he was stopping me from the ridicule he&#8217;d experienced as a teen. He didn&#8217;t realize &#8211; and did anyone, back then? &#8211; the long-standing effect that kind of treatment would have on my psyche. I&#8217;ve forgiven him. He doesn&#8217;t say a word now. And he&#8217;s said, without prompting, many times since, that I&#8217;m beautiful &#8211; no matter what size I am. He loves his daughter.</p>
<p>We live in a culture where it is not allowed (well, it still happens, but it&#8217;s not appropriate) to make racial jokes, or jokes about someone&#8217;s sexuality, or mental illness. But we&#8217;re still allowed to make fat jokes. Because fat jokes are funny. Fat PEOPLE are funny, right? Because, well, we CHOSE this. We chose this because we eat ALL the Twinkies and chips and cake and pie and sit around all day doing nothing. We chose this, and because we are fat, we are lazy and we also smell. Of course we do! And sometimes we fall. Ha ha! How funny!</p>
<p><a href="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/fathatebingo.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-7850" alt="" src="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/fathatebingo.jpg?w=210&#038;h=300" width="210" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>So the best thing to do is make fun of us. To shame us. Because, <a href="http://www.inquisitr.com/493779/fat-shaming-may-prevent-obesity-prominent-bioethicist-says/">as this VERY scientific study proves</a>, it&#8217;s the only way to make us get off our lazy asses and get thin. Thin and therefore healthy. Oh, because, I don&#8217;t know if you&#8217;re aware &#8211; if you&#8217;re fat, you&#8217;re immediately unhealthy. There&#8217;s no such thing as a healthy fat person. We&#8217;re all one HoHo away from our first (or second, or third, or last) coronary. So the thing to do is shame us. According to this &#8220;prominent bioethicist&#8221; (I don&#8217;t see &#8220;ethics&#8221; coming into this at all) what you should say to any fat people you know, I mean, if you care about them at all, is “If you are overweight or obese, are you pleased with the way that you look?” Because of COURSE they&#8217;re not! And they just didn&#8217;t realize it until you shamed them! Oh, what a favor you are doing for them. They will thank you on the finish line of their first triathalon! They will shout your name from the top of Kilimanjaro!</p>
<p>Or they might tell you to shut your nosy piehole. Because I&#8217;m going to tell you something right now, and if you take anything away from this, I want it to be this.</p>
<p>My body, his body, her body, their bodies &#8211; anyone&#8217;s body but your own &#8211; ARE NONE OF YOUR FUCKING BUSINESS.</p>
<p><a href="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/business.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7851" alt="" src="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/business.jpg?w=255&#038;h=197" width="255" height="197" /></a></p>
<p>I don&#8217;t care if you&#8217;re fat-shaming them, thin-shaming them (yes, it exists, <a href="http://booksnobbery.wordpress.com/2013/01/10/ladies-can-we-all-just-stop-being-bitches-for-two-seconds/">please read sj&#8217;s amazing post about it, and the comments</a>, and I know from personal experience, as I have a dear loved one who has constantly been picked on about being too thin, which she can help JUST about as much as I can help my body shape, so it&#8217;s real) or ANYTHING shaming-them, or if you say you&#8217;re doing it because you&#8217;re worried about their health, or what, exactly, your impetus for putting your nose in someone else&#8217;s business is. You have no right. None. You have no right to tell them they should lose weight (unless you are their doctor, and even then, sometimes, it gets worrisome, because there are some doctors who prescribe weightloss as an easy out for everything from asthma to a sprained toe because they don&#8217;t treat the patient, they just see a fat person and think, &#8220;I KNOW WHAT&#8217;S WRONG IT IS FATNESS!&#8221;); you have no right to say things about their lifestyle choices, their clothing choices, who they&#8217;re dating, what they&#8217;re eating, how loud they&#8217;re talking, or anything whatsoever. Keep your eyes on your own test, buckaroo. I&#8217;m sure you have something you&#8217;re not proud of. Would you like someone walking up to you and saying, &#8220;Man, that&#8217;s a huge nose you have there. You should get that surgically reduced. You know, for health reasons.&#8221; Or, &#8220;I noticed you have a very small penis, Man I&#8217;m About to Have Sex With. Have you thought about getting that surgically enhanced? You know, for health reasons?&#8221; IT WOULD BE THE SAME THING.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s some Fun With Fat-Shaming. Don&#8217;t even think I didn&#8217;t research the hell out of this.</p>
<p>First, we have Kate Upton. Who is, I think we can all agree, STUNNINGLY GORGEOUS.</p>
<div id="attachment_7843" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 294px"><a href="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/kate.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-7843" alt="She also really likes bikini shots, so it was hard to find a photo of her clothed. Hell, good for her. She is smoking hot." src="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/kate.jpg?w=284&#038;h=177" width="284" height="177" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">She also really likes bikini shots, so it was hard to find a photo of her clothed. Hell, good for her. She is smoking hot.</p></div>
<p>Well! Were you also aware she is &#8220;well-marbled,&#8221; &#8220;thick,&#8221; &#8220;vulgar,&#8221; and &#8211; this one&#8217;s my favorite &#8211; a &#8220;little piggie?&#8221; Or &#8211; well, how about a whole paragraph of hate? Sure!</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">Huge thighs, NO waist, big fat floppy boobs, terrible body definition – she looks like a squishy brick. Is this what American women are “striving” for now? The lazy, lardy look? Have we really gotten so fat in this country that Kate is the best we can aim for? Sorry, but: <em>eww</em>!</p>
<p>YES! She has been called out as too fat to model by a <a href="http://www.skinnygossip.com/kate-upton-is-well-marbled/#more-2233">VERY reputable blog site called Skinny Gossip</a>. Two things I loathe! People who judge others&#8217; bodies and gossip! (Also, she tagged the post with &#8220;fatties&#8221; and &#8220;thunder thighs,&#8221; because, well, why not?)</p>
<p>Guess why she&#8217;s not model-material? BECAUSE SHE&#8217;S NORMAL-HUMAN SIZED. Well, no. She&#8217;s actually quite a bit less than normal human sized, as normal humans are, what, a size 12 now? 14? Something like that? I don&#8217;t think she&#8217;s that size. But she&#8217;s not waif-thin, and apparently, Skinny Gossip thinks that&#8217;s what size you have to be to model clothing.</p>
<p>Psst, Skinny Gossip, MIND YOUR OWN BUSINESS. She&#8217;s stunning. And it can&#8217;t possibly make you feel any better about yourself to call people pigs, can it? Really? Do you sleep well at night knowing you put something like that out there in the world? That kind of hate?</p>
<p>Next: <a href="http://bitchmagazine.org/post/cvs-drugstore-chain-unveils-new-employee-diet-plan-fat-shaming-and-a-600-fine">employees at CVS will now be forced to take a BMI test and a blood-glucose screen to remain on their healthcare plan, or risk a fine</a>. Why?</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">The company’s rationale? Coercing employees to submit to health testing will provide incentive for workers to get—and stay—in shape.</p>
<p>Huh. &#8220;Coercing.&#8221; Forcing, really, because the fine is $600 and they don&#8217;t pay much above minimum to work at CVS. And what happens once you take the test? Do you have to see a counselor about your totally fat fatness? Are you told if you don&#8217;t lose weight, you&#8217;ll be let go? Are your test results posted in the breakroom next to a photo of a bag of Cheetos with a red circle and a line through it? WHO KNOWS.</p>
<p>Or, how about, let&#8217;s fat-shame our children with this new ad campaign? Because there&#8217;s nothing that kids need more than to be shamed. I mean, it&#8217;s worked out so well for me, right?</p>
<p><a href="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/children.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-7844" alt="" src="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/children.jpg?w=300&#038;h=300" width="300" height="300" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://everydayfeminism.com/2013/02/whats-wrong-with-fat-shaming/">Please read the article that accompanies this photo.</a> It&#8217;s kickass. It has excellent examples of fat-shaming. HEARTBREAKING examples. And, sadly, TRUE examples. People think it is ok to walk up to perfect strangers in the grocery store and QUESTION THEIR FOOD CHOICES.</p>
<p>(True story: I had a woman come up to me in the grocery store and tell me she worked for Herbalife and they had an excellent line of diet pills I might like to try. First thought: shame. Second thought: WHO THE FUCK DO YOU THINK YOU ARE. Second thought won out over first thought; I told her I was not at all interested in a pyramid scheme for products that don&#8217;t work in the first place, and I was sorry she felt the need to walk up to strangers and judge their body type, and walked away. She was offering them to the next woman that walked past as I checked out. So apparently my words meant nothing.)</p>
<p>So, anyway. Yes, that&#8217;s an ad campaign for (well, against, I guess) childhood obesity, targeting overweight children. Because they probably aren&#8217;t aware they&#8217;re fat. So let&#8217;s do a whole ad campaign for it. That&#8217;s a good way to help kids with positive self-esteem. Way to go, guys.</p>
<p><a href="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/children1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7852" alt="" src="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/children1.jpg?w=247&#038;h=204" width="247" height="204" /></a></p>
<p>Of course, there&#8217;s also good old Southwest Airlines, who expect their fat passengers to spring for two seats. And even their not-so-fat passengers. Whoever THEY deem as a little too fat. They SAY it&#8217;s if the passenger can&#8217;t put the armrests down, but <a href="http://www.nydailynews.com/entertainment/gossip/director-kevin-smith-fat-fly-southwest-clerks-writer-director-tweets-rage-airline-article-1.194397">as Kevin Smith found out a few years ago</a>, that&#8217;s not it at all &#8211; it&#8217;s racial profiling, only with your weight. It&#8217;s fat-profiling. He was able to put his armrests down; the passengers on either side of him told the flight attendant they had plenty of room. They still kicked him off the plane. And when he got back on a later flight that they hurriedly put him on once they realized who he was and that he was tweeting millions of people about this practice, they fat-profiled another person, then put her in his row, so she&#8217;d tell him about it, and he&#8217;d know it wasn&#8217;t just him, and feel better.</p>
<div id="attachment_7859" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 210px"><a href="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/smith.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-7859" alt="DEFINITELY taking up way too much room. He should have purchased the WHOLE DAMN PLANE. *eyeroll*" src="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/smith.jpg?w=200&#038;h=267" width="200" height="267" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">DEFINITELY taking up way too much room. He should have purchased the WHOLE DAMN PLANE. *eyeroll*</p></div>
<p>Yes! Because nothing makes us feel better than to be shamed in front of a crowd of people than to do it to someone else. NOTHING. (I read his book<em> Tough Shit</em> recently which went in detail into the incident, and my heart just broke for him. Because no matter what you think of Kevin Smith &#8211; you all know I think he&#8217;s fantastic, but you can hate him if you want, just don&#8217;t tell me about it, ok? &#8211; when that happened, he was just an average guy, being fat-shamed in front of a full airplane of people. Worse, he was a FAMOUS guy being fat-shamed in front of a crowd of people, and if it was an average guy, it might be a laugh or two, but with a famous person, it&#8217;s news, you know? He took control of the news and labeled it &#8220;too fat to fly&#8221; himself &#8211; he&#8217;s very good at self-deprecating &#8211; but it hurt. Of course it did. Because no matter who you are, where you are in the world, being shamed for your body size is not something you can laugh off. It just isn&#8217;t. The shame should be on Southwest Airlines, not the people they&#8217;re profiling.)</p>
<p>Then there&#8217;s this. I can&#8217;t embed a Facebook thread, so sadly, <a href="https://www.facebook.com/everydayfeminism/posts/153150451511589">you will have to click</a>. Here&#8217;s a screenshot, though, because pretty pictures, right?</p>
<p><a href="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/article-about-how.png"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-7845" alt="" src="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/article-about-how.png?w=300&#038;h=145" width="300" height="145" /></a></p>
<p>Now, you have to click to see the comments. The comments are really what makes this. Because this STARTS OUT as normal, then this person shows up who hates fat people. HATES THEM. Only, no no! She doesn&#8217;t HATE them. She has MANY FAT FRIENDS! (Does this sound at all like someone who makes a lot of racist comments, then says, &#8220;What? I&#8217;m not a racist! I have MANY MANY BLACK FRIENDS!&#8221; Yeah, to me, too.) So she starts writing things like &#8220;no, it&#8217;s a known fact that all fat people are unhealthy and many doctors refuse to operate on them because, well, they&#8217;ll just die on the table. Because, well, fat, you know?&#8221;</p>
<p>Don&#8217;t worry. There are some kickass commenters on there. They give her the smackdown. She doesn&#8217;t ever shut up, but they win intelligence. She doesn&#8217;t win anything but idiocy and mouth-flappery.</p>
<p>This is, by the way, called &#8220;concern-trolling.&#8221; It&#8217;s like being a troll, only you&#8217;re pretending it&#8217;s because you CARE. Isn&#8217;t that nice? A whole new way to be a douchecanoe!</p>
<p>Sara, from <a href="http://lamentsandlullabies.wordpress.com/">Laments and Lullabies</a>, wrote an amazing post recently about fat-shaming, which you all should read. Her post, and the terrible comments on that Facebook post up there, were what finally made me realize I needed to write my own post. <a href="http://lamentsandlullabies.wordpress.com/2013/03/12/the-fear-of-fat/">Here&#8217;s her post</a>. You should all a., read, and b., comment. Oh, and c., follow her blog.</p>
<p>There are more. There are so many more. But this is edging into way too many words for a Saturday territory, and also I&#8217;d like to get to bed at some point.</p>
<p>I will leave you with some bullet points. Because, who doesn&#8217;t like bullet points, am I right?</p>
<ul>
<li><span style="line-height:13px;">Other people&#8217;s bodies are none of your business. Keep your words off them. Unless you&#8217;re telling them they&#8217;re beautiful. Everyone likes that shit. Even if they pretend they don&#8217;t.</span></li>
<li>Pretending you&#8217;re &#8220;worried about someone&#8217;s health&#8221; is not an excuse for commenting on someone&#8217;s weight, whether they&#8217;re heavy or thin. Again, see the first bullet point. Even if they&#8217;re naked with you, their size is none of your business. Whose business is it then, Amy? THEIRS. No one&#8217;s but theirs.</li>
<li>Making fat jokes is a., not funny, and b., lazy. There are actual funny things in the world to point out. Like misspellings. Who doesn&#8217;t like a good misplaced apostrophe or missing comma? The answer to that is NO ONE.</li>
<li>To reiterate what we learned in the first bullet point: before making a comment about someone&#8217;s weight, please think the following quietly to yourself: &#8220;What is my least-favorite attribute. Now, would I like someone to loudly mention it and say it is ugly and/or unhealthy for me to have, and publicly shame me about it?&#8221; The answer to that question is always no. ALWAYS.</li>
<li>Also: if you think you are too fat, and everyone&#8217;s judging you, and you&#8217;re ugly, and OMG I CANNOT LEAVE THE HOUSE, guess what. No, seriously, guess. Hardly anyone even notices. The only people that do are assholes. And who cares what assholes think? I hope you don&#8217;t.</li>
<li>Finally: I&#8217;m going to tell you something I&#8217;ve learned in my old age. Ready? Shh, don&#8217;t share this one around, it&#8217;s kind of radical. WE ARE ALL BEAUTIFUL. I know! Every single last one of us. Fat. Thin. Tall. Short. We&#8217;re a lovely bunch of coconuts. Except &#8211; there is one thing that makes you ugly. Guess what that is? Hatefulness. Being hateful. You can&#8217;t be beautiful with hate in your mind, soul, or mouth. So get rid of that, and guess what? You&#8217;re gorgeous again. And everyone will see it. I can see it right now! Whoa, babe, dial that back, you&#8217;re blinding me with it.</li>
</ul>
<p>We&#8217;ve become a culture of shaming. We&#8217;re rape-shaming and we&#8217;re slut-shaming and we&#8217;re thin-shaming and we&#8217;re fat-shaming. It&#8217;s repulsive and this shit&#8217;s gotta stop. Like, immediately.</p>
<p>Stop shaming anyone. Including yourself. You are beautiful. The people around you are beautiful. No one should be shamed for how they look. The next time you look at yourself in the mirror, be amazed at how gorgeous you are. And tell the people around you how beautiful they are. Don&#8217;t allow them to blow it off and say things like, &#8220;Oh, I look like a cow in this top&#8221; or whatever, either. Nope. Not today, buckaroos. Tell them they&#8217;re beautiful AGAIN. Until they actually believe it.</p>
<p>Then, all of that stuff? Do quadruple that for your kids. Make sure your kids enter the world with the strongest self-esteem possible. They&#8217;re going to need it, and you can help them with that.</p>
<p>We might be surrounded by shame, but we can combat that with love. Is that the opposite of shame? Don&#8217;t care. For our purposes it is.</p>
<p>Love you guys. You&#8217;re gorgeous. Every last one of you.</p>
<p><a href="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/beautiful.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7853" alt="" src="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/beautiful.jpg?w=264&#038;h=191" width="264" height="191" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/7842/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/7842/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=7842&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://lucysfootball.com/2013/03/23/youre-gonna-carry-that-weight-carry-that-weight-a-long-time/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>214</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/cf9b29af05b1a3a436100c948157b6bc?s=96&#38;d=retro&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lucysfootball</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/goddess.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/fatshaming.jpg?w=300" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/radicalidea.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/fathatebingo.jpg?w=210" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/business.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/kate.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">She also really likes bikini shots, so it was hard to find a photo of her clothed. Hell, good for her. She is smoking hot.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/children.jpg?w=300" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/children1.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/smith.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DEFINITELY taking up way too much room. He should have purchased the WHOLE DAMN PLANE. *eyeroll*</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/article-about-how.png?w=300" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/beautiful.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Love, Loved, Light</title>
		<link>http://thecougarden.wordpress.com/2013/02/24/love-loved-light/</link>
		<comments>http://thecougarden.wordpress.com/2013/02/24/love-loved-light/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2013 19:29:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>denmother</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cougar Musings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Emotion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interpersonal relationship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Relationship]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thecougarden.wordpress.com/?p=932</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It seems all around me long-term relationships, marriages and families are, or have, or continue to blow up.  From posts in the blogging world to my friends and acquaintances and even in my own personal experience, there seems to be so much crap and residual crap floating around.  It has all definitely changed my traditional [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=932&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://thecougarden.wordpress.com/2013/02/24/love-loved-light/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>103</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/9d719b266af098c7c33435b49cb3b7ce?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">denmother2012</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Unleashing &#8220;Django Unchained&#8221;: Epiphanies for White America</title>
		<link>http://peculiarfaith.com/2013/01/31/unleashing-django-unchained-epiphanies-for-white-america/</link>
		<comments>http://peculiarfaith.com/2013/01/31/unleashing-django-unchained-epiphanies-for-white-america/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 18:03:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>The Rev. Dr. Jay</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Current Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Liturgy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Theology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Epiphany]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Incarnation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quentin Tarantino]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Racism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Slavery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[violence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[White Guilt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[white supremacy]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://peculiarfaith.com/?p=670</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[White Guilt won’t solve anything. Neither will White Denial. Trying to figure out where one sits on that spectrum is a distinct privilege for white people, like me. People of color don’t have those moments of luxury, those moments when they get to pause and wonder about all the complexities of a social and political [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=670&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>White Guilt won’t solve anything. Neither will White Denial. Trying to figure out where one sits on that spectrum is a distinct privilege for white people, like me. People of color don’t have those moments of luxury, those moments when they get to pause and wonder about all the complexities of a social and political system designed to favor white people and white communities.</p>
<p>As I sat in a dark theater watching <a href="http://www.latimes.com/entertainment/movies/moviesnow/la-et-mn-quentin-tarantino-django-unchained-20121215,0,436017.story" target="_blank"><i>Django Unchained</i></a> last week I was glad for little light. What I watched belongs in shadows and in dark corners and all those places where human beings rightly cower in the face of horror. Watching that film I felt assaulted by violence, torn by conflicting loyalties, wrenched by poignant moments of tenderness, amused by reversals of fortune, and appalled by the human capacity to act with unspeakable cruelty. Yet none of that compares to what African Americans feel when watching the same film. Of that, at least, I am certain.<a href="http://queerlychristian.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/django.jpg"><img class="alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-672" style="margin:3px;" alt="django" src="http://queerlychristian.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/django.jpg?w=189&#038;h=126" width="189" height="126" /></a></p>
<p>I’m eager to learn from my African American colleagues and friends about their responses to that Quentin Tarantino film. It is of course <a href="http://www.tarantino.info/" target="_blank">quintessentially Tarantino</a> – ridiculously violent, comically absurd, and horribly distasteful. For all its excess, the film prompted me to discern anew how to live as a white person in a society still reeling from the legacy of racial brutality.</p>
<p>I worry and I fret that even half of the violence or even a portion of the denial of human dignity portrayed in that film captures the historical reality of institutional slavery. But that’s White Guilt talking and it’s not helpful. Equally unhelpful is to suppose that all that horror is neatly sequestered in the shrouds of history and has nothing to do with us today. That’s White Denial talking.</p>
<p>If <i>Django</i><a href="http://queerlychristian.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/django2.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-673" style="margin:3px;" alt="django2" src="http://queerlychristian.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/django2.jpg?w=116&#038;h=175" width="116" height="175" /></a><i> Unchained</i> is going to contribute anything more than Oscar-worthy performances all of us will need to unleash its dangerous message. And <i>Django</i> is dangerous in the same way the Christian Gospel is dangerous, and for this reason: flesh matters.</p>
<p>Tarantino would seem to elicit precisely the opposite as we see flesh flayed, beaten, punctured, ripped apart, bleeding, and generally abused in nearly every manner imaginable. Perhaps that’s the wake-up call Christian communities need if we’re going to take our incarnational faith more seriously – to take human flesh more seriously.</p>
<p><a href="http://queerlychristian.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/epiphany_magi2.jpg"><img class="alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-671" style="margin:3px;" alt="epiphany_magi2" src="http://queerlychristian.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/epiphany_magi2.jpg?w=168&#038;h=205" width="168" height="205" /></a>I saw <i>Django</i> in this Christian liturgical season following The Epiphany – the feast of the manifestation of God’s Word made flesh. This season in concert with that film poses some gut-wrenching questions for white Christians like me. What kind of “flesh” do we mean, really? How is my white flesh consistently considered better than other kinds of flesh, not just abstractly or theoretically but concretely, in the communities where I work, worship, and play? What can and what should I do about that?</p>
<p>This liturgical season began with the story of the Magi traveling far from home, asking questions, and offering gifts when they arrived. White people committed to dismantling systemic racism can follow that same pattern by leaving our comfort zones, learning what we need to know by asking uncomfortable questions, and then offering ourselves to the divine mission of respecting and celebrating <i><span style="text-decoration:underline;">all</span></i> and not just some flesh.</p>
<p>Regardless of the cinematic merits of <i>Django Unchained</i>, unleashing its insights in this season following the Epiphany and leading into Lent could provoke some profound conversations and conversions. I like to remember that those words – “conversation” and “conversion” – come from the same linguistic root. Engaging in genuine conversation makes us vulnerable to life-changing insights, exactly what all of us need in a society built on white supremacy. (One of those insights might link the portrayal of violence to the problem of violence, though Tarantino himself <a href="http://www.theatlanticwire.com/entertainment/2013/01/quentin-tarantino-violence-quotes/60900/" target="_blank">rather testily disagrees</a>.)</p>
<p>At the very least <i>Django</i> beckons white people to consider why and how our white flesh still matters more than any other kind – and that would surely be an epiphany worthy of this peculiar season.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/670/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/670/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=670&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://peculiarfaith.com/2013/01/31/unleashing-django-unchained-epiphanies-for-white-america/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>20</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/68e85119a90b638953cfcd48e3567f14?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">drjayson</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://queerlychristian.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/django.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">django</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://queerlychristian.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/django2.jpg?w=99" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">django2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://queerlychristian.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/epiphany_magi2.jpg?w=123" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">epiphany_magi2</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
