<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2013 21:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Let There Never Be A Last Picture Show</title>
		<link>http://susannajackson.wordpress.com/2013/02/15/let-there-never-be-a-last-picture-show/</link>
		<comments>http://susannajackson.wordpress.com/2013/02/15/let-there-never-be-a-last-picture-show/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 19:34:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>susannajackson</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[On movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal Essays]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boston]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[independent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NYT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[theaters]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://susannajackson.wordpress.com/?p=40</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I am tired of the multiplex. The chairs may be comfortable but the experience as a whole is not. There is no warmth. No friendliness. On a Friday evening, ticket lines loop around the lobby, no seat is left empty and still the experience is lonely, solitary business. We avoid each others&#8217; elbows on armrests, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=40&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I am tired of the multiplex. The chairs may be comfortable but the experience as a whole is not. There is no warmth. No friendliness. On a Friday evening, ticket lines loop around the lobby, no seat is left empty and still the experience is lonely, solitary business. We avoid each others&#8217; elbows on armrests, we are irritated by someone&#8217;s &#8216;excuse mes&#8217; on the way to the bathroom, and we shoot furious glares at those responsible for the accidental kicking of one&#8217;s seat. Post-film banter with fellow moviegoers is non-existent. It is as if we go to the theater thinking we are headed to our living room and are distraught when we find a naked fat man on our sofa.</p>
<p>The movie theater experience isn&#8217;t this grim everywhere. The independently run theaters are a happy alternative to the multiplex. The folks who sell us our tickets are knowledgeable, the ticket-takers are talkative, the audience is amiable. Popcorn is available, but it is not necessary that you buy a barrel. As you file out of the darkened theater you will often encounter a  fellow film fanatic who wants to talk to you about that clever plot twist or her award-winning performance. I shared one such conversation after seeing <em>Beasts of The Southern Wild</em> at <a href="http://www.coolidge.org/">Coolidge Corner Theater</a> while my eyes were still wet with tears.</p>
<div id="attachment_201" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://susannajackson.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/beasts-of-the-southern-wild1.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-201" alt="Beasts of the Southern Wild (2012)" src="http://susannajackson.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/beasts-of-the-southern-wild1.jpg?w=300&#038;h=158" width="300" height="158" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Beasts of the Southern Wild (2012)</p></div>
<p>Movie production is changing and with it comes a threat against the theaters I love so much. All major production studios will be switching to digital format from celluloid which means that theaters across America will have to update their projection equipment. For Regal, AMC, and the other large theater chains, this poses no problem. But for most independent movie houses, the cost of updating is crippling or impossible.</p>
<p><a href="http://susannajackson.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/20130216_210649_hdr-1-1.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-287 alignright" alt="20130216_210649_HDR-1-1" src="http://susannajackson.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/20130216_210649_hdr-1-1.jpg?w=330&#038;h=450" width="330" height="450" /></a>Eric Hynes, in a <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2012/08/25/movies/resort-towns-face-a-last-picture-show.html?pagewanted=all"><em>NYT</em> article</a> printed last August, said &#8220;John Fithian, president of the <a title="group site" href="http://www.natoonline.org/index.php">National Association of Theater Owners</a>, says 30,000 screens have already been converted, leaving nearly 10,000 in some stage of transition. As he told exhibitors at CinemaCon in 2011, “If you don’t make the decision to get on the digital train soon, you will be making the decision to get out of the business.”&#8221;</p>
<p>Last fall, The Coolidge Corner Theater launched their <a href="http://www.coolidge.org/support-us/digital-cinema-challenge">Digital Cinema Challenge</a> to fundraise over $200,000 to update to digital projection. They were fortunate to reach their goals in a matter of months with donations from over six hundred contributors. Theaters across the country are taking similar initiatives. Another Boston-area theater, <a href="http://brattlefilm.org/">Brattle Theater</a> has a <a href="http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/78747263/brattle-theatre-digital-projection-and-hvac-renova?ref=card">Kickstarter</a> to help them reach their digital goals.</p>
<p>In 1977, <em>NYT</em> article, <a href="http://select.nytimes.com/gst/abstract.html?res=F10F10FF345915768FDDA90A94DA405B878BF1D3">&#8220;The Last Picture Show,&#8221; </a>prematurely predicted the end of the independent movie house. Perhaps the August article is just as prematurely pessimistic. I hope there are people like me who can&#8217;t &#8212; won&#8217;t &#8212; imagine the end of the independent theater. I hope that the digital upgrade is merely a hurdle that requires some community support to overcome.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/40/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/40/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=40&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://susannajackson.wordpress.com/2013/02/15/let-there-never-be-a-last-picture-show/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://susannajackson.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/1054179352_02e72246af.jpg?w=100" />
		<media:content url="http://susannajackson.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/1054179352_02e72246af.jpg?w=100" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/6a62ed3e3181353b600f14cd04c68776?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F0.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">susannajackson</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://susannajackson.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/beasts-of-the-southern-wild1.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Beasts of the Southern Wild (2012)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://susannajackson.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/20130216_210649_hdr-1-1.jpg?w=330" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">20130216_210649_HDR-1-1</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>We&#8217;re All Living in Portlandia</title>
		<link>http://alexwilgus.wordpress.com/2013/02/15/were-all-living-in-portlandia/</link>
		<comments>http://alexwilgus.wordpress.com/2013/02/15/were-all-living-in-portlandia/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 21:29:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>alexwilgus</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adbusters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[americana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bourgeois]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[carrie brownstein]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crisis of conformity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fred armisen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hipsters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[portlandia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vice magazine]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://alexwilgus.wordpress.com/?p=1015</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Once in a while, a popular word will snowball into a state of such broad explanatory use that thoughtful people must either whittle it down to a more definite size or call for its utter dissolution.  This is the present state of hipster, a term wielded with equal frequency as a fashion, a movement, a [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1015&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://alexwilgus.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/20130215-140957.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full" alt="20130215-140957.jpg" src="http://alexwilgus.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/20130215-140957.jpg?w=720" /></a></p>
<p>Once in a while, a popular word will snowball into a state of such broad explanatory use that thoughtful people must either whittle it down to a more definite size or call for its utter dissolution.  This is the present state of <em>hipster</em>, a term wielded with equal frequency as a fashion, a movement, a demographic, and even an insult.</p>
<p>In 2008, <em>Adbusters</em> ran an article with a title that is, to date, still the only title to successfully convince me to read <em>Adbusters.</em>  It was called &#8220;<a href="http://www.adbusters.org/magazine/79/hipster.html">Hipster: The Dead End of Western Civilization</a>.&#8221;  This article came at just the right time with just the right dose of acid to make it one of the most important pieces of social journalism of our time.  In it Douglas Haddow defined &#8220;hipsterdom&#8221; as an ugly and regrettable mutation of Western counterculture.  Its chameleonic quality&#8211;wearing the symbols of  countercultural movements the world over without taking any stake in any of them&#8211;is rivaled only by its rituals of narcissism practiced by young scenesters who attend nightly parties in hopes of being photographed, then wake up the next afternoon and check the blogs hoping to catch a glimpse of themselves.  All of it, Haddow argues, revolves around consumption.  Hipsterdom is in fact consumerism that has successfully passed itself off as counterculture.  Hipsters are nothing but young yuppies.</p>
<p>Those who rallied to defend the hipster came, perhaps predictably, from the offices of the very magazines and blogs Haddow blamed for creating the hipster monster.  <em>Vice</em> magazine&#8217;s Gavin McInnes&#8211;quoted in Haddow&#8217;s piece&#8211;famously blamed the term hipster on &#8220;chubby bloggers who aren&#8217;t getting laid any more and are bored.&#8221;  Dan Hancox of The Guardian joined in to tell Adbusters to <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/commentisfree/2008/sep/03/fashion">&#8220;lighten up&#8221;</a> and stop worrying about the lives of &#8220;fashion people&#8221; because they aren&#8217;t doing any harm to anyone.  On their count, the hipster does not exist outside of a word invented by jealous, yuppie has-beens to describe youth movements that they, due to age or unattractiveness, are no longer capable of taking part in.  That the term is used to describe such disparate social phenomena as home beer-brewing and european house music is proof of its generalizing, indefinite quality.  It is a derogatory term deployed only by those on the outside looking in.</p>
<p>Yet what are we to think when we see waxed mustaches, thick-rimmed glasses, mid-century haircuts, cutoff jeans, and bright yellow leggings all striding down the sidewalk in the same posse?  If there is no epidemic of irony gripping our nation&#8217;s youth, then why do we laugh when we see a gallery of <a href="http://www.tumblr.com/tagged/hipster%20disney%20princesses">hipster Disney princesses</a>:  stills of Ariel, Jasmine, and Belle caught in unimpressed ho-hum expressions with big glasses superimposed onto them via photoshop?  If fashion is not evolving at the breakneck speed of market appetite, then where have all the keffiyehs gone?  Why is everybody now drinking Shiner Bock instead of Pabst Blue Ribbon?  How can we dismiss the word <em>hipster</em> when its explanatory power still seems so intact, but how can we continue to use it when it seems to apply to almost any current craze?</p>
<p>I think the only satisfactory course is to retire the word &#8220;hipster&#8221; and replace it instead with &#8220;Portlandia.&#8221;  As you may notice, this entails more than a change in semantics. Indeed, it is a complete change of concept.  The genius of Fred Armisen and Carrie Brownstein&#8217;s IFC sketch-comedy is that it&#8217;s not interested in defining one or another particular type of people, rather it is trying to define a place.  No one stereotype dominates the show&#8217;s cast.  By the third season, their cast of regular characters (almost all of them are different pairs played by Armisen and Brownstein&#8211;among them the feminist bookstore owners, the grungy punks, the bar-hopping scenesters, the thirtysomething married couple, the fortysomething rich couple, the mechanic-and-wife couple, and the outdoorsy couple) has swelled to Dickensian levels.  Like Dickens, the duo are not content with satire.  Satirical comedy&#8211;that one can see Armisen perform weekly on SNL&#8211;visits a supposed social type or specific person, skewers them thoroughly, then leaves them to curl up and die.  Armisen and Brownstein on the other hand, double back to revisit their characters over and over, never closing the book on them.  The final episode of season two joins them all together in a multiple blocks-long line for a hot new brunch place.  <em>Portlandia</em> broadens our gaze beyond defining (and roasting) whatever a hipster is, and instead denotes the broader social space that all 21st Century middle-class Americans live in.  &#8221;What&#8217;s going on with those hipsters?&#8221; is not the correct question according to <em>Portlandia</em>.  Instead it&#8217;s, &#8220;what&#8217;s going on with all of us?&#8221;</p>
<p><em>Portlandia</em> makes the radical claim that hipsters, yuppies, granolas, punks, parents, and hippies are all of a type, all in the same socio-cultural-psychological-or-whatever-metaphysical-structure-you-like state, all carried along by the same social currents. Whether it is a debilitating addiction to Battlestar Galactica or a mad impulse to sew birds onto everything, it all comes down to the same sort of obsessive-consumptive behavior.  Regardless of whether or not you think this is an unfortunate predicament gripping America or just another way of life, acting out these unnamable and peculiar drives&#8211;rather than simply attributing them through two-dimensional parody to the actions and agendas of one or another type of people&#8211;makes these oddities and absurdities come alive as nameable sensations that most every middle-class American can relate to.  Portlandia is a place, both in time and physical space, and if you live there you can&#8217;t help but be part of the cast.</p>
<p>I should take a brief moment to say that <em>Portlandia</em> is not really about Portland, Oregon.  It is important to note that the &#8220;-dia&#8221; suffix suggests a broader social space than the city limits of the Rose City.  Portlandia exists in equal measure in Austin, Asheville, Nashville, San Francisco, St. Louis, Chicago, Madison, Minneapolis, Brooklyn, and of course Seattle.  Our word for 21st Century middle-classness must express itself as a specific place&#8211;Portland, Oregon in this case&#8211;to properly describe one of the features of our present bourgeoisie, a proud or perhaps artificial identification with locality.  If it is not marionberry pancakes in Portland, then it is fried avocados in Austin.  But perhaps Portland is the best place to represent our nation&#8217;s many enclaves of this particular strain of <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Bobos-Paradise-Upper-Class-There/dp/0684853787">bourgeois bohemia</a>.  Portland, Oregon is a city with a proud history of middle-classness.  Anti-capitalism, local politics, and petit-bourgeois populism run deep in Portlanders&#8217; veins, (check out Robert D. Johnston&#8217;s <em><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Radical-Middle-Class-Progressive-Twentieth-Century/dp/0691126003">The Radical Middle Class</a></em> for more on that) but what once may have been locally distinct traditions has, in the age of internet, gone national through the interstate avenues of style, consumption, and &#8220;cool.&#8221;  We certainly cannot be sure that the present mood originated in Portland.  Portlanders&#8217; historically rooted desire for self government and a wariness of corporate monopolies may still be a live instinct in certain sectors of middle-class America, but there are also newer cultural forces to explain and contend with&#8211;like why we would rather wait in a three-hour line to taste the marionberry pancakes at the newest &#8220;local&#8221; brunch place instead of spending considerably less money on the &#8220;cup o&#8217; joe side of dough&#8221; special at the (also locally-owned) diner-slash-gift shop down the street.</p>
<p>Obsession is the most central theme of <em>Portlandia</em> (the show.) Everyone is into something so intently that it&#8217;s like they have blinders on and can&#8217;t see the rest of the world around them.  No character is well-rounded (perhaps that&#8217;s a prerequisite for good comedy, but anyway, the point is clear.)  In one rapidly-edited sketch, Armisen madly tweets, facebooks, blogs, and checks his email until Brownstein snaps him out of it.  In another, the two try to one-up each other in newspaper, magazine, and blog articles they have read.  In another, a goateed Armisen goes around to all of his favorite spots, and in each one sees an annoyingly straight-laced man, clearly an out-of-town poser.  He takes such pains to avoid him that when the man grows his own goatee, Armisen shaves his and makes himself over to look like the man originally did. In the end, they&#8217;ve switched places entirely.  Each sketch plays off an obsession with one idea, a single isolated impulse that we are so invested in that we cannot get the lay of the land around us.  The obsessive impulse is evident in the show&#8217;s style.  In the vein of Michael Ian Black, David Wain, and Michael Showalter&#8217;s magnificent <em>Stella</em>, each situation and impulse is taken to its furthest extreme, and so becomes absurd. <em>Portlandia&#8217;s</em> genius lies in its portrayal of so many social types in this same mood.</p>
<p>I should draw attention to my focus on the middle-class.  I do this for two reasons.  One is that I think of myself as middle-class and cannot pretend to comment on ways of life too far outside my realm of life experience.  The other is that &#8220;middle-class&#8221; is a term that, while vague in itself, is usually deployed to mean a way of life that is reasonably moneyed.  It is a fact that having a decent amount of money and living at a certain level of comfort are sufficient conditions for regular outings at brunch, the frequent purchase of clothes, and a shelf full of DVDs.  It is possible that whatever Portlandia is, it is a space that can only be generated given a reasonably moneyed way of life.  But it does not follow that Portlandia and middle-classness is the same thing.  As you will find out if you read <em>The Radical Middle Class</em>, middle-class folks have not always been about the same business as they are today.  Anyway, even if the social and cultural, (or dare I say it&#8230;spiritual?) forces that make up Portlandia are in fact more universal than the economic enablers of a reasonably moneyed lifestyle, I can&#8217;t really speak to how they might manifest themselves in the poorer sections of our country nor those of the super-wealthy.</p>
<p>Fred Armisen <a href="http://www.mtvhive.com/2012/01/04/fred-armisen-interview/">does not believe</a> there is any such thing as a hipster.  If he was any other old uncreative blogger, I would have dismissed such an idea altogether.  But instead, whether he knows it or not, he has added tremendously to the conversation.  If the &#8220;hipster&#8221; is dead, it is not because he has been deconstructed into oblivion or finally defeated by a new cultural movement, nor has it been adequately defined, but because Armisen and Brownstein have given us a better word to describe what&#8217;s going on with the present middle-class.  In <em>Portlandia</em> we might just have a word that is capable of describing whatever it is that&#8217;s going on with us, precisely because it describes a place, not one or another kind of&#8211;to use the horrid word&#8211;subculture.  Though I can&#8217;t pretend it&#8217;s a thorough definition, I do think it&#8217;s better than <em>hipster</em>.  Where do our present consumptive maladies, obsessions, and other general peculiarities come from?  It wasn&#8217;t the hipsters, nor the bloggers.</p>
<p>&#8220;Forget about it Jake, it&#8217;s <em>Portlandia</em>.&#8221;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1015/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1015/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1015&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://alexwilgus.wordpress.com/2013/02/15/were-all-living-in-portlandia/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/9f46b81e8c3a108ac7e382648c743c7d?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">alexwilgus</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://alexwilgus.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/20130215-140957.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">20130215-140957.jpg</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The All Too Common Story of Someday</title>
		<link>http://humansareweird.com/2013/02/15/the-all-too-common-story-of-someday/</link>
		<comments>http://humansareweird.com/2013/02/15/the-all-too-common-story-of-someday/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 21:53:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Humans Are Weird</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humans Are Weird]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[irony]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lifestyle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[procrastinating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-concept]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social constructs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[someday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thought experiment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thoughts]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://humansareweird.com/?p=2414</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[For every positively fabulous thing that humans have ever done on this earth throughout history, there has always been &#8211; and will most certainly always be &#8211; an equally disastrous counterpart. For instance: Cure the common cold. Atom bomb. Invent the plane. Crash it into a building. Build up intricate, complex methods of communication. Tlk [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2414&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For every positively fabulous thing that humans have ever done on this earth throughout history, there has always been &#8211; and will most certainly always be &#8211; an equally disastrous counterpart.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration:underline;"><strong>For instance:</strong></span></p>
<p>Cure the common cold. Atom bomb.</p>
<p>Invent the plane. Crash it into a building.</p>
<p>Build up intricate, complex methods of communication. Tlk lyk dis.</p>
<p>Hamlet. The Secret.</p>
<p>Friends. Jersey Shore.</p>
<p>You get the idea.</p>
<p>However, one thing that never ceases to amaze me, is this long standing, natural human proclivity to procrastinate.</p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;"><strong>The story of &#8220;someday.&#8221;</strong></span></p>
<div id="attachment_2423" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://humansareweird.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/13935500-travel-the-world-monuments-concept.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-2423" alt="Maybe change, &quot;someday I'll travel the world&quot; to &quot;someday I'll wake up and open my eyes to the world I'm already in.&quot;  ?" src="http://humansareweird.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/13935500-travel-the-world-monuments-concept.jpg?w=300&#038;h=261" width="300" height="261" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Maybe change, &#8220;someday I&#8217;ll travel the world&#8221; to &#8220;someday I&#8217;ll wake up and open my eyes to the world I&#8217;m already in.&#8221; ?</p></div>
<p>Growing up, my parents had a philosophy that they themselves lived by puritanically. It&#8217;s not one, I don&#8217;t think, that they intentionally desired to imbue me with; but nevertheless, it was a way of thought that rubbed off on me. Kinda like a mosquito bug infects an unsuspecting traveller with malaria.</p>
<p>They taught me, through their actions that the day tomorrow will eventually come. And they taught me how to keep that day at arm&#8217;s length, at all times.</p>
<p>Some day, ma an&#8217; pa each spoke, <em>I&#8217;ll quit smoking.</em></p>
<p>Some day, <em>we&#8217;ll renovate the downstairs.</em></p>
<p>Some day, <i>we&#8217;ll travel the world</i>.</p>
<p>Some day,<em> I will read that book everyone&#8217;s been raving on about.</em></p>
<p>Someday, <em>you, my son, will be a successful, rich, handsome, tall, man, who will change the world for the better</em>.</p>
<p><strong>Some. Fucking. Day.</strong></p>
<p>First things first. Mum, dad, if either of you are reading this . . . hi! Please note that this is not really about you, <em>per se</em>, I&#8217;m just using you both as an example that a lot of people will probably be able to relate to. I could have used countless other objects of identification, but here we are.</p>
<p>Anyway.</p>
<p>Back to business.</p>
<p>Let me fill you in on a little secret, folks. Are you ready. Listen up.</p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;"><strong>Someday does not exist.</strong></span></p>
<p>Someday is merely another way to say, &#8220;I like to comfort myself for my (self-perceived) shortcomings, and so, I contrive stories where the character I play will eventually fulfil all of my &#8211; &#8216;my&#8217; meaning my very own &#8211; wildest dreams.&#8221;</p>
<p>It&#8217;s bullshit, folks.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s a funny story that my fifth grade teacher told me that, for whatever the reason, stuck to me closer than paint does to a wall.</p>
<p><strong><span style="text-decoration:underline;">It was this:</span></strong></p>
<p>A man drove past a bar. Outside the bar this man saw a sign, reading, &#8220;FREE BEERS TOMORROW.&#8221; So the man made a mental note, and decided that tomorrow, he would drive back to that same bar to claim his free beers. The next day then, the man, jolly as a pedophile at a Wiggles concert (bad taste is my forte) jumped in his car, a smile beaming on his cheeks, and drove hastily to that bar (despite it being a Wednesday afternoon and his having successfully battled alcoholism for the past three years, five months, three days and twenty minutes).</p>
<p>Once he arrived at the bar, he walked inside, slammed his fist against the bar&#8217;s bench, and said, &#8220;barkeep? I&#8217;d like my free beers, please. Thank you, sir.&#8221;</p>
<p>The barkeep, who was drying off a tall beer glass with a ragged white towel, turned to the man, with a serious glint in &#8216;is eye, and said, in a matter of fact tone, &#8220;Sir, didn&#8217;t you read the sign out the front. Free beers are tomorrow. Come back then, ay?&#8221;</p>
<p>The man, confused, replied, &#8220;But I drove past yesterday. The sign was up yesterday. Tomorrow is the day after yesterday. Free beers are then today.&#8221;</p>
<p><a href="http://humansareweird.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/6914.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-2422" alt="???????????????????????????????" src="http://humansareweird.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/6914.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" width="300" height="225" /></a></p>
<p>The barkeep, not batting an eye lid, still wiping down the dewy glass, repeated his previous statement, and turned around to serve another patron dealing with foreboding alcoholism; an Irishmen downing shots of tequila, to be precise.</p>
<p>The man then, scratching at his bald head, picked up his sunken spirits from the dirty floor, and decided that he would again try his luck tomorrow. And so he did. And so the same happened again.</p>
<p>He kept going to that same bar for three years.</p>
<p>And he never got a single free beer.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Point of the story:</span></p>
<p>Write that book. Kiss that loved one. Ask that person you&#8217;ve been stalking for five months out on a date. Tell Jenny that you love her. Tell Fred that he&#8217;s an ass-bag and you&#8217;ve hired a lawyer to take him for all his worth. Book that round the world trip. Climb Mount Kilimanjaro. Lick a &#8220;poisonous&#8221; toad. Try something different, like an orgy. Have sex with an orangutan, just to satisfy your curiosity. Hell, bang a warm apple pie, just like the movie <em>American Pie</em> said you should.</p>
<p>And do it right now! Yes! Now! Because you can! Damn it! Screw someday. Make that day, today.</p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;"><strong>Or, don&#8217;t. Whatever.</strong></span></p>
<p>It&#8217;s not like I give a shit.</p>
<p>Probably a much better idea to simply stop beating yourself up and relax, just for once?</p>
<p>Someday, right?</p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;"><strong>Humans-are-dreamers. All dreams will eventually come to an end. And frankly, most aren&#8217;t worth the scurf off an ant&#8217;s back anyhow. </strong></span></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2414/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2414/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2414&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://humansareweird.com/2013/02/15/the-all-too-common-story-of-someday/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>43</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://humansareweird.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/chris24.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://humansareweird.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/chris24.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">chris24</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/e655d0c833ef7ebd059f8427698fe52f?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">robertpoposki</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://humansareweird.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/13935500-travel-the-world-monuments-concept.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Maybe change, &#34;someday I&#039;ll travel the world&#34; to &#34;someday I&#039;ll wake up and open my eyes to the world I&#039;m already in.&#34;  ?</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://humansareweird.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/6914.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">???????????????????????????????</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Do Gay Porn Stars Kill Themselves?</title>
		<link>http://connerhabib.wordpress.com/2013/02/13/why-do-gay-porn-stars-kill-themselves/</link>
		<comments>http://connerhabib.wordpress.com/2013/02/13/why-do-gay-porn-stars-kill-themselves/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2013 20:06:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Conner Habib</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://connerhabib.wordpress.com/?p=430</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Why do porn actors kill themselves?  Who is responsible? Whenever a porn star &#8211; especially a gay porn star &#8211; commits suicide, theories show up, and people act very, very certain about them.  Arpad Miklos, who was as much as a porn “star” as anyone can be in a time when we are hyper-saturated with [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=430&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Why do porn actors kill themselves?  Who is responsible?</p>
<p><a href="http://connerhabib.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/wood2.jpg"><img class=" wp-image alignleft" id="i-429" alt="Image" src="http://connerhabib.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/wood2.jpg?w=245&#038;h=174" width="245" height="174" /></a></p>
<p>Whenever a porn star &#8211; especially a gay porn star &#8211; commits suicide, theories show up, and people act very, very certain about them.  Arpad Miklos, who was as much as a porn “star” as anyone can be in a time when we are hyper-saturated with porn, killed himself on February 3rd, 2013, at the age of 45.  As usual, many people felt sure they knew why he committed suicide, without much evidence.  It was drugs, it was studios not treating him well, it was the feeling of dehumanization, it was the vague but all encompassing “porn industry” that did it, it was the feeling of being hollow, it was it was his loss of validation after being a star for so long.</p>
<p>I can’t claim any special knowledge about his death, I didn’t know him very well.  We met in passing on a set; he’d just finished a scene, and I was about to start mine.  He was huge and handsome; I’m not saying anything new.  If you met him, you were impressed by his smile and his body and his <i>presence</i>.  Looking at him almost made you feel a sense of <i>unbalance </i>in the world, like his handsomeness and flawless physique were proof of some deep inequality between people.  But then you’d forget that feeling and be drawn back into the intense attraction.</p>
<p>He gave me a kiss and his phone number and asked me if I’d like to spend time with him later that night.  My scene ran over schedule, and I was exhausted, so I told him I couldn’t meet.  We communicated a few more times over the years by text and phone, and that was that.  I mention all of this to say:  I don’t know his motivations or who he “really” was.  We kept passing through each other’s lives without ever truly meeting.</p>
<p>But others who knew him even less than me flooded twitter, wrote articles, posted to facebook about what had happened.  The theories appeared as soon as the news did.  It was immediate, like flies to a corpse.  Theories arrived before grief, before honor and love and the experience of loss.  When a gay porn star dies, instead of an outpouring of grief, what we are usually witness to is a <i>buzzing</i>.</p>
<p>All of this is to say that not even death can trump many people’s confused and hostile attitudes towards porn and porn performers. That is how deeply injured we are as a society when it comes to sex, sexuality, and love.</p>
<p>***</p>
<p>It’s natural to turn events like suicide into cultural concerns.</p>
<p>Tragedies are <i>supposed </i>to pose questions to us &#8211; the feelings of discomfort that sadness brings can create meaningful action.  But these actions are always most effective when we don’t bypass grief and compassion to get to them.  Unfortunately, the people that make up the largest group involved in porn &#8211; the viewers and consumers &#8211; may not understand what it&#8217;s like to be a performer or to work for a studio.  The porn industry remains obscured by unexamined attitudes towards sex.  So compassion isn&#8217;t always available.</p>
<p>There’s a general confusion for outsiders about performer motivations for making porn, how much money they make, what happens during a shoot, what health and safety precautions are in place, how a scene is organized, what it feels like to be a crew member and more. The result is that a monolithic image of “gay porn star” and the “gay porn industry” is formed.  But unlike ideas of other industries &#8211; banking or agriculture, say &#8211; people’s perceptions are colored by a broader societal confusion: a difficulty in thinking and communicating clearly when it comes to sex and desire.</p>
<p>This confusion is generated by many factors, most importantly by social and cultural institutions that have historically leveraged sex as a way to control people (I address some of those forces <a href="http://connerhabib.wordpress.com/2012/11/11/the-virtues-of-being-an-object/">here</a>, and will write more about them in the future).  Because these forces create pressure and guilt around sex, when someone like Miklos, who had sex publicly, kills himself, people tend to think he was sad <i>because </i>of his public sex life.  They don’t focus on the fact that he was trained as a chemist nor do they ask what his relationships were like or if he was generally happy.  Instead, a knee-jerk reaction links his sadness with porn.</p>
<p>People want to know: How was porn involved in this death?</p>
<p>This isn’t a totally unfair question, but when left unrefined, it&#8217;s not a good one; it&#8217;s misguided at best, damaging at its worst.  Aside from not taking all the other factors of Miklos’s death into account, it’s misguided because it’s not nearly a deep enough or complete enough question. It focuses too much on the performer as victim and not enough on sex in society, nor how the porn viewer receives porn and thinks about porn performers, or how sex is legislated, or what our unquestioned assumptions about the “porn industry” are.</p>
<p>The porn performer is, in general, not a victim. This image of the performer as starting porn because of bad circumstance or compulsion is largely a lie (perpetuated, in part, by confused critics of porn).  Part of this false image comes from the idea that porn performers just “fall into” porn or that they’re “discovered” by unscrupulous studio moguls with big, villainous mustaches.  But the majority of would-be porn performers now approach studios, not vice versa.  They’re seeking porn work for different reasons.  Some of those reasons are aligned with the performer’s heart and integrity, others are not, but almost none of the reasons merit the label “victim,” at least not for deciding to be in porn.</p>
<p>The result is thousands of healthy, thoughtful, happy porn performers in gay and straight porn that haven’t killed themselves. And their ways of enacting being a porn performer are very different.  There are performers that make one movie to try it out.  There are porn stars who make a career out of it like Miklos did, appearing for years in different movies by different studios.  There are performers who shoot scenes with their boyfriends and post them to XTube; there are performers who wish they could make more.  There are people who long to be in the porn industry but can’t break into it, or are too afraid to start.</p>
<p>Many (though not all) have other jobs: Along with porn stars who are also escorts and personal trainers, I know gay porn stars who are lawyers, farmers, doctors, meteorologists, and artists. Some don’t have much overhead at all because they live with their parents, who know what they do and are proud of their children.</p>
<p>While there may be some vast archetype that encompasses all porn stars, there’s no such thing as a typical “gay porn star.”  We’re all different.</p>
<p>So sadness and mental health problems are not an industry epidemic &#8211; that perception is inaccurate, as is the notion that porn stars don’t have any other skills or feel compelled to do porn out of a lack of options.  Such statements simply aren’t true.</p>
<p>Of course, some performers <i>do </i>have mental health problems.  Some <i>are </i>suicidal, some <em>are</em> drug addicts.  The same is true for lawyers, farmers, doctors, etc. who are not porn stars.</p>
<p>If we strip misconceptions away, we still have a question of porn and mental health before us.  But it appears in in a refined version, a version that makes sense.  We can ask ourselves, what are the <i>specific </i>pressures of being in gay porn?  How can we make those pressures less of a burden?</p>
<p>***</p>
<p>None of the pressures that face porn stars are exclusive to porn &#8211; many of them face mainstream actors and athletes, for example.  One of the main problems is the constant inflation and collapse of a performer’s ego.</p>
<p>Once, after shooting a scene for a studio I hadn’t worked with before, one of the staff enthusiastically invited me to the “family.”  He told me how great I’d done and how excited he was to work with me again.  I was in a towel, exhausted, and happy to hear the news.  We were interrupted by a phone call.  He answered and entered into an urgent sounding discussion with a performer on the other end.  The studio just couldn’t hire him, the employee said, for the rate he wanted.  Then he relayed to the performer, studio by studio, how much other studios were paying.  It was significantly less than I’d been paid for work that day.  I felt a little sad for the other performer, but didn’t think much of it.  I became friendly with everyone at the studio, and we’d talk outside of work, too.</p>
<p>Months later I was the performer on the receiving end of this conversation.  Another staff member of the studio had warned me that I was “fat” and that I was asking for too much money.  My appearance hadn’t changed since they’d last hired and praised me.  If anything, I was more toned. I explained that I was only requesting the same rate they’d always paid me.  He went down the same studio-by-studio list, detailing rates, saying that everyone was paying less now.  But the rates he quoted were incorrect. I knew that now, because I’d worked for everyone on his list, appearing in a scene for one of them just a week ago.  It was a canned speech, created to dock performers’ pay.</p>
<p>Why was someone who I thought was my friend lying to me?  The first answer that comes to mind isn’t quite right : money.  Such a simple answer doesn’t explain why we couldn’t have had an honest conversation about money, rather than one coupled with insults and constructed to intimidate me in to accepting less.</p>
<p>Another time, I saw a hopeful newcomer come to the set for some preliminary casting <a href="http://connerhabib.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/abs.jpg"><img class=" wp-image alignleft" id="i-507" alt="Image" src="http://connerhabib.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/abs.jpg?w=249&#038;h=165" width="249" height="165" /></a>photos.  A director photographed him, and gave him many encouraging words when they were done.  When the aspiring performer left, the director started complaining about how fat the guy was.</p>
<p>“What a fucking slob,” he said in front of me and the other performers hired for the day.  Everyone was quiet.</p>
<p>“Did you tell him he wasn’t ready?” I asked, finally.</p>
<p>“No, he should have known,” he said.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s a fear among many performers that what we hear from employers is not reflective of how they actually feel, and this fear is, at least in part, justified by stories like these.  I’ve heard these complaints echoed again and again by other performers.   On top of this, like many entertainment-related businesses, porn studios are extremely busy but often disorganized.  Not hearing back from a studio in a timely manner after initial emails or calls creates a  flashing anxiety; is it because they&#8217;re ignoring you, because they forgot, or are they simply, reasonably, busy? Until you learn how to navigate it, all this puts you in a weird split state.  Are your employers your smiling and nodding friends or are they harboring thoughts about you that they’re not expressing?</p>
<p>Again, this isn’t a complaint confined to the porn industry &#8211; it’s a problem with many American business models, where honesty and forthrightness are not properly valued.  But in porn, it’s  compounded by the fact that these concerns mix into performers’ anxieties about their bodies.  Every porn performer I know has at least some fear of how the public will receive our bodies or how “fat” or “skinny” or “small” we look, even though we may not be fat or skinny or small by any means (and if we <i>are</i>, that brings in a separate set of societal issues).  This situation isn’t made any better by unscrupulous internet commenters and bloggers, who are happy to leave the cruelest comments they can think of under photos of our naked bodies.</p>
<p>***</p>
<p>Seen in this light, working in porn has a healthy aspect and a dark shadow.</p>
<p>Porn is healthy for a performer to the extent that it allows him to detach, rather than immerse himself in his body.</p>
<p>***</p>
<p>Porn offers an amazing opportunity to <i>think about </i>your body.  You have to think about how it looks, what food to put into it, what exercises to do to refine it, how to relax it, how to take care of it.  You even have to consider that other people may not like your body, no matter what you do.  Your dick might be too small (or too big!) for them.  They may not like your face or think your abs are undeveloped.  In porn, you have the opportunity to hear these complaints and to love yourself anyway.  It’s very freeing if you can achieve it.  When you can think about your body, you create a loving distance from it, a detachment.  It becomes an honor to have a body when you know it’s only an aspect of your being.</p>
<p>One happy and surprising side effect being in porn has had on me is that it’s loosened up my response to societal standards of beauty, allowing me to see who I actually find attractive.  Before porn, I found myself having a reflexive response to men with huge pecs and six pack abs.  If a huge guy walked into a bar, I (along with a lot of the other patrons) would turn instinctively to look at him.  Maybe I’d compare myself or other guys at the bar to him.  After being paid to have sex on camera with men like that, the feeling has totally left me.  Sometimes I’m still attracted to men who fall into society’s standard of beauty, but it’s not reactive.  Being in porn, being detached from my body, has helped me see the real contours of my desire and attraction, rather than conforming to what I’m told to think is attractive.</p>
<p>The same detachment is what allowed me to hear from the studio owner that I was “fat” and not breakdown, or to read mean-spirited comments on blogs, or to resist the command to do steroids from another studio worker.  My body is linked to my worth, but it’s mine, after all.  I&#8217;m a caretaker for my body.  The more detachment I get from it, the more clearly I see that.  I can feel this way most of the time now, but I still dip into the shadow every once in awhile.</p>
<p>The shadow side is that, as a porn performer, you can begin to completely identify with your body.  You can think it’s who you are. You can stumble off to the gym and onto the set and through parties and bars, cutting off your mind from other aspects of experience.   When you’re in this immersed state, an internet commenter or mean-spirited blogger or tactless industry employee calling you fat can feel devastating.</p>
<p>This is problematic enough, but it becomes crushing when you start to believe that your body is all you have to offer.  While I think <a href="http://connerhabib.wordpress.com/2012/11/11/the-virtues-of-being-an-object/">most arguments about objectification are shallow</a>, I also notice how porn performers <i>can </i>limit their own freedom and destroy their happiness by equating their bodies with their worth (and their worth with how much people are willing to validate their bodies by paying to film them.)  This is where a cliche comes from, the one where the ex-porn actor says desperately, “But porn is all I know!”  How to perform on camera is never all anyone knows, but being in porn creates the possibility of that self-delusion.</p>
<p>It’s <i>good</i> to equate some self-worth with the appearance of your body.  Too little emotional and thoughtful investment in our bodies can lead to poor health and compulsive daily patterns.  Equating<em> too much</em> self worth with our bodies can do the same, but the damage is often to mental health.  We become sensitive, obsessive, or prone to taking mood- altering steroids which for some can amplify the problem.</p>
<p>***</p>
<p>But these are just the pressures porn performers face directly through their involvement in porn.</p>
<p>Since porn is a global phenomenon, watched by millions and millions of people, the largest part of the porn industry is the consumer.  Consumers make up a special and powerful part of pornography.  Since viewers derive pleasure from porn, they are connected to it, not exempt from shouldering some of the responsibility for the well-being of porn performers.</p>
<p>Despite the global popularity of porn, prejudice against performers has not diminished. <a href="http://www.advocate.com/politics/commentary/2011/12/07/oped-investigating-porn">Teachers</a> have been fired, simply because they had consensual sex with another person on camera; but no one is prepared to say <i>why </i>being in porn should make someone unfit to teach.  <a href="http://www.gmax.co.za/look04/08/02-sportscomplex.html">Olympic hopefuls</a> with a porn past have been banned from competing under the auspices that they wouldn’t properly represent their country; but isn’t porn part of the country’s culture?  <a href="http://www.axelhotels.com/live/ex-cop-reality-tv-star-fired-over-porn-film-fights-back/">Reality TV stars</a> &#8211; have been disqualified from their shows for being in porn; but pornography was the original reality TV, a blend of real and unreal, and certainly full of performers that people are willing to pay to watch.</p>
<p>Involvement with porn becomes an automatic, unthinking grounds for discrimination.  The same people who fire or “out” porn and former performers must have watched porn.  But the porn viewer can conceal his/her enjoyment of pornography.  So long as this is true, the many people who have masturbated to pornography &#8211; and this includes most men and an increasing number of women &#8211; don’t have to feel any connection to the well-being of porn performers, who have provided the viewers with sexual pleasure.</p>
<p>All that is a broad, societal issue.  But what about smaller, personal instances of discrimination?  Porn viewers make discriminate against porn viewers on a smaller scale, through unthinking slut-shaming. But porn performers aren’t just a spectacle, they are, in one sense, the sexual partners of the people who watch them.  Their images and actions tie into the arousal and orgasm of the viewer.   Why are we asking, “What is it with gay porn?” but not asking, “What is it with the way society treats people who bring them pleasure?”</p>
<p>These are larger questions that I &#8211; and many other sex workers &#8211; continue to work through, and that are larger than the scope of this essay.  One of the reasons many sex workers are interested in these questions is because they expose something fascinating about Western culture and sex.  But another is that we want to be able to stop this unwarranted discrimination, to be able to be ourselves without reproach or dismissal.</p>
<p>***</p>
<p>So: Why do porn actors kill themselves? is not the right question.  It’s bound to prejudices, misconceptions, and shame.</p>
<p>A better question: What can we do to make involvement with porn easier, less stressful, and healthier?</p>
<p>Each of us, depending on our relationship to porn, can approach this by asking a series of different questions, and by working towards honest answers.</p>
<p><strong>Performers can ask themselves: </strong></p>
<p>Am I ready to be in porn? Does porn fit into the context of my life and my vision of my future?</p>
<p>Can I endure the misunderstandings of others without lashing out in anger or being weighed down by sadness?  Will I be okay when my parents and loved ones find out (and they invariably find out)?</p>
<p>Most importantly, can I maintain the knowledge that I am not only my body, that my body is a part of me, not all of me?</p>
<p><strong> People who work for studios can ask themselves</strong>:</p>
<p>Am I ready to put in effort to deal with performers, who may have sensitive feelings about their bodies, in a gentle way that is at the same time honest and open?</p>
<p>Am I being honest and open with the performers I work with and hire?</p>
<p>Am I being transparent (with myself and my performers) about pay and why certain performers are being paid the amounts they are, and why they were hired or rejected in the first place?</p>
<p><strong>Studio employees and owners can also ask performers</strong> the questions that performers should be asking themselves:  Are you ready for this?  Can you do this and not put your self-worth into it?  Does this fit into the context of your life? Etc.</p>
<p><strong>Viewers can ask themselves</strong>:</p>
<p>How do I feel about porn performers?</p>
<p>Am I grateful for the pleasure that porn gives me, or do I feel shame about it?</p>
<p>If I met a porn actor I liked, how would I react?</p>
<p>Viewers can also talk more openly about watching porn (and sex in general), which will help give voice to just how commonplace a phenomenon pornography is.</p>
<p>Of course, these questions don’t have to be phrased the way that I’ve written them.  They don’t have to all be asked at once; any one of them might be difficult to answer honestly.  I’m also familiar enough with the many problems we face in pornography &#8211; the way it tangles in with some of the best and worst aspects of economics, desire, and shame &#8211; to know that questions alone won&#8217;t solve all the problems facing us. But asking questions like these can help cultivate more kindness within porn and more acceptance in those outside of it.</p>
<p>When Arpad died, many people rerouted their guilt about porn &#8211; stemming from a lack of openness, reflection, and care about sex, pornography, and desire &#8211; onto his life.  Instead of sympathy, many people projected guilt and shame.  It’s up to all of us involved in porn &#8211; not just performers, and studio workers, but viewers as well -  to be more loving, open, and honest with ourselves and each other.  That way guilt, shame, and confusion can be redeemed and transformed, rather than absorbed by the empty space where a beautiful man used to be.</p>
<p><i>For John Bruno and Arpad Miklos</i></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://connerhabib.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/arpad.jpg"><img class="wp-image aligncenter" id="i-502" alt="Image" src="http://connerhabib.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/arpad.jpg?w=282&#038;h=392" width="282" height="392" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/430/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/430/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=430&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://connerhabib.wordpress.com/2013/02/13/why-do-gay-porn-stars-kill-themselves/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>80</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/81d7e0b78c2c7e9fab22f58d99cf3a0c?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">connerhabib</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://connerhabib.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/wood2.jpg?w=350" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://connerhabib.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/abs.jpg?w=415" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://connerhabib.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/arpad.jpg?w=447" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Invasion of the Mystery Beach Huts</title>
		<link>http://homesickandheatstruck.com/2013/02/15/invasion-of-the-mystery-beach-huts/</link>
		<comments>http://homesickandheatstruck.com/2013/02/15/invasion-of-the-mystery-beach-huts/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 11:20:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Homesick and Heatstruck</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Allo Allo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bathing machines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Britishness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[changing huts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[changing on a beach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dubai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dubai beach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[homesick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[huts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[locked changing huts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[postaweek]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UAE]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Victorian bathing machines]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://homesickandheatstruck.com/?p=188</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Recently, hundreds of these mysterious little huts have appeared on our beaches. They are, as you can see, white, about eight feet tall and roofed with a sort of parasol. All along the Dubai coastline they are now dotted along the sand in neat little his-and-hers pairs, situated about every hundred yards or so. I [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=188&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Recently, hundreds of these mysterious little huts have appeared on our beaches. They are, as you can see, white, about eight feet tall and roofed with a sort of parasol. All along the Dubai coastline they are now dotted along the sand in neat little his-and-hers pairs, situated about every hundred yards or so. I am fascinated by them. <a href="http://homesickandheatstruck.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/huts-1.jpg"><img class="alignright  wp-image-189" title="Mysterious huts" alt="Mysterious huts" src="http://homesickandheatstruck.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/huts-1.jpg?w=420&#038;h=315" width="420" height="315" /></a></p>
<p>At first glance they appear to be changing huts for bathers – and this would indeed be a practical and innovative idea (and thus somewhat out of character for this part of the world, one might say if one were in a cynical mood, which one invariably is these days) – but so far the little metal doors have been permanently locked and it would be a hell of an ungainly squeeze to cram one’s fat British head underneath the thin metal wall (not that I tried to. Obviously. Ahem).</p>
<p>Some of the huts are covered in advertisements, which makes me think that they might simply be small cylindrical bill-boards – an ingenious scheme to make money out of thin air and to prevent us from feeling deprived of the usual onslaught of aggressive consumerism, even while relaxing on the beach.</p>
<p>They are vaguely reminiscent of traditional French urinals, don’t you think? I am basing this on my encyclopaedic knowledge of French history and culture gleaned entirely from Allo Allo, of course… One half expects to see the faces of Rene Artois and Michelle of the Resistance (hers adorned with an unconvincing false moustache) peering over the top of the wall, while the awful English spy disguised as a policeman sidles up with his beach-towel and says loudly, “I am just pissing by the bitch for a quick swom in the soo…” and Rene looks into the camera and rolls his eyes theatrically to the sound of canned laughter…</p>
<p>It is possible that they are in fact alien space-craft. Certainly the way in which they appeared, almost overnight, in such vast numbers is suggestive of some sort of well-orchestrated incursion. If this were an episode of Doctor Who they would no doubt turn out to be Genesis Arks for the Daleks, a new model of the TARDIS manufactured by the Master, or Cybermen teleporters. Or something. Though why the Doctor’s various nemeses would stage an invasion on this part of the planet is beyond me. Unless they were after the oil. Or a bit of winter sunshine and a nice cocktail.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.old-postcards-of-dover.co.uk/detail/43"><img class="alignleft  wp-image-192" title="Bathing machines on Dover Beach. It looks a bit different these days..." alt="Bathing machines on Dover Beach. It looks a bit different these days..." src="http://homesickandheatstruck.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/victorian-bathing-huts.jpg?w=350&#038;h=208" width="350" height="208" /></a>The huts remind me of the bathing machines beloved by the Victorians: a ludicrously cumbersome way of getting in and out of the sea without anyone glimpsing you in your comedy stripy swimwear. I have always loved the concept of bathing machines, if only because the word ‘machine’ suggests something much more exciting and hi-tech than a shed on wheels. They did at least save people from the humiliation of an indecorous changing incident – a terror that haunts the British in their darkest nightmares.</p>
<p>While it is important to respect the local culture here and to be appropriately dressed at all times when in public, in many other parts of the world, people will gaily strip off their damp swimwear and parade around totally starkers. Not so much the British, though… British women are natural experts at changing clothes discreetly on beaches that lack appropriate facilities – even in the face of a typhoon, or an unexpected seagull attack. We instinctively know all sorts of Houdini-esque tricks with knickers and bra-straps that mean the swift and dignified change into a bikini is nothing short of an unfathomable magic trick. British men, on the other hand, tend to wobble about on one leg whilst clutching two ends of a towel between their teeth, inevitably swearing, falling face-first in the sand and shrieking to their wives in panic, “The arse is out!”</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://homesickandheatstruck.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/huts-2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-190" title="Enigmatic huts. What could they possibly be?" alt="Enigmatic huts. What could they possibly be?" src="http://homesickandheatstruck.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/huts-2.jpg?w=480&#038;h=360" width="480" height="360" /></a></p>
<p>Do you think these enigmatic huts might indeed be changing facilities? I do hope so! Or perhaps they will be emergency first aid depots. Or dovecotes. Or ice-cream stands. Or tin tents for people who can sleep standing up. Or nesting boxes for flamingos?</p>
<p>All suggestions would be most gratefully received&#8230;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/188/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/188/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/188/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/188/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/188/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/188/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/188/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/188/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/188/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/188/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/188/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/188/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/188/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/188/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=188&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://homesickandheatstruck.com/2013/02/15/invasion-of-the-mystery-beach-huts/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>29</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c18e9ab413828f40b67ce29019c7aa91?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lucystrange2012</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://homesickandheatstruck.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/huts-1.jpg?w=600" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mysterious huts</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://homesickandheatstruck.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/victorian-bathing-huts.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Bathing machines on Dover Beach. It looks a bit different these days...</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://homesickandheatstruck.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/huts-2.jpg?w=600" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Enigmatic huts. What could they possibly be?</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hoping For a Return to the US . . . No More</title>
		<link>http://mundocitizen.com/2013/02/04/hoping-for-a-return-to-the-u-s-no-more/</link>
		<comments>http://mundocitizen.com/2013/02/04/hoping-for-a-return-to-the-u-s-no-more/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2013 07:51:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Mundo Citizen</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Immigration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Barack Obama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Board of Immigration Appeals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Guardian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Irregular immigration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mexico]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U.S. government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mundocitizen.com/?p=492</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[After a forceful return to Mexico due to a deportation in 2009, rebuilding a life of 20 years in the U.S. can seem an insurmountable task. There is no doubt that I miss my friends, my community, my neighborhood&#8230;life as I knew it, was forever gone. I suppose that many other deportees as well as undocumented immigrants that [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=492&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After a forceful return to Mexico due to a deportation in 2009, rebuilding a life of 20 years in the U.S. can seem an insurmountable task. There is no doubt that I miss my friends, my community, my neighborhood&#8230;life as I knew it, was forever gone.</p>
<p>I suppose that many other deportees as well as undocumented immigrants that have returned to Mexico by choice are hopeful that someday they will return to the U.S.  Right after my arrival in Mexico, I felt the same way. I used my limited resources to contact my attorney to file a petition to re-open my case in hopes that an immigration judge could see the injustice done to me. I was only a nine year-old child brought into the U.S. by no choice of mine, living under a broken immigration system that did not allow me to change my status during my stay in the U.S., and with no criminal history, I was sent back to Mexico within hours after my detention.</p>
<p>My friends were also unwilling to accept that I could not return to the U.S. for at least 10 years. But unfortunately, <em>hope</em> did not overcome my unchanged legal reality - I had no means to be able to return legally to the U.S. and the Board of Immigration Appeals confirmed that when it denied my motion to re-open my case in 2011.</p>
<p>On the other hand, I feel fortunate that I was able to re-settle, at least temporarily, in a border town which is only a two-hour drive from my community of friends in Los Angeles.  I still get to see my friends that cross the border to visit me. In return, I tour them around a city that has much more to offer to tourists than the typical &#8220;Revolucion Blvd.&#8221; experience including  BajaMed food dining, wine tasting, and the breathtaking drive along the Baja coast. On their visits, we talk about our shared experiences and relive the cherished moments of the time I used to be &#8220;<em>en el otro lado&#8221;</em> (Spanish term to refer to the other side of the border). It does not take too long into our conversation when we begin talk about &#8220;my hopeful return&#8221; to the U.S. which is now 6.6 years away, assuming the best case scenario I get granted a pardon by the U.S. government.</p>
<div id="attachment_507" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://mundocitizen.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/tijuana-sd-border.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-507" alt="Tijuana-SD Border" src="http://mundocitizen.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/tijuana-sd-border.jpg?w=300&#038;h=177" width="300" height="177" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Tijuana-US Border &#8211; View of San Diego from &#8220;el otro lado&#8221; (the other side)</p></div>
<p>Over the last year, I began to experience a shift of perspective of my return to the U.S. as I realize that it is no longer my only option for a better life. Recently, I read an interesting piece in the <strong>The Guardian</strong> titled<a title="The Guardian" href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/feb/04/undocumented-migrants-reform-hopes-mexico" target="_blank"> Undocumented migrants back in Mexico hope to some day return to US</a> that made this contrast much clearer for me. It shared more stories of DREAMers just like me, that will not be able benefit from any type of immigration reform as they are back in Mexico, in their case by choice. Many of them had the same fears as I had of being unable to progress economically in Mexico, but with time are discovering that that such opportunities are also available in their own country.</p>
<p>For many of us that lived as undocumented immigrants in the U.S., our fears to restart a life in our native countries are based on conditions that we remember it to be when we left, and we expect it to be the same or worse when we are forced to return. In some cases, resettlement can be tough, especially for immigrants that do not have a skill that may be in demand, like being bilingual, or may lack the skills to find a job in growing industries such as manufacturing. Although we are still a developing nation with much more work to be done to improve the quality of life so its citizens are not forced to emigrate, I feel Mexico is no longer the country my parents escaped from in the early 1990s. Although at times it can be classified as mediocre, some progress has been made to grow a middle class and improve opportunities for employment.</p>
<p>I am not implying I would support all undocumented immigrants to return to their native country. I believe comprehensive immigration reform should be the first course of action. I do remain hopeful that a much anticipated immigration reform would solve the legal limbo of the 11.2 million undocumented living in the U.S.</p>
<p>Can I expect it to factor deportees and undocumented immigrants that are now residing outside the U.S.? I doubt any reform proposal will bring the flexibility needed in the immigration system to address our plight. Some will be waiting for an opportunity to rejoin family members in the U.S., and others like me, will have moved on to pursue the &#8220;American Dream&#8221; somewhere else.</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://mundocitizen.com/category/immigration/'>Immigration</a> Tagged: <a href='http://mundocitizen.com/tag/barack-obama/'>Barack Obama</a>, <a href='http://mundocitizen.com/tag/board-of-immigration-appeals/'>Board of Immigration Appeals</a>, <a href='http://mundocitizen.com/tag/guardian/'>Guardian</a>, <a href='http://mundocitizen.com/tag/immigration/'>Immigration</a>, <a href='http://mundocitizen.com/tag/irregular-immigration/'>Irregular immigration</a>, <a href='http://mundocitizen.com/tag/mexico/'>Mexico</a>, <a href='http://mundocitizen.com/tag/u-s-government/'>U.S. government</a>, <a href='http://mundocitizen.com/tag/united-states/'>United States</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/492/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/492/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/492/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/492/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/492/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/492/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/492/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/492/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/492/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/492/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/492/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/492/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/492/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/492/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=492&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://mundocitizen.com/2013/02/04/hoping-for-a-return-to-the-u-s-no-more/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/097b0d3f83eaa78f044705523867b6f5?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mundocitizen</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mundocitizen.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/tijuana-sd-border.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Tijuana-SD Border</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why I Feel Let Down By Marvel</title>
		<link>http://fairmountox.wordpress.com/2013/02/14/why-i-feel-let-down-by-marvel/</link>
		<comments>http://fairmountox.wordpress.com/2013/02/14/why-i-feel-let-down-by-marvel/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 19:12:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>shannongreaney</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[graphic novel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marvel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[she hulk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[super hero]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fairmountox.wordpress.com/?p=292</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[With the influx of super hero films, the awesomeness of Scott Pilgrim and the televised version of The Walking Dead, it hasn&#8217;t taken long for a bookworm like myself to start dabbling in the world of comics. I&#8217;m still fairly new to the genre and despite having titles and series that I want to read, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=292&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With the influx of super hero films, the awesomeness of Scott Pilgrim and the televised version of The Walking Dead, it hasn&#8217;t taken long for a bookworm like myself to start dabbling in the world of comics. I&#8217;m still fairly new to the genre and despite having titles and series that I want to read, I don&#8217;t really know where to start (other than the beginning, I&#8217;ve got that.) So, searching around and trying to avoid spending a lot of money on the Iron Man series, I&#8217;ve come across the super heroine &#8216;She Hulk.&#8217; Fair play, I thought &#8211; I appreciate that women haven&#8217;t been excluded from the world of the graphic novel; I appreciate that feisty, kick ass women are celebrated in amongst men who save the world. As a female reader, particularly one that has a background of being forced to read literature where women aren&#8217;t allowed to be promiscuous, are inferior to men and are pretty much forced into marriage by the end of the novel, graphic novels and their super heroines are a breathe of a fresh air. In fact, I&#8217;d say the fact that it&#8217;s a graphic novel celebrating kick ass women are encouragement enough to start exploring the genre.</p>
<p>Today I read that Marvel are trying to widen their target audience and fan base, there is an urge to generate interest from female readers. Their solution to this, of course, is the moronic step backward by making &#8216;She-Hulk&#8217; for example, a long-form fiction. That&#8217;s right, we&#8217;re headed straight back in<a href="http://fairmountox.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/shehulk-jpg22013813361.jpeg"><img class=" wp-image alignleft" id="i-301" alt="Image" src="http://fairmountox.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/shehulk-jpg22013813361.jpeg?w=256&#038;h=383" width="256" height="383" /></a>to the world of novels. Even worse, it&#8217;s already being defined as chick-lit which is inevitable really when the cover is a tube of green lipstick. It&#8217;s also going to be imaginatively called &#8216;The She-Hulk Diaries.&#8217; You know, just like The Vampire Diaries? Now, I understand that women probably do take more time out to read novels and I understand that Marvel will be able to communicate their super heroines across a new medium and more readers will become familiar with them; but this for me, undermines their whole aim to encourage females to read graphic novels.</p>
<p>The novel is set for release in June and the narrative will explore how She Hulk (Jennifer Walters) can balance her career as a lawyer with turning green and angry. That&#8217;s not all though, lucky females who this novel is aimed at will get to read about how the super heroine tries to balance her life with, wait for it, relationships. Who could have possibly have guessed that?</p>
<p>I personally feel really let down, not only are female readers being encouraged back into their secluded realm of long-prose, but we&#8217;re back to reading about the dependant woman. Now, the graphic novel series for all I know might be exactly the same. If that&#8217;s the case, Marvel really need to update their thinking about how they approach the problem of female characters and targeting the audience for them. Maybe I want my super heroine scantily clad, maybe I want to see actual graphics of her getting all green and angry. Maybe, just maybe I want the super heroines I&#8217;m reading about to be independent women that don&#8217;t need a man.</p>
<p>What I certainly don&#8217;t want is to be led back into the long prose genre, particularly when the representation of someone who is &#8220;super&#8221; comes down to a ridiculous shade of lipstick. Marvel are taking a step that makes a clear gendered distinction in the world of graphic novels and prose literature. Some of us girls want to read comics and personally, putting more creativity into the heroine&#8217;s name would be far more encouraging, She-Hulk seems a less than even half arsed effort. Once Marvel start to take pride in their own heroines as actual graphic novel characters, maybe female readers would be more willing to take time out for graphic novels.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/292/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/292/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=292&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://fairmountox.wordpress.com/2013/02/14/why-i-feel-let-down-by-marvel/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/17f0d174946b91d35a7b2f2a395eff63?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">shannongreaney</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://fairmountox.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/shehulk-jpg22013813361.jpeg?w=710" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Sorcerer\&#8217;s Method</title>
		<link>http://rhapsodistreviews.wordpress.com/2013/02/07/flashfic-11/</link>
		<comments>http://rhapsodistreviews.wordpress.com/2013/02/07/flashfic-11/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2013 08:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Alex Willging</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[The Written Word]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alex Willging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fantasy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flash Fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Literary Criticism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pop Culture Review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quality Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science Fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sorcerer's Method]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Rhapsodist]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rhapsodistreviews.wordpress.com/?p=11188</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[You might have learned about the scientific method in school, but you probably never saw it applied like this. Enjoy! &#8212; The Sorcerer&#8217;s Method, by Alexander Paul Willging Word Count: 658 “It won’t work like that.”  Sweat coursed through Dr. Bell’s goatee as he brought his staff to a defensive angle.  “Step back, Geoffrey.  I’ll cover [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=11188&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://rhapsodistreviews.wordpress.com/2013/02/07/flashfic-11/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a6c3769587f74f6bfbae98b4a3381a84?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">alexwillging</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Sip Heard \&#8217;Round the World</title>
		<link>http://semilledge.wordpress.com/2013/02/14/the-sip-heard-round-the-world-marco-rubios-desperate-grasp-for-a-tiny-gulp/</link>
		<comments>http://semilledge.wordpress.com/2013/02/14/the-sip-heard-round-the-world-marco-rubios-desperate-grasp-for-a-tiny-gulp/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 20:22:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>semilledge</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Florida Senator]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GOP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GOP response]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marco Rubio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SOTU]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[State of the Union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[water]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://semilledge.wordpress.com/?p=374</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[If, like me, your vote to watch Tuesday&#8217;s episode of &#8220;Dance Moms&#8221; was vetoed by nobler Americans in favor of watching the State of the Union address, you may have seen Florida Senator Marco Rubio deliver the GOP response. More likely is that in all your social media goings on, you&#8217;ve stumbled upon some sort [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=374&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If, like me, your vote to watch Tuesday&#8217;s episode of &#8220;Dance Moms&#8221; was vetoed by nobler Americans in favor of watching the State of the Union address, you may have seen Florida Senator Marco Rubio deliver the GOP response. More likely is that in all your social media goings on, you&#8217;ve stumbled upon some sort of reference to his awkward intermission and grapple for a tiny bottle of water.</p>
<p><a href="http://semilledge.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/marco-rubio-water-hed-2013.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image" id="i-379" alt="Image" src="http://semilledge.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/marco-rubio-water-hed-2013.jpg?w=642" /></a></p>
<p>Courtesy of adweek.com</p>
<p>Bless him. &#8220;Marco Rubio water&#8221; pops up in the Google search bar before you can even finish typing the poor guy&#8217;s last name. In case you missed it, <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=19ZxJVnM5Gs">here&#8217;s</a> the video. Or one of them. There are many YouTube submissions of the gaffe with titles ranging from the demure to &#8220;Marco Rubio is THIRSTY.&#8221;</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve always been a bit of a fan of Rubio&#8217;s, simply because, in the words of the Scottish Korean man from the <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4h3ewZxrqU4">Starburst commercial</a>, he&#8217;s a juicy contradiction. At 41-years-old, Rubio is the GOP&#8217;s next big thing. The Miami native is the son of Cuban immigrants, but only about 18% of Latino voters classify themselves as Republican. (Resurgent Republic has a great <a href="http://www.hispanicvoters2012.com">site</a> full of other statistics on Hispanics in America.)</p>
<p>I couldn&#8217;t tell you much about Rubio&#8217;s speech, aside from that uncomfortable reach off-screen for the world&#8217;s tiniest bottle of water. The media has dubbed the bottle snag &#8220;The new &#8216;Watergate.&#8217;&#8221;</p>
<p><a href="http://semilledge.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/art-rubio-2-1-620x349.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image" id="i-481" alt="Image" src="http://semilledge.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/art-rubio-2-1-620x349.jpg?w=610" /></a></p>
<p>Courtesy of theage.com.</p>
<p>Far from a scandal, &#8220;The new &#8216;Watergate&#8217;&#8221; has made Rubio look pretty darn good. It seems that the public has responded well to the gaffe. Rubio&#8217;s response? &#8220;I needed water. What am I going to do?&#8221;</p>
<p>An <a href="http://www.theage.com.au/technology/technology-news/the-new-watergate-rubios-awkward-sip-goes-viral-but-senator-has-last-laugh-20130214-2ee4x.html">article</a> on theage.com highlights some of the most hilarious tweets about the incident, in addition to explaining that Rubio had taped the response to the State of the Union in Spanish immediately before he addressed the nation. Of course the guy was thirsty.</p>
<p>An NPR <a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/monkeysee/2013/02/13/171903635/rubio-s-water-bottle-and-the-authenticity-craving?ft=1&amp;f=1001&amp;sc=tw&amp;utm_source=twitterfeed&amp;utm_medium=twitter">story </a>extolled Rubio&#8217;s authenticity. On a night where everything from suits to speeches to hugs and handshakes were choreographed, Rubio&#8217;s thirst may have been the only authentic thing. It generated an honest response, both on the part of the Senator and the public. It was obviously unplanned (that great big reach out of camera shot) and incredibly uncomfortable. And we ate it up.</p>
<p>So, my hat&#8217;s off to Senator Rubio. Thank you for providing us social media fodder and the opportunity to show off our water puns. But most of all, on a night that was planned to the T, thanks for giving us a little something human. Stay thirsty, my friend.</p>
<p><a href="http://semilledge.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/mqaskjq.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image" id="i-510" alt="Image" src="http://semilledge.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/mqaskjq.jpg?w=710" /></a>Courtesy of reddit.com.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/374/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/374/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=374&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://semilledge.wordpress.com/2013/02/14/the-sip-heard-round-the-world-marco-rubios-desperate-grasp-for-a-tiny-gulp/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>35</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/80cfd0ea65f0061d29b2630f103846c4?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">semilledge</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://semilledge.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/marco-rubio-water-hed-2013.jpg?w=642" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://semilledge.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/art-rubio-2-1-620x349.jpg?w=610" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://semilledge.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/mqaskjq.jpg?w=710" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The State of Obama’s Union</title>
		<link>http://jamesdboys.com/2013/02/13/the-state-of-obamas-union/</link>
		<comments>http://jamesdboys.com/2013/02/13/the-state-of-obamas-union/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2013 20:44:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dr. James D. Boys</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Political Perspectives]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2016 Presidential Election]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bill Clinton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marco Rubio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Medicare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[President Barack Obama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[State of the Union]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://jamesdboys.com/?p=1090</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[After the glitz and glamour of President Obama’s second inauguration, Washington finally got down to business last tonight with the State of the Union Address. This was another opportunity for the president to talk at Congress, if not necessarily to Congress. Certainly, he has not proved very adept at talking with Congress so far. The [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1090&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;"><span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='640' height='390' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/BiTyTJc92Bc?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span></p>
<p>After the glitz and glamour of President Obama’s second inauguration, Washington finally got down to business last tonight with the State of the Union Address. This was another opportunity for the president to talk at Congress, if not necessarily to Congress. Certainly, he has not proved very adept at talking with Congress so far. The State of the Union is the equivalent of the budget speech in the UK, an occasion of high politics and low manners, at which the president’s supporters cheer, his opponents boo and the pundits ponder. It is, if you will, presidential pantomime.</p>
<p>The State of the Union address has evolved with the nation. Until 1913 it was merely a written report delivered to Congress as required by the Constitution. Later, it was delivered in person, but as late as the 1960s it was delivered in the afternoon with little consideration for the growing TV audience. However, with the rise of the Imperial Presidency came the emergence of the State of the Union as a Prime Time event, scheduled with military precision and designed to be one of the signature events in the Washington, D.C. calendar. It is an all too rare opportunity for the president to address both houses of Congress, the members of the Supreme Court and a TV audience that has reached as high as 52.4 million in 2009.</p>
<p>Of course, give ‘em and inch and they will steal the evening, and some presidents have been known to talk and talk, none more so than Bill Clinton, who in 1995 and 1999 came dangerously close to talking for 90 minutes. That’s the length of a football game, but without the change of ends at half time. Perhaps Clinton’s verbosity can be forgiven in light of his incredible capacity to ad-lib the first 20 minutes of his 1994 State of the Union Address, when the incorrect speech was loaded into his TelePrompter. Slick? Absolutely. Thank goodness he never went into the car business. For this, after all, is a presidential sales pitch; an opportunity for the president to demonstrate his mastery of Washington and to talk directly to the American people, literally over the heads of Congress and to ask for support on issues that half of the chamber would resist tooth and nail.</p>
<p>This year was no different. Forget any misperceptions about a new term and a new start in which Republicans and Democrats put aside their differences for national unity. The State of the Union, despite the theatrics, is about cold, hard politics and the stakes are higher than ever with the president determined to push ahead with his priorities; climate change, nuclear weapons reduction, gun control, tax reform, immigration reform and the withdrawal of forces from Afghanistan. All were touched on, dwelt on or in some cases lingered over last night, as the president sought to press the right buttons within the chamber, with viewers at home and with the all important ‘randomly selected group of voters’ who were being polled for instant feedback and which will do much to drive the direction of policy in the months ahead.</p>
<p>Obama opened by announcing, “The state of our union is stronger.” But stronger than what precisely? Mexico? Greece? A house of cards? Bill Clinton used to intone, “The State of our Union is strong.” Such a declaration would be welcome in 2013, but would appear to be merely a useful fiction. Obama’s address covered a wide range of issues; a smorgasbord of delights for his supporters, and a sack of ashes for his opponents. There was little here that was unexpected, little here that was conciliatory and little here that will alter perceptions or feelings on either side of the political aisle. As expected there were no niceties from the president, or anything except superficial pleasantries from his opponents in the chamber. Neither side are in the mood for compromise. Both have recently been re-elected, with new mandates to continue doing what they have been doing for the past 4 years.</p>
<p>Medicare reform was proposed, coupled with a plea to “save hundreds of billions of dollars by getting rid of tax loopholes and deductions for the well-off and well-connected.” Tax reform was not going to be a topic that kept viewers glued to their seats, but it was what was being proposed, along with job creation proposals to stimulate the economy. This was, in many ways, a speech that could have been given a year ago as America prepared for an election campaign, and was, therefore, an indication of how little has been achieved in the last twelve months.</p>
<p>Immigration reform was addressed as the president laid claim to having put “more boots on the southern border than at any time in our history,” and having reduced “illegal crossings to their lowest levels in 40 years.” One wonders how the government claims to be able to record the rate of illegal crossings whilst being unable to prevent them? Obama proposed a concept of Earned Citizenship, “a path that includes passing a background check, paying taxes and a meaningful penalty, learning English, and going to the back of the line behind the folks trying to come here legally.” The big question, however, must surely be: How long before drones are patrolling the boarders to prevent such incursions? Perhaps that will be addressed next year.</p>
<p>It had already leaked that 34,000 American personnel would be withdrawn from Afghanistan this year and that the combat mission would be complete in 2014, but the president reiterated the fact nonetheless. Good news, it seems, will be taken wherever it can be found. For that matter, enforced measures are always better if they can be presented as a generous offer, hence the president’s revelation that the White House would “engage with Congress to ensure…that our targeting, detention, and prosecution of terrorists remains consistent with our laws.” Such a declaration was the result of revelations that have emerged from the Senate Confirmation hearings that have been continuing on Capitol Hill and which look set to rumble on, with questions remaining in relation to kill or capture policies.</p>
<p>The time allocated to foreign as opposed to domestic affairs was telling. Traditionally, presidents have spent their first terms addressing domestic issues and their second on international relations, seeking to win Nobel Prizes. President Obama, of course, has done both already, having passed health care reform in his first 2 years and won the Nobel Peace Prize in his first year in office. Accordingly, this does all rather risk becoming The Curious Case of Barack Obama; the man who lived his presidency in reverse and so what Obama does for his second act will be telling. He cannot run for re-election, so he could be courageous and take on vested interests and lobby groups that have previously been untouchable. Last night he addressed the issue of gun violence that has received so much media coverage of late. However, he didn’t campaign on this issue and has said previously that he has no intention of removing guns from gun owners. This has not prevented gun shops from doing a roaring trade from customers who fear the end is neigh for their right to bear arms. This was, however, the emotional highpoint of the speech, as the president insisted that victims of gun violence “deserve a vote” and urged Congress to declare where they stood on the issue that has killed over a thousand Americans since the shooting at Sandy Hook Elementary School. Long before that vote is even contemplated, however, it appears that the chance of reform in this area is dissipating fast.</p>
<p>For whilst Obama is beyond the reproach of voters, his party is not, so again, discount any notion of a president free to do as he wishes for the next four years. He will come under intense pressure from those who are seeking to replace him in 2016 not to stray from the mainstream for fear of driving voters from the Democratic Party and into the hands of the Republicans on a whole range of contentious issues that could decide the next two election cycles. For make no mistake, the American system of government is geared up for campaigning, not governing. In less than two years the entire House of Representatives and a third of the Senate will have been re-elected, and once that is out of the way, all eyes will turn to the presidential election of 2016 and any residual political clout that Obama retains at that point will rapidly disappear.</p>
<p>With so much at stake it is little wonder that the president’s opponents are ill-prepared to allow him the entire spotlight and now they get the chance to respond in a rather down at heel address shortly after the president speaks, in a process that actually serves to demonstrate the gulf that exists between the President of the United States and any other mere mortal. This year’s lucky contestant was Marco Rubio, the Republican Senator from Florida, by way of Havana. Senator Rubio is the Republican Party’s Great Hispanic Hope in 2016, so it was no surprise that he was selected to respond to the president, in what is in all probability the opening salvo of the 2016 election. In his response, Senator Rubio urged the president to abandon his ‘obsession’ with higher taxes, but his moment in the national spotlight was sullied by his decision to take a breather and provide Poland Spring bottled water a much needed product placement. Such are the little things that memories of such events are made of.</p>
<p>&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;</p>
<p>Dr. James D. Boys is a Visiting Senior Research Fellow at King’s College, London. He maintains a website at <a href="http://www.jamesdboys.com/">www.jamesdboys.com</a> and can be followed on Twitter @jamesdboys</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1090/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1090/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1090&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://jamesdboys.com/2013/02/13/the-state-of-obamas-union/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f1a3f80f3da71a68c32e8a2ebe88c57d?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jamesdboys</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
