<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2012 22:02:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>The Swifts, Conflict, Decision Making &amp; Following Dreams</title>
		<link>http://theperpetualvagabond.com/2012/09/18/the-swifts-conflict-decision-making-and-following-my-dreams/</link>
		<comments>http://theperpetualvagabond.com/2012/09/18/the-swifts-conflict-decision-making-and-following-my-dreams/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2012 21:08:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>The Perpetual Vagabond</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[conflict]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[decision making]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fear]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[following your dreams]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life lessons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Portland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[swifts]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://theperpetualvagabond.com/?p=1141</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Last night I went to watch the swifts in Portland, who every September on their fall migration roost in the chimney of Chapman School in NW Portland. Watching the swifts is one of my favorite fall activities in this city, as hundreds of people come out with their families and friends and have picnic dinners [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1141&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://theperpetualvagabond.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/swifts-2.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1143" title="Swifts  2" src="http://theperpetualvagabond.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/swifts-2.jpg" alt="" width="525" height="347" /></a></p>
<p>Last night I went to watch the swifts in Portland, who every September on their fall migration roost in the chimney of Chapman School in NW Portland. Watching the swifts is one of my favorite fall activities in this city, as hundreds of people come out with their families and friends and have picnic dinners on the steeply sloped hill, while watching thousands of birds swirl into the chimney at sunset. It’s a beautiful community event and I try to go see it at least a few times during the season.</p>
<p>But, last night turned out to be more than just a nice night of watching the beauty of nature and the strength of community. I learned something about myself that took me by surprise and has left me a bit unsure of where to go next. It came about during a conversation about past relationships, in which I said to my friend, “we broke up because we fought too much…although I have never fought with anyone else I’ve dated…” and then it hit me; I haven’t fought with ANYONE else since we broke up, not boyfriends, not friends, not bosses, not my mother, not anyone. Suddenly I was slapped in the face with the realization that for the past 4 years I have been avoiding conflict at all costs.</p>
<p>I knew that I had changed quite a bit since the summer of 2008, and I often liked my new amicable self, but I also had slowing been losing my path, unable to make decisions, developing patterns of self isolation and becoming even more flighty than before. I had many potential explanations for my behavior; my most important long-term relationship had ended, I was in graduate school, the economic recession was making opportunity sparse, and I was dealing with issues of self worth and confidence. All normal things that happen in life, but for 4 years I had been trying to address these issues so that my life could be better and I could maybe discover some idea of how to live my dreams, but nothing ever worked.</p>
<p>So over the last 4 years I have looked at everything in this quest for clarity; my jobs, my living situations, my diet, my hobbies, my friends, my spirituality, everything. I have sought out therapy, Naturopaths, energy work, new friends, new adventures, new jobs and homes, but still nothing brought me to a place that felt right. It was like I forgot who I was and I was now just trying on different lives to see if they fit. I developed an inability to make real decisions instead opting for whatever presented itself to me in the moment. But, it never occurred to me that most of this might be the result of developing a pervasive avoidance of conflict.</p>
<p>Now I think it is reasonable to avoid unnecessary conflict, but when you avoid conflict at all costs you become willing to give up just about everything in order to keep the peace. You give up your hopes, desires, and the things that are most important to you. You isolate yourself from any situation that might evoke deep emotions. And you find ways to justify people’s bad behavior so as not to have to confront it. Avoiding conflict makes you begin to think that being nice is more important than being authentic.</p>
<p>Over the years I have started to feel successful in my interpersonal life because people began to perceive me as nice and pleasant to be around. I no longer got comments that I was “opinionated” and “bitchy”. People would talk about how kind and diplomatic I was. Which are all great things to be and it felt good to be this way, but it has all been at the expense of pursing my passions and dreams. I have not found a balance; I just swung from one extreme to the other.</p>
<p><a href="http://theperpetualvagabond.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/swifts-1.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1142" title="Swifts  1" src="http://theperpetualvagabond.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/swifts-1.jpg" alt="" width="525" height="792" /></a></p>
<p>And now I can see so clearly how it all started and it had nothing to do with my ex boyfriend that I did all the fighting with (it just occurred around the same time we broke up). It was during my second year serving in AmeriCorps, where I worked as an environmental educator in the mountains of Idaho. For the first three months everything was great, I loved my coworkers, my job and the town. As a group we worked well together and had a great dynamic. We did however avoid any real conflict which left things stewing under the surface, unaddressed. Then, just after winter break everything changed; the group finally let what was simmering come out and conflict erupted into an all out battle. And as an opinionated, stubborn, process oriented person I met it head on with dire consequences. I became the group’s scapegoat for all conflict; everything was my fault, which it sometimes was, but definitely not always.</p>
<p>For months every time the group had an issue I would be placed in the central point of blame and criticized for anything I said or did. It was horrible and I didn’t know what to do to fix it. I was in a constant state of anxiety and defensiveness. It wasn’t until I came down with a fortunate (yes I said fortunate) case of food-poisoning in which I was out of commission for a whole week and the group (in my absence) continued to have conflict and therefore had to acknowledge that maybe it wasn’t always my fault. A few of my coworkers decided to stand up for me and bring the issue of how I was being treated to the group. So, after months of dealing with conflict by making me the scapegoat, we finally had to address the real issues that were plaguing our group and I was finally allowed to move on with my life without constant harassment and negativity.</p>
<p>Unfortunately by this point, I had already completely shut down and must have subconsciously vowed never to do anything that would put me in that position again. I turned inward, began to avoid groups, and quickly lost my ability to make decisions. I became paralyzed with anxiety over doing anything that might upset someone or make someone think I was being contrary. I stopped speaking up or asking for what I wanted. And unfortunately, I was never able to make the connection that my sudden change in personality and behavior came from this very difficult experience and the resulting subconscious coping strategies.</p>
<p>And I now realize that my coping strategies have consumed my life. Being unable to make decisions, I stared to create predictable patterns that make my decisions for me. I go to the same restaurants, order the same foods, do the same things with the same people on a regular basis, wear the same clothes and generally leave the rest up to chance. I have learned to always be ok with whatever anyone else chooses, I no longer am a picky eater, I reserve my opinions for groups of people I know agree with me (and I can always see the opposition’s side and understand why they feel the way they do), I avoid people who I know have strong beliefs and tend to get worked up over them, and I spend more and more time alone.</p>
<p>I even recently decided that I wanted to live alone (even though I have a great, affordable house, with great roommates) because I feel like I’m always having to compromise, never acknowledging though that I never ask for what I want, never being willing to address my concerns or feelings with the people I live with. I would rather move out than discuss something that might not be pleasant. I’d rather run away than make things work.</p>
<p><a href="http://theperpetualvagabond.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/swifts-3.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1144" title="Swifts  3" src="http://theperpetualvagabond.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/swifts-3.jpg" alt="" width="525" height="349" /></a></p>
<p>So, that brings me to today. This whole realization just came crashing down in a torrent of insight and clarity, but now I don’t know what to do with it. Seeking out conflict doesn’t seem like the answer, but I clearly need to face my fear and maybe learn about strategies for effective conflict resolution instead of conflict avoidance. I know I don’t want to go through the rest of my life not authentically living with purpose because I am too afraid of being criticized or attacked for my choices. I want to have the courage to follow my dreams even if it may involve some unpleasantness. And I want to find a balance between being kind and diplomatic and being strong and living with conviction.</p>
<p>It’s gotten to the point where I don’t even know what I want anymore because it has just been easier to go with the flow and let things happen, than to risk being confronted for my choices. The problem is that this is incredibly uninspiring and leaves me feeling lost and confused most of the time as well as dependent on the spontaneity of others to keep my life interesting and fulfilled. And it makes my relationships unbalanced and inauthentic and leaves me feeling isolated from those I care about.</p>
<p>So, I guess my lesson is that sometimes going and watching the swifts is just a nice way to pass the time, but sometimes watching animals live out their purpose in life makes us question our own and helps us better understand our true nature. Fear is an amazingly powerful thing that can bury us under its weight if we don’t keep it in check. If the swifts were afraid of coming home to roost because of the peregrine falcons that prey on them each season, then the whole ecosystem would collapse. The swifts don’t avoid their journey because of the battle that awaits them at that chimney, they show up every year without fail and remind us that the journey is hard, but we have to go on it anyway.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1141/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1141/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1141&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://theperpetualvagabond.com/2012/09/18/the-swifts-conflict-decision-making-and-following-my-dreams/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/9aceb8eb433c56c4fba2eea0fc25b8c4?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">theperpetualvagabond</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theperpetualvagabond.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/swifts-2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Swifts  2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theperpetualvagabond.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/swifts-1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Swifts  1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theperpetualvagabond.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/swifts-3.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Swifts  3</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Poetry: Drafts of &#8216;Split My Thumb&#8217;</title>
		<link>http://monkeymoonmachine.com/2012/09/16/poetry-drafts-of-split-my-thumb/</link>
		<comments>http://monkeymoonmachine.com/2012/09/16/poetry-drafts-of-split-my-thumb/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2012 21:34:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>MonkeyMoonMachine</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Nonfiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Poems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[teaching writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[word play]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing process]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://monkeymoonmachine.com/?p=161</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Last week, in the creative writing classes I teach, we read Richard Hugo&#8217;s essay &#8220;Writing off the Subject,&#8221; and then I asked my students to write a poem in the way Hugo describes: starting from a particular idea, following the lead of one&#8217;s inner voice to end up at a new idea, a new place, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=161&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://monkeymoonmachine.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_6248.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-173" title="IMG_6248" src="http://monkeymoonmachine.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_6248.jpg?w=300&h=225" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a>Last week, in the creative writing classes I teach, we read Richard Hugo&#8217;s essay &#8220;<a href="http://ualr.edu/rmburns/RB/hugosubj.html" target="_blank">Writing off the Subject</a>,&#8221; and then I asked my students to write a poem in the way Hugo describes: starting from a particular idea, following the lead of one&#8217;s inner voice to end up at a new idea, a new place, something one hadn&#8217;t planned to say (Hugo implies a method like that in his discussion of &#8220;Autumn Leaves&#8221;). I followed the same instructions, and below are two free-writing drafts before the final (for now) draft.</p>
<p>But here&#8217;s the difficulty, of course: the real writing process is in my mind, and what&#8217;s in the drafts below is only the residue. Since my mind during freewrites tends to work associatively, I can&#8217;t explain why one thing led to another. And I can&#8217;t describe why I ended up with the poem I did, except to say that it felt right, it felt interesting. It might not even interest me later.</p>
<p>A student brought up a good question: when does an artist ever know when a poem is ready for publishing on a blog?  I don&#8217;t really know, I said, thinking out loud that the costs are low, which encourages publishing, but is the poem worth sharing? That answer requires thinking about what readers might appreciate, but also about being willing to send writing out that isn&#8217;t perfect. I guess my answer for these things below is  that the creative writing process is mysterious enough, and fascinating enough, that I want to discuss it, and these are at least a model, if a poor one.</p>
<p><strong>Freewrite 1</strong></p>
<p>(The two freewrites were hand-written, but the final poem was composed via word-processor. This freewrite started from the prompt word &#8220;surge,&#8221; given by a random word-lookup technique &#8212; picking shards of words out of newsprint that had been through a shredder &#8212; and an image/memory of a finger being jammed while playing basketball came to mind.)</p>
<p><em>Surge into the top joint, the basketball did, and rough skin slid back into my hand and pores spread open, air met body, lines decline to limit the me from the sky &#8212; the nearby sky the air-ocean we are pressed down by – impressed – tender is the light that strikes us – surge, the burst surges out from me and yet I stay the hand, the skin the sh!t box – swipe the keen face of the tandem bike rhizomes – strawberry marmalade takes tokens from toad </em></p>
<p><strong>Freewrite 2:</strong></p>
<p>(I took &#8220;rough skin&#8221; and &#8220;tandem bike rhizomes&#8221; from the previous freewrite, and then tried to let go, encourage words to come to mind without being too particular about which words got written down. It&#8217;s a process skill that has taken me a while to get good at doing.)</p>
<p><em>Rough skin slid back into my hand and pores spread open.  The world – the air confronts an enemy, the closed sealed entombed world of the blood – the inner sanctum where air is blocked – and tandem bike rhizomes – and air is the enemy, air is the enema, and toads kill the healing vice – the red rice bucks company plans – the rough skin slid again (over?) my hand – pores opened, veins poured open, the blood leaks like a radiator, like a brake line, and I push and no resistance – the blood leaks out – it’s under pressure inside, like a break line, like a family – the air is the enemy but the body pushes out the blood – the air-skin boundary – where I stop – leaks into air – where a r becom – I likes into a r to become “air” – where I becomes it</em></p>
<p><strong>Final &#8212; for now &#8212; draft:</strong></p>
<p>I liked the image of the air-ocean and the body-air boundary, but wanted to be more concrete, less philosophical here, and so I went with a description of an event that really had happened to me days earlier, which event-image had been in my mind as I had written earlier about the body-boundary. This poem is  blunt, which was an intentional &#8212; at this point in the process &#8211; choice of voice/mood, and so I was restricting my word choices to one-syllable ones where possible. When I am less self-restrictive, more automatically voiced, in my freewriting, longer words tend to come out (see my recent poem, written the same week, using a similar process, called &#8220;<a href="http://monkeymoonmachine.com/2012/09/16/poem-the-whistle-of-heat/" target="_blank">The Whistle of Heat</a>&#8220;).  I made a choice to use spare language here, to show as rawly, bluntly, physically as possible, the action &#8212; with my impulse to make interpretive associations held in check.</p>
<p><em>The stainless-steel paring knife </em><br />
<em>splits my thumb where it </em><br />
<em>backstopped </em><br />
<em>a tough tomato skin. </em><br />
<em>Blood comes to the air. </em><br />
<em>A paper towel </em><br />
<em>records</em><br />
<em>the blood drop </em><br />
<em>as a red dot. </em></p>
<p>This was where the poem stopped as the class period ended, but I was feeling like there could have been more added to it. I&#8217;m not sure more was needed, I&#8217;m not sure what the more would be, but I remind myself that poems don&#8217;t need to be long &#8212; I&#8217;m just not sure I&#8217;m entirely satisfied with this poem being short.</p>
<p>But I do like the simplicity of the images: skin being split by a knife, blood &#8220;comes&#8221; (&#8220;oozes&#8221; or &#8220;spurts&#8221; didn&#8217;t seem right, nor did the idea from earlier of blood under pressure seem interesting in the end) to air, and the implication of the verb &#8220;record&#8221; &#8212; that the body may not keep the record of the blood, blood being temporarily and not permanently liquid, but that the paper might &#8212; our bodies write themselves into their surroundings, the 3-D drop of blood becoming a 2-D stain, etc.  As I talk <span style="text-decoration:underline;">about</span> the poem, I could associate further, but this poem&#8217;s strength, such as it is, comes from being minimal.</p>
<p>Of course, this demonstration can&#8217;t really be a tutorial of how to write a poem &#8212; a new poem, at its most creative, has no model, and <a href="http://artsbeat.blogs.nytimes.com/2007/10/19/stray-questions-for-kay-ryan/" target="_blank">so is a new island</a>, so this  demonstration cannot be imitated the way other modeled skills can be. And writing about a process like this feels like that quote about how writing about music is like tap dancing about sculpture (or <a href="http://quoteinvestigator.com/2010/11/08/writing-about-music/" target="_blank">various other activities</a>).  A new poet must figure out her own process.  But as a teacher, I&#8217;d hope to give at least an idea of a path &#8212; those suggestions seemed to help me, I recall.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/161/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/161/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=161&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://monkeymoonmachine.com/2012/09/16/poetry-drafts-of-split-my-thumb/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>17</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f9815331c6e870a8b372510b74ac85f1?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">inschoolsuspension</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://monkeymoonmachine.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_6248.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_6248</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What Makes a Post Freshly Press-able: A Space For Learning</title>
		<link>http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2012/09/19/what-makes-a-post-freshly-press-able-a-space-for-learning/</link>
		<comments>http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2012/09/19/what-makes-a-post-freshly-press-able-a-space-for-learning/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2012 14:01:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Cheri Lucas</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Freshly Pressed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tactics/Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[better blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing tips]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dailypost.wordpress.com/?p=10193</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Every day, 19 WordPressers are featured on the Freshly Pressed section of WordPress.com. And every day, many more wonder, “What do I have to do to get Freshly Pressed?” Well, it’s time to reveal what the folks who push the launch button are thinking. Each week, a member of our editorial team will do a [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=10193&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Every day, 19 WordPressers are featured on the Freshly Pressed section of WordPress.com. And every day, many more wonder, “What do I have to do to get Freshly Pressed?”</em></p>
<p><em>Well, it’s time to reveal what the folks who push the launch button are thinking. Each week, a member of our editorial team will do a close-up on one post and why we thought it was Press-worthy. We hope we can provide insight into the process and give you tips and tools to make your blog the best it can be.</em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________________</p>
<p>Pamela Moran&#8217;s recent post, <a href="http://spacesforlearning.wordpress.com/2012/09/13/abandoning-the-space-shuttle-a-lesson-for-educators/">Abandoning the Space Shuttle&#8230;a Lesson for Educators</a>, resonated with me, and I&#8217;ve thought about it numerous times since I promoted it to Freshly Pressed last week. I&#8217;m enthusiastic about Pamela&#8217;s post not just because it&#8217;s original, but because it&#8217;s at once timely and reflective. She tackles something topical—NASA&#8217;s space exploration—but also uses personal experience to frame and shape the post. Through this lens, she weaves a unique and much larger discussion about the state of 21st-century education.</p>
<p>Here are three ways she does this:</p>
<p><span id="more-10193"></span></p>
<h2>She uses a metaphor to connect disparate topics in a natural way.</h2>
<p><a href="http://spacesforlearning.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/earths-orbit-the-silhouet-002.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-10204" title="A Space For Learning" src="http://dailypost.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/a-space-for-learning-2.jpeg?w=300&h=225" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a>In the introduction, Pamela grounds us by recounting a recent talk by retired space shuttle astronaut Kathy Thornton. Kathy said NASA abandoned the shuttle program—a tough decision—to dream up a new, bold human narrative of space exploration for the 21st century that moves beyond orbiting Earth. &#8220;Otherwise,&#8221; writes Pamela, &#8220;the current program doomed NASA’s astronauts to circling the globe in low space orbit, over and over and over again.&#8221;</p>
<p>After describing this evening with Kathy, Pamela states:</p>
<blockquote><p> I thought that night—just like kids doomed to sitting in rows, facing the same direction, doing 20th century test prep worksheets over and over and over again. When she finished speaking, I couldn’t help but think that <em>we educators </em><em>are caught in low orbit work, too.</em></p></blockquote>
<p>I felt that Pamela&#8217;s connection between the abandonment of the space shuttle program and the stunted state of education is natural and fitting, evoking visuals of shuttles in low orbit and apathetic students at desks. You don&#8217;t have to be a space enthusiast or educator to understand this metaphor. Through it, she weaves a fresh, intriguing discussion about two separate topics: space exploration and education.</p>
<p>If you want to experiment with metaphors in your own posts, consider different subjects that interest you. Can you find connections? Crafting a metaphor can be tricky, and you need to be sure the comparison you are drawing is not contrived. Furthermore, using a metaphor may not be appropriate for every post. Read your writing aloud to be sure it makes sense and doesn&#8217;t sound forced.</p>
<h2>The language is appropriate and accessible.</h2>
<p>A commenter on last week&#8217;s &#8220;What Makes a Post Freshly Press-able?&#8221; post talked about the <em>authority </em>of a blogger. Must a writer be an <em>expert</em> to write about a topic? Fellow bloggers commented that we don&#8217;t have to be seasoned journalists or established sources to share our thoughts; the blogosphere has room for many modes of writing.</p>
<p>That said, Pamela establishes credibility in both space exploration and education through her word choice. In the first paragraph, she writes:</p>
<blockquote><p>[Kathy's] earned that right, having been key to several major payload deployments into space including the first service work on the Hubble telescope. She’s a real-deal spacewalker.</p></blockquote>
<p><a href="http://spacesforlearning.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/curiosity.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-10208" title="Curiosity" src="http://dailypost.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/curiosity-2.jpeg?w=500" alt=""   /></a>Above, Pamela establishes her authority with insider speak such as &#8220;payload deployments.&#8221; But in the next sentence, she balances the jargon with more accessible language: &#8220;she&#8217;s a real-deal spacewalker.&#8221; She&#8217;s authoritative, but doesn&#8217;t distance herself from us.</p>
<p>She also strengthens her metaphor with precise (and evocative) word choice. She uses phrases like &#8220;shuttling test prep cargo&#8221; and plays with language:</p>
<blockquote><p>If NASA is doing it, shouldn’t we also “go boldly where no educators have gone before?”</p></blockquote>
<p>Reworking a well-known phrase, like this one from <em>Star Trek, </em>may help readers to identify with your topic and engage in your discussion.</p>
<p>In your own writing, pay attention to the words you use. Are you using the best adjective? Is there a more appropriate noun that matches your tone or the mood you want to create? Don&#8217;t worry too much about word choice when writing your first draft. Structure your post, do a round or two of editing, and <em>then</em> zoom in on revising specific phrases and words.</p>
<h2>Links support stats and information.</h2>
<p>Lastly, Pamela supports her post with links to external sources, but doesn&#8217;t overwhelm readers with <em>too many </em>links—it is possible to link too much! Many posts on WordPress.com—such as information-heavy pieces on science, politics, and history—include percentages, statistics, and monetary figures. Your discussions are stronger and more reliable when you cite and link to credible sources.</p>
<p>For more posts from Pamela, visit <a href="http://spacesforlearning.wordpress.com/">A Space for Learning</a>.</p>
<p>So, tell us: Do you think this is an appropriate selection for Freshly Pressed?</p>
<p><em>For more on our Freshly Pressed content, check out <a href="http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2012/09/12/what-makes-a-post-freshly-press-able-the-rise-of-ebooks-evil-or-essential/">last week’s Freshly Press-able post</a>, read our roundup of <a href="http://en.blog.wordpress.com/2012/09/04/freshly-pressed-editors-picks-for-august-2012/">Editors’ Picks for August</a>, or read <a href="http://en.support.wordpress.com/freshly-pressed/">So You Want to Be Freshly Pressed</a>.</em></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/10193/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/10193/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=10193&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2012/09/19/what-makes-a-post-freshly-press-able-a-space-for-learning/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>32</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/36207d4c7c014b0999b995ca3971d383?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">CL</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dailypost.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/a-space-for-learning-2.jpeg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">A Space For Learning</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dailypost.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/curiosity-2.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Curiosity</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>WordPress Powers Politics</title>
		<link>http://vip.wordpress.com/2012/09/13/wordpress-powers-politics/</link>
		<comments>http://vip.wordpress.com/2012/09/13/wordpress-powers-politics/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2012 19:52:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Peter Slutsky</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Case Studies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2012]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[campaign]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[candidate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[congress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[democrats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[election]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[republican]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vip.wordpress.com/?p=6656</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[WordPress is the most powerful content management system in the world &#8211; today it powers just under 17% of the top one million websites in the world. Millions of people from across the globe turn to WordPress to build websites of all shapes and sizes and across all different categories. Now that the political conventions [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=6656&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:left;"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-6661" title="infographic-header" src="http://vip.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/infographic-header.png?w=640&h=122" alt="" width="640" height="122" /></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">WordPress is the most powerful content management system in the world &#8211; today it powers just under 17% of the top one million websites in the world. Millions of people from across the globe turn to WordPress to build websites of all shapes and sizes and across all different categories.</p>
<p>Now that the political conventions are over and we have officially turned the corner towards the November election, WordPress.com VIP is proud to release this infographic which clearly shows that WordPress is now the backbone that powers websites from across the political spectrum.</p>
<p>Check it out!</p>
<p><a href="http://vip.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/wordpress-com-vip-politics-infographic-final-1.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-6663" title="WordPress Powers Politics - Infographic" src="http://vip.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/wordpress-com-vip-politics-infographic-final-1.png" alt="" width="759" height="1896" /></a></p>
<p>This research project started when we began to notice that more and more political websites were being built on WordPress. We focused on a couple of key categories: state parties, U.S. House races, U.S. Senate races, and Gubernatorial races. We looked at all of the major-party candidates across these categories and manually checked to see what content management system was being used. We were excited by the results and thus, they became the impetus for this lovely infographic.</p>
<p>If you want to learn more about WordPress for your political website, or any other purpose, get in touch with the WordPress.com VIP team <a href="http://vip.wordpress.com/contact/">here</a>.</p>
<h3>Spread the Word</h3>
<p>Copy the embed code below to share the infographic on your own site:</p>
<p><pre class="brush: xml; auto-links: false; gutter: false;">
&lt;a href=&quot;http://vip.wordpress.com/2012/09/13/wordpress-powers-politics/&quot;&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;WordPress Powers Politics -- compiled by WordPress.com VIP: Enterprise Hosting and Services for WordPress&quot; src=&quot;http://vip.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/wordpress-com-vip-politics-infographic-final-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;WordPress Powers Politics - Infographic&quot; width=&quot;759&quot; height=&quot;1896&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
</pre></p>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=6656&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://vip.wordpress.com/2012/09/13/wordpress-powers-politics/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a496fa3fc8dd609938802f54b9e96563?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">peterslutsky</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://vip.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/infographic-header.png?w=640" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">infographic-header</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://vip.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/wordpress-com-vip-politics-infographic-final-1.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">WordPress Powers Politics - Infographic</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The New Bizarre Online Security Questions</title>
		<link>http://kristenbrakeman.com/2012/09/17/the-new-bizarre-online-security-questions/</link>
		<comments>http://kristenbrakeman.com/2012/09/17/the-new-bizarre-online-security-questions/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2012 19:57:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>krisbrake</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[comedy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[websites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[passwords]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[website]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://kristenbrakeman.com/?p=337</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Blatant rip off of Jerry Seinfeld here, but what is the deal with those online security questions lately? They used to be so easy, so straightforward, like what’s your mother’s maiden name, high school mascot, or favorite pie? But now these questions have gotten strange.   Either the website designers are trying hard to foil the [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=337&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://kristenbrakeman.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_72261.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-341" title="IMG_7226" src="http://kristenbrakeman.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_72261.jpg?w=300&h=213" alt="" width="300" height="213" /></a></p>
<p>Blatant rip off of Jerry Seinfeld here, but what is the deal with those online security questions lately?</p>
<p>They used to be so easy, so straightforward, like what’s your mother’s maiden name, high school mascot, or favorite pie?</p>
<p>But now these questions have gotten strange.   Either the website designers are trying hard to foil the hackers or, as I suspect, they’re just really, really bored.  What else could account for these bizarre questions?<br />
ACTUAL SECURITY QUESTIONS:</p>
<p><strong>What was your favorite game to play as a child?</strong>  Good Lord, who on earth would remember such a thing?  And do they mean board game like Dream Date, or kickball or hide and seek?  I need some clarity here.</p>
<p><strong>What was your dream job as a child?</strong>  You mean when I was a five and wanted to be a princess – does that count as an actual job?</p>
<p><strong>What was your favorite place to visit as a child?</strong>  Okay really people, let’s think about this for a second &#8211; if I can’t remember my password, one I likely created only a month ago, why do you think I can remember what games I liked to play, or what I thought, or what I felt back when I was a child, so many eons ago?</p>
<p><strong>What was the name of your first pet?</strong>  Sandy.  Uh, oops, darn.  Now you all know.</p>
<p><strong>Where is your great grandmother buried? </strong> My great-grandmother.  Seriously?  Well, I never met her and don’t even know her first name so I’m gonna guess I don’t know where she’s buried either.  But I’ll take a stab at it &#8211; in a grave?</p>
<p><strong>What is your favorite food?</strong>  Easy:  shrimp and pasta.  Oh and hamburgers.  And that ahi tuna sandwich with avocado at that place on Third.  I like Sushi too.  Also steak and baked potato with sour cream.  And garlic bread with spaghetti.  God I’m so hungry now.</p>
<p><strong>What was your hair color as a child?</strong>  I don’t like what you’re implying there mister.</p>
<p><strong>Where were you when you heard about 9/11?</strong>  Huh?  Holy crap.  Here I was having a perfectly good day and now I’m thinking about that horrible morning and, jeez, people, come on.</p>
<p><strong>What is the coolest place you’ve ever visited?</strong>  Gosh, that seems really subjective.  Is there some hip meter I’m supposed to use to decide?  I’ll have you know I’ve been to lots of hip places because I’m pretty cool and . . . wait, oops I didn’t have my reading glasses on.  Apparently it’s “What’s the coldest place . . . ?”  Still, no idea.</p>
<p><strong>Who spoke at your high school graduation?</strong>   The valedictorian.  Hmm, what was her name again . . . brown hair . . . over-achiever . . . went to Berkeley and uh . . . ”</p>
<p><strong>What is the license plate (registration) of your dad&#8217;s first car? </strong> Let’s see, since my dad bought his first car about a decade before I was born I’m not sure I remember that.  Why stop there?  What was the thesis of my dad’s sophomore year history term paper?  What was he thinking back on July 18th, 1952?  How many hairs did he have on his head?</p>
<p><strong>What is the first name of the boy or girl that you first kissed? </strong> Why, that would be my husband of course.  Ahem.  That’s the story I’m sticking with.</p>
<p><strong>What is your dream vacation? </strong> Oh this is easy – Fiji.  Wait no, that takes too long to get to.  I know, Grand Cayman.  Yes I&#8217;ve always wanted to go there!  Oh, but I’ve also heard that the Bahamas are quite nice, and then there are a lot of wintery places I want to see.  The Alps, Banff, The Himalayas &#8211; how will I ever narrow this down?<br />
<strong> </strong><br />
<strong>What is the name of a college you applied to but didn&#8217;t attend? </strong> Gee, thanks for bringing up that old wound.</p>
<p><strong>What sports team do you love to see lose? </strong> That’s a very negative question.  These programmers must be a ton of fun to be around.  Frankly I don’t care who wins or loses as long as they’re serving cold beer.</p>
<p><strong>What is the name of your least favorite relative?</strong>  Whaaat?  I can’t believe that people have a least favorite relative and even if they did, wouldn’t they feel guilty actually typing their name?  Because what if you die and that is the one relative who is able to crack your password codes to access your accounts and then they see their name listed there as your least favorite relative?   That’s too much of a risk for me, and my backstabbing cousin Jennifer.</p>
<p>I’m mentally exhausted from answering all their questions.  I think this website knows more about me now than my therapist ever did.  I could use a cold beer . . . on Fiji . . . and that Ahi Sandwich from that place on Third.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/337/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/337/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=337&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://kristenbrakeman.com/2012/09/17/the-new-bizarre-online-security-questions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>60</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/ec3dec4ecebba632499276baec169dd7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">krisbrake</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://kristenbrakeman.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_72261.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_7226</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Louie’s Choice: Lynch, Dads &amp; the Weird Chain of Causality</title>
		<link>http://deartelevision.wordpress.com/2012/09/17/louies-choice-lynch-dads-and-the-weird-chain-of-causality/</link>
		<comments>http://deartelevision.wordpress.com/2012/09/17/louies-choice-lynch-dads-and-the-weird-chain-of-causality/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2012 07:51:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lili Loofbourow</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Louie]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deartelevision.wordpress.com/?p=476</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Dear Dear TV, God, I loved these two episodes. Loved ‘em for the thrills, the gossipy content (Late Night wars!), but also, and mainly, because of their weird chains of causality. Tom Cruise doesn’t like surprises, so Louie goes on The Tonight Show. The maid refuses to Not Disturb, and it’s thanks to her that [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=476&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dear Dear TV,</p>
<p>God, I loved these two episodes. Loved ‘em for the thrills, the gossipy content (Late Night wars!), but also, and mainly, because of their weird chains of causality. Tom Cruise doesn’t like surprises, so Louie goes on <em>The Tonight Show</em>. The maid refuses to Not Disturb, and it’s thanks to her that he gets up, checks his phone, and makes it to his meeting with the head of CBS. These are chains of causality we know: a crazy person explains to you that a remote control is counterintuitive, then murder suicides his whole family. This, in some deep, deep way, is the world we live in.</p>
<p>It’s not like surrealism is new to Season 3 of <em>Louie</em>, but sometimes (for me, anyway) Louie’s been hitting his uncanny baseballs out of the park. It’s a home run, sure, but I’d rather see the ball, catch it, take it home. If I had to group the show’s balls (So To Speak) into two camps, then Uncle X and Bizarro-Louie are In, and so is everything up to and including the window breaking in <em>Dad</em>, but the runaway scene is Out. Never-the-kid shitting in the tub is in—so’s throwing the rug out the window. Never causing traffic accidents and eating raw meat is out. Parker Posey’s in, Chloe Sevigny’s out. Ramón and all of <em>Miami </em>is in, along with Maria Bamford, Mark Maron, crabs, and even the crazy pharmacist grilling the lady on her bowel movements. When the surrealism gets too broad, it starts to get too dream-sequencey. If you’ve ever taught creative writing, then you know how legendary the And Then I Woke Up ending is, and by legendary I mean universal and lame.</p>
<p>Louis CK’s at his best when he’s showing us the inside of Louie’s head while showing us the outside world too in a way that shows the angle of distortion. The distinction I’m asking for is exactly the one he makes in <em>Late Night: Part 2</em>, when the show cuts between Louie watching Jackie Doll on the monitor with the music-glory vs. Jackie in “real life”.</p>
<p>Speaking of surrealism going outside the stadium, I watched all of <em>Twin Peaks</em> this last spring. When it ended I understood how everyone who watched <em>Lost</em> and complained about it endlessly truly felt. It’s a THERE IS NO GOD feeling. It stinks, because you’ve invested so much energy and thought in a show, trying to work out its premises, how it’s coding its mysteries, and then it turns out it was all just sort of slapped together with no real plan. Crazy lady with an eye patch! Ha, she’s strong! Um, cousin who looks exactly like Laura! Evil owls! A fake diary and a real diary! Dwarf! Giant! Billy Zane!</p>
<p>Not that I don’t like <em>Twin Peaks</em>—I have real affection for it in retrospect and I think parts of it are amazing mood pieces, but that doesn’t change the Disappointment With Dave. He’s SO the Wizard of the Oz after Dorothy’s gone behind the curtain.</p>
<p>And that’s what Louie keeps offering us—<em>here</em>! He keeps saying. <em>I’m drawing the curtain back! Here’s comedian world. Here’s single fatherhood. Here’s what late-show negotiations are like</em>. And that’s what differentiates Louie from Lynch: where Lynch withholds information and turns plot points into shallow riddles, Louie just keeps giving you all the answers.</p>
<p>“Five years ago you probably peaked,” says the CBS guy, one of many Men Behind the Curtain in the Late Night series.  “You do standup. You make 80,000 a year on your club dates. You don’t think you can do it. You think it’s over and you’re afraid to try. … I’ve seen it, and I’ve seen it turn around.”</p>
<p>CBS knows EVERYTHING. But it won’t lie about the future. The CBS guy is part Wizard and part Sphinx, just as powerful, just as vast in its perspective, and just as honest about how the world works:</p>
<p>“If the test is good, I’ll put you on the air. And then, if you’re a hit, everyone will think I’m a genius, and I’ll have saved the network about 12 million. If America hates you, no one’s gonna blame me. … But you’ll take the heat on all that. You’re gonna crack your head on the ceiling and you’re gonna go down, probably for good. “</p>
<p>Do you have chills? Because that’s a novel right there. Who puts that idea—that crazy enormous modern-day <em>Rise of Silas Lapham</em> of an idea—into the mouth of a CBS executive? HOLY COW. This is Satanic temptation meets genie meets, I don’t know, <em>Indecent Proposal</em>.</p>
<p>And there’s more!</p>
<p>“Look Louie, we’re talking about the big game here, so forgive me if I use big terms. Here’s the reality. In ten years you’re gonna be teaching comedy at a community college to support your kids, and falling asleep to the Late Show with Jerry Seinfeld. You’re circling failure in a rapidly decaying orbit. … But it’s in your power to change that.”</p>
<p>And this is where Part 1 ends—beautifully, because it could so easily have made the point of the episode Louie’s Yes or Louie’s No. Instead, it leaves the viewer with the agonizing question in the air. WHAT WOULD YOU DO?</p>
<p>Let’s just pause for a minute and think about how much less interesting this scene would have been if we were seeing it only through Louie’s anxious eyes. Say the CBS exec started getting bigger and bigger in the room while Louie got younger and younger. It would have been SO stupid, right, because <em>that’s what’s happening anyway</em>. The next episode is all about Louie being surrounded by Dads.</p>
<p>Louie downplays his smarts, which makes him better than Lynch in the sense that he’s (supposedly) keeping our expectations low. See his explanation of how he hired the actress who plays Janet for an example of this Oh, I Just Decided And Fuck It Everyone Will Be Fine With It sort of attitude. But let’s face it: dude’s a genius, and it would su-u-u-ck if he wasn’t putting serious thought into this stuff, which he obviously is. It’s no coincidence that the index cards in the background of wherever Jay Leno’s calling from say “Adam Smith,” “Products For A Better You,” and “Halloween Products.” There it all is: cutthroat competition, Louie’s self-improvement program, and Jay’s scare tactics.</p>
<p>But anyway, back to the chain of causality. Things in <em>Late Show: Parts I</em> and <em>II</em> are good and bad in pretty stupid ways in the moment (damn the maid! She woke me up!), but those outcomes are actually just steps toward some bigger, blustery whole. (Shot at the Late Show! Thank the maid!) Nothing in the world really connects to anything else the way it’s supposed to: that you were flown into LA for <em>The Tonight Show</em> in no way guarantees that you are going to perform on <em>The Tonight Show</em>. But there’s slant continuity, to use <a href="http://deartelevision.wordpress.com/2012/09/05/recapping-from-the-green-room/">Jane’s coinage</a>: you’ll always get either much more or much less than you want. Having planned 4.5 minutes for late-night television, you’re either going to get bumped or else you’ll just stay, pointing finger-guns at the audience, forever.</p>
<p>The trouble is that there’s no right vantage-point from which to look at the future. The end of Late Night: Part 1 is a true cliff-hanger, and the head of CBS is every inch the Satanic tempter as the music plays mournfully behind him.</p>
<p>What surrealism there is (how many different phones were ringing in Louie’s hotel room by the time he picked up?), it all <em>feels</em> extremely real. The baseball is within the stadium. Take these old men asking you to do truly odd things, then blaming you a little for not getting it right. They blow past your faults too, that’s how little you matter. “You don’t need to tell ‘em your name, son.” And yet, if you’re Louie, you have all these new dads who keep throwing you in the water, giving you black eyes.</p>
<p>And oh, what a precious kind of surrealism that is, because it’s damn close to how different generations see each other anyway. The Old Men in the business of show communicate telegraphically, so accustomed are they to being read correctly and to having their frame of reference be the only frame. “Carnegie Deli,” says the head of CBS after calling the lawyer in, and we waffle off-balance, like Louie, trying to figure out what to do with those words. Is Carnegie Deli the lawyer’s name? Is it a part of speech? There’s no context for what those two words mean, but they’re hovering in the air, awaiting a response.  By the time we’ve recognized the phrase, it’s too late—the conversation has moved on. “Timing is everything,” says David Lynch, after Louie fails to perform an activity that Jackie Doll seems to think is Telling A Joke.</p>
<p>Do Not Turn This Off, says the index card in Jackie Doll’s booth, Just Turn The Intensity Down.</p>
<p>I do want to register a minor complaint re: Janet’s conversation with Louie, and it’s that their talk felt too rational. These people are divorced. They coparent, certainly, but there’s a painful past locked up there. Aaron Bady, with whom I was watching this episode, observed that when Louie tells Janet his news and she immediately says, “Cuz you’re cheap,” there should have been a moment of annoyance. I felt that when she says, “You’d have a job” and he says “I have a job,” his annoyance, his sip of water, the  bad silence that follows&#8211;it all suggests something bigger than what comes next. Their body language is great. It’s uncomfortable, and bitter.  That sounds like an old fight, and no such fight gets sipped away. If you’re Janet in that fight, if you spent years being mad because Louie’s job wasn’t reliable (and it sounds like it was an issue, even though she says she appreciated him supporting them), you push that harder, you don’t just zoom out into a reflection on his career arc and say, in a moment of generosity: this is what it’s all been building up to. “If you don’t do this, what was it all for. … What did I put my nine [years] in for?”</p>
<p>But that’s beside the point. The real object of that conversation (besides reestablishing Louie’s passivity and need to have every woman with whom he comes in contact explain him to himself) is to redefine the Right Thing To Do. We’ve talked a lot here at Dear TV about how central Louie’s fatherhood is to the show, so for Janet to redefine what being a good father means for Louie is a big deal. “You’ve been a fine father, but nobody needs a father that much,” she says. YOWCH. His job isn’t to be there for the kids, she says, reestablishing a definition of masculinity and fatherhood that&#8217;s as old as the Reagan and Nixon jokes. His job is to make it.</p>
<p>And that achieves something remarkably interesting: it means that Louie, in order to <em>be</em> a good father, has to <em>submit</em> to this old crop of show-business fathers at the very moment he’s losing his brother Chris Rock, who shaved and ditched the collar and donned the infamous late-night suit. I’m looking forward to seeing how this goes.</p>
<p>No today jokes yet. You&#8217;re not ready.</p>
<p>Lili</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/476/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/476/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=476&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://deartelevision.wordpress.com/2012/09/17/louies-choice-lynch-dads-and-the-weird-chain-of-causality/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/534a37c7b68fddb380fcdd3bec3e21d2?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">millicent</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Six Six Six: On Instagram</title>
		<link>http://totalebag.wordpress.com/2012/09/18/666/</link>
		<comments>http://totalebag.wordpress.com/2012/09/18/666/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2012 05:01:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>@emilybelden</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[There's a point to this, I swear.]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[generation y]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[instagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zuckerberg]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://totalebag.wordpress.com/?p=1393</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I set up an Instagram account (emilybelden). And I kind of hate it. First off, let it be known I have nothing against photos. I have nothing against sharing (unless it&#8217;s food or boyfriends). But when you put the two together, the magical reaction that six million other filter-loving photographers seem to have is just [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1393&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I set up an Instagram account (emilybelden). And I kind of hate it.</p>
<p>First off, let it be known I have nothing against photos. I have nothing against sharing (unless it&#8217;s food or boyfriends). But when you put the two together, the magical reaction that six million other filter-loving photographers seem to have is just not happening for me. The thought that I am app-impotent has crossed my mind more than once.</p>
<p>My key observation about it so far is as follows: this thing is god&#8217;s gift for solid 6&#8242;s. Go ahead try it: load a photo of someone who is average-looking, filter it, and try to tell me they don&#8217;t immediately become at least an 8 thanks to a deeper contrast and an orientation that doesn&#8217;t allow for the ability to zoom. A buffer for bad pictures? That fact alone should make it my go to camera device. But for now, I just see it for what it is: a wingman for the world.</p>
<p>Also, it makes everyone and everything appear to be vacationing in California, circa 1974. While this is slightly obnoxious, the good news is that everyone seems to be having fun. I mean, think about it: have you ever seen someone Instagram something that looked like pure hell? No one takes the time to filter a photo of an overflowing toilet. You don&#8217;t see many fender benders on there. No one is applying Kelvin to their mystery rash and leaving it up to their followers to diagnose it. That shit is reserved for Facebook now. Sorry, Zuckerberg. How does it feel to know your brainchild has become the receptacle of everything that blows about being gen-Y&#8217;er?</p>
<p>Alas, I&#8217;m trying my hardest to get into the groove, but nothing seems to be sticking. My photos are sporadic and unoriginal. So yes, that means my feed is  essentially a photographic essay of the teenage mind. And after posting an ensemble of cute dogs, giant cupcakes, and the occasional good hair day, it has become evident I have zero hobbies and a terrible eye for good Instagrams. Who knew knew there&#8217;d be so much pressure associated with creating a collage of my extremely mundane life? Do I get a bye because I&#8217;m a writer and I think in terms of words, not pictures? Ugh.</p>
<p>Regardless, I refuse to greet the next big thing with disdain. After all, I work in social media and have to embrace the things that contribute to my paycheck in a round-about way. So, to the two people who are following me, and to the one who consistenly &#8220;likes&#8221; my photos because he thinks it will translate into sexual activity, I thank you. Thank you for keeping me on track with chronicling my life, one solid 6 at time.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1393/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1393/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1393&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://totalebag.wordpress.com/2012/09/18/666/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>32</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/60136e8e8edaa29c359b8452db5b4a7d?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F0.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">emilybelden</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>I Was Wrong About Occupy Wall St.</title>
		<link>http://stefanbc.wordpress.com/2012/09/17/i-was-wrong-about-occupy-wall-st/</link>
		<comments>http://stefanbc.wordpress.com/2012/09/17/i-was-wrong-about-occupy-wall-st/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2012 21:22:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>kennystevenfuentes</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[US Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DFH's of the World UNITE!]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Drum circles and patchouli]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Occupy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[S17]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://stefanbc.wordpress.com/?p=2063</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It’s September 17th, 2012. One year ago, the Occupy movement began its first action in Zuccotti Park. My initial response to the movement was that of skepticism. Having come of age during the anti-war protests of the early 2000’s, I felt certain the movement would devolve into nothing more than a couple of drum circles [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2063&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://stefanbc.wordpress.com/2012/09/17/i-was-wrong-about-occupy-wall-st/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>58</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/4277b283caf60726d686d7d2f113a473?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">kennystevenfuentes</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://stefanbc.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/bain.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Bane Capital</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is Occupy One?</title>
		<link>http://politicsoutdoors.com/2012/09/16/is-occupy-one/</link>
		<comments>http://politicsoutdoors.com/2012/09/16/is-occupy-one/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2012 04:40:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>David S. Meyer</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[99 percent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[democracy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[elections]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[horizontal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[influence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Occupy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Occupy Wall Street]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[organization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tea party]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zuccotti Park]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://politicsoutdoors.com/?p=2847</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I mean: is Occupy now one year old?  Is it still around?  Is it unified? A year ago on September 17, the Occupation of Zuccotti Park began, with a beautiful poster and far less participation and promise than it soon showed.  Journalists and activists want to make sense of what&#8217;s left now that the Occupations [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2847&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.marketplace.org/sites/default/files/styles/primary-image-610x340/public/occupy_0.jpg"><img class="alignleft" title="Occupy anniversary" src="http://www.marketplace.org/sites/default/files/styles/primary-image-610x340/public/occupy_0.jpg" alt="" width="488" height="272" /></a>I mean: is Occupy now one year old?  Is it still around?  Is it unified?</p>
<p>A year ago on September 17, the Occupation of Zuccotti Park began, with a beautiful poster and far less participation and promise than it soon showed.  Journalists and activists want to make sense of what&#8217;s left now that the Occupations are gone.  There will be commemorations and evaluations everywhere.  (I participated in one yesterday at <em><a href="http://www.marketplace.org/topics/economy/occupy-wall-st/lasting-legacy-occupy-wall-street-remains-unclear" target="_blank">Marketplace;  </a></em>the 20 minute interview condensed to 5-7, which is how these things go.)</p>
<p>Most evaluations are unlikely to be very optimistic.  Occupations across the United States&#8211;and around the world, were surprising, very visible, disruptive, and unpredictable.  The organization was confusing to outsiders, and the goals of the occupations were hard to <img class="alignright" title="Occupy wall street" src="http://www.enduringamerica.com/storage/blog-post-images/OCCUPY%20WALL%20STREET%20BALLERINA%20BULL.jpg?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1320144095051" alt="" width="182" height="276" />pin down, not the least because activists differed in both their ultimate objectives and in their visions of how to achieve them.  Occupations saw their diversity as a strength, and were reluctant to adopt organizations that silenced or back burnered anyone.  In the name of democracy and horizontalism, nothing very specific came to the fore.  But critics were reluctant to acknowledge the very clear concerns with political and economic inequality.</p>
<p>The unwieldy and time consuming governance at the Occupations made it hard for Occupiers to agree on anything beyond continuing their encampments, and local governments refused to let them do so. <a href="http://politicsoutdoors.com/2012/04/30/occupy-on-may-day/" target="_blank">Once the occupations ended</a>, Occupy was a lot harder for journalists to cover and to make sense of, and much less visible to a broader public.  To be sure, meetings and actions continued, but without an overarching unity.  And if you weren&#8217;t following the right sites or plugged into an active network, Occupy just slipped from visibility.</p>
<p>Elections crowd out social movements in America, sucking up attention, activists, and money.  Many people redirect their efforts from issues to candidates, compromising a message for a messenger.</p>
<p>The Tea Party, still visible in national politics, mostly through a few Washington-based groups and the Republican Party, has made this move vigorously.  With some disappointment, Tea Party organizations and activists have embraced their 29th choice for the Republican nomination, Governor Mitt Romney because, whatever his flaws, they see him as preferable to another term of President Obama.</p>
<p>Occupy activists were determined not to let this happen, to face a fate like that of the movement that helped provoke them, to wind up sucked in and sold out by a politician who would use them offering only slight reforms.  They refused to build formal organizations, open national offices, or endorse candidates, emphasizing the grassroots as an alternative approach.  But there are risks associated with that strategy as well: lack of a clear message, lack of visibility, difficulties in mobilizing broadly, and difficulties in influencing mainstream politics.  That&#8217;s what we now see.</p>
<p>So, activists are trying to use the anniversary to revivify Occupy&#8211;or at least remind Americans that they and their concerns are still out there.</p>
<p><a href="http://s17nyc.org/schedule/s17/" target="_blank">#S17NYC</a>, representing the 99 percent, will work to resume an Occupation &#8220;with non-violent civil disobedience and flood the area around it with a roving carnival of resistance.&#8221;  Several groups have already turned out to protest, and police have arrested <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/09/15/occupy-wall-street-anniversary-arrests-ows_n_1887421.html" target="_blank">dozens of would-be Occupiers in New York City and elsewhere</a>.  The authorities will certainly be better prepared and less tolerant of Occupations than they were a year earlier.</p>
<p><img class="alignleft" title="Occupiers return" src="http://msnbcmedia.msn.com/i/reuters/2012-09-15t195704z_1372910904_gm1e89g0ary01_rtrmadp_3_usa.jpg" alt="" width="454" height="300" />It will be hard to re-raise a mass movement during the last phase of the electoral campaign, but Occupy campaigns across the country will continue to search for events and issues that will spark the imagination in the same way that the first Occupation did.</p>
<p>In the meantime, thousands of young people cut their political teeth sleeping outside in public spaces around the United States.  They&#8217;re not done, even if we don&#8217;t see what they&#8217;re doing now.</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://politicsoutdoors.com/category/uncategorized/'>Uncategorized</a> Tagged: <a href='http://politicsoutdoors.com/tag/99-percent/'>99 percent</a>, <a href='http://politicsoutdoors.com/tag/democracy/'>democracy</a>, <a href='http://politicsoutdoors.com/tag/elections/'>elections</a>, <a href='http://politicsoutdoors.com/tag/horizontal/'>horizontal</a>, <a href='http://politicsoutdoors.com/tag/influence/'>influence</a>, <a href='http://politicsoutdoors.com/tag/occupy/'>Occupy</a>, <a href='http://politicsoutdoors.com/tag/occupy-wall-street/'>Occupy Wall Street</a>, <a href='http://politicsoutdoors.com/tag/organization/'>organization</a>, <a href='http://politicsoutdoors.com/tag/politics/'>politics</a>, <a href='http://politicsoutdoors.com/tag/tea-party/'>tea party</a>, <a href='http://politicsoutdoors.com/tag/zuccotti-park/'>Zuccotti Park</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2847/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2847/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2847&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://politicsoutdoors.com/2012/09/16/is-occupy-one/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>44</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/7f7a14b665bdd02f0fac00ab8c62c836?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">politicsoutdoors</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://www.marketplace.org/sites/default/files/styles/primary-image-610x340/public/occupy_0.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Occupy anniversary</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://www.enduringamerica.com/storage/blog-post-images/OCCUPY%20WALL%20STREET%20BALLERINA%20BULL.jpg?__SQUARESPACE_CACHEVERSION=1320144095051" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Occupy wall street</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://msnbcmedia.msn.com/i/reuters/2012-09-15t195704z_1372910904_gm1e89g0ary01_rtrmadp_3_usa.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Occupiers return</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What&#8217;s In a Name?</title>
		<link>http://kimberlypackard.wordpress.com/2012/09/18/whats-in-a-name/</link>
		<comments>http://kimberlypackard.wordpress.com/2012/09/18/whats-in-a-name/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2012 00:20:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Kimberly Packard</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[character development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[editing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[indie publishing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[literature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[names]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[novel writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[novels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[publishing industry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shakespeare]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://kimberlypackard.wordpress.com/?p=732</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[That which we call a character By any other name smell as sweet? Juliet may have been trying to soothe her lover&#8217;s concerns over their warring families, but I completely disagree with her notion that a name is a meaningless convention. One of the greatest gifts &#8211; or curses &#8211; a parent can bestow upon [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=732&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://kimberlypackard.wordpress.com/2012/09/18/whats-in-a-name/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>166</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/da1ba815748222b27b0376ccda6cf192?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">kimberlypackard</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://kimberlypackard.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/rose.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Rose</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>