<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2013 21:02:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>I Confess.  I Cheated.</title>
		<link>http://dfsalvador.com/2013/01/23/i-confess-i-cheated/</link>
		<comments>http://dfsalvador.com/2013/01/23/i-confess-i-cheated/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 14:13:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>dfsalvador</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Current Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scrabble]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lance Armstrong]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cheating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[school]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[morals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[competitive advantage]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dfsalvador.com/?p=700</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[You’re in school taking the most important and hardest class you’ll ever take.  There’s a lot of pressure because if you make an A you’ll be guaranteed a job.  A B might get you the job depending on how everyone else in the class does.  But you’re pretty confident because you’ve worked harder than your [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=700&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://dfsalvador.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/cheat.png"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-704" alt="cheat" src="http://dfsalvador.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/cheat.png?w=300&#038;h=58" width="300" height="58" /></a></p>
<p>You’re in school taking the most important and hardest class you’ll ever take.  There’s a lot of pressure because if you make an A you’ll be guaranteed a job.  A B might get you the job depending on how everyone else in the class does.  But you’re pretty confident because you’ve worked harder than your classmates.</p>
<p>First test you make a B.  A few of your classmates make Cs and Ds but the majority make As, and you wonder how they did that.  Soon, you hear that one of your classmates has a copy of all the semester’s tests, obtained perhaps by cleverly hacking into the professor’s computer.  The ones who are cheating ask if you’d like to come over and “study” with them for the next test.  You decline because you don’t want to be a cheater.</p>
<p>You study more than you did for the last test because you know you have to just to keep up.  You end up with a B plus.  They make As again.  They’re contacted by job recruiters.  You are not.  Even some of the ones who made Cs and Ds on the first test are now making As, moving you closer to the bottom of the pack.  You’d like to tell on them, but you have no proof.  Besides, that would really tick off the whole group, and they pretty much detest you anyway for your goody-two-shoes routine.</p>
<p>You do what you have to.  You join them.  You make your A.  You get the job.  You’re financially independent and so happy about that.  You get married and have kids, whose piano and tennis lessons you can pay for thanks to that good job.  Your family is happy.  No regrets.  You and your college buddies laugh about that class years later.</p>
<p>Now you’ve got this great job in a tight economy.  Again, you’re working your butt off, eating lunches at your desk, never taking sick days or personal days, yet the productivity of your co-workers is surpassing your own.  You know they’re cutting corners, backdating documents, shredding customer complaints and doing what they can to stay a step ahead of the curve.  One misstep and they could be fired.  They know that.  You know that.  At the same time, you know that management tacitly condones this behavior as long as they don’t make an obvious blunder that forces management’s hand.  You have a family and hate taking risks especially when it comes down to your livelihood.  However, you wonder that if you can’t keep up with the pack and their inflated numbers, you might lose your job.   You give up vacations, work on holidays, extend your work week to eighty hours just to do what your co-workers claim they do in a forty hour week.  You have your integrity.  You keep up this pace for twenty years, put your kids through college, watch them have families of their own, and finally you retire.</p>
<p>When you look back, you wonder what it would have been like to spend just a little more time with your kids?  You regret not spending more, because when it comes down to it, isn’t the family the most important thing?  You feel bitter at the rest of the world who seems happier than you with fewer wrinkles around the eyes.  They never faced the consequences of their misdeeds.  Or were they really misdeeds?  You wonder if making three follow up calls and fibbing on the required fourth would have made that much of a difference.</p>
<p>We face these kinds of tough decisions every day, sometimes without even considering the moral and ethical significance.  Cheating and getting ahead is the easy decision.  Choosing not to cheat is the tough one.  However, cheating does, after all, imply getting a competitive advantage.  What if you are at a competitive disadvantage if you don’t cheat because everybody else is?  It’s easy to justify it in our own heads when we are pursuing our goals to be successful and respected.</p>
<p>Let’s be honest.  What we all want is to be successful.  Society puts pressure on us to be successful.  In our culture, success is measured by the acquisition of things.  A businessman who nets one million dollars is more successful than one who nets a hundred thousand dollars.  No one asks to compare their bookkeeping or business practices.  An NBA superstar who has five championship rings is more successful than one who doesn’t have any.  Even successful parents are ones who produce successful children, children who are able to obtain a lot of things and money.  Sometimes we need to see ourselves as successful.</p>
<p>It’s time for me to come clean.  I am a Scrabble cheater when it comes to games played on my mobile device.  At first I just played against a friend at work against whom I racked up a record of twenty wins and no losses.  I branched out and began playing other players online.  I’d lose a few games here and there, but I was much more serious about the game than ninety-five percent of the other people that I played, so that in itself gave me an advantage.  There was one guy I liked to play.  We’d have close games but I’d win about eighty percent of the time.  Then his average score suddenly shot up by sixty points.  I’d been playing long enough to know the difference between making good use of the board and pulling insane words out of nowhere, and not just crazy two or three-letter goofy words like ZO and ZA that every Scrabble player with a hundred games under his belt begins to know.  These were words like ALUNITES or HODJAS or ORIGAN (no, not “origin” or “Oregon” but &#8220;origan&#8221;, in botany, another name for marjoram).  I didn’t want to directly accuse him of cheating but I sent him a message that said, “Are you a Muslim botanist and chemist?” to which he replied, “No.  Someone just played these words against me once, and I remembered them.”</p>
<p>Whatever.  I knew he was cheating.  It’s easy to hop onto the internet and use an anagram solver, and no one on the other side can ever prove it.  He started beating me.  It made me mad.  I watched my win/loss record fall below ninety percent, not that it really matters since no one but me ever looks at it.</p>
<p>So then, I started doing it, using the anagram solvers.  I started to beat him again.  And it felt <i>good.  </i> I didn’t feel guilty about it.  If that’s the way he wants to play, that’s the way I’ll play, I told myself.</p>
<p>The point of all this is not to suggest that cheating is the proper way to go but merely how easy it is to justify to ourselves that not only is cheating the better way but also the vital way.  There is an insane pressure placed on us from birth to succeed, and although many of us are brought up in the Christian tradition of humility and charity, we all know that piety and moral purity are not the main criteria society considers when labeling a person a success.</p>
<p>Since we are social beings, how others see us <i>is</i> so important to how we define and view ourselves.  We want others to like us and we naturally hide our flaws.</p>
<p>So now we come to Lance Armstrong.  Of course I had to watch his interview with Oprah.  I genuinely feel bad for him not because I sympathize with what he did but because I can only imagine how painful the fall from the top to the thorny pit of despair must be.  The truth is, we’ve all been in his situation.  You might say my Scrabble example is nothing like Lance Armstrong because there was nothing really at stake.  But really, that makes my actions even more preposterous.  The only thing at stake was my own vanity.</p>
<p>I’ve talked to some who might understand why he cheated, but cannot tolerate the way he viciously went after the people who accused him of cheating.  Anyone who has had an affair and is trying to hide it will scorch the earth before they reveal their lie.  It’s not noble or right.  It’s just a desperate attempt to stay above everything and scrape and claw at whatever might catch before the inevitable avalanche sends us tumbling down the mountain.  The deeper and more important the lie, the more people we are willing to hurt to protect it.  The way I see it, a man at his worst is usually no worse than most men.</p>
<p>To be clear, I’m not excusing Lance Armstrong’s behavior.  His titles should be stripped, a ban implemented, and his legend in the sport of racing tarnished.  But I don’t hate him either.  I’m just considering the reality that Lance Armstrong, like us all, is human.  Perhaps <em>that</em> is the biggest disappointment.</p>
<p><a href="http://dfsalvador.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/lance.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-708" alt="lance" src="http://dfsalvador.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/lance.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/700/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/700/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=700&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://dfsalvador.com/2013/01/23/i-confess-i-cheated/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/d027c489057b9feedaba746e01f0952a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">dfsalvador</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dfsalvador.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/cheat.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cheat</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dfsalvador.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/lance.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lance</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Teaching White Privilege in Education: Is it Important?</title>
		<link>http://whitemomblog.com/2013/01/23/teaching-white-privilege-in-education-is-it-important/</link>
		<comments>http://whitemomblog.com/2013/01/23/teaching-white-privilege-in-education-is-it-important/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 13:55:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>White Mom</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[being white]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[conversation starters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[current events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[motherhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[white privilege]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://whitemomblog.com/?p=114</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The other day, I came across a tweet about a Wisconsin school being investigated for teaching white privilege. Apparently, a parent at this particular school became very upset after reading the content of a course her son was taking titled &#8220;American Diversity.&#8221; The mother felt the curriculum was being used to teach white students that they [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=114&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_132" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://whitemomblog.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/freeimage-8577967.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-132 " alt="http://www.stockfreeimages.com/" src="http://whitemomblog.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/freeimage-8577967.jpg?w=300&#038;h=200" width="300" height="200" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text"><a href="http://www.stockfreeimages.com/" rel="nofollow">http://www.stockfreeimages.com/</a></p></div>
<p>The other day, I came across a tweet about a Wisconsin school being investigated for teaching white privilege. Apparently, a parent at this particular school became very upset after reading the content of a course her son was taking titled &#8220;American Diversity.&#8221; The mother felt the curriculum was being used to teach white students that they are racist and oppressive. She also felt the lesson on white privilege made her son feel unearned guilt for being white.</p>
<p>I can&#8217;t speak to how the material was presented or what the exact lesson plans were, but my takeaway is simple: kids aren&#8217;t the only ones who need these lesson—adults do, too.</p>
<p><span id="more-114"></span></p>
<p>I went to a diverse high school in Seattle, but I had no idea what white privilege was back then. It wasn&#8217;t until my sophomore year in college when I took a class called &#8220;The African-American Experience” that something clicked for me. A lot of little things I had experienced in high school started to make sense. Like why most of the people in my honors class were white. Or why our school didn&#8217;t get funding like most other schools in the area. Or why people stared at my volleyball team when we travelled to games out of Seattle city limits (the team was mostly students of Color).</p>
<p>A switch had been turned on for me, and it’s like Alice Hoffman once said: Once you know some things, you can&#8217;t unknow them. It&#8217;s a burden that can never be given away.</p>
<p>I did feel burdened. I felt guilty. I felt angry. I felt a lot of bad feelings about what it meant for me to be white. But then I got fired up. I read books I would have never read before, I watched documentaries, joined anti-racist organizations, and started asking more questions.</p>
<div>
<p>I started looking at the world through a different lens.</p>
</div>
<p>I stopped feeling guilty and started feeling responsible to transform myself and the world around me.</p>
<p>That class changed me. It opened my eyes and pushed me to be introspective. It didn&#8217;t happen overnight, but the seed had been planted. I was 20 years old when I took that college course, and I wish someone had taught it to me earlier.</p>
<p>As a parent, I don&#8217;t want my daughter to hurt and I don&#8217;t want guilt to consume her—but I also don&#8217;t value my child&#8217;s comfort over another child&#8217;s sense of value.</p>
<p>I hope the students in that Wisconsin classroom can move past feeling guilty and oppressive and begin to be change agents in their lives and communities. I hope their parents can start to feel that way, too.</p>
<p>Here’s the article, “<a title="School Under Fire for Teaching that Whites are Oppressive " href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-2263136/School-class-teaches-white-people-oppressors.html" target="_blank">School under fire for class that teaches white people are oppressors</a>.”</p>
<p><strong>What do you think about teaching whiteness in curriculum?</strong></p>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=114&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://whitemomblog.com/2013/01/23/teaching-white-privilege-in-education-is-it-important/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/0615f35247d9d2c8e20f47c395db67a8?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">buffycurtin</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://whitemomblog.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/freeimage-8577967.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">http://www.stockfreeimages.com/</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>I Say Tomato; You Say, &#8220;What&#8217;s That?&#8221;</title>
		<link>http://paltrymeanderings.com/2013/01/23/i-say-tomato-you-say-whats-that/</link>
		<comments>http://paltrymeanderings.com/2013/01/23/i-say-tomato-you-say-whats-that/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 11:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Miss Snarky Pants</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Comedy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andrew Zimmern]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[banana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bizarre Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[butternut squash]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cashier]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clown]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dirty dancing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Downton Abbey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[farmer's market]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fear of clowns]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fruits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[funny]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gristle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hairy foods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Honey Boo Boo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humorous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[I hate clowns]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jamie Oliver]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jennifer grey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kid won't eat vegetables]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kitchen slattern]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[martini]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[McDonalds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[picky eater]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[potato]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[produce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[roadkill]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ronald McDonald]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[seeds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sketti]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[teenagers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[texture issues]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vegetables]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vegetarian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vodka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wal-mart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[watermelon]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://paltrymeanderings.com/?p=2066</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Growing up, I was a picky eater. Tomatoes were persona non grata on my plate. Though I recognized that the &#8220;I&#8217;m-A-Fruit-Masquerading-As-A-Vegetable&#8221; meant well, I couldn&#8217;t understand why tomatoes insisted on encasing their precious seeds in something the consistency of snot. Oranges were also out of the question. If we were meant to eat them, why [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2066&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://paltrymeanderings.com/2013/01/23/i-say-tomato-you-say-whats-that/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>86</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/ba78e144a7502cf704f7593062e0fd96?s=96&#38;d=wavatar&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cristycarringtonlewis</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://paltrymeanderings.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/picky-eater.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">picky eater</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://paltrymeanderings.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ronald-mcdonald-capitalcommentary-com.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">I&#039;ll Show You Grisley, Junior Miss Snarky Pants!</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://paltrymeanderings.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/kid-licking-cat-stephenfalepau-tumblr.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Bad Form</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://paltrymeanderings.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/watermelon-martini.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Vodka Is Not A Food Group; It&#039;s A Lifestyle</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://paltrymeanderings.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/honey-boo-boo-sketti-bravo.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mmmmm! &#039;Sketti!</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Ongoing Saga of My Innards</title>
		<link>http://excitementontheside.com/2013/01/23/the-ongoing-saga-of-my-innards-or-five-fun-facts-about-my-new-iud/</link>
		<comments>http://excitementontheside.com/2013/01/23/the-ongoing-saga-of-my-innards-or-five-fun-facts-about-my-new-iud/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 17:46:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Kelly</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pregnancy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[birth control]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[birth control pills]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breastfeeding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[colposcopy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[contraceptive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IUD]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mental-health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mirena]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mothering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Paragard]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://excitementontheside.com/?p=4784</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[You havent heard enough about my innards, have you?  When I showed you a picture of my IUD moments after it was removed, that wasn&#8217;t enough.  When I took a picture of the view from my colposcopy I know I really left you wanting more.  And I know that when I gave you the play [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4784&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You havent heard enough about my innards, have you?  When I showed you a picture of my <a href="http://excitementontheside.com/2010/08/30/day-24-barter-day/" target="_blank">IUD moments after it was removed</a>, that wasn&#8217;t enough.  When I took a <a href="http://excitementontheside.com/2012/03/15/just-do-it/" target="_blank">picture of the view from my colposcopy </a>I know I really left you wanting more.  And I know that when I gave you the play by play of Lucy&#8217;s birth I left out a lot of details.</p>
<p>So, that is why I feel compelled to give you some more deets about Lady Town.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong><em>Five Fun Facts About My Choice to Have My Paragard Replaced With a Mirena </em></strong></p>
<p><strong>1.  Fact</strong>:  I love my kids. I was blessed to fall in love with each of them the moment they were born.  Moments after Emily was born I knew I would do it again.  And the moment after Lucy was born and Emily said &#8220;It&#8217;s a sister&#8221; I knew that I was done. These were my children.  We were complete.</p>
<p><strong>2.  Fact:</strong> I have good intentions.  And grand plans.  Eat a healthy snack every day becomes eat peanut M&amp;Ms on occasion.  Stop wearing yoga pants unless I am exercising becomes wear yoga pants when you are planning on staying home for the day.  Make sure I have planned our dinners in such a way that I do not have to throw away a single leftover easily turns in to I totally I forgot I bought this cilantro but we ate everything else! Go, me!</p>
<p>Small things.  A single bag of M&amp;Ms, cozy yoga pants when it is cold outside and a $2 bag of fresh cilantro won&#8217;t change  the course of history.  But take this pill every single day at the same time or you might get pregnant. Another baby? A baby changes you.  Forever.</p>
<p>It took me 36 years to like me just fine.  This Life, the one where I forgive myself for a bag of M&amp;Ms or some wasted cilantro, I want this Life.  And the &#8220;Yes, actually I was on birth control pills but aren&#8217;t we Blessed to have this baby&#8221; baby just doesn&#8217;t fit in this Life.</p>
<p><strong>3.  Fact:</strong> Nursing my babies is important to me.  It might even be more than important.  It goes well beyond nutrition and it is the cornerstone to my parenting philosophy.  Many of the decisions that I have made about how to be the best mother that I can be center around continuing the mother-baby nursing relationship for as long as it is mutually desired.</p>
<p>I am not denying that other women can be wonderful mothers and not breastfeed. (Nor am I telling you that daily M&amp;Ms, a wardrobe made up solely of yoga pants and regular take-out because you forgot to pull chicken breasts out to thaw signals the imminent failure of your family foundation.  But it doesn&#8217;t add up to the Life that I want.  For me.)</p>
<p>So, I breastfeed.  And I avoid things that can have a negative impact on that relationship, things like hormonal birth control.</p>
<p>I shared here about how I had <a href="http://excitementontheside.com/2012/02/14/marital-relations-in-three-easy-steps/">Big Plans</a> for getting back in the marital saddle as soon as I got my IUD last February. I had a copper IUD after Emily was born and it worked well for me for years. There is an adjustment period, pardon the pun.  But it is worth it.</p>
<p><strong>4.  Fact:</strong> I am not a squeamish gal when it comes to my own body.  I sing the praises of the menstrual cup loud and proud.  Who wants to think about their period all of the time? Not me.  Twice a day you can empty a menstrual cup and chances are your periods will be shorter in length!  The Diva Cup is awesome.  The other day a friend asked me if she could talk to me about it.  I laughed.  I sat in my living room and showed her how it works, folded it, talked about the magical twist and release that creates a perfect seal.  Ordinarily someone has to ask me to <strong>not</strong> talk about my menstrual cup.  I am what one might call a huge fan.</p>
<p>But that doesn&#8217;t mean I want to wear it every day.  The Diva Cup is not intended to be an everyday accessory.  You see where I am going with this, right? This is when I try to find a clever way to explain that I have had my period on average for 14 days out of every 21 since I got it back (at three months post-partum!!) Umm.  I don&#8217;t need a separate paragraph to include the <strong>Fact</strong> that that is some bullshit right there.</p>
<p><strong>5.  Fact:</strong> Every women is different.  Every body is different.  And evidently every woman&#8217;s body isn&#8217;t even the same year after year.  My beloved hormone-free Paragard isn&#8217;t working for me this time.  After much research and soul searching I am having it removed and replaced with the levonorgestrel-releasing Mirena. Many women have had a Mirena with no impact on their milk supply at all.</p>
<p>But I am afraid.</p>
<p>The rest of the ill side-effects that are possible: hellacious acne, migraines and depression, I won&#8217;t be able to ignore them. It won&#8217;t sneak up on me.  I will never sit down at the end of the day and say &#8220;Damn, I have had a debilitating headache all day, I didn&#8217;t even realize it.&#8221;</p>
<p>But I don&#8217;t know what low milk supply feels like.  I don&#8217;t know how to know that it is happening.  I know I do not want my baby (and yes, she turned one last week, but she is a baby) to wean.  I don&#8217;t even know what weaning a baby looks like.  And more than that &#8211; I do not know how to mother a toddler without nursing.</p>
<p>I am, as I always am, nursing Lucy while I type.  And I am, as I sometimes am, crying.  If the Mirena works for us I will be happy.  And if it doesn&#8217;t, if my mik supply dips and I can&#8217;t get it back up quickly, I will be having it removed &#8220;even though&#8221; my baby is over a year old.</p>
<p>I struggled with this decision.  Above all else I struggled with admitting that I was making choices about my birth control largely based on my ability to breastfeed my twelve month old.  And I shouldn&#8217;t have to struggle to admit that.  It&#8217;s how I choose to parent.  And it works for me.  And for my kids.  And when I put it like that it doesn&#8217;t sound so complicated.</p>
<p>If you find this because you are struggling with your own decision, feel <a href="mailto:excitementontheside@gmail.com" target="_blank">free to contact me</a>.  If you want to share your experience because it will be helpful to you, please do.  If you want to tell me about your sister-in-law with a Mirena that breastfed her entire neighborhood until they graduated from high school or warn me that my insides will likely turn inside out I can assure that I have weighed both the risks and the benefits and made a choice.</p>
<p>In the coming weeks I can promise to keep y&#8217;all posted about my milk supply.  More boobs, less uterus! Now that&#8217;s a campaign platform if ever there was one.</p>
<p>Update: What did my seven-year-old think of watching me get my IUD? <a href="http://excitementontheside.com/2013/01/24/mom-gets-up-close-personal-with-the-big-kid/">Find out!</a></p>
<div id="attachment_4793" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://bowlegged.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/photo.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-4793" alt="It is understandably difficult to comprehend why I do not want any more of these.  It is even hard for me to wrap my mind around.  " src="http://bowlegged.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/photo.jpg?w=720"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">It is understandably difficult to comprehend why I do not want any more of these. It is even hard for me to wrap my mind around.</p></div>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://excitementontheside.com/category/parenting/'>Parenting</a>, <a href='http://excitementontheside.com/category/pregnancy/'>Pregnancy</a> Tagged: <a href='http://excitementontheside.com/tag/birth-control/'>birth control</a>, <a href='http://excitementontheside.com/tag/birth-control-pills/'>birth control pills</a>, <a href='http://excitementontheside.com/tag/breastfeeding/'>Breastfeeding</a>, <a href='http://excitementontheside.com/tag/colposcopy/'>colposcopy</a>, <a href='http://excitementontheside.com/tag/contraceptive/'>contraceptive</a>, <a href='http://excitementontheside.com/tag/health/'>health</a>, <a href='http://excitementontheside.com/tag/iud/'>IUD</a>, <a href='http://excitementontheside.com/tag/mental-health/'>mental-health</a>, <a href='http://excitementontheside.com/tag/mirena/'>Mirena</a>, <a href='http://excitementontheside.com/tag/mothering/'>mothering</a>, <a href='http://excitementontheside.com/tag/paragard/'>Paragard</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4784/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4784/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4784&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://excitementontheside.com/2013/01/23/the-ongoing-saga-of-my-innards-or-five-fun-facts-about-my-new-iud/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>32</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/d1f960648d180ef1361c4606be00f701?s=96&#38;d=monsterid&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bowlegged</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://bowlegged.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/photo.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">It is understandably difficult to comprehend why I do not want any more of these.  It is even hard for me to wrap my mind around.  </media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Staring at Rectangles</title>
		<link>http://briandbuckley.com/2013/01/23/staring-at-rectangles/</link>
		<comments>http://briandbuckley.com/2013/01/23/staring-at-rectangles/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 11:40:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Brian D. Buckley</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://briandbuckley.com/?p=2185</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Every morning, I spend an hour on the computer, writing a blog post and checking e-mail. Then I go to work for eight hours. Generally, I spend six of those hours at my desk, on the computer. In the evening, I work on the AI for an hour and a half, and spend at least [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2185&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://briandbuckleydotcom.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/rectangles.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2188" alt="Rectangles" src="http://briandbuckleydotcom.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/rectangles.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>Every morning, I spend an hour on the computer, writing a blog post and checking e-mail.</p>
<p>Then I go to work for eight hours. Generally, I spend six of those hours at my desk, on the computer.</p>
<p>In the evening, I work on the AI for an hour and a half, and spend at least another half hour writing my journal and doing other little things.</p>
<p>If I&#8217;m lucky, I get an hour in there somewhere to read a book, or sometimes watch a little TV.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s 10 hours a day. I spend over half my waking life staring at rectangles.</p>
<p>The thing is, I don&#8217;t regret it. Work pays the bills. The AI is the project I&#8217;m most excited about. I love reading; I&#8217;d never give it up. And writing the blog is a way to channel and structure the mess of thoughts bouncing around my head.</p>
<p>I spend <em>most of my time</em> staring at rectangles, and I like it. What the hell? What does that mean? How do I make sense of a fact so utterly bizarre?</p>
<p>Actually, I think I know the answer. It&#8217;s like cells in the body. (Stay with me here.)</p>
<p>Lone single-celled organisms, like amoebas, have to survive on their own. They&#8217;re responsible for everything: finding food, avoiding danger, navigating obstacles. They have to be, because no other cells are helping them out.</p>
<p>Cells in the human body are different. They&#8217;re part of a system, so they don&#8217;t have to do everything alone. They specialize. A neuron, for example, doesn&#8217;t worry about chasing down nutrients or dodging enemy bacteria. It just does its thing, sending and receiving signals, 24/7. Other cells fill other needs. No single cell has to do everything, and the overall system is vastly more capable than the sum of its parts.</p>
<p>The body is like society, and I&#8217;m like a neuron &#8211; or a skin cell, or anything else you want to pick. I couldn&#8217;t survive in the wild on my own, and I don&#8217;t have to, because I&#8217;m part of a system. I&#8217;ve specialized. I&#8217;m good at working in a particular environment, and (judging by the paychecks) society needs that.</p>
<p>Is it weird to spend most of your time looking at rectangles? Of course. But no weirder than anything else.</p>
<p>How much time do you spend rectangle-gazing, and how do you feel about it?</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2185/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2185/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2185&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://briandbuckley.com/2013/01/23/staring-at-rectangles/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/2a79866c82a0aaa16a9e5b4936bd3442?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bbd127</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://briandbuckleydotcom.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/rectangles.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Rectangles</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Asperger\&#8217;s, the Meda, and Social Justice</title>
		<link>http://eyesthroughtheglass.wordpress.com/2013/01/23/sandy-hook-aftermath-aspergers-the-media-and-social-justice/</link>
		<comments>http://eyesthroughtheglass.wordpress.com/2013/01/23/sandy-hook-aftermath-aspergers-the-media-and-social-justice/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 16:16:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dylan</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Current Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ableism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asperger's]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media Literacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prejudice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sandy Hook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social Justice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[society]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://eyesthroughtheglass.wordpress.com/?p=1954</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I wish to warn readers in advance that this is going to be a very heavy post. Dealing with the tragedy of Sandy Hook properly requires an acknowledgment of its seriousness as well as its lasting impact. The reason I haven&#8217;t written about it earlier is that I felt as if everything had already been [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1954&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I wish to warn readers in advance that this is going to be a very heavy post. Dealing with the tragedy of Sandy Hook properly requires an acknowledgment of its seriousness as well as its lasting impact.</p>
<p>The reason I haven&#8217;t written about it earlier is that I felt as if everything had already been said. Of course, as I dug around more these things began to change. I believe that this calls attention to some deeper cultural issues, especially revolving around Asperger&#8217;s and Autism.</p>
<p><span id="more-1954"></span></p>
<p><strong>Opening the Floodgates</strong></p>
<p><a href="http://eyesthroughtheglass.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/beaver_dam_ar_floodgates.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-2080" alt="Beaver Damn Floodgates Opening" src="http://eyesthroughtheglass.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/beaver_dam_ar_floodgates.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>There are of course many different things that arose from what happened at Sandy Hook. The gun control debate, the disquieting notion that this is not an isolated incident but now added to a list of mass shootings, the dark shadow cast upon our culture of violence, and so forth.</p>
<p>I will, however, focus on the Asperger&#8217;s-centric parts of the issue. While I have my own viewpoints about these other issues, fact of the matter is that this blog is meant to discuss Asperger&#8217;s.</p>
<p>I remember reading a Facebook post on Adventures In Asperger&#8217;s quoted as follows:</p>
<blockquote><p><em>&#8220;You know why our parents didn&#8217;t have school shootings &amp; all this </em><br />
<em>       bullsh*#? It&#8217;s because back then we could beat the sh*t outta the </em><br />
<em>       weird withdrawn f*#king sh*tbags!&#8221;<br />
</em></p></blockquote>
<p>As the blogger had noted, this post has received likes from his friends. He continued to voice his concern for his Asperger&#8217;s affected children, and the media&#8217;s handling of the situation.</p>
<p>I am equally concerned. However, I wish to address this in the context of a systemic problem, rather than its own issue. All in all, this plays into social justice and functions as an example of the hostile attitude towards those on the spectrum.</p>
<p><strong>Breaking Down The Broken Down</strong></p>
<p>Let&#8217;s begin by unpacking what exactly happened. What motive was there for posting information about his diagnosis? After any given school shooting or massacre, information about the perpetrator is gathered and released. But why call attention to Asperger&#8217;s?</p>
<p>We want to know why Adam Lanza did it. Just what goes on inside the head of someone who commits such an act? So naturally, the media is going to look is for anything mental health related.</p>
<p>However, this overly simplistic view is more respective of 1950&#8242;s understanding of the human brain rather than the understanding we are capable of today. As such, Asperger&#8217;s is lumped into the &#8220;mental illness&#8221; category. There is no vetting to figure out whether or not it&#8217;s even relevant to the case, because honestly it&#8217;s hard to vet something when you&#8217;re looking for the juiciest scoop.</p>
<p><strong>Word About Words</strong></p>
<p>But what of the conflation of Asperger&#8217;s and &#8220;mental illness&#8221;? Let&#8217;s stop and analyze that for a moment. Despite the old saw &#8220;Sticks and stones will break my bones, but words will never hurt me.&#8221;, real world evidence points to the fact that words are more powerful than we tend to believe.</p>
<p>Framing Asperger&#8217;s as a mental illness rather than what it actually is, a pervasive developmental disorder, is key when it comes to how it&#8217;s handled. The phrase &#8220;pervasive developmental disorder&#8221; is a rather large gobbledygook of words that sounds quite technical, and lacks the emotional charge of &#8220;mental illness&#8221;.</p>
<p>More importantly, using the term &#8220;mental illness&#8221; allows us to separate ourselves from Lanza. Certainly we are not capable of such an act ourselves. We can take comfort in that, because it&#8217;s very easy for us to imagine ourselves on one side of the moral chasm and the school shooter on the other.</p>
<p><strong>The Moral Gradient</strong></p>
<p>But I&#8217;ve done my homework on this sort of issue. I&#8217;ve read about the Stanley Milgram and Stanford Prison Experiment ran by Philip Zimbardo. In fact, I&#8217;ve read Zimbardo&#8217;s &#8220;Lucifer Effect&#8221; cover to cover.</p>
<div id="attachment_2081" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 594px"><a href="http://eyesthroughtheglass.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/zimbardo_in_warsaw_2009.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-2081" alt="Philip Zimbardo Speaking In Warsaw" src="http://eyesthroughtheglass.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/zimbardo_in_warsaw_2009.jpg?w=720"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Philip Zimbardo, author of The Lucifer Effect and head of the Stanford Prison Experiment.<br />Source: Wikimedia Commons photo by user &#8220;Jdec&#8221;</p></div>
<p>It&#8217;s an uncomfortable fact, but a lot of things go into any given shooting. Reducing it to a game of &#8220;find the crazy&#8221; is simply an exercise in fooling ourselves. We have a wealth of human atrocities to know that we are indeed more malleable than we like to think.</p>
<p>But alas, it&#8217;s so easy to boil it down as such. This is why even in the face of such powerful reminders, we are given the same fable of &#8220;he&#8217;s just crazy&#8221;, and we keep buying into it.</p>
<p><strong>The Dangers of Dehumanizing</strong></p>
<p>So why do I call attention to this at all? Because as the aftermath of the incident has demonstrated, <strong>this has dangerous long term consequences.  </strong>The behavior such as the above Facebook post enabled and fed by the media is a process that Zimbardo terms &#8220;dehumanization&#8221;.</p>
<div id="attachment_2079" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 455px"><a href="http://eyesthroughtheglass.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/anti-japan2.png"><img class="size-full wp-image-2079" alt="Anti-Japanese Propaganda" src="http://eyesthroughtheglass.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/anti-japan2.png?w=720"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Example of propaganda involving dehumanization. Linguistics such as slurs, in addition to caricature, are meant to influence the reader&#8217;s viewpoint on the Japanese.</p></div>
<p>Dehumanization is the systematic stripping of human qualities from a person or group. We can see it throughout history with the Holocaust, when Jews were branded as &#8220;vermin&#8221;. In Rwanda, the Tutsis were labeled &#8220;cockroaches&#8221;.  This is not a trite detail, <strong>but a necessary linguistic element. </strong>It is much harder for humans to harm others if the reminder of the victim&#8217;s humanity remains ever-near.</p>
<p><strong>The Insidiousness Revealed</strong></p>
<p>Let&#8217;s look at that Facebook post yet again, this time with highlights for emphasis:</p>
<blockquote><p><em>&#8220;You know why <strong>our parents didn&#8217;t have school shootings</strong> &amp; all this </em><br />
<em>       bullsh*#? It&#8217;s because back then <strong>we could beat the sh*t outta the </strong></em><br />
<em><strong>       weird withdrawn f*#king sh*tbags!</strong>&#8220;</em></p></blockquote>
<p>If we examine the structure of this monstrous claim, we can begin to see elements of dehumanization. People are referred to as &#8220;weird withdrawn fucking shitbags.&#8221;(Uncensored this time for demonstrative purposes).</p>
<p>And of course, this is piggybacked onto an implied solution: Corporal punishment. If parents were able to hit their children again, this problem would simply disappear. Forgive my own incredulity, but I&#8217;m honestly not buying that.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s remember this: The proposed solution to a problem of violence is more violence. That&#8217;s a bogus argument if I ever saw one. What really happens when you hit a child? That stays with them, and that becomes part of what is taught, that you solve your problems with violence. I asked my father why he never hit me, and that was his response, that he didn&#8217;t want to teach me to solve problems with violence.</p>
<p>Instead, I would propose that we further examine our culture, its methods, and its implied values, and ask what exactly we are teaching in terms of behavior. Much like dealing with sexism and racism, we have to deconstruct the prejudice against those on the spectrum in order to get anywhere. This prejudice is also known as &#8220;ableism&#8221;, and it remains a constant reminder for those on spectrum, now amplified by the fallout from Sandy Hook.</p>
<p>Links:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.adventuresinaspergers.com/2012/12/a-scary-time-for-aspergers-parents.html" rel="nofollow">http://www.adventuresinaspergers.com/2012/12/a-scary-time-for-aspergers-parents.html</a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1954/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1954/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1954&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://eyesthroughtheglass.wordpress.com/2013/01/23/sandy-hook-aftermath-aspergers-the-media-and-social-justice/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>16</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/fe813491e9febac6ee9e00fdbee8215a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">arenejo</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://eyesthroughtheglass.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/beaver_dam_ar_floodgates.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Beaver Damn Floodgates Opening</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://eyesthroughtheglass.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/zimbardo_in_warsaw_2009.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Philip Zimbardo Speaking In Warsaw</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://eyesthroughtheglass.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/anti-japan2.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Anti-Japanese Propaganda</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Of Course I&#8217;m Afraid of Nuclear Fallout</title>
		<link>http://melaniecrutchfield.com/2013/01/23/of-course-im-afraid-of-nuclear-fallout/</link>
		<comments>http://melaniecrutchfield.com/2013/01/23/of-course-im-afraid-of-nuclear-fallout/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 16:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Melanie Crutchfield</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[On Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Things I Dislike]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weird Stuff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dreams]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fear]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Frustration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instincts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nightmares]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nuclear Fallout]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Paranoia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reality]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://melaniecrutchfield.com/?p=1920</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve been having weird dreams lately. And sleeping kinda restlessly. Sleep is literally my favorite thing to do, so it makes me a little bit cranky when it doesn&#8217;t work out quite the way I want it to. A lot of things make me cranky, though. Like: Bathrooms that don&#8217;t have toilet seat covers When [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1920&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 650px"><a title="[220/365] Nuclear Fear (Explored) by pasukaru76, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/pasukaru76/5606183129/"><img title="Photo by pasukaru76 @ Flickr" alt="[220/365] Nuclear Fear (Explored)" src="http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5025/5606183129_9695c06f9e_z.jpg" width="640" height="426" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Photo by pasukaru76 @ Flickr</p></div>I&#8217;ve been having weird dreams lately. And sleeping kinda restlessly. Sleep is literally my favorite thing to do, so it makes me a little bit cranky when it doesn&#8217;t work out quite the way I want it to. A lot of things make me cranky, though. Like:</p>
<ul>
<li>Bathrooms that don&#8217;t have toilet seat covers</li>
<li>When you think you have another mango in the fridge, but discover you don&#8217;t</li>
<li>(Related) Starting a recipe and discovering half way through that you&#8217;re missing a key ingredient</li>
<li>People that don&#8217;t signal</li>
<li>Anything sticky</li>
</ul>
<p>I could go on for some time in this fashion, because I&#8217;m essentially an 84-year-old woman in a 33-year-old&#8217;s body. I&#8217;m fine with that.</p>
<p>Aaaanyway…so yes, I&#8217;ve been having cranky-making sleep as of late. And the weird dreams always linger in the morning, so I spend the first couple hours of the day trying to get over the yelling match I had with my non-existent boss while ice skating; or the panic of accidentally marrying some terrible other person, then remembering I&#8217;m married to someone great, and now I have some serious paperwork to do; or spilling ALL the milk in the grocery store and trying in vain to clean it up before anyone notices.</p>
<p>This is a piss poor way to start the day, friends. If I was dreaming about flying that crazy dog thing from the NeverEnding Story to a sushi restaurant where I ate some yummy nigiri, the morning would be spent with the lingering memory of tasty fish. Wouldn&#8217;t that be nice?</p>
<p>Anyway, what happened the other night is WORSE than all those other stupid things. You know those times where you roll over and you&#8217;re awake for a little nanosecond and then you fall back asleep again? Well, something happened in that nanosecond. A little noise. Like, a bang or something. I live in the city, so it was probably someone&#8217;s cat farting in a trash can. You know, something innocuous like that. It was definitely not, as my sleepy little mind imagined, a nuclear bomb being intercepted high above the city, whose toxic contents were now showering 1.2 million people, all of whom, including myself and my family, were soon to have melting insides.</p>
<p>Yeah, it definitely wasn&#8217;t that.</p>
<p>But to a sleepy little brain, whose imagination truly knows no bounds, that didn&#8217;t matter one little bit. Nope, because the idea had hatched, like a frightening sharp-toothed alien turtle, and now it was going to rip apart my conscience like a squeaky chew toy. Can I just say that I&#8217;m <em>super fun?</em> I mean, like a laugh riot o&#8217; fun.</p>
<p>So the next half hour&#8217;s thoughts went like this:</p>
<blockquote><p>That was probably a nuclear bomb.</p>
<p>Okay, it definitely wasn&#8217;t.</p>
<p>But probably most certainly was. *scratches skin* Is my skin coming off? No, not yet. That&#8217;s good. But when will it? Or is that even the right test? Do your insides just melt or something? I think I remember reading that once. And that all the DNA in all of my cells is fried now. What happens?</p>
<p>Everyone is going to die. We don&#8217;t have enough food in the house to survive nuclear fallout. I&#8217;m a terrible parent. Couldn&#8217;t I have just donated $50 to NPR? I&#8217;m pretty sure one of their <a href="http://shop.npr.org/sangean-cl-100-am-fm-same-weather-alert-radio" target="_blank">contributor gifts</a> would save my whole family, AND keep <a href="http://www.npr.org/programs/wait-wait-dont-tell-me/" target="_blank"><em>Wait, Wait…Don&#8217;t Tell Me</em></a> on the air. What the hell is my problem?!</p>
<p>I should check Google.</p>
<p>You definitely should not check Google, you crazy SOB. Stay in bed. GO TO BED.  Now. Go to bed now. Now. Right now.</p>
<p>I should check Google. Although, would they even put it on Google? The government would probably hide it as long as possible as to not create a panic. But I know already. I&#8217;m ahead of the curve.</p>
<p>My poor family. We can&#8217;t drink the water now, probably. We have no water or food and our insides are melting.</p></blockquote>
<p>And THEN…and then. Oh freaking lord, and then. I start thinking how if we&#8217;re going to starve, and dehydrate, and our insides were turning to goo, then we should probably figure out a way to commit suicide together.</p>
<p>WHAT?! WHAT IS WRONG WITH MY BRAIN?!</p>
<p>And that&#8217;s when I a) see, in stark relief, that this line of thinking has gone a touch too far and b) beg whatever demented gremlin that has taken over my brain to please, oh please, oh please let me fall asleep.</p>
<p>To my credit, I didn&#8217;t check Google. Somehow, I fell back asleep. And in the morning, everyone&#8217;s insides were intact, and the fear that had gripped me so tightly in the middle of the night was gone. Like magic. <em>Poof.</em></p>
<p>I don&#8217;t know how this stuff happens, but I know this: I don&#8217;t want to live gripped in fear. I hate that fear gets the best of me sometimes. Clearly, it&#8217;s a pretty big freaking bummer. The last few months have given us all a thousand things to fear, and it seems like that won&#8217;t be letting up any time soon. But fear and worry have never solved anything. So I&#8217;m gonna try to do less of that.</p>
<p>Good luck to me. Good luck to all of us.</p>
<p>(p.s. I&#8217;ve decided I won&#8217;t be watching that new show, <a href="http://www.fox.com/programming/shows/?sh=the-following" target="_blank"><em>The Following</em></a>. I&#8217;m pretty sure it will make me afraid of all humans—even the baby ones. An ounce of prevention…)</p>
<p><em>What kind of monsters are in your closet? </em></p>
<br /> Tagged: <a href='http://melaniecrutchfield.com/tag/dreams/'>Dreams</a>, <a href='http://melaniecrutchfield.com/tag/fear/'>fear</a>, <a href='http://melaniecrutchfield.com/tag/frustration/'>Frustration</a>, <a href='http://melaniecrutchfield.com/tag/humor/'>Humor</a>, <a href='http://melaniecrutchfield.com/tag/instincts/'>Instincts</a>, <a href='http://melaniecrutchfield.com/tag/life/'>Life</a>, <a href='http://melaniecrutchfield.com/tag/nightmares/'>Nightmares</a>, <a href='http://melaniecrutchfield.com/tag/nuclear-fallout/'>Nuclear Fallout</a>, <a href='http://melaniecrutchfield.com/tag/paranoia/'>Paranoia</a>, <a href='http://melaniecrutchfield.com/tag/reality/'>Reality</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1920/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1920/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1920/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1920/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1920/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1920/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1920/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1920/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1920/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1920/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1920/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1920/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1920/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1920/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1920&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://melaniecrutchfield.com/2013/01/23/of-course-im-afraid-of-nuclear-fallout/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>16</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/45a5bf9493fbdc80bf932cb4743d3a5a?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F1.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mlcrutchfield</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5025/5606183129_9695c06f9e_z.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Photo by pasukaru76 @ Flickr</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>For Amusement Only? Growing up with Technology</title>
		<link>http://rewiringvirtue.com/2013/01/21/for-amusement-only/</link>
		<comments>http://rewiringvirtue.com/2013/01/21/for-amusement-only/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 01:51:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jim Caccamo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tech culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[charity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[development]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rewiringvirtue.com/?p=1216</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Over the Christmas holiday, my son and I were talking about video game arcades. I spent so much time in them during junior high. That and at the roller rink, where I first played Pong, Missile Command, and Space Invaders. Good times, mostly with my brother. My son hasn&#8217;t been to one and really wants [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1216&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://rewiringvirtue.com/2013/01/21/for-amusement-only/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/93d70008231c2f1e9ac57e15987c7aeb?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jimcaccamo</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>I&#8217;ll Make Up a Biker Boyfriend If It Makes Life Easier</title>
		<link>http://newyorkcliche.com/2013/01/22/ill-make-up-a-biker-boyfriend-if-it-makes-life-easier/</link>
		<comments>http://newyorkcliche.com/2013/01/22/ill-make-up-a-biker-boyfriend-if-it-makes-life-easier/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 16:39:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>newyorkcliche</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Single and Fabulous Exclamation Point]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bikers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boyfriends]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boys]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chronically single]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[men]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[motorcycles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[single]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[single life]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://newyorkcliche.com/?p=3529</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I spent my weekend working at the International Motorcycle Show. The convention center was filled to capacity with leather garments, reprehensible hair cuts, flinch-inducing tattoos, and TESTOSTERONE. With the male to female ratio an astounding 10:1, this may be the #1 place to meet a man in NYC. If you&#8217;re into muscled biker types, buy [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3529&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I spent my weekend working at the International Motorcycle Show. The convention center was filled to capacity with leather garments, reprehensible hair cuts, flinch-inducing tattoos, and TESTOSTERONE. With the male to female ratio an astounding 10:1, this may be the #1 place to meet a man in NYC. If you&#8217;re into muscled biker types, buy your ticket for next year&#8217;s show NOW. My job, as it <a href="http://newyorkcliche.com/2011/06/02/she-works-hard-or-not-for-the-money/">so often is</a>, was to stand, smile, and look pretty (and interest people in a brand/sell a product- it is actually work). I spent the entire weekend fighting off men. Not surprisingly, they are a more aggressive bunch than the <a href="http://newyorkcliche.com/2010/10/15/the-strange-world-of-comiccon/">ComicCon</a> <del>nerds</del> lot.</p>
<div id="attachment_3540" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://newyorkcliche.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/p1030139.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-3540" alt="motorcycleshow" src="http://newyorkcliche.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/p1030139-e1358879358937.jpg?w=500&#038;h=315" width="500" height="315" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The 2013 International Motorcycle Show</p></div>
<p><em>Oh woe is me!</em> It&#8217;s <em>so hard</em> being a pretty girl! The constant flattery, frequent free drinks, rarely having to open a door for myself, it&#8217;s <em>exhausting! </em></p>
<p>I can feel the collective eye roll from my dude-readers. It&#8217;s such a pretty girl cliché to complain about the men who hit on us. Yes, most of them are harmless and -I&#8217;ll be the first to admit it- ego boosts. That said, the slimy feeling when a man&#8217;s eyes scan your body, slowly from toe to tip, is a real one. The look in his eyes says he&#8217;s a ravenous beast and you&#8217;re a fresh cut of meat. He&#8217;s an Italian grandmother at the butcher and you&#8217;re the perfect roast behind the counter. He can imagine sticking you with his meat thermometer as you cook in the oven. If any one shows interest in you before the butcher calls his number, he will smack that bitch with his handbag. Imagine feeling like a bloody, raw, 125 pound chunk of meat sliced from the flank of genetically modified livestock. It sucks. Am I right, ladies?</p>
<p>That said, the men who look at me like I&#8217;m sirloin are few and far between. Even at a biker bonanza with the accompanying &#8220;bad boy&#8221; and &#8220;rebel without a cause&#8221; clichés. I&#8217;m a grown women, someone who&#8217;s been &#8220;pretty&#8221; for the majority of her adult life (post-college at least). I&#8217;ve refuted the advances of plenty of men in my time. Bikers may be more intimidating than the average man on my subway commute, but they don&#8217;t punch you in the nose if you decline to give them your number. Still, as all women -from homely to drop dead gorgeous- know, nothing gets a man to accept rejection better than ye old &#8220;I have a boyfriend&#8221; line. Thus, I spent the entire weekend pretending to have a boyfriend.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">His name is Joe. He rides a Yamaha. He is also in a band called <em>The SpitTakes</em> where he plays a Yamaha. Did you know Yamaha is a brand of motorcycle AND a brand of pianos? I never knew that prior to attending the motorcycle show but I think it&#8217;s AWESOME. Joe is 31 and works in construction. He&#8217;s on the team building the Freedom Tower, how cool is that? He&#8217;s Irish, 6&#8217;2&#8243; tall, full head of jet black hair, and sparkling blue eyes. He has the ever-so-slight beginnings of a beer belly. A tattoo of a mermaid/lady pirate is inked upon his forearm. My father hates him. Joe would<em> kick your ass</em> if he knew you were flirting with me.</p>
<p><div id="attachment_3541" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://www.totalmotorcycle.com/photos/2005models/2005-Yamaha-R6a.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-3541  " alt="motorcycleyama" src="http://newyorkcliche.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/motorcycleyama.jpg?w=300&#038;h=240" width="300" height="240" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">This is his motorcycle. Sexy right?<br />[image: totalmotorcyle.com]</p></div><div id="attachment_3542" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://www.musiciansbuy.com/prod.asp?ic=TYROS2KIT"><img class="size-medium wp-image-3542  " alt="But not as sexy as his other Yamaha!" src="http://newyorkcliche.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/keyboardyamaha.jpg?w=300&#038;h=157" width="300" height="157" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">But not as sexy as his other Yamaha!<br />[image: musiciansbuy.com]</p></div>So that&#8217;s &#8220;Joe&#8221;. I haven&#8217;t had a <em>real</em> boyfriend in almost four years. It&#8217;s at the point where the TV series/movie/book based on my life would start referring to their heroine as &#8220;chronically single&#8221;. To the point where blogs about my life, autobiographical no less, start identifying me as such. This was a recent realization. One likely made in the shower, on a solitary stroll, or whilst lying awake in bed. (Ok, I don&#8217;t remember where I realized it, so I fall back on cliché). The point is, I realized that however much I <em>think</em> I want a boyfriend, the <em>actual</em> prospect terrifies me. An actual flesh and body, independent minded man whom I have <strong>no</strong> control over. One I choose and connect myself to so that he is directly associated with me by a label: <i>BOYFRIEND.</i> A man who won&#8217;t see me as a piece of meat or just a pretty face. He&#8217;ll see <em>all my flaws</em>. This man will <em>undeniably</em> threaten my current way of life&#8230;</p>
<p>Yes, you guessed it: this realization was in part spurred by a man in my life who seems interested in the label. My hands are sweating just thinking about it (which isn&#8217;t <em>really</em> saying much, my hands are always clammy -fun fact, right? But the affliction sometimes comes in handy  -pun intended- to emphasize a point). <del>But maybe he&#8217;s not! He hasn&#8217;t <em>exactly</em> said as much&#8230;I&#8217;m probably making it up!</del> Ok, admitting you have a problem is the first step. Acceptance is a vital step toward change.</p>
<p>Here goes:<br />
Hi. My name is New York Cliché. I am chronically single. I make up boyfriends to make my life easier. And..and&#8230;<em>commitment scares me.</em></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3529/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3529/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3529/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3529/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3529/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3529/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3529/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3529/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3529/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3529/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3529/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3529/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3529/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3529/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3529&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://newyorkcliche.com/2013/01/22/ill-make-up-a-biker-boyfriend-if-it-makes-life-easier/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>50</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/674c1dbeef2b85a259c98997e29d41de?s=96&#38;d=monsterid" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">newyorkcliche</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://newyorkcliche.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/p1030139-e1358879358937.jpg?w=500" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">motorcycleshow</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://newyorkcliche.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/motorcycleyama.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">motorcycleyama</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://newyorkcliche.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/keyboardyamaha.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">But not as sexy as his other Yamaha!</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>To Pee or Not to Pee? A Movie Theater Guide</title>
		<link>http://tdylf.com/2013/01/22/flowchart-to-pee-or-not-to-pee-a-movie-theater-guide/</link>
		<comments>http://tdylf.com/2013/01/22/flowchart-to-pee-or-not-to-pee-a-movie-theater-guide/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2013 09:21:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>John</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flowchart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the best time during a movie to pee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Theaters]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tdylf.com/?p=10778</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[To pee, or not to pee? That is the question. Everyone who has ever gone to a movie knows this predicament- whether &#8217;tis nobler to suffer the slings and arrows of painfully watching a movie when you have to relieve yourself, or to take arms against a sea of porcelain and miss a few minutes [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=10778&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://thedroidyourelookingfor.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/theaterpeeheader-copy.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-10788" style="margin-bottom:20px;margin-right:1500px;" alt="TheaterPeeHeader copy" src="http://thedroidyourelookingfor.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/theaterpeeheader-copy.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>To pee, or not to pee? That is the question. Everyone who has ever gone to a movie knows this predicament- whether &#8217;tis nobler to suffer the slings and arrows of painfully watching a movie when you have to relieve yourself, or to take arms against a sea of porcelain and miss a few minutes of a movie you&#8217;ve paid to see. To help you determine the best possible time to pee during a movie, I&#8217;ve created this flowchart.<span id="more-10778"></span></p>
<p><em>As usual, click on the image for the full-resolution version.</em></p>
<p><a href="http://thedroidyourelookingfor.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/moviepeeingflowchart1.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-10789" alt="MoviePeeingFlowchart" src="http://thedroidyourelookingfor.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/moviepeeingflowchart1.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/10778/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/10778/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=10778&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tdylf.com/2013/01/22/flowchart-to-pee-or-not-to-pee-a-movie-theater-guide/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>137</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f67d481f16c534c575cb2a22a8351b09?s=96&#38;d=monsterid&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Celluloid Hero</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thedroidyourelookingfor.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/theaterpeeheader-copy.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">TheaterPeeHeader copy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thedroidyourelookingfor.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/moviepeeingflowchart1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">MoviePeeingFlowchart</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
