<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2012 20:02:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Incredible Coral Bay, Western Australia</title>
		<link>http://ardunward.com/2012/10/12/incredible-coral-bay-western-australia/</link>
		<comments>http://ardunward.com/2012/10/12/incredible-coral-bay-western-australia/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2012 13:53:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ardun Ward</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Telling Tales]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adventure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beaches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coral bay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reef]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[western australia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[whale sharks]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ardunward.com/?p=231</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[My first trip of 2012 began on the 2nd January and consisted of a 12 hour road trip from Perth, Western Australia to Coral Bay. With my wife and good mates Fredrico &#38; Sasha (names changed for all government agencies out there) we took to the road at 8pm. Fredrico owns a single cab Toyota [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=231&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>My first trip of 2012 began on the 2nd January and consisted of a 12 hour road trip from Perth, Western Australia to Coral Bay.</p>
<p><a href="http://ardunward.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/coralbay011.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-232" title="CoralBay01" alt="" src="http://ardunward.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/coralbay011.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=682" height="682" width="1024" /></a></p>
<p>With my wife and good mates Fredrico &amp; Sasha (names changed for all government agencies out there) we took to the road at 8pm. Fredrico owns a single cab Toyota Landcruiser with a canopy on the back, loaded up to the nines with fishing gear, swags, fridges, cookers and a couple of wild turkeys. Actually a couple of slabs of Wild Turkey, which may not be as useful as the turkeys themselves if we broke down and needed to eat, or ride to a nearby town. Speaking of towns, I will tell you now that if you are in Perth, Western Australia and planning to drive for 12 hours north to coral bay, don&#8217;t expect to see many (towns or turkeys). This drive would have to be one of the most boring I&#8217;ve ever done, with the road being straight and flat for nearly the entire way. The landscape which we missed on the way up in the dark, we experienced on the way back, and I will say it is one I only need to see once. Small trees turn to shrubs, which then turn back to small trees and there is barely a hill or a bump for most of the drive.</p>
<p><a href="http://ardunward.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/coralbay29.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-234" title="CoralBay29" alt="" src="http://ardunward.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/coralbay29.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=682" height="682" width="1024" /></a></p>
<p>On a positive note, my old mate Fredrico knew heaps about the few small towns on the way up which included the Hutt River Province, an actual country within Australia due to a cheeky cocky (farmer) from back in the forties who found a loophole in the law books and claimed his land exclusively as his own nation. Sadly it was midnight and we weren&#8217;t exactly on top of the province and we heard he has a large army of goats and boxing kangaroos so we thought it best not to bother him. Apparently though he is a great old chap who is getting on now but still stamps your passport before making you drink his home-brew and fight his kangaroos.</p>
<p><a href="http://ardunward.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/coralbay12.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-233" title="CoralBay12" alt="" src="http://ardunward.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/coralbay12.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=682" height="682" width="1024" /></a></p>
<p>Another place to note on the way is of course Kalbari which is a small detour to the coast and a place I will be sure to make a halfway stop next time. The seaside town is famous for pristine beaches and great fish and many other things I cannot remember since my last visit was when I was 12. You may think this is a copout but since this is a post about Coral Bay I say you&#8217;ll just have to wait.</p>
<p><a href="http://ardunward.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/coralbay20.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-237" title="CoralBay20" alt="" src="http://ardunward.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/coralbay20.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=682" height="682" width="1024" /></a></p>
<p>Driving through the night and keeping each other awake via the two-way radio, we reached a rest stop just outside Carnarvon by sunrise. Rolling out the swags and crashing out for a couple of hours before the morning sun warmed up, we recharged enough for the final leg. I would not recommend tackling the entire drive in one go, even with two drivers as we did on the way back. I will definitely include a stop overnight next time. Having said that, driving at night was largely a good idea, being cooler and quieter on the road, albeit for the kangaroos and foxes. Thankfully though, Fredrico drove up front and alerted us to any wildlife hovering by the roadside, I&#8217;m sure the Holden Viva would have turned in to an accordion if we hit something.</p>
<p><a href="http://ardunward.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/coralbay18.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-238" title="CoralBay18" alt="" src="http://ardunward.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/coralbay18.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=682" height="682" width="1024" /></a></p>
<p>Passing through Carnarvon we tried to buy some bananas, the one thing the place is famous for, alas we did not find one farm selling them. Disgruntled and low on potassium we tackled the final stretch to arrive in Coral Bay. This one-street town is like an oasis after the 12 hours of shrubs and to see a pristine beach with ultramarine water makes it all worth while.</p>
<p>There are only a few options when it comes to accommodation in Coral Bay, being the back packers and a couple of caravan parks including the Bayview where options range from tent and caravan spots, to one bed villas up to multi-room dwellings. Prices are reasonable with a one bed villa with small kitchen and living room only $130 AUD per night for 4 adults. The living room has a single bed and trundle but being the bush boy that he is, Fredrico laid his swag out on the floor.</p>
<p>By the time we checked in it was close to 2 o&#8217;clock and over 30 degrees so we went down to the pool in the camp grounds and had a much deserved drink, which we were lucky to have the foresight to bring, since Coral Bay has no bottle shop. Fredrico devised a plan to load the ute up full of cartons on our next trip up here, a kind of black market import business where we can charge outrageous prices for liquor to unprepared campers.</p>
<p>With only a couple of days here in Coral Bay, we grabbed our snorkel gear and headed down to the beach. Ningaloo Reef runs from Coral Bay all the way up to Exmouth around 150kms north and is one of only a few places where the magnificent Whale Shark is known to frequent. Unfortunately for us, this mysterious creature can be found here from March to June so we had to entertain ourselves with the other marine life in the shallow reef off the beach. Parrot fish, Snapper, Stingrays and the odd turtle are frequent inhabitants amongst the giant purple and blue coral and sea grasses. My wife dived straight back into the snorkelling since her last time in Florida almost 18 months ago and calls it: &#8220;the best snorkelling I have ever done&#8221; largely due to the great coral and marine species as well as the reef&#8217;s close proximity to the beach.</p>
<p>Fredrico spent a lot of his time in the water worried about being taken by a tiger shark, especially after a dusk fishing session. Over near the Coral Bay boat ramp, we parked the 4&#215;4 on the rocky headland in a spot we scoped out earlier in the day. The half-metre deep water was teeming with schools of fish that afternoon so we thought it a spot we couldn&#8217;t go wrong. On arrival at sundown, Jen and I followed some kangaroos and wild sheep along the cliff line. Fredrico and Sasha threw a line in and caught a small reef fish in seconds. Fredrico then peed into the shallow water and minutes later the pair witnessed a 1.5 metre tiger shark move in and circle the area below them. When we returned we threw a line in, the sun now set. We spent an hour casting out and received nothing, not even a bite.</p>
<p><a href="http://ardunward.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/coralbay22.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-236" title="CoralBay22" alt="" src="http://ardunward.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/coralbay22.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=682" height="682" width="1024" /></a></p>
<p>We returned that night empty-handed, disappointed we were not feasting on the pink snapper we have been diving with, and resort to a diet of Wild Turkey. As any good camping trip needs, we spend the night playing UNO and board games. On our final day we do much the same, snorkelling and soaking up the sun and 30 degree weather. From the shark incident, Fredrico is not the same in the water and is furious when i inform him of my need to go (pee) in the water. With a final swim and no further shark sightings we say goodbye to our friends who continued on to Exmouth.</p>
<p>Coral Bay is an incredible place if you enjoy swimming, snorkelling and sun baking and for Jen (my wife) and I it was the perfect escape no matter how brief. If you need a bit more, Exmouth is the place to go with pubs, restaurants and better fishing. Sasha and Fredrico were lucky enough to witness the turtle egg laying season (January), where they saw 12 turtles slowly crawl on to the beach the second the moon came out. With Coral Bay providing a great escape, I know it will be a place I will return to again perhaps even this whale shark season.</p>
<p>Get in touch when you make it &#8216;down under&#8217; my foreign friends!</p>
<p><a href="http://ardunward.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/coralbay28.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-235" title="CoralBay28" alt="" src="http://ardunward.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/coralbay28.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=682" height="682" width="1024" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/231/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/231/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=231&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://ardunward.com/2012/10/12/incredible-coral-bay-western-australia/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://ardunward.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/coralbay011.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://ardunward.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/coralbay011.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">CoralBay01</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/69b477ab920cb987d23c53ac918f2927?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">dodgeramapalooza</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ardunward.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/coralbay011.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">CoralBay01</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ardunward.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/coralbay29.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">CoralBay29</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ardunward.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/coralbay12.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">CoralBay12</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ardunward.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/coralbay20.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">CoralBay20</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ardunward.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/coralbay18.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">CoralBay18</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ardunward.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/coralbay22.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">CoralBay22</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ardunward.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/coralbay28.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">CoralBay28</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why a Spencer Is Better Than an Oreck</title>
		<link>http://remissionary.wordpress.com/2012/10/10/why-a-spencer-is-better-than-an-oreck/</link>
		<comments>http://remissionary.wordpress.com/2012/10/10/why-a-spencer-is-better-than-an-oreck/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2012 05:05:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>LubbyGirl</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Wednesday Wanderings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dachshund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dpchallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kibbles and bits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pets]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://remissionary.wordpress.com/?p=1475</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[When it comes to cleaning the kitchen floor, NOTHING works better than a Spencer. I&#8217;ve had many different floor cleaners, and I realize Oreck is a good brand, but come on, let&#8217;s get real here. It doesn&#8217;t hold a candle to a Spencer. Why do I say that? Well, I will enumerate. 1. Suction Power: A [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1475&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:justify;">When it comes to cleaning the kitchen floor, NOTHING works better than a Spencer. I&#8217;ve had many different floor cleaners, and I realize Oreck is a good brand, but come on, let&#8217;s get real here. It doesn&#8217;t hold a candle to a Spencer. Why do I say that? Well, I will enumerate.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><strong>1. Suction Power</strong><strong>:</strong> A Spencer leaves no crumb unvacuumed. Where an Oreck might miss the crumbs in the corners and under my feet while I&#8217;m cooking, I can always count on my Spencer to find every single one &#8211; whether I&#8217;m standing on it or not.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><strong>2. Removal of waste: </strong>A Spencer has a self-emptying bag. An Oreck must be emptied periodically to keep it from becoming gorged with floor-gunk, whereas my Spencer empties itself, without my help. But then . . . I do have to remember where it empties, and avoid that area until its contents have solidified.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><strong>3. Thoroughness: </strong>An Oreck just vacuums up the debris. My Spencer not only sucks up every single crumb in sight, but it also licks up any little grease spots in the process. When my Spencer is finished, the floor looks like it&#8217;s been mopped! Just try to get an Oreck to do that!!</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><strong>4. Storage:</strong> After using an Oreck, it must be put away in the closet. A Spencer puts itself away!</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><strong>5. Trip hazard:</strong> The electrical cord on an Oreck is long and one must be careful not to trip over it. A Spencer is self-propelled. No cords to worry about &#8211; but there may be just the slightest danger of getting rear-ended.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><strong>6. Cost: </strong>An Oreck is expensive. A Spencer works for Kibbles. And Bits. But mostly Kibbles.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><strong>7. Ease of operation:</strong> I have to push the Oreck around in front of me and direct it toward the item I want picked up. It can be tiring and slow. A Spencer not only is self-propelled (see item #5), but is also extremely fast. My Spencer is fine-tuned to sense where the crumbs and bits of food are about to fall, and can dart in almost before they hit the floor. A couple of times I&#8217;m sure they were caught in mid-air.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><strong>8.</strong> <strong>Motivation:</strong> An Oreck just sits there, waiting for me to force it into action. My Spencer is ready to work as soon as I get up in the morning, and leads me to the kitchen.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><strong>9. Multi-Use Function: </strong>An Oreck only cleans floors. My Spencer can find crumbs and remove them instantly from floors, beds, couches, shirts, and bathrobes, and can even clean any stray food particles from between my fingers. It would work just as well on faces if I&#8217;d allow that, but that&#8217;s what napkins are for. My Spencer is a floor-cleaner, face-washer, foot-warmer, lap-quilt, intruder-alert, guest-greeter, deer-stalker, and best buddy. Now I ask you, can an Oreck do all that?</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><strong>10.</strong> And finally, unlike a Spencer, <strong>an Oreck has no personality.</strong>  I rest my case.</p>
<div id="attachment_1514" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 896px"><a href="http://remissionary.wordpress.com/2012/10/10/why-a-spencer-is-better-than-an-oreck/dsc01152/" rel="attachment wp-att-1514"><img class="size-large wp-image-1514" title="Spencer" alt="" src="http://remissionary.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/dsc01152-e1349929047957.jpg?w=886&#038;h=1024" height="1024" width="886" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">David Oreck&#8217;s got nuthin&#8217; on me!</p></div>
<address>This was written in response to this week&#8217;s <a href="http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2012/10/08/weekly-writing-challenge-and-now-for-something-completely-different/">WordPress writing challenge</a>, and naturally, I neglected to provide a link to that so you could go see what others are writing. OOPS!! Anyway&#8230;hope you enjoy my top-ten list.</address>
<p style="text-align:justify;">
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1475/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1475/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1475&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://remissionary.wordpress.com/2012/10/10/why-a-spencer-is-better-than-an-oreck/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/ecdbebd5e7d8aba2806e8083c3d6906f?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lubbygirl</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://remissionary.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/dsc01152-e1349929047957.jpg?w=886" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Spencer</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lying vs. Being Wrong</title>
		<link>http://feralcreatures.wordpress.com/2012/10/12/lying-vs-being-wrong/</link>
		<comments>http://feralcreatures.wordpress.com/2012/10/12/lying-vs-being-wrong/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2012 14:26:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>feralcreatures</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Fatherhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parenting]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://feralcreatures.wordpress.com/?p=623</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[CB is stalling. It’s time for bed, past time, way past time. Water, snacks, brushing teeth, books, we’ve run the gamut. Now she’s got to go the bathroom. I tell her that I’m going to have to get up early the next morning but that she’ll see me before we go. CB: “Are you sure? [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=623&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>CB is stalling. It’s time for bed, past time, way past time. Water, snacks, brushing teeth, books, we’ve run the gamut. Now she’s got to go the bathroom. I tell her that I’m going to have to get up early the next morning but that she’ll see me before we go.</p>
<p>CB: “Are you sure? Last time you said that you’d see me but you lied.”</p>
<p>Dad: “ I didn’t lie, hon, I was wrong. There’s a difference. I ran out of time and you weren’t up yet so I had to go. I thought I was going to have time but didn’t.”</p>
<p>She’s chewing on her lip.</p>
<p>Dad: “Ok, hold on, I’ll show you what I mean.”</p>
<p>I go and get a nickel off of the desk in the front room.</p>
<p>Dad: “You know what the heads-or-tails game is?”</p>
<p>CB shakes her head.</p>
<p>Dad: “Ok, on this side, there’s, like always a picture of some famous person, usually a president or something. This guy’s name is Jefferson. That’s the head, you can see his head. On the other side is the tail, could be anything on that side.”</p>
<p>I put the coin on my thumb.</p>
<p>Dad:” Ok, now I guess that it’s going to be heads.”</p>
<p>I flip the coin, it lands. We look. Tails.</p>
<p>Dad: “Ok, tails. Now, was I lying, or was I just wrong?”</p>
<p>She thinks a second.</p>
<p>CB: “You were wrong!”</p>
<p>Dad: “That’s right. Now you try.”</p>
<p>I flip the coin, it lands, I cover it.</p>
<p>Dad: “Heads or tails?”</p>
<p>CB: “Heads!”</p>
<p>Dad: *checks* You’re right! See?”</p>
<p>CB verifies it, has dad flip the coin a couple of more times to watch the flipping and catching process.</p>
<p>She’s ready for bed now.</p>
<p>CB: “Can we play the flipping game a couple more times tomorrow?”</p>
<p>Dad: “Sure hon, we can do that…”</p>
<p>CB: “And maybe it will land on the LYING side!”<a href="http://feralcreatures.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/20101013135636.jpg"><img id="i-624" class="size-full wp-image" alt="Image" src="http://feralcreatures.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/20101013135636.jpg?w=1014" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/623/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/623/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=623&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://feralcreatures.wordpress.com/2012/10/12/lying-vs-being-wrong/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/11c9f2809c636b8950648def91d95439?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">feralcreatures</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://feralcreatures.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/20101013135636.jpg?w=1014" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Weekly Photo Challenge: Happy</title>
		<link>http://milnersblog.wordpress.com/2012/10/10/weekly-photo-challenge-happy/</link>
		<comments>http://milnersblog.wordpress.com/2012/10/10/weekly-photo-challenge-happy/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2012 20:04:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Carl Milner</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Carl Milner Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Happy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jack Russell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[My Dog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[One man and his Dog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[postaday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weekly Photo Challenge Happy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WordPress Photo Challenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WordPress Weekly Photo Challenge]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://milnersblog.wordpress.com/?p=2710</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[What makes you Happy? What a great theme this weeks WordPress Weekly Photo Challenge is, I was originally going to show a variety of pics including some of my lovely Wife and my gorgeous Girls that make me so happy, but I decided to submit an individual subject&#8230;MY DOG &#8230;this is not to say I [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2710&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://milnersblog.wordpress.com/2012/10/10/weekly-photo-challenge-happy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>53</slash:comments>
		<georss:point>53.799639 -1.549122</georss:point>
		<geo:lat>53.799639</geo:lat>
		<geo:long>-1.549122</geo:long>
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/acf1631fc0d9ccbb84a6424f0af8a7f2?s=96&#38;d=retro&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">carlmilner</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://milnersblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/did-you-say-cheese.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Did you say CHEESE</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://milnersblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/is-it-time-to-get-up.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Is it time to get up</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://milnersblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/yeah-its-park-time.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">YEAH its Park time</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://milnersblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/looking-at-dad.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Looking at Dad</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://milnersblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/is-that-my-ball.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Is that my Ball</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://milnersblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/is-that-a-frog.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Is that a FROG</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://milnersblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/was-that-a-spider.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Was that a Spider?</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://milnersblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/im-sure-i-heard-the-postman.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Im sure I heard the Postman</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://milnersblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/hes-coming.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Hes coming</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://milnersblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/my-friend.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">My Friend</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://milnersblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/squirrel.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Squirrel</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How I Opened a Wormhole Simply By Reading</title>
		<link>http://geekybooksnob.wordpress.com/2012/10/10/how-i-opened-a-wormhole-simply-by-reading/</link>
		<comments>http://geekybooksnob.wordpress.com/2012/10/10/how-i-opened-a-wormhole-simply-by-reading/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2012 12:55:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>geekybooksnob</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Musings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPchallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[freshly pressed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[imagination]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quantum physics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the neverending story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wormholes]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://geekybooksnob.wordpress.com/?p=387</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I can tell you how to use a book to open a wormhole, but I can&#8217;t describe what it will be like.  Every experience is unique to the person experiencing it.  In fact, I can&#8217;t even promise that you will remember seeing the wormhole open because I sure didn&#8217;t.  All I remember is that I [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=387&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://geekybooksnob.wordpress.com/2012/10/10/how-i-opened-a-wormhole-simply-by-reading/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>56</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/12a43c973edf5fdcb28c0321501b0783?s=96&#38;d=wavatar&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">geekybooksnob</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://geekybooksnob.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/falcor-flying-through-a-wormhole1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">falkor flying through a wormhole</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Reflections on Mr. Penumbra\&#8217;s 24-Hour Bookstore</title>
		<link>http://bibliostrumpet.wordpress.com/2012/10/11/when-page-and-screen-collide/</link>
		<comments>http://bibliostrumpet.wordpress.com/2012/10/11/when-page-and-screen-collide/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2012 11:43:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Miss Brill</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Contemporary Fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bookselling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bookshops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[debut novel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[future of the book]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[geek culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mystery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quest narrative]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quirky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[secret society]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://bibliostrumpet.wordpress.com/?p=375</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Working in an independent bookshop is one of those jobs that people tend to make assumptions about. Incorrect ones. Like, that booksellers get to sit behind the counter and read all day, or that we’re all like Bernard in Black Books, drinking red wine and freely abusing ignorant customers (I wish). Alas, the reality is [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=375&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Working in an independent bookshop is one of those jobs that people tend to make assumptions about. Incorrect ones. Like, that booksellers get to sit behind the counter and read all day, or that we’re all like Bernard in <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0262150/"><em>Black Books</em></a>, drinking red wine and freely abusing ignorant customers (I wish). Alas, the reality is not nearly so interesting, particularly when you work in a shop like mine, where the computers are from circa 1985 and all the returns have to be pulled by hand (don’t even ask).</p>
<p>But it’s nice to hold onto this fantastical image of the quirky indie bookshop, and Mr Penumbra’s 24-hour Bookstore, the mysterious place at the centre of Robin Sloan’s charming and imaginative <a href="http://www.boomerangbooks.com.au/Mr-Penumbras-24-hour-Bookstore/Robin-Sloan/book_9781922079169.htm">debut novel</a> of the same name, brings it vividly to life; albeit with a very modern twist.</p>
<p>What’s special about Sloan’s novel is how seamlessly it blends old and new: it’s a mish-mash of Internet gadgetry and ancient artefacts, typefaces and printing presses, ereaders and leather-bound tomes, an old-fashioned quest narrative and a modern love story—and, somehow, it all fits together like Bernard and a bottle of red.</p>
<p>Twenty-six-year old Clay Jannon is an affable, unemployed nerd with a passion for fantasy fiction and a talent for web design. When ‘the great food-chain contraction that swept through America in the early twenty-first century’ costs him his marketing job with a company called NewBagel, he’s at a loose end—until he finds Mr Penumbra’s 24-Hour Bookstore when he’s wandering the streets of San Francisco. While it’s ignominiously located next to a neon-signed bar called Booty’s, in ‘a euphemistic part of town,’ Penumbra’s isn’t what it seems: inside, rows and rows of dizzyingly tall shelves are stacked with ancient volumes that appear to be filled with code.</p>
<p>Of course, after a mysterious encounter with old Mr Penumbra, who talks a little bit like a wise old wizard in a quest novel (‘I am the custodian of this place’), Clay gets the job of night clerk. From 10 pm until 6 am, he mans the desk, lending the ancient books of code to an odd group of customers who appear to be part of a secret society. It’s not long before Clay’s curiousity prompt him to start investigating: what do the symbols inside the books mean? What ancient mystery are Penumbra and his strange clients devoting their lives to solving? And will it get Clay a date with Kat, the hot girl from Google who wanders into the bookshop one fateful night?</p>
<p>Clay’s quest is a wildly imaginative and rather Potter-esque trip that encompasses everything from Gutenberg to Google HeadQuarters, a place where employees’ food is personalised with vitamins and natural stimulants. With the aid of his friends and colleagues, whose talents range from data whizbangery to esoteric archaeological knowledge, Clay begins to unravel the truth behind Penumbra’s bookstore and the part it plays in the mysterious Festina Lente Corporation.</p>
<p>At the heart of this journey all is the eternal human yearning for immortality, a desire that even the cleverest technology can’t give us (yet—Kat proudly tells Clay that Google is working on it via a project called Google Forever). But, as in any good quest novel, what turns out to be most important isn’t the symbols or the coveted objects, but the people who seek them, and the passions and ideas that bring them together.</p>
<p>In this unsettling climate of closing bookshops, and the growing popularity of ebooks and online retailers such as the <a href="http://www.bookdepository.com">Book Depository</a>, you might not think that there could be any kind of union (imagined or not) between the technology of the future and the dusty bookshelves of the past. But Sloan has created such a delightful and fun fictional universe, and such a lovable cast of characters with which to populate it, that his ideas about how to embrace the future without losing or forgetting the past feel both inspiring and plausible. While his heroes can’t solve their mystery without the might of Google, they’re also lost without what Google employees amusingly refer to as ‘old knowledge’ (OK) and ‘traditional knowledge’ (TK): what’s existed in people’s heads, and in the pages of books, for centuries. “Imagine if we could make all that OK/TK available all the time, to everyone,”’ one of Kat’s colleagues muses. At the heart of Clay’s quest is the desire to unite this knowledge with the leaps and bounds of modern technology—to bring the two together without losing something important, and indefinably human, in the process.</p>
<p>Is it actually possible? Who knows. For all that it touches on a very timely and topical issue, <em><a href="http://www.boomerangbooks.com.au/Mr-Penumbras-24-hour-Bookstore/Robin-Sloan/book_9781922079169.htm">Mr Penumbra&#8217;s 24-hour Bookstore</a></em> has a lovely lightness of touch, and it resonates with Sloan’s obvious passion for the printed word. It’s a fantasy with its head rooted in reality, but it’s no less enjoyable and inventive for that—and no less a resounding testament to why we love stories, no matter what form they take.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/375/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/375/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=375&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://bibliostrumpet.wordpress.com/2012/10/11/when-page-and-screen-collide/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/83c95100b093dc9b1dd1d70a328d5474?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">misswhisk</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>To Want &#8220;But Little&#8221;: Reflections from a Second Grade Classroom</title>
		<link>http://erikachristakis.wordpress.com/2012/10/12/to-want-but-little-reflections-from-a-second-grade-classroom/</link>
		<comments>http://erikachristakis.wordpress.com/2012/10/12/to-want-but-little-reflections-from-a-second-grade-classroom/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2012 13:37:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>ErikaChristakis</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Children/Teens/Young Adults]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[My story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children's moral thinking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children's play]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[importance of play]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moral development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[play]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://erikachristakis.wordpress.com/?p=2338</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[“My greatest skill in life was wanting but little.”   -Henry David Thoreau Here&#8217;s an old journal entry I wrote when I was student-teaching in a second grade class with a master teacher who had a profound influence on me. I&#8217;ve been reflecting more recently on the value of children&#8217;s play (something I do a lot) and [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2338&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://erikachristakis.wordpress.com/2012/10/12/to-want-but-little-reflections-from-a-second-grade-classroom/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>23</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/6a75cd09a1ad41b5bee55fa5503ac7f9?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">erikachristakis</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://erikachristakis.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/images6.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">images</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Getting Out the Vote</title>
		<link>http://themamafesto.wordpress.com/2012/10/12/getting-out-the-vote/</link>
		<comments>http://themamafesto.wordpress.com/2012/10/12/getting-out-the-vote/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2012 12:00:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>The Mamafesto</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[kid thoughts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Obama2012]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://themamafesto.wordpress.com/?p=2240</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s no secret that I&#8217;ve always been politically minded and involved. When I had my son, that didn&#8217;t change and I probably became even more politically conscious. I strapped him to my back and went out to vote, ran exit polls for Planned Parenthood, and helped campaign on both local and national levels. But more [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2240&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_2241" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://themamafesto.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/402668_10151442713324988_1970704435_n.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-2241" title="402668_10151442713324988_1970704435_n" alt="" src="http://themamafesto.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/402668_10151442713324988_1970704435_n.jpg?w=300&#038;h=211" height="211" width="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Yup. That&#8217;s my kiddo.</p></div>
<p>It&#8217;s no secret that I&#8217;ve always been politically minded and involved. When I had my son, that didn&#8217;t change and I probably became even more politically conscious. I strapped him to my back and went out to vote, ran exit polls for Planned Parenthood, and helped campaign on both local and national levels. But more importantly, I did my best to keep an open dialogue with my son about the political process at an age-appropriate level. I taught him the importance of voting as a civic duty, and he&#8217;s joined me as I&#8217;ve casted my ballot in every election since his birth, even in non-presidential election years.</p>
<p>We&#8217;re a family that listens to the local (some might call it progressive) radio show in the morning and NPR at other times while in the car, and I happen to have a 5.5 year old who is a total sponge with really well trained ears, and an inquisitive nature. Something will catch his attention and he&#8217;ll ask question after question until he&#8217;s satisfied. I&#8217;m both proud and &#8211; at times &#8211; overwhelmed by this particular quality.</p>
<p><a href="http://themamafesto.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/big-bird-presidential-debates-romney1.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-2242" title="big-bird-presidential-debates-romney1" alt="" src="http://themamafesto.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/big-bird-presidential-debates-romney1.jpg?w=246&#038;h=300" height="300" width="246" /></a>So it hasn&#8217;t really taken me by surprise that in the last few weeks, most of his questions are related to the election &#8211; especially when that&#8217;s pretty much all everyone is talking about. Last week after the first debate between President Obama and Mitt Romney, somebody on the radio mentioned Big Bird and the kiddo&#8217;s ears perked up big time.</p>
<p>&#8220;Big Bird?! Why are they talking about Big Bird?&#8221;</p>
<p>We listened to the analysis of the debate together before I answered his questions. By the end of the car ride, EZ was well versed in Romney&#8217;s declaration that he&#8217;d pull funding from PBS in order to lower the national debt (which, as my pal Joanne Bamberger <a href="http://www.punditmom.com/2012/10/romney-thinks-big-bird-is-a-moocher" target="_blank">has explained</a>, is less than a drop in the bucket in the grand scheme of things). Later that evening, I found him still puzzling over what we had talked about earlier.</p>
<p>&#8220;Does that mean I won&#8217;t get anymore Wild Kratts? He can&#8217;t take my Wild Kratts!&#8221; I asked.</p>
<p>&#8220;I&#8217;m sure you&#8217;d still get your Wild Kratts. Maybe.&#8221;</p>
<p>And that, I thought, was the end of that.</p>
<p>Until yesterday evening when I got an email from EZ&#8217;s teacher (who also happens to be a friend of mine from before his days in Kindergarten) that included the following:</p>
<blockquote><p>E is apparently a VERY passionate Obama supporter. He was telling everyone at snack that Mitt Romney [...] would get rid of Pbs.org so everyone HAD to vote for Obama.</p></blockquote>
<p>The email went on to say that while she thought it was very cute, that perhaps we could talk to EZ about framing his thoughts in another way, since we never know which way other families lean, and EZ&#8217;s enthusiastic emphasis on <em><strong>needing</strong></em> to vote for Obama might leave some kids feeling out of place.</p>
<p>I totally understood what his teacher was saying, and agreed to think about ways to talk about this with EZ, but not before feeling a huge swell of pride that my son took it upon himself, unprompted, to do a little bit of campaigning for the President. Then, I sat down to figure out how to deal with this situation. His teacher certainly wasn&#8217;t saying that political talk in school was discouraged (although it did seem clear that EZ was the only kid bring politics up at snack), but that we had to find a way to discuss politics where everyone&#8217;s choices felt validated.</p>
<p>Fair enough.</p>
<p>So, while he took his bath, the kiddo and I talked. We talked about how just like we can&#8217;t force someone to like the same type of food or music we like, we also can&#8217;t do the same for who we feel should be President. I told him that I loved that he thought about these things and that he clearly felt so passionate about this one issue, but that we can find a way to discuss this and also make sure that everyone leaves the conversation having their own opinion. It seemed to go over well &#8211; I think. In typical 5.5 year old fashion, he then immediately turned the topic over to his birthday party plans (which, ahem, isn&#8217;t until January, but clearly ever-present on his mind) and all political talk ended for the time being.</p>
<p>However, I want to hear from YOU &#8211; have your kids broached politics in school or in a similar setting? How did it go? And I would also love any thoughts you might have on additional conversations I could have with the kiddo about politics and how we talk about them. <strong>Please leave your thoughts below!</strong></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2240/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2240/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2240&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://themamafesto.wordpress.com/2012/10/12/getting-out-the-vote/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>49</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://themamafesto.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/402668_10151442713324988_1970704435_n.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://themamafesto.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/402668_10151442713324988_1970704435_n.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">402668_10151442713324988_1970704435_n</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/de400df62df5592d2a3c647842246ff7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">themamafesto</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://themamafesto.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/402668_10151442713324988_1970704435_n.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">402668_10151442713324988_1970704435_n</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://themamafesto.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/big-bird-presidential-debates-romney1.jpg?w=246" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">big-bird-presidential-debates-romney1</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Post Challenge: Stairway to Heaven</title>
		<link>http://breezybooksblog.wordpress.com/2012/10/08/stairway-to-heaven/</link>
		<comments>http://breezybooksblog.wordpress.com/2012/10/08/stairway-to-heaven/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2012 20:30:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Maddie Cochere</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[breezy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[haiku]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[limerick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-publishing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stairway to heaven]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://breezybooksblog.wordpress.com/?p=1225</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I’m a fiction writer. Poetry is not my thing. I tried to write a poem for this post, and my husband said, “You didn’t rhyme the last two lines.” Of course I did. I’m not an idiot. I went back and read them. Hmmm … I guess “come” doesn’t rhyme with “done.” Crap! But, in [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1225&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I’m a fiction writer. Poetry is not my thing. I tried to write a poem for this post, and my husband said, <a href="http://breezybooksblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/mothergoose1.jpg"><img class="alignright" style="border:0 none;" src="http://breezybooksblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/mothergoose1.jpg?w=256&#038;h=370" alt="Image" width="256" height="370" /></a>“You didn’t rhyme the last two lines.” Of course I did. I’m not an idiot. I went back and read them. Hmmm … I guess “come” doesn’t rhyme with “done.” Crap!</p>
<p>But, in an effort to post outside of my comfort zone, I am forging ahead with poetry. I even have a picture to use for inspiration. Also outside of my comfort zone is to ask for participation. I can barely squeak out a question at the end of my posts, so this is definitely outside of my comfort zone. (I just used the words “comfort zone” three times in one paragraph. Now four.) So, here we go …</p>
<p>Sing with me. Led Zepplin. Stairway to Heaven. Do you have it in your head? Good.</p>
<p>Thanks to my husband, whenever I go out into our backyard, the song rolls around in my head. There isn’t a stairway to heaven out there, there’s a stairway to nowhere. Now sing the song using the words “buying a stairway to nowhere.”</p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 340px"><a href="http://breezybooksblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/dsc00327.jpg"><img style="border:0 none;" src="http://breezybooksblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/dsc00327.jpg?w=330&#038;h=249" alt="Image" width="330" height="249" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Click for a closer view.</p></div>
<p style="text-align:left;">This summer, the house next door to ours was gutted and completely renovated. The stairway in question used to go to the door to the kitchen. As you can see, they made a new entrance with new stairs. They didn’t remove the old stairs; they simply painted them <em>brown</em>. What were they thinking? For me personally, the stairs to nowhere would be a deal breaker.</p>
<p>Rather than try to understand the logic, let us pay homage to the stairs to nowhere today. Leave a poem, limerick, haiku, or simply your comment about the stairs to nowhere – or anything else for that matter. I’ll walk over, sit on the stairs, and read your work or comment aloud. Maybe. I might pay a neighbor kid to do it.</p>
<p>We’ll start. Here’s hubby’s limerick because he is a fountain when it comes to limericks:</p>
<p>There once were some steps, a total of four,<br />
That led from the ground up to the door.<br />
The door went away,<br />
An improvement some say.<br />
Now they lead to a door that’s no more.</p>
<p>Good, but BORING. His <a href="http://breezybooksblog.wordpress.com/2012/09/08/do-you-want-to-kill-your-blog-posts2/#comments">bacon/schmeckel</a> limerick was so much better. If he hadn’t mowed the grass this past weekend and used up all of his energy, I’m sure he would have given us better.</p>
<p>Here’s my poem:</p>
<p>Oh stairs once gray,<br />
I feel your dismay.<br />
Slathered in brown,<br />
The bane of the town.</p>
<p>You went to the kitchen,<br />
You used to be bitchin’.<br />
Now useless to all,<br />
There is only a wall.</p>
<p>That is why I don’t do poetry.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://breezybooksblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/ugly_leaves1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter" style="border:0 none;" src="http://breezybooksblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/ugly_leaves1.jpg?w=428&#038;h=261" alt="Image" width="428" height="261" /></a></p>
<p>Let me try a haiku:</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Gray happy stairway<br />
Leaves fall on distressing brown<br />
Renovation sucks</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">I’m supposed to take a moment to reflect on the experience of this new type of blog post for me. It only took a nanosecond to have my thought: Poetry is hard. I’m stickin&#8217; with fiction.</p>
<p>Your turn.<br />
Just go with it.</p>
<p><a href="http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2012/10/08/weekly-writing-challenge-and-now-for-something-completely-different/">http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2012/10/08/weekly-writing-challenge-and-now-for-something-completely-different/</a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1225/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1225/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1225&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://breezybooksblog.wordpress.com/2012/10/08/stairway-to-heaven/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>116</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/b862d8acaa80f1418e5b224c9c5133b5?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=R" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">maddiecochere</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://breezybooksblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/mothergoose1.jpg?w=390" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://breezybooksblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/dsc00327.jpg?w=487" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://breezybooksblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/ugly_leaves1.jpg?w=428" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nudibranch and the Ocean</title>
		<link>http://krisss86.wordpress.com/2012/10/11/nudibranch-and-the-ocean/</link>
		<comments>http://krisss86.wordpress.com/2012/10/11/nudibranch-and-the-ocean/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2012 13:49:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Krisss</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Underwater]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life cycle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nudibranch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scuba diving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sketch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[undereater]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://krisss86.wordpress.com/?p=2092</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Once upon a time, in the vast open ocean, there were corals as diverse as plants on land and fishes as much as the stars in the sky. But they weren&#8217;t the only ones. There were also sharks, turtles, starfish, seahorse, crabs and other sea animals as much as you can count (if you can). [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2092&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Once upon a time, in the vast open ocean, there were corals as diverse as plants on land and fishes as much as the stars in the sky. But they weren&#8217;t the only ones. There were also sharks, turtles, starfish, seahorse, crabs and other sea animals as much as you can count (if you can). But of course, there lived one tiny creature that was hard to miss.</p>
<p>She was colourful and considered one of the most beautiful creature underwater. Due to her striking colours, she was quite safe from her predators because it gives out warning that she was poisonous, which was not the case at all. Some of her relatives do pose danger for other animals if disturbed, but she just somehow harmlessly possess vibrant colours. Her name was <strong>Risbecia Tryoni</strong>.</p>
<p><a href="http://krisss86.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/423430_10150991190477934_830168810_n.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-2094" title="tryoni1" alt="" src="http://krisss86.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/423430_10150991190477934_830168810_n.jpg?w=300&#038;h=300" height="300" width="300" /></a></p>
<p>She was barely 2 centimeters in length. She was so tiny that you might think she&#8217;ll get washed up by the strong currents and get eaten by other animals. But no, she thrived to survive. Her small figure helped her hid in holes and crevices easily, which was great because that&#8217;s where her food source will be. Sponges and algae she feeds on everyday.</p>
<p><a href="http://krisss86.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/223954_10151029410077934_1600707728_n.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-2095" title="tryoni2" alt="" src="http://krisss86.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/223954_10151029410077934_1600707728_n.jpg?w=225&#038;h=300" height="300" width="225" /></a>And soon enough, she grew to matured size. Her angel-like mantle flapping was one of her captivating features besides the purple spots and lines along her mantle.</p>
<p><a href="http://krisss86.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/418853_10151043429672934_1000600770_n.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-2096" title="tryoni3" alt="" src="http://krisss86.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/418853_10151043429672934_1000600770_n.jpg?w=225&#038;h=300" height="300" width="225" /></a>Along the way she met friends. She&#8217;s a follower. She loved following them. And follow is what they do to each other! Sometimes one of them will be the leader. Sometimes one becomes the follower. Sometimes one will realise that it&#8217;s better off to trail away.</p>
<p><a href="http://krisss86.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/p1160552-copy.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-2097" title="tryoni4" alt="" src="http://krisss86.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/p1160552-copy.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" height="225" width="300" /></a>But for Tryoni, she loved being a follower <img src='http://s0.wp.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif' alt=':)' class='wp-smiley' /> . One time, a friend that she was following caught her attention. She had found her soulmate. She knew that this other Tryoni is the best for her and it was a mutual feeling. So they started dating and exchanged their personal keepings.</p>
<p><a href="http://krisss86.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/p1160481.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-2098" title="tryoni5" alt="" src="http://krisss86.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/p1160481.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" height="225" width="300" /></a>Sad to say that she needs to move on after that. All of them do. All her relative slugs do. They move on after the courtship. But that doesn&#8217;t slow her down because she knows she has went through that one important step in her life! And by now, all the personal keepings that she has exchanged with her ex-partner were ready to be released. So she kept crawling and looking for a suitable spot. Better still, a place where it&#8217;s near to her food source. She finally found it and started her ritual dance. The sacs started coming out from her reproductive organs called gonopore, forming red ribbon-like structures on the rock. She started swirling in the direction of an anti-clockwise while laying the red ribbon, filled with millions of eggs.</p>
<p><a href="http://krisss86.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/p1170032-copy.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-2099" title="tryoni6" alt="" src="http://krisss86.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/p1170032-copy.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" height="225" width="300" /></a></p>
<p>And after she&#8217;s done, she moved on, leaving her next generation behind, hoping that they too will survive in the wild like her. What&#8217;s her next plan? I don&#8217;t know. Only she knows where her trail will lead her to. She might bump into new friends, start her trailing dance, meeting new partners again. But one thing she knows for sure. The ocean is a big playground with plenty of adventures, risks and dangers waiting for her. But she will just have to keep crawling endlessly into the open ocean until she needs to stop and rest eternally.</p>
<p><em>*This short story is inspired by all the nudibranchs I&#8217;ve met. All of them told me more or less the same story anyway. <img src='http://s2.wp.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_razz.gif' alt=':P' class='wp-smiley' /> </em></p>
<p>To commemorate Tryoni&#8217;s bravery, here&#8217;s a sketch I did of her (no pun intended)<a href="http://krisss86.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/cb3c7ecc138311e2942b123138190f7f_7.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-2103" title="tryoni7" alt="" src="http://krisss86.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/cb3c7ecc138311e2942b123138190f7f_7.jpg?w=300&#038;h=300" height="300" width="300" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2092/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2092/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2092&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://krisss86.wordpress.com/2012/10/11/nudibranch-and-the-ocean/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>23</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/93e58ec3b51e6111c6d799dc24b76481?s=96&#38;d=monsterid&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">KristenSoong</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://krisss86.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/423430_10150991190477934_830168810_n.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tryoni1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://krisss86.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/223954_10151029410077934_1600707728_n.jpg?w=225" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tryoni2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://krisss86.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/418853_10151043429672934_1000600770_n.jpg?w=225" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tryoni3</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://krisss86.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/p1160552-copy.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tryoni4</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://krisss86.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/p1160481.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tryoni5</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://krisss86.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/p1170032-copy.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tryoni6</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://krisss86.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/cb3c7ecc138311e2942b123138190f7f_7.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tryoni7</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>