<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2012 18:53:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>The Crayon Fascist</title>
		<link>http://deepbluenight.wordpress.com/2012/01/08/the-crayon-fascist/</link>
		<comments>http://deepbluenight.wordpress.com/2012/01/08/the-crayon-fascist/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2012 01:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>techlady911</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[childhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[control]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crayon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fascist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[funny]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[neurosis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[postaweek2012]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deepbluenight.wordpress.com/?p=267</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[They&#8217;re my Crayons. I&#8217;ll show you exactly how to use them. But I won&#8217;t let you. This is how my husband described my childhood issue with my Crayons. I think it&#8217;s pretty accurate. Let me explain. As a kid, I loved to color. For the longest time, I got along with my little box of 16 [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=267&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><!--?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?-->They&#8217;re my Crayons. I&#8217;ll show you exactly how to use them. But I won&#8217;t let you.</p>
<p>This is how my husband described my childhood issue with my Crayons. I think it&#8217;s pretty accurate. Let me explain.</p>
<p>As a kid, I loved to color. For the longest time, I got along with my little box of 16 measly colors (I was a spoiled kid), wishing I could color Cinderella&#8217;s gown Cornflower when all I had was Blue. Then one day my mom came home from a shopping trip with that magic box of 64 Crayola® crayons &#8211; the one with the built-in sharpener on the back. (I&#8217;m hearing a choir of angels right now just thinking about it.) I carefully opened the lid &#8211; how cool was that lid? &#8211; and beheld the majesty of the 64 different colors. Maize! I had a Maize crayon! They were packaged so carefully, with the crayons subdivided into four smaller boxes. It looked to me like the people at the Crayola® factory arranged the colors into four coordinated and happy groups. It was just beautiful.</p>
<div id="attachment_269" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 260px"><img class="size-full wp-image-269 " title="64crayons" src="http://deepbluenight.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/64crayons.jpg" alt="" width="250" height="250" /><p class="wp-caption-text">gocksfrocks.blogspot.com</p></div>
<p>And that&#8217;s where my issues started.</p>
<p>Any time I used my Fantastic Box of 64 Crayola® Crayons, I would carefully select the color that was exactly appropriate to the item I was coloring, gently slide it out of its spot in the Smaller Box Inside the Big Box, color with it lightly (after first meticulously outlining the section to be colored), then slide it back into its appointed space. Thus I maintained the order and beauty of The Fantastic Box of 64 Crayola® Crayons the way the fine people of Binney &amp; Smith had worked so hard to provide.</p>
<p>Then the neighborhood kids came to my house to color.</p>
<p>We headed to the basement where my little kid-sized table &amp; chairs were. There was the Fantastic Box. As I spread out the selection of coloring books, I watched in utter horror as my friend Beth opened the Fantastic Box and dumped the contents out onto the tabletop. I was speechless. But not for long.</p>
<p>&#8220;WHAT ARE YOU DOING?!&#8221; I shrieked.</p>
<p>Beth was just as dumbfounded. &#8220;Coloring.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;NO!! YOU CAN&#8217;T DO THAT!! THEY&#8217;RE IN ORDER!!&#8221; Panic was beginning to rise, along with the pitch of my voice. Binney &amp; Smith were never going to allow me to have another Fantastic Box of 64 Crayola® Crayons if I didn&#8217;t fix this <em>fast</em>.</p>
<p>&#8220;DON&#8217;T TOUCH THEM!&#8221; I hollered. I tried to envision that pristine box. Was Cerulean next to Brick Red, or Indian Red? Or was that Blue Green?</p>
<p>Beth just stared at me. &#8220;You&#8217;re weird,&#8221; she pronounced, and picked up a crayon &amp; started coloring. Roughly, too. I lost it.</p>
<p>I have very little memory of exactly what I said and did right then, but I think it involved some pushing and grabbing. Poor Beth got disgusted and left. I did my best to put the Box back together the way it was, hoping that Binney &amp; Smith would forgive me.</p>
<p>And thus it happened every time one of my playmates came over to color. I would hold tightly to the Fantastic Box of 64 Crayola® Crayons, and instruct my little friend in the acceptable usage of my crayons: take one at a time, do NOT peel the paper, and put it back in the exact spot that it came from. God help the child who broke one. They were banished from my basement indefinitely.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s safe to say that I lost more than one friend over my fascism. But it didn&#8217;t faze me.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s the sad part: I see this quirk raising its horrid head to this day. I&#8217;m very picky about how my classroom equipment is used &amp; stored. (This can be quite a problem, as I&#8217;m in charge of several video cameras, tapes, microphones, and headphones for our broadcast program.) I have two pen/pencil holders at work: one that is for anyone to use as they wish, and one that is MINE. I get very uncomfortable when anyone mistakenly takes something from the MINE holder. I manage to not yank whatever it is out of the hand of the poor unsuspecting student or colleague, but my stomach is slightly queasy until it is back in its home in the MINE container. I even prohibit students from touching anything on my desk. I keep it light, and thankfully they always comply, asking before they come into the Magic Space (as they call it.) I&#8217;m also responsible for the maintenance of the school&#8217;s laptop carts. Just close your eyes and imagine what kind of stress that causes me. I keep a large supply of Tums in my desk.</p>
<p>The Crayon Fascist lives.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/267/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/267/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/267/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/267/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/267/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/267/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/267/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/267/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/267/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/267/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/267/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/267/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/267/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/267/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=267&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://deepbluenight.wordpress.com/2012/01/08/the-crayon-fascist/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/062606cc673848578107766b97540838?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F0.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">techlady911</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://deepbluenight.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/64crayons.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">64crayons</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>New Year, New World</title>
		<link>http://boundsouth.org/2012/01/01/new-year-new-world/</link>
		<comments>http://boundsouth.org/2012/01/01/new-year-new-world/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2012 02:47:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Isaiah Berg</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Mexico]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new years]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[patzcuaro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reflection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[satanic jungle of Mazatlan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TCM cargo ferry]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://boundsouth.org/?p=1369</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[We_awoke_in_our tent to the gentle rocking of a cargo ferry with mainland Mexico and the port city of Mazatlan on the horizon.  Impossibly thick ropes soon flew from the ship to secure it to the numerous huge pylons anchored on shore.  Following dozens of big rigs and their sleepless drivers, many of whom had slept [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=1369&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We<span style="color:#ffffff;">_</span>awoke<span style="color:#ffffff;">_</span>in<span style="color:#ffffff;">_</span>our tent to the gentle rocking of a cargo ferry with mainland Mexico and the port city of Mazatlan on the horizon.  Impossibly thick ropes soon flew from the ship to secure it to the numerous huge pylons anchored on shore.  Following dozens of big rigs and their sleepless drivers, many of whom had slept on the cold hallway floors of the ship the night before, we rode our bicycles off the ferry and into the gateway to mainland Mexico.  We stopped at an auto garage to ask for directions to the Malecon, the shorefront main street of many Mexican port cities where we were meeting a North Dakota connection.  After receiving directions and some words of caution, we were assured by the mechanic that Mazatlan was a “satanic jungle” and that he would pray for our safety as we traveled through.  Someone should put that on a billboard or something.</p>
<p><a href="http://boundsouth.org/2012/01/01/new-year-new-world/img_6107/" rel="attachment wp-att-1385"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-1385" title="IMG_6107" src="http://boundsouth.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/img_6107.jpg" alt="" width="1000" height="760" /></a></p>
<p>Mild confirmation bias is our saving grace.  It is certainly <em>possible</em> that Mazatlan was the most dangerous city we’ve seen yet in Mexico.  We’re not so sure.  Our hosts in the city did drive me by a restaurant that had been shot up by the local mob after it didn’t pay its protection money.  The traffic and people were far from menacing, though they may have been in more of a rush than those on the Baja.  We’ve received dire warnings from other Mexicans about Mazatlan, and when we got to Mazatlan we received dire warnings about the places we passed through to get there.  Were it not for a careful optimism on our parts, we would have never braved the border at Tijuana.  We continue to absorb as much information as we can, even if it does little to alter our route or our conscious optimism about the road ahead.  If Mom and Dad are reading this, don’t worry, we’ll totally consider hitch hiking or something if a Latin American civil war breaks out in 2012.</p>
<p><a href="http://boundsouth.org/2012/01/01/new-year-new-world/img_5654/" rel="attachment wp-att-1379"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-1379" title="IMG_5654" src="http://boundsouth.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/img_5654.jpg" alt="" width="1000" height="606" /></a></p>
<p>I miss home and our family a great deal, accustomed as I was to spending this season with them.  The New Year has us all reflecting on the past year, especially the way that countless families have taken us in and made us feel like one of their own.  The Catholic Diocese of Whitehorse, the Coopers of Coeur d’Alene, the Pfeiffers of Portland, the Samuels of Santa Monica, the Taylors of San Diego, and the Salazars of Guadalajara are just a few of these.  Thank you all for what you’ve done for us.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><a href="http://boundsouth.org/2012/01/01/new-year-new-world/img_5970/" rel="attachment wp-att-1383"><img class="size-full wp-image-1383 aligncenter" title="IMG_5970" src="http://boundsouth.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/img_5970.jpg" alt="" width="667" height="1000" /></a><br />
December has foreshadowed the rest of our journey in 2012.  We’ve climbed some tremendous mountains in Mexico’s western highlands, and we respect the toll that it takes on our bodies.  The Andes will only be bigger, more challenging, and more spectacular.  I’ve dealt with illness for the first time since leaving Anchorage.  A dreadful headache became a cold and ear infection; sadly, I’m still recovering and the illness has cost us some time and miles.  Rest and health can’t be compromised, and once I’m healthy we’ll be riding strong once again.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><a href="http://boundsouth.org/2012/01/01/new-year-new-world/img_5784/" rel="attachment wp-att-1380"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-1380" title="IMG_5784" src="http://boundsouth.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/img_5784.jpg" alt="" width="1000" height="485" /></a></p>
<p>The human and geographical diversity of the mainland is incredible.  Megacities and rural farming villages and beautiful lakes and mountains rise up at every turn.  Most of North America, even the Baja, has been defined by the vast, empty natural landscapes between places.  This New World brims with life and a constant human presence.  Riding a few mornings ago beside Lake Chapala, we struggled up an impossibly steep cobblestone climb for seven kilometers.  Every turn had us greeting another farmer or laughing child or family with a breathless “Buenos Dias” and a smile through gritted teeth.  It’s almost as if we’ve been practicing piano in the family room since leaving Alaska, and finally we’ve reached our recital and constant audience in the new world of mainland Mexico.  Sometimes we’re self-conscious, but most of the time we’re smiling, inspired, and excited for our next opportunity to inspire a stranger’s day with our story.</p>
<p><a href="http://boundsouth.org/2012/01/01/new-year-new-world/img_5972/" rel="attachment wp-att-1384"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-1384" title="IMG_5972" src="http://boundsouth.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/img_5972.jpg" alt="" width="1000" height="857" /></a></p>
<p>Hemingway once recounted in a conversation with a friend, A.E. Hotchner, that &#8220;If you are lucky enough to have lived in Paris as a young man, then wherever you go for the rest of your life it stays with you, for Paris is a moveable feast.&#8221;  If there ever was a moveable feast, it is this bicycle expedition.  The sights and smells and sensations will linger and move with me long after we reach Ushuaia in Argentine winter.  In the meantime, I hope that you all find richness and love and a moveable feast of your own in 2012.</p>
<p><a href="http://boundsouth.org/2012/01/01/new-year-new-world/img_5905/" rel="attachment wp-att-1382"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-1382" title="IMG_5905" src="http://boundsouth.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/img_5905.jpg" alt="" width="1000" height="827" /></a></p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://boundsouth.org/category/mexico/'>Mexico</a> Tagged: <a href='http://boundsouth.org/tag/new-years/'>new years</a>, <a href='http://boundsouth.org/tag/patzcuaro/'>patzcuaro</a>, <a href='http://boundsouth.org/tag/reflection/'>Reflection</a>, <a href='http://boundsouth.org/tag/satanic-jungle-of-mazatlan/'>satanic jungle of Mazatlan</a>, <a href='http://boundsouth.org/tag/tcm-cargo-ferry/'>TCM cargo ferry</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1369/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1369/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1369/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1369/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1369/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1369/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1369/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1369/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1369/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1369/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1369/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1369/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1369/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1369/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=1369&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://boundsouth.org/2012/01/01/new-year-new-world/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">isaiahberg</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://boundsouth.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/img_6107.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_6107</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://boundsouth.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/img_5654.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_5654</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://boundsouth.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/img_5970.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_5970</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://boundsouth.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/img_5784.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_5784</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://boundsouth.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/img_5972.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_5972</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://boundsouth.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/img_5905.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_5905</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Death of Anticipation</title>
		<link>http://incaseimgone.com/2012/01/09/death-of-anticipation/</link>
		<comments>http://incaseimgone.com/2012/01/09/death-of-anticipation/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2012 18:30:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>leighmcg3</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Open thoughts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[busyness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christmas season]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cookie magazine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[death of anticipation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Generation Me]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nathaniel branden]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twenge]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://incaseimgone.com/?p=1115</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The Christmas season is over and as I reflect back I see that for all it&#8217;s rushing and busyness, there is something to be said for a time of year that forces us to wait for something. Christmas Day is the one day of the year that still has the build of anticipation. That giddy [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=1115&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Christmas season is over and as I reflect back I see that for all it&#8217;s rushing and busyness, there is something to be said for a time of year that forces us to wait for something. Christmas Day is the one day of the year that still has the build of anticipation. That giddy feeling that something you really want is coming. That the promise of what&#8217;s ahead is so exciting you can barely sleep. It&#8217;s a special feeling, and one we are sorely lacking in today&#8217;s highly technological and immediate world.</p>
<p>Years ago I read an article in Cookie Magazine about the Death of Anticipation and it stuck with me. Our modern world leaves less and less room for expectation and excitement and in many ways I think that&#8217;s a shame. I&#8217;ll take you through the top points heralded in Cookie to better illustrate what I mean:</p>
<p>In 1969 Nathaniel Branden wrote <em>The Psychology of Self Esteem</em> which established a link between healthy self esteem and future success. Though I believe this to be true, that a healthy sense of self worth is essential to future success, I believe we might have gone a bit too far. Every child is important and every effort is worthy of praise but we&#8217;ve found ourselves in a world where every child gets a medal. Where simply showing up is considered success. A world where children aren&#8217;t to be singled out for bad OR good behavior. Loch got his first medal at his pre-school annual Thanksgiving fundraiser. It&#8217;s called the Turkey Trot. The kids run as many laps as they can around the school and then everyone gets a certificate printed with their name and number of laps and a medal. I thought this was terrific. He was proud. I was proud.  The kids are all included. Whether you did 50 laps or 5, no one is left out. But they&#8217;re in preschool. The oldest kid is 5. I think the problem stems from extending this mentality straight through high school. Why should anyone get excited about winning a race when the people who just put on their shoes get as much fanfare. In 1996 Dr. Jean M. Twenge published a fascinating book called <em><a href="http://www.amazon.com/o/ASIN/0743276981" target="_blank">Generation Me</a></em>. <a href="http://incaseimgone.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/bookcover.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-1126" title="generation me" src="http://incaseimgone.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/bookcover.jpg?w=194&#038;h=300" alt="" width="194" height="300" /></a>Generation Me is defined as anyone born in the 1970&#8242;s, 80&#8242;s and 90&#8242;s. Though being born in the mid 70&#8242;s myself, I&#8217;d say I see this phenomenon more in the 80&#8242;s and 90&#8242;s babies, but for the purpose of the example you can lump us 1970&#8242;s kids in there. The Me Generation is the generation that take it for granted that self comes first. We&#8217;re also known as the Entitlement Generation. &#8220;Generation Me has never known a world that put duty before self, and believes that the needs of the individual should come first. This is not the same thing as being selfish – it is captured, instead, in the phrases we so often hear: &#8220;Be yourself,&#8221; &#8220;Believe in yourself,&#8221; &#8220;Love yourself before you can love someone else.&#8221;* These have become some of our most deeply entrenched beliefs.</p>
<p>&#8220;We live in a time when high self-esteem is encouraged from childhood, when young people have more freedom and independence than ever, but also far more depression, anxiety, cynicism, and loneliness. Today&#8217;s young people have been raised to aim for the stars at a time when it is more difficult than ever to get into college, find a good job, and afford a house. Our expectations are very high just as the world is becoming more competitive, so there&#8217;s a huge clash between expectations and reality. More than any other generation in history, the children of Baby Boomers are disappointed by what they find when they arrive at adulthood.&#8221; ** The question becomes are we raising our children, and have we ourselves been raised with, unrealistic hopes, undisciplined self-assertion, and endless, baseless self-congratulation.*** You find examples of this in the school system every day. In Canada you can no longer fail a student. Grade inflation is a big gaff of the United States that runs right into college, and &#8220;independent spelling&#8221; and self grading has become way more accepted than it should. According to Twenge 30% of students polled believed they should pass a class simply because they showed up. If everything we do is fabulous and worthy then how do we adjust when everything doesn&#8217;t go our way?</p>
<p>If just being there earns us a medal, it creates a disconnect in our brain regarding what we are worth and what we deserve with very little effort on our parts. In a world where reality stars make more money than doctors what are we teaching our children? It&#8217;s the Teen Mom / Kardashian empire phenomenon. I was recently talking to a 17 year old who was graduating from High School and when I asked her what she wanted to do she said she wanted to be a reality star or, tongue and cheek, a trophy wife. It was depressing. She wasn&#8217;t really joking. But why shouldn&#8217;t she want that? Lack of talent and shame is now a calling card in our society. It&#8217;s as if we&#8217;ve been told we&#8217;re so great for so long that we buy our own press. Why wouldn&#8217;t everyone want to know what I&#8217;m eating for dinner? Tweet. Why should I start at the bottom of this company? I&#8217;m really smart and special. Quit. Why should I work for a company in the first place? I&#8217;ll just start my own business. Fail. It&#8217;s tough. Upbringing and celebrity culture are at a real cross roads with reality. <a href="http://incaseimgone.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/474334-l.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-1127" title="Ready or not here comes life" src="http://incaseimgone.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/474334-l.jpg?w=195&#038;h=300" alt="" width="195" height="300" /></a>Dr. Mel Levine, a pediatrics professor at the University of North Carolina Medical School and author of a book called <em>Ready or Not, Here Life Comes</em>, says  &#8221;We&#8217;re seeing an epidemic of people who are having a hard time making the transition to work — kids who had too much success early in life and who&#8217;ve become accustomed to instant gratification&#8221; .</p>
<p>I&#8217;m all for going out on your own. For entrepreneurial endeavors. For thinking outside the box. Some say it&#8217;ll be the new generation of &#8220;Me thinkers&#8221; that get America on it&#8217;s feet again. They&#8217;re referred to as &#8220;productive narcissists&#8221;. Michael Maccoby, author of <em>Narcissitic Leaders: Who Succeeds and Who Fails</em>, argues &#8220;that businesses that rely on innovation, new technology, and globalization require far bolder leaders who can take risks, shrug off conventional wisdom, project confidence, formulate hyper-ambitious plans, and charm the pants off investors and underlings alike, so that they, too, will make a leap of faith and believe in the next cold-fusion-powered car or the iPod that pays your bills and runs your household.&#8221; <a href="http://incaseimgone.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/103228501.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-1132" title="Narcissitic Leaders" src="http://incaseimgone.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/103228501.jpg?w=200&#038;h=300" alt="" width="200" height="300" /></a>It is just my opinion that self esteem can be healthy without being over blown, and that once you get past preschool the best project, runner, swimmer, etc. should be the one who goes home with the ribbon. Why would anyone ever practice, strive or work to uncover their talents if they&#8217;re taught that everything they already do is amazing and worthy of praise? Who are these people auditioning for <em>American Idol</em> who can&#8217;t sing? Or <em>So You Think You Can Dance</em> who can&#8217;t dance? Why are their families there with signs that say they&#8217;re the best. Why can&#8217;t we believe in our children without blowing smoke up their a*%es. Why can&#8217;t we love them and support them within the frame of reality? Egos become very fragile when they aren&#8217;t based in truth.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s hard to anticipate your future successes if you think by simply existing you will succeed. The only people that works for is trust fund babies and supermodels.</p>
<p>But, I digress. Other things we have ceased to anticipate&#8230;.</p>
<p>In the 1980&#8242;s strawberries became available all year round. This might seem simplistic and not worth mentioning but I think it&#8217;s indicative of a culture that has placed value more on quantity over quality. Have</p>
<div id="attachment_1143" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://incaseimgone.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/dscf1099.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1143" title="huge strawberry" src="http://incaseimgone.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/dscf1099.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">peneloperow.blogspot.com</p></div>
<p>you seen strawberries lately? They used to be my favorite fruit. Juicy, sweet, red all the way through and the size of a quarter. Now, you bite into one and it&#8217;s almost always white, flavorless and more often than not, the size of a plum. Strawberries were not meant to get that big. We were supposed to eat apples in the fall and strawberries in the spring and summer. To this day I think there is nothing more delicious than a Ontario grown summer peach. But I don&#8217;t want one in the middle of February. Just like I don&#8217;t want Turkey in May. I&#8217;ll wait for Thanksgiving or Christmas. In our efforts to give everyone what they want when they want it, we&#8217;ve sacrificed the very thing we desire. It&#8217;s the waiting that makes it special.</p>
<p>In 1987 the sonogram was perfected to let us know the sex of our baby with almost 100% certainty and without a great aunt twirling a spoon over our belly. Now, I would be a hypocrite to critize this technology as I found out what we were having before Loch was born.Though I was happy to know I&#8217;ll readily admit it does take the surprise out of it. Personally, it was a surprise I didn&#8217;t want. Not so much so we could do the baby room in the right color or get appropriate non-gender neutral baby gifts, but more because I was favoring a girl and I didn&#8217;t want to have even one moment of confusion or disappointment in the delivery room. I wanted to be happy and adjusted and feel nothing but joy. And that was the right choice for me. As I&#8217;ve said before, it took me about a month to get over pig tails and party dresses and the fact that most children&#8217;s stores are 3/4 girl stuff, till I was psyched to have a boy. When Loch came out, I was thrilled to see him. However, I think it&#8217;d be fair to say that the sonogram and it&#8217;s subsequent technology has also lead to scheduled C-sections (of which many of my friends are big proponents of), early inductions pre-delivery date to avoid those last pounds, and official birth plans that rarely go as expected and more often than not cause mothers endless extra hours of grief as they try and keep on point. Sometimes you just have to let things unfold as they will.</p>
<div id="attachment_1145" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://incaseimgone.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/browser-war-market-share-internet-news-technology-chrome-ie9-firefox-safari-opera-free-online-thenextweb.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1145" title="browsers" src="http://incaseimgone.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/browser-war-market-share-internet-news-technology-chrome-ie9-firefox-safari-opera-free-online-thenextweb.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">mmncs.com</p></div>
<p>The 1990&#8242;s were probably the biggest blow to the concept of delayed gratification. We saw the birth of the internet, the creation of caller ID, answering machines or services in almost every home and the creation of digital cameras. No more waiting all day for your song to come on the radio. Or for your pictures to be developed. No more trying to time a call just right to make sure someone was home. You can avoid people you don&#8217;t want to speak to with caller ID but our kids will never know the joy of hoping that that ring is for you. &#8220;Please let it be Jeff. Pleeease let it be Jeff. &#8221; There is an entire generation of kids that don&#8217;t realize that you didn&#8217;t use to be able to look at a picture right after you took it and quite frankly, it&#8217;s just made us all more vain. &#8220;Ugh, I look terrible. Delete it. Take it again.&#8221;</p>
<p>We don&#8217;t get telegrams. We don&#8217;t wait for letters. We have email and voice mail and text messaging. Everything is right away. Every new step is faster than the next.</p>
<p>You no longer have to wait for your show to come on TV as you can watch it at your leisure on whatever DVR device you happen to be using now. Personally I often miss the television season altogether and watch the episodes back to back on Netflix or On Demand later. You don&#8217;t have to hope that Blockbuster isn&#8217;t out of the movie you want, because they&#8217;re all available on streaming services in your mailbox, on line or on your TV.</p>
<p><a href="http://incaseimgone.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/tinkerbellwonderfulworlddisneysmall.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-1153" title="TinkerbellWONDERFULworldDisneySMALL" src="http://incaseimgone.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/tinkerbellwonderfulworlddisneysmall.jpg" alt="" width="243" height="172" /></a>I can remember as a child waiting all week for <em>The Wonderful World of Disney</em> to come on on Sunday nights. It was so exciting to hear those first few cords of <em>When You Wish Upon A Star</em> knowing I had one whole hour of television just for me. Loch has been watching kids shows on demand since he was a baby. He&#8217;ll never know the joy of that suspense. And, not that it matters like it used to with all of today&#8217;s viewing choices, but 1994 also saw the Olympics switched to an alternating schedule. Instead of waiting 4 years between Olympics we now wait 2 and really are only one trial away from the next one. The Olympics used to be an event. Capital E. It was the only time we ever brought a TV to the cottage. Now you watch the opening ceremonies and TiVo the rest. I&#8217;m still glued to it, but will the next generation be? The more available something is the less exciting. Or maybe, we have so much now, very little even registers as exciting at all&#8230;</p>
<p>Kids still await summer but with the talk of year round school really becoming a reality &#8211; LAUSD is starting mid August now &#8211; what summer will they really be awaiting? And, to be a real downer &#8211; if you look at the environmental shifts, the Greenhouse effect is making our earth warmer and warmer every year. Without a real change we could be looking at a future of summer all year round. Let&#8217;s try to avoid that shall we?</p>
<p>It&#8217;s the little things as well as the big ones. It&#8217;s being grown up enough to wear high heels. Nope, Suri Cruise, age 3 has them, I want them too. Earning money to buy your first car. No way dude, I&#8217;m 16, where&#8217;s my ride?! Waiting till you&#8217;re in a serious relationship to sleep with someone? Who does that? Trading sex for favors in grade school or jr. high sex parties are becoming the NORM. I&#8217;m literally afraid for my kid.</p>
<p>The biggest things we anticipate nowadays is new technology (if you&#8217;re my husband) or sequels to films and books (if you&#8217;re me). Ah, <em>Deathly Hallows </em>how I loved you. I eagerly awaited you in print and celluloid and you didn&#8217;t disappoint. But please, can more people do this? It&#8217;s so fun to look forward to something.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s the thing, kid&#8217;s need to look forward to things. Adults do too. It makes things special. Loch is blessed at Christmas time to have a Gigi that gives us a present for every day (!) of advent. It&#8217;s incredibly thoughtful and we love it, but when I watched Loch wake up every morning in December excited to open a present, I wondered how much it was distracting from the excitement of Christmas Day itself. When I was young I did an advent calendar with pictures for every day. Some years I even added a chocolate one. I loved it but I didn&#8217;t get any presents till the 25th. I&#8217;d certainly never tell my mother-in-law to stop. It&#8217;s a lovely tradition that comes from her heart &#8211; and I&#8217;m sure it&#8217;s different for Sean&#8217;s brother&#8217;s family who have 3 children, so that the majority of the gifts aren&#8217;t for just one child &#8211; I&#8217;m just not crazy about Loch seeing December as one big smorgasbord of gifts. Maybe I should stop letting him unwrap Sean and my gifts. It&#8217;s become more about the present itself than the meaning behind it.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m hoping to instill some sense of suspense into Loch&#8217;s life but it&#8217;s hard. Everything in his world is so readily available. So instantaneous. He asked to do something the other day and I said, &#8220;We&#8217;ll see.&#8221; and he said, &#8220;Yay!!!&#8221;. I realized in that moment that though I don&#8217;t give him everything he asks for, I do give him a lot, and a lot right away. If he wasn&#8217;t going to get it I would have just said, &#8220;No.&#8221; My saying &#8220;We&#8217;ll see.&#8221; to him meant &#8220;Yes&#8221;. It also leads to a &#8220;what&#8217;s next&#8221; mentality. When you get what you want right away, you&#8217;re often off to the next thing before you really enjoy the first. Without anticipation. Without waiting. Without having the time to truly want, it&#8217;s hard to appreciate and ever really, truly enjoy.</p>
<p>Anticipation in itself is a gift. One I&#8217;m going to have to work harder to give.</p>
<div id="attachment_1139" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 560px"><a href="http://incaseimgone.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/wallcoo-com_christmas_66-550x412.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1139" title="waiting for Santa" src="http://incaseimgone.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/wallcoo-com_christmas_66-550x412.jpg" alt="" width="550" height="412" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Lovely Kid waiting for Santa wallcoo.net</p></div>
<p>* Generation Me, Jean M. Twenge, PhD</p>
<p>** Generation Me, Jean M. Twenge, PhD</p>
<p>***Roy F. Baumeister, author of <em>The Cultural Animal: Human Nature, Meaning, and Social Life</em>, and Eppes Eminent Professor of Psychology, Florida State University</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1115/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1115/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1115/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1115/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1115/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1115/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1115/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1115/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1115/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1115/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1115/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1115/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1115/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1115/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=1115&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://incaseimgone.com/2012/01/09/death-of-anticipation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/e2adac0cf1e919c391393d47744bb3aa?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">leighmcg3</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://incaseimgone.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/bookcover.jpg?w=194" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">generation me</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://incaseimgone.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/474334-l.jpg?w=195" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ready or not here comes life</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://incaseimgone.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/103228501.jpg?w=200" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Narcissitic Leaders</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://incaseimgone.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/dscf1099.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">huge strawberry</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://incaseimgone.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/browser-war-market-share-internet-news-technology-chrome-ie9-firefox-safari-opera-free-online-thenextweb.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">browsers</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://incaseimgone.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/tinkerbellwonderfulworlddisneysmall.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">TinkerbellWONDERFULworldDisneySMALL</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://incaseimgone.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/wallcoo-com_christmas_66-550x412.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">waiting for Santa</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Urban Composting: how to convince your building that it&#8217;s cool.</title>
		<link>http://domaphile.com/2012/01/10/urban-composting-how-to-convince-your-building-that-its-cool/</link>
		<comments>http://domaphile.com/2012/01/10/urban-composting-how-to-convince-your-building-that-its-cool/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2012 02:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>domaphile</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[garden]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Green]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[composting]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://domaphile.com/?p=2632</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s January 10th and I am pleased to announce that I have already fulfilled a resolution!  Never mind that it was a resolution made back in 2010.  This weekend we inaugurated a volunteer-run, community-wide composting program in my apartment building.  It took about two seconds to dump the first batch of kitchen scraps into it [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=2632&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://domaphile.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/5.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2630" title="SONY DSC" src="http://domaphile.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/5.jpg?w=465" alt=""   /></a></p>
<p>It&#8217;s January 10th and I am pleased to announce that I have already fulfilled a resolution!  Never mind that it was a resolution made back in 2010.  This weekend we inaugurated a volunteer-run, community-wide composting program in my apartment building.  It took about two seconds to dump the first batch of kitchen scraps into it and about two  years to get to that point.</p>
<p><a href="http://domaphile.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/32.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2628" title="SONY DSC" src="http://domaphile.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/32.jpg?w=465" alt=""   /></a></p>
<p>Until yesterday, my family had been composting with worms in our apartment for several years and I can&#8217;t say enough <a title="It’s Earth Day.  Time to get your compost on." href="http://domaphile.com/2011/04/22/earth-day-time-to-get-your-compost-on/" target="_blank">good things about worm bins</a>! In my perfect world, every apartment kitchen would come with a built-in worm cabinet, just like they used to come with drop-down ironing boards.  However, as a family of four that cranks out three meals a day, the number of food scraps we produced was overwhelming our bin.  We would need three or four worm bins to manage our food scraps and &#8211; unless we built our coffee table out of worm bins (which isn&#8217;t such a bad idea, actually) &#8211; there would be nowhere to put them in our &#8220;cozy&#8221; abode.  Since a number of my neighbors had also expressed interest in composting (one was already going to the trouble of freezing her scraps and hauling them down to the Union Square Greenmarket, one of the cities compost collection sites), it seemed worth exploring a communal composting solution for our building.</p>
<p>Composting in New York City seems to be where <a href="http://www.nyc.gov/html/nycwasteless/html/resources/history.shtml" target="_blank">recycling was in the early 1980&#8242;s</a>: something that is slowly gaining momentum, but is still viewed as outside the mainstream.  I imagine there were the same arguments against recycling then, as there are against composting now:  that it takes too much time to separate your garbage, that somehow the building&#8217;s facilities staff will be unduly burdened, and is it really worth it anyway? And, of course, there is an extra barrier for some people: &#8220;Ew! Worms!&#8221; or &#8220;won&#8217;t it smell gross?&#8221;.   While I&#8217;m an advocate of recycling and feel that everyone should take responsibility for the waste they produce, recycling by necessity relies on an infrastructure to actually transform your plastic bottle or newspaper into something new and useful.  Composting, by contrast, is a closed system.  You get a bin, add your scraps, stir it around, and a few months later you have a beautiful, rich compost that can be added to your plants or tree beds (you could probably even sell it on Etsy).  There is literally no downside and a huge upside in the palpable reduction of your own garbage (26% of the material that ends up in landfills is food scraps and yard waste that could be composted instead).  With the vast number of different types of <a href="http://www.gardeners.com/Composters/20706,default,sc.html" target="_blank">compost bins on the market these days</a>, there is a fit for just about any lifestyle.  For people outside urban areas with easy access to outdoor space, a compost bin should be a no-brainer.  And if you live in a city and don&#8217;t produce more than 3 lbs of food scraps per week, a worm bin would suit you just fine.  But for those of us in the middle: living in a city with a family and producing more waste than one worm bin can handle, the best thing to do is to band together with your neighbors.</p>
<p>We are lucky in New York City to have organizations like the <a href="http://www.lesecologycenter.org/" target="_blank">Lower East Side Ecology Center</a> that work to promote sustainability through community-based recycling and composting programs.  They offer workshops on all types of recycling, including a class I attended back in 2010 on how to go about initiating a building-wide composting initiative.  The presenter spoke about the ups and downs of convincing her co-op board to let a few residents install communal worm bins in the basement of her large building.  As you can imagine, not everyone was on board with this idea (see: &#8220;Ew! Worms! above).  She outlined a strategy to go about convincing her board and neighbors that, indeed, communal composting is a fabulous idea:</p>
<ol>
<li><span style="color:#000000;"><strong>Start by garnering the support of your neighbors</strong>. This is a volunteer endeavor and doesn&#8217;t require the buy-in of the entire building.   You just need between 2-4 families to form a pilot project.  In fact, it is better to start small and add people as the project becomes a success.</span></li>
<li><span style="color:#000000;"><strong>Try to get the building management on your side</strong>.  After all, even if the program is completely resident run, it will have an impact on the building&#8217;s waste management workflow and it is helpful to have a good relationship with those who maintain the public spaces.  If you live in a rental building with high turnover, this will be a harder sell as it will really fall to building maintenance staff to keep it going. But who knows? They may just be waiting for this opportunity!</span></li>
<li><span style="color:#000000;"><strong>Present it to the powers-that-be in the form of a well written proposal. </strong> Outline it as a pilot-project involving a core group of residents that will be reviewed by the board in three to six months. Knowing that they have a mechanism for terminating the project if it doesn&#8217;t work seems to go a long way toward assuaging the angst many building managers and their boards have about this kind of change.  Make sure the proposal highlights the benefits of composting while also addressing common concerns all in one page.  Here is a basic template to use: <a href="http://domaphile.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/composting-proposal-template.pdf"><span style="color:#000000;">Composting Proposal Template</span></a></span></li>
<li><span style="color:#000000;"><strong>Prepare to be rebuffed initially</strong>.  Perhaps outright or perhaps by evasion.  There will never be time to address it in the meeting.  Or it will be &#8220;too much for the building to take on right now&#8221;.  Don&#8217;t be discouraged &#8211; it took over a year and a half for my building to come around.  Gentle prodding and reminders about how many buildings in the city are already composting successfully will help.  Without being totally annoying, talk incessantly about how many fewer garbage bags will sit on the curb once we are composting.  Appeal to the &#8220;green&#8221; side of the folks in control.  No one wants to look like the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Lorax" target="_blank"><span style="color:#000000;">Once-ler</span></a>.  </span></li>
<li><span style="color:#000000;"><strong>If you live in NYC, call in the experts</strong>. For only $25, a member of the LESEC  will visit your building, give a composting demonstration and talk to building managers and residents about the specifics of composting in the city, which is what we did one Sunday in early December. There is nothing like hearing it from an outside authority and I can&#8217;t say enough about how important this was for us.  We spent two hours on a Sunday afternoon talking about &#8220;greens&#8221; and &#8220;browns&#8221; with Natalie from LESEC and at the end of it, even the initial critics were enthusiastic about the project. They even helped us select the most appropriate bin for our building.</span></li>
</ol>
<p>Once you get the green light, you are almost there.  The next step is selecting and ordering the bin.  After much reflection, we decided to go with the <a href="http://eartheasy.com/jora-jk270-compost-tumbler" target="_blank">Jora JK270 Compost Tumbler</a>, which we ordered from EarthEasy.  It is on the more expensive end of the spectrum and you can certainly get a good bin for much less, but we chose it because it had enough capacity for our entire building, and it&#8217;s dual chamber set allows one to keep adding to the other side of the bin once the first side is full and needs to cure.  The fact that it sits high off the ground making it extra pest proof and easy to spin sealed the deal.</p>
<p><a href="http://domaphile.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/11.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2626" title="SONY DSC" src="http://domaphile.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/11.jpg?w=465" alt=""   /></a></p>
<p>Once it arrived, the next step was to put it together.  Coming from Sweden, the directions were written in high IKEA and totally unfathomable.  Luckily, EarthEasy includes helpful assembly videos on their site.   We watched as a strapping young lad took about 11 minutes to assemble the bin all by himself.</p>
<span style="text-align:center; display: block;"><a href="http://domaphile.com/2012/01/10/urban-composting-how-to-convince-your-building-that-its-cool/"><img src="http://img.youtube.com/vi/f6ccQCVCNBU/2.jpg" alt="" /></a></span>
<p>If I showed you a video of my husband and me assembling the JoraJK270, it would have to be a feature length-film, as it took us nearly three hours to put the damn thing together and almost ended our marriage. The film would be considered a  &#8220;dramedy&#8221;, and I do admit that I questioned my commitment to the environment that evening.  But that is behind us now and we have a rockin&#8217; bin to show for it.</p>
<p>The next challenge was collecting enough &#8220;browns&#8221; &#8211; the carbon based plant material that forms one part of the composting quadrivium: Browns, Greens, Air and Water. In a healthy outdoor bin, you should have two parts brown material to one part green material.  Greens are what you have in your kitchen.  Browns are what you have in your yard.  Except when it&#8217;s December in NYC and you don&#8217;t exactly have a yard.  Thus, began a rather comical search for lawn waste that ended in my surreptitious foraging for mulch in Central Park.  It was exciting. I mean, I could have been <em>arrested</em>.</p>
<p>Once the bin, the browns and the appropriate signage had all been assembled, the bin was open for business:</p>
<p><a href="http://domaphile.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/21.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2627" title="SONY DSC" src="http://domaphile.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/21.jpg?w=465" alt=""   /></a></p>
<p>First the &#8220;browns&#8221; were added.</p>
<p><a href="http://domaphile.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/6.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2631" title="SONY DSC" src="http://domaphile.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/6.jpg?w=465" alt=""   /></a></p>
<p>Then the kitchen scraps.</p>
<p>I covered them with some more browns, gave the bin a spin, and walked away.  It should be that easy in every building.  So far, we have five committed participants and another 5 or 6 residents who want to join in the fun.  As half of our building consists of graduate students, we will orient them to the bin next fall.  Who knows what lies ahead: fruit flies? Strange smells? Reduced garbage?  Hopefully gorgeous compost that is so badly needed in our garden and for our poor street trees.  Wish us luck and we will keep you posted.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2632/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2632/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2632/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2632/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2632/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2632/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2632/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2632/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2632/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2632/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2632/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2632/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2632/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2632/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=2632&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://domaphile.com/2012/01/10/urban-composting-how-to-convince-your-building-that-its-cool/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/b6f87a566ac5fce4031c0148ba993a8a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">domaphile</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://domaphile.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/5.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">SONY DSC</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://domaphile.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/32.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">SONY DSC</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://domaphile.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/11.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">SONY DSC</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://domaphile.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/21.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">SONY DSC</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://domaphile.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/6.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">SONY DSC</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Review: Moonwalking with Einstein</title>
		<link>http://seejy.wordpress.com/2012/01/11/book-review-moonwalking-with-einstein/</link>
		<comments>http://seejy.wordpress.com/2012/01/11/book-review-moonwalking-with-einstein/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2012 10:30:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jie Yi See</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Book reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Book review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Moonwalking with Einstein]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Memory]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tony Buzan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ben Pridmore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mind map]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internal memory]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[external memory]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://seejy.wordpress.com/?p=1327</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Have you thought about something, turned your head and SNAP, our mind just goes blank at the next instant. If this sounds familiar to you, then “Moonwalking with Einstein” will bring you new insights about your internal memory. Written by science and tech journalist Joshua Foer, this book extensively discusses about the art and science [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=1327&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://seejy.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/moonwalking22.jpg"><img src="http://seejy.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/moonwalking22.jpg" alt="" title="Moonwalking with Einstein" width="263" height="400" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1344" /></a>Have you thought about something, turned your head and SNAP, our mind just goes blank at the next instant. If this sounds familiar to you, then <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Moonwalking-Einstein-Remembering-Everything-ebook/dp/B004H4XI5O/ref=br_lf_m_1000744291_1_15_img?ie=UTF8&amp;s=digital-text&amp;pf_rd_p=1330163142&amp;pf_rd_s=center-4&amp;pf_rd_t=1401&amp;pf_rd_i=1000744291&amp;pf_rd_m=ATVPDKIKX0DER&amp;pf_rd_r=03ACX6KV0PGX7645P3VM" target="_blank">“Moonwalking with Einstein”</a> will bring you new insights about your internal memory.</p>
<p>Written by science and tech journalist <a href="http://joshuafoer.com/" target="_blank">Joshua Foer</a>, this book extensively discusses about the art and science of remembering.</p>
<p>Warning: This is not a self-help book and will not instruct you to improve your memory. Rather, this book should be treated as an intriguing piece of investigative journalistic work, where history, research, interviews and Foer’s personal experiences get mashed up in its narrative.</p>
<p>Initially assigned to cover memory competitions, Foer grew increasingly fascinated after hearing repeatedly from numerous memory champions that anyone could boost their memory.<br />
<blockquote>“It’s all about technique and understanding how the memory works,” <a href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/uk_news/magazine/7982327.stm" target="_blank">Ben Pridmore, a World Memory Champion</a> said in a newspaper interview. “Anyone could do it, really.”</p></blockquote>
<p>Such bold claims not only kick-start Foer’s journey into memory sports but also got me suckered into the finishing the book.<br />
<span id="more-1327"></span><br />
Alright, I admit to relying heavily on my electronic devices as an external memory to remind me about the “nitty-gritty details” in my daily life. I need my iPhone to store all my contacts because I can barely recall beyond five telephone numbers, Facebook to remind me about my friends’ birthdays and my camera to record visual copies of my holiday trips.</p>
<p><em>“As more and more of our lives move online, more and more is being captured and preserved in ways that are dramatically changing the relationship between our internal and external memories,” Foer wrote. </em></p>
<p>This book strongly juxtaposes against our modern behavior, advocating for us to rely on our notoriously unreliable internal memory.</p>
<p>Foer proves this point by using his own brains as an experiment and also training grounds to gear up for the 2006 U.S. Memory Competition in under a year’s time and he was dead-pan serious about what he did. <div id="attachment_1346" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 410px"><a href="http://seejy.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/foer-earmuffs-and-goggles.jpg"><img src="http://seejy.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/foer-earmuffs-and-goggles.jpg" alt="" title="Foer, earphones and goggles" width="400" height="263" class="size-full wp-image-1346" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Foer with his earphones and black goggles to help him concentrate</p></div>Picture a grown-up man wearing industrial-grade earmuffs and black safety goggles with two small eyeholes, hunching and staring intensely at pages of random numbers in the basement of a house. Reading about his trainings were at times laughable but his spirit is definitely admirable. </p>
<p>Yet his seriousness did prove one thing in the end &#8211;  our memories are improvable. </p>
<p><em>“The goal of training one’s memory was to develop the capacity to leap from topic to topic and make new connections between old ideas,” Foer wrote.</em></p>
<p>One of the many tricks mentioned to boost your memory is to develop the capacity to quickly create multisensory images that will link disparate ideas. In fact, conjuring dirty images or funny jokes will better lock the memory as compared to sheer rote memorization. </p>
<p>And amongst the memorization techniques mentioned, I was surprised to find out that I have been taught in elementary school one of them. The image below is an example of it: <a href="http://www.mindmapinspiration.com/3d-thinking-mind-map-paul-foreman/"><img src="http://seejy.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/mind-map-example1.jpg" alt="" title="Mind map example" width="500" height="393" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1330" /></a>Mind mapping is a memory technique commonly linked with mnemonist <a href="http://www.tonybuzan.com/" target="_blank">Tony Buzan </a>to create various associative hooks to help sink in images of a particular concept.</p>
<p>Towards the end of the book, Foer concludes in a very simple manner,<br />
<blockquote>“Now more than ever, as the role of memory in our culture erodes at a faster pace than ever before, we need to cultivate our ability to remember. Our memories make us who we are.”
</p></blockquote>
<p>As true as his words are, as I finish up the last words of the book, I realized I have already forgotten the earlier contents that I have read.</p>
<p>Time to work on my memory.  </p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1327/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1327/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1327/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1327/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1327/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1327/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1327/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1327/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1327/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1327/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1327/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1327/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1327/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1327/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=1327&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://seejy.wordpress.com/2012/01/11/book-review-moonwalking-with-einstein/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/4ccdca162f99d96eebb8e0e84b7c184d?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Jie Yi See</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://seejy.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/moonwalking22.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Moonwalking with Einstein</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://seejy.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/foer-earmuffs-and-goggles.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Foer, earphones and goggles</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://seejy.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/mind-map-example1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mind map example</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The way to our hearts</title>
		<link>http://loveandaleash.com/2012/01/10/the-way-to-our-hearts/</link>
		<comments>http://loveandaleash.com/2012/01/10/the-way-to-our-hearts/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2012 11:18:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Aleksandra</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Snickerdoodle]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://loveandaleash.com/?p=3170</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s funny, how some of them find the way to your heart as though they were hitching a ride on cupid&#8217;s arrow. Don&#8217;t get us wrong. We have loved every one of our foster dogs to little bits and pieces. With some of them, the bond we&#8217;ve formed feels almost as strong as the one [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=3170&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s funny, how some of them find the way to your heart as though they were hitching a ride on cupid&#8217;s arrow.</p>
<p>Don&#8217;t get us wrong. We have loved every one of our foster dogs to little bits and pieces. With some of them, the bond we&#8217;ve formed feels almost as strong as the one we share with our own Sir Chick. But with Snickerdoodle? We fell hard and fast. Within 24 hours, I was saying to foster dad &#8220;we&#8217;re going to keep him.&#8221; Within 48, I was brainstorming how we could possibly squeeze three dogs into our tiny house &#8212; two of our own plus a foster.</p>
<p>In the interest of full disclosure, I&#8217;ve threatened to keep at least four our fosters so far, and gone on to bravely find them a perfect home of their own. Saying goodbye has been bittersweet with most of them, and I&#8217;ve cried after sending off at least half of them. But we&#8217;ve done what&#8217;s best for them and sent them on their way. I&#8217;m putting my money on the same thing happening with Snickerdoodle.</p>
<p>We&#8217;re already mourning the day in the future when we&#8217;ll have to say goodbye, but in the meantime, we&#8217;re walking on clouds and loving every minute.</p>
<p><a href="http://loveandaleash.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/snickerdoodle-120105-59.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3171" title="Snickerdoodle-120105-59" src="http://loveandaleash.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/snickerdoodle-120105-59.jpg" alt="" width="550" height="365" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://loveandaleash.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/snickerdoodle-120105-79.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3172" title="Snickerdoodle-120105-79" src="http://loveandaleash.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/snickerdoodle-120105-79.jpg" alt="" width="550" height="365" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3170/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3170/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3170/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3170/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3170/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3170/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3170/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3170/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3170/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3170/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3170/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3170/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3170/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3170/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=3170&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://loveandaleash.com/2012/01/10/the-way-to-our-hearts/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>32</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/040ba26a9a506dc9b22c7de7e9b7ef75?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">agajdeczka</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://loveandaleash.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/snickerdoodle-120105-59.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Snickerdoodle-120105-59</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://loveandaleash.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/snickerdoodle-120105-79.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Snickerdoodle-120105-79</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tokyo winterscape</title>
		<link>http://tokyoholic.wordpress.com/2011/11/28/tokyo-winterscape/</link>
		<comments>http://tokyoholic.wordpress.com/2011/11/28/tokyo-winterscape/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2011 12:11:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Natalia</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Japan and me]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Out and about]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mitou-san]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Okutama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[three mountains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[toumin no mori. hiking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[winter forest]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tokyoholic.wordpress.com/?p=3247</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Last Saturday, me and my husband rented a car and went to Okutama (the far western part of Tokyo prefecture) to enjoy a 4 hour hike to the top of Mitou-san. I was hoping to see koyo (red leaves) but the season was already over due to the cold weather in that particular mountain area.. [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=3247&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://tokyoholic.wordpress.com/2011/11/28/tokyo-winterscape/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/21c3466c55e882660aeff2bf553ed291?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F0.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Natalia</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tokyoholic.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/p1160360.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Momiji</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tokyoholic.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/p1160386.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Yellow leaves</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tokyoholic.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/p1160389.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Old leaves</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tokyoholic.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/p1160590.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Pine</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tokyoholic.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/p1160394.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Trail</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tokyoholic.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/p1160395.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Winter forest</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tokyoholic.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/p1160428.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mountain ridge</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tokyoholic.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/p1160442.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">At the top</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tokyoholic.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/p1160457.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Fujisan</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tokyoholic.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/p1160464.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Picnic at the top</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tokyoholic.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/p1160511.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">On the trail</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tokyoholic.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/p1160558.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Sunset in the forest</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tokyoholic.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/p1160583.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Dry kaki</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Asparagus and feta quiche</title>
		<link>http://ilrossoleone.com/2011/11/21/asparagus-and-feta-quiche/</link>
		<comments>http://ilrossoleone.com/2011/11/21/asparagus-and-feta-quiche/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2011 09:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>ajbatchelor</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Lunch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spring]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ilrossoleone.com/?p=68</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8216;That smells so good I can&#8217;t even sleep&#8217; It&#8217;s a great compliment to hear. My wife was attempting a pre-lunch snooze on the couch and was having trouble drifting off, the smell of my cooking was keeping her awake. I&#8217;d just opened the oven to turn the quiche 180 degrees, which I&#8217;d learnt through experience [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=68&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&#8216;That smells so good I can&#8217;t even sleep&#8217;</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a great compliment to hear. My wife was attempting a pre-lunch snooze on the couch and was having trouble drifting off, the smell of my cooking was keeping her awake.</p>
<p>I&#8217;d just opened the oven to turn the quiche 180 degrees, which I&#8217;d learnt through experience was a necessity if I didn&#8217;t want whatever I was cooking to be half underdone and half overdone.</p>
<p>This was my first quiche, asparagus and feta with a pastry lining that happened to be gluten free. Not that I have anything against gluten, some of my favorite foods contain gluten.</p>
<p>My wife however is a glutenist. An unabashed glutenist. If she&#8217;s at a restaurant and gets even a faint hint of gluten in her food, she&#8217;ll down her cutlery and refuse to eat another mouthful. She&#8217;s been known to be at a party and if there is gluten in the food, she&#8217;ll flat-out refuse to eat.</p>
<p>Sometimes she even asks for a separate menu that is entirely gluten free.</p>
<p>Which is why I&#8217;d chosen to adapt my quiche to being gluten free.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://ilrossoleone.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/quiche-pics.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-83" title="Quiche pics" src="http://ilrossoleone.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/quiche-pics.jpg?w=738&#038;h=461" alt="" width="738" height="461" /></a></p>
<p>We&#8217;d had a surfeit of eggs through our kitchen recently, I&#8217;d soft-boiled some for salads and snacks, contemplated throwing some at passing cars and also decided to make a quiche.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s the perfect weather here for quiche, the spring time days lend themselves to outdoor eating, you want something that has a bit of substance but is also light. And as it&#8217;s spring there&#8217;s an abundance of great vegetables about. After a quick look in the fridge I&#8217;d decided that my first quiche was going to be salmon, tomato, asparagus, feta, cucumber and bean. That thought lasted about 10 seconds before I realised there&#8217;d be more veggies than egg and parred it back to onion, asparagus and feta.</p>
<p>I started with the pastry. I&#8217;d never attempted gluten free pastry before and wasn&#8217;t entirely sure what to expect. The recipe I was using suggested that I throughly knead the pastry, I interpreted this as sqiudge the dough together quickly, I wanted to keep my hands out of the pastry as much as possible to keep the butter from getting to warm and figured that without gluten there wasn&#8217;t much point in spending time trying to develop long gluten strands.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://ilrossoleone.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/quiche-pics1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-84" title="Quiche pics1" src="http://ilrossoleone.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/quiche-pics1.jpg?w=738&#038;h=461" alt="" width="738" height="461" /></a></p>
<p>The free-range eggs that we&#8217;ve been getting gave the pastry a really warm yellow glow. I wrapped the pastry in cling-film and placed it in the fridge to make a start on the filling.</p>
<p>As there was only three ingredients it was pretty straight-forward. I sliced and steamed some asparagus and then as soon as it was crisp but still cooked dunked it in ice and cubed up some feta.</p>
<p>The pastry had been chilling for long enough.  I floured my bench and faced my first cooking dilema. No rolling pin.  I&#8217;ve always viewed single-purpose kitchen tools as redundant and as a rolling pin only does one thing I&#8217;d never got around to purchasing one.  I&#8217;ve used many round things as a substitute over the years, vodka bottlers, milk bottles and the occasional just flatten it out with my hands approach. This time I went high-tech and used a thermos.</p>
<p>The pastry ended up being a bit more sticky than I thought it would be so I had to separate it from the bench with a spatula and roll it up to get it into the tin for cooking.  Once the pastry was in the tin there were a couple of holes on the sides that needed patching but as soon as I was happy with it the mixture was poured in.</p>
<p>Which gets me to where I started. &#8217;That smells so good I can&#8217;t even sleep&#8217;.</p>
<p><strong>Recipe</strong></p>
<p><strong>Pastry</strong></p>
<p>225 grams gluten free flour</p>
<p>100 grams butter</p>
<p>1 large egg, beaten</p>
<p><strong>Filling</strong></p>
<p>1 red onion, sliced</p>
<p>3 eggs, beaten</p>
<p>150 ml milk</p>
<p>150 grams feta, cubed</p>
<p>1 bunch asparagus, steamed and sliced</p>
<p><strong>Method</strong></p>
<p>Add the butter to the flour in a large bowl, with a pinch of salt. Rub the ingredients together to form a breadcrumb texture. Add 2-3 tablespoons of water to form a dough. Wrap in plastic wrap and refrigerate.</p>
<p>Pre-heat the oven to 200C. Slice the onion, steam the asparagus and cube the feta. Beat eggs and add milk. Add onion, feta and asparagus to the egg mixture. Set aside. Roll out pastry on floured surface to 5mm thick. Grease quiche tin and place pasty in tin, patch any holes.</p>
<p>Pour the mixture into the pastry lined tin and season with pepper and salt.</p>
<p>Cook for 25-30 minutes.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://ilrossoleone.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/quiche-pics2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-85" title="Quiche pics2" src="http://ilrossoleone.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/quiche-pics2.jpg?w=819&#038;h=512" alt="" width="819" height="512" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/68/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/68/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/68/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/68/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/68/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/68/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/68/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/68/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/68/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/68/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/68/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/68/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/68/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/68/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=68&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://ilrossoleone.com/2011/11/21/asparagus-and-feta-quiche/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/82942bc9cca46ced7c47a812b8595822?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ajbatchelor</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ilrossoleone.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/quiche-pics.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Quiche pics</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ilrossoleone.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/quiche-pics1.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Quiche pics1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ilrossoleone.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/quiche-pics2.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Quiche pics2</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Documenting a motorbike adventure in the Himalayas</title>
		<link>http://iaincrockart.wordpress.com/2011/11/26/documenting-a-motorbike-adventure-in-the-himalayas/</link>
		<comments>http://iaincrockart.wordpress.com/2011/11/26/documenting-a-motorbike-adventure-in-the-himalayas/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2011 13:57:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>iaincrockart</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Black and White]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Himalayas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photographic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Royal Enfield Bullet]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://iaincrockart.wordpress.com/?p=336</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I love motorbiking. I have recently returned from the Himalayas where I was documenting a 1400km journey made by over 30 people on 350cc Royal Enfield Bullets. The landscape was literally out of this world. We road to a height of 18,340ft. If you would like to see the book I made of this incredible [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=336&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://iaincrockart.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/iaincrockart-_d3x3548.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-337" title="www.iaincrockart.com" src="http://iaincrockart.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/iaincrockart-_d3x3548.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="426" /></a><a href="http://iaincrockart.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/iaincrockart-_d3x3717.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-338" title="IainCrockart-_D3X3717" src="http://iaincrockart.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/iaincrockart-_d3x3717.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="426" /></a><a href="http://iaincrockart.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/iaincrockart-_d3x2963.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-340" title="IainCrockart-_D3X2963" src="http://iaincrockart.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/iaincrockart-_d3x2963.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="426" /></a>I love motorbiking. I have recently returned from the Himalayas where I was documenting a 1400km journey made by over 30 people on 350cc Royal Enfield Bullets. The landscape was literally out of this world. We road to a height of 18,340ft. If you would like to see the book I made of this incredible adventure click on this link&#8230; http://www.blurb.com/bookstore/detail/2526661  The adventure was organised by www.endurohimalaya.com</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/336/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/336/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/336/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/336/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/336/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/336/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/336/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/336/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/336/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/336/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/336/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/336/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/336/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/336/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=336&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://iaincrockart.wordpress.com/2011/11/26/documenting-a-motorbike-adventure-in-the-himalayas/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/220f27f12ae637264156a950e118c15b?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">iaincrockart</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://iaincrockart.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/iaincrockart-_d3x3548.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">www.iaincrockart.com</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://iaincrockart.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/iaincrockart-_d3x3717.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IainCrockart-_D3X3717</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://iaincrockart.files.wordpress.com/2011/11/iaincrockart-_d3x2963.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IainCrockart-_D3X2963</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Darkness Indulged</title>
		<link>http://amuseume.wordpress.com/2012/01/11/darkness-divulged/</link>
		<comments>http://amuseume.wordpress.com/2012/01/11/darkness-divulged/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2012 17:47:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>lalalalainat</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Fashion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aldo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[banana republic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[black]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[forever21]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fur]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[h&m]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lipstick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[maxi skirt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rebecca minkoff]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://amuseume.wordpress.com/?p=225</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I think this blog has been instrumental in forcing myself to choose bolder pieces. Up until this winter, I don&#8217;t think I ever would have considered fur, and now I have this black coat and a  vest! Of course, they&#8217;re both  faux fur, but they actually retain a lot of heat to keep me warm. [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=225&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://amuseume.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/img_9285.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-226" title="IMG_9285" src="http://amuseume.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/img_9285.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=682" alt="" width="1024" height="682" /></a><a href="http://amuseume.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/img_9302.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-227" title="IMG_9302" src="http://amuseume.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/img_9302.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=682" alt="" width="1024" height="682" /></a><a href="http://amuseume.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/img_9299.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-228" title="IMG_9299" src="http://amuseume.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/img_9299.jpg?w=682&#038;h=1024" alt="" width="682" height="1024" /></a>I think this blog has been instrumental in forcing myself to choose bolder pieces. Up until this winter, I don&#8217;t think I ever would have considered fur, and now I have this black coat and a  vest! Of course, they&#8217;re both  faux fur, but they actually retain a lot of heat to keep me warm. Best of all, this one was on sale at Banana Republic! However, this has led to the slight problem of buying things with the excuse that it&#8217;s &#8220;for the blog!&#8221;. My fellow blogger and friend Gigi has a great nail polish blog and boasts a giant (growing) collection of polishes which she reviews.<a href="http://thelacquerlog.wordpress.com/">Click here to see her blog.</a></p>
<p><a href="http://amuseume.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/img_9322.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-230" title="IMG_9322" src="http://amuseume.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/img_9322.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=682" alt="" width="1024" height="682" /></a><a href="http://amuseume.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/img_9331.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-231" title="IMG_9331" src="http://amuseume.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/img_9331.jpg?w=682&#038;h=1024" alt="" width="682" height="1024" /></a>I wish you could see it better in these photos, but this full-length skirt is lace and the shirt has a bit more texture and sheen. I tied the shirt to make it tighter for better contrast against the flow of the skirt. With such a dark outfit, I added a very red based fuscia lip to create some dimension to the whole ensemble. Again, I love that my purse is a very dark green, and not black as it gives the purse more intrigue.</p>
<p>Its my second week back at school, and you can totally throw spit balls and paper wads at me, but I kind of love school. Aside from all the stress it provides, I love that feeling of truly gaining knowledge that is relevant and important to me. Hope you&#8217;re all doing well post-holidays!</p>
<p><a href="http://amuseume.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/img_9340.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-232" title="IMG_9340" src="http://amuseume.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/img_9340.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=682" alt="" width="1024" height="682" /></a>Fur coat from <strong>Banana Republic</strong>, shirt from <strong>H&amp;M</strong>, lace skirt from <strong>Forever 21</strong>, purse from <strong>Rebecca Minkoff</strong>, bangles from <strong>Plenty</strong>.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/225/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/225/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/225/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/225/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/225/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/225/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/225/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/225/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/225/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/225/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/225/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/225/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/225/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/225/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=225&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://amuseume.wordpress.com/2012/01/11/darkness-divulged/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/3ccbe21875911ddba7520a3b1f7cfa68?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lalalalainat</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://amuseume.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/img_9285.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_9285</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://amuseume.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/img_9302.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_9302</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://amuseume.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/img_9299.jpg?w=682" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_9299</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://amuseume.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/img_9322.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_9322</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://amuseume.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/img_9331.jpg?w=682" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_9331</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://amuseume.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/img_9340.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_9340</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>