<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2012 22:29:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>What is it about being put &#8220;on hold&#8221; that drives me crazy?</title>
		<link>http://ohmsweetohmdotme.wordpress.com/2012/08/04/what-is-it-about-being-put-on-hold-that-drives-me-crazy/</link>
		<comments>http://ohmsweetohmdotme.wordpress.com/2012/08/04/what-is-it-about-being-put-on-hold-that-drives-me-crazy/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2012 21:54:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Allan G. Smorra</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Something Completely Different]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[#DPchallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[postaday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sweet Mother]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ohmsweetohmdotme.wordpress.com/?p=2173</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The other day I made a phone call to a large corporation and my call was immediately transferred to the Pre-recorded Pacification of Permanent Hold: &#8220;All of our representatives are currently busy helping other callers. Please remain on the line and your call will be answered in the order that it was received. All of our [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2173&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://ohmsweetohmdotme.wordpress.com/2012/08/04/what-is-it-about-being-put-on-hold-that-drives-me-crazy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/db8eb93fea0528dbadeb7edad15f4552?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">chaos48</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What&#8217;s going on in Aleppo?</title>
		<link>http://possibilitiesandperspectives.wordpress.com/2012/08/08/whats-going-on-in-aleppo/</link>
		<comments>http://possibilitiesandperspectives.wordpress.com/2012/08/08/whats-going-on-in-aleppo/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2012 18:58:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>garrett.dee</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aleppo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Assad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[International Relations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Iran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Syria]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://possibilitiesandperspectives.wordpress.com/?p=95</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Yesterday, fighting began in Aleppo, one of Syria&#8217;s largest cities, between the rebel forces known as the Free Syria Army and the government-sponsored military in what Syrian President Bashir al-Assad called the decisive battle of the months-long civil war. This morning, reports are coming in from the New York Times that rebels are currently fleeing [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=95&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday, fighting began in Aleppo, one of Syria&#8217;s largest cities, between the rebel forces known as the Free Syria Army and the government-sponsored military in what Syrian President Bashir al-Assad called the decisive battle of the months-long civil war. This morning, reports are coming in from the New York Times that rebels are currently fleeing the city, having run out of ammunition and facing an overwhelming ground assault by government forces.</p>
<p>The outcome of the battle of Aleppo shows just how far the situation in Syria has deteriorated and how complicated the dynamics of the struggle are. Despite several high-profile defections from the Syrian government, including the resignation of prime minister Riyad Farid Hijab on Monday and his subsequent flight into Jordan, it is now obvious that the Assad regime is able to hold out against the rebels and is even beginning to show signs of a resurgence against the poorly armed forces. Text messages were sent out early Wednesday by the government to those Syrians that had not already fled the country urging them to denounce the rebels in order to &#8220;save yourself and your family&#8221;.</p>
<p>The conflict seems to straddle ethnic and sectarian lines in Syria, a common factor in many of the uprisings we have currently been seeing in the Middle East, a region where even slight ethnic and religious divisions matter in a way that most Western societies are not typically familiar with. Mr. Assad&#8217;s inner circle, like that of the government which his father headed before him, is made up mostly of members of the Alawite sect of the Shi&#8217;a branch of Islam. The majority of the population of Syria, however, belongs to the Sunni branch of Islam, a division which the rebels have claimed causes corruption in the Assad government and persecution of a large part of the Syrian nation. Assad&#8217;s elite cadre of Alawite followers have been accused of abusing their power and the power of the military at the expense of the interests of the people of Syria, sparking the violent rebellions that have been taking place for nearly a year at this point.</p>
<p>Syria&#8217;s civil war is complicated even further by the added international involvement in the conflict and what it represents to the interests of the various nations involved. On the one hand, you have Russia, Syria&#8217;s most prominent international sponsor, with naval bases in the country showing support for the continuity of the Assad regime. Regionally, the regime also has the support of Iran, another Shi&#8217;ite-governed nation, who has in recent years been in notable and accelerating conflict with Western powers over its nuclear enrichment programs. The United States, most of the European Union, and Turkey (the most significant liberal democracy in the region) have all voiced their support for the rebel forces in Syria and have denounced the Assad regime as despotic and inhumane. In recent months, US Secretary of State Hillary Clinton has begun urging the nations allied with the reble forces (known as the Friends of Syria) to begin planning for a post-Assad Syria and a recalculation of the nations place in the Middle East.</p>
<p>Perhaps, however, such talk is premature, given the intensity with which the struggle seems to be occurring and the absence of any sign of decline. The government&#8217;s victory in Aleppo, though certainly not a decisive one, is symbolic enough to give further credence to those in support of the Assad regime and will discourage the rebels (many of whom are young and relatively inexperienced in combat) from further aggression. Former UN Secretary-General and special peace envoy to Syria Kofi Annan&#8217;s resignation and withdrawal from the diplomatic process is a concrete sign of how little progress is being made in ending the conflict. To this end, if liberal pro-democratic nations want to see the Assad regime toppled, it is imperative that they begin actively supporting the rebel forces in Syria much like those in Libya nearly two years ago. France, who holds to rotating chair to the United Nations Security Council, has already called a special meeting of the Council later this month with the express purpose of deciding a course of action in the ongoing conflict. The United States, who has a serious stake in this conflict given its very sensitive relations with Iran, must make a very clear show of support to the Free Syria Army if it wishes to influence the outcome of the civil war in a way favorable to its own needs.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/95/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/95/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=95&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://possibilitiesandperspectives.wordpress.com/2012/08/08/whats-going-on-in-aleppo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/4d5decebf422f49ad90819d8446f2594?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">grrtt9113</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What a perfect haystack means</title>
		<link>http://minnesotatransplant.wordpress.com/2012/08/09/what-a-perfect-haystack-means/</link>
		<comments>http://minnesotatransplant.wordpress.com/2012/08/09/what-a-perfect-haystack-means/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2012 18:19:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>minnesotatransplant</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[#DPchallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Farming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[memories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[North Dakota]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weekly Writing Challenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://minnesotatransplant.wordpress.com/?p=4613</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Symbols remind us of what’s important. A wedding ring symbolizes a commitment. A lushly green, well-watered lawn symbolizes suburban perfection. A signed baseball symbolizes a brush with fame. For my uncle, a perfect haystack symbolizes a summer’s work. I recently found a black-and-white picture of the haystack in my uncle’s collection of personal photos. “You’ve [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4613&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Symbols remind us of what’s important. A wedding ring symbolizes a commitment. A lushly green, well-watered lawn symbolizes suburban perfection. A signed baseball symbolizes a brush with fame.</p>
<p>For my uncle, a perfect haystack symbolizes a summer’s work.</p>
<div id="attachment_4614" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://minnesotatransplant.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/stacked-hay-final.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-4614" title="stacked hay final" src="http://minnesotatransplant.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/stacked-hay-final.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="303" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">A meaningful stack of North Dakota hay, circa 1965.</p></div>
<p>I recently found a black-and-white picture of the haystack in my uncle’s collection of personal photos.</p>
<p>“You’ve had this photo for 40-some years,” I said. “There must be a reason you kept it so long.”</p>
<p>“That hay stack represented a finished job,” Uncle Lee said. “I don’t get many ‘finished jobs’ in my line of work now.”</p>
<p>Nowadays, making hay is highly mechanized. Round bales, created by a machine, dot the rural landscape around the little town where I live on the outskirts of Chicago.</p>
<p>But a century ago, hay was cut with scythes and moved with pitchforks, and haystacks shaped like little houses were fixtures of the Midwestern landscape. Square balers mechanized the process in the 1940s. As the farming industry moved to a more corporate operation in recent years, large round bales have become more common.</p>
<p>The biggest advantage of small square bales like those handled by my uncle is that they can be moved by one person without a lot of machinery.</p>
<p>Square hay bales must be stacked in such a way as to shed moisture and prevent rotting. My uncle estimates his haystack probably had 2,000 square bales in it.</p>
<p>“I probably handled those bales six times each,” he said. “That’s why I was in such great shape! The knees wore out of my blue jeans from hiking up those bales. I could throw them like you couldn’t believe.”</p>
<p>As the saying goes, you make hay while the sun shines. One has to cut it, rake it and bale it first. “Dad [my grandfather] had a brand new baler at the time,” Uncle Lee remembers. “Then I’d go out and put ’em in six packs &#8212; that’s the first time I handled ’em. Then I’d pick ’em up and throw ’em on the hay wagon (that’s two), then stack ’em again on the wagon (three), bring ’em home, throw ’em down (there’s four, right?), then stack them like you see here in the picture.”</p>
<p>The stack in that picture symbolized a whole summer of work.</p>
<p>“Wait, that’s five times, I think,” I said.</p>
<p>“Then in the winter time, you have to feed the cattle – I had to throw the bales on the ground for the cows.”</p>
<p>Six.</p>
<p>“I like everything about cattle,” said Uncle Lee, who grew up and made hay in the western plains of North Dakota. “I enjoyed that part of farming. I didn’t like seeding or combining, but one of my favorite times of year was when we moved the cattle to summer pasture. All winter, they were cooped up in the barnyards, but in spring we moved them to the open fields. They were like little kids! They’d kick up their heels and hit their heads together, they were so happy.</p>
<p>“I still like cattle.”</p>
<p>Early on, Uncle Lee left farming because there was no money in it and embarked on a career in education. He started out as a social studies teacher. Now, he’s a school administrator – the top of the stack, so to speak – in a small, rural school district in Wisconsin.</p>
<div id="attachment_4615" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://minnesotatransplant.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/lee-with-haystack.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-4615" title="Lee with haystack" src="http://minnesotatransplant.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/lee-with-haystack.jpg?w=300&h=190" alt="" width="300" height="190" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Lee in 1965.</p></div>
<p>“That’s probably why I prefer rural districts,” Uncle Lee said. “North Dakota built my foundation. It was a hard place to make a living: It’s got a short growing season. It’s colder than hell. Sometimes it doesn’t rain. It can be a very lonely, lonely place.”</p>
<p>But he learned what hard work can accomplish.</p>
<p>And the picture of his haystack symbolizes it.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4613/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4613/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4613&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://minnesotatransplant.wordpress.com/2012/08/09/what-a-perfect-haystack-means/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/8a36eed58dd3b0709b19414fb977355e?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">minnesotatransplant</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://minnesotatransplant.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/stacked-hay-final.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">stacked hay final</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://minnesotatransplant.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/lee-with-haystack.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Lee with haystack</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>epic adventure</title>
		<link>http://fetchhappy.com/2012/08/07/epic-adventure/</link>
		<comments>http://fetchhappy.com/2012/08/07/epic-adventure/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2012 01:05:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>fetchhappy</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advertising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corolla]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[north carolina]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outer banks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Patches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wild horses]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fetchhappy.com/?p=787</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[When I was a kid my Granddad took me on a little aluminium boat to an overgrown island where we tracked the wild horses of Currituck, North Carolina. It was incredible. We got to see a foal just yards away, and I was totally amazed. They seemed so majestic out there with no fences, totally [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=787&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When I was a kid my Granddad took me on a little aluminium boat to an overgrown island where we tracked the wild horses of Currituck, North Carolina. It was incredible. We got to see a foal just yards away, and I was totally amazed. They seemed so majestic out there with no fences, totally free. I never forgot that experience. </p>
<p>So when I got the opportunity to work as the writer on an advertising campaign for North Carolina tourism, that memory kept inching its way back up. It was something personal that became work. Memories that morphed into words. I think often the best, most authentic work is personal. </p>
<p>I was around horses before I can even remember. As a little girl I had my own pony, Patches, who gave me some of the happiest and most heartbreaking moments of my life. </p>
<p><a href="http://fetchhappy.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/patchesandme.jpeg"><img src="http://fetchhappy.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/patchesandme.jpeg" alt="" title="PatchesAndMe" width="600" height="419" class="alignright size-full wp-image-800" /></a></p>
<p>There&#8217;s just something about a horse. All you have to do stand near them, and you can feel the power and emotion. Two souls become one.</p>
<p><a href="http://fetchhappy.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc06577.jpg"><img src="http://fetchhappy.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc06577.jpg" alt="" title="DSC06577" width="600" height="450" class="alignright size-full wp-image-814" /></a></p>
<p>Telling the story of North Carolina&#8217;s wild horses was important for me because it&#8217;s one of the most unique and memorable adventures found here. I just had to share it. So as it turns out, we got the opportunity. And I got to follow along with a world renowned photographer and the herd manager as we tracked the wild horses of Corolla. Wow. Lucky me. Now two incredible, unforgettable experiences. I saw many horses this time. Some were more hidden in the fields while others walked alongside tourists on the beach. Though flowing freely, their sun-kissed mane almost looked styled. With confidence founded in freedom, they seemed unshakable and often looked right at me. Right into me. </p>
<p><a href="http://fetchhappy.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc06598.jpg"><img src="http://fetchhappy.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc06598.jpg" alt="" title="DSC06598" width="600" height="450" class="alignright size-full wp-image-803" /></a></p>
<p>I even had my own <em>once in a liftime</em> moment when a stallion climbed down from the top of a sand dune to whisper something in my ear. While I tried to respect the 50 foot distance rule, apparently he hadn&#8217;t read the brochure. And what he had to say was pretty important. But that&#8217;s all I can say.</p>
<p><a href="http://fetchhappy.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc06176.jpg"><img src="http://fetchhappy.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc06176.jpg" alt="" title="wildstallion" width="600" height="450" class="alignright size-full wp-image-804" /></a></p>
<p>Like most animals I&#8217;ve ever known, their eyes were deep and soulful. Pulling you in with every glance and head toss. The massive and rolling sand dunes felt like I was on another planet while the ocean grounded me. </p>
<p><a href="http://fetchhappy.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc06025.jpg"><img src="http://fetchhappy.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc06025.jpg" alt="" title="DSC06025" width="600" height="450" class="alignright size-full wp-image-840" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://fetchhappy.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc06389.jpg"><img src="http://fetchhappy.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc06389.jpg" alt="" title="DSC06389" width="600" height="450" class="alignright size-full wp-image-808" /></a></p>
<p>Everywhere I looked, there was gold. Golden light that cast a halo behind their fuzzy coat. Golden oats in the fields. Golden sand beneath my feet. It was magical. They were free, but I was captured. So of course I took lots of photos and put them together in the short video below. </p>
<p><div class='embed-vimeo' style='text-align:center;'><iframe src='http://player.vimeo.com/video/47087089' width='500' height='281' frameborder='0'></iframe></div>
<p><a href="http://vimeo.com/47087089">Wild Horses of NC</a> from <a href="http://vimeo.com/margaretbond">Margaret Bond</a> on <a href="http://vimeo.com">Vimeo</a>.</p>
<p>Many of these photos I took looking over the shoulder of one of the best (and nicest) photographers in the world while several others were only seen by me. And now &#8211; you. </p>
<p><a href="http://fetchhappy.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc06248.jpg"><img src="http://fetchhappy.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc06248.jpg" alt="" title="DSC06248" width="600" height="450" class="alignright size-full wp-image-817" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/787/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/787/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=787&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://fetchhappy.com/2012/08/07/epic-adventure/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>29</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/5be7dc33d33f14e4554091a3fa8b2c19?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">fetchhappy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://fetchhappy.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/patchesandme.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">PatchesAndMe</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://fetchhappy.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc06577.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC06577</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://fetchhappy.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc06598.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC06598</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://fetchhappy.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc06176.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">wildstallion</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://fetchhappy.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc06025.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC06025</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://fetchhappy.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc06389.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC06389</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://fetchhappy.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc06248.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC06248</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Achromat</title>
		<link>http://gentlewit.com/2012/08/06/achromat/</link>
		<comments>http://gentlewit.com/2012/08/06/achromat/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2012 17:58:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Cyndy Otty</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Noteworthy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[achromatopsia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blindness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPchallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[postaday]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://gentlewit.com/?p=6227</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;You know, we sometimes forget you&#8217;re blind,&#8221; my grandmother matter-of-factly stated in response to a situation that inevitably happens between me and every sighted person I spend any amount of time with. The exact event varies, but always involves me not seeing something that is right in front of me. In this particular instance she [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=6227&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;You know, we sometimes forget you&#8217;re blind,&#8221; my grandmother matter-of-factly stated in response to a situation that inevitably happens between me and every sighted person I spend any amount of time with. The exact event varies, but always involves me not seeing something that is right in front of me. In this particular instance she had left me a cup of coffee on the counter, which I only discovered after nearly knocking it into the sink when I set a second cup by it to reach for the sugar bowl. I must have looked a bit dumbfounded because she continued: &#8220;You get around so well most of the time we just don&#8217;t think about it.&#8221;</p>
<p>I remember it gave us both a good laugh, but for a good part of my life that rather mundane exchange with my grandmother would have bothered me because it seemed like I constantly had to defend my own inability to see.<sup>1</sup> This was especially difficult when I was younger because I&#8217;ve always seen <a href="/2010/07/10/seeing-blind/">the way that I do</a> and so I had nothing to compare it to. I knew I was colorblind, but it held as much meaning to me as being legally blind. I once heard my father tell someone that my vision was like watching &#8220;an old black-and-white television.&#8221; It was the first time that people seemed appeased by a description of my blindness and so for the longest time it was the explanation I used. Until I actually watched an old black-and-white television and realized this description was wholly inaccurate. I could tell the difference between what I was seeing and how things appeared on the television screen where the world was portrayed as monotone and I found it hard to distinguish things like clothing and furniture from the background. Whereas in reality things were vibrant and full of contrast. Sometime after I had a discussion with my father about this and, at least for me, it was the moment of realization that there was possibly no way sighted people would truly understand how I saw things.</p>
<p>I was born with the retinal condition achromatopsia. You probably have never heard of it outside of the few mentions on this blog because it is incredibly rare, <a href="http://www.achromat.org/what_is_achromatopsia.html">affecting roughly 1 in 33,000 people</a>.<sup>2</sup> Nowadays there are <a href="http://www.achromatopsia.info/diagnosis-testing/">genetic tests that can aid in diagnosing achromatopsia</a>, but when I was younger the tests were far more complicated. There were signs, of course. As an infant the main one was that I had nystagmus, which is an involuntary movement of the eye and is a common sign of vision loss in children. However, it can occur all on its own and it can even improve with age. My parents were predictably freaked out about it, but their fears were basically brushed aside by doctors. I can&#8217;t really fault them on this because these were the same doctors that told my parents my allergy to cow&#8217;s milk was a heat rash and so mostly I&#8217;m glad my parents didn&#8217;t succeed in freezing me to death before that was cleared up.<sup>3</sup></p>
<p>Anyway, the years passed and as my father put rather succinctly, &#8220;We just thought you were clumsy.&#8221; He explained that I could &#8220;obviously see <em>stuff</em>&#8221; but then I seemed to deliberately walk into the coffee table on almost a daily basis. In his defense, he did cart me around to pretty much every doctor on the planet, though, to this day I&#8217;m still not sure if it was my increasingly quirky behavior that spurred him on or his lack of faith in military doctors after the heat rash debacle.</p>
<p><img class="alignleft" title="Ishihara color test" src="http://farm5.staticflickr.com/4039/4602068121_2d010e5bf9.jpg" alt="The first six 'ishihara plates' which are circles formed by alternating colored dots" width="362" height="500" /> It was through this that I became familiar with colorblindness tests like the example of the Ishihara Color Test to the left. I can only assume that lack of understanding about achromatopsia contributed to how often these color perception tests were administered. Otherwise, someone probably would have bothered to explain to me that as I possess absolutely no ability to perceive color it was <em>literally</em> impossible for me to see anything beyond that first plate&#8217;s number 12.<sup>4</sup> Instead I perused these circles with a same devotion many give to <a href="http://magiceye.com">Magic Eye images</a>.<sup>5</sup> I forget exactly how I came to understand that I was completely colorblind, but I can assure you that it had nothing to do with these tests.</p>
<p>The other main feature of achromatopsia is that it causes severe light sensitivity. The type of achromatopsia I have is classified as &#8220;complete rod monochromacy&#8221; and means that the only functioning part of my retina are the rods. Whereas cones function best in bright light, rods saturate at higher light levels. It&#8217;s basically the concept of being dazzled by high-beams, except that in my case I don&#8217;t have cones to pick up on the visual slack and so instead I&#8217;m<em> completely blinded by light</em>. You know how most people loathe going to the dentist? Well that&#8217;s basically how I feel about the eye doctor. Part of this is because having my eyes dilated is basically like taking the entire sun and shoving it straight into my eyeball and it seems to take about twice the normal amount of time for the solution&#8217;s effects to wear off. But mostly it&#8217;s because I have very distinct memories of being subjected to electroretinogram tests. ERGs test the eye&#8217;s reaction to natural stimuli, which sounds innocuous when you put it like that. In practice it was more traumatizing and involved sticking me in a dark box and having lights shined straight into my eye for an hour. Really puts that teeth cleaning into perspective now, doesn&#8217;t it?</p>
<p>My childhood nightmares aside<sup>6</sup> there is one last defining characteristic of achromatopsia: it is incredibly stable. In fact it is so stable that aside from a change to bifocals at about ten, I&#8217;m wearing nearly the exact same prescription in my eyeglasses right this moment as I did in the first pair I was given at four. My eye doctor finds this one of the most fascinating things about achromatopsia. Second only to the fact that the retina of an achromat does not appear any different than that of a fully-functioning one. He and I have very different feelings on what is fascinating, but then I wasn&#8217;t the one who went to college so I could look in people&#8217;s eyes all day.</p>
<p>What&#8217;s more, <a href="/2009/12/01/blind-reading/">as I&#8217;ve detailed before</a>, if I&#8217;m in an optimal light situation I can read regular print without the aid of a magnifier. Much like the coffee table, this has caused no small amount of confusion for people throughout my life. It&#8217;s difficult to understand unless you fully grasp the anatomy of the eye. In the simplest terms, it&#8217;s basically cones that handle distance vision and give clarity and crispness to your sight. Without them, there isn&#8217;t so much an absence of these but a substantial drop in both. Meaning that things I can see are in sharp detail, but they need to be relatively &#8212; sometimes <em>extremely</em> &#8212; close. A person with 20/20 vision looking out at the horizon on a clear day can see for quite a ways, but at some point things start to grow indistinct and they can&#8217;t <em>quite</em> make them out. In my case, that line where things grow indistinct is very dependent on the amount of light, but sometimes it&#8217;s hardly six inches away. Which is why trying to explain what I can see in terms of visual acuity is like describing a cell phone to Alexander Graham Bell. It&#8217;s sort of gets the point across, but it&#8217;s not really the same thing at all.</p>
<p><a href="/2012/07/26/help-emma/">Recent events</a> have sparked a lot of chatter about the different viewpoints between people who are born blind and those who lose their sight later in life. It&#8217;s a topic I&#8217;ve given a lot of thought to over the years and actually wrote a paper on for a Psychology class in college. In a lot of ways the two are almost different disabilities because of the different psychological effects they present.<sup>7</sup> Where this comes into the sharpest relief for me is in understanding color perception. Being able to <em>perceive</em> color is an ability, but actually identifying colors is something that is taught to you. Our understanding of this has grown lately due to scientific studies that prove animals such as dogs, cats and birds can perceive color and can be taught to appreciate them. Learning colors is one of the very first things we teach our children and because of that knowledge a person with color perception would consider my vision an absence of color, but it&#8217;s really not. Unfortunately, there&#8217;s no way to really bridge this gap because you can&#8217;t really <em>un</em>learn colors and my understanding of vision would change drastically were I suddenly able to perceive them. When I think about it I can understand how frustrated people in my life must have been in trying to understand my vision. Me? I find the whole thing thoroughly fascinating.</p>
<hr />
<p><span style="font-size:.75em;">1. Though it&#8217;s more accurate to say that my elementary through high school years were spent feeling disgusted and ashamed of being blind. But that&#8217;s a whole other post.<br />
2. It should be noted that statistics on achromatopsia have not been updated since the 1960s, but using <a href="http://quickfacts.census.gov/qfd/states/00000.html">the United States July 2011 census results</a> that works out to less than 9,500 people in a country of an estimated 21.5 million people with &#8220;<a href="http://www.afb.org/section.aspx?SectionID=15">trouble seeing</a>.&#8221; I&#8217;ve been seeing the same eye doctor, <a href="http://consumeroptical.com">a low vision specialist</a>, since I was four and he&#8217;s only ever had one other achromatopsia patient. And aside from people I&#8217;ve met via the Internet and through a support group (that was more accurately a list of pen pals), I&#8217;ve met one other achromat in my life and it was at <a href="/2009/08/13/lions-world-services-for-the-blind/">a school for the blind</a>.<br />
3. I&#8217;m really not kidding about the freezing me to death thing because they had me naked in my crib with fans blowing on me and the thermostat set to 55°. I ended up being properly diagnosed on the fly by a pediatrician on a bus who took one glance at me in my mother&#8217;s arms and bluntly told my parents: &#8220;That baby&#8217;s allergic to milk.&#8221;<br />
4. The first plate is a control plate that <em>everyone</em> should see regardless of the level/type of color blindness. I can kind of see the 15 in the sixth plate, but only because I know that it&#8217;s supposed to be a 15. The other plates are 8, 29, 5, and 3. If you have red-green color blindness you&#8217;ll see different numbers for those five plates.<br />
5. No, I can&#8217;t see those either.<br />
6. ERGs and colorblindness tests featured heavily in a recurring nightmare I had as a child. Honestly, I try not to think about it.<br />
7. It&#8217;s worth noting that there is something of a controversy over this. Essentially it boils down to the two being different because one is a &#8220;worse&#8221; type of blindness. Yeah, I don&#8217;t understand it either.</span></p>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=6227&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://gentlewit.com/2012/08/06/achromat/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/378e4cbcfa201c8ff0b8398b9da9d1b3?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ceo</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm5.staticflickr.com/4039/4602068121_2d010e5bf9.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ishihara color test</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>If I was single&#8230;</title>
		<link>http://malibumom.com/2012/08/08/if-i-was-single/</link>
		<comments>http://malibumom.com/2012/08/08/if-i-was-single/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2012 19:41:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>susannabrisk</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bedtimes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fantasies]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://malibumom.com/?p=163</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Last night I had a particularly hideous bedtime with the kids, in which I lost my temper and screamed one sentence that likely permanently scratched my vocal chords and everyone cried and once they were asleep, I was incapable of any more rational thought, so my mind started to wander… When I was younger and [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=163&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last night I had a particularly hideous bedtime with the kids, in which I lost my temper and screamed one sentence that likely permanently scratched my vocal chords and everyone cried and once they were asleep, I was incapable of any more rational thought, so my mind started to wander…</p>
<p>When I was younger and more obviously &#8220;hot&#8221; as opposed to somewhat hot on a good day when I have concealer on and the lighting is right and I&#8217;m not scowling which always make me look jowly, men would often say the following to me:</p>
<p>&#8220;Man, if I was single&#8230;&#8221; the implication being that if there wasn&#8217;t some pesky wife or girlfriend to get in the way, he would gladly hump me for a while, before moving on to someone else he could cheat on me with. <span id="more-163"></span>While <em>flattering</em>, I always thought the expression &#8220;If I were single&#8221; to be unbelievably insulting to the wife/girlfriend/husband/boyfriend/roommate-you-occasionally-copulate-with-when-too-drunk-to-say-no-who-thinks-you&#8217;re-in-a-relationship. I always felt that I couldn&#8217;t imagine my life without my husband and children and didn&#8217;t care to and what a cad you are, sir.</p>
<p>However now that I am <a title="I have finally separated from my husband" href="http://malibumom.com/2012/08/06/i-have-finally-separated-from-my-husband-3/">&#8220;separated&#8221; (hint: read to the end of that blog!)</a> and while I actively choose to be monogamously married, I can actually imagine a life in which I am self-sufficient enough to survive without my husband. This is a revelation for me as I always thought that if left alone, I would begin &#8220;Melting melting&#8230;&#8221; like the Wicked Witch of the West. (By the way, Glenda the Good Witch says that only Bad Witches are ugly, but Good Witches are beautiful. Tell that to Mother Theresa who managed to achieve a fair amount without a great skin regimen. Haven’t seen Giselle Bundchen do an awful lot for society lately, but I digress…)</p>
<p>I have gotten to the bottom of myself, and it turns out you cannot die of loneliness, or embarrassment or even frustration, although these feelings can certainly make you throw things, eat compulsively and watch endless re-runs of Law and Order SVU.</p>
<p>However I have known more than a few people who have slashed their wrists because they were so codependent (my what an uplifting post this is turning out to be&#8230;) and even though they slashed them vertically so maybe they didn’t intend to really cark it, I would probably prefer the L &amp; O option.</p>
<p>So even though I am firmly grounded in shit-sucking reality, I am entitled to some fantasies to get me through the dark night of the kids’ bedtimes. The fantasies occur in an imaginary parallel universe where I am rich, childless and single, and everyone else on earth is rich, childless and single, and everyone I desire desires me, so no one gets hurt and also my husband was never born hence I never met him so I have never been really and truly in love and never had children (I am SO thin) and life is still one long fun party. So put down those dishes/files/nunchucks and come live vicariously through my imaginary world&#8230;</p>
<p>1.This man&#8230; Who shall remain nameless.</p>
<p><a href="http://susannabrisk.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/charliehunnan_shirtless1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-165" title="charliehunnan_shirtless1" src="http://susannabrisk.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/charliehunnan_shirtless1.jpg" alt="" width="584" height="761" /></a>I will do things to him and he will do things to me and I hate that I am alive and he is alive and we have never met (I smell a restraining order…)</p>
<p>2. Lest you think I’m monogamous in this fantasy, there is also this man, who will bounce on top of me, likely requiring extensive chiropractic&#8230; but it will be WORTH IT.</p>
<p><a href="http://susannabrisk.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/cavallari_cutler.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-166" title="jay cutler" src="http://susannabrisk.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/cavallari_cutler.jpg" alt="" width="236" height="322" /></a>They’re very different aren’t they? Unless they are both drug addicts/alcoholics – in which case I’m right on type.</p>
<p>3. Italy. Just, Italy. I will live there. There will be cheese. Gelato. Sometimes a museum. Numbers 1. and 2. will live in separate rooms in my Tuscan Villa breathlessly awaiting my arrival. They will have no life in their respective rooms, each will not even know the other exists, just read books while I’m gone so they are ready to amuse me with endless quips/pleasure me when I return. They will intuitively know when I want to be roughly manhandled and gently held while I cry.</p>
<p>4. Over there in Italy I will have a bi-lingual nursemaid/caretaker/confidante such as the “Nurse” character in Romeo and Juliet. Older, pleasantly round and endlessly patient, she will wake me in the morning with a Lavazza Latte, warm croissant and a foot rub. She will pick up my dirty underwear and constantly ask me how I’m doing and whether I need anything. I will let her fuck 1. or 2., but only on her one night off a year.</p>
<p>5. The Nurse starts fucking Jay Cutler and Charlie Hunnam and spills the secret of the other’s existence (in two languages.) They hatch a plan, and one night she slips Ambien into my Hot Chocolato amazing night time whipped cream drink. While I sleep innocently, they make a ladder out of the 3000 thread count Pratesi sheets, and escape the villa, into the Tuscan night.</p>
<p>Fuck my life.</p>
<p>What’s your favorite fantasy?</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/163/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/163/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=163&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://malibumom.com/2012/08/08/if-i-was-single/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>18</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a62b4c7bc393a49518296af4279fe214?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">susannabrisk</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://susannabrisk.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/charliehunnan_shirtless1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">charliehunnan_shirtless1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://susannabrisk.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/cavallari_cutler.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jay cutler</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Everything Is Not The Same {or, Weekly Writing Challenge: From Mundane To Meaningful}</title>
		<link>http://writingthegirl.wordpress.com/2012/08/08/everything-is-not-the-same-or-weekly-writing-challenge-from-mundane-to-meaningful/</link>
		<comments>http://writingthegirl.wordpress.com/2012/08/08/everything-is-not-the-same-or-weekly-writing-challenge-from-mundane-to-meaningful/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2012 01:18:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Janice D</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[365 post challemge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[black and white photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creative writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dpChallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mundane to meaningful]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Online Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[postaday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the daily post]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weekly writing challenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[word press]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://writingthegirl.wordpress.com/?p=3329</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Sleep gives way to morning. This is not new. I try, as much as I can, to hold on to Sleep &#8211; but no.  Sleep is slipping away from me.  Even with my eyes still closed, I can feel daylight making its grand entrance.  If the day is beginning, my ability to stay under the [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3329&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sleep gives way to morning.</p>
<p>This is not new.</p>
<p>I try, as much as I can, to hold on to Sleep &#8211; but no.  Sleep is slipping away from me.  Even with my eyes still closed, I can feel daylight making its grand entrance.  If the day is beginning, my ability to stay under the covers dissipates rapidly.</p>
<p>I open my eyes, as I do every day , and sigh.  As I do, everyday &#8211; especially on Monday&#8230;the dreaded start to the week.  Same old story, right after every Sunday&#8230;</p>
<p>Monday.</p>
<p>Always.</p>
<p>Except, this one is different.</p>
<p>I swing my legs over the side of the bed and force myself up into the position known as &#8220;sitting&#8221;, feet making contact with the floor.  I stand on still sleepy legs and stretch, numbly leaving my bedroom.</p>
<p>Same as I always do when I wake up&#8230;.</p>
<p>But this morning my path is different.</p>
<p>The kitchen is not where it was the previous day. The coffee maker has also changed locations.  Luckily, I manage to find both.</p>
<p>When I finally make it out to the patio, caffeine, laptop and notebook in hand, I pause and survey my environment.</p>
<p>Again, I sigh.</p>
<p>All I want is something that has not changed.  My chair &#8211; at the head of the table.  It has not changed! &#8211; And there it is &#8211; waiting for me with open arms.  A soft place to land.  Such an odd feeling &#8211; doing the same sequence of events as they are done every morning&#8230;but in a completely different place.</p>
<p><a href="http://writingthegirl.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_8010.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-3345 alignright" title="chair," src="http://writingthegirl.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_8010.jpg?w=614&h=409" alt="" width="614" height="409" /></a></p>
<p>This is my first morning in my new house, having just moved in the day before.  Everything I do is the same, but the setting is not.  The stage I am doing it on is completely different.</p>
<p>Routine can be fickle?  Routine can be warped?  Yes, it can.</p>
<p>I take my usual position at the table.  Coffee within comfortable reach of my left hand.  The screen on my laptop casting a soft glow, news feed telling me what I have missed in the rest of the world.</p>
<p><em>But wait.</em></p>
<p>The sun is coming up behind me now.  Before, in that place I used to call home, it rose in front of me.</p>
<p><a href="http://writingthegirl.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_8008.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-3335" title="Morning Routine" src="http://writingthegirl.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_8008.jpg?w=1024&h=682" alt="" width="1024" height="682" /></a></p>
<p>The garden to my left is no longer dominated by Hostas and Beebalm.  Now it is full of Brown-Eyed Susans and Roses.</p>
<p>The pond has been replaced by a long row of Day Lilies, planted en masse, in a narrow sea of orange, yellow and white.  They, like me, are slowly, tentatively, greeting the day.</p>
<p>It is all foreign&#8230;every single detail within view.</p>
<p>Nothing will be exactly as I knew it for so many years before this morning.</p>
<p>Nothing.</p>
<p>Now I have work to do&#8230; with all of this new-ness.  I will carry on.  I will adjust.  I wonder about the mornings yet to come.  The years I will spend in this place.  The events that will shape my life.  The memories that will be created.  The words I will write while sitting on this patio.  The changes that will happen to me and to my family for as long as we call this place &#8220;home&#8221;.</p>
<p>With these thoughts, I am suddenly filled with optimism.</p>
<p>This day is not just a day. This morning is not just a routine.  This is a new chapter just getting started in a whole new book.</p>
<p>I understand that this current drama of feeling unfamiliar will cease to be.  That which is new right now, will soon become merely another fold in the fabric of what is widely known as day-to-day.</p>
<p>This day is the first day &#8211; and none that follow will hold such a title.</p>
<p><a href="http://writingthegirl.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_8007.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-3348" title="birdhouse" src="http://writingthegirl.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_8007.jpg?w=1024&h=682" alt="" width="1024" height="682" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><em><em>(Truly &#8220;Writing&#8221; The Girl today!  <a href="http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2012/08/06/writing-challenge-1/comment-page-1/#comment-66279" target="_blank">This is the first of a new weekly writing challenge hosted by the awesome folks at the Daily Post! </a> Maybe a bit more &#8220;wordy&#8221; than my recent posts&#8230;but wow &#8211; ! Awesome writing fun!!!)  </em> </em></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3329/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3329/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3329&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://writingthegirl.wordpress.com/2012/08/08/everything-is-not-the-same-or-weekly-writing-challenge-from-mundane-to-meaningful/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/646a516b7e11aae95a16e2a5c53ca53c?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">janicemd</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://writingthegirl.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_8010.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">chair,</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://writingthegirl.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_8008.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Morning Routine</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://writingthegirl.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_8007.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">birdhouse</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Louisville&#8230; ten stops in the Possibility City.</title>
		<link>http://becauseijustdo.wordpress.com/2012/08/08/louisville-ten-stops-in-the-possibility-city/</link>
		<comments>http://becauseijustdo.wordpress.com/2012/08/08/louisville-ten-stops-in-the-possibility-city/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2012 19:48:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>becauseijustdo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Places]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kids]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Louisville]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[summertime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://becauseijustdo.wordpress.com/?p=198</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[We made it home safely to SoCal yesterday.  In an effort to capture all the exciting places we visited and all the fun adventures we had exploring my hometown, I thought I&#8217;d do a top ten from our two weeks in lovely Louisville, KY.  Here goes our top 10 Louisville highlights, in no particular order&#8230; [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=198&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We made it home safely to SoCal yesterday.  In an effort to capture all the exciting places we visited and all the fun adventures we had exploring my hometown, I thought I&#8217;d do a top ten from our two weeks in lovely Louisville, KY.  Here goes our top 10 Louisville highlights, in no particular order&#8230;</p>
<h3>1.  <a href="http://www.louisvilleglassworks.com/">Glassworks</a></h3>
<p>Two glass studios and 2 galleries under one roof!  Mack (my son) and I spent about 30 minutes watching the artists in sweltering heat blow glass from air-conditioned bleachers located inside the studio.  We were both fascinated.  There are daily tours through Flame Run&#8217;s Hot Shop and the Mark Payton Glass Center to introduce you to the world of glassmaking.  While Mack was mesmerized by the fires in the kilns, I was attracted to the beautiful artwork for sale in their 2 galleries.  If you are in the area head to Museum Row in Downtown Louisville.  Glassworks is worth checking out!</p>
<div id="attachment_243" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://becauseijustdo.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/glassworks.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-243" title="Glassworks" src="http://becauseijustdo.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/glassworks.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="281" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Glassworks.</p></div>
<h3>2. <a href="http://www.sluggermuseum.com/">Louisville Slugger Museum &amp; Factory</a></h3>
<p>Just around the block from Glassworks is the Louisville Slugger Museum &amp; Factory.  While we chose not to take a tour of the factory (though next time it will be one of our first activities) there was still plenty for my little man to explore.  There are batting cages for the older kids and a toddler-sized batting cage complete with a tee for the smaller ones.  It&#8217;d be hard to come to Louisville and not &#8220;swing&#8221; by.  You can&#8217;t miss it, The World&#8217;s Biggest Bat (a replica of Babe Ruth&#8217;s 34-inch Louisville Slugger) is just out front, standing 120-feet tall on West Main Street.</p>
<div id="attachment_244" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://becauseijustdo.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/slugger.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-244" title="Slugger" src="http://becauseijustdo.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/slugger.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="281" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Louisville Slugger Museum &amp; Factory.</p></div>
<h3>3. <a href="http://thecomfycow.com/">The Comfy Cow</a></h3>
<p>It&#8217;s hot in Louisville in August so we made a couple of after-dinner, evening ice cream runs.  My new favorite Ice Cream shop is The Comfy Cow.  Each batch of ice cream is handcrafted in Louisville and uses only the best ingredients (all natural, hormone-free, fresh and fine).  While they always carry signature flavors (Black Raspberry Chip, Salty Caramel and Strawberry Fields Forever to name a few) they also rotate in crazy, new experimental flavors.  You can see the fabulous flavors listed in the photo below.  I was blown away by the Mint Julep&#8230; a refreshing mint ice cream with the tiniest hint of bourbon.  With 3 locations in the Louisville area, you can never be too far from creamy, cool bliss.</p>
<div id="attachment_248" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://becauseijustdo.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_0446.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-248" title="DSC_0446" src="http://becauseijustdo.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_0446.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="146" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Flavor Board at The Comfy Cow.</p></div>
<h3>4.  <a href="http://www.belleoflouisville.org/">Belle of Louisville</a></h3>
<p>The Belle of Louisville is the oldest operating Mississippi River-style steamboat in the world.  Aside from the Twin Spires of Churchill Downs, it has to be the city&#8217;s most recognizable landmark.  Mack adores boats and so one afternoon we hopped on board for a 2-hour cruise down the Ohio River.  Nothing beats a boat ride.</p>
<div id="attachment_257" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://becauseijustdo.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_0639.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-257" title="DSC_0639" src="http://becauseijustdo.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_0639.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="332" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The Belle of Louisville&#8217;s paddlewheel.</p></div>
<h3>5. <a href="http://hadleypottery.com/">M.A. Hadley Pottery</a></h3>
<p>If you&#8217;ve eaten in the home of a native Louisvillian chances are you were served on a plate from Hadley Pottery.  Also, nearly every lady in the city has a Hadley ring holder (pictured below) sink-side in their kitchen.  Every piece is crafted from local Indiana clay, hand-painted and then single fired.  I purchased a tiny ashtray with a fleur-de-lis (Louisville&#8217;s city symbol) to place at my bedside for jewelry.</p>
<div id="attachment_262" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://becauseijustdo.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/desktop61.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-262" title="Desktop6" src="http://becauseijustdo.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/desktop61.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="312" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">M.A. Hadley Pottery ring holders, plate and ashtray.</p></div>
<h3>6. <a href="http://www.classicbiplanetours.com/">Classic Biplane Tours</a></h3>
<p>A year ago my Mom gave my Father a gift-certificate for a Biplane ride over Louisville.  They recently found out that the Biplane could hold two passengers and my Dad invited me to join him for a 30 minute flight over the city.  It was a blast!  Viewing the city from the air was such a treat.  We flew over Churchill Downs (home of the Kentucky Derby), past the downtown skyline, then up along the Ohio River and returned flying over all the neighborhoods where my childhood friends and I grew up.  Next time we&#8217;re back with my husband,  he and my son are definitely taking this beautiful flight!</p>
<div id="attachment_264" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a href="www.classicbiplanetours.com"><img class="size-full wp-image-264" title="14.jpg" src="http://becauseijustdo.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/14-jpg1.gif" alt="" width="500" height="371" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">photo courtesy of www.classicbiplanetours.com</p></div>
<h3> 7. <a href="http://www.classicbiplanetours.com/">Henry County Supply</a></h3>
<p>Mack loves farm equipment.  We headed out early one morning to Henry County Supply, a John Deere Dealership and agriculture supply store.  The people there were so friendly, they even let Mack climb up and &#8220;drive&#8221; the tractors.  It didn&#8217;t hurt that they also have a full-on John Deere toy section so Mack was able to take home his very own tractor, complete with trailer and harrow.  It&#8217;s north of the city but a stunning drive along U.S. 421 to New Castle, KY was well worth it for my little farmer.</p>
<div id="attachment_249" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://becauseijustdo.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_0408.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-249" title="DSC_0408" src="http://becauseijustdo.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_0408.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="332" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Nothing runs like a Deere.</p></div>
<h3>8.  <a href="http://scoutonmarket.com/">Scout </a></h3>
<p>My sweet cousin, Susan introduced me to this store a few years ago.  It is located in an area of town now known as <a href="http://eastmarketdistrict.com/">NuLu</a>, a recently renovated area along East Market Street with hip shops and restaurants.  This store has everything I love.  As their website says, &#8220;Scout is a modern eclectic mix of furniture, home accessories, giftware, artwork and jewelry.&#8221;  All of this in a great range of prices.  I walked away with the necklace below for $25 and the earrings for just $10!</p>
<div id="attachment_250" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://becauseijustdo.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/desktop5.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-250" title="Desktop5" src="http://becauseijustdo.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/desktop5.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="312" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Purchases from Scout.</p></div>
<h3>9. <a href="http://www.plehns.com/">Plehn&#8217;s Bakery</a></h3>
<p>If you have never had a Butter Bun from this place you have not lived.  It&#8217;s easy for my Mom and I to eat an entire package of these little guys smothered with <a href="http://www.courier-journal.com/article/99999999/DERBYFUN/90422022/Benedictine-spread">benedictine</a> (a cucumber, cream cheese spread) at lunchtime.  And, yes, I&#8217;ve even had my Mother ship them to me in California.  But it doesn&#8217;t stop there&#8230; their cupcakes, cookies, deli, breakfast pastries and donuts are out of this world.  Also, I love the southern charm in this place.  They still have an old-fashioned counter where you can climb up on a stool, order a cup of coffee and enjoy a delicious cheese danish or chocolate donut.  A really fun treat for kids!</p>
<div id="attachment_251" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://becauseijustdo.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/desktop.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-251" title="Desktop" src="http://becauseijustdo.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/desktop.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="281" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Baked Goods from Plehn&#8217;s Bakery in St. Matthews.</p></div>
<h3>10. <a href="http://www.milb.com/index.jsp?sid=t416">Louisville Bats Baseball</a></h3>
<p>The Louisville Bats are the Triple-A affiliate of the Cincinnati Reds.  I told my husband that if we lived in Louisville we would be at a Bats Baseball game at least once a week during the summer.  Truth be told, the best part about attending a Bats game is being at Louisville Slugger Field.  The Field, located downtown near the river opened in 2000 and has seats for approximately 13,000 fans.  It is, in a word, perfect.  Our tickets, which were about 6 rows up from the 1st baseline cost only $11 a piece.   You can sit on the lawn (left field) for only $7 per person and there is even a merry-go-round and a playground inside the stadium if the kids get antsy.</p>
<div id="attachment_270" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://becauseijustdo.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_0492.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-270" title="DSC_0492" src="http://becauseijustdo.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_0492.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="880" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Buddy Bat. Official mascot of the Louisville Bats.</p></div>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/198/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/198/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=198&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://becauseijustdo.wordpress.com/2012/08/08/louisville-ten-stops-in-the-possibility-city/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/65d913e80c824edaa97dc90ab6206364?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">becauseijustdo</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://becauseijustdo.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/glassworks.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Glassworks</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://becauseijustdo.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/slugger.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Slugger</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://becauseijustdo.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_0446.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0446</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://becauseijustdo.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_0639.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0639</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://becauseijustdo.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/desktop61.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Desktop6</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://becauseijustdo.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/14-jpg1.gif" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">14.jpg</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://becauseijustdo.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_0408.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0408</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://becauseijustdo.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/desktop5.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Desktop5</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://becauseijustdo.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/desktop.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Desktop</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://becauseijustdo.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_0492.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0492</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Do you have to let it linger?</title>
		<link>http://craigblessing.wordpress.com/2012/08/10/do-you-have-to-let-it-linger/</link>
		<comments>http://craigblessing.wordpress.com/2012/08/10/do-you-have-to-let-it-linger/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2012 00:27:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>craigblessing</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[musings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPchallenge]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://craigblessing.wordpress.com/?p=41</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I don&#8217;t often listen to the radio. The constant repetition on local stations is enough to cause road rage! How many times can you listen to Bieber sing about his baby before you just want to hit someone? Instead, when in my car, I listen to audible books; at home, it is almost always Pandora [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=41&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I don&#8217;t often listen to the radio. The constant repetition on local stations is enough to cause road rage! How many times can <em>you</em> listen to Bieber sing about his baby before you just want to hit someone? Instead, when in my car, I listen to audible books; at home, it is almost always Pandora Radio. The other day though, something made me tune it in and turn it up.</p>
<p>There was a retro party playing and I drove along enjoying songs that were the soundtrack of my youth. These were songs that meant something to me. And while &#8220;Mmm Bop&#8221; may not be a shining example of literary or musical gold, it made me smile nonetheless.</p>
<p>Song after song filled the car. I sang along with them all. I mean really singing, too. I wasn&#8217;t just mouthing the words or humming with the music. I was belting them out like I was the front man for the best band in the world!</p>
<p>Then it happened.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>But I&#8217;m in so deep, you know I&#8217;m such a fool for you<br />
You got me wrapped around your finger<br />
Do you have to let it linger?<br />
Do you have to, do you have to<br />
Do you have to let it linger?</em></p></blockquote>
<p>The Cranberries took me back to an entirely different place and time. This wasn&#8217;t just simple memory.  It wasn&#8217;t like I was watching the events of my life on a movie screen. This was powerful and almost overpowering.</p>
<p>I wasn&#8217;t just remembering the cold tiles of Moses Hall, room 402. I could actually <em>feel</em> them under my feet. I could <em>smell</em> the stale smell of too many guys living in a single place. I could <em>hear</em> my neighbors arguing about whether the crowd would be better at the Chicken or at Dudley&#8217;s.</p>
<p>I was there in one of the craziest, most difficult, and most amazing times of my life. In the span of a few moments I experienced coming out, my first love, my first heart break, and a true time of growing up.</p>
<p>And suddenly, the words meant something completely different to me. While I did have some hard times and a broken heart that I thought would never mend, these weren&#8217;t the things that came to mind.</p>
<p>In those few minutes of vivid recall, all I could think about was the good. The bad things were still there, of course but they were dim and faded. The good things shone as if they had been lovingly polished and put on a shelf for display.</p>
<p>Even now, I smile as I think about the happiest Burger Boy in the world riding through the rain.</p>
<p>No matter how bad it seems at the time, it gets better. </p>
<p>The pain and sorrow and tears and joy and laughter all pile together into an imperfectly perfect moment in the past.</p>
<p>So I finally have an answer.</p>
<p> Yes. You do have to let it linger.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/41/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/41/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=41&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://craigblessing.wordpress.com/2012/08/10/do-you-have-to-let-it-linger/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>27</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/dab87c3129cfab821b3db4b28b864a5c?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">craigblessing</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Birth of a Francophile</title>
		<link>http://thepreface.org/2012/08/08/francophile/</link>
		<comments>http://thepreface.org/2012/08/08/francophile/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2012 19:14:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Brett</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Narrative]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edith piaf]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[francophile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[French]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Musings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[people]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[random]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thoughts]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thepreface.org/?p=498</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I sat around reading warning labels as a kid. Maybe some kids played basketball or kickball. Nope. Not me. That’s where I first learned French. The words were musical. Though they burbled from my lips in lumps, I still sensed the lush vowels and fluid links. Of course I had no idea what they meant. [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=498&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I sat around reading warning labels as a kid. Maybe some kids played basketball or <a href="http://theprefacedotorg.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/100_0695.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-502" title="Eiffel Tower" src="http://theprefacedotorg.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/100_0695.jpg?w=300&h=224" alt="" width="300" height="224" /></a>kickball. Nope. Not me. That’s where I first learned French.</p>
<p>The words were musical. Though they burbled from my lips in lumps, I still sensed the lush vowels and fluid links. Of course I had no idea what they meant.  <em>Attention!</em> I said to my dad. <em>Regardez! Gonflable! </em>The last one means airbags, in case you’re wondering.</p>
<p>I started taking French in middle school. My teacher was a lean woman with a face like Edith Piaf and frantic red hair that never changed. She swore in Greek under her breath and was a lyricist of French grammar.</p>
<p><span id="more-498"></span></p>
<p>My dad and I met her at the open house. I crept in behind his shadow, entering a room marinated in cafe music, Nutella, and pictures of Paris.</p>
<p>It proved to be an ambush.</p>
<div id="attachment_503" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://theprefacedotorg.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/france-butchers.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-503" title="France, Butchers" src="http://theprefacedotorg.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/france-butchers.jpg?w=300&h=224" alt="" width="300" height="224" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">A typical poster-like image I took in Paris</p></div>
<p>Two French-class groupies flanked us. One captured my dad, while the other&#8211;with short blond hair and flush cheeks&#8211;backed me against a wall. She said my feathery blond hair was cute and asked if I new any French. I nodded.</p>
<p>&#8220;Bonjour?&#8221; I squeaked.</p>
<p>&#8220;Here, take this!&#8221; she said, thrusting a baguette slice spread with Nutella. I held it. &#8221;Try it,&#8221; she said.</p>
<p>I did. It was love at first bite.</p>
<p>The teacher, Doc, infused her lectures with cooky stories with characters like &#8220;Chickolina&#8221; and used argyle socks to illustrate the placement of pronouns in a sentence.</p>
<p>By my final two years, Doc had retired, so I had Mademoiselle Kent. Tall, fit, with jet-black hair, and hazel eyes that glowed green in the sun. She dressed in prim, well-pressed clothes, and when she spoke, her eyebrows arched and her nose twitched in the most adorable way.</p>
<p>I had a serious crush. I even wrote a little poem about her: &#8220;Her nosed twitched when she talked,/Her feet itched when she walked.&#8221; Nothing creepy, but I blushed when she called my name and got anxious when she asked me to stay after class.</p>
<p>She was from Grenoble near the French Alps, but had spent most of her life in America and spoke English with a clean American accent that only dissolved when she spoke French. Out of boredom in most classes, I described them. Here&#8217;s an example of Mlle. Kent from tenth grade French:</p>
<blockquote><p>Her eager, oscillating features remind me of a hopeful school girl who tries, fails, but never loses hope as she shuffles her feet with the excitement that perhaps today will be a good day. Perhaps, she hopes, the class will listen, and she will be able to teach. It will be different today, she thinks, and they will understand!</p>
<p>&#8220;<em>Bonjour</em>, Brett,&#8221; she happily states with a stifled, rapid wave. She smiles, and I look up with tired eyes.</p>
<p>&#8220;<em>Bonjour, Madam</em>,&#8221; I return with a smile. Yes have a good day. Dream your dreams, and hope against hope that today will be different, poor fool. As I turn the corner, I here the noise outside, and the noise within. I can not decide which is louder.</p>
<p>I see a cunning little paper missile whizz across the room. It hits a wall, and somewhere someone curses. A war seems to be in the works&#8230;</p></blockquote>
<p>A typical day. The blonde ballet dancer who sat in front of me&#8211;my first head-over-heals infatuation&#8211;would always crack her back, with a sickening percussion of snaps and bodily gurgles. My friend Matt and I sat in the back passing messages back and forth by packing them in a pen. Another guy would idle in the corner, planning tricks. Once he locked a girl&#8217;s thong to the chair. Another time he pulled a block of wood with a nail in it from his Mary Poppins backpack.</p>
<p>When the teacher turned her back, paper balls flew.</p>
<p>Eleventh grade was different. AP French was serious business. We had five people&#8211;my friend James and three girls. Studies included French movies, French bread, Edith Piaf, and artful paper fish to stick on people&#8217;s back&#8211;apparently an April Fool&#8217;s tradition called the <em>poisson d&#8217;Avril.</em></p>
<p>My parents and I also went to Paris for a week.</p>
<div id="attachment_504" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://theprefacedotorg.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/france-city-overview.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-504 " title="France, City overview" src="http://theprefacedotorg.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/france-city-overview.jpg?w=300&h=224" alt="" width="300" height="224" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Paris!</p></div>
<p>Day one, we ambled through the city half-lost and saddled with jet lag until the gray sky spilled its guts against the wide boulevards and beige buildings. You could drink the air. We swam in it until Dad bought an overpriced umbrella.</p>
<p>The week strolled on. We saw art at <em>La Grande Louvre</em> and the <em>Musée d&#8217;Orsay, </em>climbed the Eiffel Tour and <em>L&#8217;Arch de Triomphe</em>,<em> </em>and<em> </em>visited one of Paris&#8217; largest cemeteries, <em>Père Lachaise</em>, where I sat at Chopin&#8217;s grave beneath the pastel-pink blossoms of early spring. Outside <em>La Louvre,</em> my mom threw an umbrella at my dad to the joy of a Frenchman smoking nearby.</p>
<p>We were typical American tourists.</p>
<p>But amid the sightseeing, my fondest memories were from cafés. Nibbling<em> pain au chocolat </em>with its warm, buttery folds falling on my lap. Sipping <em>cafe au lait</em> as sexy Parisian women strutted by on the <em>Champs</em>-<em>Élysées. </em>Watching the city dim in a haze of golden light and billowed shadows, the Eiffel Tour lit against the black sky like a silver beacon. Sipping wine and cracking <em>crème brûlée </em>with a teaspoon.</p>
<div id="attachment_505" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://theprefacedotorg.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/france-chopins-grave.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-505" title="France, Chopin's grave" src="http://theprefacedotorg.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/france-chopins-grave.jpg?w=300&h=224" alt="" width="300" height="224" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Chopin&#8217;s grave</p></div>
<p>Since then, I&#8217;ve blossomed from a precocious young French student to a full-fledged francophile. I have more French movies than English-speaking titles. I listen to French music and sing it in the shower. I read French books. I love French history.</p>
<p>Where it all leads, I can&#8217;t tell. Where it all came from, I don&#8217;t know. Perhaps warning labels. Perhaps crazy French-class groupies bearing baguettes. Perhaps my hot French teacher or my vacation to Paris.</p>
<p>When an urge or an interest becomes a label, the whole ordeal gets sticky. The label molds us to its image, yet already has its source from within. I always wonder if there&#8217;s a single seed&#8211;a memory perhaps&#8211;that sprouts and runs its leafy tendrils through our being until it proves dominant or if experiences and quirks accumulate and knot together under a single name, like <em>francophile</em>.I wonder where it ends and where we begin.</p>
<p>But for now, I&#8217;ll eat my Nutella and turn up Joe Dassin with <em>joie de vivre. </em>After all, <em>c&#8217;est la vie</em>.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/498/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/498/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=498&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thepreface.org/2012/08/08/francophile/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>19</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/68b9b3f8bc43d7beed43a6440c21834c?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sisyphus1789</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theprefacedotorg.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/100_0695.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Eiffel Tower</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theprefacedotorg.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/france-butchers.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">France, Butchers</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theprefacedotorg.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/france-city-overview.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">France, City overview</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theprefacedotorg.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/france-chopins-grave.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">France, Chopin&#039;s grave</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>