<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2013 20:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Rock, Paper, Laptop</title>
		<link>http://authordianemhow.com/2013/01/24/rock-paper-laptop/</link>
		<comments>http://authordianemhow.com/2013/01/24/rock-paper-laptop/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2013 23:45:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>authordianemhow</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inspiration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[funny]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[laughter]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://authordianemhow.com/?p=273</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Ancient Egyptian writers depended upon chisels and stone as the medium for their hieroglyphics. I’m sure many of them embraced the advances in technology that introduced other resources for their passions. Yet, I imagine there were some who struggled to move forward gleefully. There was a time when pads of yellow paper graced nearly every [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=273&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://authordianemhow.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/hieroglyphics.jpg"><img src="http://authordianemhow.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/hieroglyphics.jpg?w=720" alt="hieroglyphics"   class="alignnone size-full wp-image-274" /></a><a href="http://authordianemhow.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/yellow-pads1.jpg"><img src="http://authordianemhow.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/yellow-pads1.jpg?w=720" alt="Yellow Pads"   class="alignnone size-full wp-image-277" /></a><a href="http://authordianemhow.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/laptopcomputer.jpg"><img src="http://authordianemhow.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/laptopcomputer.jpg?w=720" alt="LaptopComputer"   class="alignnone size-full wp-image-278" /></a></p>
<p>Ancient Egyptian writers depended upon chisels and stone as the medium for their hieroglyphics.  I’m sure many of them embraced the advances in technology that introduced other resources for their passions.  Yet, I imagine there were some who struggled to move forward gleefully.</p>
<p>There was a time when pads of yellow paper graced nearly every table top of our home, patiently waiting for any random thoughts of gibberish to find its way onto a meticulously clean surface.  With my companions, a smooth writing pen and lined paper, I delight in sitting cross-legged on my couch or out on the deck, scribbling away with the security of knowing I can rip off a page, crumble it and have a clean slate ready for my next attempt. </p>
<p>Much like reminiscing through old photographs, I can pick up a journal or notebook stuffed with pages of deep thoughts, easily revisiting my attempts to imitate Robert Frost <a href="http://www.poemhunter.com/robert-frost/" rel="nofollow">http://www.poemhunter.com/robert-frost/</a> or Erma Bombeck <a href="http://www.ermamuseum.org/home.asp" rel="nofollow">http://www.ermamuseum.org/home.asp</a>.  Sometimes, the words I scripted are buried so deep in the recesses of my mind I don’t recognize the words, yet I always know they are mine because of the handwriting.  </p>
<p>It isn’t that I don’t know the capabilities of the black box that had been assigned its own room in the house for many years.  My job required extensive knowledge of numerous, ever-changing, complex programs, including the infamous MS Word.  Perhaps the challenges forced upon me daily formed a callous on my brain that makes it too painful to imagine drafting my work on my computer.  </p>
<p>Seldom did I take the time to store my creations electronically.  The few that made it through the final stages of editing onto the complex contraption were lost when the hardware failed.  (Thank goodness for my archaic backups!)  The thought of composing something while sitting at the keyboard was as foreign the thought of writing a romance novel.</p>
<p>My daughter frequently reminded me of the century we now live in and the advances in technology that she believed would make my life easier, if only I would try something new.  The way she rolled her eyes when I’d pick up a tablet and began writing reflected her frustration in my failure to listen.  Bless her heart.  Instead of nagging endlessly, she generously provided me with a laptop upon my retirement.  “You can use it anywhere, mom.  You’ll love it.”  </p>
<p>So I tried sitting cross-legged on the sofa with the slim blue device balanced on my lap.  That lasted about ten minutes before the phone rang and I had to untangle my legs from the wire to get across the room to the phone.  What wires you say?  The one attached to the mouse of course.  Yes, I know others may use the one built into their machine, but using the touch pad doesn’t work for me because I keep resting my thumbs as I ponder my next line.  If you have never been gifted in this ability, let me describe what happens next.  The perfect words you struggled for fifteen minutes to compose transform themselves into paragraphs and sentences for which they were not intended.  The time it took to find and edit them is just long enough for the thought to pass and there you sit staring at the screen again. I fixed the problem by disabling the gizmo – ok, I had to have help with that too.</p>
<p>I often found myself reverting back to paper and pen.  It wasn’t until I decided to write my first novel that I considered the time-consuming effort it would take to write a 50,000 word manuscript and then transpose it onto the computer.  One day, after much deliberation, I relented and established a work zone in my dining room where I began typing and editing the dozens of pages I had written before coming to my senses.  </p>
<p>I opened the French doors leading onto the deck and felt a delightful breeze drift in.  The chirp of a nearby cardinal provided for an opportunity to procrastinate and it wasn’t long before I ventured out onto the deck with all tools in hand. My fairybook visions of spending the next few hours accomplishing great things dissipated in seconds. The gentle wind turned into a gust and blew my stacks of paper high into the sky.  With arms flailing, I scrambled urgently to retrieve the papers in flight for fear of a neighbor stealing page 10 of a best seller.</p>
<p>Once I even tried taking my laptop on a daytrip to the river where my husband docked his boat.  He often liked to visit for hours with a friend who lives there.  What a great opportunity, I thought.  I&#8217;ll be inspired as the river carries barges through the lock and dam.  Surely a poem or some type of masterpiece was waiting to find its way into my laptop.  I proudly headed to the lovely swing where I had often written in my small journal.  </p>
<p>I shifted the mouse and pad from my leg to the bench of the swing.  I tried numerous positions to no avail.  I decided to remove the accessory and use the touchpad.  Try as I might, I could not remember the sequence of steps my friend had shown me to reactivate the function.  By the time I successfully retrieved the info from my wary brain, the battery died on the laptop.  I bit my lower lip to keep from screaming and quietly closed the lid and stood up, dropping the mouse and pad at my feet.   Anger turned into tears as I gathered all of the pieces and headed back to the car. </p>
<p>My frown turned into a smile when I opened the door and glanced down at the yellow pad and Cross pen that patiently waited for my attention.  In one hand, I tossed the laptop on the seat and with the other, I embraced my faithful companions, hugging them close as I strolled back to the wooden swing and settled in for a lovely afternoon.</p>
<p>The transition from rock to paper to laptop has not been easy for some of us.  Still, there are benefits to each.  Had it not been for the stones that ancient Egyptians carved, much of history would have been lost. Yet hieroglyphics presented many challenges, especially in portability.  Paper is readily available, portable and can be treasured for many years, yet it is fragile and fades in time.  A laptop stores immense amounts of data, offers unlimited features that transform the written word into works of art, and advances nearly daily in new technology, but with the touch of a delete key, a year’s worth of work can be forever lost into space.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve taken small steps to embrace the wonders of digital technology, but I doubt I will ever relinquish the comfort of paper and pen.  </p>
<p>Can you relate?</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/273/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/273/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=273&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://authordianemhow.com/2013/01/24/rock-paper-laptop/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/9b025bf166a587d0337ab5b5ad703cab?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">authordianemhow</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://authordianemhow.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/hieroglyphics.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">hieroglyphics</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://authordianemhow.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/yellow-pads1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Yellow Pads</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://authordianemhow.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/laptopcomputer.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">LaptopComputer</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How To: Name Your Baby</title>
		<link>http://cappywrites.com/2013/01/24/how-to-name-your-baby/</link>
		<comments>http://cappywrites.com/2013/01/24/how-to-name-your-baby/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2013 22:46:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>cappy writes</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[How To...]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[baby names]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comedy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[funny]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gwyneth Paltrow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kids]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[list]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[names]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[random]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thoughts]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cappywrites.com/?p=2618</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[So, I know my name is Cappy, and that might confuse some people. It might make other people angry that I&#8217;m writing a post about naming children when it seems that my parents named me under a haze of marijuana smoke and black lights. (Surprisingly enough, they didn&#8217;t. To get the full story behind my [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2618&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:left;"><a href="http://bymyink.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/baby-name.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-2815" alt="baby name" src="http://bymyink.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/baby-name.jpg?w=328&#038;h=366" width="328" height="366" /></a>So, I know my name is Cappy, and that might confuse some people. It might make other people angry that I&#8217;m writing a post about naming children when it seems that my parents named me under a haze of marijuana smoke and black lights. (Surprisingly enough, they didn&#8217;t. To get the full story behind my name, click <a href="http://cappywrites.com/2010/12/29/i-hereby-dub-thee/">here</a>.) But I, an extremely opinionated and slightly grumpy blogger, figured I had something to say, so I might as well say it. Listen up, and save the crazy names for middle names.</p>
<p>1. Don&#8217;t give your kid a bizarre-noun-name. There&#8217;s nothing worse (or easier to make fun of) than a kid named after a tree (Aspen is alright, Birch is not).<br />
Girl Examples: Harp, Cedar, Dream, Muse, Petri.<br />
Boy Examples: Wrangler, Trick, Track, Cannon, Knight.<br />
Exceptions include: Joy, Hope, Iris, May, June, Daisy. <em>Don&#8217;t get too exotic with your flowers&#8230;your kid shouldn&#8217;t be named Hibiscus or Anthurium.</em> There are no exceptions for boys except maybe August. Maybe.</p>
<p>2. Avoid names of continents, countries or cities.<br />
Girl Examples: Africa, Europe, Italy, Wales (that one&#8217;s for more reasons than one).<br />
Boy Examples: Scotland, Denmark.<br />
Exceptions: There are a lot of exceptions. One of my sorority sisters is named Britain and I think that&#8217;s delightful. Someone else I know is named Sicily. But don&#8217;t call them Zimbabwe or Seattle or something, cuz that just sounds weird&#8230;and sounds like you&#8217;ve decided any word that exists can be a name.</p>
<p>3. Don&#8217;t turn your girl-child into a stripper. You shouldn&#8217;t be allowed to name your kid Chastity, because even if she&#8217;s the most chaste girl in the world, everyone will think she&#8217;s a dirty tramp.<br />
Girl Examples: Verity, Charity, Trinity, Cinnamon (fun fact: I had a hamster named Cinnamon. Yep, just ruined it for you).<br />
Boy Examples: Well, don&#8217;t name your boy after a girl stripper, cuz that&#8217;s just wrong. And don&#8217;t name him Magic Mike.<br />
Exceptions: There are <em>no </em>exceptions.</p>
<p>4. Don&#8217;t go all Gwyneth Paltrow on your kid.<br />
Girl Examples: Apple, Orange, Banana, Pear, Peanut, Flute, Lute&#8230;the list goes on.<br />
Boy Examples: Rocket, Explosive, Banjo, Guitar, Picolo.<br />
Exceptions: If Gwyneth Paltrow <em>wouldn&#8217;t</em> like it, you can use it.</p>
<p>5. You are not a flower child, and neither is your one-second-old baby.<br />
Girl Examples: Wind, Flower, Breeze, Whisper, Peace, Love, Mist.<br />
Boy Example: Random, Earth, Strength, Virility, Rain.<br />
Exceptions: Skye might be acceptable, but only if they grow up to be super awesome.</p>
<p>6. Never, EVER, name your child after where they were conceived. Ever.<br />
I met a girl named Kastle once and she said it was because right before she was born her parents went to this Italian castle and stayed there and loved it&#8230;I guarantee they did the don&#8217;t in there and she is the product of their sordid night on a bed made of stone. Don&#8217;t do it.<br />
<em>On another note, don&#8217;t tell your kid where they were conceived. </em></p>
<p>7. After I&#8217;ve said all this, try not to name your kid the same thing as everyone else they&#8217;ll grow up with. It&#8217;s annoying growing up and being known as &#8220;Morgan F&#8221; because there are 5 other Morgans in your class. I&#8217;m not going to give examples, because they&#8217;re so obvious. Also, I feel like I&#8217;m going to offend everyone I know if I do.</p>
<p>Of course, there are a million exceptions and I&#8217;m a jerk about names, but a great rule of thumb is <em>DO NOT NAME YOUR CHILD ANYTHING SARAH PALIN WOULD NAME HERS. Except Piper, cuz that&#8217;s cute.</em></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2618/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2618/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2618&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://cappywrites.com/2013/01/24/how-to-name-your-baby/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>15</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/81c507d6be7448983f85f11aab53446f?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bymyink</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://bymyink.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/baby-name.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">baby name</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lost: One Mojo, Reward If Found</title>
		<link>http://puckerupbuttercup.wordpress.com/2013/01/24/lost-one-mojo-reward-if-found/</link>
		<comments>http://puckerupbuttercup.wordpress.com/2013/01/24/lost-one-mojo-reward-if-found/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2013 23:49:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Pucker Up Buttercup</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lesbian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sex]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Straight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaydar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Soccer Mom]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://puckerupbuttercup.wordpress.com/?p=391</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I was sitting in a local coffee dispensary, writing the first draft of a blog post in my Moleskine notebook and enjoying a latte (full caffeine, whole milk, five packets of raw sugar &#8230; I&#8217;m hardcore like that, it&#8217;s just the way I roll). This particular establishment had once been known as a meeting place [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=391&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I was sitting in a local coffee dispensary, writing the first draft of a blog post in my <a title="Moleskine" href="http://www.moleskineus.com/largeruled.html" target="_blank"><em>Moleskine</em></a> notebook and enjoying a latte (full caffeine, whole milk, five packets of raw sugar &#8230; I&#8217;m hardcore like that, it&#8217;s just the way I roll). This particular establishment had once been known as a meeting place for lesbians; but over the years the herd has thinned and rather than a flock of femmes or a bevy of butches you&#8217;re more likely to see a gaggle of high school girls being incredulous and astonished about <em>everything!</em>, or important business men taking important business calls about important business things and ignoring the barista who&#8217;s trying to take their order, gathered at the watering hole.</p>
<p>So it came as no surprise when I heard two young lesbians at the table next to me lamenting the decline of &#8220;our&#8221; coffee shop from lesbian hot-spot to gay-friendly neighborhood joint.</p>
<p>&#8220;This sucks,&#8221; said one to the other. &#8220;There&#8217;s nothing but fucking straight people here anymore.&#8221;</p>
<p>When I glanced up at them, smiling in commiseration, she turned to me and said, &#8220;Oh, sorry!&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;No problem,&#8221; I replied, assuming she thought she&#8217;d disrupted my writing or offended me by swearing.</p>
<p>&#8220;I didn&#8217;t mean anything,&#8221; she continued. &#8220;It&#8217;s not like I have something against straight people.&#8221;</p>
<p>I looked at her, momentarily confused, until what she was saying finally hit me. &#8220;No, I&#8217;m gay!&#8221;</p>
<p>Now she was the one who looked confused. &#8220;You are? Wow, I totally couldn&#8217;t tell.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Yeah,” her friend chimed in. &#8220;Me neither. Totally.&#8221;</p>
<p>Suddenly I was stricken with writer&#8217;s block and my latte tasted of despair. Totally.</p>
<p>That evening I recounted the disturbing episode to a friend. “No wonder I can&#8217;t meet anyone,” I whined. “My own people don&#8217;t even know I&#8217;m one of them!”</p>
<p>&#8220;I didn&#8217;t know you were gay when I met you either,&#8221; she confessed.</p>
<p>&#8220;That&#8217;s different,&#8221; I told her. &#8220;You&#8217;re straight.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;When I first saw you,&#8221; she said. &#8220;I thought you were a soccer mom or something.&#8221;</p>
<p><a href="http://puckerupbuttercup.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/0011-soccer-mom.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-402 alignleft" alt="0011 Soccer Mom" src="http://puckerupbuttercup.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/0011-soccer-mom.jpg?w=720"   /></a>I looked around for a vial of poison to drink, an asp to press against my breast or a windswept cliff upon the moors from which I might throw myself. Alas, there were none.</p>
<p>Please don&#8217;t misconstrue any of what I&#8217;ve said as a disdain or contempt for the heteronormative community. I love my Straights! I am like the Kathy Griffin of lesbians … except I don&#8217;t do stand-up, make a lot of money, piss off celebrities, my mother isn&#8217;t an alcoholic and I look <em>way</em> better when I&#8217;m not wearing make-up.</p>
<p>I know a lot of gay people say things like &#8230; <em>There&#8217;s a guy at work who&#8217;s straight</em> or <em>I had a straight roommate in college once</em> or <em>I think Chelsea Handler is <strong>so</strong> funny! &#8230; </em>in an attempt to &#8220;relate&#8221; to heterosexuals. And I&#8217;m sure when we do, it sounds just as ridiculous as meeting someone who&#8217;s Japanese and blurting out, &#8220;I love origami!&#8221;</p>
<p>But my experience is a little different. In the summer of 2010, three weeks after my 17-year relationship imploded, a car accident left me with an ankle too badly broken to even hobble. Since neither my Ex nor I enjoyed hiking, camping or wymyn&#8217;s music festivals, we&#8217;d drifted apart from most of the lesbian-couple friends we&#8217;d once had (for those who don&#8217;t know, <em>The Rules of Lesbian Relationships</em> state that once you enter into one, you must phase out activities that involve things such as fun, in favor of forced marches and sleeping in the dirt). So when it ended I found myself separated from the lesbian herd, stranded in the vast desolation of South Orange County. I was lost and alone.</p>
<p>But then a kind woman found me. She took me in and gave me a place to sleep, she fed me, she bathed me, she got me drunk. I ate at her table, I played with her children and she made me feel like part of her family. There were social gatherings with friends who were fun and friendly and got me drunk. Eventually, she even stopped locking up her jewelry when I was alone in the house.</p>
<p>That woman was a heterosexual.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m not shocked that straight people don&#8217;t know I&#8217;m gay. Typically the only indicator I display is the silver ring on my right thumb &#8212; not the most conspicuous piece of signage.  A few years ago however, when my hair was short, they were much more adept at picking-up on my lesbianisoty, sometimes saying, &#8220;I knew it! My gaydar&#8217;s always been really great!&#8221; And by &#8220;gaydar,&#8221; I can only assume they meant guessing that inch-long, purple, spiky hair might be favored by lesbians, because they were <em>really great</em> at doing that! It&#8217;s weird though, now that my hair is longer and blonde and I&#8217;ve learned to use some basic tools (blow-dryer, round-brush, thing that&#8217;s a blow-dryer and a round-brush combined together), I don&#8217;t meet as many straight people with really great gaydar.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m not really all that surprised when other gay people don&#8217;t know I&#8217;m a lesbian because I&#8217;m not the best at just spotting other gay people, either; and I usually have to do the eye-contact thing. My lesbian-detection abilities are weakest at the bank or Target or a shopping mall &#8212; places that I think of as <em>out of context. </em>So it stand to reason that there are others like me who have trouble getting a signal in certain areas. But when I&#8217;m in a recognized lesbian-zone (eg, hiking trails, softball fields, The Home Depot) &#8212; places that are <em>in context</em>, I&#8217;m a little bewildered. Has my lesbi-mojo slipped so far that even in a lesbian(ish) coffee shop I&#8217;m undetectable to other lesbians?</p>
<h3>The eye-contact thing &#8230;</h3>
<blockquote><p>&#8230; is when two gay people see each, their eyes meet and in that moment, however brief, a message passes between them saying, &#8220;Hello. I see that you are gay. I too am gay.&#8221; I&#8217;ve describe this &#8220;telepathy&#8221; to heterosexuals who also claimed to have it, they are mistaken however. They may correctly identify someone and think &#8220;Hello. I see that you are lesbian. I am one of those straight people who can tell.&#8221;  But, straight people make accurate guesses based on outward appearance, while gays can do it without such signs. Also, the lesbian looking back at you is thinking, &#8220;Wow, good guess. Were my cargo shorts your first clue?”</p></blockquote>
<p>And now that we&#8217;ve got my mojo all beat down and weak, let&#8217;s throw that soccer mom comment at it and see if we can kill it, shall we? But don&#8217;t jump to any anti-soccer mom conclusions about me just yet. The truth is I like soccer moms. <em>A lot</em>. I have this image of a tired woman schlepping around her screaming brood and their tangled accumulation of sports equipment, turning up the stereo in the minivan to try and drown out the incessant noise and the voice in her head that won&#8217;t stop asking <em>is this the life you always dreamed of?</em></p>
<p>Maybe I&#8217;m just a romantic, or maybe I watch too much porn, but I want to take Soccer Mom away from all that. If it&#8217;s the former, then I&#8217;ll meet her at work or perhaps the gym, she&#8217;ll find me witty and charismatic and strangely intriguing. We&#8217;ll become fast friends and there will be a montage of us walking on the beach with our pants rolled up to the knee, laughing together over drinks and one where we both reach for something at the same time, our fingers touch, our eyes meet and then we both look quickly away, played over a song like Corrine Bailey Rae&#8217;s <em><a title="Put Your Records On" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3XWyD98rd14" target="_blank">Put Your Records On</a></em>. Eventually she&#8217;ll confess that she has feelings for me but that it&#8217;s too complicated because of the kids and the custody fight with her bastard of an ex-husband. She&#8217;ll say &#8220;I&#8217;m sorry, I just can&#8217;t do this&#8221; and walk out of the apartment, leaving me standing there feeling hurt and alone &#8230; only to burst back through the door a minute later saying, &#8220;Who am I kidding?&#8221; as she throws her arms around me and kisses me (dear heterosexuals, you&#8217;ve just been introduced to the basic plot line of almost every lesbian romance movie on the market &#8230; we have movies too, and they&#8217;re just as cheesy as yours!). If it&#8217;s the latter, I&#8217;ll show up at her house to do some repair work inexplicably wearing 5” pumps and carrying a toolbox full of sex toys (there&#8217;s a <em>Snap-on Tools</em> joke in there, but this post is already getting too long), and we will commence to fuck like monkeys as soon as the <em>bowchicabowow</em> music starts (dear uhhh &#8230; oh hell, you all already know &#8230; everyone watches this crap).</p>
<p>So you see, my anguish has nothing to do with an aversion to either heterosexuals or mother&#8217;s of children involved in organized sports. It&#8217;s that I now feel my self-image is distorted and my self-perception on par with that of Donald Trump. By allowing my hair to grow did I inadvertently don some kind of lesbian cloak of invisibility? Did the time I spent living with the heterosexuals alter my chemical pheromones that alert others gays to my presence among them? Do I not exude the aura of self-assured, devilishly-charming lesbian romance-movie character I imagine? After living in South Orange County for so long could I have absorbed the appearance and mannerisms of a soccer mom without even realizing it? Is it possible that the <em>Stepford Wives</em> phenomenon rumor is actually true?</p>
<p>My mind reels with self-doubt, unanswered questions and thoughts of the <em>Wahl</em> clipper gathering dust on the top shelf of my closet.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/391/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/391/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=391&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://puckerupbuttercup.wordpress.com/2013/01/24/lost-one-mojo-reward-if-found/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/6513a5ca30a57141798f78bbcf1ce35e?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">puckerupbuttercup</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://puckerupbuttercup.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/0011-soccer-mom.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">0011 Soccer Mom</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>On My Long and Wearied Search for a Hairdresser</title>
		<link>http://her30s.wordpress.com/2013/01/24/on-my-long-and-wearied-search-for-a-hair-dresser/</link>
		<comments>http://her30s.wordpress.com/2013/01/24/on-my-long-and-wearied-search-for-a-hair-dresser/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2013 20:14:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>her30s</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Beauty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[being thirty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Growing Old Gracefully]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beauty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[being 30]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[growing up]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://her30s.wordpress.com/?p=246</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[When I was a kid spirals would cascade out of my scalp in the most unruly way driving my mother crazy. Being a straight haired woman herself, she had no clue as to how to care for a daughter with this type of mane. She was convinced, despite my screaming and countless tears, that she [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=246&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong><a href="http://her30s.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/dep_8500539-barber-hair-salon-hairdresser-icon-symbol-sign-pictogram.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-247" alt="dep_8500539-Barber-Hair-Salon-Hairdresser-Icon-Symbol-Sign-Pictogram" src="http://her30s.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/dep_8500539-barber-hair-salon-hairdresser-icon-symbol-sign-pictogram.jpg?w=300&#038;h=300" width="300" height="300" /></a>When I was a kid spirals would cascade out of my scalp in the most unruly way driving my mother crazy. Being a straight haired woman herself, she had no clue as to how to care for a daughter with this type of mane. She was convinced, despite my screaming and countless tears, that she could brush my hair and have it sit atop my head in an organized fashion. Of course this is not the case with curly haired girls as the cardinal rule of having healthy curls is, “Thou shall not brush curly hair.” When my mom grew tired of dealing with this “problem,” she simply took me to the salon and had the hair dresser cut off all of my curls. It sounds traumatic but having short hair was quite liberating.</strong></p>
<p><strong>My mom and I went to the same salon for over twenty years at least twice a month if not weekly. My mom would get her hair and nails done and I would maintain my short hair by getting it trimmed, cutting in layers and sometimes making the fatal mistake of cutting in bangs that I would then have to hide by pasting down with gel or wearing head bands even when they were out of fashion. It was fun to feel transformed and renewed even if my mom and I left the salon looking exactly the same, which was most often the case. When our hair dresser’s husband passed away, she suffered through a period of mental illness and had to close down her shop. That is when my hair began to grow down my back, the long forgotten spirals returned, and my mother by then an older lady on a tighter budget, began to do her own hair. It was the end of a tradition, more evidence that time had passed.</strong></p>
<p><strong>As a woman in her thirties I have no hair dresser to call my own. As a result I have been to a different salon every single time I have needed a haircut since 2007 and still have not found someone I can pay a return visit to. I went to the young gay guy who was skilled and gentle to my tender head but worked in a location too far away. I went to a woman who gasped when she saw my hair and said that whoever had cut it last left one side 2 inches longer than the other, (I think that might have been me…Who knew!?). I went to a lady recommended by a co-worker who was sporting various colors and various hair lengths in a jumble that almost made sense as a fashion forward hair style. That should have been my clue, the haircut she gave me left me with more split ends than I walked in with. And finally, last night after work I walked into a salon in a shopping center in North Hollywood where I experienced the cutest and the worst hairdresser of them all.</strong></p>
<p><strong>This young man of bulky, clumsy hands and gentle soul was experiencing his first day as a professional cosmetologist. He was nervous, concerned and every time he asked me a question it came out as if it had been rehearsed. He excused himself to the back room and left me mid hair cut various times to consult with someone. He worked slow and meticulously with sweat pouring down his forehead even though we were in a temperature controlled environment. His big hands got tangled in the knots in my hair and he actually cut his own finger instead of my hair. He came back with a band aid on that pulled my hair out even more as it stuck to the adhesive. I felt like a little kid again getting her hair brushed by her mother. Even though I was in pain the entire time and a simple trim took over an hour, I was rooting for him the entire time. At the end I told him he had done a good job and left him a generous tip. This morning I noticed he left one thick strand on the right side longer than the rest of my hair. I will either be cutting that piece myself, or combing it to the other side…</strong></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/246/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/246/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=246&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://her30s.wordpress.com/2013/01/24/on-my-long-and-wearied-search-for-a-hair-dresser/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>20</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f22cf00c3b4abfd56918f216377e9af0?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">her30s</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://her30s.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/dep_8500539-barber-hair-salon-hairdresser-icon-symbol-sign-pictogram.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">dep_8500539-Barber-Hair-Salon-Hairdresser-Icon-Symbol-Sign-Pictogram</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Morning Swim</title>
		<link>http://somedayiwilllearn.wordpress.com/2013/01/25/dpchallenge-morning-swim/</link>
		<comments>http://somedayiwilllearn.wordpress.com/2013/01/25/dpchallenge-morning-swim/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2013 01:36:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>stuffytales</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://somedayiwilllearn.wordpress.com/?p=3</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Before: I jumped into the pool and swam to the other side. After: I glanced briefly at the water before jumping in. The sun glistened through the windows and onto the surface of the pool, casting light grey shadows on the bottom of the pool with little twinkling stars floating on the surface. No one [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Before: I jumped into the pool and swam to the other side.</p>
<p>After: I glanced briefly at the water before jumping in. The sun glistened through the windows and onto the surface of the pool, casting light grey shadows on the bottom of the pool with little twinkling stars floating on the surface. No one had broken the perfection of the top of the water yet, although two red and white lane ropes ran from end to end cutting the pool into thirds. It was like they were part of the pool structure though, immovable and permanent, red on the ends with white in between. The water moved ever so slightly, shifting the twinkling stars around like little buoys. In a few minutes the sun would move and be gone from the surface but in the meantime I dawdled in an effort to prolong the beauty. From my left I heard a &#8220;splash!&#8221; and in that instant, the water went from serene to beaten. Splashy, angry little waves struck the edge, and several &#8220;sloops&#8221; were heard as the first waves were sucked into the filters. The lane ropes helped to calm the waves but they would not halted. &#8220;Slap, slap, slap,&#8221; went the arms of the other swimmers as they began to jump in in droves now, one after the other. It was time.</p>
<p>I chose to jump in the pool, deciding it would be preferable to get my feet wet first rather than my head. In that split second in the air before hitting the water, I cringed at the thought of being cold, and wondered what was in store for us in the pool today. Then the feeling was gone. My feet hit, enjoying the cold water, but as it rose to my chest I felt the chill. After my face hit the water, I allowed my body to sink to the bottom. As my feet hit the tiny tiles on the bottom, I shifted into gear; it was time to work. My feet pushed off the bottom, thrusting my body to the surface into a horizontal position. My head cradled in the wave I was creating in front of me, my feet propelling me forward with their constant flutter, and my arms creating ovals through the air and water. As I approach the wall, I shift my stroke slightly, pull harder underwater and force myself around in a somersault. Pushing off the wall is the best part of the length; using the force of your biggest muscles, the body is propelled much more quickly and out you go, streamlined and ready to take on another length. As I push off the wall, the swimmer behind me is entering it, pushing me to go faster in the next length to avoid the dreaded touch of the swimmer behind on my feet. Looking ahead as I glide forward, I can see the other bodies moving through the water, with their shadows visible on the pool bottom. The lane ropes stretch from end to end, looking endless, appearing to stop only when you are touching the wall. Back and forth, back and forth we go. Shifting my gaze from the bottom of the pool to just in front of me, I know where I should be looking but can&#8217;t resist the temptation to stare at the shadows and light dancing on the bottom.</p>
<p>Over and over again the arms and legs of the swimmers are drawn through the water, each one purposeful and beautiful and unique. It takes less than 15 metres to get into the rhythm and to hear the beauty of the noise, everyone being in a slightly different spot in their stroke but coming together into swimming symphony. In each moment, someone is starting a breath, another is finishing, a few are stealing a glance onto the pool deck, but all of us swimming. Each of us alone in our thoughts but together in the pool making beautiful music.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://somedayiwilllearn.wordpress.com/2013/01/25/dpchallenge-morning-swim/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/9398bb6b41c511b8a8437f0252c39a84?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">stuffytales</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8220;BROKEN&#8221;</title>
		<link>http://thespiritofawriter.wordpress.com/2013/01/25/broken/</link>
		<comments>http://thespiritofawriter.wordpress.com/2013/01/25/broken/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2013 21:25:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Megan Olson</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[broken]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creative writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPchallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[homeless]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thespiritofawriter.wordpress.com/?p=246</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[WordPress Writing Challenge:The Devil is in the Details &#8220;BROKEN&#8221; I scratched the surface of the bar with my thumbnail to see what the wood looked like before beer, vomit and oil from its patrons’ hands had coated its surface. My own beer had gone relatively flat. It probably hadn’t been stored properly to begin with. [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=246&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div style="text-align:left;"><em>WordPress Writing Challenge:The Devil is in the Details</em><a href="http://thespiritofawriter.wordpress.com/2013/01/25/broken/34480753367117913_z95p6w4s_b/" rel="attachment wp-att-247"><br />
</a></div>
<div style="text-align:left;"></div>
<div style="text-align:left;"></div>
<div style="text-align:left;"></div>
<div style="text-align:left;"><a href="http://thespiritofawriter.wordpress.com/2013/01/25/broken/34480753367117913_z95p6w4s_b/" rel="attachment wp-att-247"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-247 aligncenter" alt="34480753367117913_z95P6w4s_b" src="http://thespiritofawriter.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/34480753367117913_z95p6w4s_b.jpg?w=720"   /></a></div>
<div style="text-align:center;"></div>
<div style="text-align:center;">&#8220;BROKEN&#8221;</div>
<p>I scratched the surface of the bar with my thumbnail to see what the wood looked like before beer, vomit and oil from its patrons’ hands had coated its surface. My own beer had gone relatively flat. It probably hadn’t been stored properly to begin with. I watched Dale, the bar keep, swipe the silver surfaces of the countertops with a wet and filthy rag. I wondered why he bothered?</p>
<p>He had an affinity for country music sung by sorrowful women and I knew he was singing it in his head while he pretended to work.  As I watched him, he glanced up casually before letting his eyes fall back to his hands. Then he lifted his eyes with deliberate slowness, like some irresistible force was summoning them. Whatever was holding his interest was directly over my left shoulder. Not wanting to inflate the ego of whatever newcomer had just strolled through the doors, I allowed a solid beat to pass before looking up into the mirror that hung over the vast collection of liquor bottles.</p>
<p>A flash of red caressing long legs. It was all I needed to see before my heart froze. Before my chest ached. Before I had to grip the edge of the wooden bar and stare at the ground.</p>
<p>I felt her survey the room like I would have felt her hand slide across my back. Part of me wanted desperately to turn and face her. My shoulders were fighting me, trying to turn of their own accord in her direction. But, I couldn’t. I couldn’t allow myself to fall into this pit again. I knew what would happen if I did and the bottom was not where I wanted to end up.</p>
<p>The scent of her soft sweet perfume lapped over me along with the voice of the singer that flowed from the speakers around the room. The song fit. I wasn’t sure why but it felt right, like it was singing to me. Saying something for me that I couldn’t say for myself. And just as suddenly as I had been lost in my memories, she was sitting next to me, smiling, asking Dale for a Grey Goose martini. Dale complied without resistance and I wondered how he could betray me. Its not like he didn’t know who she was, we had come here for years before… before what had happened to us. He should have turned her away. He should have been a friend and spared me from myself. But he wasn’t my friend; He was a bartender. I couldn’t fault him for it; it was the reason I showed up at the dingy bar every night. Because I didn’t want the company of friends. Not their kindness or their questions. I wanted an empty bar with bad lighting and sad music.</p>
<p>I could feel her watching me then and I looked up to take in the perfect shape of her face. She smiled, the same smile I knew so well and I felt the pieces of my heart splinter into smaller shards. She was talking to me. I could see her lips moving, red full lips, with flashes of white between them. I smiled; I couldn’t help myself. It was a relief to see her. And then I was lost. That quickly. I couldn’t stop myself. I reached up to stroke her face.</p>
<p>The impact of her hand against my cheek knocked me backwards on my stool. I grappled with the side of the bar and air as I watched its feet lift up off of the ground. It took all my focus to keep me upright. And when I looked back at her, her face had changed. It was rounder and the eyes were brown. The red dress was gone, replaced by a faded black one. Her face was indignant and her mouth moved releasing unintelligible garble.</p>
<p>It wasn’t her.<br />
It had never been her.</p>
<p>My wife was gone.</p>
<p>Dale watched me, his eyes understanding but not forgiving. I scrambled off of my bar stool and headed for the door. But I couldn’t completely leave. I had seen her in there. My wife had been there, right there. I let my face fall into my hands and felt the familiar sway of my body back and forth. The brick on the wall lifted my shirt and scraped my back as I slid to the ground. My hands filled with salty tears and my own sobs echoed off of the walls of the alleyway. I went through that night again. For the millionth time and let the <i>ifs</i> wash over me. <i>If</i> I hadn’t had those last five drinks… <i>If</i> I had rolled down the window… <i>If</i> we had been fighting and she had leapt out of the car at a stoplight… <i>if</i> … <i>if</i>…. <i>If</i>…. Then I heard Dale comfort the woman still left behind in the bar.</p>
<p>“Don’t worry about him. He’s crazy, but harmless.” And he was right. I am crazy. And it was exactly what I deserve. I deserve to be hungry. I deserve to be cold. I deserve to have the scent of urine on my clothes. I deserve it. All of it. I let my body continue to rock and ignored the flesh rubbing off on the bricks. Tomorrow, I decided as I swayed and caught the eye of passerbys, my sign will read &#8220;BROKEN.&#8221; Because I am.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/246/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/246/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=246&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thespiritofawriter.wordpress.com/2013/01/25/broken/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f8252b9fe9bb1be4ca7ef74d79e022ec?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">megolson3</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thespiritofawriter.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/34480753367117913_z95p6w4s_b.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">34480753367117913_z95P6w4s_b</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pascagoula Public</title>
		<link>http://evolutionofx.com/2013/01/25/pascagoula-public/</link>
		<comments>http://evolutionofx.com/2013/01/25/pascagoula-public/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2013 22:44:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Evolution of X</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[that was then]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[card catalog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[details]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dewey decimal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPchallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[library]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[media center]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[memoir]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obsolete]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[public library]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://evolutionofx.com/?p=169</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I remember the smell like dried mushrooms and tree bark, a touch of vanilla and sawdust and smoke. There were secret doors that I imagined only I knew about, hidden windows that filtered daylight through rippled panes of glass dusted with fifty summers-worth of salt and pollen and pelted clean again by a thousand thunderstorms. [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=169&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I remember the smell like dried mushrooms and tree bark, a touch of vanilla and sawdust and smoke. There were secret doors that I imagined only I knew about, hidden windows that filtered daylight through rippled panes of glass dusted with fifty summers-worth of salt and pollen and pelted clean again by a thousand thunderstorms. That’s when I loved it most – on a summer day when the rain cut the heat and swelled the ditches full of polliwog water but the lightning kept me indoors by my mother’s decree.</p>
<p>We had to drive 2 miles of asphalt winding through pine woods, twice crossing low bridges over bronze bayous, past the tiny St. Pierre’s Episcopal Church and the abandoned creosote plant, over the railroad tracks, and onto the highway that arrowed through 8 miles of marsh, arced over the river on an ancient drawbridge and into “town.” Pascagoula was twice as big as my hometown &#8211; big enough to have a Sears and a high school and a hospital. Big enough to merit a public library.</p>
<p>It was an old brick building – ancient by my kid-reckoning &#8211; with big windows all around and white stone steps spilling from the front door. Everything on the other side of that door was a catalyst for fantasy and daydreams. The hardwood floors creaked like the trees they used to be bending in the wind on some Appalachian mountainside. The ceiling towered twenty feet high and dust motes like tiny planets or fields of asteroids floated through shafts of light shining through the tall windows, whole galaxies adrift above the readers bowed over their books like monks at long tables.</p>
<p>In the center of the room, a bank of card catalog cabinets stood like a high mesa of wood and brass in a badland desert of comfy reading chairs. The card holders and pulls on each drawer weren’t just brass but an arcane alloy made of copper from the desert southwest and zinc from Alaskan mines mixed and cast in metal loops the girth of a finger to open a drawers full of secrets written in Dewey Decimal code. The stacks occupied the left half of the room, canyon walls of fiction and fact made from paper, ink and glue. I was convinced that if all the books could whisper, a flood of sound and stories would wash us away, all the way down Market Street and into the Gulf of Mexico.</p>
<div id="attachment_171" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://evolutionofx.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the-old-library-via-ebookfriendlycom.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-171     " alt="" src="http://evolutionofx.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the-old-library-via-ebookfriendlycom.jpg?w=300&#038;h=240" width="300" height="240" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">(image via ebookfriendly.com)</p></div>
<p>The Pascagoula Public Library was demolished in 1987 and a bland new brick and glass box was erected on the site. It has fluorescent lights and Berber carpets and computers instead of card catalogs. I hate it, but I’m almost glad. Have you ever reread a book you loved as a kid only to find it wasn’t nearly so captivating the second time around? The old library is gone. I’ll never reread that particular book, so I can remember it however I like.</p>
<p>It seems a shame, though, that our sons will never have the same experience. We went to the library quite a lot when they were little guys for story time or to get stacks of books for us to read to them at bedtime. But by late elementary school, I had to beg, bribe or threaten them to get them to a library. They just wanted to stay home and play video games or watch Cartoon Network. And now that they’re in high school, they have laptops, Facebook, Youtube, and Netflix as well as an Xbox and the Nintendo Wii. Even the word “library” is becoming obsolete. Their schools have “media centers” where books are almost extraneous. The only reason our boys know what a card catalog is is because I bought one at an architectural salvage place and put it in the living room.</p>
<div id="attachment_176" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://evolutionofx.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/full-bookcase-of-books1.jpeg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-176 " alt="full-bookcase-of-books" src="http://evolutionofx.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/full-bookcase-of-books1.jpeg?w=300&#038;h=188" width="300" height="188" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Can you smell them? (image via Cafe Press)</p></div>
<p>I read an article recently about the smell of old books. It detailed the aromatic chemicals given off as the organic materials they are made from &#8211; the paper, glue and ink &#8211; decay. Books die, it said, but that also means they have a life. And in the course of that lifetime, they actually absorb certain strong odors, too, from things their readers expose them to like cigarette smoke or coffee. That’s what future “media centers” will lack along with the card catalogs and world globes and the maze-like stacks. One thing will be noticeably absent &#8211; the smell of all those living-dying, well-handled books.</p>
<p>A small price, you might say, for our kids growing up with a whole world of information and literature at their fingertips. And it is, I agree, an amazing time to be alive and curious. Until the power goes out.</p>
<p><em>*This post was written in response to the WordPress Daily Post Writing Challenge. Check it out at:</em></p>
<p><a href="http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2013/01/21/writing-challenge-details/">http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2013/01/21/writing-challenge-details/</a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/169/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/169/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=169&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://evolutionofx.com/2013/01/25/pascagoula-public/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>25</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/32b3e547131e706f1d30f4a9a9f3b023?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">forkinmyeye</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://evolutionofx.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the-old-library-via-ebookfriendlycom.jpg?w=300" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://evolutionofx.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/full-bookcase-of-books1.jpeg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">full-bookcase-of-books</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>I Confess.  I Cheated.</title>
		<link>http://dfsalvador.com/2013/01/23/i-confess-i-cheated/</link>
		<comments>http://dfsalvador.com/2013/01/23/i-confess-i-cheated/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 14:13:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>dfsalvador</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cheating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[competitive advantage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Current Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lance Armstrong]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[morals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[school]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scrabble]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dfsalvador.com/?p=700</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[You’re in school taking the most important and hardest class you’ll ever take.  There’s a lot of pressure because if you make an A you’ll be guaranteed a job.  A B might get you the job depending on how everyone else in the class does.  But you’re pretty confident because you’ve worked harder than your [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=700&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://dfsalvador.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/cheat.png"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-704" alt="cheat" src="http://dfsalvador.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/cheat.png?w=300&#038;h=58" width="300" height="58" /></a></p>
<p>You’re in school taking the most important and hardest class you’ll ever take.  There’s a lot of pressure because if you make an A you’ll be guaranteed a job.  A B might get you the job depending on how everyone else in the class does.  But you’re pretty confident because you’ve worked harder than your classmates.</p>
<p>First test you make a B.  A few of your classmates make Cs and Ds but the majority make As, and you wonder how they did that.  Soon, you hear that one of your classmates has a copy of all the semester’s tests, obtained perhaps by cleverly hacking into the professor’s computer.  The ones who are cheating ask if you’d like to come over and “study” with them for the next test.  You decline because you don’t want to be a cheater.</p>
<p>You study more than you did for the last test because you know you have to just to keep up.  You end up with a B plus.  They make As again.  They’re contacted by job recruiters.  You are not.  Even some of the ones who made Cs and Ds on the first test are now making As, moving you closer to the bottom of the pack.  You’d like to tell on them, but you have no proof.  Besides, that would really tick off the whole group, and they pretty much detest you anyway for your goody-two-shoes routine.</p>
<p>You do what you have to.  You join them.  You make your A.  You get the job.  You’re financially independent and so happy about that.  You get married and have kids, whose piano and tennis lessons you can pay for thanks to that good job.  Your family is happy.  No regrets.  You and your college buddies laugh about that class years later.</p>
<p>Now you’ve got this great job in a tight economy.  Again, you’re working your butt off, eating lunches at your desk, never taking sick days or personal days, yet the productivity of your co-workers is surpassing your own.  You know they’re cutting corners, backdating documents, shredding customer complaints and doing what they can to stay a step ahead of the curve.  One misstep and they could be fired.  They know that.  You know that.  At the same time, you know that management tacitly condones this behavior as long as they don’t make an obvious blunder that forces management’s hand.  You have a family and hate taking risks especially when it comes down to your livelihood.  However, you wonder that if you can’t keep up with the pack and their inflated numbers, you might lose your job.   You give up vacations, work on holidays, extend your work week to eighty hours just to do what your co-workers claim they do in a forty hour week.  You have your integrity.  You keep up this pace for twenty years, put your kids through college, watch them have families of their own, and finally you retire.</p>
<p>When you look back, you wonder what it would have been like to spend just a little more time with your kids?  You regret not spending more, because when it comes down to it, isn’t the family the most important thing?  You feel bitter at the rest of the world who seems happier than you with fewer wrinkles around the eyes.  They never faced the consequences of their misdeeds.  Or were they really misdeeds?  You wonder if making three follow up calls and fibbing on the required fourth would have made that much of a difference.</p>
<p>We face these kinds of tough decisions every day, sometimes without even considering the moral and ethical significance.  Cheating and getting ahead is the easy decision.  Choosing not to cheat is the tough one.  However, cheating does, after all, imply getting a competitive advantage.  What if you are at a competitive disadvantage if you don’t cheat because everybody else is?  It’s easy to justify it in our own heads when we are pursuing our goals to be successful and respected.</p>
<p>Let’s be honest.  What we all want is to be successful.  Society puts pressure on us to be successful.  In our culture, success is measured by the acquisition of things.  A businessman who nets one million dollars is more successful than one who nets a hundred thousand dollars.  No one asks to compare their bookkeeping or business practices.  An NBA superstar who has five championship rings is more successful than one who doesn’t have any.  Even successful parents are ones who produce successful children, children who are able to obtain a lot of things and money.  Sometimes we need to see ourselves as successful.</p>
<p>It’s time for me to come clean.  I am a Scrabble cheater when it comes to games played on my mobile device.  At first I just played against a friend at work against whom I racked up a record of twenty wins and no losses.  I branched out and began playing other players online.  I’d lose a few games here and there, but I was much more serious about the game than ninety-five percent of the other people that I played, so that in itself gave me an advantage.  There was one guy I liked to play.  We’d have close games but I’d win about eighty percent of the time.  Then his average score suddenly shot up by sixty points.  I’d been playing long enough to know the difference between making good use of the board and pulling insane words out of nowhere, and not just crazy two or three-letter goofy words like ZO and ZA that every Scrabble player with a hundred games under his belt begins to know.  These were words like ALUNITES or HODJAS or ORIGAN (no, not “origin” or “Oregon” but &#8220;origan&#8221;, in botany, another name for marjoram).  I didn’t want to directly accuse him of cheating but I sent him a message that said, “Are you a Muslim botanist and chemist?” to which he replied, “No.  Someone just played these words against me once, and I remembered them.”</p>
<p>Whatever.  I knew he was cheating.  It’s easy to hop onto the internet and use an anagram solver, and no one on the other side can ever prove it.  He started beating me.  It made me mad.  I watched my win/loss record fall below ninety percent, not that it really matters since no one but me ever looks at it.</p>
<p>So then, I started doing it, using the anagram solvers.  I started to beat him again.  And it felt <i>good.  </i> I didn’t feel guilty about it.  If that’s the way he wants to play, that’s the way I’ll play, I told myself.</p>
<p>The point of all this is not to suggest that cheating is the proper way to go but merely how easy it is to justify to ourselves that not only is cheating the better way but also the vital way.  There is an insane pressure placed on us from birth to succeed, and although many of us are brought up in the Christian tradition of humility and charity, we all know that piety and moral purity are not the main criteria society considers when labeling a person a success.</p>
<p>Since we are social beings, how others see us <i>is</i> so important to how we define and view ourselves.  We want others to like us and we naturally hide our flaws.</p>
<p>So now we come to Lance Armstrong.  Of course I had to watch his interview with Oprah.  I genuinely feel bad for him not because I sympathize with what he did but because I can only imagine how painful the fall from the top to the thorny pit of despair must be.  The truth is, we’ve all been in his situation.  You might say my Scrabble example is nothing like Lance Armstrong because there was nothing really at stake.  But really, that makes my actions even more preposterous.  The only thing at stake was my own vanity.</p>
<p>I’ve talked to some who might understand why he cheated, but cannot tolerate the way he viciously went after the people who accused him of cheating.  Anyone who has had an affair and is trying to hide it will scorch the earth before they reveal their lie.  It’s not noble or right.  It’s just a desperate attempt to stay above everything and scrape and claw at whatever might catch before the inevitable avalanche sends us tumbling down the mountain.  The deeper and more important the lie, the more people we are willing to hurt to protect it.  The way I see it, a man at his worst is usually no worse than most men.</p>
<p>To be clear, I’m not excusing Lance Armstrong’s behavior.  His titles should be stripped, a ban implemented, and his legend in the sport of racing tarnished.  But I don’t hate him either.  I’m just considering the reality that Lance Armstrong, like us all, is human.  Perhaps <em>that</em> is the biggest disappointment.</p>
<p><a href="http://dfsalvador.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/lance.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-708" alt="lance" src="http://dfsalvador.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/lance.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/700/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/700/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=700&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://dfsalvador.com/2013/01/23/i-confess-i-cheated/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>58</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/d027c489057b9feedaba746e01f0952a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">dfsalvador</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dfsalvador.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/cheat.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cheat</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dfsalvador.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/lance.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lance</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Teaching White Privilege in Education: Is it Important?</title>
		<link>http://whitemomblog.com/2013/01/23/teaching-white-privilege-in-education-is-it-important/</link>
		<comments>http://whitemomblog.com/2013/01/23/teaching-white-privilege-in-education-is-it-important/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 13:55:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>White Mom</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[being white]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[conversation starters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[current events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[motherhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[white privilege]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://whitemomblog.com/?p=114</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The other day, I came across a tweet about a Wisconsin school being investigated for teaching white privilege. Apparently, a parent at this particular school became very upset after reading the content of a course her son was taking titled &#8220;American Diversity.&#8221; The mother felt the curriculum was being used to teach white students that they [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=114&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_132" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://whitemomblog.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/freeimage-8577967.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-132 " alt="http://www.stockfreeimages.com/" src="http://whitemomblog.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/freeimage-8577967.jpg?w=300&#038;h=200" width="300" height="200" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text"><a href="http://www.stockfreeimages.com/" rel="nofollow">http://www.stockfreeimages.com/</a></p></div>
<p>The other day, I came across a tweet about a Wisconsin school being investigated for teaching white privilege. Apparently, a parent at this particular school became very upset after reading the content of a course her son was taking titled &#8220;American Diversity.&#8221; The mother felt the curriculum was being used to teach white students that they are racist and oppressive. She also felt the lesson on white privilege made her son feel unearned guilt for being white.</p>
<p>I can&#8217;t speak to how the material was presented or what the exact lesson plans were, but my takeaway is simple: kids aren&#8217;t the only ones who need these lesson—adults do, too.</p>
<p><span id="more-114"></span></p>
<p>I went to a diverse high school in Seattle, but I had no idea what white privilege was back then. It wasn&#8217;t until my sophomore year in college when I took a class called &#8220;The African-American Experience” that something clicked for me. A lot of little things I had experienced in high school started to make sense. Like why most of the people in my honors class were white. Or why our school didn&#8217;t get funding like most other schools in the area. Or why people stared at my volleyball team when we travelled to games out of Seattle city limits (the team was mostly students of Color).</p>
<p>A switch had been turned on for me, and it’s like Alice Hoffman once said: Once you know some things, you can&#8217;t unknow them. It&#8217;s a burden that can never be given away.</p>
<p>I did feel burdened. I felt guilty. I felt angry. I felt a lot of bad feelings about what it meant for me to be white. But then I got fired up. I read books I would have never read before, I watched documentaries, joined anti-racist organizations, and started asking more questions.</p>
<div>
<p>I started looking at the world through a different lens.</p>
</div>
<p>I stopped feeling guilty and started feeling responsible to transform myself and the world around me.</p>
<p>That class changed me. It opened my eyes and pushed me to be introspective. It didn&#8217;t happen overnight, but the seed had been planted. I was 20 years old when I took that college course, and I wish someone had taught it to me earlier.</p>
<p>As a parent, I don&#8217;t want my daughter to hurt and I don&#8217;t want guilt to consume her—but I also don&#8217;t value my child&#8217;s comfort over another child&#8217;s sense of value.</p>
<p>I hope the students in that Wisconsin classroom can move past feeling guilty and oppressive and begin to be change agents in their lives and communities. I hope their parents can start to feel that way, too.</p>
<p>Here’s the article, “<a title="School Under Fire for Teaching that Whites are Oppressive " href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-2263136/School-class-teaches-white-people-oppressors.html" target="_blank">School under fire for class that teaches white people are oppressors</a>.”</p>
<p><strong>What do you think about teaching whiteness in curriculum?</strong></p>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=114&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://whitemomblog.com/2013/01/23/teaching-white-privilege-in-education-is-it-important/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>83</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/0615f35247d9d2c8e20f47c395db67a8?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">buffycurtin</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://whitemomblog.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/freeimage-8577967.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">http://www.stockfreeimages.com/</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>I Say Tomato; You Say, &#8220;What&#8217;s That?&#8221;</title>
		<link>http://paltrymeanderings.com/2013/01/23/i-say-tomato-you-say-whats-that/</link>
		<comments>http://paltrymeanderings.com/2013/01/23/i-say-tomato-you-say-whats-that/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 11:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Miss Snarky Pants</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Comedy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andrew Zimmern]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[banana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bizarre Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[butternut squash]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cashier]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clown]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dirty dancing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Downton Abbey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[farmer's market]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fear of clowns]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fruits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[funny]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gristle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hairy foods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Honey Boo Boo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humorous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[I hate clowns]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jamie Oliver]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jennifer grey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kid won't eat vegetables]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kitchen slattern]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[martini]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[McDonalds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[picky eater]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[potato]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[produce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[roadkill]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ronald McDonald]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[seeds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sketti]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[teenagers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[texture issues]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vegetables]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vegetarian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vodka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wal-mart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[watermelon]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://paltrymeanderings.com/?p=2066</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Growing up, I was a picky eater. Tomatoes were persona non grata on my plate. Though I recognized that the &#8220;I&#8217;m-A-Fruit-Masquerading-As-A-Vegetable&#8221; meant well, I couldn&#8217;t understand why tomatoes insisted on encasing their precious seeds in something the consistency of snot. Oranges were also out of the question. If we were meant to eat them, why [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2066&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://paltrymeanderings.com/2013/01/23/i-say-tomato-you-say-whats-that/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>114</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/ba78e144a7502cf704f7593062e0fd96?s=96&#38;d=wavatar&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cristycarringtonlewis</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://paltrymeanderings.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/picky-eater.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">picky eater</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://paltrymeanderings.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ronald-mcdonald-capitalcommentary-com.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">I&#039;ll Show You Grisley, Junior Miss Snarky Pants!</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://paltrymeanderings.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/kid-licking-cat-stephenfalepau-tumblr.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Bad Form</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://paltrymeanderings.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/watermelon-martini.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Vodka Is Not A Food Group; It&#039;s A Lifestyle</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://paltrymeanderings.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/honey-boo-boo-sketti-bravo.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mmmmm! &#039;Sketti!</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
