<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2012 20:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>My Battered Roman Eagle</title>
		<link>http://kateshrewsday.com/2012/09/24/my-battered-roman-eagle/</link>
		<comments>http://kateshrewsday.com/2012/09/24/my-battered-roman-eagle/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2012 05:15:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>kateshrewsday</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Quirks of History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[archaeology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eagle of the Ninth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[history]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Romans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rosemary Sutcliffe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Silchester]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[University of Reading]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://kateshrewsday.com/?p=8221</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The heavens opened. And duty called, even on a Sunday. For school, a display on the Victorians, ready for a public event on Monday evening, was necessary. And I needed Victorian artefacts. I trawled the sources of Victorian wooden toys in my mind and decided wistfully that a trip into our local market town was [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=8221&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://kateshrewsday.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dsc_0240.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-8222" title="DSC_0240" src="http://kateshrewsday.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dsc_0240.jpg?w=640&h=425" alt="" width="640" height="425" /></a></p>
<p>The heavens opened.</p>
<p>And duty called, even on a Sunday. For school, a display on the Victorians, ready for a public event on Monday evening, was necessary. And I needed Victorian artefacts.</p>
<p>I trawled the sources of Victorian wooden toys in my mind and decided wistfully that a trip into our local market town was going to be a must. I must make a wet, crowded, expensive drive, alone because everyone else in the house had colds.</p>
<p>I braced myself. I got in the car. And I turned the ignition key, backed out of the drive and got on the road.</p>
<p>I found a parking place in a great shopping cathedral and scuttled off through the fat drops of rain to the museum, a worthy red-brick building. I walked through the doors into a museum which, with the gloom outside, looked as if the caretaker had already turned half the lights out.</p>
<p>My heart sank. Even one of my favourite sanctuaries felt abandoned.</p>
<p>I located and bought what I had to. And then, I instinctively headed for the one exhibit with which I must commune, this rainy afternoon.</p>
<p>It is two floors up, in a glass lift. I stepped out expecting to see no-one. There were a few straggling sightseers, grandparents with toddlers looking for rainy-day activity.</p>
<p>I wandered into the Roman galleries: and there he stood. My battered Roman eagle.</p>
<p>He is called the Silchester Eagle, and the Romans are thought to have thrown my eagle away for scrap.</p>
<p>The cads.</p>
<p>Silchester is the site of an old Roman town, Calleva Atrebatum. We&#8217;ve been digging it for well over a century: <a href="http://www.reading.ac.uk/silchester/about-silchester/sil-about-silchester-calleva.aspx">Reading&#8217;s University oversees it </a>these days.</p>
<p>My eagle was discovered a very long time ago, on October 9, 1866, by a clergyman. The Reverend JG Joyce, who excavated the dig from 1864-1878, was certain it was a very important eagle indeed: probably part of a Roman standard.</p>
<p>And it was in this capacity that author Rosemary Sutcliffe used him to inspire her classic tale <em><a href="http://books.google.co.uk/books?id=iEy1btLSKLAC&amp;printsec=frontcover&amp;source=gbs_ge_summary_r&amp;cad=0#v=onepage&amp;q&amp;f=false">The Eagle Of The Ninth</a> , </em>published in 1954, a must-read for anyone who hasn&#8217;t.</p>
<p>In actual fact, research has revealed that he was once sitting on a sphere as part of a Roman ornament. Than the original craftsman was extremely skilled but subsequent repairs after accidents were clumsier. And that, according to his location, he was probably awaiting being melted down for scrap.</p>
<p>Originally, my eagle had glorious great outspread wings, but no more. He is time-battered. But he has a circumspect air, as if really, it is all one could expect from life.</p>
<p>He has seen a rainy afternoon or two.</p>
<p>Here we stood, he and I, in a darkened room on a wet September afternoon. His attitude seemed to speak much louder than words. This is life, he said. You keep going, you tread each step, you serve your masters faithfully, spend years buried under ashes and lose a wing or two: and still, a kind of immortality can be yours.</p>
<p>With a wisdom borne of more than a millennium of experience, I would swear he was smiling.</p>
<p>Hello, Eagle, I said.</p>
<p>Hello, he replied companionably.</p>
<p>And then it was time to leave: to draw away from my eagle and trail reluctantly back to the gliding glass lift, leaving him amongst the coins and pots and tiles and remains of a city which died more than a thousand years ago. Time to come down from the mountain and rejoin life in the soggy streets of an English market town.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/8221/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/8221/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=8221&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://kateshrewsday.com/2012/09/24/my-battered-roman-eagle/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>53</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://kateshrewsday.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dsc_0240.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://kateshrewsday.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dsc_0240.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0240</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/5b7e170afcd4b88cc9db28c51ecabc44?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">kateshrewsday</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://kateshrewsday.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dsc_0240.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0240</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Technology Is Running Amok</title>
		<link>http://richarddaybell.wordpress.com/2012/09/24/technology-is-running-amok/</link>
		<comments>http://richarddaybell.wordpress.com/2012/09/24/technology-is-running-amok/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2012 17:42:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Richard Daybell</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Life Is (Fill in Blank)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fail Safe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fax]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fax machine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhone5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://richarddaybell.wordpress.com/?p=1487</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Apple&#8217;s iPhone5 went on sale last Friday and sold out within nanoseconds. It does wondrous things, I guess. It must, because 5 million people jumped right on it. It costs $649. We have a phone that&#8217;s attached to the wall. It lets you talk on it, that&#8217;s about all. We have a cellphone, too. I&#8217;m [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1487&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="LEFT"><span style="color:#000000;"><span style="font-size:medium;">Apple&#8217;s iPhone5 went on sale last Friday and sold out within nanoseconds. It does wondrous things, I guess. It must, because 5 million people jumped right on it. It <a href="http://richarddaybell.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/fax-machine1.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-1489" title="fax-machine1" src="http://richarddaybell.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/fax-machine1.jpg" alt="" width="250" height="233" /></a>costs $649. We have a phone that&#8217;s attached to the wall. It lets you talk on it, that&#8217;s about all. We have a cellphone, too. I&#8217;m not sure what all it does. It must not do much. It cost $14.99. Chances are I&#8217;ll never buy an Apple iPhone5. Technologically, I&#8217;m pretty far behind the curve. To give you an example, here&#8217;s a piece I wrote back in the 90&#8242;s about my first fax. I know, people usually write about first loves, first cars and first jobs, but when you&#8217;re hopelessly behind the curve . . .</span></span></p>
<p align="CENTER"><span style="color:#000000;"><span style="font-size:medium;"><strong>Fax Me the Pillow That You Dream On</strong></span></span></p>
<p align="LEFT"><span style="color:#000000;"><span style="font-size:medium;">Officially, it&#8217;s known as a facsimile communications machine. Those on more familiar terms with it call it a fax machine.</span></span></p>
<p align="LEFT"> <span style="color:#000000;"><span style="font-size:medium;">I prefer facsimile communications &#8212; it&#8217;s formal, cold and aloof &#8212; just the way I would like our relationship to remain.</span></span></p>
<p align="LEFT"> <span style="color:#000000;"><span style="font-size:medium;">Our relationship is new, and it&#8217;s more of a brief encounter. I recently, for the first time, sent a facsimile to someone. It&#8217;s worth noting that not only are a lot of people on a nickname basis with the thing, but they also have made a verb out of what was clearly intended to be a noun. It is important that every thinking person take a vow never, never to </span></span><span style="color:#000000;"><span style="font-size:medium;"><em>fax</em></span></span><span style="color:#000000;"><span style="font-size:medium;"> anything.</span></span></p>
<p align="LEFT"> <span style="color:#000000;"><span style="font-size:medium;">I don&#8217;t know if that someone to whom I sent the facsimile ever received it, but I did send it. I did it; it&#8217;s over; I can get on with my life. It was this someone, of course, who instigated the whole thing, suggesting that this particular document needed</span></span><span style="color:#000000;"><span style="font-size:medium;"> to be rushed enough not to trust it to the vagaries of the postal service. I myself happen to be a fan of postal delivery. You stick something in an envelope, slap a stamp on it, and a few days later, a real human being, beaming with pride, delivers it to its destination. It&#8217;s easy, it&#8217;s fun and it&#8217;s environmentally friendly.</span></span></p>
<p align="LEFT"> <span style="color:#000000;"><span style="font-size:medium;">After determining the location of the nearest facsimile communication device and preparing the document in question, I sat down with paper and pencil to list pros and cons, possible dangers inherent in the action, and penalties for lack of action. I could</span></span><span style="color:#000000;"><span style="font-size:medium;"> remain defiant &#8212; stick it in an envelope, slap a stamp on it, and let the chips fall where they may. That would have been a rational response, a consistent one, and the safe one. But as I prepared to lick the stamp, I noted that it portrayed tiny astronauts landing on a tiny moon. These brave explorers, these one-giant-leap-for-mankind heroes looked up at me as if to say &#8220;Wimp!&#8221;</span></span></p>
<p align="LEFT"> <span style="color:#000000;"><span style="font-size:medium;">So even though I deeply distrust and avoid anything invented after 1967, I decided to go for it. It was a moment filled with emotional stress; breaking a technological barrier usually is. For those of you who have yet to screw up your courage and try it, I am happy to report that the anticipation is worse than the experience itself.</span></span></p>
<p align="LEFT"> <span style="color:#000000;"><span style="font-size:medium;">I removed the document from its mailing envelope, unfolded it, and inserted it in the rather harmless looking machine (quicksand looks harmless, too). I picked up the receiver of a rather ordinary telephone, dialed my recipient&#8217;s number, and waited for my</span></span><span style="color:#000000;"><span style="font-size:medium;"> cue. The cue is an ear-shattering screech (just like, for those of you who remember the movie </span></span><span style="color:#000000;"><span style="font-size:medium;"><em>Fail Safe</em></span></span><span style="color:#000000;"><span style="font-size:medium;">, the screech that came to the President of the United States over the hot line, indicating that our inadvertently launched nuclear missiles had reached the USSR, and Moscow was no more).</span></span></p>
<p align="LEFT"> <span style="color:#000000;"><span style="font-size:medium;">Once the screech ends, you crawl out from under the desk, press a button, and the paper disappears into the machine. A minute later, it magically reappears. Presumably, the original has been divvied into millions of little molecules, each of which reprod</span></span><span style="color:#000000;"><span style="font-size:medium;">uces itself. The clones are then fed through the phone lines to be reassembled at the other end and the original is reassembled here. I don&#8217;t know. I do know the machine ironed the creases out of my document; I can vouch for nothing beyond that.</span></span></p>
<p align="LEFT"> <span style="color:#000000;"><span style="font-size:medium;">I may never send a facsimile again (and I will not fax) but it was worth experiencing. It fills one with that same heady exhilaration that diving to the ocean floor or landing on the moon must. And even though I may never send a facsimile again, I&#8217;m seriously considering giving the electric can opener a try. Technology is running amok, and it&#8217;s sweeping me along with it.</span></span></p>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1487&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://richarddaybell.wordpress.com/2012/09/24/technology-is-running-amok/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>76</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/ad148bba4951a54988dbcc9db70d51c6?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">rdaybell</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://richarddaybell.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/fax-machine1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">fax-machine1</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Song Sung Blue</title>
		<link>http://tinman18.wordpress.com/2012/09/24/song-sung-blue/</link>
		<comments>http://tinman18.wordpress.com/2012/09/24/song-sung-blue/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2012 17:28:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Tinman</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Daily Post 2012]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[How do you categorize this?]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[View from the Side]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[postaday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the blues]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tinman18.wordpress.com/?p=10284</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Sidey&#8217;s Weekend Theme is &#8220;blue&#8221;, so here is Tinman&#8217;s guide to one of the most famous of all music genres&#8230;. ***************************************************** The first requirement of being a blues singer is that you woke up this morning. Of course, most of us did, but we don’t feel the need to complain about it. Your next problem [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=10284&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em><a href="http://viewfromtheside.wordpress.com/">Sidey&#8217;s</a> Weekend Theme is &#8220;blue&#8221;, so here is Tinman&#8217;s guide to one of the most famous of all music genres&#8230;.</em></p>
<p>*****************************************************</p>
<p>The first requirement of being a blues singer is that you woke up this morning. Of course, most of us did, but we don’t feel the need to complain about it. Your next problem could be anything &#8211; your woman could have left you (the Lovesick Blues) you could have a hangover from last night’s pub-crawl (the 12-Bar Blues) or you might be tired after the walk uphill home (the Hill Street Blues). This problem will form the second line of your song.</p>
<p>In case your audience don’t get it, the first and second lines are then sung again, before the verse ends with one line summing up just how bad the situation is. An example would be “Woke up this mornin’/Found ma woman gone/woke up this mornin’/found ma woman gone/Now I ain’t got no-one/to put ma dinner on.”</p>
<p>It is important to note the use of the word “woman”. As a blues singer you are never left by your girl (that’s boy-bands), your honey (that’s Bobby Goldsboro) or your doll (that’s just weird). You will certainly never be left by your wife, because you won’t have one.</p>
<p>All blues numbers have the same tune. This is a golden rule. The sole optional amendment is that a harmonica, the musical equivalent of nails on a blackboard, is sometimes thrown in, so that the listener’s agony can match that of the singer.</p>
<p>This singer’s name will not be something like, say, Julian. No, blues singers have names like Silly Hair Jones, Bicycle-Pump Wilson or Old Yeller Jackson, who got the name not because he was a terrible singer, but simply because he was an old geezer.</p>
<p>It is the only occupation in which you can call someone “Fats” without them getting offended.</p>
<p>The typical blues singer lives to be about 120, singing night after night about their considerably more than fifty shades of blue.</p>
<p>There is only one thing that they are afraid of, and that is happiness. Nothing can kill a blues career quicker than to wake up one morning, and find that things are good.</p>
<p>Coz there ain’t no cure for the Funtime Blues.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/10284/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/10284/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=10284&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tinman18.wordpress.com/2012/09/24/song-sung-blue/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>23</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/9f2e67f6f0a87bc6397711a76de06c77?s=96&#38;d=retro&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tinman18</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>\&#8221;The Landscape Flowed Away, Back to Its Source.\&#8221;</title>
		<link>http://gerryco23.wordpress.com/2012/09/24/on-offas-dyke-the-landscape-flowed-away-back-to-its-source/</link>
		<comments>http://gerryco23.wordpress.com/2012/09/24/on-offas-dyke-the-landscape-flowed-away-back-to-its-source/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2012 09:28:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Gerry</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Places]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bronze Age]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Clwyd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Clwydian Range]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[history]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Iron Age]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Offa's Dyke]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Penycloddiau]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wales]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[walks]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://gerryco23.wordpress.com/?p=11841</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The weather map in the morning paper said it all: one oval isobar, a lazy ridge of high pressure lapping at the shores of the British Isles. Nothing like it for the whole of this damp, drab summer. Early on, with the dog in the dog in the park, there had been frost, now the [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=11841&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://gerryco23.wordpress.com/2012/09/24/on-offas-dyke-the-landscape-flowed-away-back-to-its-source/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>34</slash:comments>
		<georss:point>53.410777 -2.977838</georss:point>
		<geo:lat>53.410777</geo:lat>
		<geo:long>-2.977838</geo:long>
		<media:thumbnail url="http://gerryco23.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/offa-5.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://gerryco23.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/offa-5.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Offa 5</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/4db4088fb4054ae42ae74053033a5ff7?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F1.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gerryco23</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gerryco23.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/offa-1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Offa 1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gerryco23.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/offa13.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Offa13</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gerryco23.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/offa-2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Offa 2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gerryco23.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/offa-8.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Offa 8</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gerryco23.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/offa-3.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Offa 3</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gerryco23.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/offa11.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Offa11</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gerryco23.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/offa-4.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Offa 4</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gerryco23.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/penycloddiau-hillfort-2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Penycloddiau Hillfort 2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gerryco23.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/offa-5.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Offa 5</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gerryco23.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/offa-7.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Offa 7</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gerryco23.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/offas-mercia.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Offa&#039;s Mercia</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gerryco23.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/offa-coin.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Offa coin</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gerryco23.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/gold-imitation-dinar-of-offa.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Gold imitation dinar of Offa</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gerryco23.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/offa-9.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Offa 9</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gerryco23.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/offa10.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Offa10</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gerryco23.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/offa12.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Offa12</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gerryco23.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/offa-6.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Offa 6</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>There\&#8217;s Something About Mr. Weebles</title>
		<link>http://fearnoweebles.wordpress.com/2012/09/21/theres-something-about-mr-weebles/</link>
		<comments>http://fearnoweebles.wordpress.com/2012/09/21/theres-something-about-mr-weebles/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2012 23:30:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Madame Weebles</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Random thoughts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Badass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cancer blows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[What the fuck]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fearnoweebles.wordpress.com/?p=1291</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[You may have read this already&#8212;I linked to it recently, and some of you may have read it when I originally posted it back in April.  In any case, I&#8217;m reposting it with an addendum. It was one year ago today that Mr. Weebles finished radiation and chemotherapy.  He is one of the most extraordinary [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1291&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em><strong>You may have read this already&#8212;I linked to it recently, and some of you may have read it when I originally posted it back in April.  In any case, I&#8217;m reposting it with an addendum.</p>
<p>It was one year ago today that Mr. Weebles finished radiation and chemotherapy.  He is one of the most extraordinary people I have ever had the privilege to know.</strong></em><br />
&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;-<br />
This may be my very last blog entry because Mr. Weebles may kill me after he reads it. He&#8217;s a private guy, and he probably won&#8217;t love that I&#8217;m devoting an entire entry to him. But I&#8217;m doing it anyway. (What can I say, honey, you knew what you were getting into when you married me.)</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve mentioned Mr. Weebles in many entries here, and you&#8217;ve even seen comments from the man himself. Now I want to tell you more about him.</p>
<p>The first thing you need to know about Mr. Weebles that he is truly awesome. He doesn&#8217;t even know how awesome he is, which makes him even <em>more</em> awesome.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ve been married for almost 6 years&#8212;our anniversary is nigh&#8212;and we&#8217;ve been together for about 8 years total. Before I met Mr. Weebles, I had pretty rotten luck with relationships. During my dating life I encountered textbook examples of almost every disorder listed in the DSM-IV.</p>
<p>And because dating in NYC is only slightly less painful than tweezing your legs, I decided to cast as wide a net as possible to meet guys. I went online. That&#8217;s how I met Mr. Weebles. In fact, I saw his profile and wrote down his profile name so that I could write to him. But he beat me to it&#8212;I got a message from him the next day. And that&#8217;s how it started.</p>
<p>I knew pretty quickly that he was The One. Many, many years ago I asked my mother, &#8220;How do you know when a guy is the right one?&#8221; And she said, &#8220;You&#8217;ll just <em>know</em>.&#8221; At the time I thought it was a load of horse shit (sorry Mom), but of course she was right. With Mr. Weebles, I just <em>knew</em>.</p>
<p>He and I are very similar&#8212;sometimes when two people are so much alike it can cause friction, but in our case it&#8217;s just comical. One of us will say, &#8220;I want to use the brain today, you got to use it yesterday!&#8221; because we finish each other&#8217;s sentences and thoughts so often that it creeps me out in the best possible way. We get annoyed by the same things (although to be fair, he doesn&#8217;t get nearly as annoyed as I do), our neuroses compliment each other&#8217;s, we care about the same things, and we have the same sensibilities and opinions about how life should be.</p>
<p>He puts up with my crankiness. He tolerates the fact that I&#8217;m a Yankee fan (he is not). He takes it in stride when I&#8217;m randomly bitchy. He humors me when I do silly things. He talks me off the ledge when I&#8217;m really upset or worried. And I&#8217;m very lucky to have found a guy who can cook, is handy around the house, takes out the trash more often than I do, and often gets my coffee ready for me in the morning when I&#8217;m running late. Plus, he&#8217;s 6&#8217;3&#8243; so he can reach stuff on the top shelves.</p>
<p>Mr. Weebles is a very funny guy. He doesn&#8217;t just make me laugh&#8212;he makes me <em>cackle</em>. I don&#8217;t know how he thinks of half the stuff he says. His brain just works so quickly, and it works in amazing ways. He&#8217;ll make some off-the-cuff comment about something on television or whatever, and invariably it will be the cleverest, funniest thing I ever heard. (Until the next time he says something clever and funny.) I always wonder, &#8220;How does he DO that??&#8221; And he has one of the most creative minds of anyone I know. If you could attach a megaphone to his head and hear him think of things, you&#8217;d laugh your ass off at how funny he is and how many great ideas he has.</p>
<p>He&#8217;s the kindest, most decent soul I&#8217;ve ever known. I don&#8217;t mean that in a treacly sort of way. I mean that he is truly the best person I know. He has an extremely honest, caring, and thoughtful nature. There is more integrity in his toenail clippings than many people have in their entire bodies. And he has a great deal of compassion. Stories about injustice upset him deeply. He&#8217;s far more savvy about world events and politics than I am, so he knows about all the awful things going on here and around the world. When he hears about the latest corruption scandal or about people who are being mistreated in some way, he gets riled up to the extent that you&#8217;d think it happened to him personally. And I mean that as a compliment; it&#8217;s one thing to think, &#8220;Gee, what a shame,&#8221; but it&#8217;s another thing to contemplate how these miscarriages of justice affect us all somehow. Mr. Weebles does that. If he were ever to inflict pain on someone, it would be because that person deserved it in spades.</p>
<p>But the acid test, of course, for determining whether people are truly good, is seeing them interact with animals. When Mr. Weebles and I first started dating, I had a cat whom I&#8217;ll call Kitty Emeritus because she&#8217;s in the Great Catnip Patch in the Sky now (although she never did like catnip so I&#8217;m not sure how thrilled she is about that). Kitty Emeritus was a fearless cat with a ridiculously well-developed sense of entitlement. You had to work hard to impress her. She was friendly and tolerant of every human I ever saw her with, and she usually gravitated towards men (I was so proud of her for that). But she <em>loved</em> Mr. Weebles. And the three cats we have now&#8212;the Weeblettes&#8212;also love him like crazy. They climb all over him and follow him around the house. And as anyone who has ever had a cat knows, when you have the love and trust of a cat, it&#8217;s because you&#8217;ve <em>earned</em> it. Mr. Weebles has earned it and then some. He&#8217;s the best Kitty Daddy a feline could hope for.</p>
<p>But wait! There&#8217;s more!</p>
<p>I learned that the awesome Mr. Weebles is more extraordinary than I even knew already. I found out in a way that people shouldn&#8217;t have to find out, but sometimes these things happen.</p>
<p>Last year Mr. Weebles was diagnosed with cancer, at the age of 40. Ironically&#8212;and cruelly&#8212;this cancer was a long-term side effect of the radiation treatment he received for an entirely different type of cancer when he was 21. Last summer he went through surgery, radiation (different type of radiation than the first time, fortunately), and chemotherapy, and now he&#8217;s doing great with an excellent prognosis. Overall it could have been much, much worse, but it still sucked pretty royally. For those of you who have cared for sick loved ones, you know how awful it is to see them suffer. It was brutal, knowing there wasn&#8217;t much I could do while Mr. Weebles went through treatment. All I could do was focus on the light at the end of the tunnel and keep him as comfortable and as stress free as possible in the meantime.</p>
<p>What I discovered, though, was that Mr. Weebles is one tough hombre. Even tougher than I thought. He&#8217;s fucking badass. The radiation and chemo regimen he endured was nasty. He hated going through treatment, but he did it. And he did it with class and dignity.</p>
<p>If I were in his shoes, I would have been spitting fire. Having cancer? <em>Again</em>? At the age of <em>40</em>? Because of the treatment for the first cancer? I would have been mad at the entire world. I would have been a raging, self-pitying, sobbing basketcase and I would have been mean as hell.</p>
<p>But not Mr. Weebles. He was very upset, of course. And as far as I&#8217;m concerned he would have had every right to be a raging, self-pitying, sobbing basketcase himself. But he just has a different perspective on things&#8212;maybe because he&#8217;s been through this before, maybe not. Doesn&#8217;t matter. He just did what he had to do. And he was still polite to everyone. He was like a cowboy who rides into town, gets into a vicious shootout with the bad guys, drives them out of town, and then tips his hat, riddled with bullet holes, saying, &#8220;Bye, folks, be seein&#8217; ya.&#8221; Fucking badass.</p>
<p>Watching him go through such an ordeal gave me an even greater appreciation for him and everything he&#8217;s about. I&#8217;m insanely proud of him. He inspires me to be a better human being. The world needs more people like Mr. Weebles.</p>
<p>If I could just get him to wear a combat uniform or some sort of Victorian gentleman&#8217;s outfit, he&#8217;d be perfect.</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://fearnoweebles.wordpress.com/category/life/'>Life</a>, <a href='http://fearnoweebles.wordpress.com/category/random-thoughts/'>Random thoughts</a> Tagged: <a href='http://fearnoweebles.wordpress.com/tag/badass/'>Badass</a>, <a href='http://fearnoweebles.wordpress.com/tag/cancer-blows/'>Cancer blows</a>, <a href='http://fearnoweebles.wordpress.com/tag/love/'>Love</a>, <a href='http://fearnoweebles.wordpress.com/tag/what-the-fuck/'>What the fuck</a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1291&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://fearnoweebles.wordpress.com/2012/09/21/theres-something-about-mr-weebles/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>186</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/0bc7385d57296e0a84ffcfa6067744c4?s=96&#38;d=monsterid&#38;r=X" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jweebles</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Buyxiety</title>
		<link>http://j-bo.net/2012/09/23/buyxiety/</link>
		<comments>http://j-bo.net/2012/09/23/buyxiety/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2012 22:43:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>J-Bo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anxiety]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[career]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[decisions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finances]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[interior design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[neuroticism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[paintings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quarter-life crisis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[work]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://j-bo.net/2012/09/23/buyxiety/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Buyxiety: Part 2 in a 3-Part Series of my Anxiety. I get extremely anxious when I buy things. Unavoidable and expensive purchases such as car repairs, cat vaccinations, and tickets to ride a Greyhound bus across the country make me nauseous. This means I’m good at saving money. I buy things used, never spend more than $15 on [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=565&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Buyxiety: Part 2 in a 3-Part Series of my Anxiety.</p>
<p>I get extremely anxious when I buy things. Unavoidable and expensive purchases such as <a href="http://j-bo.net/2012/08/19/a-tale-of-two-couches/">car repairs</a>, cat vaccinations, and <a href="http://j-bo.net/2012/07/22/cincinnati-homeboy-and-the-traveling-salesman-2/">tickets to ride a Greyhound bus across the country</a> make me nauseous.</p>
<p>This means I’m good at saving money. I buy things used, never spend more than $15 on any article of clothing, and am driving the same ’98 Mazda I’ve had since before I got my license.</p>
<p>This also means I’m terrible at spending money without convulsing at the register and succumbing to fits of buyer’s remorse that leave me debilitated on my bedroom floor for half a day.</p>
<p>Recently I’ve been trying to decorate my new office at work.</p>
<p>“I bet you have a lot of stuff in your car to bring in,” my boss said on my first day.</p>
<p>Uhhh, not exactly. (You might recall that I’ve spent the past year <a href="http://j-bo.net/2011/07/16/pee-spraying-babies-and-caricatures-of-the-elderly-my-volunteer-adventures-continue/">getting peed on by babies in the slums of India</a>, <a href="http://j-bo.net/2011/11/08/top-14-signs-its-time-to-quit-a-therapy-start-up-and-reasons-you-should-look-up-your-bosss-public-records-before-accepting-a-job/">unknowingly working for a drug dealer</a>, and <a href="http://j-bo.net/2012/04/18/adorable-dog-that-helps-kids-read-aka-my-arch-nemesis/">begging to be allowed to conduct therapy sessions in storage closets</a>. Beginning a collection of office decorations had not ever crossed my mind. Not once).</p>
<p>My co-worker with the Hollywood-themed office came into my office the next day and closed the door behind her. “I think it’s so great you’re here,” she said. “But I just think you should know that the counselor who had this office before you worked here for five years and killed himself two months ago. So this office has just been really empty and sad since then. So it’s going to be so much less depressing for everyone once you start to decorate it and really make it your own.”</p>
<p>Holy. Shit. Not good news for someone who believes that <a href="http://j-bo.net/2012/08/30/fresh-start/">walls can have unresolved feelings</a>.</p>
<p>That night I was browsing paintings on Etsy and wondering why everything cost a month’s-worth of rent until I realized that I could filter my search by price. Then I wondered why everything in my price range looked like something a five-year-old could draw with their non-dominant hand.</p>
<p>I walked out of my early doctor’s appointment the next morning right into a random art sale filled with really cool paintings. It felt like it was meant to be. But they were a bit pricey by my standards, seeing as the only painting I’d ever purchased before was at Hobby Lobby for $6.</p>
<p>A guy who worked there came up to where I stood, paralyzed with indecision. “If you get home and decide you don’t like it,” he said, “You can bring it back for a full refund.”</p>
<p>That was enough for me to finally decide to get two. “How long do I have to bring them back?” I asked as I was digitally signing my receipt.</p>
<p>“Twenty-four hours,” he said. I froze mid-signature. What if I didn’t wake up in time tomorrow? What if I went to get them out of my office late tonight and couldn’t get into my building? What if I damaged them taking them to or from my car? What if I had a terrible, debilitating accident in the next twenty-four hours and couldn’t return them and also couldn’t earn any money for the rest of my life?</p>
<p>“Have a great day!” he said, handing me my copy of the receipt that had printed out with only half my signature on it.</p>
<p>“I’ve made a horrible financial decision!” I shouted to Doug as I walked through the door. “We can’t eat for two months!”</p>
<p>He didn’t seem too concerned but I felt the need to justify anyway. “But I’ll have these paintings in my office for the rest of my professional life,” I said. “So it’s an investment, right?”</p>
<p>“Not really,” he said. “Do you know what ‘investment’ means?”</p>
<p>“Aaaaaaaaah,” I moaned, wrapping my arms around my chest, pulling my hair around my chin, and rocking back and fourth to self-soothe.</p>
<p>I spent the rest of the morning looking up what my paintings cost on other web sites and calculating what the additional costs of shipping and framing would be to convince myself that what I paid was actually a steal, considering mine came with high-quality frames and no glass so therefore no glare, and wasn’t no glare worth an extra dollar a year (if I divided the extra cost of mine by the number of years I will potentially work in an office)?</p>
<p>I hung them in my office that afternoon. But then I thought: What if they are <em>too </em>fancy for an office setting? And I’m just that snotty girl whose paintings are just a little too fancy?</p>
<p>I walked down the hall pretending I was on my way to the bathroom so I could peak into other peoples’ offices. Nobody else’s paintings had frames, they were just canvases- probably that they painted themselves! What if it was universally understood that frames are for living rooms, not offices, and I’m the only person who didn’t know this, and now I have created an awkward living room/office hybrid?</p>
<p>I went back to my desk and did a Google image search of “office paintings.” A-ha! One of the first pictures that came up was of an office with framed paintings at least as fancy as mine. But then I clicked on the picture and realized it was one of the offices in the White House. Dammit!</p>
<p>Then I closed out of the internet entirely because I started worrying that someone would walk by and see me Googling “office paintings,” and my computer is super slow at closing windows so by the time someone stepped inside my office it would be too late.</p>
<p>By the time I woke up the next morning, the 24-hour mark had passed. I breathed a sigh of relief that there was no decision left to be made. I went to work, looked up at my paintings, and smiled. I really like them.</p>
<p><a href="http://jbodotnet.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/frogs2.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-573" title="VLUU L200  / Samsung L200" src="http://jbodotnet.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/frogs2.jpg?w=524&h=393" alt="" width="524" height="393" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://jbodotnet.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/long-painting.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-574" title="VLUU L200  / Samsung L200" src="http://jbodotnet.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/long-painting.jpg?w=393&h=524" alt="" width="393" height="524" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://j-bo.net/2012/09/11/an-exploration-of-my-neuroticism-part-1-of-a-3-part-series/">Part 1 of 3: Catxiety</a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/565/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/565/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=565&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://j-bo.net/2012/09/23/buyxiety/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>30</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/56731d841905e6ebd12d938faac012fb?s=96&#38;d=wavatar&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">juliaboriss</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jbodotnet.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/frogs2.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">VLUU L200  / Samsung L200</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jbodotnet.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/long-painting.jpg?w=768" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">VLUU L200  / Samsung L200</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Monday Musings &amp; Motivations — Mettle</title>
		<link>http://brigittebanter.com/2012/09/24/monday-musings-and-motivations-mettle/</link>
		<comments>http://brigittebanter.com/2012/09/24/monday-musings-and-motivations-mettle/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2012 13:32:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Brigitte</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Other Musings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing & Writers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Non-Fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Literary Ramblings and Thoughts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Motivations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Love and life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Good Things]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[peace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mettle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[great leaders]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kindness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[success]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nelson Mandela]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pablo Picasso]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[free thinker]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brigittebanter.com/?p=2142</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I’ve always loved that word:  Mettle. It means this:  A person’s ability to cope well with difficulties or to face a demanding situation in a spirited and resilient way. I don’t think we use it enough.  We toss around words like amazing, phenomenal, awesome to describe anything from a scientist or physician’s ability to discover [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2142&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I’ve always loved that word:  Mettle.</p>
<p>It means this:  <em>A person’s ability to cope well with difficulties or to face a demanding situation in a spirited and resilient way.</em></p>
<div id="attachment_2144" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 129px"><a href="http://brigittebanter.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/399px-kim_kardashian_4.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-2144  " title="399px-Kim_Kardashian_4" src="http://brigittebanter.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/399px-kim_kardashian_4.jpg?w=119&h=180" alt="" width="119" height="180" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Omg, I&#8217;m amazing. My clothes are amazing, my hair&#8230;<br />You may be a very nice person, I don&#8217;t know you. But amazing? Hmmm.</p></div>
<p>I don’t think we use it enough.  We toss around words like amazing, phenomenal, awesome to describe anything from a scientist or physician’s ability to discover life-changing/saving discoveries and medicines to a reality show star’s conversation or hairstyle.  Their meanings have become as mundane and average as the latest YouTube sensation &#8212; here today, gone tomorrow, until the next one comes along.  But for a moment, they’re all AMAZING, PHENOMENAL, AWESOME, PERFECT with plenty of omg’s and lol’s and lmao’s surrounding them.  Sigh.</p>
<p>As a lover and writer of words, I try to use those adjectives sparingly.  I want someone or something to <strong><em>earn</em></strong> their meaning. I’ve said it before and I’ll say it again:  Words have weight.  They matter.  And once they’re out there, they’re out there &#8212; no take backs, baby.</p>
<div id="attachment_2146" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 150px"><a href="http://brigittebanter.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/jean-marc_nattier_003.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-2146  " title="Jean-Marc_Nattier_003" src="http://brigittebanter.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/jean-marc_nattier_003.jpg?w=140&h=189" alt="" width="140" height="189" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Proving her mettle wearing a corset that restricted breathing whilst sitting and playing an instrument.</p></div>
<p>By the 18th century the word “mettle” (derived from the other one, “metal,” both being interchanged to mean that “hard, shiny substance” ) was being used to describe someone’s character, “the stuff we are made of.”  It appeared in <em>The Free Thinker</em> in 1719 in this phrase:  &#8220;I like the Lady&#8217;s Wit and Mettle.&#8221;</p>
<p>If someone described me that way, I’d be thrilled.</p>
<p><strong>Proving Your Mettle</strong></p>
<p>I come from humble beginnings, I suppose it was middle-class.  But, most everyone around us was the same way.  I don’t know how my parents were able to raise four children on their income.  I’ve asked my mother that before and she always says the same thing:  <em>You just do what you have to do.  You make the best of what you have until you can do better</em>.</p>
<p>My parents were creative, artists of sorts, but they didn’t make money at being artists.  My mother could make any kind of clothing, sometimes from cutting patterns out of newspaper.  My father could make furniture, recover it, reuse it.  Paint &#8212; not just the porch or house but paintings.  They could fix things. Grow things. There wasn’t a plumber to call when something broke.  It may not have worked perfectly, but it worked and we made it.   <strong>Mettle</strong>.</p>
<div id="attachment_2147" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 410px"><a href="http://brigittebanter.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/amazingpeoplewithmettle.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-2147" title="AmazingPeopleWithMettle" src="http://brigittebanter.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/amazingpeoplewithmettle.jpg" alt="" width="400" height="168" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Just a few people who used their mettle. Pretty amazing.</p></div>
<p>When I think about all the accomplishments I’ve achieved in my life, those that mean the most are the ones that I worked my ass off to achieve, usually through not so great circumstances.  But there’s something about doing that &#8212; working through adversities and reaching a goal despite all the odds.  It <strong><em>feels</em></strong> good.</p>
<p>I don’t have any stories of walking uphill through twelve feet of snow.  I was fed, sheltered, clothed.  I was never hungry or cold, but I think my parents went through times I can’t imagine.  They lived much more simply than they raised us.</p>
<p>My mother told me that when she and my father lived in Germany they lived in one room.  Had to heat it with a coal stove.  People had just a few items of clothing &#8212; everyday clothes and Sunday best.  Maybe two pairs of shoes.  She also said they were insanely happy.  Strange how that works.  Imagine not having so many choices; that must take some stress off of you.</p>
<div id="attachment_2149" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 250px"><a href="http://brigittebanter.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/happy-hubby-19501.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-2149 " title="happy-hubby-19501" src="http://brigittebanter.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/happy-hubby-19501.jpg?w=240&h=190" alt="" width="240" height="190" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">I&#8217;m not one to complain, honey but&#8230;..</p></div>
<p>I’m not saying I’d want to experience those kinds of times.  The “good ole days” weren’t so good for women and minorities.  But people survived through much more adversity and  conditions/beginnings that we can fathom today.</p>
<p>Their mettle is what got them through.  And we still see that today, people who overcome enormous adversity and achieve greatness.  And the definition of “greatness” is different for everyone.</p>
<p>Every generation wants something better for the next one.  My parents taught me what mettle meant.  You have to earn respect.  You have to work hard for what you want.  No one gives it to you and life isn’t fair &#8212; it doesn’t owe you a thing.  Sometimes you eat the bear and sometimes the bear eats you.  Life’s messy.  It’s your mettle that gets you through the worst of it.</p>
<p>I wonder what we’re teaching the next generation.</p>
<p><strong>Then and Now</strong></p>
<div id="attachment_2151" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 190px"><a href="http://brigittebanter.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/tolerance1.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-2151  " title="tolerance1" src="http://brigittebanter.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/tolerance1.jpg?w=180&h=179" alt="" width="180" height="179" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">We&#8217;re kind of all in this together.</p></div>
<p>The generation now has much to work through in order to prove their mettle as well and I believe most are doing a good job of it.  They’re much more tolerant than past generations.  I think they realize the enormity of what faces them.  They’re coming up with new ways of learning and taking care of our planet.  They care about what’s going on in the world instead of their own little bubble.</p>
<p>They have access to it &#8212; the world, more than we ever did.  We are learning from them.  I think there’s so much goodness and openness going on now than ever before.  Hopefully, they’ll take a few cues from us as well, the previous generations &#8212; of what’s important and what’s not.  It’s not all reality television and mindless, shallow thinking.</p>
<p>Despite all the doom and gloom we hear, we’re living better than before.  Ask your parents or grandparents.  I think most of us have it pretty good, probably better than our parents/grandparents did.  We have the generation before us to thank for that.  They proved their mettle and now we have to pass that on to the next generation.</p>
<p>If my legacy was “she had wit and mettle,” that would be a fine one indeed.  Because mettle encapsulates a lot:  integrity, strength, purpose, character <strong><em>and</em></strong> having a sense of humor through it all.   Not taking yourself too seriously.  To me, that&#8217;s success, amazing, great.  If you think of all the great leaders, philosophers, scientists, physicians &#8212; those people who made our lives and world better &#8212; they had and have that.  Those who have that mettle are the ones I look up to.</p>
<p>I’m not sure what sparked the idea for this post and although it may not be amazing or phenomenal, it’s not so bad.</p>
<p>I’ll take not so bad over nothing special any day.  <img src='http://s0.wp.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif' alt=':)' class='wp-smiley' /> .</p>
<p>Happy Monday everyone.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">***</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">Read more Monday Musings <a href="http://brigittebanter.com/feel-good-stuff/" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2142/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2142/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2142&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://brigittebanter.com/2012/09/24/monday-musings-and-motivations-mettle/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>128</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://brigittebanter.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/le-reve-1932-by-pablo-picasso.jpg?w=127" />
		<media:content url="http://brigittebanter.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/le-reve-1932-by-pablo-picasso.jpg?w=127" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Le-reve-1932 by Pablo Picasso</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/673c0b8d0f8443cf1ba451650aad9658?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">brigitte622</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://brigittebanter.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/399px-kim_kardashian_4.jpg?w=199" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">399px-Kim_Kardashian_4</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://brigittebanter.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/jean-marc_nattier_003.jpg?w=223" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Jean-Marc_Nattier_003</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://brigittebanter.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/amazingpeoplewithmettle.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">AmazingPeopleWithMettle</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://brigittebanter.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/happy-hubby-19501.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">happy-hubby-19501</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://brigittebanter.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/tolerance1.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tolerance1</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Failing at Music–Succeeding at Life: Part Two</title>
		<link>http://cafecasey.com/2012/09/23/failing-at-music-succeeding-at-life-part-two/</link>
		<comments>http://cafecasey.com/2012/09/23/failing-at-music-succeeding-at-life-part-two/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2012 11:20:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>cafecasey</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[satire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[teaching]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chicago Symphony Orchestra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chris Botti]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eastman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eastman School of Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Johannes Brahms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sibley Music Library]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[University of Rochester]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cafecasey.com/?p=210</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#160; I wanted to be a professional musician, but I did not have the chops. So I began my evil plan. I had two choices for college. One was an Ivy League college that I didn’t exactly like and, as it turned out, didn’t exactly like me.  The second was the University of Rochester in [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=210&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><div id="attachment_255" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://cafecasey.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/screen-shot-2012-09-23-at-7-17-14-am.png"><img class="size-medium wp-image-255" title="Screen Shot 2012-09-23 at 7.17.14 AM" src="http://cafecasey.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/screen-shot-2012-09-23-at-7-17-14-am.png?w=300&h=233" alt="" width="300" height="233" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Eastman Theatre<br />[image: akustiks.com]</p></div>I wanted to be a professional musician, but I did not have the chops. So I began my evil plan.</p>
<p>I had two choices for college. One was an Ivy League college that I didn’t exactly like and, as it turned out, didn’t exactly like me.  The second was the University of Rochester in upstate New York. It was filled with friendly people who let me stay with them for a weekend and drink&#8211;much better marketing.  And this school <em>just so happened</em> to have a music school attached to it—the Eastman School of Music.  It was a postern of fate.</p>
<p>Had I told anyone—a single soul—about my plan to attend the Eastman School of Music they’d have committed me on the spot<em>.</em>  Eastman was one of the Big Three. It required some element of musical preparation or training. But I was going to take it completely off guard.</p>
<p>In order to go to the Eastman School of Music, one had to apply, audition, and be accepted, which presumably meant it was necessary to be a master of at least <em>some</em> particular instrument. Those who went to Eastman not only started their training two years prior to conception, they practiced every day for twenty-six hours, forgoing even basic nutrition for music, which they considered sufficient nourishment for the soul.  They talked about Beethoven incessantly and threw birthday parties for Mozart instead of for themselves.  Their idea of a fraternity party was to get together at night and contemplate Brahms some more over a bowl of chips that had grown stale because everyone was too busy discussing Brahms  to actually eat them.</p>
<p>I, on the other hand, could neither read nor hand-write music—and as a result, I spent a great deal of my time cheating my way through like an illiterate person reading road signs.  Every once in a while, you get one very, very wrong.  “Sorry, chief—that said ‘one-way.’”</p>
<p>This wasn’t going to be easy—disguising myself as a musician and getting into what I still did not realize was the premiere classical conservatory in the nation. I would need a loophole, and that&#8217;s just what I found.  Rochester students could take music courses at Eastman.  What if I just registered for <em>all the good music courses?</em>  Eastman students were there, and the classes commingled.  I could take almost the same classes with the Future Musicians of America, join bands with them, discuss Brahms with them, scoff at the poor slobs majoring in pre-med, economics, and history, and be musically, intellectually, and socially superior to the entire universe.  And I wouldn’t even have to be properly trained—it was a win-win situation by any stretch of the imagination.</p>
<p>Thus, I registered for classes at the Eastman School of Music through the regular university. Totally legal. I studied all the theory I could muster and passed the exam through rote memorization, because that’s what academic people without “proper musical training” do.  Then—on the day of truth—I showed up for my audition.</p>
<p>I was playing what some would consider a challenging piece—Mozart’s Clarinet Concerto.  I couldn’t actually <em>read</em> the score, so I bought a record—the Chicago Symphony Orchestra conducted by Sir George Solti—and read alongside the record—sort of a closed caption for the musically impaired.   I practiced for the entire summer before on my borrowed clarinet, because I was neither good enough nor well-funded enough to own one, and went off to college.</p>
<p>Audition day. Imagine the panel of musical geniuses waiting to hear the next lead of the Boston Philharmonic. Imagine that they have just endured a thousand auditions—the next Yanni, the next Yo Yo Ma, next Chris Botti…and then…there…was me.</p>
<p>Twenty years later, I am truly remorseful for the sorrow I inflicted on these men and I include them in my daily prayers.  I ask the Lord for forgiveness and to make their lives better in some subtle way.  If I were Jewish, I’d track them all down on Yom Kippur and beg them to accept my apology outright, because after hearing me, they were never quite the same.  I’m convinced that I took a little piece of music from each and every one of their souls and trampled on it like Marilyn Manson at a Boston Pops concert.</p>
<p>At the end of what they must have thought was a Candid Camera prank or a CIA torture training mission (miraculously cut short because God Himself sped down into that hallowed hall, and broke my clarinet in half), all the men could do was look straight ahead, pause, and say, “So, you like Sir George Solti.”</p>
<p>I steeped myself in everything Eastman. I laughed at the Beethoven jokes; I walked laps around the Gilded-Age auditorium. I went to concerts.  I breathed in the stale air of the practice rooms.  Even though it took me a 45 minute ride on the blue bus, I took a work-study job at the Sibley Music Library, where I began cataloguing music scores for less money than I would have made in a prison laundry, getting highly indignant—alongside the other Brahms lovers—when people misalphabetized the Russian version of Shostakovich  and put Von Weber under “w.”</p>
<p>After that, it took me exactly two weeks to flunk entirely out of the music program, which I <em>still</em> did not realize was <em>the</em> best program in the nation.  I called my former band director who had inspired me to tell him I was struggling at Eastman and I feared I most probably would not succeed.</p>
<p>“YOU DID WHAT?” He didn&#8217;t sound impressed.  And so I came clean. I divulged the whole story—of my sneaking onto the “Eastman” rosters under cover of darkness, of my torturing the great musicians on the panel taking musical years off their lives. How I got a 40 on my first assignment, major scales, and a 20 on minor scales, and that was only because the infinitely good Dr. Harrison said, “You didn’t <em>earn</em> that 20—but I can see that you tried <em>really hard</em>.”</p>
<p>In the end, the stress got me sick.  I was sick for a solid month. I shuffled back and forth to health services.  I commiserated with my yet-to-be-premed friends, with whom I now spoke since Brahms was giving me the cold shoulder, and I plugged through the rest of first semester before finally admitting I was not musician material.</p>
<p>The discipline of “proper training” made music seem more like another aspect of calculus than the soul and essence of life.  It became a self-torture I couldn’t stop—a train wreck—the part of a mountain climb where it seems that the summit is right around the corner, but when you pass the next tree, you see the ridgeline open up and reveal it to be so far in the distance that you’re not sure you want to press on.  When you ultimately decide to continue and you arrive at the next point where you thought the summit would be, it turns out to be an illusion once again.  I was left with the sinking feeling of defeat and disappointment, where the thing I thought I loved—the passion in my soul, turned out to be one giant red herring.</p>
<p>I didn’t even get into the lowest of piano courses—the one <em>everyone</em> takes.  My audition turned out to be surprisingly similar to my clarinet audition.  The professor said, “Very good,” when I played the Mozart, and then, “Read this,” handing me some Chopin that looked like Chinese Braille.  Game over.</p>
<p>I was forced to finish that semester in clarinet.  I continued to travel over to Eastman to study with my personal graduate student, Michelle, who was undoubtedly in trouble for something and had to redeem herself by teaching me.  I sincerely hope she is not working in a sub-par elementary music program soon to be cut.  She was an angel.  She made me feel good.</p>
<p>I played one semester in the River Campus Symphonic Wind Ensemble, being too ignorant to know that it was an entire year commitment until my conductor found me and said, “WHERE HAVE YOU BEEN?”  By that time I supposed the loss of one more third clarinet was probably a blessing to everyone.</p>
<p>I sang Gospel during the rest of my tenure at school—one of two white people in that group.  Gospel I could handle—no music reading, a history of musical improvisation, and fun group of people with a conductor, Dr. Alvin Parris, who demonstrated that music was a gift from heaven channeled through people regardless of “proper training.”  In this group, I learned some technical skills, and had the experience of being the only person of another race in a large overpowering majority—I experienced the smallest sampling of the struggles with which my choir members lived constantly, the subtle infusion of racism that permeated their very existence, from which I could escape but they could not.  That was a gift I carry with me to this day.</p>
<p>I left music behind with a better understanding of the timeless cliché, “Be careful what you wish for. You just might get it.”</p>
<p>Today, music has returned to my life. I see the beauty, joy, and patterns in nature.  I pick up my guitar and write, sing, and play on my terms.  I write satire, folk, and other pieces of no particular consequence that will never be produced for the betterment of humanity.  I have sung a roast or two, and I freestyle with my students when directly challenged. I always win.</p>
<p>And I am grateful for my failure. I am happy with my music.  Once again, it brings me great joy.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/210/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/210/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=210&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://cafecasey.com/2012/09/23/failing-at-music-succeeding-at-life-part-two/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>73</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/b9fa5e78902a522dbe731bd611ce5bdd?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cafecasey</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cafecasey.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/screen-shot-2012-09-23-at-7-17-14-am.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen Shot 2012-09-23 at 7.17.14 AM</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Light Up the Streets</title>
		<link>http://blog.invisiblechildren.com/2012/09/20/light-up-the-streets/</link>
		<comments>http://blog.invisiblechildren.com/2012/09/20/light-up-the-streets/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2012 15:59:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Juan Frausto</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Darius Twin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[light art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[light painting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Los Angeles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[street]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Street art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[urban]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.invisiblechildren.com/?p=9378</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Darius Twin&#8216;s re-imagination of Los Angeles, CA combines elements of light painting and photography, bringing a new spin to what street art usually looks like. Using long-exposure photography to capture the intricate paintings, he recreates an everyday setting into something that makes you second-guess what is and isn&#8217;t real. With the photos&#8217; subjects only existing as the artist creates them and then disappearing [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=9378&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="size-full wp-image-9418 aligncenter" title="after life breaking bones " src="http://invisiblechildrenblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/anigif_enhanced-buzz-5680-1347654056-19.gif?w=545&h=407" alt="Darius Twin Breaking Bones" width="545" height="407" /></p>
<p><a href="http://www.dariustwin.com" target="_blank">Darius Twin</a>&#8216;s re-imagination of Los Angeles, CA combines elements of light painting and photography, bringing a new spin to what street art usually looks like. Using <a title="long-exposure photography" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Long-exposure_photography" target="_blank">long-exposure photography</a> to capture the intricate <em>paintings</em>, he recreates an everyday setting into something that makes you second-guess what is and isn&#8217;t real. </p>
<p><img class="size-full wp-image-9419 aligncenter" title="Darius angel" src="http://invisiblechildrenblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/darius-angel.jpg?w=545&h=356" alt="Darius Twin" width="545" height="356" /></p>
<p><img class="size-full wp-image-9415 aligncenter" title="sabre tooth light painting" src="http://invisiblechildrenblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/784899-sabre-tooth.jpg?w=545&h=306" alt="" width="545" height="306" /></p>
<p>With the photos&#8217; subjects only existing as the <a href="http://www.heraldsun.com.au/travel/news/la-based-artist-takes-to-the-streets-with-a-torch-and-a-camera-with-creepy-results/story-fn32891l-1226459836994" target="_blank">artist</a> creates them and then disappearing to only exist on camera, the frames gain a surreal/creepy vibe that makes them even more intriguing. Since 2006, Darius Twin has been perfecting his skill and works within five to seven minute exposures.</p>
<p>Although the medium provides freedom to capture various settings along his travels, it also makes it that much harder: &#8220;With paint you can smudge, add colors to, and blend if you cross a line &#8211; Light as a medium, is less forgiving.&#8221;</p>
<p><img class="size-full wp-image-9416 aligncenter" title="Skeleton surfers" src="http://invisiblechildrenblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/7703001070_2bc4a6c740_b.jpg?w=545&h=363" alt="Darius Twin photography" width="545" height="363" /></p>
<p><img class="size-full wp-image-9422 aligncenter" title="enhanced-buzz Darius Twin" src="http://invisiblechildrenblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/enhanced-buzz-4189-1347653525-7.jpg?w=545&h=362" alt="" width="545" height="362" /></p>
<p><img class="size-full wp-image-9417 aligncenter" title="skeletons camping" src="http://invisiblechildrenblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/7900918118_e05460e602_b.jpg?w=545&h=363" alt="" width="545" height="363" /></p>
<p><img class="size-full wp-image-9420 aligncenter" title="darius space" src="http://invisiblechildrenblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/darius-space.jpg?w=545&h=299" alt="" width="545" height="299" /></p>
<p><img class="size-full wp-image-9425 aligncenter" title="dino" src="http://invisiblechildrenblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/x8xcd.gif?w=545&h=363" alt="" width="545" height="363" /></p>
<p><img class="size-full wp-image-9423 aligncenter" title="enhanced-buzz-30340-1347654014-11" src="http://invisiblechildrenblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/enhanced-buzz-30340-1347654014-11.jpg?w=545&h=360" alt="" width="545" height="360" /></p>
<p><img class="size-full wp-image-9421 aligncenter" title="enhanced-buzz-3954-1347653420-4" src="http://invisiblechildrenblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/enhanced-buzz-3954-1347653420-4.jpg?w=545&h=466" alt="" width="545" height="466" /></p>
<p><img class="size-full wp-image-9424 aligncenter" title="Darius Twin America Skeleton" src="http://invisiblechildrenblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/tumblr_m9x6bxgiho1qa50jho1_500.jpg?w=545" alt=""   /></p>
<p>- Juan Frausto</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">(Photo credit: <a href="http://www.dariustwin.com/" target="_blank">Darius Twin</a>)</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://blog.invisiblechildren.com/category/culture/'>Culture</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/9378/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/9378/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=9378&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://blog.invisiblechildren.com/2012/09/20/light-up-the-streets/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>22</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://invisiblechildrenblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/7703001070_2bc4a6c740_b.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://invisiblechildrenblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/7703001070_2bc4a6c740_b.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Skeleton surfers</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jfrausto214</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://invisiblechildrenblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/anigif_enhanced-buzz-5680-1347654056-19.gif" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">after life breaking bones </media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://invisiblechildrenblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/darius-angel.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Darius angel</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://invisiblechildrenblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/784899-sabre-tooth.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sabre tooth light painting</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://invisiblechildrenblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/7703001070_2bc4a6c740_b.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Skeleton surfers</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://invisiblechildrenblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/enhanced-buzz-4189-1347653525-7.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">enhanced-buzz Darius Twin</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://invisiblechildrenblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/7900918118_e05460e602_b.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">skeletons camping</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://invisiblechildrenblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/darius-space.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">darius space</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://invisiblechildrenblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/x8xcd.gif" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">dino</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://invisiblechildrenblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/enhanced-buzz-30340-1347654014-11.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">enhanced-buzz-30340-1347654014-11</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://invisiblechildrenblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/enhanced-buzz-3954-1347653420-4.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">enhanced-buzz-3954-1347653420-4</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://invisiblechildrenblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/tumblr_m9x6bxgiho1qa50jho1_500.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Darius Twin America Skeleton</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Spanish Little Churches in the Middle of Nowhere</title>
		<link>http://covetotop.wordpress.com/2012/07/01/spanish-little-churches-in-the-middle-of-nowhere/</link>
		<comments>http://covetotop.wordpress.com/2012/07/01/spanish-little-churches-in-the-middle-of-nowhere/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 16:52:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Covetotop</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[architecture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christianity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Medieval art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Middle Ages]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Religion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Romanesque]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spirituality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://covetotop.wordpress.com/?p=900</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Most of the little churches you are about to see belong to the Romanesque style, and were built between the late 10th and the 12th century. Some of them are even older (Pre-Romanesque style, 8th-10th centuries) A few of them are inscribed in the United Nations list of World Heritage Sites. They are spread through [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=900&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Most of the little churches you are about to see belong to the Romanesque style, and were built between the late 10th and the 12th century.</p>
<p>Some of them are even older (Pre-Romanesque style, 8th-10th centuries)</p>
<p>A few of them are inscribed in the United Nations list of <a href="http://whc.unesco.org/en/statesparties/es" target="_blank">World Heritage Sites</a>.</p>
<p>They are spread through the deep Spain (Europe), in distant locations, far away from the beaten path and, in a few cases, they’re pretty difficult to reach if you didn’t have a big breakfast before hiking to them.</p>
<p>They may seem old, unpretentious and solitary &#8230; But make no mistake: God lives very happy in them.</p>
<p><a href="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church1.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-901" title="Romanesque church Spain" src="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church1.jpg" alt="Romanesque in Burgos" width="640" height="480" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church2.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-902" title="Romanesque Palencia" src="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church2.jpg" alt="medieval church on rock" width="640" height="480" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church3.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-903" title="Medieval art in Spain" src="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church3.jpg" alt="La Rioja church" width="640" height="480" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church4.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-904" title="Río Lobos canyon church" src="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church4.jpg" alt="Soria romanesque" width="640" height="480" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church5.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-905" title="Pre-romanesque church" src="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church5.jpg" alt="preromanesque spain" width="640" height="480" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church6.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-906" title="El Conventín Asturias" src="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church6.jpg" alt="Preromanesque Asturias" width="640" height="480" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church7.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-907 aligncenter" title="Church under snow" src="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church7.jpg" alt="Palencia romanesque" width="590" height="480" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church8.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-908" title="church in middle of nowhere" src="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church8.jpg" alt="romanesque church" width="640" height="480" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church9.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-909" title="little jewel in Spain" src="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church9.jpg" alt="Romanesque in Segovia" width="640" height="480" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church10.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-910" title="little church by the beach Spanish Atlantic Ocean" src="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church10.jpg" alt="romanesque in Galicia" width="640" height="480" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church11.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-911" title="romanesque in Northern Spain" src="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church11.jpg" alt="church siones" width="640" height="480" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church12.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-912" title="Catalan Romanesque church" src="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church12.jpg" alt="Pyrenees romanesque" width="640" height="480" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church13.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-913" title="Romanesque in Segovia" src="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church13.jpg" alt="Church canyon" width="640" height="480" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church14.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-914" title="Ábside romanesque" src="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church14.jpg" alt="Absis romanesque in Spain" width="640" height="480" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church15.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-915" title="Solitary church in Castilla" src="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church15.jpg" alt="romanesque in Castille" width="640" height="480" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church16.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-916" title="Pre-Romanesque Spain" src="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church16.jpg" alt="preromanesque spanish church" width="640" height="480" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church17.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-917" title="Church by the river (Pyrenees)" src="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church17.jpg" alt="Pyrenees Romanesque" width="640" height="480" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church18.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-918" title="Lonely church" src="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church18.jpg" alt="Romanesque in Burgos" width="640" height="480" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church19.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-919" title="Little Pre-romanesque Monastery in La Rioja (Suso)" src="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church19.jpg" alt="Suso Monastery" width="640" height="480" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church20.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-920" title="St. Martin church Frómista" src="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church20.jpg" alt="Romanesque jewel" width="640" height="480" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h6 class="zemanta-related-title" style="font-size:1em;">Related articles</h6>
<ul class="zemanta-article-ul">
<li class="zemanta-article-ul-li"><a href="http://covetotop.wordpress.com/2012/06/10/happy-monsters-from-the-middle-ages-in-spain/" target="_blank">Happy monsters from the Middle Ages (in Spain)</a> (covetotop.wordpress.com)</li>
</ul>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://covetotop.wordpress.com/category/art/'>Art</a> Tagged: <a href='http://covetotop.wordpress.com/tag/architecture/'>architecture</a>, <a href='http://covetotop.wordpress.com/tag/art/'>Art</a>, <a href='http://covetotop.wordpress.com/tag/christianity/'>Christianity</a>, <a href='http://covetotop.wordpress.com/tag/culture/'>culture</a>, <a href='http://covetotop.wordpress.com/tag/medieval-art/'>Medieval art</a>, <a href='http://covetotop.wordpress.com/tag/middle-ages/'>Middle Ages</a>, <a href='http://covetotop.wordpress.com/tag/photography/'>photography</a>, <a href='http://covetotop.wordpress.com/tag/religion/'>Religion</a>, <a href='http://covetotop.wordpress.com/tag/romanesque/'>Romanesque</a>, <a href='http://covetotop.wordpress.com/tag/spain/'>Spain</a>, <a href='http://covetotop.wordpress.com/tag/spirituality/'>spirituality</a>, <a href='http://covetotop.wordpress.com/tag/travel/'>Travel</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/900/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/900/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=900&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://covetotop.wordpress.com/2012/07/01/spanish-little-churches-in-the-middle-of-nowhere/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>81</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/3b9b77e54df6dd9956b11af41cc18119?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">marmermare</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Romanesque church Spain</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Romanesque Palencia</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church3.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Medieval art in Spain</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church4.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Río Lobos canyon church</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church5.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Pre-romanesque church</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church6.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">El Conventín Asturias</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church7.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Church under snow</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church8.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">church in middle of nowhere</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church9.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">little jewel in Spain</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church10.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">little church by the beach Spanish Atlantic Ocean</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church11.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">romanesque in Northern Spain</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church12.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Catalan Romanesque church</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church13.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Romanesque in Segovia</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church14.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ábside romanesque</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church15.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Solitary church in Castilla</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church16.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Pre-Romanesque Spain</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church17.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Church by the river (Pyrenees)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church18.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Lonely church</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church19.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Little Pre-romanesque Monastery in La Rioja (Suso)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://covetotop.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/church20.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">St. Martin church Frómista</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>