<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2013 20:02:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>An Open Letter to the Girl I Pretended To Have a Crush  On in Eighth Grade</title>
		<link>http://rottenindenmark.wordpress.com/2013/01/15/an-open-letter-to-the-girl-i-pretended-to-have-a-crush-on-in-eighth-grade/</link>
		<comments>http://rottenindenmark.wordpress.com/2013/01/15/an-open-letter-to-the-girl-i-pretended-to-have-a-crush-on-in-eighth-grade/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 09:52:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Mike</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Essays]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[longform]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[longreads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[memoir]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[middle school]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rottenindenmark.wordpress.com/?p=6537</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Dear Tracy Dolan, Every gay teenager has a different strategy for surviving adolescence. Some join the choir, some write or paint, some play sports, some try to make themselves invisible. And some, like me, make themselves as visible as possible. You were the first girl I pretended to have a crush on so no one [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=6537&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dear Tracy Dolan,</p>
<p>Every gay teenager has a different strategy for surviving adolescence. Some join the choir, some write or paint, some play sports, some try to make themselves invisible. And some, like me, make themselves as visible as possible.</p>
<p>You were the first girl I pretended to have a crush on so no one would know I was gay. I didn’t intend for it to happen, for it to be you, for it to be so easy. But it did, and it was.</p>
<p>I want to tell you how it happened. In another world we could have been friends. In this one, you’re the girl who told me, on the last day of school, to go fuck myself. And I’m the guy that deserved it.</p>
<p align="center">&#8212;</p>
<p>She had red cheeks, a cheerleader’s skirt and a big triangle smile. Her arms and legs were spread out like she was making a letter in the air, though she wasn’t moving. She had three spindly fingers on each hand, no toes, no shoes and a weak, crooked neck.</p>
<p>‘What are you drawing?’ Trevor Schmidt said from behind me. I had my notebook open to the inside cover. I had given her a sun-blonde ponytail, and was drawing wavy yellow lines around it.</p>
<p>We were sitting in staggered rows, in those cagelike middle school desks. Trevor often made comments like this, what are you writing, what page are you on, etc., because this arrangement gave him a perfect diagonal view of my desk and because he was an asshole.</p>
<p>We were three years into middle school, two months into our eighth grade year, and 30 seconds until Mr. Farina started his lecture.</p>
<p>‘Huh? Nothing,’ I said. My forearm wasn’t big enough to cover up the entire sketch, so I moved it over her skirt.</p>
<p>Trevor leaned forward over his desk to get a better look. His hair, long and parted down the middle like the boys on ‘Home Improvement’, hung in his face. This was Seattle in 1995, so he was probably wearing a flannel shirt, maybe a No Fear T-shirt underneath, and saggy Kris Kross jeans.</p>
<p>But I had never really noticed what Trevor wore. Mostly what I noticed about him was that sometimes, when standing, he would lift his shirt a little and rub the tuft of hair just above his belt buckle. I found this utterly captivating, and for nearly two years told myself I was jealous of his flat, soccer-toned stomach. Between seventh and eighth grade, I realized that I was jealous of the hand rubbing it.</p>
<p>‘Is that Tracy Dolan?’ he said, craning. I remember a silver cross dangling from his neck, but I may have edited that into this memory, to give him some external totem of the bully he was inside. Two years earlier, he tripped me—actually fucking tripped me!—as I was running to class. I got a bloody nose and became a school-wide comedy event for the rest of the week. I never forgot that, and I’m certain he did instantly.</p>
<p>‘It’s just a doodle,’ I lied. I had spent hours on it, cross-legged, colored pencils in a pile next to me. Not that I was good at drawing, or even enjoyed it, but hunching over your notebook is a trick introverts have passed down through the generations for disappearing when you’re supposed to be socializing.</p>
<p>Mr. Farina held up his spread left hand and started counting the fingers down, his way of telling us he was about to start talking.</p>
<p>‘Why are you drawing Tracy Dolan on your notebook?’ Trevor said.</p>
<p><i>Who the hell, </i>I thought as Mr. Farina started talking, <i>is Tracy Dolan?</i></p>
<p align="center">&#8212;</p>
<p>You were from Montana, that much I knew, and you had the blondest hair I had ever seen. You wore it the same every day, long bangs and a ponytail, and from the back it practically threw off sparks.</p>
<p>I don’t actually remember meeting you, sorry about that. As boys had slowly, then suddenly, rearranged themselves under the stage lights of my attention, girls had receded into the backdrop. You were just there one day, and it only occurred to me later that you hadn’t been before.</p>
<p>At the time I only knew your hair and your smile. Well, not the smile really, more its limits. You never smiled to be polite, or to be liked, or because you didn’t know what to say. You smiled when you meant it, and stopped immediately when you didn’t.</p>
<p>But the most amazing thing about you wasn’t your hair or your smile. It was your twin brother Mark, who was the most beautiful boy I had ever seen in my life.</p>
<p>I noticed him for the first time in history, on the first day of class. The teacher had arranged the desks in a U, facing inward. ‘It’s a Socratic seminar’, she told us as she Sharpied her name on the overhead. I had taken a seat at the front.</p>
<p>At the back, in the bend of the U, was your brother, who I had never seen before. He was as blonde as you, but skinnier, more restless. He reminded me of the poplars we had in our backyard, which lost their leaves in November and rattled in the wind until March. Every time I looked at him he was moving: bouncing his leg, spinning his pencil, flicking his eyes between ceiling tiles. Later I would learn that this this was a symptom of being a born athlete, one of those people who instantly, effortlessly masters every sport they’ve ever tried.</p>
<p>He was sitting as far from the front of the class as possible. This meant that staring at him—which I wanted to do for the entire class period, followed by the rest of my life—meant I had to face away from the teacher.</p>
<p>‘The 20th century,’ Ms. Dalton was telling 29 faces and the back of my head, ‘has seen a growing recognition of freedom and liberty all over the … Yes?’</p>
<p>He had his hand up.</p>
<p>‘What’s your name?’ Ms. Dalton asked.</p>
<p>‘Mark,’ he said. <i>It’s perfect! </i>I thought meaninglessly. ‘What do you mean “liberty”?’</p>
<p>‘That’s an interesting question, Mark,’ Ms. Dalton said. She had written ‘Miss D’ on the overhead. We called her ‘Misty’ all semester, and were seldom corrected. ‘What does it mean to you?’</p>
<p>Mark looked confused. ‘No,’ he said, bouncing his pencil eraser on his desk like a drumroll. ‘Like, what does the actual word mean?’</p>
<p>‘Oh,’ Ms. Dalton said, visibly deflating as a philosophical question was rendered a logistical one. ‘It means freedom, basically.’</p>
<p>‘Thanks!’ Mark said.</p>
<p>‘Yeah, it’s a technical term meaning “fucking retard”,’ my friend Tom murmured next to me.</p>
<p>‘Shhh, he seems nice!’ I said, lost somewhere in that trembling sparkle of blond hair.</p>
<p align="center">&#8212;</p>
<p>I could have taken the sketch off my notebook, but I didn’t. A week later in Mr. Farina’s class, I deliberately left it open to the cover page, and was slightly disappointed that Trevor, tired or possibly hung over under a baseball cap, failed to notice it.</p>
<p>I had known I was gay for at least a year. There were signs before middle school—I’m standing contraposto in every family photo from 1988 onwards—but I didn’t admit it to myself until I read Jean M. Auel’s ‘Plain of Passage’ in the summer between sixth and seventh grade.</p>
<p>I started reading Auel’s ‘Clan of the Cave Bear’ series when I was 11, and still not ready to admit the blatant fact of my homosexuality. Yes, I had been transfixed by the German men’s swim team in the 1992 Olympics. Yes, I had asked for a Barbie Dream House for Christmas for the last three years—and had locked myself in the bathroom a la Diana Ross upon not receiving it.</p>
<p>But these were just quirks, I told myself. Hadn’t I also purchased the (mostly female) Marvel Comics swimsuit edition? Hadn’t I traced the swimsuited bodies of Jean Grey and Psylocke with a pencil and put them on my wall? No gay kid would do that.</p>
<p>Jondalar first appears in the second book of the ‘Clan of the Cave Bear’ series. He is Early Man, loincloth and everything, and he takes the heroine, Ayla, as his mate.</p>
<p>‘Plains of Passage’ is book three. I had started it when I was 12. I remember lying on my stomach, reading a scene in which Jondalar cuts wood for the evening fire. His ropy arms lifting the axe, his hips putting power into his swing, the sweat dripping from his brow.</p>
<p><i>Why do I have a boner? </i>I thought.</p>
<p>And then, in that actual instant, I knew I was gay. I don’t know why that did it, but it did. Whenever I recall it, I hear an actual <i>ding! </i>In the room,<i> </i>like<i> </i>the microwave telling me my Hot Pocket is ready. <i>Ding! You’re gay! </i></p>
<p><i>… Now what?</i></p>
<p>In the week since Trevor noticed the sketch, I had discovered that you and I had two classes together.</p>
<p>‘Tracy Dolan?’ Tom said. ‘She’s the girl who always has her hand up in the back of Mr. Fisher’s class.’</p>
<p>‘Oh her?’ I said.</p>
<p>‘She’s from Montana. Her brother is that halfwit Mark kid in Misty’s class.’</p>
<p><i>Jondalar! </i>I tried not to noticeably react.</p>
<p>‘Who? … Oh right, the twitchy dude.’ <i>With hair like the sun, </i>was how I wanted to finish the sentence, but I stopped.</p>
<p>‘They’re twins,’ Tom said.</p>
<p>Being openly gay at Nathan Eckstein Middle School in 1995 was not an option. The closest thing we ever had to a homosexual was Gaylord Crestbotham, and he wasn’t even gay, just unfortunately named. He tried to go by William, his middle name, when he came to Eckstein in sixth grade, but barely a month went by before someone saw his real name on a permission slip and started telling everyone.</p>
<p>They bullied him so severe he snapped one day in the lunch line. Someone cut in front of him with a shove and a ‘move, faggot’, and he took his tennis racquet out of his gym bag, wailed on the guy for a few minutes and got expelled.</p>
<p>I had seen this from my lunch table, eating by myself. A month later I asked Ms. Stone, the only teacher I had seen in the lunchroom that day, if she knew what had happened to him. ‘What, to Gaylord?’ she said.</p>
<p>‘William,’ I said. ‘Did he go to a private school or something?’</p>
<p>‘There’s no private school where it’s OK to assault someone for no reason,’ she said.</p>
<p>I was going to need a survival strategy.</p>
<p align="center">&#8212;</p>
<p>‘So what’s the deal with you and Mark Dolan?’ Tom asked me as we played Super Mario World at my house.</p>
<p>It was two Fridays since the sketch incident and, like every Friday, Tom was staying over.</p>
<p>Also like every Friday, we had bought $20 worth of weed from my brother (representing a street value of about $3.50), smoked it out of an apple in my garage and settled 18 inches in front of the TV in my basement until sunrise.</p>
<p>‘What do you mean?’ I asked. <i>Fuck fuck fuck fuck fuck.</i></p>
<p>In the two months since the first day of school, Mark had gone from ‘new kid’ to ‘cool kid’ in record time, and my increasingly elaborate attempts to bump into him were thwarted by a growing throng of admirers.</p>
<p>‘You’re always talking to him after class,’ Tom said. ‘And you keep inviting him to stuff, and he never comes. Why are you so obsessed with him?’</p>
<p>Tom was my only friend. I had spent 6th grade bullied (long hair, sweatpants, headgear), 7th grade invisible (introvert, straight A’s, Steven King novels at lunch) and 8th grade, so far, with Tom.</p>
<p>I met him through our neighborhood soccer team over the summer, and when school started in the fall, I suddenly had a companion for period breaks, lunches and bus rides home. Tom was the difference between staring at my shoes when I walked to class and seeing where I was going.</p>
<p>‘Mark just moved here, I just thought he might want to make some friends,’ I said.</p>
<p>‘New friends? Dude, he’s at Sarah Tanaka’s party in Laurelhurst <i>right now,’ </i>Tom said.</p>
<p>We were taking turns on Super Mario World, and I looked at Tom as he played. He had bony hands and a kind of clench in his face, concentrating on the screen. After we saw ‘Desperado’, he had decided to grow his hair long like Antonio Banderas, but he was only about halfway there.</p>
<p>Nine years later, when I told Tom I was gay and had kept this from him for nearly a decade, he didn’t say anything, he just gave me a hug. He’s still the only straight guy who ever did that.</p>
<p>But then was not now. Then was 1995, and we were 14, and our school was a great big battleship ferrying 1,400 souls to maturity, a journey our principal would later tell us, in our miniature graduation gowns, was ‘the hardest three years of your life.’ Hugs, understanding, save that shit for after the storm. Right now, you need to keep from capsizing.</p>
<p>‘So what’s the deal, dude?’ Tom asked, looking at me now.</p>
<p>‘I’m really into his sister,’ I said.</p>
<p align="center">&#8212;</p>
<p>It was the Monday after Thanksgiving. Ms. Hughes, our math teacher, stood at the front of the class and read out our seating assignments. The class huddled by the door.</p>
<p>‘Table 3,’ she was saying. ‘Frank Robbins and Diane Gregg.’</p>
<p>A week after my conversation with Tom, a girl in biology class saw me looking out the window. ‘Are you looking for Tracy Dolan out there?’ she giggled. The rest of her table leaned in for backstory. Tom had told people, and people had told people.</p>
<p><i>It was working.</i> I tried to look mortified.</p>
<p>A week after that, Trevor Schmidt slapped my shoulder from behind. ‘I fucking knew it!’</p>
<p>I pretended not to know what he was talking about, knowing that each ‘nuh uh!’ just kindled more accusations.</p>
<p>‘I’m with you, dude,’ Trevor said. ‘You don’t see her because she’s all quiet and shit. But get her out from under all that polarfleece, and she’s got a body like Sharon Stone.’</p>
<p>I had never been more proud of myself. I decided to notice you so no one would notice me, and now I was not only assumed straight, but assumed worthy of conversation. I just had to keep broadcasting straightness loud enough to drown out the gay humming underneath.</p>
<p>Despite having two classes together, I had still barely met you. Ms. Hughes’s class was divided into fifteen tables, each with two students. She had already changed the seating arrangement twice. We couldn’t tell if this was a deliberate strategy on her part—obedience through churn—or if she just couldn’t decide how she’d like us arranged. Each time, you and I had ended up at different ends of the class.</p>
<p>‘Table six,’ she was saying as we waited near the door, ‘Michael Hobbes and Tracy Dolan.’</p>
<p>The class, as one, made a kind of <i>awwwww </i>sound,<i> </i>like the studio audience on ‘Full House’.</p>
<p><i>Fuck. </i>I looked down at the floor.</p>
<p>‘Quiet!’ Ms. Hughes said as we walked to our desk. Even she probably knew about my fake crush on you by then.</p>
<p>We sat down. Ms. Hughes was assigning the rest of the desks. My cheeks were as red as yours were in the sketches I had made of you. I kept my notebook closed and my hand on top of it.</p>
<p>‘You’re Mike, right?’ you said.<br />
‘Yeah,’ I said. <i>I’m a monster.<br />
</i>‘You’re a TA for jazz band, right?’<br />
‘…’<br />
‘Were you at the concert at Roosevelt last week? It was amazing,’ you said.</p>
<p>I looked at you and you were holding out a pack of M&amp;Ms. Was it possible no one had told you?</p>
<p>‘Want some?’<br />
‘Sure, thanks’. I took one.<br />
‘Are you from here?’<br />
‘Yeah, born and raised.’<br />
‘I’m from Montana, we don’t have M&amp;Ms there.’<br />
‘Really?’<br />
‘No, idiot.’ You smiled, and I smiled back.</p>
<p align="center">&#8212;</p>
<p>‘So,’ Mark Dolan said. ‘What are we doing tomorrow?’</p>
<p>It was spring outside, not that we could tell from Mark’s basement. He was holding a ping-pong paddle, swaying back and forth, looking at me, the room, the table, his shoes, the table again. Sometimes between points he balanced the paddle on this finger like a sword. Other times he rubbed his stomach and I could see a little of it. After long rallies, he lifted it to wipe his brow. We played ping-pong a lot.</p>
<p>Pretending to like girls—specific girls—specific girls I had classes with—had been more successful than I had expected. From <i>who’s that guy? </i>I had risen in rank to <i>the guy who has a crush on Tracy Dolan </i>and onward to <i>the guy who has a crush on everyone.  </i></p>
<p>Talking about girls, it turns out, is a great way to make friends with guys. It’s an opening line, a time-killer, a narrative, a joke factory. Like all great conversation topics, it’s a way of talking about yourself while pretending not to. I started watching mafia movies on weekends for research.</p>
<p>‘Damn, Sara Kreshki looks good cleaned up’ I would tell Tom Monday morning.</p>
<p>‘Her and Teresa Singer are at the top of my list,’ Trevor Schmidt would say as Farina counted down. ‘The filling-out list.’</p>
<p>As the drawings on my notebook went from stick figure to realistic, from Dr. Seuss to Maxim, I found myself with less time alone between classes to draw them.</p>
<p>‘One more game,’ I told Mark.</p>
<p>The social epicenter of Nathan Eckstein Middle School was the foyer just inside the main entrance. During classes, silent, it was a blank crescent of tiles with curved stairways on each side, lit by Seattle’s meager daylight.</p>
<p>Before and after school, though, it was a ballroom, heaving with the din of students forming and unforming in clusters, backpacks in piles, snippets of music playing from unseen speakers.</p>
<p>Before the sketch, before you, I moved through the foyer mornings and afternoons like a virus without a host, following the wall, reaching for the exit. I arrived in an empty classroom, opened my textbook, wrote my name and the date at the top of a sheet of paper, put down my pencil and waited for class to begin. Why did we need 30 minutes between the buses arriving and classes starting?</p>
<p>Time goes by faster as a participant than a spectator, and since the sketch, since you, 30 minutes wasn’t enough. Now my walk to class zigzagged, clustered and unclustered, paused to test and tweak observations I had rehearsed.</p>
<p>Suddenly, one day Mark was there. I was telling Trevor and two other guys about ‘The Last Seduction’, which I had seen over the weekend and had decided would provide me with conversation material through at least Wednesday.</p>
<p>‘That sounds awesome,’ Mark said.</p>
<p>‘I was gonna see it again this weekend,’ I said. ‘We should go.’</p>
<p>I meant me and Mark, but Trevor thought I meant us. ‘Yeah we should,’ he said.</p>
<p>Over the next three months, my school persona began to colonize my evenings and weekends. The clusters that formed in the foyer now formed over coffee, strip-mall teriyaki, Saturday matinees, Sunday capture-the-flag.</p>
<p>‘I live pretty close,’ Mark said after school one day in March. ‘We should go to my house.’</p>
<p>All winter I had watched Mark, looking for any sign that he carried a secret like mine. I watched him listen, I watched him talk, I watched him watch me and watch others. So far my four-month investigation had turned up no evidence whatsoever.</p>
<p>But now he was inviting me over. Just me! You had joined jazz band, so you weren’t home, and your parents worked til at least six.</p>
<p>I made my face appear to deliberate. ‘What, today?’ I said.</p>
<p>‘Yeah, let’s go,’ Mark said.</p>
<p>Like Ayla gathering her stone tools into her oxskin tunic, I shoved my textbooks into my backpack, slammed my locker and set out with Mark down the hill from Eckstein, across 35th St. and up the hill to his house.</p>
<p>That was March, now it was May, and Mark and I did this two or three times a week, sometimes with Trevor, sometimes with other clustermates. Once I brought Tom, who went through the afternoon like a tourist participating in a bizarre indigenous ceremony.</p>
<p>Every afternoon, the routine was the same as the first time. We walked up the hill to Mark’s house and let ourselves in the back door. I turned on MTV and threw the remote on the couch, then stood across the kitchen island as Mark got food out of the cupboards.</p>
<p>My parents had allergies and read health magazines, so Mark’s house was the only place I was allowed to eat frozen pizza. Mark took them out of the box and put them onto little silver trays for the microwave. While they rotated, he took out the blender, a quart of ice cream, a gallon of milk and whichever bottle in his parents’ liquor cabinet was fullest.</p>
<p>Like Ayla and Jondalar, we took whatever we could forage. Some days it was strawberry ice cream and Kahlua, others cookie dough and scotch. They were all equally terrible, but to us, they tasted like adulthood, rebellion. We drank them out of martini glasses.</p>
<p>Then, feeling full and disinfected, we drifted downstairs to play ping-pong until Mark’s parents came home, when I left, breathing downwards.</p>
<p>On that day in May, we had found a zip-lock bag of Oreos and three-quarters of a bottle of champagne in the fridge. Mark aimed the cork at me and popped it, but the bottle must have been at least a week old, and the cork fell flaccidly to the floor.</p>
<p>‘Don’t worry, Mark, it happens to everyone,’ I said, a premature-ejaculation joke I had heard on a sitcom that neither Mark nor I understood. He smiled anyway, poured half the bottle of champagne and the Oreos into the blender. He scraped a huge chunk of mocha chip, your favorite, on top.</p>
<p>I had daydreamed that on one of these tipsy afternoons Mark would make the milkshake a little too strong, look at me over the ping-pong table, lean forward a little.</p>
<p>‘Mike?’ he would say.</p>
<p>‘Mark,’ I would reply, putting down my paddle, knowing where this was going.</p>
<p>‘Do you ever feel… different?’ His eyes would be moist now, pleading.</p>
<p>I wouldn’t say anything, just walk to the other side of the table and embrace him. He would tell me everything, the desires inside him he couldn’t control, how he had tied them up, chained them down, vaulted them in, how they were too strong, he couldn’t control them anymore. In my arms he would finally be still.</p>
<p>Today was the nineteenth or twentieth time this hadn’t happened, and I was beginning to lose hope. As far as I could tell, the only desires animating Mark were winning at ping-pong, shouting Chris Farley quotes at me from across the table and speculating about which girls liked him.</p>
<p>‘What <i>are</i> we doing tomorrow?’ I asked.</p>
<p>‘Lara Farquhar is going to some high school kegger,’ Mark said. Lara rode my bus, and Mark had been bugging me to talk to her about him. I was, not surprisingly, reluctant to do so.</p>
<p>‘She has tits like the balloons over the Datsun dealership on Aurora,’ I said, timing the joke right as I hit the ball to his backhand. He laughed and hit the ball too hard, and it ricocheted off the ceiling.</p>
<p>‘That’s game, bitch,’ I said, glad for the opportunity to end this conversation before it began. I put the paddle down. ‘Your folks are gonna be home in like five minutes ago’—a joke I had stolen from MadTV—‘I’d better bounce.’</p>
<p>‘You gotta admit, she’s hot, man,’ he said as we walked up the concrete steps. He ducked to avoid the low ceiling. I didn’t have to.</p>
<p>‘You haven’t seen her on the bus, dude,’ I said. ‘When she sits at the back it takes two of the Vietnamese kids just to hold her tits down.’ Jesus Christ, this was me in action.</p>
<p>As we rounded the corner at the top of the stairs, I could see that the TV had been switched to CNN. You were sitting on the couch, eating the rest of the Oreos, the bag on your lap.</p>
<p>It had been eight months since I came out as a crush-on-you haver. Mark must have known, but he never asked me about it and I never said anything. Sometimes I dreamed that his lack of interest was premeditated, deliberate. He wasn’t like me, sure, but maybe he knew my secret, could hear the hum of what I was underneath the megaphone of what I wanted to be. ‘He understands me,’ I told myself, ‘we’re connected.’</p>
<p>Either that or he just didn’t want to hear one of his buddies talk about nailing his sister.</p>
<p>From the living room, you looked over toward the noise. Your eyes didn’t meet mine, didn’t even see me. I was used to this.</p>
<p>‘Oh, hey Tracy!’ Your brother said from behind me.</p>
<p>‘Did you and this asshole eat all the mocha chip?’ you said.</p>
<p align="center">&#8212;</p>
<p>We sat together from Thanksgiving until winter break. We shared homework and M&amp;Ms, the two highest grades in the class right next to each other. We were both the kind of good at math that didn’t have to work very hard. Hughes told us the concept, we got it, we filled in the worksheets. Neither of us understood why the other students had so many questions, or why it took a whole period to explain imaginary numbers or negative square roots. We were done with our worksheets by the time everyone else started.</p>
<p>Sometimes you read your novel under the table as everyone else worked, Tom Clancy or Dean Koontz, a different one each week. You wanted to be a doctor, and you were already ranking medical schools on their proximity to mountains so you could keep skiing on weekends. For undergrad you would go to an all-girls school, you had decided, probably Vassar.</p>
<p>‘How come?’ I asked.<br />
‘I want to <i>work</i>,’ you said. ‘Not deal with boy-nonsense all day.’<br />
‘Good thing there’s no such thing as girl-nonsense,’ I said.<br />
You smiled. ‘Whatever, just because you think everyone should go to public school.’</p>
<p>One period later, in Mr. Farina&#8217;s class, I told Trevor, ‘You know what Tracy told me today dude?’<br />
‘What?’ he said, not looking up.<br />
‘She’s trying to go to an all-girls school.’<br />
‘For high school?’ His head was up now, I could see his eyes under his baseball hat.<br />
‘Yeah, high school,’ I lied. Clarification on the particulars would only be a distraction. ‘She said she liked the way the uniforms fit.’<br />
‘She did not say that,’ Trevor said.<br />
‘Yes she did, she just told me in Hughes’s class,’ I said.<br />
‘She is a <i>slut, </i>guy,’ Trevor said.</p>
<p>And that was how it was. You and I killed time in Ms. Hughes’s class with books and music, hobbies and plans for the future. Then, between second and third period, I retroactively trolled our conversations for material I could refine and distort, bulletins for my new friends. I even told them we went to see ‘While You Were Sleeping’ together.</p>
<p>‘She asked me to go, I was powerless to resist.’ Telling lies was as easy as math worksheets, just learn the rule, find the blanks and fill them in.</p>
<p>And then it was over. The first day back from winter break, huddled by the door in Ms. Hughes’s class again, I wished you a happy new year.</p>
<p>‘OK,’ you said, cold as Yellowstone, and moved to the other side of the huddle.</p>
<p><i>She knows.</i></p>
<p>I was assigned to sit with Ben Neill, one of my morning and afternoon clustermates.</p>
<p>‘Not next to Tracy anymore, huh?’ he asked. ‘I bet that would hurt if you weren’t such a homo.’</p>
<p>‘You’re just saying that because your mom likes it from the back,’ I said reflexively. <i>Someone told her, </i>I thought, <i>But who, and how much?</i></p>
<p>That was January. Before your brother invited me over, before I made up crushes on Nicole Grant and Gina Lasky, before a late-spring faux fixation on Laura Gilchrist was, mortifyingly, reciprocated and I had to fake mono to get out of it.</p>
<p>The day after we saw you in your living room, I asked your brother why you hated me so much.</p>
<p>‘She thinks you’re a pervert,’ Mark said, balancing the ping-pong paddle on his finger. ‘Everyone kind of thinks that.’</p>
<p>At the time, appallingly, I considered this a triumph. <i>Perverts are not gaylords. </i>I was safe.</p>
<p>‘What did I ever do to her though?’ I asked.</p>
<p>‘Apparently you said you wanted her to wrap her thighs around you like a python. Because she has big thighs from skiing, I guess? I don’t really get it.’</p>
<p>Had I said that? Shit, it sounded like me.</p>
<p>‘Who told her?’</p>
<p>‘Trevor,’ he said. ‘He thinks it’s hilarious how she won’t talk to you anymore.’</p>
<p>This should not have surprised me. Trevor had revealed himself to be as much of a bully as a friend than as an enemy. Two years ago he had tormented me to impress eighth graders, and now he tormented sixth graders to impress me.</p>
<p>Once, in the cafeteria, Trevor pulled down Alec Pentieff’s pants while he was carrying his lunch tray, and he had to shuffle 20 feet with his pants at his ankles before he could pull them up again. I made a show of laughing—Christ, did we high-five?—but I felt sick to my stomach the rest of the day.</p>
<p>Everywhere I looked, the consequences of my survival strategy were piling up. After I canceled our smoke-and-Super Mario Fridays three times in a row, Tom stopped assuming them, and now we walked past each other like strangers. Girls I had liked—<i>actually</i> liked, like, as people—stopped talking to me because I had publicly appreciated their breasts, their asses or, in one case, their ‘haunches’. Alec Pentioff, who rode my bus and whose parents knew mine from church, never looked at me again.</p>
<p>Every time, it came as a surprise. <i>Don’t you know this isn’t really me? </i>I wanted to shout. <i>Just because I’m doing this doesn’t mean I’m the kind of person who does. </i></p>
<p>I wish I could tell you, ‘I learned my lesson, the very next day I came out of the closet, I never lied again.’ But I didn’t. I kept it up this façade all through high school.</p>
<p>When I finally came out, on the night of high school graduation, in the Denny’s on Lake City Way, my friends told me ‘I never would have guessed’ and I received it as a compliment. Only later did I realize that there’s no such thing as hiding who you are, there’s only becoming someone else.</p>
<p>I remember you because you were the fork in the road. I could have sat next to you, just sat, just listened and spoken, just kept our conversations in that little rectangle where they began. I could have thrown away that sketch.</p>
<p>But I didn’t. The last time I saw you was the final day of eighth grade, an afternoon so bright it steamed the rain on the pavement. We ran into each other between the cluster of portables and the school building. I was heading in, you were coming out.</p>
<p>‘Hey Tracy,’ I said. You nodded and kept walking.</p>
<p>‘Hey,’ I said again. ‘Tracy? Hey, Tracy!’</p>
<p>‘What, Mike?’ You stopped. ‘What is it?’</p>
<p>It was the first time I had seen you without an audience since December. Even then, I wanted to tell you that I was sorry, that it wasn’t me who said that about you but someone else, someone mean.</p>
<p>I wanted to tell you that you had beaten me on Ms. Hughes’s final by one point and I was proud of you. That your brother turned out to be a nice guy, maybe even a friend. That the University of Colorado has a great medical school. That every time I saw you hunched over your notebook during breaks, I wanted to come over to see what you were writing. That I had read two Tom Clancy books this year and they both sucked.</p>
<p>I could have said something decent, kind, something to make you remember who I was and forget what I’d become, could have asked you what you were doing this summer, if you were reading anything good lately.</p>
<p>But I didn’t. Instead, what I said was, ‘You look great in those shorts’.</p>
<p align="center">&#8212;</p>
<p>Your brother and I were friends until junior year of high school, when we simultaneously decided to stop calling each other. I had discovered other boys, girls had discovered him, our nows replaced our thens.</p>
<p>Last month, he added me on Facebook. He sells high-end SUVs at a dealership in Kansas City. In nearly all of his pictures he’s somewhere sunny, and smiling. His girlfriend appears in at least three-quarters of them, one arm around him, smiling just as wide. And in some of them there’s you.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s how I found out that you went to Swarthmore, that you live in New York City, that you’re a veterinarian with a daughter and a husband and a Subaru Outback and a Netflix subscription. You’re grown up, lived in, but it’s definitely you. Your daughter has a ponytail, blonde as the sun.</p>
<p>On that afternoon on the last day of school, you turned away from me and walked across the concrete. You didn’t even look back, you just said, almost to yourself, ‘go fuck yourself’ as I stood there at the door.</p>
<p>I didn’t realize it then, and I wouldn’t for a long time, but I already had.</p>
<p>Hope you’re still smiling, and hope you still mean it,</p>
<p>Mike</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/6537/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/6537/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=6537&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://rottenindenmark.wordpress.com/2013/01/15/an-open-letter-to-the-girl-i-pretended-to-have-a-crush-on-in-eighth-grade/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c35fd6249a1967812426f2821d7012e4?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif&#38;r=R" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">specificshardlymatter</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The &#8216;Promised Land&#8217; in Mozambique</title>
		<link>http://africasacountry.com/2013/01/16/promised-land-in-mozambique/</link>
		<comments>http://africasacountry.com/2013/01/16/promised-land-in-mozambique/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2013 08:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Corinna Jentzsch</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[FEATURED]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MEDIA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PHOTOGRAPHY]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cateme]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coalmines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gregor Zielke]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[interview]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Moatize]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mozambique]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Promised Land]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rio Tinto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tete]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vale]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://africasacountry.com/?p=60634</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Promised Land is the title of the German photographer Gregor Zielke’s feature about the relocation of 700 families in Mozambique’s Tete province to make space for the Brazilian company Vale’s construction of the Southern Hemisphere&#8217;s second largest coalmine. The New York Times recently covered the plight of the people in Cateme following relocation. Gregor Zielke’s [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=60634&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_60683" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 559px"><a href="http://africasacountry.com/2013/01/16/promised-land-in-mozambique/moz1/" rel="attachment wp-att-60683"><img class=" wp-image-60683 " alt="Sadira Joaquim works on her family’s farmland. Instead of the initially promised two hectares of productive farmland, families were given only one hectare of unproductive farmland—hardly enough to support a family, let alone sell produce on the far away markets. Sadira is only 20 years old and has no other possibilities to work, unlike in Moatize." src="http://africasacountry.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/moz1.jpg?w=549&#038;h=365" width="549" height="365" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Sadira Joaquim works on her family’s farmland. Instead of the initially promised two hectares of productive farmland, families were given only one hectare of unproductive farmland—hardly enough to support a family, let alone sell produce on the far away markets. Sadira is only 20 years old and has no other possibilities to work, unlike in Moatize.</p></div>
<p><em>Promised Land</em> is the title of the German photographer <a title="Gregor Zielke" href="http://gregorzielke.com/" target="_blank">Gregor Zielke’s</a> feature about the relocation of 700 families in Mozambique’s Tete province to make space for the Brazilian company Vale’s construction of the Southern Hemisphere&#8217;s second largest coalmine. <em>The New York Times</em> recently <a title="As Coal Boosts Mozambique, the Rural Poor Are Left Behind" href="http://www.nytimes.com/2012/11/11/world/africa/as-coal-boosts-mozambique-the-rural-poor-are-left-behind.html?pagewanted=all&amp;_r=1&amp;" target="_blank">covered</a> the plight of the people in Cateme following relocation. Gregor Zielke’s photos capture the company’s broken promises—unproductive farmland and poorly constructed settlements—but also the communities’ resilience. Gregor Zielke is part of a <a title="PANPHOTOS . COOPERATIVE" href="http://panphotos.org/PAN/blog/" target="_blank">cooperative</a> of photographers that have been working in Mozambique for some time and seek to advance dialogue and better understanding between Germany and Mozambique by producing media reports and developing educational projects. <span id="more-60634"></span></p>
<p><strong>Why did you call your photo feature &#8220;Promised Land&#8221;? </strong></p>
<p>&#8220;Promised Land&#8221; refers to the fact that people lose their land, the land they had inhabited for generations, to a company which promised better living conditions and farmland for self-sustainment through resettlement—and the people there are very tied to their land. But looking at the conditions now you recognize that it is a promise that has not been fulfilled. For example, people were promised two hectares of productive farmland but only received one hectare of unproductive farmland hours away from their houses, which isn&#8217;t even enough to feed their own families. Houses are built cheaply and show cracks after only one or two years. Of course, at first glance they seem better than mud huts, but they’re just not suited for the area and the families. The communities&#8217; infrastructure is completely gone, at least so far away that they simply cannot afford going there on a regular basis. The land is unbelievably hot and dry, even for Tete Province where life has always been hard anyways. Obviously, &#8220;Promised Land&#8221; also plays with the biblical term and how much of an odyssey the whole resettlement process is that people go through.</p>
<div id="attachment_60842" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 559px"><a href="http://africasacountry.com/2013/01/16/promised-land-in-mozambique/photo5/" rel="attachment wp-att-60842"><img class=" wp-image-60842 " alt="This is a typical street in Cateme, wide and dusty. Walks to the wells are far, especially when carrying 20 liters of water. The whole area is more or less deserted, ground water has to be pumped by electrical pumps because it's so deep, so when the electricity goes down there is also no water." src="http://africasacountry.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/photo5.jpg?w=549&#038;h=365" width="549" height="365" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">This is a typical street in Cateme, wide and dusty. Walks to the wells are far, especially when carrying 20 liters of water. The whole area is more or less deserted, ground water has to be pumped by electrical pumps because it&#8217;s so deep, so when the electricity goes down there is also no water.</p></div>
<p><strong>What sparked your interest in Mozambique, and in Cateme in particular?</strong></p>
<p>I think that Mozambique is a good example of how the local population doesn&#8217;t benefit from the current resource boom in Africa, similar things are happening in many other countries too. Kind of like the return of the colonial era. I think it&#8217;s an important issue to talk about and raise international awareness, on the other hand it&#8217;s just as important to inform the displaced communities about their rights and raise resistance so that there at least can be better consultation with the local communities in the future. You can&#8217;t really blame the government for exploring the resources; but they should be used to generate sustainable development on a local and national level. That&#8217;s just not happening. Living conditions worsened.</p>
<p><strong>How did you prepare for the trip? </strong></p>
<p>I worked with the Mozambican NGO <a href="http://ja4change.wordpress.com/" target="_blank">Justiça Ambiental/Friends of the Earth Mozambique</a> (JA!) that made it possible to work in the resettlement. They have very good contacts and work in the region in the field of human rights and environmental issues. Without them, the work simply wouldn&#8217;t have been possible. There&#8217;s a lot of red tape, and getting permission from the local administration and local leaders to work in Cateme was uncertain until the last minute. In fact, we spent quite a bit of time of the two weeks we were there getting permission before we could even start working in the area. JA! also opened the doors to the families in Cateme; of course there is a lot of distrust and also fear. The families in Cateme needed to understand what we were about to do, what side we were on. They were suspicious of what we were going to report from Cateme, afraid we could make it look beneficial for the people, favorable for Vale and the government. Some even thought that we had been hired by Vale. But after initial concern they were very giving and open.</p>
<div id="attachment_60839" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 559px"><a href="http://africasacountry.com/2013/01/16/promised-land-in-mozambique/photo3/" rel="attachment wp-att-60839"><img class=" wp-image-60839 " alt="This man works in a brick manufacture near Moatize. Along with his colleagues, he was resettled to Cateme and went back to Moatize because otherwise he is simply unable to support his family. They stay in the mud pit five days a week and only return to their families on the weekends because their workplace now is 40 kilometers from their homes. They sleep in the mud pit or by the ovens. They have no choice. This illustrates quite clearly how little care is being taken in the whole resettlement process." src="http://africasacountry.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/photo3.jpg?w=549&#038;h=365" width="549" height="365" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">This man works in a brick manufacture near Moatize. Along with his colleagues, he was resettled to Cateme and went back to Moatize because otherwise he is simply unable to support his family. They stay in the mud pit five days a week and only return to their families on the weekends because their workplace now is 40 kilometers from their homes. They sleep in the mud pit or by the ovens. They have no choice. This illustrates quite clearly how little care is being taken in the whole resettlement process.</p></div>
<p><strong>What did you plan on capturing with your photos?</strong></p>
<p>My aim was to document people&#8217;s struggle in daily life and how they deal with these difficult circumstances—I was amazed at how people still make the best of their situation and try to cope with it. The problems these communities face are on so many different levels and not always very obvious—they&#8217;re basically sent to the desert without adequate housing, health care and—most importantly—no possibilities for self-sustainment. Most of them are farmers, they live off their land and sell their produce on the markets, now the markets are more than 40 kilometers away and people don&#8217;t have any surplus produce to sell due to the unproductive farmland they were given. They depend on their land. That really robs them of their existence.</p>
<p><strong>What impressed you most about how the people dealt with their worsened living conditions? </strong></p>
<p>The most amazing moment for me was to see people dancing on a Sunday afternoon a few kilometers from Cateme in Mwaladzi, a community resettled by the British mining company Rio Tinto. There is no electricity and no water supply and people have to rely on a water truck that comes once a week. Two boys had put up some kind of karaoke machine blasting music, powered by a solar panel they got somewhere. Adults and children alike were dancing and enjoying themselves inviting me to join them.</p>
<div id="attachment_60840" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 559px"><a href="http://africasacountry.com/2013/01/16/promised-land-in-mozambique/photo-4-3/" rel="attachment wp-att-60840"><img class=" wp-image-60840 " alt="Students hang around after school at Armando Guebuza School in Cateme. The school is a so-called &quot;white elephant&quot;: theoretically it brings education and infrastructure to the resettlement, but in reality not many families can afford the high school and examination turning the school into a de facto boarding school for students from other communities. Only approximately 10 percent of students come from Cateme resettlement." src="http://africasacountry.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/photo-4.jpg?w=549&#038;h=365" width="549" height="365" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Students hang around after school at Armando Guebuza School in Cateme. The school is a so-called &#8220;white elephant&#8221;: theoretically it brings education and infrastructure to the resettlement, but in reality not many families can afford the high school and examination turning the school into a de facto boarding school for students from other communities. Only approximately 10 percent of students come from Cateme resettlement.</p></div>
<p><strong>How do you aspire to influence political debates with your work?</strong><i> </i></p>
<p>My aim is simply to put faces to the displaced communities, to show that the big companies are not moving around figures and a nameless &#8220;population.&#8221; They have names, they are mothers, fathers, grandparents and kids, all they want is to raise their families. That&#8217;s not asking much, is it?</p>
<p><strong>You also conducted a project on the urbanization process of villages in eastern China. Do you see any parallels between the transformation processes in Mozambique and those you observed in eastern China? </strong></p>
<p>The process of resettlement in China is very different to Mozambique, the reasons and circumstances are very different. However, any kind of imposed resettlement usually means a drastic change in the living conditions. In China as well as in Mozambique people have to adapt to the changes and eventually find new ways of self-sustainment. You see many people in China’s rapidly growing cities still fishing in rivers and canals and using other natural resources they find by the roadside, mostly because they just do the things they&#8217;re used to and might have difficulties adapting to a new lifestyle. In Mozambique such things may even be a matter of survival.</p>
<div id="attachment_60837" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 559px"><a href="http://africasacountry.com/2013/01/16/promised-land-in-mozambique/photo2/" rel="attachment wp-att-60837"><img class=" wp-image-60837 " alt="The Joaquim family enjoys a little cooling down after sunset. Houses are not built to people's needs and are of poor quality. The tin clad roofs heat up the houses to temperatures of over 60°C inside and show cracks after only one or two years. Though the area is very dry, occasional rains leak in the houses, leaving inhabitants to seek shelter in the school." src="http://africasacountry.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/photo2.jpg?w=549&#038;h=365" width="549" height="365" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The Joaquim family enjoys a little cooling down after sunset. Houses are not built to people&#8217;s needs and are of poor quality. The tin clad roofs heat up the houses to temperatures of over 60°C inside and show cracks after only one or two years. Though the area is very dry, occasional rains leak in the houses, leaving inhabitants to seek shelter in the school.</p></div>
<p><em>* All photo captions written by the photographer.</em></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/60634/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/60634/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=60634&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://africasacountry.com/2013/01/16/promised-land-in-mozambique/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://africasacountry.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/photo3.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://africasacountry.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/photo3.jpg?w=150" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/7117681cc8647c448f1fda9833a623ab?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">coboje</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://africasacountry.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/moz1.jpg?w=610" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Sadira Joaquim works on her family’s farmland. Instead of the initially promised two hectares of productive farmland, families were given only one hectare of unproductive farmland—hardly enough to support a family, let alone sell produce on the far away markets. Sadira is only 20 years old and has no other possibilities to work, unlike in Moatize.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://africasacountry.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/photo5.jpg?w=610" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">This is a typical street in Cateme, wide and dusty. Walks to the wells are far, especially when carrying 20 liters of water. The whole area is more or less deserted, ground water has to be pumped by electrical pumps because it&#039;s so deep, so when the electricity goes down there is also no water.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://africasacountry.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/photo3.jpg?w=610" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">This man works in a brick manufacture near Moatize. Along with his colleagues, he was resettled to Cateme and went back to Moatize because otherwise he is simply unable to support his family. They stay in the mud pit five days a week and only return to their families on the weekends because their workplace now is 40 kilometers from their homes. They sleep in the mud pit or by the ovens. They have no choice. This illustrates quite clearly how little care is being taken in the whole resettlement process.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://africasacountry.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/photo-4.jpg?w=610" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Students hang around after school at Armando Guebuza School in Cateme. The school is a so-called &#34;white elephant&#34;: theoretically it brings education and infrastructure to the resettlement, but in reality not many families can afford the high school and examination turning the school into a de facto boarding school for students from other communities. Only approximately 10 percent of students come from Cateme resettlement.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://africasacountry.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/photo2.jpg?w=610" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The Joaquim family enjoys a little cooling down after sunset. Houses are not built to people&#039;s needs and are of poor quality. The tin clad roofs heat up the houses to temperatures of over 60°C inside and show cracks after only one or two years. Though the area is very dry, occasional rains leak in the houses, leaving inhabitants to seek shelter in the school.</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Androgyny Goes Both Ways</title>
		<link>http://badfadsblog.com/2013/01/16/androgyny-goes-both-ways/</link>
		<comments>http://badfadsblog.com/2013/01/16/androgyny-goes-both-ways/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2013 14:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>badfads</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[High Fashion Shenanigans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fashion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fashion nightmare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fashion week]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[footwear fail]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[high fashion or just plain high]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[I just have a lot of feelings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leggings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pics or it didn't happen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[What in the actual fuck were you thinking]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://badfadsblog.com/?p=1342</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There has been a trend in menswear that I don&#8217;t understand.  It all started with Kanye and his skirt and leather meggings at the 12-12-12 benefit concert, and I decided to give it a pass then because I couldn&#8217;t be bothered. But then I started seeing articles about womenswear inspired menswear on the runways.  I [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1342&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There has been a trend in menswear that I don&#8217;t understand.  It all started with Kanye and his skirt and leather meggings at the 12-12-12 benefit concert, and I decided to give it a pass then because I couldn&#8217;t be bothered.</p>
<p>But then I started seeing articles about womenswear inspired menswear on the runways.  I suppose it was only a matter of time given 1) how bonkers Fashion is right now, and 2) that women have been wearing menswear inspired outfits for ages.  For whatever reason, I find this a lot more awkward.  Social Justice! types would claim it&#8217;s because I am restrained by gender roles, or perhaps I am limited by my white, cisgender upbringing and therefore do not understand the plight of the transvestite model, but maybe I just don&#8217;t think men in skirts or dresses as a Fall Fashion campaign is really a good business decision.  It kind of limits the market, I would think.</p>
<p>But here are some examples of womenswear inspired menswear and my problems with them.</p>
<p><span id="more-1342"></span></p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 580px"><img alt="" src="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/902672/thumbs/o-KANYE-WEST-SKIRT-570.jpg?6" width="570" height="735" /><p class="wp-caption-text">This is the most prominent example I can think of, since I saw many headlines and attempted to ignore all of them. Unsuccessfully.</p></div>
<p>It&#8217;s like a leather kilt with leather leggings.  I would be mad at this outfit on ANYONE, doubly since it&#8217;s Kanye and he annoys me. That much leather is almost always a bad decision.  I can&#8217;t even imagine how sweaty he is under all that.</p>
<p>Then we have this dress and leggings from Vivienne Westwood, which was not the craziest look in her show, since a large portion of it involved what we&#8217;ll politely call color-blocking and drawn on monocles and goatees.  I&#8217;m pretty sure I only looked at that show since I saw the drawn on monocles and busted up laughing.</p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 391px"><img alt="" src="http://www3.pictures.zimbio.com/gi/Vivienne+Westwood+Runway+Milan+Fashion+Week+Yh42s5KrTetl.jpg" width="381" height="594" /><p class="wp-caption-text">That is not a tunic, it is a dress. Also those shoes are an orange I haven&#8217;t seen since I left Champaign/Urbana.</p></div>
<p>I don&#8217;t get it.  A tunic I could understand, kind of, but that is clearly a dress.  He also has what look like plastic shoes.  Oof.</p>
<p>Alexander McQueen, a designer I normally wet myself over, prominently featured dressing gowns (or bathrobes, in &#8216;Merica) as part of the menswear show.</p>
<p>And J.W. Anderson, who I know very little about, showed the male skort.  Is it a skirt? Is it a pair of shorts?  Is it a Fashion Tragedy?  YES.</p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><img class=" " alt="" src="http://www.metrovelvet.com/wp-content/themes/metrovelvet/assets/0113/jw4.jpg" width="600" height="900" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Also, having a kangaroo stomach pouch is only a good decision if you are, in fact, a kangaroo.</p></div>
<p>The proportions also look a bit off.  I&#8217;m trying to figure out if he has CRAZY long legs, or if the skort is only barely covering his junk, since the fly looks like it&#8217;s approaching his navel. I also have thoughts on the Slutty Pirate boots, most of which are, &#8220;Why is he wearing Slutty Pirate boots?&#8221;</p>
<p>Then we have a dress.</p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><img class=" " alt="" src="http://www.metrovelvet.com/wp-content/themes/metrovelvet/assets/0113/jw14.jpg" width="600" height="900" /><p class="wp-caption-text">This is an awkwardly short dress on anyone.</p></div>
<p>I would be mad at that dress on anyone, mostly because I am not convinced that a light breeze wouldn&#8217;t result in a serious wardrobe malfunction.  I&#8217;m also annoyed that I feel like I have to qualify that the dress annoys me regardless of gender, but it&#8217;s a bad dress.</p>
<p>And then, just to prove that JW Anderson was clearly messing with all of us, we have Slutty Pirate Steals A Hospital Gown And Attempts Surgery:</p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><img class=" " alt="" src="http://www.metrovelvet.com/wp-content/themes/metrovelvet/assets/0113/jw10.jpg" width="600" height="900" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Or as I put it to E: &#8220;This image may result in sexual nightmares.&#8221;</p></div>
<p>I have nothing else to say.  Please don&#8217;t buy any of these outfits.</p>
<p>(Photo Credits: The Huffington Post, Zimbio, MetroVelvet)</p>
<br /> Tagged: <a href='http://badfadsblog.com/tag/fashion/'>fashion</a>, <a href='http://badfadsblog.com/tag/fashion-nightmare/'>fashion nightmare</a>, <a href='http://badfadsblog.com/tag/fashion-week/'>fashion week</a>, <a href='http://badfadsblog.com/tag/footwear-fail/'>footwear fail</a>, <a href='http://badfadsblog.com/tag/high-fashion-or-just-plain-high/'>high fashion or just plain high</a>, <a href='http://badfadsblog.com/tag/i-just-have-a-lot-of-feelings/'>I just have a lot of feelings</a>, <a href='http://badfadsblog.com/tag/leggings/'>leggings</a>, <a href='http://badfadsblog.com/tag/pics-or-it-didnt-happen/'>pics or it didn't happen</a>, <a href='http://badfadsblog.com/tag/what-in-the-actual-fuck-were-you-thinking/'>What in the actual fuck were you thinking</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1342/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1342/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1342&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://badfadsblog.com/2013/01/16/androgyny-goes-both-ways/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>45</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/545a22af6a5cf2bcbce9ef9d44f04e92?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">badfads</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/902672/thumbs/o-KANYE-WEST-SKIRT-570.jpg?6" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://www3.pictures.zimbio.com/gi/Vivienne+Westwood+Runway+Milan+Fashion+Week+Yh42s5KrTetl.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://www.metrovelvet.com/wp-content/themes/metrovelvet/assets/0113/jw4.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://www.metrovelvet.com/wp-content/themes/metrovelvet/assets/0113/jw14.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://www.metrovelvet.com/wp-content/themes/metrovelvet/assets/0113/jw10.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Drinking the French Quarter: The Ramos Fizz</title>
		<link>http://cold-glass.com/2013/01/16/drinking-the-french-quarter-the-ramos-fizz/</link>
		<comments>http://cold-glass.com/2013/01/16/drinking-the-french-quarter-the-ramos-fizz/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2013 00:32:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Doug Ford</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[cocktails]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cream]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[egg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fiz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[freshly pressed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lemon juice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lime juice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New Orleans Gin Fizz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[orange flower water]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ramos fizz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ramos gin fizz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[seltzer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[soda]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cold-glass.com/?p=6493</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[So I&#8217;ve been shaking a Ramos Fizz for ten minutes now, in an effort to find out if the legend is true, that you have to shake this drink for a quarter hour to achieve the required consistency. It seems like a very, very long time. The shaker is really icing up. I&#8217;m thinking there may be something to [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=6493&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So I&#8217;ve been shaking a Ramos Fizz for ten minutes now, in an effort to find out if the legend is true, that you have to shake this drink for a quarter hour to achieve the required consistency.<span id="more-6493"></span> It seems like a very, very long time. The shaker is really icing up. I&#8217;m thinking there may be something to David Wondrich&#8217;s speculation about those fifteen minutes<em>,</em> that &#8220;&#8230;it only seemed that long, especially to the guy who had to do all the work.&#8221;</p>
<p>The Ramos Fizz—or &#8220;Ramos Gin Fizz,&#8221; as Huey Long called his favorite drink—is one of New Orleans&#8217;s most famous cocktails. And it&#8217;s all about the texture achieved by long shaking.</p>
<p>Henry &#8220;Carl&#8221; Ramos insisted that his fizz be shaken and shaken and shaken to reach the proper milky consistency. It&#8217;s hard to believe that any bartender could afford to shake for the purported fifteen minutes in a commercial setting, but it&#8217;s well-documented that during the drink&#8217;s pre-Prohibition heyday, bars would hire extra &#8220;shaker boys&#8221; in an effort to achieve just the right texture and body.</p>
<p>Ramos first served his namesake drink in 1888. Only a year earlier, Jerry Thomas&#8217;s <cite>Bartenders Guide</cite> had first recorded the basic &#8220;gin fiz&#8221; template: a simple gin sour with a splash of seltzer, very similar to the <a title="The Tom Collins Cocktail, at Cold Glass" href="http://cold-glass.com/2012/06/28/the-tom-collins-cocktail/">Tom Collins</a>.</p>
<p>But the Ramos Fizz is a far cry from the simplicity of the original.</p>
<h3>It&#8217;s all about texture</h3>
<p>A popular exercise in the late nineteenth century was adding milk, cream, or egg (whites, yolks, or both) to cocktails and sours to change their texture, and texture seems to be what the Ramos Fizz is all about. In the traditional parlance of the day, customers could order, for example, a Cream Fiz, a Silver Fiz (with eggwhite), or perhaps a Diamond Fiz, topped up with champagne (and known for most of the past century as the <a title="The French 75 Cocktail, at Cold Glass" href="http://cold-glass.com/2012/10/28/the-french-75-cocktail/">French 75</a>.) Ramos decided to gild the lily by combining both eggwhite and cream into his version of the Gin Fiz; and, with a typical New Orleans flourish, he topped it off with a dash of orange flower water. The Ramos Fizz was born.</p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 412px"><img class=" shadow" alt="The Ramos Fizz, photo © 2013 Douglas M. Ford. All rights reserved." src="http://www.smugmug.com/photos/i-Q5XMR6d/0/L/i-Q5XMR6d-L.jpg" width="402" height="600" /><p class="wp-caption-text">The Ramos Fizz</p></div>
<p>Ramos was very particular about the drink&#8217;s texture. <a title="&quot;In the Big Easy, 2 Cocktails Reign,&quot; Eric Asimov, NY Times" href="http://www.nytimes.com/2008/07/16/dining/16pour.html?scp=3&amp;sq=asimov%20ramos%20gin&amp;st=cse&amp;_r=0">Eric Asimov recounts a 1928 interview</a> from the<em> New Orleans Item-Tribune</em>, where Ramos is reported to have declared that you “shake and shake and shake until there is not a bubble left but the drink is smooth and snowy white and of the consistency of good rich milk.”</p>
<h3>The Ramos Fizz recipe</h3>
<p>We&#8217;re lucky to have the recipe—Ramos kept the formula a secret for decades; Prohibition seems to have convinced him to share his creation, perhaps from fear that it would be lost to posterity. Meanwhile, Harry McElhone published a nearly identical recipe called the “New Orleans Gin Fizz” in his 1927 <cite>Barflies and Cocktails;</cite> Harry Craddock picked that one up in 1930 for <cite>The Savoy Cocktail Book</cite>.</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>The Ramos Fizz / New Orleans Gin Fizz</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>1½ oz Old Tom gin (Ransom, Hayman&#8217;s), or Plymouth gin</li>
<li>1 oz heavy cream</li>
<li>1 raw egg white</li>
<li>¾ oz simple syrup (or 1 Tbsp fine sugar)</li>
<li>½ oz fresh lime juice</li>
<li>½ oz fresh lemon juice</li>
<li>¼ tsp (2–3 dashes) orange flower water</li>
<li>1 oz sparkling water</li>
</ul>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><em>&#8220;Dry shake&#8221; (no ice) all ingredients—including the water—for two minutes. Add ice, and shake for an additional two minutes, more if you can, or until you can&#8217;t stand to shake anymore. Strain into a tall tumbler or Collins glass. Optionally, garnish with a wheel of orange.</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Choose a gin that is not too juniper-heavy; sweeter gins are preferable. <a title="&quot;Ramos Gin Fizz,&quot; recipe by Henry Charles Ramos in the New Orleans Item-Tribune, 1928" href="http://www.classicmixology.com/source/new_orleans_item_tribune">Ramos&#8217;s original recipe</a> called for Old Tom; Plymouth is a pleasant alternative.</p>
<p>The thick richness of the proper cream is one of your best tools in achieving Ramos&#8217;s &#8220;good rich milk&#8221; consistency. Heavy cream is preferable to half-and-half. Low-fat and no-fat dairy just don&#8217;t work in this drink.</p>
<p>Orange flower water is the hallmark of this drink, and this is a case where there is no substitute. Without it, the drink you make is not a proper Ramos Fizz.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s something strange about the water in the recipe. Ramos indicates a specific measure of sparkling water, and does not use terms like &#8220;splash&#8221; or &#8220;top up.&#8221; His wording, immediately after the ingredient listing, is &#8221;Together well shaken and strained.&#8221; Every other Fizz gets the splash of bubbly as a finishing touch—the &#8220;fizz&#8221;—but I infer from his wording is the sparkling water is added <em>before</em> shaking. This flattens the sparkle utterly, but it does help to assure the homogenous creamy texture. (I wish I knew if this is to be taken literally, or if it was a careless shorthand statement of the standard fizz technique.)</p>
<h3>So how long  do you shake a Ramos Fizz?</h3>
<p>Meanwhile, back to that freezing cocktail shaker&#8230;</p>
<p>Don&#8217;t tell anyone, but I really did shake that Ramos Fizz for fifteen minutes.</p>
<p>I can tell you that you don&#8217;t really need to shake the Ramos Fizz for fifteen minutes. Or even for ten. I recommend a &#8220;dry shake,&#8221; with no ice, for about two minutes, then a shake with ice for a minimum of two more minutes—a total of four minutes shaking. What I learned from the fifteen-minute shake (and from eight- and ten-minute shakes) is that no magical transformation happens after a special number of minutes; each minute of shaking provides only incremental improvement in texture. A longer shake will always get you closer to Ramos&#8217;s &#8220;good rich milk&#8221;—and that is a gorgeous drink—but you&#8217;re most of the way there after four or five minutes.</p>
<p>Labor intensive and time-consuming to prepare, you&#8217;ll rarely find a bartender eager to prepare a Ramos Fizz. You&#8217;ll have to make it yourself, and it will be work, but it&#8217;s a delightful confection, and well worth the effort.</p>
<p>And it doesn&#8217;t take fifteen minutes.</p>
<hr />
<p id="dmf-copyright">“The Ramos Fizz&#8221; at <a title="Drinking the French Quarter: The Ramos Fizz, at Cold Glass" href="http://cold-glass.com/2013/01/16/drinking-the-french-quarter-the-ramos-fizz/">cold-glass.com</a> : All text and photos © 2013 Douglas M. Ford. All rights reserved.</p>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=6493&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://cold-glass.com/2013/01/16/drinking-the-french-quarter-the-ramos-fizz/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>20</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://dmford.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ramos-fizz-4-1204.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://dmford.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ramos-fizz-4-1204.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ramos Fizz</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/b99804c9d8080737d08895eb1735e2b4?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Doug</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://www.smugmug.com/photos/i-Q5XMR6d/0/L/i-Q5XMR6d-L.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The Ramos Fizz, photo © 2013 Douglas M. Ford. All rights reserved.</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Toothbrush, Shampoo, and a Full Change of Personality</title>
		<link>http://apprenticenevermaster.wordpress.com/2013/01/14/flash-fiction-toothbrush-shampoo-and-a-full-change-of-personality-805-words/</link>
		<comments>http://apprenticenevermaster.wordpress.com/2013/01/14/flash-fiction-toothbrush-shampoo-and-a-full-change-of-personality-805-words/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2013 20:29:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>apprenticenevermaster</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing Challenges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[California]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[change]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clothing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flash fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[future]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Greece]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Maine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outdoors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[packing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[postaday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[short story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[silly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[silly things]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://apprenticenevermaster.wordpress.com/?p=622</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Amanda rarely packed for a trip more than twelve hours in advance. She had never forgotten something she couldn&#8217;t live without, and she had never been late for a flight, so she had no definitive proof that she needed to change that habit. However, packing at midnight was pushing it, and she knew that when [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=622&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Amanda rarely packed for a trip more than twelve hours in advance. She had never forgotten something she couldn&#8217;t live without, and she had never been late for a flight, so she had no definitive proof that she needed to change that habit. However, packing at midnight was pushing it, and she knew that when selecting socks and shirts and shampoo became a metaphysical discussion.</p>
<p>It had started with a pair of flip flops. She bought them at the insistence of a friend, who told her that vacationing at a beach without flip-flops was like climbing Kilimanjaro without rope and harness. But Amanda couldn&#8217;t wear the flip-flops without frequently looking over her shoulder to make sure that the tapping noise she heard was not someone following her, and she rarely spent more than a few hours on the sand.</p>
<p>Except that time she&#8217;d gone to Greece. She had fallen in love with jewel blue water and thick sand, the force of the wind and the mixed smell of oranges and salt. Greek beaches had made her into a wader, and a sand-castle builder, and &#8211; at the end of two weeks &#8211; a tanned flip-flop wearer.</p>
<p>That gave Amanda a moment&#8217;s pause. But she was going to California, where the water was cold, and she expected to be more changed by the magnificence of the traffic.</p>
<p>She packed her camera, knowing she&#8217;d only use it once or twice. She picked two books for the flight, then wondered if she would want more. She felt better for having them with her, but she rarely even finished one.</p>
<p>Except for that time in Maine when she spent every evening reading by the lake, idly watching fireflies and listening to the summer breeze rustling trees that were more accustomed to resisting iced gales. She&#8217;d bought extra books on that trip, just to keep eavesdropping on that conversation between wind and leaf.</p>
<p>She looked at the stack &#8211; stared at it really &#8211; then decided that she could afford to spend the time in a bookstore if she really wanted more once she got there.</p>
<p>Then she started into her shirts. She packed all her favorites: t-shirts and her thin, soft sweaters, and tanks for hot days. She picked out a few nice tops for going out to dinner. She put in several pairs of jeans. She packed one dress, in case she need something even nicer. One dress gave her the ability to follow a surprise opportunity. Two dresses meant she would be looking for a place to wear them or else feel silly for having brought them along.</p>
<p>Unless she would want that excuse to do something silly when she arrived. Dancing or taking in a theater show or eating at a restaurant that actually had a maitre de. Or wearing an obviously too-rich outfit, and putting on a British accent while she wandered through a museum to slip into an even more exotic place. She&#8217;d never done anything like that before, and tonight all she wanted to was curl up in a sweatshirt and have a good cup of coffee, or wrap up in a  hoodie and hike a trail. But who could say what Amanda in California would choose.</p>
<p>She examined her closet and pulled out a dress she&#8217;d bought to make Audrey Hepburn proud, and only worn once. She put it out on the bed. She would make her final decision when she saw how much extra space she had.</p>
<p>And then she started stacking other things on the bed. White gloves that had been a joke gift, but seemed to belong on top of that dress. A snorkle she had never used because she&#8217;d been terrified at the idea of accidentally breathing water. Maybe Amanda in California would be inspired to conquer fears. And then the flip-flops, because the snorkle mandated a beach. A sketchbook. Two bottles of nail polish: her favorite, and one that she&#8217;d had for three years and never worn. Her passport, because a night in Mexico wasn&#8217;t out of the question. A warm blanket that smelled like home. A worn out blanket, condemned to picnicking, in case she just wanted a place to sit. CDs. First the ones that were good for passing time on headphones. Then some that was good for dancing, because she was beginning to suspect that Amanda in California might be the kind of person who would set up a boombox in the middle of an open square and start a dance party with strangers.</p>
<p>She stopped herself when she reached for her stereo.</p>
<p>Looking at the things on the bed, she laughed at the range of guesses about who she might be in a few days.</p>
<p>She put everything away and started over at who she was: Amanda, who was getting on a plane in seven hours and needed sleep.</p>
<p>&#8212;</p>
<p>Written half in inspiration from my day&#8217;s activities and half at the impetus of the <a href="http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2013/01/14/writing-challenge-starting-over/">weekly writing challenge</a>:</p>
<p>In this week’s writing challenge, we’re asking you to write a short piece of creative writing (fiction/poetry/prose poetry/freeform mindjazz/whatever floats your boat) on the theme of <em>Starting Over</em>. Drop <em>Starting Over</em> on your page and see where it takes you.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/622/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/622/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=622&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://apprenticenevermaster.wordpress.com/2013/01/14/flash-fiction-toothbrush-shampoo-and-a-full-change-of-personality-805-words/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>24</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/b468b20ade3c7872177db2a75c8e96b4?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F2.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">apprenticenevermaster</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>That Feeling</title>
		<link>http://officialmattroberts.com/2013/01/17/that-feeling/</link>
		<comments>http://officialmattroberts.com/2013/01/17/that-feeling/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2013 05:29:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Matt Roberts</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Shorts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing Challenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[daily press]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[short story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[starting over]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing challenge]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://officialmattroberts.com/?p=315</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Over at The Daily Post they&#8217;ve submitted a writing challenge that I felt the need to participate in. You can read all about it (or participate as well!) here. The prompt is &#8220;Starting Over.&#8221; Henry was standing at the door to an all night convenience store. The door was all glass except for the metal [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=315&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Over at The Daily Post they&#8217;ve submitted a writing challenge that I felt the need to participate in. You can read all about it (or participate as well!) <a href="http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2013/01/14/writing-challenge-starting-over/" target="_blank">here</a>. The prompt is &#8220;Starting Over.&#8221;</em></p>
<p><img src="http://officialmattroberts.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/convenience.jpg?w=720" alt="convenience"   class="alignnone size-full wp-image-322" /><br />
Henry was standing at the door to an all night convenience store. The door was all glass except for the metal frame and the metal handle that stuck out like a giant sideways L. There were stickers all over the door showcasing some tobacco or alcoholic product that was sold inside.</p>
<p>Henry held onto the handle and had a feeling rush over him. That feeling. The one that makes you forget everything for just a second and you question what it is you&#8217;re doing and where you&#8217;re at. Henry had that feeling before, and deja vu, it seemed as if it had happened in this very spot at exactly this moment. That&#8217;s how deja vu works, right?</p>
<p>He opened the door and went inside. The bell above the door jingled and the clerk looked up to see who had just come in. Henry nodded to the clerk and began walking, almost on instinct, towards the back of the store. It was when he was looking on the shelf while walking to the back that he realized what he had come in for, and that feeling he had outside went away.</p>
<p>He had come in for some diapers. His wife had sent him because she thought she had had enough but ran out. Lucky for them this convenience store was just down the street and it was open all night. This wasn&#8217;t the first time they had to make a trip like this. Their baby Kevin was only four months old and they were still getting used to having him in the house.</p>
<p>There was a jingle from the bell above the door and someone else came in. As far as Henry knew this new customer and himself were the only two in the store besides the clerk. It was a Tuesday night after all, so no big surprise there.</p>
<p>Henry looked at the small selection of diapers on the shelf and tried to remember which one his wife had sent him for. His wife&#8230; she popped into his head suddenly and she was crying. Henry&#8217;s face reflected his concern for her, his sadness for her. He wasn&#8217;t sure why, but he felt her pain although he didn&#8217;t know what her pain was for or why it was there. He didn&#8217;t even know how the thought popped into his head. He had just been joking with her before he left to get the diapers.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s why he couldn&#8217;t remember which diapers to get. They had been joking after she told him what kind. He had been giving her grief about running out of diapers and she was making fun of his age and saying how he should be in diapers himself. He was only four years older than her, but she jokingly made fun of his age all the time.</p>
<p>The two laughed at one another and kissed before he walked out of the house twenty minutes prior. He had walked to the store since it was so close and the neighborhood wasn&#8217;t so bad that he felt threatened walking there at night.</p>
<p>Henry heard a commotion near the register but he disregarded it. It sounded as if the cashier and the other customer knew one another and were in a heated argument. Their talking had snapped Henry out of his trance and he got back to why he was there.</p>
<p>He looked at the diapers, thought of calling his wife (although she would no doubt make fun of his memory and his old age for forgetting what brand, or for not knowing what diapers his own child wore) but put his phone away. He grabbed one of the packages and went to the back of the store for a soda. The commotion at the register continued to grow louder and over the store&#8217;s speakers CCR was playing their hit &#8220;Commotion,&#8221; which Henry thought was ironically funny.</p>
<p>He pulled a bottle of Mt. Dew out of the cooler and let the door slam shut. He began walking to the front of the store when the commotion he had been hearing died.</p>
<p>He walked out from between two aisles and saw the other customer, a man wearing a black leather jacket and ripped jeans. His shoes seemed to be rather old as well. He had on a dirty maroon knit cap and his facial hair was a few days old. The man looked at Henry and Henry nodded to him. The man turned back to the counter quickly. &#8220;Come on, hurry up!&#8221;</p>
<p>Frank the cashier, whom Henry had known from coming into the store off and on, stood up from behind the register and was stuffing something into a bag. He looked at Henry with worry on his face. The other customer looked back at Henry and then again at Frank and slammed his hand on the counter. &#8220;Hurry up!&#8221;</p>
<p>Henry couldn&#8217;t tell what was going on, but suddenly the man lifted his other arm and he was holding a gun. Henry fell into that feeling again, as if everything he had done that night up to that point wasn&#8217;t there anymore. None of it was on his mind. He felt confused about the situation, as if it were a dream. Something that had happened long ago, but that he was reliving in the present. Something that no matter what happened he wouldn&#8217;t be able to stop.</p>
<p>Henry just stood there watching as Frank was robbed at gun point. Henry realized without realizing it that Frank was stuffing money into the bag. He didn&#8217;t look at Frank again though, he just stared at the man in front of him with the gun.</p>
<p>That man turned and saw Henry staring at him. &#8220;You saw nothing pal!&#8221;</p>
<p>Henry instinctively shrugged.</p>
<p>The man turned to Frank again and snatched the bag out of his hands. A few dollar bills floated from the bag to the floor.</p>
<p>The man turned to the door and then stopped. Henry didn&#8217;t hear him so well but he was sure he heard the man say to himself, &#8220;Oh fuck it.&#8221; The man spun around, lifted his gun and fired at Frank. Frank flew backwards from the shot, slamming into a cigarette display. Cigarette packs fell from the shelves they were stocked on as Frank&#8217;s body slid down the display until he was no longer visible from where Henry was.</p>
<p>In slow motion Henry witnessed this all taking place. He once again saw his wife crying hysterically. Sobbing. He felt so bad for her, yet so alone. Because he couldn&#8217;t do anything to make her feel better. She was his life, and she was holding their four month old son, rocking him back and forth. Why was he seeing this? She was in such a good mood when he left.</p>
<p>In the continued slow motion, Henry looked from the cigarette display over to the man at the door holding a bag of money and a gun. The man had the gun pointed at Henry. Henry frowned. There was a flash.</p>
<p>He just wanted to rub his hand on her face, let her know everything was going to be okay. He felt bad that he couldn&#8217;t get the diapers to her in time. He hoped their son, Kevin, didn&#8217;t make too much of a mess.</p>
<p>A mess&#8230; Kevin&#8230;</p>
<p>Henry was standing at the door to an all night convenience store. The door was all glass except for the metal frame and the metal handle that stuck out like a giant sideways L. There were stickers all over the door showcasing some tobacco or alcoholic product that was sold inside.</p>
<p>Henry held onto the handle and had a feeling rush over him. That feeling. The one that makes you forget everything for just a second and you question what it is you&#8217;re doing and where you&#8217;re at. Henry had that feeling before, and deja vu, it seemed as if it had happened in this very spot at exactly this moment. That&#8217;s how deja vu works, right?</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/315/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/315/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=315&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://officialmattroberts.com/2013/01/17/that-feeling/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>21</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/890643439cafda5939f60034e7f8c8e8?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">randomdude9</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://officialmattroberts.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/convenience.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">convenience</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Starting Over</title>
		<link>http://reheatedcoffee.wordpress.com/2013/01/15/poetry-tuesday-starting-over/</link>
		<comments>http://reheatedcoffee.wordpress.com/2013/01/15/poetry-tuesday-starting-over/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 17:14:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Reheated Coffee</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Poetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPChallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[keys]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[loss]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[starting over]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weekly writing challenge]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://reheatedcoffee.wordpress.com/?p=826</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[What We Lost Your mother called me yesterday To tell me that she found my keys. The ones you told me you had lost. Or so you say. When I learned that you had decided not to stay, I thought it was because of me. Then your mother called me yesterday to ask me why [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=826&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://reheatedcoffee.wordpress.com/2013/01/15/poetry-tuesday-starting-over/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>36</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://reheatedcoffee.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/reheatedcoffee4.jpg?w=147" />
		<media:content url="http://reheatedcoffee.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/reheatedcoffee4.jpg?w=147" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">reheatedcoffee</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f557db1bf3dfad06d8c9fabfaaa5caf5?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">aspiringcatlady</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Starting Over</title>
		<link>http://wordswewomenwrite.wordpress.com/2013/01/16/weekly-writing-challenge-starting-over/</link>
		<comments>http://wordswewomenwrite.wordpress.com/2013/01/16/weekly-writing-challenge-starting-over/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2013 17:58:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Words We Women Write</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[daily prompt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPchallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weekly writing challenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dailypost]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[John Lennon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[postaday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WordPress]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://wordswewomenwrite.wordpress.com/?p=11638</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#160; Starting Over , A bleak morning. Ground fog, again. It never used to rain so much. And then, slowly, the mist bows to a casual cumulous, and evening cadences fall from a cloud-mouth of stars. The future catches in my throat, musky and delicious. Its name is Start Over and it sits between us [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=11638&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://wordswewomenwrite.wordpress.com/2013/01/16/weekly-writing-challenge-starting-over/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>18</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a21d50e8432a8b38044c4d19d68b6ee1?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tomaropawrite</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://www.importsounds.com/images/JOHN-LENNON_JUST-LIKE-STARTING-OVER_022712.JPG" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Say Goodbye</title>
		<link>http://lmstull.com/2013/01/16/how-to-say-goodbye/</link>
		<comments>http://lmstull.com/2013/01/16/how-to-say-goodbye/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2013 00:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>L.M. Stull</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Short Stories/Poems]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://lmstull.com/?p=3149</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As she stopped to catch her breath, she turned and looked back. Her golden curls bouncing down to her shoulder and then back up to tickle her jaw. Delicate giggles slipped through her thin pink lips. And her small hands held on to the elegant ruffles of her summer dress. It was painful to hear [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3149&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://lmstull.com/2013/01/16/how-to-say-goodbye/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>62</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/3aa66b97259736bf0918da7ee71aad36?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lmstull</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lmstull.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/girl-on-swing-clouds.jpg?w=226" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">girl-on-swing-clouds</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Can’t We Stay Out Of Jodie Foster’s “Closet”?</title>
		<link>http://thenarcissisticanthropologist.com/2013/01/15/why-cant-we-stay-out-of-jodie-fosters-closet-a-perspective-on-celebrity-as-a-fetish/</link>
		<comments>http://thenarcissisticanthropologist.com/2013/01/15/why-cant-we-stay-out-of-jodie-fosters-closet-a-perspective-on-celebrity-as-a-fetish/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 22:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>thenarcissisticanthropologist</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Anthropology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Art and culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Consumer Anthropology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Consumer Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lesbians]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pop culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sociology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Television and Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Arts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[celebrities coming out]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Celebrity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consumer anthropology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Consumerism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture of the United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Golden Globe Award]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hollywood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jodie Foster]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LGBT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sexual orientation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thenarcissisticanthropologist.com/?p=1488</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Let&#8217;s start by defining the word fetish, lest everyone think we are discussing a different kind of topic. According to the Merriam Webster online dictionary, fetish is defined as: a : an object (as a small stone carving of an animal) believed to have magical power to protect or aid its owner; broadly : a [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1488&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://thenarcissisticanthropologist.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/paparazzi.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-1495" alt="paparazzi" src="http://thenarcissisticanthropologist.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/paparazzi.jpg?w=690&#038;h=517" width="690" height="517" /></a></p>
<p>Let&#8217;s start by defining the word fetish, lest everyone think we are discussing a different kind of topic.</p>
<p>According to the Merriam Webster online dictionary, fetish is defined as:</p>
<p><em>a</em> <strong>:</strong> an object (as a small stone carving of an animal) believed to have magical power to protect or aid its owner; <em>broadly</em> <strong>:</strong> a material object regarded with superstitious or extravagant trust or reverence</p>
<p><em>b</em> <strong>:</strong> an object of irrational reverence or obsessive devotion</p>
<p>In the United States and most developed countries, celebrities tend to become the fetish object:  idolized,  revered as almost supernatural superheroes and held to extraordinarily high standards by right of their profession in the public eye and the often super-human paycheck that comes with it.  Celebrities have always been a central focus in consumer culture:  used as marketing tools to convince people that some of their magic-dust will rub off on them if they purchase a product they use publicly or speak for in an ad.</p>
<p>As a public we mostly presume the right to know anything and everything we want about celebrities as we feel it is their obligation to disclose their private lives because they &#8220;put themselves out there&#8221;.</p>
<p>The truth of it is, celebrities are working stiffs like the rest of us.  They do a job, whether it be acting, modeling clothes or playing a sport (let&#8217;s stick with the entertainment-oriented celebrities for the sake of this argument).  They are selling a product: their labor or looks or skill.  They are doing it for love and / or profit.  At the end of the day, the deal they are signing on for, in theory, is to co-opt their image or their skills.</p>
<p>However, in what may be an unpopular argument, I need to point out the fact that celebrities do not sign on to co-opt their personal lives any more than someone who works at a bank or a shipyard.  In most workplaces, we have an unspoken (and sometimes bespoke) rule that our personal lives stay at home when we are at work.  We do our jobs, we choose if we want to put pictures of our families on our desks or share stories about the weekend, but are not expected to make our personal lives part of our work lives.  It&#8217;s why there are designated work hours.</p>
<p>So why do we feel that celebrities owe us something more than what they get paid for?  Why do we feel that they have an obligation to let us in to their private lives?  And in the case of Jodie Foster and other celebrities who happen to be gay or lesbian, why do we feel like they ought to publicly pronounce their sexual orientation to the American public or be ridiculed as a fraud?  Speaking as flag-flying member of the GLBT community who has put in the time as an educator and activist and continues to donate time and money to related causes that promote equality and tolerance, I wholeheartedly say:  leave the celebrities alone!</p>
<p>Jodie Foster makes a few great points in her now all a-Twittered Golden Globe Speech:</p>
<span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='640' height='390' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/pzfEBGN2jSw?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span>
<p>I think it&#8217;s about time that we stopped trying to consume celebrities&#8217; personal lives and just allowed ourselves to be customers of the work they produce &#8211; enjoying it in perspective.  If a celebrity&#8217;s sexual orientation is something they want to share because doing so helps them point to their true north, then so be it.  However, everyone should be able to reserve the right to control the labels they want associated with their metaphorical price tag.  Let&#8217;s allow a celebrity&#8217;s value to be defined by their work and the points of view they choose to put out there for public consumption, just as we allow the value of our brands to be defined by their set of distinct benefits: from what they do to what they publicly stand for.</p>
<p>We should be wary of the concept of privacy being for sale, lest we lose ourselves to a voracious culture of consumption rather than  finding ourselves in a culture of appreciation for the beauty and potential of our human existence.</p>
<p>And let&#8217;s let the famous people keep their personal lives private.</p>
<h6 class="zemanta-related-title" style="font-size:1em;">Related articles</h6>
<ul class="zemanta-article-ul">
<li class="zemanta-article-ul-li"><a href="http://news.yahoo.com/jodie-foster-comes-gay-golden-globes-084628565.html" target="_blank">Jodie Foster comes out as gay at Golden Globes</a> (news.yahoo.com)</li>
<li class="zemanta-article-ul-li"><a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/deb-baer/why-im-so-angry-about-jodi-foster-coming-out_b_2471770.html" target="_blank">Deb Baer: Why I&#8217;m So Angry About Jodie Foster&#8217;s Coming-Out Speech</a> (huffingtonpost.com)</li>
<li class="zemanta-article-ul-li"><a href="http://r.zemanta.com/?u=http%3A//www.guardian.co.uk/commentisfree/2013/jan/15/jodie-foster-coming-out-speech&amp;a=138232780&amp;rid=0000022d-1a5e-000F-0000-0000000005d0&amp;e=209a692cb7323cd03ba4a424284eec8c" target="_blank">Jodie Foster&#8217;s &#8216;coming out&#8217; speech was glorious &#8211; but something bothered me | Patrick Strudwick</a> (guardian.co.uk)</li>
<li class="zemanta-article-ul-li"><a href="http://www.bilerico.com/2013/01/why_jodie_fosters_golden_globes_speech_was_so_infu.php" target="_blank">Why Jodie Foster&#8217;s Golden Globes Speech Was So Infuriating</a> (bilerico.com)</li>
<li class="zemanta-article-ul-li"><a href="http://www.advocate.com/commentary/2013/01/14/editors-letter-why-jodie-foster-left-us-deeply-conflicted" target="_blank">Editor&#8217;s Letter: Why Jodie Foster Left Us Deeply Conflicted</a> (advocate.com)</li>
<li class="zemanta-article-ul-li"><a href="http://impmag.org/2013/01/14/celebrities-privacy-and-fans-a-tangle/" target="_blank">Celebrities, Privacy and Fans: A Tangle</a> (impmag.org)</li>
<li class="zemanta-article-ul-li"><a href="http://gawker.com/5975748/the-sheer-gall-of-celebrities-demanding-privacy" target="_blank">The Sheer Gall of Celebrities Demanding Privacy</a> (gawker.com)</li>
<li class="zemanta-article-ul-li"><a href="http://www.suntimes.com/news/roeper/17577388-452/jodie-fosters-speech-was-dramatic-but-inspirational.html" target="_blank">Jodie Foster&#8217;s speech was dramatic, but inspirational &#8211; Chicago Sun-Times</a> (suntimes.com)</li>
</ul>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1488/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1488/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1488&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thenarcissisticanthropologist.com/2013/01/15/why-cant-we-stay-out-of-jodie-fosters-closet-a-perspective-on-celebrity-as-a-fetish/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>30</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/7395bed2f6708e9f1f5fe174530e96e0?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">thebrandsherpa</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thenarcissisticanthropologist.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/paparazzi.jpg?w=690" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">paparazzi</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
