<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2012 22:02:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>On Elephants, Obsessions &amp; Wicked Problems: A New Phenomenology of News</title>
		<link>http://newsthing.net/2012/09/16/quartz-obsessions-phenomenology-of-news/</link>
		<comments>http://newsthing.net/2012/09/16/quartz-obsessions-phenomenology-of-news/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2012 18:51:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Gideon</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://newsthing.net/?p=155</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Goodbye to the beat The first “beat reporters” were probably the men sent by newspapers to hang around the criminal courts in the early 19th century. Today almost every news outlet is organized around fixed beats: “financial markets”, “real estate”, &#8220;technology&#8221;, and so on. These are now so ingrained that we see them as an [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=155&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>Goodbye to the beat</h3>
<p>The first “beat reporters” were probably the men sent by newspapers to hang around the criminal courts in the early 19th century. Today almost every news outlet is organized around fixed beats: “financial markets”, “real estate”, &#8220;technology&#8221;, and so on. These are now so ingrained that we see them as an actual description of reality—the things the world is made of.</p>
<p>Yet the <strong>beats aren&#8217;t so much an objective taxonomy as a convenient management tool, </strong>devised for an old technology. When news came in a sheaf of pages it made sense to divide them into sections—domestic, foreign, business, and so on—with an editor and a team of writers for each one, and make each writer responsible for a slice of that section: a beat. Matching people to pages made managing the newspaper easier, and covering all the news in each beat allowed it to be comprehensive—which was how it could appeal to the most readers and get the most sales.</p>
<p>Online, however, trying to be the one comprehensive publication makes no sense. Readers can browse hundreds of news sites at no extra cost. That drives the sites to specialise. Yet most still structure themselves around fixed sections and beats. Slide your mouse across the navigation bar at the top of almost any news site, and there they are, the phantom limbs of the newspaper creatures of old. It hasn&#8217;t occurred to them that <strong>when there are no pages and sections to constrain you, you are free to reframe your description of reality too.</strong></p>
<p>At <a href="http://qz.com" target="_blank">Quartz</a>, we&#8217;ll try to fit the framework to the audience. We want to reach a global, cosmopolitan crowd, people who see themselves as living &#8220;in the world&#8221;. They are keenly aware of how distant events influence one another; their lives and careers are subject to constant disruption from changes in technology and the global economy.</p>
<p>So instead of fixed beats, <strong>we structure our newsroom around an ever-evolving collection of phenomena</strong>—the patterns, trends and seismic shifts that are shaping the world our readers live in. &#8220;Financial markets&#8221; is a beat, but &#8220;the financial crisis&#8221; is a phenomenon. &#8220;The environment&#8221; is a beat, but &#8220;climate change&#8221; is a phenomenon. “Energy” is a beat, but “the global surge of energy abundance” is a phenomenon. “China” is a beat, but “Chinese investment in Africa” is a phenomenon. <strong>We call these phenomena our &#8220;obsessions&#8221;</strong>. These are the kinds of topics Quartz will put in its navigation bar, and as the world changes, so will they.</p>
<h3>Seeing like people, not like organisations</h3>
<p>This is both a practical and a philosophical shift. Practical, because reporting these themes within a traditional beat structure is difficult: they often cut across beat boundaries, taking in politics, economics, technology, and other issues. Our journalists have to be, to some extent, all-rounders, who aren&#8217;t afraid to get outside their usual expertise and track the topic they&#8217;re following wherever it leads.</p>
<p>And philosophical, because it means changing what might (a little pretentiously) be called the phenomenology of journalism. Phenomenology is about how we structure our  experience of the world. Beats provide an institutional structure. Obsessions are a more human one.</p>
<p>What I mean by this is that when people notice a change in the world around them—a phenomenon—they don&#8217;t care what beat it belongs to; they just want to know what caused it. The institutional framework answers the question like the blind men in the Indian parable who are brought an elephant and asked to say what it is. The one who touches the elephant&#8217;s leg says it is a pillar or tree trunk, the one who feels the tail declares it to be a rope, and so on. But to unpack something like the financial crisis you can&#8217;t simply talk about securities, interest rates and banking regulation; to understand China&#8217;s activities in other parts of the world you need to be more than just a China specialist; to comprehend climate change you need science, economics, domestic and international politics, and more besides. <strong>To explain the world&#8217;s big phenomena you need to see (or feel) the whole elephant</strong>.</p>
<h3>Quartz&#8217;s wicked problem</h3>
<p>Doing this is hard, of course. It&#8217;s hard firstly because our institutions—academic, governmental, journalistic—create specialists. It takes time for someone to learn enough about each specialism to do good work that cuts across them. It&#8217;s hard secondly because while beats are pretty well established, reasonable people may disagree on what does and doesn&#8217;t count as a &#8220;phenomenon&#8221; worth paying attention to, or where its boundaries should lie.</p>
<p>And that&#8217;s because of a third difficulty: <strong>A lot of the phenomena we want to look at are so-called &#8220;<a href="http://www.apsc.gov.au/publications-and-media/archive/publications-archive/tackling-wicked-problems">wicked problems</a>&#8220;</strong>, a term used in policy and management studies. Jay Rosen of NYU, who has written thought-provokingly about how journalists might report on them, outlined the <a href="http://pressthink.org/2012/06/covering-wicked-problems/#p4" target="_blank">traits of a wicked problem</a> thus:</p>
<blockquote><p>It is hard to say what the problem is, to define it clearly or to tell where it stops and starts. There is no “right” way to view the problem, no definitive formulation. There are many stakeholders, all with their own frames, which they tend to see as exclusively correct. Ask what the problem is and you will get a different answer from each. Someone can always say that the problem is just a symptom of another problem and that someone will not be wrong. The problem is inter-connected to a lot of other problems; pulling them apart is almost impossible. In a word: it’s a mess.</p></blockquote>
<p>Climate change is the archetypal wicked problem, but there are lots of others, like obesity, domestic violence, the drug trade, and certain epidemics. And then there are phenomena that are not necessarily problems, but are complex in the same wicked way: demographic change, the shifting role of the state, the long-term effects of the financial crisis. Even once you&#8217;ve identified a phenomenon worth covering, how do you make it manageable? How do you decide where it starts and ends? How do you follow it as an incrementally evolving news story while also helping your audience grasp the bigger picture?</p>
<p>That&#8217;s what Quartz will have to figure out. Reframing news in this way is its own wicked problem. Let&#8217;s see how we do.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/155/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/155/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=155&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://newsthing.net/2012/09/16/quartz-obsessions-phenomenology-of-news/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c8db1b0ab8dbe8a5770816079b02cb62?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Gideon</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8220;Boardwalk&#8221; Walking</title>
		<link>http://bettysbrownies.wordpress.com/2012/09/14/boardwalk-walking/</link>
		<comments>http://bettysbrownies.wordpress.com/2012/09/14/boardwalk-walking/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2012 22:11:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bettysbrownies</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Boardwalk Empire]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://bettysbrownies.wordpress.com/?p=991</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This is a big week for &#8220;Boardwalk Empire&#8221;&#8211;its second season just appeared on Blu-Ray/DVD, and this Sunday will see the premiere of its third season on HBO. I&#8217;m curious as to the direction the show will take at this point, after the murder of one of its leading characters. Jimmy Darmody was no hero, but [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=991&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://bettysbrownies.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/boardwalk-empire.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-992" title="Boardwalk Empire" src="http://bettysbrownies.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/boardwalk-empire.jpg?w=300&h=171" alt="" width="300" height="171" /></a>This is a big week for &#8220;Boardwalk Empire&#8221;&#8211;its second season just appeared on Blu-Ray/DVD, and this Sunday will see the premiere of its third season on HBO. I&#8217;m curious as to the direction the show will take at this point, after the murder of one of its leading characters. Jimmy Darmody was no hero, but we saw much of the &#8220;Boardwalk&#8221; world through his eyes. He&#8217;s not easily replaced.</p>
<p>When my Season 2 set arrived from Amazon, I immediately cued up the most notorious episode the show has aired to date: <a title="Under God's Power" href="https://bettysbrownies.wordpress.com/2011/12/04/boardwalk-empire-what-a-ride/" target="_blank">&#8220;Under God&#8217;s Power She Flourishes,&#8221; </a>when all is revealed&#8212;and then some&#8212;about Gillian and Jimmy&#8217;s relationship. What a heartbreak this is, from the very beginning when we hear Angela&#8217;s &#8220;Jimmy, I&#8217;ve got to leave,&#8221; as if in a dream. And then to see Jimmy as a teen-ager, before his service in World War I, before all the killing we&#8217;d already seen him commit. If you&#8217;d like to know what a fine work &#8220;Boardwalk Empire&#8221; really is, watch this episode again, this time with the excellent commentary of among others, Gretchen Mol (who for the record was as icked out as the rest of us by Gillian&#8217;s behavior). Then go back and watch Season 1 from start to finish, and you&#8217;ll find that the show&#8217;s creators were amazingly consistent in character development with respect to Jimmy, Gillian and Angela. I suspect they had &#8220;Under God&#8217;s Power She Flourishes&#8221; in mind from the inception of the show, but waited until just the right time to pull that rabbit out of the hat.</p>
<p>Watching Season 1 again is seeing Jimmy lose his humanity, bit by bit, over the course of time. He&#8217;s genuinely contrite&#8212;he even has tears in his eyes&#8212;when he apologizes to Nucky about the booze robbery in the woods gone wrong that left five Rothstein accomplices dead.  After he flees to Chicago and sees his favorite prostitute have her face cut up by a rival gang member, he starts his slide. For the remainder of Season 1, Thug Jimmy and Compassionate Jimmy alternate. He beats the boardwalk photographer, Dittrich, unmercifully while Angela and Tommy look on in terror, yet he takes Angela back after her abortive attempt to run away with Mary Dittrich. Throughout this season and the next, we&#8217;re constantly reminded of what the war did to Jimmy, and when we ultimately learn the full extent of the damage his mother caused, it&#8217;s no surprise to see him welcome death at Nucky&#8217;s hands.</p>
<p>After Season 1, &#8220;Boardwalk Empire&#8221; lost a good deal of its social scope&#8212;no more WCTU, suffragettes, the original Ponzi scheme, incubator babies or those Margaret Sanger pamphlets on birth control. Season 2 saw Jimmy&#8217;s murder and the loss of an intriguingly complex character whom we could alternately sympathize with and be repulsed by. These are important subtractions from a show that can easily become just a Jazz Age version of &#8220;The Sopranos.&#8221; &#8220;Boardwalk Empire&#8221; needs to go back to what made it so intriguing in its first season&#8212;the character development against a strong social and political backdrop. The good news is Chalky White is still on the scene, hopefully along with more discussion of the significant African-American presence in Atlantic City. I&#8217;d like to see more politics, especially since the new season skips ahead in time to 1923, when the Teapot Dome Scandal breaks and Nucky&#8217;s friends in Washington are about to go down. Don&#8217;t get me wrong&#8212;I could watch Michael Stuhlbarg as Arnold Rothstein outsmart everyone for hours at a time&#8212;but I&#8217;d like to see more of Atlantic City in its hey day. In other words, more Eddie Cantor, fewer blood baths.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve got my fingers crossed for Sunday&#8217;s premiere. I hope I&#8217;m not disappointed.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/991/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/991/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=991&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://bettysbrownies.wordpress.com/2012/09/14/boardwalk-walking/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/fa6ed4a01693768d611475296ee8eb66?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bettysbrownies</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://bettysbrownies.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/boardwalk-empire.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Boardwalk Empire</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Scent of Old Book</title>
		<link>http://multoghost.wordpress.com/2012/09/16/the-scent-of-old-book/</link>
		<comments>http://multoghost.wordpress.com/2012/09/16/the-scent-of-old-book/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2012 00:36:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>nzumel</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Musings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[memories]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://multoghost.wordpress.com/?p=741</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In search of something to read this fine Sunday afternoon, I picked up a book I bought for five dollars the other weekend, a hopefully-not-too dry Anthropology collection from forty-five years ago. Opening it up to a random page, I found that familiar, but increasingly rare fragrance: the scent of old book. Photo: Nina Zumel [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=741&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In search of something to read this fine Sunday afternoon, I picked up a book I bought for five dollars the other weekend, a hopefully-not-too dry Anthropology collection from forty-five years ago. Opening it up to a random page, I found that familiar, but increasingly rare fragrance: the scent of old book.</p>
<div style="width:image width px;font-size:80%;text-align:center;">
<img style="display:block;margin-left:auto;margin-right:auto;" src="http://multoghost.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/book.jpg" alt="Book" border="0" />Photo: Nina Zumel
</div>
</p>
<p>I don&#8217;t know how to describe the smell, it&#8217;s just &#8212; old book. My lack of descriptive power tells you all you need to know about why I don&#8217;t make my living as a creative writer. What can I say? It smells good. It&#8217;s a little bit chemical, a little bit dusty. It smells like old paper, old good paper. Old letters smell like that, too. Old newspaper clippings, I think, don&#8217;t.</p>
<p>It smells like my grandmother, too, like the smell of her clothes folded neatly and tucked into her dresser way back when I was little, and she still lived with us. It&#8217;s the smell of the drawer of her bedside table, filled with her rosary and novena booklets, prayer cards and usually a romance novel. </p>
<p>Some of my mother&#8217;s clothes had that smell, clothes she had in the Philippines. Little peach dresses and beautiful, translucent camisa blouses, or <em>baro</em>, with their elaborate embroidery. I used to try the camisas on, hoping for a chance to wear them some day. I don&#8217;t think I ever did.</p>
<div style="width:image width px;font-size:80%;text-align:center;">
<img style="display:block;margin-left:auto;margin-right:auto;" src="http://multoghost.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/baro-002-002.png" alt="Baro 002 002" border="0" />The shawl-like lace blouses are camisas like my mother&#8217;s. Hers were made of embroidered material like the shirts on the right.<br />The top blouse is made of <em>jusi</em> (silk now, but originally banana fiber); the bottom one is made of piña (fiber from pineapple leaves).
</div>
</p>
<p>I remember being with a friend a few years ago, as she unpacked a box of goodies sent over by relatives in Punjab. The box was filled with the 2-meter-or-so long bright colorful stoles called <em>dupattas</em>, along with boxes of bangles and packets of bindis, <em>parandis</em> for our hair. I lifted out a multicolored tie-dyed <em>dupatta</em> and waved it open.</p>
<p>&#8220;Smells like India,&#8221; another friend commented. I had been thinking it smelled like the Philippines. It was <em>that</em> smell.</p>
<div style="width:image width px;font-size:80%;text-align:center;">
<img style="display:block;margin-left:auto;margin-right:auto;" src="http://multoghost.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/p1000635.jpg" alt="P1000635" />Photo: Nina Zumel
</div>
</p>
<p>I used to think of it as the smell as mothballs, I guess because of my grandmother. But it can&#8217;t be that, because why would books smell of mothballs? It isn&#8217;t India, it isn&#8217;t the Philippines. Or I should say, it isn&#8217;t <em>only</em> India, and not just the Philippines. It&#8217;s the smell of Somewhere Else. </p>
<p>And it&#8217;s also the scent of memories.</p>
<hr />
<p>UPDATE: Welcome to all of you who are visiting via Freshly Pressed! I hope you like what you see. Thanks again to the WordPress editors for choosing this post to be featured.</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://multoghost.wordpress.com/category/books/'>Books</a>, <a href='http://multoghost.wordpress.com/category/musings/'>Musings</a> Tagged: <a href='http://multoghost.wordpress.com/tag/memories/'>memories</a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=741&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://multoghost.wordpress.com/2012/09/16/the-scent-of-old-book/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>88</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/711aaeda73efb6c99d1944d67f918474?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">nzumel</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://multoghost.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/book.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Book</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://multoghost.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/baro-002-002.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Baro 002 002</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://multoghost.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/p1000635.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">P1000635</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Story of an RNC Runner</title>
		<link>http://steampunkjournalist.wordpress.com/2012/09/16/the-story-of-an-rnc-runner/</link>
		<comments>http://steampunkjournalist.wordpress.com/2012/09/16/the-story-of-an-rnc-runner/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2012 19:03:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>daylinamiller</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Florida]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gop2012]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[msnbc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NBC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NBC News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[republican national convention]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RNC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rnc2012]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[runner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tampa]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://steampunkjournalist.wordpress.com/?p=2290</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[When I applied for a runner position at NBC News for the 2012 Republican National Convention in Tampa, I had no idea what I was getting myself into. I just knew that I had to be one of those 15,000-something journalists getting in on a piece of history. Getting behind the scenes on a political [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2290&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When I applied for a runner position at NBC News for the 2012 Republican National Convention in Tampa, I had no idea what I was getting myself into. I just knew that I had to be one of those 15,000-something journalists getting in on a piece of history.</p>
<p>Getting behind the scenes on a political convention can be a once-in-a-lifetime opportunity for some people. The Republican National Convention and Democratic National Convention only happen once every four years and unless you have an in, like a media pass, you might never make it past the temporary concrete boundaries and fences set up by local police.</p>
<p>A runner, according to Manager of News Partnerships for NBC and my supervisor at the RNC, Kim Grabina-Como, is a “glorified intern.” You get paid, you only work for a short time frame (in my case, eight days), and you are able to work with a national news network. Currently, regular interns at NBC News aren’t paid, Grabina-Como said, but the network is changing that in 2013.</p>
<p>For anybody who wants to get into the industry, it&#8217;s a way to see stuff from behind the scenes. “You see the good, the bad and the ugly. It gives you a real, true feel for it in the fact that if this is the industry you want to get into, you can see it for what it is,” Grabina-Como said.</p>
<p>I got assigned to MSNBC’s set at the Channelside District in Tampa for the RNC.</p>
<p>You see on-air talent without their makeup and coming to set frustrated by traffic and the stress of such a large production. Supervisors, production managers, and other runners snap at each other on occasion when they’re overwhelmed and stressed out and you have to let it slide off your back-  it’s not personal. I spent one lunch break in the tiny bathroom in the temporary MSNBC command center at Channelside bawling my eyes out for getting yelled at by a supervisor for not having my cell phone on me, though I’d been upfront with them two days earlier when I broke it. Long days kept me from seeking a replacement- the AT&amp;T store opened after I got on set and closed long before I left. It teaches you to have a thicker skin, which you’re going to need in the industry if you want to make it.</p>
<p>On the flip-side, I got to network with media professionals, pass out some of my new business cards, and goof off at the Goggle+ Hangout at the Tampa</p>
<div id="attachment_2292" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://steampunkjournalist.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/google-hangout-irl-rnc.jpeg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-2292 " title="google hangout IRL RNC" src="http://steampunkjournalist.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/google-hangout-irl-rnc.jpeg?w=300&h=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Dani and myself goofing off in the Google+ Hangout photobooth on a break.</p></div>
<p>Convention Center while I was on break. While there, I took advantage of their photobooth and grabbed some button swag to add to my growing collection.</p>
<p>That week, Tropical Storm Isaac also threatened to rush through with heavy wind and rains. It delayed the start of the convention by one day but ended up being a pretty typical Florida summer rainstorm but you still have to make sure TV screens, speakers, mics and other assortments of equipment are stored and being used where they can’t be damaged. Every gust of wind and hint of rain sent members of the production crew scurrying to cover and relocate equipment. You have to be prepared for weather changes during live shots.</p>
<p>Runners for NBC were required to sign a social media contract agreeing not to post photos, tweets, Facebook statuses or any other form of social communication about the specifics of their jobs. The purpose, Grabina-Como said, wasn’t to dissuade student journalists from using social media as a tool in their work. Unfortunately, while most 20-somethings know how to use social media tools, they don’t always have the discretion to use them professionally and during your time as a runner, you are an employee and representative of the news network you’re hired by.</p>
<p>I got this blog post approved, which I normally wouldn’t do in my day-to-day job as a journalist. However, I knew I wouldn’t be producing any content for the RNC as part of my position and I didn’t expect to even write this blog post.</p>
<p><strong>What you can expect as a runner</strong></p>
<p>Runners are there to assist network news stations in any way they are asked to make sure the production process goes smoothly. Sometimes your responsibilities are as basic as fetching food and coffee for on-air talent, managers and the production crew but every bit of help you offer helps make the production possible.</p>
<div id="attachment_2293" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://steampunkjournalist.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/614617_10152093472990195_312315151_o-copy.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-2293 " title="614617_10152093472990195_312315151_o copy" src="http://steampunkjournalist.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/614617_10152093472990195_312315151_o-copy.jpg?w=300&h=223" alt="" width="300" height="223" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Sitting in for the Meet the Press on-air talent so that the production crew could test lighting, audio and camera angles.</p></div>
<p>Since I was a local, I was sent out in the rental car often to purchase and pick up things like studio chairs and supplies. I also dropped off press credentials at various hotels for other NBC employees and sat in for on-air talent before the convention while the photojournalists and production crew tested audio, lighting and camera angles. On my final day as a runner, I assisted with payroll paperwork for freelance production crew employees and helped clean up the temporary command center MSNBC called home for a couple weeks.</p>
<p>In between my assigned tasks, I connected with my fellow runners, students from various fields of study, and journalism professionals like my Twitter friend, Mark Luckie, the Manager of Journalism and News at Twitter.</p>
<p>Omar Jimenez, a broadcast journalism student at Northwestern University, was assigned to work in NBC news studio and to programs like Meet the Press, Nightly News and other specials.</p>
<p>“I had an opportunity to meet and talk to all those anchors,” Jimenez said. “I didn&#8217;t get a chance to do much journalism but just being around the people you want to work for one day, taking out trash, getting drinks and food and running errands, being around those people was great and I made a lot of connections.”</p>
<p>As a freelancer for local newspapers and news sites whose degree focused on print and online journalism, I was clueless as to what it takes to put together a live broadcast, especially for a major event like the RNC. It was eye-opening even for broadcast journalism students like Eric Burse, who studies at the University of Southern California:</p>
<p>“Before going there, I wouldn’t have known what exactly it means for a network to broadcast live from a location,” Burse said. “The technical operations, administrative stuff, workspaces, coordination from network to get everything going, especially with NBC and all their platforms. You can only learn so much from class and this was an opportunity that most college students in their four years don’t get.”</p>
<p><strong>Advice and tips</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>You’re going to work long hours, sometimes as many as 14+, so wear comfortable shoes. Dressy, flat baby doll shoes or nice sneakers for the ladies and comfortable dress shoes for men. I made the mistake of wearing dressy sandals one day and had to tend to my blisters for a week afterward.</li>
<li>Bring sunscreen. Many of us had to run errands between the Tampa Convention Center, Tampa Bay Times Forum and Channelside district. With the road closures and wait times for the shuttle, walking is easier but you risk sunburn without protection.</li>
<li>Lug around as little as possible. You won’t have time to keep an eye on your stuff and even a small purse or bag seems to weigh a ton after a long day of running errands.</li>
<li>Keep your phone handy, preferably one with a camera so you can document history in the making, so that your supervisors and fellow runners can touch base with you. Always have a notepad and pen at the ready to jot down notes and instructions and don’t forget to bring business cards to hand out to professionals you network with on your downtime.</li>
<li>Make sure your online portfolio, resume and LinkedIn profile are up-to-date and that all your social media profiles are professional prior to the convention, especially if you’re guiding people there via a business card. As budding journalists, you should be doing that anyway.</li>
<li>Do research about the network you were hired by. This tip comes from Grabina-Como who related a story about a runner being excited to meet Diane Sawyer. “She doesn’t work for us,” Grabina- Como said. Familiarize yourself with the specials and the on-air talent beforehand.</li>
<li>Have an open attitude.  Grabina-Como attended the 1998 Winter Olympics in Nagano, Japan as a runner for CBS News. “I went into the Olympics wanting to be a sports reporter and came out realizing there were so many other things I could do.”</li>
</ul>
<p>While several of the runners, most of whom were college students or recent graduates, were journalism or political science majors, not all aspired to work in politics or cover news one day. Their majors ranged from history to English.</p>
<p>“Even if you&#8217;re not interested in television journalism or political science, we had 52 runners that got an experience that few in your generation get,” Grabina-Como said. “It&#8217;s once every four years that you get the chance to be a part of something bigger.”</p>
<p>I encourage other journalism students and recent graduates to apply for runner positions with major news networks regardless of your journalism track. Expect to work until your legs and back ache, to go without sleep and drink way too much coffee, to be ordered around and yelled at for things beyond your control, and to be overwhelmed beyond imagination. If you can handle all of that, you’ve got what it takes to work in the industry.</p>
<p>Also, journalists are increasingly expected to know multimedia and convergence is no longer the future, but the present. What better way to experience that than as someone who gets to see it from the front line?</p>
<div id="attachment_2294" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://steampunkjournalist.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/a-zombie-rnc.jpeg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-2294 " title="a zombie rnc" src="http://steampunkjournalist.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/a-zombie-rnc.jpeg?w=300&h=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">A. Zombi, a &#8220;presidential hopeful,&#8221; and his wife dropped by the MSNBC set at Channelside with the zombie horde trailing behind them. Just one of the many interesting, weird things you get to see at a political convention.</p></div>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2290/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2290/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2290&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://steampunkjournalist.wordpress.com/2012/09/16/the-story-of-an-rnc-runner/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/1218d654da70208e6c160a73c95aa6de?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">daylinamiller</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steampunkjournalist.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/google-hangout-irl-rnc.jpeg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">google hangout IRL RNC</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steampunkjournalist.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/614617_10152093472990195_312315151_o-copy.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">614617_10152093472990195_312315151_o copy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://steampunkjournalist.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/a-zombie-rnc.jpeg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">a zombie rnc</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Libya and Yemen – Actually Different Places.</title>
		<link>http://emilylhauserinmyhead.wordpress.com/2012/09/13/libya-and-yemen-actually-different-places/</link>
		<comments>http://emilylhauserinmyhead.wordpress.com/2012/09/13/libya-and-yemen-actually-different-places/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2012 16:08:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>emilylhauser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Foreign Relations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Middle East/North Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chris Stevens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[embassy attack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Libya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yemen]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://emilylhauserinmyhead.wordpress.com/?p=11273</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This week the US lost an apparently highly skilled and much-loved diplomat to the vagaries of violent extremism and a weak central government, and, possibly, the failure of the Foreign Service to adequately protect its Ambassador in the face of terrible upheaval (including &#8220;a string of assassinations [in Benghazi] as well as attacks on international missions&#8221;). [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=11273&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_11286" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://emilylhauserinmyhead.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/mena-map-3.png"><img class="size-full wp-image-11286 " title="mena map 3" src="http://emilylhauserinmyhead.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/mena-map-3.png" alt="" width="600" height="271" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">And to top it off, they&#8217;re 2100 miles apart.<br />*<br />(Please note: This is the third map I&#8217;ve posted, because they&#8217;re all wrong in some way. Here, Palestine should be listed next to Israel, but is completely ignored. Apparently it&#8217;s really hard to find up-to-date, non-exclusionary maps of MENA online).</p></div>
<p style="text-align:left;">This week the US lost an apparently highly skilled and much-loved diplomat to the vagaries of violent extremism and a weak central government, and, possibly, <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2012/09/13/world/middleeast/us-envoy-to-libya-is-reported-killed.html?_r=2&amp;hp&amp;pagewanted=all">the failure of the Foreign Service to adequately protect its Ambassador in the face of terrible upheaval</a> (including &#8220;a string of assassinations [in Benghazi] as well as attacks on international missions&#8221;).</p>
<p>The Libyan people responded to this horrific turn of events in a genuinely moving way, many spontaneously demonstrating in support of the United States and expressing their sorrow over Ambassador Chris Stevens&#8217;s murder. Signs read <a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/international/archive/2012/09/the-other-protest-in-libya/262308/">&#8220;Thugs and killers don&#8217;t represent Benghazi or Islam&#8221;</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/emilylhauser/status/246010988892143616">&#8220;USA: We are sorry. We are sad.&#8221;</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/BentBenghazi/status/245948333804384256/photo/1">&#8220;Sorry people of America this is not the behavior of our Islam &amp; Prophet.&#8221;</a>  Words of condolence and statements of grief came pouring out, from the government to journalists to folks on Twitter and Facebook &#8212; these Libyans share our loss, and they wanted to make sure we know that they have no affection for those Libyans who attacked our consulate, ostensibly in reaction to an offensive film about the Prophet Muhammad (<a href="http://www.google.com/hostednews/ap/article/ALeqM5irzV3mhzHowp-BNTb1QT4-lEHFng?docId=e292f17c57bf4d068c9c633767eb19bd">though signs are emerging that the attack may have been planned well in advance</a> [UPDATE 9/16/12: <a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/the-fix/wp/2012/09/16/libyan-president-attack-on-u-s-consulate-was-premeditated/">US Ambassador to the UN says the attacks began spontaneously; the President of Libya disagrees</a>).</p>
<p>Today, on the other hand, <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2012/09/14/world/middleeast/mideast-turmoil-spreads-to-us-embassy-in-yemen.html?pagewanted=all">hundreds of Yemenis stormed the embassy in the capital city of Sana'a</a>, in reaction to that very same offensive film.</p>
<p>You see, it turns out that Arabs and Muslims are as many and varied as any other set of humans.</p>
<p>Many Libyans hold the United States in affection and high regard, because America helped them gain their freedom from a terrible tyrant. We didn't roll in and push people aside, we helped the people already there to do what they wanted to do. Their new government is weak and (as the recent turmoil clearly indicates) not entirely well established, but Libyans can look behind and look ahead and see the potential for better -- and that's thanks to us. That's why <a href="http://www.gallup.com/poll/156539/Opinion-Briefing-Libyans-Eye-New-Relations-West.aspx">Libya has the highest approval rating for the United States in the Middle East and North Africa</a> outside of Israel.</p>
<p>On the other hand, <a href="http://www.thenation.com/article/166265/washingtons-war-yemen-backfires">as Jeremy Scahill reported for The Nation in February</a>, this is what we've been doing in Yemen:</p>
<blockquote><p><em>[In the spring of 2011], rather than fighting AQAP [Al Qaeda in the Arabian Peninsula], US-backed units—created and funded with the explicit intent to be used only for counterterrorism operations—redeployed to Sanaa to protect the collapsing regime from its own people. The US-supported units exist “mostly for the defense of the regime,” says [Abdul Ghani al Iryani, a well-connected political analyst]&#8230;. President Obama’s top counterterrorism adviser, John Brennan, acknowledged late last year that the “political tumult” has caused the US-trained units “to be focused on their positioning for internal political purposes as opposed to doing all they can against AQAP.”</em></p>
<p><em>&#8230;Even as demonstrations grew against the Saleh regime, US officials praised his government’s cooperation. “I can say today the counterterrorism cooperation with Yemen is better than it’s been during my whole tenure,” Brennan declared in September.</em></p>
<p><em>But US counterterrorism policy is extremely unpopular in Yemen&#8230;.</em></p>
<p><em>By last summer, the Obama administration had begun construction on a secret air base on the Arabian peninsula, closer than its base in Djibouti, that could serve as a launching pad for expanded drone strikes in Yemen. The September [2011] drone strike that killed US citizen Anwar al-Awlaki was reportedly launched from that new base, which analysts suspect is either in Saudi Arabia or Oman, both of which border Yemen&#8230;. The Americans have also provided real-time intelligence, obtained by drones, to Yemeni forces in [the hotly contested province of Abyan]. “It has been an active partnership. The Americans help primarily with logistics and intelligence,” [Gen. Mohammed al-Sumali] says. “Then we pound the positions with artillery or airstrikes.”</em></p>
<p><em>&#8230;Some of the unilateral strikes have killed their intended targets, such as the CIA attack on Awlaki. But others have killed civilians—at times, a lot of civilians. And many of these have been in Abyan and its neighboring province of Shebwa, both of which have recently seen a substantial rise of AQAP activity. President Obama’s first known authorization of a missile strike on Yemen, on December 17, 2009, killed more than forty Bedouins, many of them women and children, in the remote village of al Majala in Abyan. Another US strike, in May 2010, killed an important tribal leader and the deputy governor of Marib province, Jabir Shabwani, sparking mass anger at the United States and {then-President] Saleh’s government. “I think these airstrikes were based on false intelligence from the regime, because that is the nature of the contractor,” [opposition leader Mohammad] Qahtan charges. “The contractor wants to create more work in return for earning more money.”</em></p>
<p><em>&#8230;The October drone strike that killed Awlaki’s 16-year-old son, Abdulrahman, a US citizen, and his teenage cousin shocked and enraged Yemenis of all political stripes. “I firmly believe that the [military] operations implemented by the US performed a great service for Al Qaeda, because those operations gave Al Qaeda unprecedented local sympathy,” says [Abdul Rezzaq al Jamal, an independent Yemeni journalist]. The strikes “have recruited thousands.” Yemeni tribesmen, he says, share one common goal with Al Qaeda, “which is revenge against the Americans, because those who were killed are the sons of the tribesmen, and the tribesmen never, ever give up on revenge.” Even senior officials of the Saleh regime recognize the damage the strikes have caused. “People certainly resent these [US] interventions,” Qirbi, the foreign minister and a close Saleh ally, concedes.</em></p>
<p><em>For the United States, the most serious question that lingers over Yemen after [President] Ali Abdullah Saleh is: Did US counterterrorism policy strengthen the very threat it sought to eliminate? “It was a major fiasco,” Iryani says of the past decade of US counterterrorism policy in Yemen. “I think if we had been left alone, we would have less terrorists in Yemen than we do now.”</em></p>
<p>(Note: This is only a small portion of a truly excellent piece of reporting. I highly recommend that you read the whole thing &#8211; <a href="http://www.thenation.com/article/166265/washingtons-war-yemen-backfires">click here</a>).</p></blockquote>
<p>And just to be clear: President Saleh may have <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/commentisfree/2011/nov/24/yemen-ali-abdullah-saleh-resigns">resigned last November</a>, but his family and cronies <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/commentisfree/2011/nov/24/yemen-ali-abdullah-saleh-resigns">still retain a firm grip on power</a> &#8211; <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2012/aug/21/yemen-protests-continue-after-saleh">which is why Yemenis are still protesting</a>.</p>
<p>So it turns out that Yemenis and Libyans are autonomous actors, human beings who respond to others in a manner that reflects their relationship with those people.</p>
<p>There are, of course, many, many differences between the two countries, not least Libya&#8217;s much higher level of education and much lower rate of poverty, and all the complex, domino results that such factors create in two societies that are already very different. The position of women, life expectancy, the function of tribal alliances &#8212; all of these play different roles in each country.</p>
<p>But one simple thing may still be said: Help a nation topple a tyrant and reclaim their own power? They&#8217;ll probably like you. Help a tyrant kill his own enemies and then allow his power base to stay in control? The people he ruled might not like you so much. <a href="http://www.gallup.com/poll/142631/Worldwide-Leadership-Approval.aspx">To the tune of an 18% approval rating</a>.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/11273/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/11273/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=11273&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://emilylhauserinmyhead.wordpress.com/2012/09/13/libya-and-yemen-actually-different-places/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>23</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/5e861047c6a51ca75636af267294adf9?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">emilylhauser</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://emilylhauserinmyhead.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/mena-map-3.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mena map 3</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Romney&#8217;s &#8220;Jello&#8221; Strategy Fails</title>
		<link>http://scotterb.wordpress.com/2012/09/16/why-romneys-jello-strategy-fails/</link>
		<comments>http://scotterb.wordpress.com/2012/09/16/why-romneys-jello-strategy-fails/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2012 14:35:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Scott Erb</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[2012 Election]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Barack Obama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Democrats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fiscal Cliff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mitt Romney]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Republicans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[US Politics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://scotterb.wordpress.com/?p=7385</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[You can&#8217;t nail jello to a tree, the saying goes, and it has been the philosophy of the Romney campaign.    It&#8217;s not working, and if Romney doesn&#8217;t change course soon, he&#8217;ll enter the twilight zone inhabited by John McCain, Bob Dole and Walter Mondale as they went through the motions in a campaign whose [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=7385&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_7387" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://scotterb.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/romney-flip-flop.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-7387" title="romney flip flop" src="http://scotterb.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/romney-flip-flop.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="388" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">In politics it&#8217;s a good idea to turn a weakness into a strength; Romney tried to do so with his reputation as a flip flopper</p></div>
<p>You can&#8217;t nail jello to a tree, the saying goes, and it has been the philosophy of the Romney campaign.    It&#8217;s not working, and if Romney doesn&#8217;t change course soon, he&#8217;ll enter the twilight zone inhabited by John McCain, Bob Dole and Walter Mondale as they went through the motions in a campaign whose outcome was already known.</p>
<p>On paper, Romney&#8217;s &#8220;Jello&#8221; strategy made sense.   First, Romney has a record as a solid businessman who saved the Salt Lake City Olympic games (exaggerated credit, but hey &#8211; this is politics) and is known as a pragmatic moderate.   He&#8217;s in a race against an incumbent suffering an ongoing economic crisis, and whose legislative activism has generated strong antipathy on the right.   Still, Obama has a solid campaign team good at opposition research and not afraid to play rough.</p>
<p>The fear in Romneyworld?   Team Obama will take apart any specific plan or policy they put forth and use it against them targeting whatever demographic might be most turned off.   Worse, they could make the election about comparing plans as the campaign sinks to a morass of detail, rather than it being about replacing a failing President who got in over his head with an experienced private sector success.</p>
<p>The answer?   Stay vague.   Don&#8217;t give them any ammo, say nothing specific that can be used against Romney.   Instead, play the game on their own turf, make it about how the President&#8217;s plans have failed, put Obama on the defensive.    Be jello.   If they land a punch &#8211; squish &#8211; the jello shifts shape and remains.    Obama will be flailing but unable to connect.   Romney can pick and choose from Obama&#8217;s four year record to attack at will.</p>
<p>Won&#8217;t people demand specifics?   Nope &#8211; modern campaigns are about big themes and slogans.   Moderates will simply assume that a pragmatic moderate Republican businessman can be trusted.   Romney will veer right in rhetoric but people will assume that&#8217;s just for politics.   The right wing will have to accept the rhetoric and support him because they&#8217;re virulently anti-Obama.</p>
<p>Keys: keep it about the economy, avoid distractions, and don&#8217;t get suckered into giving details or responding to them.  Stay on track, implement the strategy and don&#8217;t let the ups and downs of the campaign tempt you to respond!   Expect the flip flop charge to work in your favor &#8211; moderates won&#8217;t believe the scare tactics coming from Obama, but the base will be satisfied that you&#8217;re the best choice.    Meanwhile massive amounts of negative advertising by outside groups will grind Obama so far down that he&#8217;ll be like Dukakis in 1988, diminished and ridiculed.   Indeed the rhetoric trotted out this summer by right wing pundits telegraphed that strategy &#8211; Obama was described as a desperate and incompetent loser, flailing about uncertainly in order to hold power.    Team Romney counted on that image to stick.</p>
<p>Trouble is, the strategy isn&#8217;t working.   President Obama has found a way to nail jello to a tree &#8211; nail the whole box!</p>
<div id="attachment_7386" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 630px"><a href="http://scotterb.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/jellotree.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-7386" title="jellotree" src="http://scotterb.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/jellotree.jpg" alt="" width="620" height="465" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Can you nail jello to a tree?</p></div>
<p>Instead of trying to trap Romney on details, the Obama team decided that if Romney didn&#8217;t want to paint a clear picture of who he is and what he&#8217;ll do, they&#8217;d oblige and paint one for them.    They&#8217;d choose how to define him, and shape the campaign narrative instead.    They nailed the entire Romney box to a tree.</p>
<p>Romney is afraid to release his tax returns.  He&#8217;s secretive.  He&#8217;s far right.  His policies are the same of those of President Bush, the same policies that brought this mess upon us.  His foreign policy is bravado and bluster, look where that got us!  Talking tough and saying America must be strong sounds like George W. Bush all over again &#8211; will Iran be the next Iraq?  And it&#8217;s working, Romney seems empty, doesn&#8217;t seem to stand for anything, and the campaign narrative is being defined by the President&#8217;s team.  Intrade odds are now 67% for an Obama victory.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve said this before, but now it&#8217;s critical.   If we are to have a real race for the Presidency Romney has to come out and make a case, take a stand and level with the American people.   Being Jello may have seemed to be a good idea on paper, but it isn&#8217;t working.   I don&#8217;t think his campaign yet understands the extent of the change that they need.  Consider the focus they&#8217;re shifting to the &#8220;fiscal cliff.&#8221;</p>
<div id="attachment_7393" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 630px"><a href="http://scotterb.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/fiscalcliff.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-7393" title="fiscalcliff" src="http://scotterb.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/fiscalcliff.jpg" alt="" width="620" height="353" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">People don&#8217;t want vague attacks, they want solutions.</p></div>
<p>The debt ceiling was raised last year in an agreement that if the Congress could agree on spending cuts/revenue enhancements by 2013 automatic spending cuts would snap in place.   These include cuts on programs the Democrats support and defense cuts that Republicans are loathe to see implemented.  The idea was that the this would force them to compromise.   It didn&#8217;t work, at least not yet.</p>
<p>Governor Romney is issuing strong denunciations of Obama&#8217;s role in this agreement, though it was essentially a bi-partisan compromise.  Even Paul Ryan voted for it.  Moreover, it&#8217;s complex &#8211; look at the chart.   Warning of a &#8220;fiscal cliff&#8221; sounds vague and strange to voters.   If he gets into the details of what that entails, it gets confusing.  I think one mistake the Romney camp has made this year is that they are too &#8220;inside politics&#8221; in their arguments.   They use terms and labels that bloggers and political junkies know, but aren&#8217;t connecting to average voters.   Politicians need to always remember that the &#8220;inside game&#8221; is oblique and mysterious to most Americans.</p>
<p>The &#8220;Jello&#8221; strategy certainly seemed compelling on paper, but it&#8217;s failed.   Romney can stubbornly stick to it, hoping that bad news and perhaps a stumble by Obama will pull him over the top.  Given the economy, that <em>might</em> work (though I doubt it).   Or he can do something that some people doubt he knows how to do:  be himself.  Say what he thinks.   Defend the principles he believes in without worrying about what demographic group he might offend, or how the Obama team might use it against him.   He can take specific stands and lay out a vision of the future that goes beyond, &#8220;hey, I&#8217;m a businessman, I know how to run a company, trust me with the country.&#8221;</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a high risk high reward shift.  If he pulls it off, he could beat Obama.   If he fails he could turn off his base and risk an even bigger defeat than what now looks likely.     Yet the American people deserve to know what the Republican challenger wants for the country.   We&#8217;re not looking for a CEO, we&#8217;re looking for a President.    And if Romney refuses to comply, then team Obama will be happy to fill in the blanks and define what Romney&#8217;s vision really is.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/7385/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/7385/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=7385&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://scotterb.wordpress.com/2012/09/16/why-romneys-jello-strategy-fails/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>46</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f69adb1eef282ff6040b276698d1ebe4?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F0.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">scotterb</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://scotterb.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/romney-flip-flop.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">romney flip flop</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://scotterb.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/jellotree.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jellotree</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://scotterb.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/fiscalcliff.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">fiscalcliff</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Wordhacking Made Easy</title>
		<link>http://makeapowerfulpoint.com/2012/09/05/wordhacking-made-easy/</link>
		<comments>http://makeapowerfulpoint.com/2012/09/05/wordhacking-made-easy/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2012 04:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Gavin</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Words]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Neoligism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Truthiness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Word of the year]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wordhacking]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://makeapowerfulpoint.com/?p=1351</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Dirty Harry speaks to a chair and overnight, Eastwooding enters the vocabulary. Eastwooding is an easy one, like Tebowing. Adding a gerund (an ing) to a noun is child&#8217;s play. More advanced wordhacks — Stephen Colbert elevating truthiness to a word of the year —  is an art form. Making up new words (that&#8217;s neologisms for the wordanistas [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1351&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://makeapowerfulpoint.com/2012/09/05/wordhacking-made-easy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>47</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://makeapowerfulpoint.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/powerfulpoint-blog-post-word-hacking-made-easy.png?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://makeapowerfulpoint.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/powerfulpoint-blog-post-word-hacking-made-easy.png?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">PowerfulPoint-Blog-Post-word-hacking-made-easy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/4770fa87e113c38e79fbe0beeebaeb7a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">makeapowerfulpoint</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://makeapowerfulpoint.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/wordhacking-part1.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">WordHacking-Part#1</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>On Child-Free Weddings</title>
		<link>http://thisruthlessworld.wordpress.com/2012/09/05/on-child-free-weddings/</link>
		<comments>http://thisruthlessworld.wordpress.com/2012/09/05/on-child-free-weddings/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2012 17:44:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Amused</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[feminism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weddings]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thisruthlessworld.wordpress.com/?p=805</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Over at Feministe, there is a discussion on whether banning children from weddings &#8212; which is becoming a trend, apparently &#8212; should be perceived as offensive to parents who are invited. Lots of virtual ink is spilled detailing children’s propensity for undecorous behavior, the poor parenting skills of people who reproduce (as oppose to the [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=805&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://thisruthlessworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/d0ba_d0b5_d0bcd0b0d0bad0bed0b2d181d0bad0b8d0b9_d0b1d0bed18fd180d181d0bad0b8d0b9_d181d0b2d0b0d0b4d0b5d0b1d0bdd18bd0b9_d0bfd0b8d180_d0b2_x.jpg"><img src="http://thisruthlessworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/d0ba_d0b5_d0bcd0b0d0bad0bed0b2d181d0bad0b8d0b9_d0b1d0bed18fd180d181d0bad0b8d0b9_d181d0b2d0b0d0b4d0b5d0b1d0bdd18bd0b9_d0bfd0b8d180_d0b2_x.jpg?w=300&h=174" alt="" title="K.E. Makovsky, &quot;A Boyar&#039;s Wedding Feast in the 17th Century&quot; (1883)" width="300" height="174" class="alignright size-medium wp-image-806" /></a><a href="http://www.feministe.us/blog/archives/2012/08/13/not-another-mummy-blogger-2/#comment-498732">Over at Feministe</a>, there is a discussion on whether banning children from weddings &#8212; which is becoming a trend, apparently &#8212; should be perceived as offensive to parents who are invited.  Lots of virtual ink is spilled detailing children’s propensity for undecorous behavior, the poor parenting skills of people who reproduce (as oppose to the child-free, who frequently emerge in these discussions as <i>the</i> experts on proper parenting), and why whole classes of adults are not excluded from such events based on unacceptable behavior of certain of their members, while excluding children is okay.<span id="more-805"></span></p>
<p>In all fairness, an invitation banning children from a wedding isn’t so controversial these days.  I once read of a couple whose wedding invitations specified that guests were expected to have mastered classic waltz by the day of the event, set forth instructions on how to twirl properly, warned that incorrect or ungraceful twirling would not be tolerated and contained a request that anyone unable or unwilling to twirl properly refrain from attending.  Even that, I am sure, isn’t the most extreme of attempts by marrying couples to achieve a “perfect” wedding.</p>
<p>Incidentally, think of what most people believe makes a wedding “perfect”.  The word conjures up images of palacial spaces, billowing pastel-colored dresses, immaculately coiffed hair, fine china and moving, heartfelt pontification.  Weddings were once rowdy affairs where children ran around, people danced with abandon, and newlyweds would sneak off right about when the merrymaking reached a fever pitch.  No longer.  A “perfect” modern American wedding more closely resembles a funeral than a family celebration &#8212; hence the growing feeling that it’s inappropriate for children.  Often, it’s not a celebration at all, but rather a <i>proceeding</i>, a stilted, highly scripted event, in which a bunch of ordinary yokels pretend to be Marie Antoinette.  </p>
<p>Few people get to do this more than three times in a lifetime, and therefore the stakes are very high.  The months and sometimes years leading up to the Big Day are full of feverish preparation and agonizing over the most minute details, arguing over tablecloth shades and sitting arrangements, insane diet-and-workout routines designed to make the bride look her most photogenic for that unforgiving (yet absolutely mandatory) strapless gown and ungodly amounts of stress, that threatens to undermine the very relationship that the wedding is intended to celebrate.  The proceedings are meticulously rehearsed &#8212; the canned, preachy speeches and the obviously choreographed “first kiss as a married couple”.  (Bleh.)  The modern wedding is a spectacle.  The emphasis is on solemnity, order and display &#8212; but above all, on creating an impressive, flawless photographic and video record.  There is very little place there for actual fun.  It is not unlike putting on a full-scale opera, except that relative to means, it represents Mars Rover landing-levels of cost, preparation, and delicacy of execution.   Is it any wonder some massively stressed-out couples don’t want kids anywhere near such an important and complicated operation?  An untimely yelp from some little fucker at any point during a wedding would be no different than a baby bawling in the middle of a performance of <i>Don Giovanni</i>.  Weddings are serious business, people.</p>
<p>Bashing weddings is not unpopular, and I hasten to separate myself from the crowd that always rushes to point out that the money spent on a wedding would be better used towards a downpayment on a home.  I actually hate it when people say things like that.  (I myself did not have a traditional wedding, but I recall a conversation by the side or a water cooler when a co-worker expressed dismay and outrage that my husband and I would spend money on a trip to Italy when we didn’t even own a home yet.)  The American obsession with home ownership for its own sake, no matter the cost or individual circumstances, is almost as ridiculous as the obsession with “perfect” weddings.  Moreover, I cringe at the underlying notion here, that it’s wrong to spend lots of money on pleasure, that young married couples should prove their grasp of responsibility by spending money only in “serious” ways, such as by buying a home when they may not want or need one.  I think that leading an enjoyable life &#8212; within reason, of course, but still &#8212; is just as important as investing money (and buying a home isn’t the only, and isn’t always the best, way to do this) and providing for any kids’ educations and one’s old age.  </p>
<p>Rather, what bothers me about “perfect” weddings is that so much emotional capital is staked on something so ephemeral, that friendships and familial ties are put in jeopardy for the sake of putting on a show.  If people applied the same energy and hard work to their marriages, the divorce rate would be close to zero.  It’s not the money that I see as the problem &#8212; though the great expenditures are certainly one manifestation of what I believe is the trouble here &#8212; it’s the over-the-top tackiness, the haughty showmanship implicit in “perfect” weddings.  The latest “no children allowed” trend is merely part of the growing obnoxiousness of that display.</p>
<p>It was said repeatedly in the thread I linked that the marrying couple have the right to decide who does or does not attend their wedding.  After all, it’s <i>their</i> day, and the guest list is their prerogative.  That is, of course, true.  However, there is often a confusion in people’s minds between having the right to do something and having the right to receive only innocuous reactions to whatever it is you do simply because you have the “right” to do it.  Of course the marrying couple may bar whomever they want to achieve their own version of a successful wedding, but expecting people never to take offense is a bit much.  The Bride and the Groom could just as well send out invitations that instruct guests not to bring significant others who are overweight, <i>because we want only conventionally attractive people at our wedding for the purpose of producing an aesthetically pleasing visual record, and it’s OUR special day, and we have the right not to allow any fat fatties, so don’t feel offended, we have the RIGHT</i>.  I’m sorry, but that’s highly unrealistic.  Point is, when you invite a relative or a friend to an event that’s meant to celebrate you starting a family, and tell them that a member of their immediate family is not welcome for reasons of elegance, you convey to that friend or relative exactly how much you value your relationship.  </p>
<p>Don’t be surprised if she gets the message.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/805/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/805/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=805&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thisruthlessworld.wordpress.com/2012/09/05/on-child-free-weddings/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>90</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/849260008d0626b824c96d8208ae7198?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">khozyajka</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thisruthlessworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/d0ba_d0b5_d0bcd0b0d0bad0bed0b2d181d0bad0b8d0b9_d0b1d0bed18fd180d181d0bad0b8d0b9_d181d0b2d0b0d0b4d0b5d0b1d0bdd18bd0b9_d0bfd0b8d180_d0b2_x.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">K.E. Makovsky, &#34;A Boyar&#039;s Wedding Feast in the 17th Century&#34; (1883)</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Lonely States of America?</title>
		<link>http://stephenedelstein.wordpress.com/2012/08/31/the-lonely-states-of-america/</link>
		<comments>http://stephenedelstein.wordpress.com/2012/08/31/the-lonely-states-of-america/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2012 14:43:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>lib1187</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Airbnb]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Atlantic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kurt Vonnegut]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mass transit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://stephenedelstein.wordpress.com/?p=598</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[“The great American disease is loneliness,” Kurt Vonnegut once said in an interview. He was right, as he was about most things, and that loneliness seems to be facilitated by technology. When Vonnegut was raising his family in postwar America, television was seen as an engine of antisocial behavior. Now, we have something much better: [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=598&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://stephenedelstein.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_0485.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-599" title="People on the T" src="http://stephenedelstein.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_0485.jpg?w=225&h=300" alt="People on the T" width="225" height="300" /></a>“The great American disease is loneliness,” Kurt Vonnegut once said in an interview. He was right, as he was about most things, and that loneliness seems to be facilitated by technology.</p>
<p>When Vonnegut was raising his family in postwar America, television was seen as an engine of antisocial behavior. Now, we have something much better: Facebook. In an article for the <em>Atlantic</em> called <a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2012/05/is-facebook-making-us-lonely/308930/">“Is Facebook Making Us Lonely?”</a> Stephen Marche argues that social media facilitate an innate desire people have to keep each other at a distance.</p>
<p>Marche correlates an increase in loneliness (measured by such things as the UCLA Loneliness Scale) and the rise of social media. However, he does not blame social media for American loneliness.</p>
<p>“Loneliness is certainly not something that Facebook or Twitter or any of the lesser forms of social media is doing to us,” Marche said. “We are doing it to ourselves.”</p>
<p>People are, after all, annoying, and Marche acknowledges this. He says Facebook and other social media apparatus could be used to bring people together, but people instead use them to sanitize all their social interactions and, ultimately, avoid all the unpleasantness of real time, face-to-face communication.</p>
<p>If Marche is right, then American society is about to get a whole lot lonelier.</p>
<p>In <a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2012/05/is-facebook-making-us-lonely/308930/">“The Cheapest Generation,”</a> a more recent article in the <em>Atlantic</em>, Derek Thompson and Jordan Weissmann argue that “Millenials” are ditching automobile and home ownership for sharing schemes like Zipcar and Airbnb. They say Millenials will push America toward a more communal economy, focused on “urban light” neighborhoods instead of traditional suburbs.</p>
<p>That sounds pretty appealing, but I don’t think the America my generation builds will be an urban hipster version of a hippie commune. It might be even lonelier than it is today.</p>
<p>Car sharing programs like Zipcar give members most of the convenience of car ownership without the soul-crushing costs and perpetual need for parking spaces. Members can pick up a car from designated stations on short notice, drive it as much as they want (they get charged by the minute or hour) and drop it off when they’re done.<a href="http://stephenedelstein.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/zipcar-004.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-600" title="Zipcar at Clark University" src="http://stephenedelstein.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/zipcar-004.jpg?w=225&h=300" alt="Zipcar at Clark University" width="225" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>It’s a great solution for people who live in urban areas, but it also reduces the driving experience to its essence: privacy. Unless a Zipcar driver is going somewhere with no mass transit, why not take the train? It would be cheaper, and give one more free time.</p>
<p>Car owners need privacy because they’re going places no one else is going; they need flexibility. But if the future really is in car sharing, would anyone take the subway if they knew they could just as easily ride alone?</p>
<p>The &#8220;Millenial&#8221; generation might easily choose the latter. We&#8217;ve grown up accustomed to texting instead of talking, and thinking that social movements can be organized solely through social media. We control the amount of our reactions with other people in a way no previous generation has.</p>
<p>Thompson and Weissmann believe personal property is a concept this generation is not accustomed to. In the same vein, spontaneous everyday interactions could be something that we avoid, and don&#8217;t want to experience just because they represent a current social norm.</p>
<p>If people are so quick to trade the uncertainty of phone calls for Facbeook statuses, and the tedium of waiting in line for self-checkout, will they be able to resist hopping in a car instead of riding with the crowd? Or will urban transportation become one more people-free aspect of our society?</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/598/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/598/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=598&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://stephenedelstein.wordpress.com/2012/08/31/the-lonely-states-of-america/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>33</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/473a4f165247f3cf60a8ae9ea38aaf47?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lib1187</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://stephenedelstein.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_0485.jpg?w=225" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">People on the T</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://stephenedelstein.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/zipcar-004.jpg?w=225" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Zipcar at Clark University</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What Choice(s) Do I Have?</title>
		<link>http://whatsmyage.wordpress.com/2012/09/09/what-choices-do-i-have/</link>
		<comments>http://whatsmyage.wordpress.com/2012/09/09/what-choices-do-i-have/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2012 00:54:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Justin Almeida</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advocacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[choice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[citizen power]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consumerism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[environment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fair trade]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[human rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[responsible investment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[slavery]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://whatsmyage.wordpress.com/?p=102</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I am an American consumer. I have no little choice in the matter. There are extreme options for living off the grid, but I live in a big city (Seattle).  Therefore, I must do as the Seattlites do. I try to make intelligent, conscientious consumer choices: buying second hand, buying local, buying independent. However, these choices [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=102&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://whatsmyage.wordpress.com/2012/09/09/what-choices-do-i-have/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>70</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/88b8b349ad6a440dd5267bf37b637cba?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">justinwalmeida</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://whatsmyage.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/consumer_jesus_banksy1.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">consumer_jesus_banksy1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://whatsmyage.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/bloody-usb-f.jpg?w=200" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Bloody-USB-f</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://whatsmyage.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/csr.jpg?w=227" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">CSR</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://whatsmyage.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/food-desert-1.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">food-desert-1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://whatsmyage.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/01.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">01</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://whatsmyage.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/el-traje-de-gandhi.jpg?w=208" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">el traje de Gandhi</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>