<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2012 23:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Sometimes a Punch In the Face Is All It Takes</title>
		<link>http://meghankrein.wordpress.com/2012/11/13/sometimes-a-punch-in-the-face-is-all-it-takes-to-find-out-whos-your-daddy/</link>
		<comments>http://meghankrein.wordpress.com/2012/11/13/sometimes-a-punch-in-the-face-is-all-it-takes-to-find-out-whos-your-daddy/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2012 22:16:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>megkrein</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Family Crap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Secrets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dysfunction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Effed-up]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mama's Baby]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Break up]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Domestic Violence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Engagement]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://meghankrein.wordpress.com/?p=511</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[My dad has called me a lot of things in my life: Megs, Meghan Beghan Ronald Reagan, and even, on occasion, mama’s baby. But, he never got around to calling me Daddy’s Little Girl, which was the one thing I wanted so desperately. Like, I wanted it more than I wanted a Barbie Dreamhouse. I [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=511&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>My dad has called me a lot of things in my life: Megs, Meghan Beghan Ronald Reagan, and even, on occasion, mama’s baby. But, he never got around to calling me Daddy’s Little Girl, which was the one thing I wanted so desperately. Like, I wanted it more than I wanted a Barbie Dreamhouse. I wanted it more than I wanted Punky Brewster’s style. I wanted it more than I wanted my first kiss with Chris King to be seen by the entire 6<sup>th</sup> grade class. I wanted it more than I wanted a driver’s license. I even wanted it more than I wanted my first roommate and I to live a lifestyle similar to that of <i>Laverne &amp; Shirley</i>. Really, I never stopped wanting it.</p>
<p>The only consolation to not being Daddy’s Little Girl was knowing my older sister wasn’t either.  It was comforting knowing the rejection wasn’t anything personal. My dad just wasn’t the touchy-feely type of guy. Living in small town Iowa, he was a construction worker; one of those big, tough guys, you know? He wore steel-toe boots, ripped jeans and plaid, flannel shirts. And, kept his feelings neatly tucked under a hard hat. During the week, my dad would venture off to places like New York where he&#8217;d throw together a skyscraper or Minneapolis and work on the Mega Mall; on the weekend he’d come home to us, a cooler dangling from his sleeve, not his heart.</p>
<div id="attachment_512" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://meghankrein.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/father-daughter.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-512" title="Father-Daughter-" alt="" src="http://meghankrein.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/father-daughter.jpg?w=300&#038;h=272" height="272" width="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">These boots are made for&#8230;kicking some ass.</p></div>
<p>I can count on my right hand the number of times my dad told me he loved me. Maybe that makes it all the more special when it does happen? Maybe. But, I would argue it makes it all the more awkward. Mostly because my dad is so utterly uncomfortable saying those three little words. And, when he does say them, it sounds like he’s just eaten three tablespoons of peanut butter.  And, the only impulse I have is not to say ‘I love you’ back, but rather to hand the man a glass of milk.</p>
<p>Either way, when I was 22, I found my very own older man to call me his little girl and in certain situations, I could call ‘daddy’ &#8211; and moved right on in. The pressure to marry T mounted about 6 months in. I would find jewelry store catalogues lying around the house, the engagement ring section marked with post-its, and random rings circled in red marker. I was confused; wasn’t I supposed to be doing this? Side note: T had been married twice before. I had no intention of being his third ex-wife. Yet, I found myself infected with a platinum, princess-cut engagement ring. I hated it. But, I hated hurting people’s feelings even more.</p>
<p>I didn’t know how to get myself out of the situation, so I stayed away. And, the more I stayed away, the more controlling and aggressive T became.  One night, after enjoying a happy hour with a few co-workers, T met me at our front door.</p>
<p>He was all decked out in a suit. He slurred, “Well, you said you’ve never seen me in one before.” Clearly he’d been in the company of Jim Beam all night. Seeing where this was going, I told him he looked nice and went into the bedroom to get ready for bed.</p>
<p>Apparently, while I was out, T found some graduate school applications I had filled out, without telling him. He was furious<i>. Why hadn’t I told him? Who did I think I was? Was I really planning on moving away and leaving him? </i>Really, my 22-year-old mind hadn’t thought about any of that. I was just trying to figure out who I was and what I wanted to do with my life. Either way, I apologized for keeping him in the dark.</p>
<p>My apology was met with a blow to the nose.</p>
<p>The punch hurled me onto the bed, T hovering above me. Stunned, I leapt up and did a maneuver similar to the limbo underneath his arm. On my way out of the bedroom, I grabbed my cell phone before shielding myself behind the locked bathroom door. As I was desperately calling my brother, M for help, T was punching and kicking holes in the door. I waited for M to come and wondered at what point my life turned into an episode of <i>Cops</i>.</p>
<p>M came to the rescue and took me to our parents, where I stayed for the following three months. My mom helped me move all of my stuff out of T’s house the next day. The only thing I left was his ring, which he eventually gave back &#8211; I’m sure out of guilt. My nose was black and blue and it felt like I’d been punched in the face. Because I had.</p>
<p>No one pushed me to defend myself by pressing charges or anything, which I really needed in this situation. Plus, wasn’t my dad supposed to walk out in overalls, wild eyes, and carrying a shotgun? That’s what happens on <i>Lifetime</i>. But, mine just stood idly by, which made me feel like I’d been punched a dozen more times.</p>
<p>It wasn’t until six years later that I found out the truth. M and I were having dinner and drinks at Zipp’s, when he let it slip, “Dad did stick up for you when all that went down, you know. He scared the shit out of T.”</p>
<p>What?! How could I not know this after all these years? I demanded details. M told me that the day after it happened, Dad ordered M to get in his truck. The two of them drove to T’s where Dad barged into the house, grabbed T by the front of his shirt and pinned him against the wall; T’s feet dangling, his face turning as blue as my nose. “Don’t you ever touch my daughter again you piece of shit, you hear me?!” Dad bellowed in T’s face. T whimpered “like a little bitch.”</p>
<p>“It was so awesome! Dad was quite the stud,” M boasted. M went on to tell me that Dad asked him to keep it a secret. Why? I have no idea. Maybe he thought I would get mad. Maybe he was being humble. Or maybe having me know and the emotions involved was far too uncomfortable for him. Really, it doesn’t matter. What matters is I’m my dad’s little girl.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/511/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/511/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=511&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://meghankrein.wordpress.com/2012/11/13/sometimes-a-punch-in-the-face-is-all-it-takes-to-find-out-whos-your-daddy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/8a2d0e97b5d2a32dff3b77e865acccc1?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">megkrein</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://meghankrein.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/father-daughter.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Father-Daughter-</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Do Not Fear Potatoes</title>
		<link>http://speaker7.wordpress.com/2012/11/13/do-not-fear-potatoes/</link>
		<comments>http://speaker7.wordpress.com/2012/11/13/do-not-fear-potatoes/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2012 12:15:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>speaker7</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[27 vaginas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[browsing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[do not fear potatoes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fifty Shades of Grey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gonorrhea tonsils]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Katherine Heigl]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[potato phobia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[potato salad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[search terms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[searching]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wordpress]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://speaker7.wordpress.com/?p=4234</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Seven people found my blog yesterday using those search terms: do not fear potatoes. Do people really fear potatoes? According to some random seach engine question and answer thingy, there&#8217;s not even a word for potato phobia. The second most asked question about potato fear was this: I didn&#8217;t realize I wrote much about potatoes, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4234&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Seven people found my blog yesterday using those search terms: do not fear potatoes.</p>
<p>Do people really fear potatoes? According to some random seach engine question and answer thingy, there&#8217;s not even a word for potato phobia.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><a href="http://speaker7.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/fearofpotatoes.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-4235" title="fearofpotatoes" alt="" src="http://speaker7.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/fearofpotatoes.jpg?w=479&#038;h=198" height="198" width="479" /></a>The second most asked question about potato fear was this:</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://speaker7.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/fearofpotatosalad.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-4236" title="fearofpotatosalad" alt="" src="http://speaker7.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/fearofpotatosalad.jpg?w=512&#038;h=155" height="155" width="512" /></a></p>
<p>I didn&#8217;t realize I wrote much about potatoes, and I have no idea how entering those terms would lead a person to my blog. But since you&#8217;re here, I want you to know this&#8211;</p>
<p>Potatoes make good detectives . . . because they always have their eyes peeled.</p>
<p>*swish*</p>
<p>Oh&#8211;and you shouldn&#8217;t fear them. Feel better?</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://speaker7.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/potato.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-4238" title="potato" alt="" src="http://speaker7.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/potato.jpg?w=322&#038;h=230" height="230" width="322" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Well you may want to fear that one. That one is definitely not sweet.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">I&#8217;m hoping now that I&#8217;ve mentioned &#8220;do not fear potatoes&#8221; a number of times, this blog will appear higher in the results for that extremely popular search.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">This is why I&#8217;m now also mentioning my second most popular search terms from yesterday: gonorrhea tonsils.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><a href="http://speaker7.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/screen-shot-2012-11-12-at-5-52-03-pm.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-4245" title="Screen Shot 2012-11-12 at 5.52.03 PM" alt="" src="http://speaker7.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/screen-shot-2012-11-12-at-5-52-03-pm.png?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">This is actually a thing, I am horrified to have found out. It is contracted by putting your mouth on something that has gonorrhea.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Like a potato? you wonder, your fear of them beginning to resurface.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">No, probably not. Really, you do not need to fear potatoes.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Only in this instance:</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://speaker7.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/potatosaladgonorrhea.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-4243" title="potatosaladgonorrhea" alt="" src="http://speaker7.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/potatosaladgonorrhea.jpg?w=512&#038;h=155" height="155" width="512" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">While I may not be an expert in this particular area, my advice to you is to refrain from putting your mouth on something soaked with gonorrhea.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Most of my other search terms had to do with <a title="Fifty Shades of Grey" href="http://speaker7.wordpress.com/fifty-shades-of-grey/">Fifty Shades of Grey</a>. There was one that stuck out from the pack.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><a href="http://speaker7.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/27types.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-4247" title="27types" alt="" src="http://speaker7.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/27types.png?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">I believe this is the title of a new rom-com starring Katherine Heigl. I cannot wait to see it. I think Gerard Butler plays one of the vaginas.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">If you search for 27 types of vagina, my blog comes up pretty high in the results as does an article about 8 types of vagina from a man&#8217;s perspective, which I would only recommend reading if you contracted tonsil gonorrhea from potato salad. You&#8217;re already feeling pretty bad at that point.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><em>Dearest Reader: Speaker7 is attempting to write a post every day in November so she doesn’t have to participate in NaNoWriMo (National Novel Writing Month). This is the thirteenth post. She does not fear potatoes, but does fear gonorrhea tonsils. </em></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4234/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4234/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4234&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://speaker7.wordpress.com/2012/11/13/do-not-fear-potatoes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>72</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/9f1c15a65eb5ffe1a0013207d1530890?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">speaker7</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://speaker7.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/fearofpotatoes.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">fearofpotatoes</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://speaker7.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/fearofpotatosalad.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">fearofpotatosalad</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://speaker7.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/potato.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">potato</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://speaker7.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/screen-shot-2012-11-12-at-5-52-03-pm.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen Shot 2012-11-12 at 5.52.03 PM</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://speaker7.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/potatosaladgonorrhea.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">potatosaladgonorrhea</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://speaker7.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/27types.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">27types</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Himachal Pradesh &#8211; The Final Images</title>
		<link>http://nomadruss.me/2012/11/13/himachal-pradesh-the-final-images/</link>
		<comments>http://nomadruss.me/2012/11/13/himachal-pradesh-the-final-images/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2012 12:05:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>nomadruss</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[india]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nomadruss.me/?p=2773</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[After weeks of editing I&#8217;m down to the final images from the Ropa Valley in Himachal Pradesh. Being the final edit means that there are some images that aren&#8217;t as strong as images from previous edits, but if they weren&#8217;t shown they&#8217;d just sit on a hard drive for the next 30 years, and I [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2773&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://nomadruss.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/rbt06851.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2793" title="" alt="" src="http://nomadruss.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/rbt06851.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=680" height="680" width="1024" /></a>After weeks of editing I&#8217;m down to the final images from the Ropa Valley in Himachal Pradesh. Being the final edit means that there are some images that aren&#8217;t as strong as images from previous edits, but if they weren&#8217;t shown they&#8217;d just sit on a hard drive for the next 30 years, and I just didn&#8217;t want to let them go. A couple are a bit quirky and the final image from along the highway just seemed to say, &#8220;the end.&#8221; In any case I hope they give a bit more insight into the culture, and that you enjoy them. Next week it&#8217;s back to the United States and some images from Fall in the Blue Ridge Mountains of North Carolina, see you then.</p>
<p><a href="http://nomadruss.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/rbt0285.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2774" title="" alt="" src="http://nomadruss.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/rbt0285.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=681" height="681" width="1024" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://nomadruss.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/rbt1243.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2775" title="" alt="" src="http://nomadruss.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/rbt1243.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=680" height="680" width="1024" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://nomadruss.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/rbt0790.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2777" title="" alt="" src="http://nomadruss.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/rbt0790.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=680" height="680" width="1024" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://nomadruss.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/rbt0464.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2778" title="" alt="" src="http://nomadruss.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/rbt0464.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=680" height="680" width="1024" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://nomadruss.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/rbt0723.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2779" title="" alt="" src="http://nomadruss.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/rbt0723.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=682" height="682" width="1024" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://nomadruss.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/rbt0806.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2780" title="" alt="" src="http://nomadruss.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/rbt0806.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=680" height="680" width="1024" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://nomadruss.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/rbt1090.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2781" title="" alt="" src="http://nomadruss.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/rbt1090.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=680" height="680" width="1024" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://nomadruss.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/rbt1725.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2782" title="" alt="" src="http://nomadruss.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/rbt1725.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=680" height="680" width="1024" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://nomadruss.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/rbt9329.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2783" title="" alt="" src="http://nomadruss.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/rbt9329.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=681" height="681" width="1024" /></a><a href="http://nomadruss.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/rbt9874.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2784" title="" alt="" src="http://nomadruss.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/rbt9874.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=680" height="680" width="1024" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://nomadruss.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/rbt1235.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2785" title="" alt="" src="http://nomadruss.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/rbt1235.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=680" height="680" width="1024" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://nomadruss.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/rbt1769.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2786" title="" alt="" src="http://nomadruss.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/rbt1769.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=680" height="680" width="1024" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://nomadruss.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/rbt2134.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2796" title="" alt="" src="http://nomadruss.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/rbt2134.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=680" height="680" width="1024" /></a><br />
<a href='http://twitter.com/nomadruss' class='twitter-follow-button' data-show-count='false'>Follow @nomadruss</a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2773/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2773/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2773&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://nomadruss.me/2012/11/13/himachal-pradesh-the-final-images/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://nomadruss.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/rbt06851.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://nomadruss.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/rbt06851.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">rbt06851</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/1d5a913bf7d3b1fa002018a5919d7e05?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">nomadruss</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nomadruss.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/rbt06851.jpg?w=1024" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://nomadruss.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/rbt0285.jpg?w=1024" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://nomadruss.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/rbt1243.jpg?w=1024" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://nomadruss.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/rbt0790.jpg?w=1024" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://nomadruss.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/rbt0464.jpg?w=1024" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://nomadruss.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/rbt0723.jpg?w=1024" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://nomadruss.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/rbt0806.jpg?w=1024" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://nomadruss.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/rbt1090.jpg?w=1024" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://nomadruss.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/rbt1725.jpg?w=1024" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://nomadruss.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/rbt9329.jpg?w=1024" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://nomadruss.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/rbt9874.jpg?w=1024" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://nomadruss.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/rbt1235.jpg?w=1024" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://nomadruss.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/rbt1769.jpg?w=1024" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://nomadruss.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/rbt2134.jpg?w=1024" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>We All Have to Stop Working For Free…Don’t We?</title>
		<link>http://cuadernoinedito.wordpress.com/2012/09/08/we-all-have-to-stop-working-for-free-dont-we/</link>
		<comments>http://cuadernoinedito.wordpress.com/2012/09/08/we-all-have-to-stop-working-for-free-dont-we/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2012 06:09:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Julie Schwietert Collazo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Business of Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creativity and marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unpaid gigs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cuadernoinedito.wordpress.com/?p=907</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Last month, Francisco* and I narrowly averted an argument. As is the case with most couples&#8217; arguments, our near-miss fight was about money. Francisco and I are not an argument-prone pair; though we&#8217;re both hard-headed and opinionated, we don&#8217;t like conflict and we&#8217;re very careful about protecting one another. Which is why we were almost [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=907&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Last month, Francisco* and I</strong> narrowly averted an argument. As is the case with most couples&#8217; arguments, our near-miss fight was about money. </p>
<p>Francisco and I are not an argument-prone pair; though we&#8217;re both hard-headed and opinionated, we don&#8217;t like conflict and we&#8217;re very careful about protecting one another.</p>
<p>Which is why we were almost fighting. </p>
<div id="attachment_932" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 620px"><a href="http://cuadernoinedito.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/should-this-guy-work-for-free.jpg"><img src="http://cuadernoinedito.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/should-this-guy-work-for-free.jpg?w=590" alt="Should this guy work for free? " title="Should this guy work for free?"   class="size-full wp-image-932" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Should this guy work for free?</p></div>
<p>While photographing an event on assignment, Francisco met a producer from a local radio station. They exchanged pleasantries and business cards, and the next day she contacted him about a gig. Would he be interested in photographing some VIP station supporters before and after a Broadway show? He said that he would and discussions began about the particulars of the gig. </p>
<p>He was flattered to have been asked and he was visibly excited about the assignment when he told me about it. He shared some of the details and it all sounded great. And then I asked, &#8220;So what are they paying you?&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Well, um, the producer said they don&#8217;t have a budget for this because they&#8217;re a public radio station and they don&#8217;t have a lot of money, but, you know, it&#8217;s great exposure and they&#8217;ll definitely keep me in mind for future paying work, and they&#8217;ll credit me and I can use it in my publication history.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;What a bunch of bullshit,&#8221; I said, before padding off to the kitchen for some seltzer. I returned, glass in hand. Imagine a full, bright balloon floating in a child&#8217;s hand and then being popped by a cynical older kid on the playground. Then imagine what the balloon-holding kid&#8217;s face looks like, and you&#8217;ll have a decent approximation of Francisco&#8217;s expression. </p>
<p>In short, he was defeated. </p>
<p>I knew I&#8217;d fouled, though that hadn&#8217;t been my intention at all. He felt that my &#8220;Bullshit!&#8221; declaration was a value judgment about his decision-making skills. &#8220;I feel like you think I&#8217;m an idiot for accepting a gig that doesn&#8217;t pay anything,&#8221; he said. And though I scrambled to explain that it was actually a statement of how much value I place on his photography, there weren&#8217;t any words&#8211;at least not at that moment&#8211;that were going to salve the wounded ego. </p>
<p>**<br />
<strong>When the initial bruise of my words had faded</strong>, I raised the issue again. I wanted to explain what I had meant. I have more experience than he does with the dilemmas surrounding &#8220;work for exposure&#8221; schemes, and I felt like my own grapplings&#8211; some successful, most not, but all having led me to a clearer personal and professional stance on being asked to work for free&#8211; could shorten his own learning curve in what has turned from his hobby to a career.   </p>
<p>&#8220;Look,&#8221; I started, &#8220;the radio station would never call a web developer and ask them to build a website for free. They&#8217;d never call ConEd and say, &#8216;You know, we&#8217;re a public radio station and we don&#8217;t have much cash, so we&#8217;re just not going to pay our light bill. But hey, we&#8217;ll give you a shout-out on the station&#8211; sound good?&#8217; But for some reason, they&#8217;re completely okay with asking a photographer to provide his services for free in exchange for the promise of a 3-second mention on air. See what I mean?&#8221;</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve done enough of the &#8220;work for exposure&#8221; gigs to know that the &#8220;exposure&#8221; is usually nominal at best, meaningless at worst, and almost never leads to anything bigger, better, or paying.   </p>
<p>**<br />
<strong>Though our exchange was a sore spot</strong> and though his enthusiasm for the gig had vanished completely, Francisco had committed to doing the job, and he did it. When the photos were published, his name didn&#8217;t appear on them as promised&#8230; not until he contacted the station and requested that they make good on their deal. Francisco conceded (and no, I didn&#8217;t crow a triumphant &#8220;I told you so!&#8221;) that he probably could have spent the time he invested in the gig better&#8211; either by hustling up some paying work, processing the massive backlog of photos sitting on his hard drive, or moving some images over to a stock site.</p>
<p>&#8220;Live and learn,&#8221; I said. &#8220;It&#8217;s all good.&#8221;</p>
<p>**<br />
<strong>I&#8217;m not against creative people sharing their gifts</strong> for free. My friend, <a href="http://lolaakinmade.com/">Lola Akinmade Akerstrom</a>, is a wonderful example of someone who makes a living as a professional photographer <em>and</em> offers a percentage of her time and talent to pro-bono causes that are important to her. </p>
<p>But&#8230;</p>
<p>I now make decisions about how I apportion my own &#8220;will work for free&#8221; time according to two caveats:</p>
<p>1.   <strong>Is the person or organization asking for my time and skills <em>really</em> in need or are they simply not prioritizing their desires in a way that includes those desires as a line-item in a budget?</strong> Having worked in non-profits, I know the realities of creative financing and the importance of streamlining the cost of contracted services.^ But as a <em>provider</em> of goods and services&#8211;writing and photography are products, after all&#8211;I&#8217;m not willing to participate in a financial system that operates any differently from the office supply store. The radio station producer doesn&#8217;t walk into Staples and say she needs office supplies but won&#8217;t pay for them because she doesn&#8217;t have the budget for them. Why should creative services be any different? </p>
<p>2.  <strong>What percentage of my time and work am I willing and able to give away freely, without expectation of compensation AND credit?</strong> As a person who doesn&#8217;t have enough time to realize all of her own projects, that percentage is quite low.<br />
**<br />
<strong>But back to our near-fight.</strong></p>
<p>As I&#8217;ve reflected on our exchange, I realized that my problem was this: I wanted Francisco to decline the gig based on <em>my</em> principles, not his. And though I truly do want him to value his own work and not give it away, I shouldn&#8217;t try to mandate whether he works for free or how he sets his fees. </p>
<p>Among the community of writers and photographers I know, I often hear us trying to influence one another about this issue. &#8220;You CAN&#8217;T work for free,&#8221; a writer friend once counseled me, &#8220;because then we&#8217;ll ALL be expected to work for free. Writing won&#8217;t have any value.&#8221; </p>
<p>Though I agree with her in theory, we each have to make our own decisions, and often, these are made on a case-by-case basis. <em>Do</em> we all have to stop working for free? When do you choose to give your work and skills away and what&#8217;s the line you absolutely won&#8217;t cross when it comes to establishing and defending the value of your work? When do you push an editor or a client who&#8217;s asking you to work below-market rate to adjust their fees? </p>
<p>Francisco and I would love to hear from you in the comments. </p>
<p>&#8211;<br />
*If you&#8217;re new to the blog, Francisco is the most important member of CuadernoInedito&#8217;s cast of characters. He&#8217;s my husband and business partner, and most of his professional work involves photography. </p>
<p>^I also know how CEOs are compensated, and let&#8217;s just say that non-profits typically aren&#8217;t quite as cash-strapped as they appear; they just don&#8217;t allocate money as effectively as they could or should. </p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/907/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/907/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=907&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://cuadernoinedito.wordpress.com/2012/09/08/we-all-have-to-stop-working-for-free-dont-we/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>15</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/abc8ec53fdc00662285887d39bf1d4fa?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">papertrail23</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cuadernoinedito.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/should-this-guy-work-for-free.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Should this guy work for free?</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>On a Dream, New York City, and a Little bit of Fatalism</title>
		<link>http://thepiccadillyline.com/2012/09/21/on-a-dream/</link>
		<comments>http://thepiccadillyline.com/2012/09/21/on-a-dream/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2012 18:27:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Just Be.</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[write]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brooklyn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[day trip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dream city]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[essay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[living abroad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[my life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NYC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photograph]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ramblings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[random]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[US]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vacation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thepiccadillyline.com/?p=1838</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve been imagining life in New York City since I was like five. Staying in posh hotels. Walking through the Central Park on snowy winter mornings wrapped in fur coats sipping on hot chocolate. I would watch episodes of Seinfeld and Friends, imagining the future studio I would call home. The one with the exposed [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1838&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://cobblestonestreets.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/photo-3.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1868" title="photo-3" alt="" src="http://cobblestonestreets.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/photo-3.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>I&#8217;ve been imagining life in New York City since I was like five. Staying in posh hotels. Walking through the Central Park on snowy winter mornings wrapped in fur coats sipping on hot chocolate. I would watch episodes of Seinfeld and Friends, imagining the future studio I would call home. The one with the exposed brick walls and tiny kitchen and fire escape. Even after all the dreaming, somehow I never managed to find myself in the Big Apple. Something always <em>always </em>got in the way. But then, a miracle&#8230; My sister moved there for school and after several months of planning, we finally decided on a weekend for me to visit. I booked my ticket, requested off work and counted down the days until a much needed sister reunion in my dream city.</p>
<p>I expected to be swept off my feet in a blur of late nights, early morning coffee runs and writing inspiration galore. I expected to miss my flight and camp out on the floor of Erin&#8217;s room until I found a job and a place to live. I expected NYC to steal my heart.</p>
<p>Then my plane landed. I was exhausted from a long day at work. The train took ages. I didn&#8217;t have my &#8216;Subway Legs&#8217; and about ended up face first in an old man&#8217;s crotch when I stumbled almost halfway down a train car. (#thatawkwardmoment). After dropping my stuff at my sister&#8217;s apartment we wandered about trying to find a place to get a drink. I had sensory overload and felt dirty. Please, Erin, I said, let&#8217;s just get food and go back. I&#8217;m so lame and so tired and so hungry. So we did. My first night in the city was spent eating hummus and cucumber on the floor of Erin&#8217;s bedroom watching The Dictator. (Although in my defense by this point it was after 1am and this grandma hadn&#8217;t seen that hour of the morning in a while.)</p>
<p>When I woke up the next day I showered, straightened my hair, put on makeup and picked out a cute outfit. Alright. Let&#8217;s do this, New York. Let&#8217;s fall in love.</p>
<p>I never fell in love.</p>
<p>Maybe I forced it just a little too hard. Maybe NYC baulked because I was just a little too intense. Subtlety has never been one of my qualities. I know what I want. ALWAYS. But I think my intensity, while admirable, can also cause burn out and let down.</p>
<p>I expected too much.</p>
<p>I wanted New York to be my American London. But that place, I realize now, had already been filled. Everyone told me I would love it. Everyone told me it was my kind of city. I told me it was my kind of city. But there was just&#8230; something missing. I didn&#8217;t get <em>that </em>feeling. That feeling I get when something is right. When I&#8217;m in a place I&#8217;m supposed to be.</p>
<p>My outlook on life tends to lean toward fatalism. While I think we exhibit a degree of control over our own lives and the choices we make, I also believe everything happens for a reason. That is not to say one should remain, essentially, a passive observer in their life because what will be will be. No. I simply believe that when something doesn&#8217;t work out it&#8217;s because something <strong>better </strong>is supposed to happen.</p>
<p>Had I visited New York with younger, inexperienced eyes, I would have fallen in love immediately. The lights and people would have danced in front of my eyes, hypnotic in their abundance. Instead all I could smell was the trash that lined the streets. The homeless begging for food and money made me sad. I felt dirty and grimy and constantly on edge. I was uncomfortable and unsettled. I grasped at Erin&#8217;s company and only found solace in a Saturday spent in Brooklyn.</p>
<p>I searched and searched for the feeling. For the butterflies to appear in my stomach. For the anxiety squeezing my chest to loosen its grasp. I searched for the feeling under the Statue of Liberty. On Ellis Island. On walks around the city. It appeared, for brief moments, on the streets of Willamsburg. Sitting on the beach slightly tipsy from sangria, gazing across the water to Manhattan. Relaxing at a pub, sheltered from the world by beer garden walls. But those moments were fleeting. And evaporated into the air as quickly as they appeared.</p>
<p>I do not want to portray my trip as a completely miserable experience. I did have a wonderful time. Rooftop bars at night. Starbucks in the park. Making up elaborate stories with Erin. But&#8230; Just but.</p>
<p>New York City failed to live up to the romantic version I created in my mind, falling hard from that pedestal on which it was placed so many years ago. I&#8217;m surprisingly OK with it. Like an amicable breakup from a relationship that never quite came to fruition. One where we can still be friends. See each other on occasion. Remember the good times that could have been.</p>
<p>New York City and I? We aren&#8217;t meant to be.</p>
<p>My thoughts have been wandering. Dreaming. Distracting me. There are two places I love. One is here and one is there. Two cities where my overwhelming and sometimes debilitating anxiety magically disappears. Two cities that are perfect in all their imperfections. Two cities that just <em>are</em>. My dream of New York has died. But two new dreams have taken root in its place. Something is going to take me to one of them. I can feel it.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1838/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1838/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1838&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thepiccadillyline.com/2012/09/21/on-a-dream/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>31</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/e5e920a1ff2a94c3a2a91f0f9e3b2079?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Just B.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cobblestonestreets.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/photo-3.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">photo-3</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What Kerouac Knew, But Not About Motorcycles—Café Racers Vs. The Digital Gods</title>
		<link>http://tenthmusememphis.wordpress.com/2012/11/09/what-kerouac-knew-but-not-about-motorcycles-cafe-racers-vs-the-digital-gods/</link>
		<comments>http://tenthmusememphis.wordpress.com/2012/11/09/what-kerouac-knew-but-not-about-motorcycles-cafe-racers-vs-the-digital-gods/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2012 18:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Tonya Thompson</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[cafe racer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Motorcycles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital age]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kerouac]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[motorcycling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[restoration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vintage motorcycles]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tenthmusememphis.wordpress.com/2012/11/09/what-kerouac-knew-but-not-about-motorcycles-cafe-racers-vs-the-digital-gods/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[By Tonya L. Thompson Sometimes, I’m afraid the world’s too digital.  When I watch a table of three at a restaurant—on the edges of their seats smartphone surfing—the nostalgia’s so bad I can almost taste it.  It’s the little stuff I miss, like animated conversations over dinner, photos in analogue color and a time when [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=138&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;">By Tonya L. Thompson</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://tenthmusememphis.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/images-11.jpg"><br />
<img id="i-137" class="size-full wp-image aligncenter" alt="Image" src="http://tenthmusememphis.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/images-11.jpg?w=265" /></a></p>
<p>Sometimes, I’m afraid the world’s too digital.  When I watch a table of three at a restaurant—on the edges of their seats smartphone surfing—the nostalgia’s so bad I can almost taste it.  It’s the little stuff I miss, like animated conversations over dinner, photos in analogue color and a time when people weren’t so constantly interrupted while living. I miss that time when every event wasn’t reduced to a photo op for Facebook, and when people lived in the moment, not in the digital recording of it once they are finally able to sync and upload. I know we were there once. I have memories of living that life, although it seems so far away from this one.</p>
<p>This is why the café racer, to me, is such a thing of beauty.  Words like ‘simplicity’, ‘basic’ and ‘only the necessities’ are dying in our culture.  Part of me wonders if café racers aren’t one niche way to mourn that death.  On the inside, where the grease meets the piston, it’s a return to the raw basics.  On the outside, while generations of bikers have divided into motorcycle patches and lifestyles, status symbols and outlaws, the rider of a café racer focuses on simplicity, baring his bike’s soul for the sake of removing excess and returning to the heart of the thing.  Why? I think it’s because sometimes, it takes straddling a seat built for one, with very little cushion, to rediscover what motorcycling is really about for the individual on the bike. The core of riding was never about money and women, gangsters and brotherhood. If you’ve felt it once, then you’ll know what I’m saying—motorcycling is, and always will be, about four very basic things: wind, speed, lightness and BEING.</p>
<p>The metaphors connecting a café racer bike and a return to the basics are almost endless. For the café racer restorer, there is recycling and redirecting, all while removing the rust created by years of neglect and the elements that piled up as the digital gods subtly staked their claim.  The flair is taken off, the parts providing comfort but slowing the whole thing down are removed, and the core of the motorcycle—its frame, engine, suspension and wheels—are laid bare.  These core pieces are the focus, and they are meticulously healed through fire and sand, elbow grease and water, cursing and bleeding, until the bike is as new as when it came off the line.  The rewards of that restorer’s work pay off: For the café racer rider, what you see is what you feel is what you get, and you’re reborn along with the bike as the clean engine sucks in the air of an open road and open throttle once again, like it did when it was first created.</p>
<p>And it’s here, on the road, where the aesthetics of the thing comes alive.  It’s rebellion and independence, reclaiming the freedom that should have never been taken.  It’s living on the edge of social norm because that’s where the most truths are revealed.  It’s the personification of James Dean and Marlon Brando, with fire under their skin and contempt for the establishment that would have them conform and forget how to live.  It’s notorious and lonely, and yes, even dangerous; but it’s in that moment, with the wind in your face, that you’ll understand what Kerouac meant when he wrote, “the only people for me are the mad ones, the ones who are mad to live, mad to talk, mad to be saved, desirous of everything at the same time, the ones who never yawn or say a commonplace thing, but burn, burn, burn, like fabulous yellow roman candles exploding like spiders across the stars.”  He didn’t ride a café racer, but he should have—he would have been at home on the thing.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/138/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/138/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=138&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tenthmusememphis.wordpress.com/2012/11/09/what-kerouac-knew-but-not-about-motorcycles-cafe-racers-vs-the-digital-gods/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/b21f05408b1c38c98bdcdb6ff30cb0f0?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bloodnblue</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tenthmusememphis.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/images-11.jpg?w=265" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Diego Negotiations.</title>
		<link>http://serenitynowinfertile.wordpress.com/2012/11/12/the-diego-negotiations/</link>
		<comments>http://serenitynowinfertile.wordpress.com/2012/11/12/the-diego-negotiations/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2012 13:32:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Serenity</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Battles (aka: toddlerhood)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NaBloPoMo]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://serenitynowinfertile.wordpress.com/?p=3785</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[We don&#8217;t watch a lot of TV in our house. We don&#8217;t really have a rule against it; I have no problem with Lucky watching a show here and there. We use our Netflix a lot; they have Backyardigans, Curious George, and other things he likes to watch here and there. I can&#8217;t tell you [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3785&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src='http://imageshack.us/a/img204/166/liarliaro.jpg' border='0' /> </p>
<p>We don&#8217;t watch a lot of TV in our house. We don&#8217;t really have a rule against it; I have no problem with Lucky watching a show here and there. We use our Netflix a lot; they have Backyardigans, Curious George, and other things he likes to watch here and there.</p>
<p>I can&#8217;t tell you exactly when it happened. But right now?</p>
<p>Lucky is obsessed to Diego episodes on Netflix. </p>
<p>And by obsessed, I mean ADDICTED. From the first moment he is awake in the mornings, it&#8217;s an ongoing negotiation for more Diego time. </p>
<p>Which, honestly, wouldn&#8217;t be awful, except for the extreme fits he&#8217;ll pitch when we shut Diego off. After one episode. Ten episodes. It doesn&#8217;t actually matter how much or little he has watched his beloved Diego.</p>
<p>When we turn it off, the freakout is worse than any three year tantrum he ever had; there&#8217;s screaming, hitting, kicking, yelling, crying.</p>
<p>And when Diego isn&#8217;t on, it&#8217;s all he talks about and asks for. <em>Mommy, can I watch a Diego?</em> Last week, when he had a friend over for a playdate? He tried to convince his friend that Diego was awesome and they should watch it.</p>
<p>Diego makes our weekends really hard lately. We&#8217;ve done everything we can to structure our time away from the house; keep Lucky busy outside and away from the TV. Otherwise we risk hours of negotiation for more Diego. </p>
<p>HOURS, I say. I wish I was kidding, but I&#8217;ve kept track. I spent two hours yesterday morning trying to get Lucky to do something DIFFERENT. Draw pictures &#8211; <em>hey, look, here&#8217;s a Diego coloring book!</em>- or play with Legos or build with blocks or help me sweep the garage or let&#8217;s just go for a drive because <em>SERIOUSLY I AM GOING TO LOSE MY MIND IF I HEAR YOU ASK FOR DIEGO ONE! MORE! TIME!</em></p>
<p>*sigh*</p>
<p>Yesterday we watched <del datetime="2012-11-12T12:49:30+00:00">50 million</del> a couple Diego episodes in the morning. After weathering the inevitable meltdown when we told Lucky he needed to do something else, we successfully managed to avoid The Diego Negotiations for the rest of the afternoon. Lucky decided to clean our garage (he wanted to use the broom), and the weather was awesome &#8211; in the 60s &#8211; so he played outside for a good while. We watched the Patriots game, the three of us.</p>
<p>And then it was time to say goodbye to Charlie Brown, and it was he and I. I was cleaning up from dinner, when Lucky came into the kitchen.</p>
<p><em>Mommy?</em> he asked. <em>I was really good today: I was good, and kind, and brave. Wasn&#8217;t I?</em></p>
<p>I laughed (on the inside! Always on the inside!) because I knew what was going to come next.</p>
<p><em>Mommy,</em> he said, very seriously. <em>I did a good job today keeping my underwear dry*. I used the potty LOTS of times. I cleaned the garage. I ate all my lunch. I FINK**&#8230;</em> he paused for effect, looking up at me very seriously,<em>that I deserve a Diego episode. JUST ONE. And THEN, we can go upstairs, and take a baff, and read ONE story, and then go to bed!</em> </p>
<p>In that moment, I wished I had a video of his performance. Because the child played the part PERFECTLY. It was an oscar-worthy performance; the shrug of his shoulders, and open hands, the wide open eyes, the smile on his face. His tone of voice was perfect &#8211; enthusiastic but quiet. </p>
<p>He was very convincing in that moment. Sure, just one episode! Surely that will be fine!</p>
<p>I can tell you what comes next. I say yes, and he claps his hands, jumping for joy, and he says, <em>Yay!! One more Diego!!!</em> And he watches one episode, and then we start the negotiation all over again once it&#8217;s over.</p>
<p>If I say no? He turns into the exorcist 4 year old: he screams, throws himself on the floor, sobbing like I&#8217;m the worst mother in the world.</p>
<p>I am largely impressed AND freaked out by his ability to negotiate, I have to admit. And all I repeat to myself when this happens? </p>
<p><em>This will serve him well later in life. This will serve him well later in life.</em></p>
<p>He&#8217;s learning by watching, at least. Yesterday he told me that chinchillas live in mountains and didn&#8217;t know how to swim. He can count to ten in Spanish. </p>
<p>But yeah. Exhausting stuff, these Diego Negotiations.</p>
<p>*Another post about this coming. He is still struggling with accidents and keeping his underwear dry during the daytime. We actually have an appointment scheduled with a pediatric urologist at the end of January.</p>
<p>** I will be so sad when he loses his toddler lisp; one of the few remnants of baby left in him these days. </p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3785/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3785/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3785&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://serenitynowinfertile.wordpress.com/2012/11/12/the-diego-negotiations/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>16</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/d20e0d203ae94269fadf84baa65d4bb8?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Serenity</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://imageshack.us/a/img204/166/liarliaro.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Super Mario: Black and Blue</title>
		<link>http://biasworldview.wordpress.com/2012/11/12/super-mario/</link>
		<comments>http://biasworldview.wordpress.com/2012/11/12/super-mario/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2012 18:36:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bia</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[The Word]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Euro 2012]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[football]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Italy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mario Balotelli]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[racism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[soccer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TIME]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[World Cup 1998]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zinedine Zidane]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://biasworldview.wordpress.com/?p=425</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[When I was a kid, Super Mario was a video game that featured a tiny Italian American plumber with a red cap and blue overalls. The times, they are a-changin&#8217;. Today Super Mario, last name Balotelli, is one of the biggest stars in the soccer solar system. Still, it was with no small degree of [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=425&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When I was a kid, Super Mario was a video game that featured a tiny Italian American plumber with a red cap and blue overalls. The times, they are a-changin&#8217;. Today Super Mario, last name Balotelli, is one of the biggest stars in the soccer solar system. Still, it was with no small degree of surprise that I found out he was gracing the cover of TIME magazine. <a href="http://biasworldview.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/20121112_600.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-426" title="20121112_600" alt="" src="http://biasworldview.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/20121112_600.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>The <a href="http://www.time.com/time/magazine/article/0,9171,2128258-1,00.html" target="_blank">article</a> by Catherine Mayer and Stephan Faris is well done and I personally always find it intriguing when mainstream American news media turn their attention to European football. They tend to look at the sport through a geopolitical/societal lens and as much as I love the game itself and some of the players who excel at it, that perspective is endlessly fascinating to me.</p>
<p>The game and everything that surrounds it reveals so much &#8211; to my mind &#8211; about European society as a whole but also about the nuances from one country to the other. And in that landscape, complicated as it is, Balotelli is still something else, some thing apart.</p>
<p>He&#8217;s the first black player to play for the Azzuri (Italy&#8217;s national team). He&#8217;s young, extremely talented, as just as extremely mercurial. The piece in TIME does a good job of explaining some of the events and experiences that have shaped him but what really interested me was the conversation that it opened up about racism.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;ve been reading my blog for a while, you&#8217;ll no doubt recall my <a href="http://biasworldview.wordpress.com/2012/09/27/are-you-kidding-me-terry-punishment-is-a-joke/" target="_blank">rant </a>about the punishment handed down to Chelsea captain (and former England captain) John Terry who was found guilty of racially abusing another player.</p>
<p>England, which has done such a remarkable job of sussing out a huge chunk of the nefarious elements that plagued football in the 80s and further back, finds itself dealing with an increasing number of high profile incidents of racism. The latest in date involved referee Mark Clattenburg who is accused of using racist and xenophobic language towards two Chelsea players during the recent Man United v Chelsea match.</p>
<p>And despite that, England is considered to have a much better handle on racism in football than countries like Spain and Italy where monkey chants and other forms of abuse towards black players are not uncommon. Imagine what that&#8217;s like for Balotelli. He scored two goals against Germany in the Euro 2012 semi final, which qualified Italy for the final. In case you&#8217;re not clear on it, that is A. Big. Effing. Deal.  Think scoring the touchdown that takes your team to the Superbowl. And yet as Mayer and Faris recount, he&#8217;s had racist abuse hurled at him from Italy fans who purport that &#8220;there&#8217;s no such thing as a black Italian&#8221;.</p>
<p>This brings me to a conversation that I&#8217;ve had more than once, usually with American friends or colleagues, about racism in America and racism in Europe. Just the other day in fact, in the aftermath of Barack Obama&#8217;s re-election, the topic came up again. If I&#8217;m perfectly honest, I don&#8217;t think America is more or less racist than Europe or vice versa. What I think is that racism manifests differently because the contexts are different.</p>
<p>Don&#8217;t get me wrong, racism is a problem no matter <em>how</em> it manifests but fighting it requires looking at its roots and the context in which it thrives. In other words, racism doesn&#8217;t necessarily exist for the same reasons in one place as it does in another.</p>
<p>America, as we know it now, was built by immigrants, by people not native to its shores. And while those people haven&#8217;t always gotten along and many have been oppressed and discriminated against, they have nevertheless always been forced to co-exist. And so the diversity has always been present if not peaceful.</p>
<p>This is not the case in Europe and what we&#8217;re seeing now  are generations of Europeans that live in an existential no man&#8217;s land. Born in Europe, with relatively recent foreign origins, who don&#8217;t fit in the country or culture of their parents or grandparents but who haven&#8217;t been fully accepted by the societies that they grew up in. It&#8217;s an identity crisis not just for them, but for the whole continent. Coming to grips with it isn&#8217;t going to be easy and for better or worse, it&#8217;s going to take time.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, in America, it would be a mistake to think that upward social mobility and increased opportunities for minorities automatically means that there is less racism than before. All it definitively shows is that racism is less overt than it used to be and no longer institutionalized in the same way.</p>
<p>Progress has definitely been made but we shouldn&#8217;t throw political correctness into the mix and think we&#8217;re farther along than we are. Bottom line is we <em>all </em>have work to do when it comes to fighting prejudice.</p>
<p>And to take it back to Balotelli. Until I wrote this, it would never have occurred to me to compare him to Zinedine Zidane, the legendary French player (of Algerian descent), but all of a sudden the comparison makes an odd kind of sense. After France won the World Cup in 1998, the team was turned into this political and cultural instrument and used to tout the success of immigrant integration in France. Zidane, as the team&#8217;s play maker and because of his origins, found himself right in the thick of that.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s no doubt that Balotelli could experience something similar and I doubt he&#8217;ll be any more comfortable with it than Zidane was.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/425/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/425/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=425&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://biasworldview.wordpress.com/2012/11/12/super-mario/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/e780ce8b7e68b44ac39c9a7d26885286?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">terrapromessa25</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://biasworldview.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/20121112_600.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">20121112_600</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Homemade Pinecone Firelighters</title>
		<link>http://katescreativespace.com/2012/10/19/homemade-pinecone-firelighters/</link>
		<comments>http://katescreativespace.com/2012/10/19/homemade-pinecone-firelighters/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2012 15:23:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Kate</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Homing Instinct]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Making]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autumn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christmas gifts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cinnamon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[craft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fall]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fir]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[firelighters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[holiday craft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ikea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[log fire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pinecones]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://katescreativespace.com/?p=1771</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Log fires, blankets, mugs of hot chocolate, toasty warm socks&#8230; there&#8217;s something magical about this time of year. It&#8217;s been a misty, cold day here and we&#8217;re planning to light the first fire of the season tonight to celebrate the start of  the weekend and our hibernation from the winter weather.  In preparation I&#8217;ve made [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1771&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://katescreativespace.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/diy-pinecones-master.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1772" title="DIY Pinecone Firelighters from www.katescreativespace.com" alt="" src="http://katescreativespace.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/diy-pinecones-master.jpg?w=590"   /></a><br />
<a class="pin-it-button" href="http://pinterest.com/pin/create/button/?url=http%3A%2F%2Fkatescreativespace.com%2F2012%2F10%2F19%2Fhomemade-pinecone-firelighters%2F&amp;media=http%3A%2F%2Fkatescreativespace.files.wordpress.com%2F2012%2F10%2Fdiy-pinecones-master.jpg&amp;description=Simple%20DIY%20Pinecone%20Firelighters%20tutorial%20from%20www.katescreativespace.com"><img title="Pin It" alt="" src="//assets.pinterest.com/images/PinExt.png" /></a><br />
Log fires, blankets, mugs of hot chocolate, toasty warm socks&#8230; there&#8217;s something magical about this time of year. It&#8217;s been a misty, cold day here and we&#8217;re planning to light the first fire of the season tonight to celebrate the start of  the weekend and our hibernation from the winter weather.  In preparation I&#8217;ve made these pinecone firelighters, lightly scented with cinnamon and guaranteed to set the kindling alight with a pop and a crackle.</p>
<p>You can buy these commercially but at vast expense, so I decided to have a go at making my own, with a view to giving these as homemade gifts this Christmas.  My research uncovered scarily complicated instructions involving double-boilers, safety goggles, wick-trimming and dipping and general scientific sorcery&#8230; so I applied some lateral thinking and came up with a <em>much</em> simpler approach.  It&#8217;s very safe and quick, though perhaps the only downside of this is that you&#8217;re unlikely to need to attract your local Firemen for manly assistance.</p>
<p><strong>You&#8217;ll need:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>A pocketful of pine cones</li>
<li>Pack of tea-lights or small candles; I used IKEA&#8217;s gorgeous white <a href="http://www.ikea.com/us/en/catalog/products/50138444/" target="_blank">Fenomen</a> ones.</li>
<li>Cupcake cases, slightly larger than your pine cones</li>
<li><em>Optional</em> candle scent; cinnamon, pine, cranberry and sandalwood are all divine.</li>
</ul>
<p>Firstly, gather all your pine cones.  Size doesn&#8217;t matter here, but give them a quick brush to remove dust and bits of forest-floor debris.  Pinecones which are tightly closed will open once exposed to the warm, so you may want to store them inside for a week before using.</p>
<p><a href="http://katescreativespace.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/pine-copy1.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1777" title="pine cones" alt="" src="http://katescreativespace.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/pine-copy1.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>When you&#8217;re ready to &#8216;cook&#8217;, line a cupcake tin with cases and place one of your tea lights or candles into each.  Make sure you remove the little metal cases if using tea lights, and tweak the wicks so that they are standing upright and proud of the wax; it&#8217;s much easier than fishing for them later.  Place in a moderate oven and keep checking until the wax melts and resembles water.  At this point you can add a drop of candle scent to each, or simply leave plain.</p>
<p><a href="http://katescreativespace.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/diy-pine-melt.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1780" title="DIy pine melt" alt="" src="http://katescreativespace.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/diy-pine-melt.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>Once the wax has melted, move the wicks gently to one side of the case, using tweezers (or with your best pointy fingers; remember that some people claim to quite enjoy being covered in hot wax&#8230;hmmm).  This will ensure that the wicks don&#8217;t get lost underneath the cones.</p>
<p><a href="http://katescreativespace.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/diy-pine-wicks.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1779" title="DIY pine wicks" alt="" src="http://katescreativespace.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/diy-pine-wicks.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>Then simply place a pinecone into each case; the wax will rise around it and hold it firmly in place as it sets.</p>
<p><a href="http://katescreativespace.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/diy-pine-placement.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1778" title="DIY pine placement" alt="" src="http://katescreativespace.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/diy-pine-placement.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>When the wax has cooled and set, lift the cases out of the pans and peel away the cupcake case, revealing your firelighters in all of their glory&#8230;</p>
<p><a href="http://katescreativespace.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/diy-pine-unpopped.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1781" title="DIY pine unpopped" alt="" src="http://katescreativespace.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/diy-pine-unpopped.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://katescreativespace.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/diy-pine-red-80.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1782" title="DIY pine cones from katescreativespace" alt="" src="http://katescreativespace.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/diy-pine-red-80.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>These also look very pretty when left in their cases; I&#8217;ll be tying a bundle of these (below) up in cellophane bags or small burlap sacks to take as gifts for those we visit during the festive season (though I&#8217;ll probably check that they have an open fireplace first&#8230;).</p>
<p><a href="http://katescreativespace.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/diy-pine-blue-80.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1783" title="DIY pine cone firelighters" alt="" src="http://katescreativespace.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/diy-pine-blue-80.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>And now the light is fading, the kettle is on, and we&#8217;re almost all home; have a wonderful weekend whatever you&#8217;re doing!</p>
<p><em><strong>*Update*</strong></em>; a few people have asked via email or comments how these work; to use these firelighters, simply place them at the base of your fire and arrange kindling over the top before lighting the wick; the wax ensures that the pinecone will catch light and burn for long enough to ignite the kindling and create a real blaze; at that point you can add bigger logs and settle back for an evening watching the flames.  Here&#8217;s how ours turned out this evening;</p>
<p><a href="http://katescreativespace.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/using-pinecone-firelighters1.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1792" title="using pinecone firelighters" alt="" src="http://katescreativespace.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/using-pinecone-firelighters1.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://katescreativespace.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/fire-final.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1793" title="fire final" alt="" src="http://katescreativespace.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/fire-final.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://katescreativespace.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/pinecones-katescreativespace.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1785" title="pinecones katescreativespace" alt="" src="http://katescreativespace.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/pinecones-katescreativespace.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1771/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1771/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1771&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://katescreativespace.com/2012/10/19/homemade-pinecone-firelighters/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>39</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/710c2731acd135510f5ea3cc591f13fd?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">katescreativespace</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://katescreativespace.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/diy-pinecones-master.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DIY Pinecone Firelighters from www.katescreativespace.com</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://katescreativespace.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/pine-copy1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">pine cones</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://katescreativespace.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/diy-pine-melt.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DIy pine melt</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://katescreativespace.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/diy-pine-wicks.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DIY pine wicks</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://katescreativespace.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/diy-pine-placement.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DIY pine placement</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://katescreativespace.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/diy-pine-unpopped.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DIY pine unpopped</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://katescreativespace.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/diy-pine-red-80.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DIY pine cones from katescreativespace</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://katescreativespace.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/diy-pine-blue-80.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DIY pine cone firelighters</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://katescreativespace.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/using-pinecone-firelighters1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">using pinecone firelighters</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://katescreativespace.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/fire-final.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">fire final</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://katescreativespace.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/pinecones-katescreativespace.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">pinecones katescreativespace</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Designing a Creative Travel Journal, Part 1</title>
		<link>http://smallestforest.net/2012/11/05/designing-a-creative-travel-journal-part-1/</link>
		<comments>http://smallestforest.net/2012/11/05/designing-a-creative-travel-journal-part-1/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2012 04:32:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>smallestforest</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[art + design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Inspirations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[projects]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artifacts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Arts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[course]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Coursera.org]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[study]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[university]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://smallestforest.net/?p=3769</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I decided to make some sort of journal/repository for creative travelers...an object I'd very much like for myself, but parts of which I thought might be incorporated into the hand-bound journals I sell in my shop, as well. Travel journals need to be so much more than books with pages for writing...what would such a journal have to include in order to be your first choice?<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3769&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://smallestforest.net/2012/11/05/designing-a-creative-travel-journal-part-1/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>25</slash:comments>
		<georss:point>-12.449029 130.855172</georss:point>
		<geo:lat>-12.449029</geo:lat>
		<geo:long>130.855172</geo:long>
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/1df113b333e83df8ddd627ec069faeb0?s=96&#38;d=monsterid&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">smallestforest</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8195/8149321042_d10aa270c7_c.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">1-4 memento travel journal</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8193/8149291599_6ed7184863_c.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">prototype 1.4 scaled03</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7128/8155966360_4cbd5a57cc.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">prototype 1.4 scaled04</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8485/8155965846_120dd3d2a8.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">prototype 1.4 scaled06</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7118/8155934579_8d2d76403a.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">prototype 1.4 scaled07</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>