<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2013 21:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>The Why: In Which I Defend  Living In The South</title>
		<link>http://kchapmangibbons.wordpress.com/2013/01/18/the-why/</link>
		<comments>http://kchapmangibbons.wordpress.com/2013/01/18/the-why/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2013 16:40:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>kchapmangibbons</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Demographics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diversity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Religion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[demographics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Divesity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Homophobia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Maddow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Millennials]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Racism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stereotypes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The South]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://kchapmangibbons.wordpress.com/?p=49</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Yesterday on Rachel Maddow&#8217;s blog, there was a question to all &#8220;blue dots.&#8221; Why do you stay in red states and do you ever want to leave? The question struck right at the issue most on my mind since the reelection of the President. It seems that writers (particularly from the Northeast) publish article after article [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=49&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday on Rachel Maddow&#8217;s blog, there was a question to all &#8220;blue dots.&#8221; Why do you stay in red states and do you ever want to leave? The question struck right at the issue most on my mind since the reelection of the President. It seems that writers (particularly from the Northeast) publish article after article along the lines of &#8220;What is wrong with the South?&#8221; Or, &#8220;Go Ahead And Secede Already.&#8221; They have been popping up like Honey Boo Boo references. Most of them are almost gleeful at the thought of dumping the South. (Because this is what Lincoln wanted ?!?)</p>
<p>Each time I see these articles, I get a little more angry. It would be dishonest to say that this isn&#8217;t a longstanding peeve for me. Bill Maher is a perpetual offender. The Simpsons, the media (old &amp; new) and even my beloved Jon Stewart all take shots at the South regularly.</p>
<p>Now, let me be crystal clear. I get angry at all the hatred, bigotry and racism in the South every day of my life. But the jabs from other progressives are particularly hurtful. It would seem that with many red states trending purple (Virginia, North Carolina and Texas and Georgia soon enough) that this might be counter intuitive to winning elections, but the South is a dependable punchline nonetheless.</p>
<p>As I read through the comments of the Maddow blog post, a few themes began to emerge. There are two main groups of &#8220;blue dots.&#8221; There are those, like myself who stay because we feel an obligation, a connection and/or are immersed in activism. However, there were many more who expressed a desire to leave and be done with the whole struggle. I sympathize with those so isolated in their own communities. It must also be said without reservation, that I stay as a white, married woman with children. Even though I am not religious and a vocal advocate for equality, my circumstance is much more comfortable than for many in the lgbtqai community and for people of color. My friends in these communities have sometimes left because their safety was at risk and because no one deserves to be surrounded by people who hate them. I get this. I support these friends because I know what it means to stand out in any way in communities of cultural lag.</p>
<p>I left the Southeast for the first time for Grad School at Drew University in the early 1990&#8242;s. Previously, I had grown up all over the region because my father was a Baptist preacher. I was given a scholarship to Drew (one of two a year) due to my &#8220;minority status,&#8221; as Appalachian. I never once thought of myself this way, although my heritage and culture were and are very dear to me. It was a bizarre experience. By the end of my first semester, I went to my mentor determined to withdraw and head South. She was from Texas and told me she experienced a similar dislocation when first up North. She suggested I find a place to eat food I liked (had to go to Harlem for that), make friends with other immigrants and buy cowboy boots. In essence, she told me if people were making assumptions about my intelligence, then I should at least make them feel uncomfortable about it. I took her advice and finished the degree. Without a doubt, it was the loneliest time of my life.</p>
<p>Since my return, the South has changed in many ways, particularly in the cities. And like everywhere else in the world, the cities are where the growth is occurring. People are less religious, more open with regard to sexuality, gender and race and less tolerant of intolerance. Anyone who read demographic information from the election knows this is happening all over the country. The Millennials are different. Teaching in colleges the last decade, it has been no surprise to me the ways in which this generation differs from previous ones. In my Diversity class, I survey students the first day about many aspects of their socialization. Less than a third in any class I&#8217;ve taught in six years still attend the religious services they grew up with&#8211;and I live under the buckle of the Bible Belt. They are consistently more liberal about social issues. I didn&#8217;t need Pew to know this, although it is always good to have statistical evidence to back anecdotal information. There is also a rapidly growing Hispanic population.</p>
<p>This trend is bigger than one region, no doubt. But I believe it is also because there are many of us who have refused to abandon our own culture; the good (you are welcome for almost all modern music) and the bad (the racism, homophobia, etc.). If we all left, there would be no counter to ever pervasive right-wing yammer&#8211;on the radio, in the office and in the State Legislature. Young people raised here need to know that you can embrace where you come from and redefine it. Not so young people need to know it is okay to buck tradition, disobey the Church, distance themselves from the darker opinions of the past. Bottom line: We progressives are desperately needed.</p>
<p>Please don&#8217;t think this is a martyr move. I love living below the Mason-Dixon for many reasons. Here is a short list:</p>
<ul>
<li><span><span style="line-height:14px;">My family (99%) of them are still here. I see them several times a year&#8230;cousins, aunts, uncles, grandparents and other relatives. </span><del style="line-height:14px;">Family is still a high priority here.</del><span style="line-height:14px;">  (It was rightly pointed out to me that this sentence is both bone-headed and inaccurate. Of course people the world over value their families.)  We don&#8217;t scatter as much as other Americans.</span></span></li>
<li>Way of life. One reason I hated living up North so vehemently was because it is all about work. We value leisure here. That is why we sit on porches.</li>
<li>Friendliness. I know this freaks people out at times and others think it is all a show. For me, banter with strangers makes society less hostile. Southern people aren&#8217;t known for their hospitality for nothing.</li>
<li>The land. Whether it is the beach, the mountains or the foothills&#8211;many of our ancestors came here for fertile land and freedom. My people are from Oconee County, South Carolina, which borders North Carolina and Georgia. When I see the Smokies, I breathe deeper and feel the power of the landscape each and every time.</li>
<li>Culture. Encompassing music, food and all else this word conjures. If I want to hear a banjo, I only have to drive a few miles. And if I want good biscuits and tea that is sweet, there is a meat and three down the road.</li>
<li>Faith. I sincerely believe that things are and will continue to change in the region. It is my hope that we can hold on to some of the aspects that distinguish us and still continue to evolve on social and religious issues. It may take longer than I want it to. It will surely take longer if me and all my fellow liberals flee and join the sneering ranks.</li>
</ul>
<p>Perhaps it&#8217;d be a quicker evolution if our progressive peers would dial back the haughtiness. Each time people from the South are portrayed as dumb, inbred, more racist than all other Americans, fat, lazy, and backward, it makes it that much harder to change opinions. These stereotypes have long lives and only nurse resentments from another time in history. Recognize that both historically and presently, the United States is not all it can be without the South. Lincoln did.</p>
<p>Yes, we use more resources from the Federal government and also like to complain about it. Yes, we have a persistent strain of racism in our history and in 2013. Yes, we speak a different dialect. Yes, our students&#8217; test scores are lower. Yes, we have more poverty. Yes, we are more overweight because we REALLY like butter. But, we did give you rock n&#8217; roll, blues and country music. We are teaching some of you how to relax (because you keep coming here to retire). We can claim The Highlander Center, Molly Ivins and former President Carter. And as poor Notre Dame found out, we give you kick ass football.</p>
<p>The South contributes a lot to the country. We are not a lost cause. And to Stewart et al: feel free to mock our politicians mercilessly. Most of them deserve it. Just leave the rest of us out of it&#8230;we need to keep our anger focused on injustice.</p>
<p>** Link to Maddow Blog post from 1/17/13:<a title="Blue dot wonders: Better Life Somewhere Else? " href="http://http://on.msnbc.com/Sef4bE" target="_blank"> http://on.msnbc.com/Sef4bE</a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/49/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/49/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=49&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://kchapmangibbons.wordpress.com/2013/01/18/the-why/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>47</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://kchapmangibbons.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/cropped-freethinker2.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://kchapmangibbons.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/cropped-freethinker2.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cropped-freethinker2.jpg</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/117f84cd6da96558760fb080e1c5716e?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">kchapmangibbons</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Ghost of Almost</title>
		<link>http://alwaystayliejay.wordpress.com/2013/01/19/the-ghost-of-almost/</link>
		<comments>http://alwaystayliejay.wordpress.com/2013/01/19/the-ghost-of-almost/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2013 01:08:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Taylor Devost</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Poetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[all the things you almost did would have changed your life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[don't give up on your dreams]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family vacation i never took]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[i almost did]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life unloved]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[orphans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[regret]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shelter dogs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the ghost of almost]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[you can make a difference if you try]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://alwaystayliejay.wordpress.com/?p=970</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The book you didn’t finish writing would have changed the lives of many people. The band you gave up on would have radically changed the world of music even more so than The Beatles. The family vacation you didn’t take would have been the last time your whole family would be together and happy. Your [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=970&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The book you didn’t finish writing would have changed the lives of many people.</p>
<p>The band you gave up on would have radically changed the world of music even more so than The Beatles. </p>
<p>The family vacation you didn’t take would have been the last time your whole family would be together and happy. Your dad would die two weeks later. </p>
<p>The dog you didn’t save from being euthanized at the local shelter would have saved your son from drowning that cold day in November. </p>
<p>The orphan who sits on her bed praying for a family to come take her home and love her will never get adopted. She will become homeless and die of a drug overdose. If she had been adopted, she would have become the next Mother Theresa. </p>
<p>The man who never proposed to his girlfriend out of fear of ending up like his parents died, sad and alone. </p>
<p>The vacation to Hawaii you wanted to take twenty years ago, but never did, would have changed your whole life. You would have met your soul mate and eloped on the beach.  You would still be happily married today. </p>
<p>The girl you see on your bus every day that sits in the same seat with the same black fingernail polish and the loneliest look in her eyes wants to kill herself. If you had sat next to her that last day, you would have made a new friend. She would have been a bridesmaid at your wedding. Her parents were the only ones that went to her funeral. </p>
<p>If you had quit the corporate job that makes you miserable, you would still have a good relationship with your children. </p>
<p>The homeless man on the street corner that you drive by without a second glance would have used that dollar you gave him to buy a lottery ticket. He would have won millions and used the money to help find a cure for aids. </p>
<p>The old lady sitting in her rocking chair talking to her grandchildren about life has terminal cancer. She tells her grandchildren stories of love and adventure from her younger days. Her grandson will ask, “So did you do everything in life you always wanted to, Grandma?” </p>
<p>“Almost,” she says. </p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/970/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/970/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=970&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://alwaystayliejay.wordpress.com/2013/01/19/the-ghost-of-almost/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>15</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/700500a719937e36ddd82840a1a4c86b?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tayliejay</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Manti Te&#8217;o Hoax: What the Hell Were Thousands of Media Professionals Thinking?</title>
		<link>http://misanthropology101.wordpress.com/2013/01/18/the-manti-teo-hoax-what-the-hell-were-thousands-of-media-professionals-thinking/</link>
		<comments>http://misanthropology101.wordpress.com/2013/01/18/the-manti-teo-hoax-what-the-hell-were-thousands-of-media-professionals-thinking/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2013 20:45:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Geoffrey Cubbage</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Media & Internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[deadspin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[football]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hoax]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lennay kekua]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manti te'o]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[notre dame]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://misanthropology101.wordpress.com/?p=5313</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[My first job out of college, at a quarterly magazine, was a quaint little thing called &#8220;fact checking.&#8221; (Also, to be fair, copy editing, web content, and even the occasional bit of writing &#8212; it was a pretty good gig, as far as those first jobs go. But the key part of it for today&#8217;s [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=5313&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://misanthropology101.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/manti-teo-notre-dame.jpg"><img class="alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-5315" alt="manti-teo-notre-dame" src="http://misanthropology101.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/manti-teo-notre-dame.jpg?w=179&#038;h=211" width="179" height="211" /></a>My first job out of college, at a quarterly magazine, was a quaint little thing called &#8220;fact checking.&#8221; (Also, to be fair, copy editing, web content, and even the occasional bit of writing &#8212; it was a pretty good gig, as far as those first jobs go. But the key part of it for today&#8217;s purposes is the fact checking.)</p>
<p>Fact checking is not a particularly sophisticated art. It involves going through the rough draft of a story and making a little mark in red next to every statement of checkable fact. So if the lede is something like &#8220;Dr. John Dongley Thompson, an erectile dysfunction specialist at Sweet Mother of God Hospital in downtown Chicago, is having a hard time keeping up with demand for his services,&#8221; the fact checker goes through and makes a little dash or something above &#8220;Dr.,&#8221; above the name, above the specialization, and above the hospital name and location.</p>
<p>Then he/she hastens to yon internet and double-checks that all those things are, in fact, true &#8212; that this guy exists and has a doctorate from somewhere, that his name is spelled right, that he does indeed practice the kind of medicine the story says he practices, and that he is in fact employed by the hospital named and that it is still in business and located where the article says it is.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not a very glamorous job. But it is an important one, and at the risk of self-aggrandizement, I&#8217;m going to go ahead and say that having done it for a summer more than qualifies me to ask: where the <em>hell</em> were everybody&#8217;s fact-checkers when they were running their heartwarming Manti Te&#8217;o stories?</p>
<p><a href="http://misanthropology101.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/manti-teo-deadspin-blarney.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-5317" alt="manti-teo-deadspin-blarney" src="http://misanthropology101.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/manti-teo-deadspin-blarney.jpg?w=300&#038;h=168" width="300" height="168" /></a></p>
<p>If you&#8217;re like me, &#8220;Manti Te&#8217;o&#8221; was not a name you&#8217;d heard before this week. He is apparently a bit of a somebody in college football? But this year he was especially somebody because he not only played football well, he also had a heartwarming story about a sick girlfriend and, eventually, a <em>dead</em> girlfriend, along with a dead grandmother or something like that.</p>
<p>And like many people this week, I found out about this whole precious story because <em>Deadspin</em> blew it out of the water. I&#8217;d never heard of Manti Te&#8217;o, much less his girlfriend and her tragic battle with cancer or whatever, until <em>Deadspin</em> (<em>Deadspin!</em> Fucking <em>Deadspin!</em>) ran a blockbuster &#8220;scoop&#8221; pointing out that <a href="http://deadspin.com/5976517/manti-teos-dead-girlfriend-the-most-heartbreaking-and-inspirational-story-of-the-college-football-season-is-a-hoax">Manti Te&#8217;o doesn&#8217;t have a dead girlfriend</a>. So maybe it&#8217;s a little too easy for me to pass judgement.</p>
<p>But seriously? From the <em>Deadspin</em> article:</p>
<blockquote><p><em>Manti Te&#8217;o did lose his grandmother this past fall. Annette Santiago died on Sept. 11, 2012, at the age of 72, according to Social Security Administration records in Nexis. But there is no SSA record there of the death of Lennay Marie Kekua, that day or any other. Her passing, recounted so many times in the national media, produces no obituary or funeral announcement in Nexis, and no mention in the Stanford student newspaper.</em></p>
<p><em>Nor is there any report of a severe auto accident involving a Lennay Kekua. Background checks turn up nothing. The Stanford registrar&#8217;s office has no record that a Lennay Kekua ever enrolled. There is no record of her birth in the news. Outside of a few Twitter and Instagram accounts, there&#8217;s no online evidence that Lennay Kekua ever existed.</em></p>
<p><em>The photographs identified as Kekua—in online tributes and on TV news reports—are pictures from the social-media accounts of a 22-year-old California woman who is not named Lennay Kekua. She is not a Stanford graduate; she has not been in a severe car accident; and she does not have leukemia. And she has never met Manti Te&#8217;o.</em></p></blockquote>
<p>This would not be a big story if every major news source in the country hadn&#8217;t run something or other, at some point, about all of those untrue claims the <em>Deadspin</em> article just listed.</p>
<p>ESPN talked about his inspiring story. <em>Sports Illustrated</em> talked about it. <em>The South Bend Tribune</em> wouldn&#8217;t shut up about it, ever. And they were all printing something completely unsupported by the simplest and most checkable of facts, and then <em>other</em> news sources picked it up and ran the same, bogus story, without ever checking it on <em>their</em> watch.</p>
<p><a href="http://misanthropology101.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/newspaper-reporter-typewriter.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-5321" alt="newspaper-reporter-typewriter" src="http://misanthropology101.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/newspaper-reporter-typewriter.jpg?w=129&#038;h=129" width="129" height="129" /></a>The sad part is that <em>Deadspin</em> finally figuring their shit out (and even they got an anonymous tip that got them moving; it&#8217;s not like they started doing basic journalism on their own either) is being treated like a serious investigative scoop, when all they did was what everyone that ever touched this story should have done: check the goddamn facts.</p>
<p>Did the guy tell you his girlfriend went to Stanford? Brilliant! <em>Check their student registries.</em> He talks about a car crash? Look up the accident report! She&#8217;s in the hospital? Maybe think about calling around and seeing if anyone has a patient by that name.</p>
<p>These things are thirty second jobs, maybe a minute, tops, for a $12-an-hour summer intern fresh out of undergrad. There&#8217;s no excuse for <em>The New York Times</em> to be running a story that refers to a made-up woman as a &#8220;Stanford alumnus&#8221; &#8212; but the <em>Times</em> did. And the list of top-tier media sources that made the same basic error goes on and on; the <em>Deadspin</em> article quite gleefully &#8212; and quite correctly &#8212; calls them out on it one by one.</p>
<p>Sports writers are going to be making a lot of hay out of who knew what when, and whether Manti Te&#8217;o was in on the scam and if so how deep, and so on, but that&#8217;s all a bunch of barn-door closing. The real story here is that, for at least a year, sports media have been making front page news out of a bogus story, and not even a very good one. Five minutes of fact-checking could have spiked any one of the dozens of headline Manti Te&#8217;o/Lennay Kekua articles that ran in 2012.</p>
<p>Good job, guys.</p>
<p><em>Deadspin </em>(fucking <em>Deadspin</em>; seriously now) sums it all up bluntly:</p>
<blockquote><p><em>There was no Lennay Kekua. Lennay Kekua did not meet Manti Te&#8217;o after the Stanford game in 2009. Lennay Kekua did not attend Stanford. Lennay Kekua never visited Manti Te&#8217;o in Hawaii. Lennay Kekua was not in a car accident. Lennay Kekua did not talk to Manti Te&#8217;o every night on the telephone. She was not diagnosed with cancer, did not spend time in the hospital, did not engage in a lengthy battle with leukemia. She never had a bone marrow transplant. She was not released from the hospital on Sept. 10, nor did Brian Te&#8217;o congratulate her for this over the telephone. She did not insist that Manti Te&#8217;o play in the Michigan State or Michigan games, and did not request he send white flowers to her funeral. Her favorite color was not white. Her brother, Koa, did not inform Manti Te&#8217;o that she was dead. Koa did not exist. Her funeral did not take place in Carson, Calif., and her casket was not closed at 9 a.m. exactly. She was not laid to rest.</em></p>
<p><em>Lennay Kekua&#8217;s last words to Manti Te&#8217;o were not &#8220;I love you.&#8221;</em></p></blockquote>
<p>And that&#8217;s the real story here.</p>
<p>If your mother says she loves you, <em>check it out.</em></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5313/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5313/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=5313&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://misanthropology101.wordpress.com/2013/01/18/the-manti-teo-hoax-what-the-hell-were-thousands-of-media-professionals-thinking/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>30</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/3be3d39af6be758061a883bde208f25d?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F0.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=R" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cubbageg</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://misanthropology101.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/manti-teo-notre-dame.jpg?w=127" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">manti-teo-notre-dame</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://misanthropology101.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/manti-teo-deadspin-blarney.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">manti-teo-deadspin-blarney</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://misanthropology101.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/newspaper-reporter-typewriter.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">newspaper-reporter-typewriter</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>On Digital Dualism</title>
		<link>http://erinstark.net/2013/01/19/on-digital-dualism-or-why-in-2013-are-people-still-fearmongering-the-internet/</link>
		<comments>http://erinstark.net/2013/01/19/on-digital-dualism-or-why-in-2013-are-people-still-fearmongering-the-internet/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2013 00:23:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>erin</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[academia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[geekology 101]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cyber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dichotomies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital dualism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hoax]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Manti Te'o]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nathan Jurgenson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online/offline]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real/virtual]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://erinstark.net/?p=7182</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve spent the better part of the past 48 hours editing a chapter of my thesis called &#8216;Always online: How social networks and mobile phones re-embodied and re-placed digital narratives&#8217;. The crux of the piece is that over the course of the past ten years (what some might call the &#8216;Web 2.0&#8216; era), and particular [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=7182&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve spent the better part of the past 48 hours editing a chapter of my thesis called &#8216;Always online: How social networks and mobile phones re-embodied and re-placed digital narratives&#8217;.</p>
<p>The crux of the piece is that over the course of the past ten years (what some might call the &#8216;<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_2.0" target="_blank">Web 2.0</a>&#8216; era), and particular over the past five years since smartphone ownership rates skyrocketed and Internet-enabled mobile devices became the norm, the dichotomies of online/offline and virtual/real have become less meaningful, and certainly less useful, ways of describing the relationship that we, the users, have with the Internet. Not only has the Internet moved rapidly from being the haunt of geeks and researchers to a tool that everyone uses, but really, we&#8217;re always online. Having access is something that we take for granted; the trade off of ubiquity is that we&#8217;re never really alone, and never really &#8216;offline&#8217;.</p>
<p>I read <a href="http://thesocietypages.org/cyborgology/2013/01/18/digital-life-is-a-hoaxbecause-theres-no-such-thing/" target="_blank">this blog post</a> by Nathan Jurgenson, a doctoral researcher from the University of Maryland, about the tendency of society &#8211; particularly the mainstream media &#8211; to still reduce life to digital dualisms, despite the fact that the notion of there being anything at all &#8216;fake&#8217; about the Internet is far out of date. It was a timely post for me, as he&#8217;s managed to say in 500 words what I&#8217;ve been battling with for the past two days (more eloquently, of course).</p>
<p>The term that Jurgenson uses is <strong><em>digital dualisms</em></strong><em>. </em>This is the notion that the dichotomies I mentioned above &#8211; online/offline, virtual/real (and others, like disembodied/corporeal, mind/body) &#8211; are absolutes when it comes to the Internet. It is the idea that everything that happens online is fake &#8211; and that, somehow, we possess the ability to switch ourselves on and off &#8211; connecting and disconnecting from &#8216;the matrix&#8217; (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neuromancer" target="_blank">hi, 1980s cyberpun</a><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neuromancer" target="_blank">k fantasies</a>).</p>
<p><i>Digital dualism</i> is the attitude that regards the Internet as some kind of digital other-space, and the interactions and relationships that are enacted within that space as entirely fictional.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7183" alt="virtual-reality-8" src="http://erinstark.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/virtual-reality-8.jpg?w=720"   /></p>
<h6 style="text-align:center;"><em>zomg virtual reality. this is how i access the internet. <a href="http://static.ddmcdn.com/gif/virtual-reality-8.jpg" target="_blank">/source/</a></em></h6>
<p>For most of us in the field of Internet research, online space stopped being perceived as a virtual Other a long time ago. For me, it began with the move toward an increasingly social web. Once upon a time (in a land far away), people would go online and construct alternate identities for themselves. They weren&#8217;t necessarily <em>fake, </em>digital representations of the self, but they weren&#8217;t quite the same as the everyday offline self, either. It was not always the norm to use our real names and post photos of ourselves on publicly accessible profile pages, nor was it the norm to connect online (via social network &#8216;friendships&#8217;) with people we knew offline. It happened, definitely, but not on the scale that we today perceive as standard, thanks to Myspace, Facebook, and the like. Without going in to the details of how Jurgenson&#8217;s post arose (<a href="http://deadspin.com/5976517/manti-teos-dead-girlfriend-the-most-heartbreaking-and-inspirational-story-of-the-college-football-season-is-a-hoax" target="_blank">you can read the full story here</a> &#8211; basically it involves an American college footballer being duped into a relationship with a woman who didn&#8217;t exist, and the media are calling it a &#8220;digital hoax&#8221;), I instead wanted to highlight some of the things that he&#8217;s said that really exemplify how incorrect many attitudes are to the way so-called &#8220;digital&#8221; life works.</p>
<p>For some reason, users &#8211; especially young ones &#8211; are depicted in the mainstream media as possessing a plethora of social ineptitudes as a result of always having their eyes glued to their smartphones. Their only real skills, some would have you believe, are taking selfies and demonstrating nonchalance toward anything that happens in the &#8216;real&#8217; world. They&#8217;re portrayed as so disconnected that they&#8217;re more zombie than human, lost causes aimlessly wandering the digital (ahem) streets of cyberspace. Probably on the Information Superhighway. When they&#8217;re not too busy surfing the net. And sexting.</p>
<p>Jurgenson writes:</p>
<blockquote><p>The point isn’t that there exists a digital world that’s fake; it’s that there isn’t a digital world. The hoax is the invention of some cyber reality we’ve traded the offline for, where interaction is fake. The hoax is this conceptual error that Egan and other digital dualists rely on to make many of their arguments.</p>
<p>These writers get mileage out of calling this a “digital deception” and declare the Internet “fake” in order to have a convenient answer (“technology!”) for real, messy, complicated, human problems like celebrity, romance, and deception. Blaming technology also provides a simpler solution: “less technology!” And as I discuss in my <a href="http://thenewinquiry.com/essays/the-irl-fetish/">IRL Fetish</a> essay, by constructing the digital as some “other” place, and then judging that as “virtual” and less real, one can then value their own <em>non-use</em> as more human and deep.</p></blockquote>
<p>I couldn&#8217;t agree with this any more. For some reason that makes absolutely no sense to me, but complete sense to most, the Internet and its goings-on are still a convenient scapegoat for real, complicated human problems. Young person has a naked photograph plastered all over the web? Blame Facebook! Celebrity attacked by the public via social media? Blame Twitter! Parents don&#8217;t know how to control their children? Blame <a href="http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=intarweb" target="_blank">teh intarwebz</a>!</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s a thought. Perhaps the reason that the media and, it must be said, many parents, are still demonising the Internet is because they&#8217;re from a generation that didn&#8217;t grow up online, and this technology is still relatively new to them. As such, they lack the skills to adequately interpret the place that it has in society. It&#8217;s like that idea that guns don&#8217;t kill people, people kill people. Likewise, the Internet (which is not actually a sentient, autonomous being, incidentally) doesn&#8217;t create hoaxes &#8211; people do. People attack and hurt and deceive each other, and it&#8217;s high time that we (the collective We &#8211; society) realised that. The Internet is merely a communications tool. It&#8217;s the same as a telephone or a CB radio or a letter, for god&#8217;s sake. Without people, these are <em>inert objects and systems</em>.</p>
<p><a href="http://erinstark.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/map-of-the-internet.png"><img class="wp-image-7184 aligncenter" alt="Map-of-the-Internet" src="http://erinstark.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/map-of-the-internet.png?w=500&#038;h=500" width="500" height="500" /></a></p>
<h6 style="text-align:center;"><em>the internet: not as terrifying as you think. <a href="http://www.opte.org/" target="_blank">//source//</a></em></h6>
<p>I&#8217;d really recommend that you read Nathan Jurgenson&#8217;s post. He makes a lot of sense. More than me. My prediction is that to the society-leading adults of the future, this malarkey over cyber-hoaxes and general digital fear mongering will seem completely ridiculous. They&#8217;ll have grown up online, they&#8217;ll have already made the mistakes that we&#8217;re accusing them of now making, and they&#8217;ll have come up with ways to deal with it &#8211; from different parenting skills, to formal education, to the relaxation of hype in the media. More to the point, online behaviour will just be <em>common sense</em> because it will be <em>normal</em>. Nobody who grew up with a telephone fears the unseen dangers that lurk on the other side of the line, and the media has, for the most past, stopped with the moral panic about television.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s called <em>technology</em>, everyone. It changes, and sometimes it&#8217;s a bit scary, but it&#8217;s not always a bad thing.</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://erinstark.net/category/academia/'>academia</a>, <a href='http://erinstark.net/category/geekology-101/'>geekology 101</a> Tagged: <a href='http://erinstark.net/tag/cyber/'>cyber</a>, <a href='http://erinstark.net/tag/dichotomies/'>dichotomies</a>, <a href='http://erinstark.net/tag/digital-dualism/'>digital dualism</a>, <a href='http://erinstark.net/tag/hoax/'>hoax</a>, <a href='http://erinstark.net/tag/internet/'>internet</a>, <a href='http://erinstark.net/tag/manti-teo/'>Manti Te'o</a>, <a href='http://erinstark.net/tag/nathan-jurgenson/'>Nathan Jurgenson</a>, <a href='http://erinstark.net/tag/onlineoffline/'>online/offline</a>, <a href='http://erinstark.net/tag/realvirtual/'>real/virtual</a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=7182&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://erinstark.net/2013/01/19/on-digital-dualism-or-why-in-2013-are-people-still-fearmongering-the-internet/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>18</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/6785c36f6139bdf960df4dd40cdd0953?s=96&#38;d=monsterid&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">erin</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://erinstark.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/virtual-reality-8.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">virtual-reality-8</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://erinstark.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/map-of-the-internet.png?w=625" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Map-of-the-Internet</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Majorly Blinkered Mainstream Media Does Mali</title>
		<link>http://zoetropic.wordpress.com/2013/01/18/majorly-blinkered-mainstream-media-does-mali/</link>
		<comments>http://zoetropic.wordpress.com/2013/01/18/majorly-blinkered-mainstream-media-does-mali/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2013 14:12:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>zoetropic</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cultural Comparisons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal Essays]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Algeria]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mali]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Military]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[resources]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[terrorism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thoughts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[war]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://zoetropic.wordpress.com/?p=2930</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Should I still be surprised when journalism doesn&#8217;t do the job it&#8217;s supposedly meant to do? When articles in the most important newspapers in the world are riddled with massive blind spots, coming off as either shockingly naive or else blatantly misleading to anyone who has done a bit of further reading?  Should I still [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2930&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Should I still be surprised when journalism doesn&#8217;t do the job it&#8217;s supposedly meant to do? When articles in the most important newspapers in the world are riddled with massive blind spots, coming off as either shockingly naive or else blatantly misleading to anyone who has done a bit of further reading?  Should I still be unnerved when headline stories take powerful governments at their word, digging no deeper, just regurgitating what has been said at press conferences?</p>
<p>I know I shouldn&#8217;t be surprised, it&#8217;s nothing new.  These are symptoms of the disease that has afflicted American mainstream journalism for a very long time (has it always been this way?). No I can&#8217;t say it surprises me exactly &#8211; but it still disappoints, saddens, frustrates, and angers me.  I am angry at editors with an agenda, at journalists without enough backbone or imagination and at readers/viewers for being spoon-fed crap and not demanding better.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">***</p>
<p>The New York Times is one of the most respected newspapers in the world &#8211; and I DO love some of their op-ed columnists (<span style="text-decoration:underline;"><span style="color:#99ccff;text-decoration:underline;"><a title="Nicholas Kristof New York Times" href="http://topics.nytimes.com/top/opinion/editorialsandoped/oped/columnists/nicholasdkristof/index.html" target="_blank"><span style="color:#99ccff;text-decoration:underline;">Nicholas Kristof!</span></a> </span></span>Yes I love you!). Occasionally they have talented stringers that break great stories, and have spots of quality investigative journalism or features.</p>
<p>But.</p>
<p>But….</p>
<p>The New York Times (like most mainstream news coming out of the US) is frighteningly America-centric; a lot of their justifications, arguments and explanations look tremendously sloppy for the lack of global or marginal perspective.  I have long found that when it comes to reporting on global breaking news, they tend to stick to the obvious, conventional American wisdom about geopolitics; they rarely challenge the typical government storyline about why the US does the things it does, or question the dynamics of power and how politics shapes these narratives about other peoples and places.</p>
<p>A tremendous example of the NYT&#8217;s frequently lazy or one could even say misleading approach to complicated issues is the latest reporting on Mali.</p>
<p>I read the NYT front page articles on Thursday about <span style="text-decoration:underline;"><span style="color:#99ccff;text-decoration:underline;"><a title="New York Times:  France Sends Reinforcements to Confront Islamist Forces in Mali" href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/01/18/world/africa/france-mali-intervention.html" target="_blank"><span style="color:#99ccff;text-decoration:underline;">French military intervention in Mali</span></a></span></span>, <span style="color:#99ccff;"><a title="U.S. Sees Hazy Threat From Mali Militants" href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/01/17/world/africa/us-sees-hazy-threat-from-mali-militants.html?_r=0" target="_blank"><span style="text-decoration:underline;color:#99ccff;"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">US expert perspective on Mali threat</span></span></a></span>, and <a title="Militants Seize Americans and Other Hostages in Algeria" href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/01/17/world/africa/islamists-seize-foreign-hostages-at-algeria-gas-field.html?hp" target="_blank"><span style="color:#99ccff;">t</span><span style="text-decoration:underline;"><span style="color:#99ccff;text-decoration:underline;">he related attack in Algeria</span></span></a>, and I was quite struck by the NYT angle on these stories.</p>
<p>The thing I noticed most was how single-focused all the articles were on Islamists and terrorism, as though that was explanation enough for everything that was happening &#8211; French intervention, US promises to help the French, the many years of US covert involvement in the region, and the tragic hostage situation in Algeria. They tell us there are dangerous militants in Mali threatening to take over so OF COURSE France has sent in its military, and of COURSE the US will help!  What other explanation is necessary?</p>
<p>Wait what?  Why? Slow down&#8230;what&#8217;s happening?  In particularly why were the French so quick to jump into a very volatile situation?  Do they have the military and the money to spare or something?  Then why not Syria? What exactly is going on here? Why aren&#8217;t you asking why?</p>
<p>I&#8217;m not saying you should have all the answers &#8211; but you are journalists&#8230;why aren&#8217;t you asking why?</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">***</p>
<p>If I knew absolutely nothing about what has been happening in Mali and I were to read yesterday&#8217;s headlining NYT piece on the French fighting there, I would understand the following: <strong> </strong> 1) The French are now at war in Mali 2) The President of France, François Hollande, is determined to kill terrorists, 3) The International Criminal Court is very upset about human rights abuses in Mali.  From the information supplied by the article, the conclusion I would probably have to come to is that France, righteous country that it is, is at war in Mali against terrorists, to protect Europe from attacks and innocent Malians from human rights abuses.</p>
<p>Would I be close enough to understanding the situation, as close as one could expect from a simple news piece?  Is the NYT pointing me in the right direction, helping me to understand?  Or are they leading me to false or at least only fractionally true conclusions?</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">***</p>
<p>The NYT left out some rather important pieces of information that might give a slightly more nuanced context to the situation. For example, neither France&#8217;s relationship to Mali historically (Mali having been a French colony not all that long ago) nor its relationship economically (France is quite dependent on the region for a lot of important natural resources) were alluded to once.</p>
<p>Mali has vast natural resources, and many companies from many countries really want Mali to be safe and accessible.  Mali is a traditional mining country, and Africa&#8217;s 3rd largest producer of gold, with seven important gold mines in operation, and exploration for more ongoing.  Mali has potential for diamond exploration as well as garnet.  Mali has  calcareous rock deposits, and iron ore, bauxite, copper, marble, gypsum, kaolin, phosphate, lead, zinc, lithium, bitumen schist, lignite, rock salt, and diatomite reserves, among other things.</p>
<p>And Mali also quite possibly has exploitable uranium and oil.  Uranium exploration is currently being carried out by several companies, with clear indications of deposits.  The Taoudeni Basin in Northern Mali, extending far into Mauritania, and somewhat into Algeria, is thought to be the location of significant reserves of oil.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-1707" title="Mali-TaoudeniBasin" alt="" src="http://www.panafricanistinternational.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/Mali-TaoudeniBasin-300x193.jpg" width="300" height="193" /></p>
<p>While French companies are not necessarily deeply invested in Mali, not enough to justify military involvement per se, the stability of region as a whole is of vital strategic interest to France.  Given that France has 58 nuclear reactors that supply 75% of the country&#8217;s electricity, and also generate enough surplus to earn France EUR 3 billion annually (making them the world&#8217;s top exporter of electricity) the continued well-being of their uranium supplies is of great importance to the French economy and energy security.   France gets more than 1/3 of its uranium from Niger, to Mali&#8217;s east, the world&#8217;s 4th largest producer of uranium.   Niger&#8217;s two main uranium mines are owned and operated by French nuclear giant Areva, Niger&#8217;s biggest investor. If all goes according to plan Areva hopes to boost Niger&#8217;s uranium output to 5,000 tons per year by 2013 or 2014, making it the world&#8217;s second-largest exporter of the nuclear fuel.  If all goes according to plan&#8230;<em><strong><br />
</strong></em></p>
<p>The French oil major Total has prospects not only in Mali, but also in neighboring Mauritania, Algeria, and Cote d&#8217;Ivoire, and nearby Nigeria and Ghana. Stability of the region therefore is crucial to French mineral and energy prospects, and to French energy stability.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">***</p>
<p>Control of resources is an important element of most global military decisions.  To ignore that is to ignore one of the driving forcing of human history.  This is an important part of the picture that somehow the NYT never even ALLUDED to. How could they fail to even MENTION these things in an article about a European power taking military action in Africa?</p>
<p>Well I wanted to give the NYT a fighting chance, the benefit of the doubt &#8211; after all, the situation this week in Mali has been complicated, and constantly evolving.  I thought maybe the NYT&#8217;s coverage failed to mention France&#8217;s complex relationship to the region in TODAY&#8217;S piece, because they were focusing on the details of the actual military operation instead.  Maybe they&#8217;d gone deeper in past articles?</p>
<p>SO &#8211; I read every single NYT article I could find about Mali from the last week (since France began military action there) as well a vast number of articles about Mali from the past year.  All told I read over 30 articles.  I also ran searches on the NYT website for keywords &#8220;France Mali economic&#8221;, &#8220;France Mali gold&#8221;, &#8220;France Mali uranium&#8221;, &#8220;France Mali oil,&#8221; &#8220;France Mali colony,&#8221;  &#8221;France Mali ex-colony,&#8221; etc. to see if I could find some buried articles that might make reference to France&#8217;s vested interests in this particular African nation.</p>
<p>I couldn&#8217;t find any relatively recent articles (from the last year or two) that discuss France&#8217;s economic interests in Mali and bordering countries.  There was almost no mention of Mali as an important producer of gold in any of the articles I read.  There was no mention at all of how the regions uranium might affect the situation (in fact there wasn&#8217;t much mentioning of France&#8217;s interest in uranium during the Niger coup d&#8217;état in 2010 either!).  There was minimal mention of oil.  It was only a handful of mentions that Mali is France&#8217;s ex-colony.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">***</p>
<p>I&#8217;m not saying the NYT has to come out blazing, accusing France of covering up their true motives.   But I also don&#8217;t think the NYT should take the French government&#8217;s motives at face value and refuse to complicate them by adding salient details about France&#8217;s history in this region and France&#8217;s stakes in the resources there.  This information IS relevant and the NYT avoidance of it is negligence at BEST.</p>
<p>Out of all the articles I read the only motives ever given for French military action in Mali were short statements like:  1)&#8221;France, plagued by kidnappings of its citizens&#8230; and fearful of a radical enclave so close to the Mediterranean, has been the most vocal about kicking out the Islamists. 2)&#8221;Mr. Hollande said that the capture of the northern half of the country by Islamic radicals posed a clear and present terrorist danger to <a href="http://topics.nytimes.com/top/news/international/countriesandterritories/france/index.html?inline=nyt-geo">France</a> and to Europe.&#8221; 3) &#8220;Responding to an urgent plea for help from the Malian government, French troops carried out airstrikes against Islamist fighters, blunting an advance by hundreds of heavily armed extremists.&#8221;  4) &#8220;President <a href="http://topics.nytimes.com/top/reference/timestopics/people/h/francois_hollande/index.html?8qa">François Hollande</a> of France has been blunt about his overall intentions, however. “What do we plan to do with the terrorists?” he said on Tuesday. “Destroy them. Capture them, if possible, and make sure that they can do no harm in the future.”</p>
<p>Out of DOZENS of articles about Mali, this is the closest the NYT got to explaining why the French would RASHLY begin military engagement there.  It&#8217;s so upsetting to have a &#8220;trusted&#8221; news source go for the most simplistic reasoning for all actions by all players when it comes to geopolitics.  Their explanations seem lazy and frighteningly specious. To try to convince readers that this is all about battling terrorism is irresponsible and manipulative, not to mention plays right into the government&#8217;s line, their catchall reason since 9/11 for letting them do whatever they want abroad and increasingly at home:  &#8221;Terrorism: Global Enemy #1.&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">***</p>
<p>If France is in Mali just to fight extremism, why isn&#8217;t France in every other country threatened by jihadists? Most people that understand a little bit about governments, military, and economics should realize IT&#8217;S NOT THAT SIMPLE!  So why do prestigious papers like the New York Times keep stuffing terrorism down our throats as the obvious reason for everything?</p>
<p>To be fair &#8211; I did a much quicker skim of a selection of articles from the Washington Post, the LA Times and other important newspapers, as well as articles written by television news sources, and the results were the same.  US mass market media nearly across the board is discussing Mali from the sole vantage of TERRORISM.  ISLAMIST THREAT. JIHADISTS. Etc.  (My other favorite explanation was that France was getting involved in order to protect its 5 or 6,000 citizens that live in Mali.  Right.  Protect them&#8230;by invading the country they live in, making them an immediate target by making their nationality an even more obvious count against them. Protect them&#8230;right&#8230;) This is an epidemic of specious reasoning.</p>
<p>I understand why the government would be crying terrorism left and right &#8211; it&#8217;s a very powerful idea, even more effective in a sense than demonizing communism was back in the day &#8211; because terrorists could be anywhere, and it is almost impossible for US citizens to be able to clearly see whether or not the target justifies the fuss.  Threat of terrorists is this wonderful blank card that can be played at almost any time and in any place justifying military involvement there.  The government doesn&#8217;t want to give that up.  I get that.</p>
<p>But why is the media involved in emphasizing terrorism?</p>
<p>It&#8217;s interesting to note that this is not necessarily a global media trend.  I haven&#8217;t thoroughly checked out other english-speaking countries&#8217; news outlets &#8211; but I can tell you that the French press has no problems asking whether the government&#8217;s actions have more to do with economics than terrorism or humanitarianism.</p>
<p>For example French conservative newspaper Le Figaro openly discusses France&#8217;s economic interests in Mali and the surrounding region in this piece, immediately broaching the subject of oil and uranium:<span style="text-decoration:underline;"><span style="color:#99ccff;text-decoration:underline;"> </span><span style="color:#99ccff;text-decoration:underline;"><span style="color:#99ccff;text-decoration:underline;"><a href="http://www.lefigaro.fr/conjoncture/2013/01/17/20002-20130117ARTFIG00381-les-interets-economiques-limites-de-la-france-au-mali.php"><span style="color:#99ccff;text-decoration:underline;">Les intérêts économiques limités de la France au Mali</span></a></span></span><span style="color:#99ccff;text-decoration:underline;"><span style="color:#99ccff;text-decoration:underline;">.</span></span></span>  This article claims the interests in Mali itself aren&#8217;t large, but the government&#8217;s interest in maintaining stability in the region as a whole is obvious.</p>
<p>Or French national TV channel TF1 on the same subject:<span style="color:#99ccff;"><span style="text-decoration:underline;"><strong> </strong></span></span><span style="text-decoration:underline;"><span style="color:#99ccff;"><a href="http://lci.tf1.fr/monde/afrique/mali-la-france-a-t-elle-un-interet-economique-a-intervenir-7775967.html" target="_blank"><span style="color:#99ccff;text-decoration:underline;">Mali : la France a-t-elle un intérêt économique à intervenir ?</span></a></span></span> <span style="color:#99ccff;"><span style="color:#99ccff;text-decoration:underline;"> </span></span>which reached similar conclusions &#8211; Mali itself may not be a key economic partner, but the destabilization of Mali would affect the entire region, which would be problematic strategically for France.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">***</p>
<p>I searched only for seconds before finding these kinds of analyses in mainstream French news &#8211; because it turns out its not that hard OR that controversial in France for journalists to dig a little bit under the surface.  These are obvious questions to ask, and the French media is doing its job by asking them.</p>
<p>So what&#8217;s up with American media?  Do they believe their jingoism themselves?  Are they that naive, or does terrorism sell better than more complex reasoning?  Is the US in such an information bubble that the media as a whole completely believes in the narrative of &#8220;hunting terrorists&#8221; as a reason for all military involvement everywhere?  Have they been selling terrorism for so long that they no longer even ask themselves if it&#8217;s true?    Or do they have a specific an agenda?  Are they pawns or are they players?</p>
<p>Why have they stopped asking why?</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">***</p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><em>If you liked this post you might also enjoy the following by<strong> The Annotated Zoetrope</strong>:</em></p>
<ul>
<li>
<h2><span style="color:#99ccff;"><a title="The Indignant Indigent Youth of Spain" href="http://zoetropic.wordpress.com/2012/08/23/the-indignant-indigent-youth-of-spain/" target="_blank"><span style="color:#99ccff;">The Indignant Indigent Youth of Spain</span></a></span></h2>
</li>
<li>
<h2><a title="Caracas: Rotten Town" href="http://zoetropic.wordpress.com/2012/03/02/caracas-rotten-town/" target="_blank"><span style="color:#ccffff;"><span style="color:#ccffff;">Caracas: Rotten Town</span></span></a></h2>
</li>
<li>
<h2><a title="Bill Clinton and a Dirty Beach: Nostalgia and Denial" href="http://zoetropic.wordpress.com/2012/09/18/bill-clinton-and-a-dirty-beach-nostalgia-and-denial/" target="_blank"><span style="color:#99ccff;"><span style="color:#99ccff;">Bill Clinton and a Dirty Beach: Nostalgia and Denial</span></span></a></h2>
</li>
<li>
<h2><a title="Ten Rupees" href="http://zoetropic.wordpress.com/2012/03/28/ten-rupees/" target="_blank"><span style="color:#ccffff;">Ten Rupees</span></a></h2>
</li>
<li>
<h2><span style="color:#99ccff;"><a title="Protest:  Egypt, France, Venezuela" href="http://zoetropic.wordpress.com/2011/03/01/protest-egypt-france-venezuela/" target="_blank"><span style="color:#99ccff;">Protest: Egypt, France, Venezuela</span></a></span></h2>
</li>
<li>
<h2><span style="color:#ccffff;"><a title="The Parable of France and the Mediocre Pants" href="http://zoetropic.wordpress.com/2011/01/26/the-parable-of-france-and-the-mediocre-pants/" target="_blank"><span style="color:#ccffff;">The Parable of France and the Mediocre Pants</span></a></span></h2>
</li>
<li>
<h2><span style="color:#99ccff;"><a title="Warning: Be Afraid – London Ad Rhetoric (Part II)" href="http://zoetropic.wordpress.com/2010/11/05/warning-be-afraid-london-ad-rhetoric-part-ii/" target="_blank"><span style="color:#99ccff;">Warning: Be Afraid – London Ad Rhetoric (Part II)</span></a></span></h2>
</li>
<li>
<h2><span style="color:#ccffff;"><a title="The Burial of Life as a Young Girl" href="http://zoetropic.wordpress.com/2011/04/14/the-burial-of-life-as-a-young-girl/" target="_blank"><span style="color:#ccffff;">The Burial of Life as a Young Girl</span></a></span></h2>
</li>
</ul>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2930/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2930/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2930&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://zoetropic.wordpress.com/2013/01/18/majorly-blinkered-mainstream-media-does-mali/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/568153117dd35a2012e060028e6b5c84?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">zoetropic</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://www.panafricanistinternational.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/Mali-TaoudeniBasin-300x193.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mali-TaoudeniBasin</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What Are Your Core Beliefs?</title>
		<link>http://workitwell.wordpress.com/2013/01/18/what-are-your-core-beliefs/</link>
		<comments>http://workitwell.wordpress.com/2013/01/18/what-are-your-core-beliefs/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2013 01:34:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lynda at Work</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Consciousness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yoga]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[baby boomers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beliefs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[deprogram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[environment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[examined life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Generation Y]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[materialism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[values]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yoga]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://workitwell.wordpress.com/?p=444</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A decade ago I moved from northern Virginia to a small town in Colorado with just a carful of belongings.   I left behind a marriage and a job and joined some good friends who were living what I saw as a conscious and sane life.  A part of me was looking for time in the [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=444&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://workitwell.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/img_0042.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-331" alt="IMG_0042" src="http://workitwell.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/img_0042.jpg?w=112&#038;h=150" width="112" height="150" /></a>A decade ago I moved from northern Virginia to a small town in Colorado with just a carful of belongings.   I left behind a marriage and a job and joined some good friends who were living what I saw as a conscious and sane life.  A part of me was looking for time in the mountains to deprogram and start afresh.  With more space and quiet, in a gentler town, perhaps I could get down to some wiser ways.</p>
<p>Did that happen?  In many ways it did.  The East is so dense with people, buildings, and culture that a girl sometimes can’t separate her own values out from those of the society.  In the cacophony, the quick pace, the getting and spending, one doesn’t even have time to think.  The attitudes of society soak in through her pores and affect her thoughts and behavior.</p>
<p>When I settled in Colorado, I found a job with odd hours, and I hiked up many a mountain.  I sought out yoga classes, then a yoga teacher training.  Slowly I began to unwind my physical patterns, my muscular tension and my defenses against the world.  In a hakomi, or body-centered psychotherapy, training I sat with peers in mindfulness and observed my core beliefs emerge.  I found an outstanding yoga teacher whose classes took me on an ecstatic journey, and after all this, I could feel my feet on the ground, my animal body engaged in the world, my heart open so that I engaged more easily with others.  I hoped work and love would flow more easily.  And they did, especially love.  Work?  I’m still progressing on that front.</p>
<p>Presently I find myself wondering how we in this country developed the mindset we have and the belief that we must work excessively and purchase new gadgets regularly.  I wonder how our environment, healthcare system, and political system all became so toxic or dysfunctional.  There is an armoring and network of habits at the national level just as there is at the individual level, of course.  We buffer ourselves against remembering another set of values by escaping into entertainment and the pursuit of status, or things.  I see a clinging to old beliefs and habits.  I see a belief in the dominance of a market economy above all.</p>
<p>I turned to history to understand more, and I read about the founding fathers and their ideas, about Christian fundamentalism, about the decline of intellectualism, about our perspectives on the body and about the evolution of psychology.  How, I wondered, did we become so materialistic?  How did a business mentality so thoroughly permeate medicine and education?  How did we get to this place where we must work such long hours and commute such long distances to have enough money for expenses?</p>
<p>At the same time I wonder what might help us to loosen hold of those beliefs and reconsider.  Let some new ideas in.  Would it be a change in education?  More yoga and less time on treadmills?  More time in nature?  That’s my prescription!  But each of us thinks we know what would be best, and none of us knows the whole truth about our troubles and what to do about them.</p>
<p>The good news is that younger people coming up with new ways of doing things.  Whether it is because they are facing less abundance than their parents or just seeing what the world is now, they are already trying something different.  Generation Y, for example, is said to want a shorter work day and more time for family, more flexibility in their jobs, and meaningful work or lifestyle that includes work.  They want to support their communities.</p>
<p>I see this trend evolving in this small town I landed in.   Many young people are starting small businesses, collaborating to build a counter economy.  There are people making a living as web designers, social media managers, artists, and healers.  They find ways to network, or share office space, to promote one another’s businesses.  When our society can sustain these folks well, or if they can sustain themselves, we will all be healthier.</p>
<p>There is so much that is rich in life that becomes buried in business and striving.  I am a baby boomer with the values of Generation Y.  A yoga teacher in need of a job, a job in which I work with others for something I believe in and yet also have time for family and creative work.  Time to be outside.  Time for prayer and mediation and the study of history.  We need to really think about what we believe, what we feel in response to the world around us, and where we need to go.  Because if we don’t change course, we will pay a big price.</p>
<p>Can we not examine the bundles of assumptions and beliefs wrapped around us so tightly that we can’t notice?  It is time, right now, to slow down, to look both inside and out and consciously choose the values we will live.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/444/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/444/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=444&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://workitwell.wordpress.com/2013/01/18/what-are-your-core-beliefs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>24</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c41bf978b198ba925142793532049d78?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">yogalynda</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://workitwell.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/img_0042.jpg?w=112" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0042</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>25 Things I Wish I Knew Before Moving to San Francisco</title>
		<link>http://jasonevanish.com/2013/01/17/25-things-i-wish-i-knew-before-moving-to-san-francisco/</link>
		<comments>http://jasonevanish.com/2013/01/17/25-things-i-wish-i-knew-before-moving-to-san-francisco/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2013 14:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jason Evanish</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Living]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lifestyles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[san francisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stereotypes]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://jasonevanish.com/?p=1623</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I moved to San Francisco 9 months ago from the East Coast bastion of Boston. Despite having experience living in a major US city, I found quite a few surprises coming here.  Some have been great, while others not so much. If you&#8217;re planning the move here, I hope this will help you know better [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1623&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://jasonevanish.com/2013/01/17/25-things-i-wish-i-knew-before-moving-to-san-francisco/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>548</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/22dace2d1674f486d6edb5d18720521c?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F2.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jasonevanish</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://i.huffpost.com/gen/339949/BIKES-OF-SAN-FRANCISCO.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://sf.curbed.com/uploads/5-14-12uuugggghhhh.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://jasonevanish.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/screen-shot-2013-01-07-at-10-40-39-pm.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Don&#039;t go inside the dotted lines</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://www.boozenews.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/06/a14.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://jasonevanish.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/screen-shot-2013-01-09-at-1-24-12-am.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">How the Fog rolls in SF</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://24.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_mbcph9JN7R1rgmpcfo1_500.png" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://cdn.macrumors.com/article-new/2011/05/foldersIMG_0975ios4-5.png" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://ww3.hdnux.com/photos/10/00/02/2097314/5/628x471.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Month Later, Still No Answers</title>
		<link>http://someoldguy.wordpress.com/2013/01/17/a-month-later-still-no-answers/</link>
		<comments>http://someoldguy.wordpress.com/2013/01/17/a-month-later-still-no-answers/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2013 02:58:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Phil</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://someoldguy.wordpress.com/?p=2454</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It is too much for the rational mind to acknowledge, to comprehend, to accept. We cry, “This could not have happened!” But it did happen. Then, “How did it happen?” We hear some few details of how, and turn away in horror from the rest. Next, “Why did it happen?” For that, answers abound, few [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2454&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://someoldguy.wordpress.com/2013/01/17/a-month-later-still-no-answers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>15</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/ba92c617c968eefd05b9822145f22cdc?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=R" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">philsheehan</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>That&#8217;s &#8216;Amour&#8217;</title>
		<link>http://thepartycrashers.wordpress.com/2013/01/17/thats-amour/</link>
		<comments>http://thepartycrashers.wordpress.com/2013/01/17/thats-amour/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2013 20:45:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>D. Seliber</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Michael Haneke]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thepartycrashers.wordpress.com/?p=1098</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In this month’s 60 Minutes/Vanity Fair poll, all the questions were about love. While most of the queries were boring and predicable—“Do you believe in love at first sight?” “How important is good sex to a successful relationship?”— there was one consideration that caught my eye, and is worth pondering at greater length:  “Which marriage [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1098&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:justify;">In this month’s <i>60 Minutes/Vanity Fair</i> <a href="http://www.vanityfair.com/magazine/2013/02/60-minutes-poll-love-relationships#slide=1">poll</a>, all the questions were about love.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">While most of the queries were boring and predicable—“Do you believe in love at first sight?” “How important is good sex to a successful relationship?”— there was one consideration that caught my eye, and is worth pondering at greater length:  “Which marriage vow is the hardest to keep?”</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Is it “To always be faithful”?  “In sickness and in health”?  “For richer and for poorer”?  Or perhaps, simply, “For better and for worse”?</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">In other words, how might we truly take the measure of one’s love for someone else?  That is, of course, assuming such a thing can be measured at all.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">These impossible questions are the subject of <i>Amour,</i> the amazing new <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amour_%282012_film%29">movie</a> by Michael Haneke, which opens in Boston this weekend.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">What the film is about—indeed, all that the film is about—is that it’s easy enough for two halves of a marriage to declare their love for one another when they’re young, healthy and relatively carefree.  It is the arrival of difficulty, disease and death when the measure of one’s devotion is put to the test.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><i>Amour</i> is the story of Anne and Georges, a long-married couple now in their 80s.  After a lifetime of mutual self-sufficiency, Anne suffers a stroke and requires Georges’s support—moral and physical—in ways neither of them is used to or particularly adept at handling.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">What makes <i>Amour</i> great—nay, what makes it tolerable—is its understanding that true love, in the context of a long marriage, has very little to do with sex or even romance, and everything to do with commitment, sacrifice and accepting that some things are more important than your own happiness.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">In one sequence, we see Georges feeding Anne a glass of water through a straw, which she is no longer able to do herself.  Anne is deeply demoralized by having to go about such a basic task in this manner, and George’s own impatience is evident as well.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Georges’s measure of devotion here is proved not by the pleasure he might derive from assisting his wife, but by the obvious agony.  Scenes of him helping Anne off the toilet, raising her from bed and cutting up her vegetables make a similar point:  He doesn’t particularly enjoy doing any of these things, but his marriage vows demand it.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">The movie contains no musical score, no moments of overt melodrama, no yelling and shouting—no “action,” at least by the standards of conventional cinema.  <i>Amour</i> is largely a series of long, static shots as the characters carry on their lives as best they know how.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">As a movie, <i>Amour</i> would be unbearably tedious were it not so well-acted, well-directed and, well, true.  It is dramatic in the sense that life itself is dramatic.  It works because we understand why Anne and Georges behave as they do—even if we might have acted differently in a comparable situation.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">But then we can’t know such things until they actually happen.  People express love in different ways, and there are certain forms we might not notice or appreciate until after the fact.  In his first <i>Late Late Show</i> monologue following the death of his father, Craig Ferguson very affectingly <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AvBh9AssPj4">recounted</a> the way his father never expressed emotion, but that through four decades of hard work as a postal worker, providing steady support for his wife and kids, “I was never in any doubt that he loved me.”</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">In its way, <i>Amour</i> is a cautionary tale against entering into a marriage lackadaisically, not taking the commitment seriously and not thinking things through.  It is an institution that is not for the fainthearted.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">As America grapples with the changing meaning of marriage in today&#8217;s society, we have come to recognize that for a time marriage was largely about commitment, but that today it is largely about love.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">What <em>Amour</em> suggests above all else is that these two enigmatic concepts are not mutually exclusive.  Those traditional marriage vows, as old as the hills, are not a hindrance to true love, but rather are the means to its fullest expression.  For better and for worse.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1098/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1098/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1098&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thepartycrashers.wordpress.com/2013/01/17/thats-amour/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>20</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f8823232d548578cd1621b3def8fca38?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F0.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">thegypsybiker</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Boys to Men</title>
		<link>http://writingbetweenfriends.com/2013/01/17/boys-to-men/</link>
		<comments>http://writingbetweenfriends.com/2013/01/17/boys-to-men/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2013 21:03:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>maria polonchek</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kids]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[motherhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boys]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[feminism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gender]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[violence]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://writingbetweenfriends.com/?p=1461</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Here is the immediate context in a long-term process: right before Christmas, a school shooting, killing children who were the age of my twin boys, sitting diligently in their classrooms like mine do every day. My quiet tears at the simplest moments in the following weeks, self-censored, because they do not know, don&#8217;t need to know, and [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1461&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://writingbetweenfriends.com/2013/01/17/boys-to-men/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>78</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/720828a7f88472c4411b2560422ec78a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">maria</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://writingbetweenfriends.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/photo.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">photo</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
