<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 21:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>You\&#8217;re Gonna Carry That Weight; Carry That Weight a Long Time</title>
		<link>http://lucysfootball.com/2013/03/23/youre-gonna-carry-that-weight-carry-that-weight-a-long-time/</link>
		<comments>http://lucysfootball.com/2013/03/23/youre-gonna-carry-that-weight-carry-that-weight-a-long-time/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 15:45:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>lucysfootball</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[angry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[I hate people]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[issues]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[famous people]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[childhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kevin Smith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[judgments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fat-shaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thin-shaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[men]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gender]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shame]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fat]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://lucysfootball.com/?p=7842</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I was a skinny kid. Photos of me from back then are all pigtails and smeary glasses and I&#8217;m usually covered in mud. And I&#8217;m sometimes brandishing things like frogs or buckets of mucky water, for whatever reason. I probably had a plan for those buckets. Maybe I was going to put the frog in [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=7842&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I was a skinny kid. Photos of me from back then are all pigtails and smeary glasses and I&#8217;m usually covered in mud. And I&#8217;m sometimes brandishing things like frogs or buckets of mucky water, for whatever reason. I probably had a plan for those buckets. Maybe I was going to put the frog in them. I don&#8217;t know.</p>
<p>Then puberty hit. You can&#8217;t fight science, people. I come from hearty peasant stock on both sides of my family. Dad&#8217;s side are all, in his words, &#8220;built like tops &#8211; big on the top, skinny on the bottom.&#8221; (I attempted to explain to him that&#8217;s not exactly how tops work, and also we don&#8217;t spin very well, but he was all &#8220;WE ARE LIKE TOPS!&#8221; so who am I to argue with him?) and my mom&#8217;s side are all built like the Goddess of Willendorf. Curvy doesn&#8217;t even begin to explain it. Genetics decided I needed a little of both, apparently.</p>
<p><a href="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/goddess.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7847" alt="" src="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/goddess.jpg?w=490"   /></a></p>
<p>Now, Dad had been heavy growing up, and teased about it mercilessly. He lost quite a bit of weight when he married my mother (who was, and remains, thin; she&#8217;s the only one in her family that is.) Dad saw that I was starting to gain weight and immediately feared that I was going to be teased about it at school.</p>
<p>His solution? Constantly watch everything I put in my mouth, tell me how disgusting being fat was, tell me I needed to be working out and/or being active every single minute of every single day, tell me I was never going to find anyone to love me if I was fat, and call me things like &#8220;elephant.&#8221; If I got upset about this, he was genuinely confused. &#8220;I just want you to be happy,&#8221; he&#8217;d say. &#8220;I just want you to be pretty and thin.&#8221;</p>
<p>Now, I don&#8217;t know what size you&#8217;re imagining me in high school, but if I remember correctly, I was about a size twelve. A twelve. I was probably around&#8230;oh, I don&#8217;t know. 140 pounds, maybe? 150? Just about the thinnest I&#8217;ve ever been in my adulthood, anyway. I certainly wasn&#8217;t fat. And I&#8217;m fairly tall. 5&#8217;8.</p>
<p>I WAS COMPLETELY NORMAL.</p>
<p>However, years and years of being told, by the person you love and admire most in the whole world, that you are ugly, fat and worthless, take their toll. My self-esteem, never overly good to begin with, wasn&#8217;t getting much better.</p>
<p><a href="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/fatshaming.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-7848" alt="" src="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/fatshaming.jpg?w=300&#038;h=139" width="300" height="139" /></a></p>
<p>Senior year, I was tired of being so ugly and fat (although I was neither &#8211; I look at photos of myself from that time and think &#8220;GOOD GRIEF, WHY DIDN&#8221;T YOU REALIZE HOW GORGEOUS YOU WERE?!?!&#8221;) and went on a crash diet. This diet was basically a bowl of cereal at breakfast and a can of Chinese vegetables at dinner. Sometimes some chicken. No lunch. This was what I ate every day for about 8 months. I worked out for hours at a time daily. I lost about fifty pounds. I could see my hipbones and my ribs and my cheekbones. My collarbones were so prominent I would sometimes accidentally bump them and leave bruises.</p>
<p>It was the first time my father ever told me I was beautiful. He followed it with &#8220;See? All you had to do was lose weight. I knew you were beautiful underneath that.&#8221;</p>
<p>I was starving. I had headaches constantly. I was tired all the time. But I was THIN. Boys were paying attention to me. One of my teachers told me, &#8220;Don&#8217;t you dare ever gain weight again. Don&#8217;t you DARE&#8221; which at the time I was all &#8220;Aw, nice!&#8221; and now, looking back, I&#8217;m all, &#8220;Um. CREEPSTER!&#8221;</p>
<p>I think you can see where this is going. Can anyone maintain that kind of diet and exercise regimen in the long-term? And not get scurvy? And not go CRAZY? I mean, I couldn&#8217;t eat ANYTHING. I was counting the calories in CORNSTARCH. I&#8217;m not even kidding you about this. This is not a way to live a life.</p>
<p>I gained the weight back over about a year. I felt terrible shame. I&#8217;d let everyone down. I was disgusting. I was ugly and fat again. I had no self-esteem; I didn&#8217;t like to go out in public, I didn&#8217;t like to go out with my friends, I didn&#8217;t date because who would have me? I drank a lot, though. Liquid courage, right? Mmm-hmm. Works every time, except when you start needing it for everything, ever. Like getting out of bed in the morning, or to get to sleep at night. Or for everything in between.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve fluctuated in weight ever since. Sometimes I&#8217;m heavier; sometimes I&#8217;m lighter. And here&#8217;s the thing; as I age, it matters less to me. I still don&#8217;t love what I see in the mirror every day; I still see photos of myself and think, &#8220;Good grief, that&#8217;s an unflattering photo.&#8221; I still have residual shame. I still think &#8220;If only I was thinner, life would be easier, in a million different ways.&#8221; But it&#8217;s not a daily thing. It&#8217;s not even all that often anymore.</p>
<p><a href="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/radicalidea.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7849" alt="" src="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/radicalidea.jpg?w=490"   /></a></p>
<p>And before you start to hate him, Dad understands, and has repeatedly apologized, for what he did when I was younger. I often think most of parenting is a fly-by-the-seat-of-your-pants affair. He really, truly thought he was doing the right thing. He thought he was stopping me from the ridicule he&#8217;d experienced as a teen. He didn&#8217;t realize &#8211; and did anyone, back then? &#8211; the long-standing effect that kind of treatment would have on my psyche. I&#8217;ve forgiven him. He doesn&#8217;t say a word now. And he&#8217;s said, without prompting, many times since, that I&#8217;m beautiful &#8211; no matter what size I am. He loves his daughter.</p>
<p>We live in a culture where it is not allowed (well, it still happens, but it&#8217;s not appropriate) to make racial jokes, or jokes about someone&#8217;s sexuality, or mental illness. But we&#8217;re still allowed to make fat jokes. Because fat jokes are funny. Fat PEOPLE are funny, right? Because, well, we CHOSE this. We chose this because we eat ALL the Twinkies and chips and cake and pie and sit around all day doing nothing. We chose this, and because we are fat, we are lazy and we also smell. Of course we do! And sometimes we fall. Ha ha! How funny!</p>
<p><a href="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/fathatebingo.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-7850" alt="" src="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/fathatebingo.jpg?w=210&#038;h=300" width="210" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>So the best thing to do is make fun of us. To shame us. Because, <a href="http://www.inquisitr.com/493779/fat-shaming-may-prevent-obesity-prominent-bioethicist-says/">as this VERY scientific study proves</a>, it&#8217;s the only way to make us get off our lazy asses and get thin. Thin and therefore healthy. Oh, because, I don&#8217;t know if you&#8217;re aware &#8211; if you&#8217;re fat, you&#8217;re immediately unhealthy. There&#8217;s no such thing as a healthy fat person. We&#8217;re all one HoHo away from our first (or second, or third, or last) coronary. So the thing to do is shame us. According to this &#8220;prominent bioethicist&#8221; (I don&#8217;t see &#8220;ethics&#8221; coming into this at all) what you should say to any fat people you know, I mean, if you care about them at all, is “If you are overweight or obese, are you pleased with the way that you look?” Because of COURSE they&#8217;re not! And they just didn&#8217;t realize it until you shamed them! Oh, what a favor you are doing for them. They will thank you on the finish line of their first triathalon! They will shout your name from the top of Kilimanjaro!</p>
<p>Or they might tell you to shut your nosy piehole. Because I&#8217;m going to tell you something right now, and if you take anything away from this, I want it to be this.</p>
<p>My body, his body, her body, their bodies &#8211; anyone&#8217;s body but your own &#8211; ARE NONE OF YOUR FUCKING BUSINESS.</p>
<p><a href="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/business.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7851" alt="" src="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/business.jpg?w=490"   /></a></p>
<p>I don&#8217;t care if you&#8217;re fat-shaming them, thin-shaming them (yes, it exists, <a href="http://booksnobbery.wordpress.com/2013/01/10/ladies-can-we-all-just-stop-being-bitches-for-two-seconds/">please read sj&#8217;s amazing post about it, and the comments</a>, and I know from personal experience, as I have a dear loved one who has constantly been picked on about being too thin, which she can help JUST about as much as I can help my body shape, so it&#8217;s real) or ANYTHING shaming-them, or if you say you&#8217;re doing it because you&#8217;re worried about their health, or what, exactly, your impetus for putting your nose in someone else&#8217;s business is. You have no right. None. You have no right to tell them they should lose weight (unless you are their doctor, and even then, sometimes, it gets worrisome, because there are some doctors who prescribe weightloss as an easy out for everything from asthma to a sprained toe because they don&#8217;t treat the patient, they just see a fat person and think, &#8220;I KNOW WHAT&#8217;S WRONG IT IS FATNESS!&#8221;); you have no right to say things about their lifestyle choices, their clothing choices, who they&#8217;re dating, what they&#8217;re eating, how loud they&#8217;re talking, or anything whatsoever. Keep your eyes on your own test, buckaroo. I&#8217;m sure you have something you&#8217;re not proud of. Would you like someone walking up to you and saying, &#8220;Man, that&#8217;s a huge nose you have there. You should get that surgically reduced. You know, for health reasons.&#8221; Or, &#8220;I noticed you have a very small penis, Man I&#8217;m About to Have Sex With. Have you thought about getting that surgically enhanced? You know, for health reasons?&#8221; IT WOULD BE THE SAME THING.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s some Fun With Fat-Shaming. Don&#8217;t even think I didn&#8217;t research the hell out of this.</p>
<p>First, we have Kate Upton. Who is, I think we can all agree, STUNNINGLY GORGEOUS.</p>
<div id="attachment_7843" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 294px"><a href="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/kate.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-7843" alt="She also really likes bikini shots, so it was hard to find a photo of her clothed. Hell, good for her. She is smoking hot." src="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/kate.jpg?w=490"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">She also really likes bikini shots, so it was hard to find a photo of her clothed. Hell, good for her. She is smoking hot.</p></div>
<p>Well! Were you also aware she is &#8220;well-marbled,&#8221; &#8220;thick,&#8221; &#8220;vulgar,&#8221; and &#8211; this one&#8217;s my favorite &#8211; a &#8220;little piggie?&#8221; Or &#8211; well, how about a whole paragraph of hate? Sure!</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">Huge thighs, NO waist, big fat floppy boobs, terrible body definition – she looks like a squishy brick. Is this what American women are “striving” for now? The lazy, lardy look? Have we really gotten so fat in this country that Kate is the best we can aim for? Sorry, but: <em>eww</em>!</p>
<p>YES! She has been called out as too fat to model by a <a href="http://www.skinnygossip.com/kate-upton-is-well-marbled/#more-2233">VERY reputable blog site called Skinny Gossip</a>. Two things I loathe! People who judge others&#8217; bodies and gossip! (Also, she tagged the post with &#8220;fatties&#8221; and &#8220;thunder thighs,&#8221; because, well, why not?)</p>
<p>Guess why she&#8217;s not model-material? BECAUSE SHE&#8217;S NORMAL-HUMAN SIZED. Well, no. She&#8217;s actually quite a bit less than normal human sized, as normal humans are, what, a size 12 now? 14? Something like that? I don&#8217;t think she&#8217;s that size. But she&#8217;s not waif-thin, and apparently, Skinny Gossip thinks that&#8217;s what size you have to be to model clothing.</p>
<p>Psst, Skinny Gossip, MIND YOUR OWN BUSINESS. She&#8217;s stunning. And it can&#8217;t possibly make you feel any better about yourself to call people pigs, can it? Really? Do you sleep well at night knowing you put something like that out there in the world? That kind of hate?</p>
<p>Next: <a href="http://bitchmagazine.org/post/cvs-drugstore-chain-unveils-new-employee-diet-plan-fat-shaming-and-a-600-fine">employees at CVS will now be forced to take a BMI test and a blood-glucose screen to remain on their healthcare plan, or risk a fine</a>. Why?</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">The company’s rationale? Coercing employees to submit to health testing will provide incentive for workers to get—and stay—in shape.</p>
<p>Huh. &#8220;Coercing.&#8221; Forcing, really, because the fine is $600 and they don&#8217;t pay much above minimum to work at CVS. And what happens once you take the test? Do you have to see a counselor about your totally fat fatness? Are you told if you don&#8217;t lose weight, you&#8217;ll be let go? Are your test results posted in the breakroom next to a photo of a bag of Cheetos with a red circle and a line through it? WHO KNOWS.</p>
<p>Or, how about, let&#8217;s fat-shame our children with this new ad campaign? Because there&#8217;s nothing that kids need more than to be shamed. I mean, it&#8217;s worked out so well for me, right?</p>
<p><a href="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/children.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-7844" alt="" src="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/children.jpg?w=300&#038;h=300" width="300" height="300" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://everydayfeminism.com/2013/02/whats-wrong-with-fat-shaming/">Please read the article that accompanies this photo.</a> It&#8217;s kickass. It has excellent examples of fat-shaming. HEARTBREAKING examples. And, sadly, TRUE examples. People think it is ok to walk up to perfect strangers in the grocery store and QUESTION THEIR FOOD CHOICES.</p>
<p>(True story: I had a woman come up to me in the grocery store and tell me she worked for Herbalife and they had an excellent line of diet pills I might like to try. First thought: shame. Second thought: WHO THE FUCK DO YOU THINK YOU ARE. Second thought won out over first thought; I told her I was not at all interested in a pyramid scheme for products that don&#8217;t work in the first place, and I was sorry she felt the need to walk up to strangers and judge their body type, and walked away. She was offering them to the next woman that walked past as I checked out. So apparently my words meant nothing.)</p>
<p>So, anyway. Yes, that&#8217;s an ad campaign for (well, against, I guess) childhood obesity, targeting overweight children. Because they probably aren&#8217;t aware they&#8217;re fat. So let&#8217;s do a whole ad campaign for it. That&#8217;s a good way to help kids with positive self-esteem. Way to go, guys.</p>
<p><a href="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/children1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7852" alt="" src="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/children1.jpg?w=490"   /></a></p>
<p>Of course, there&#8217;s also good old Southwest Airlines, who expect their fat passengers to spring for two seats. And even their not-so-fat passengers. Whoever THEY deem as a little too fat. They SAY it&#8217;s if the passenger can&#8217;t put the armrests down, but <a href="http://www.nydailynews.com/entertainment/gossip/director-kevin-smith-fat-fly-southwest-clerks-writer-director-tweets-rage-airline-article-1.194397">as Kevin Smith found out a few years ago</a>, that&#8217;s not it at all &#8211; it&#8217;s racial profiling, only with your weight. It&#8217;s fat-profiling. He was able to put his armrests down; the passengers on either side of him told the flight attendant they had plenty of room. They still kicked him off the plane. And when he got back on a later flight that they hurriedly put him on once they realized who he was and that he was tweeting millions of people about this practice, they fat-profiled another person, then put her in his row, so she&#8217;d tell him about it, and he&#8217;d know it wasn&#8217;t just him, and feel better.</p>
<div id="attachment_7859" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 210px"><a href="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/smith.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-7859" alt="DEFINITELY taking up way too much room. He should have purchased the WHOLE DAMN PLANE. *eyeroll*" src="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/smith.jpg?w=490"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">DEFINITELY taking up way too much room. He should have purchased the WHOLE DAMN PLANE. *eyeroll*</p></div>
<p>Yes! Because nothing makes us feel better than to be shamed in front of a crowd of people than to do it to someone else. NOTHING. (I read his book<em> Tough Shit</em> recently which went in detail into the incident, and my heart just broke for him. Because no matter what you think of Kevin Smith &#8211; you all know I think he&#8217;s fantastic, but you can hate him if you want, just don&#8217;t tell me about it, ok? &#8211; when that happened, he was just an average guy, being fat-shamed in front of a full airplane of people. Worse, he was a FAMOUS guy being fat-shamed in front of a crowd of people, and if it was an average guy, it might be a laugh or two, but with a famous person, it&#8217;s news, you know? He took control of the news and labeled it &#8220;too fat to fly&#8221; himself &#8211; he&#8217;s very good at self-deprecating &#8211; but it hurt. Of course it did. Because no matter who you are, where you are in the world, being shamed for your body size is not something you can laugh off. It just isn&#8217;t. The shame should be on Southwest Airlines, not the people they&#8217;re profiling.)</p>
<p>Then there&#8217;s this. I can&#8217;t embed a Facebook thread, so sadly, <a href="https://www.facebook.com/everydayfeminism/posts/153150451511589">you will have to click</a>. Here&#8217;s a screenshot, though, because pretty pictures, right?</p>
<p><a href="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/article-about-how.png"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-7845" alt="" src="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/article-about-how.png?w=300&#038;h=145" width="300" height="145" /></a></p>
<p>Now, you have to click to see the comments. The comments are really what makes this. Because this STARTS OUT as normal, then this person shows up who hates fat people. HATES THEM. Only, no no! She doesn&#8217;t HATE them. She has MANY FAT FRIENDS! (Does this sound at all like someone who makes a lot of racist comments, then says, &#8220;What? I&#8217;m not a racist! I have MANY MANY BLACK FRIENDS!&#8221; Yeah, to me, too.) So she starts writing things like &#8220;no, it&#8217;s a known fact that all fat people are unhealthy and many doctors refuse to operate on them because, well, they&#8217;ll just die on the table. Because, well, fat, you know?&#8221;</p>
<p>Don&#8217;t worry. There are some kickass commenters on there. They give her the smackdown. She doesn&#8217;t ever shut up, but they win intelligence. She doesn&#8217;t win anything but idiocy and mouth-flappery.</p>
<p>This is, by the way, called &#8220;concern-trolling.&#8221; It&#8217;s like being a troll, only you&#8217;re pretending it&#8217;s because you CARE. Isn&#8217;t that nice? A whole new way to be a douchecanoe!</p>
<p>Sara, from <a href="http://lamentsandlullabies.wordpress.com/">Laments and Lullabies</a>, wrote an amazing post recently about fat-shaming, which you all should read. Her post, and the terrible comments on that Facebook post up there, were what finally made me realize I needed to write my own post. <a href="http://lamentsandlullabies.wordpress.com/2013/03/12/the-fear-of-fat/">Here&#8217;s her post</a>. You should all a., read, and b., comment. Oh, and c., follow her blog.</p>
<p>There are more. There are so many more. But this is edging into way too many words for a Saturday territory, and also I&#8217;d like to get to bed at some point.</p>
<p>I will leave you with some bullet points. Because, who doesn&#8217;t like bullet points, am I right?</p>
<ul>
<li><span style="line-height:13px;">Other people&#8217;s bodies are none of your business. Keep your words off them. Unless you&#8217;re telling them they&#8217;re beautiful. Everyone likes that shit. Even if they pretend they don&#8217;t.</span></li>
<li>Pretending you&#8217;re &#8220;worried about someone&#8217;s health&#8221; is not an excuse for commenting on someone&#8217;s weight, whether they&#8217;re heavy or thin. Again, see the first bullet point. Even if they&#8217;re naked with you, their size is none of your business. Whose business is it then, Amy? THEIRS. No one&#8217;s but theirs.</li>
<li>Making fat jokes is a., not funny, and b., lazy. There are actual funny things in the world to point out. Like misspellings. Who doesn&#8217;t like a good misplaced apostrophe or missing comma? The answer to that is NO ONE.</li>
<li>To reiterate what we learned in the first bullet point: before making a comment about someone&#8217;s weight, please think the following quietly to yourself: &#8220;What is my least-favorite attribute. Now, would I like someone to loudly mention it and say it is ugly and/or unhealthy for me to have, and publicly shame me about it?&#8221; The answer to that question is always no. ALWAYS.</li>
<li>Also: if you think you are too fat, and everyone&#8217;s judging you, and you&#8217;re ugly, and OMG I CANNOT LEAVE THE HOUSE, guess what. No, seriously, guess. Hardly anyone even notices. The only people that do are assholes. And who cares what assholes think? I hope you don&#8217;t.</li>
<li>Finally: I&#8217;m going to tell you something I&#8217;ve learned in my old age. Ready? Shh, don&#8217;t share this one around, it&#8217;s kind of radical. WE ARE ALL BEAUTIFUL. I know! Every single last one of us. Fat. Thin. Tall. Short. We&#8217;re a lovely bunch of coconuts. Except &#8211; there is one thing that makes you ugly. Guess what that is? Hatefulness. Being hateful. You can&#8217;t be beautiful with hate in your mind, soul, or mouth. So get rid of that, and guess what? You&#8217;re gorgeous again. And everyone will see it. I can see it right now! Whoa, babe, dial that back, you&#8217;re blinding me with it.</li>
</ul>
<p>We&#8217;ve become a culture of shaming. We&#8217;re rape-shaming and we&#8217;re slut-shaming and we&#8217;re thin-shaming and we&#8217;re fat-shaming. It&#8217;s repulsive and this shit&#8217;s gotta stop. Like, immediately.</p>
<p>Stop shaming anyone. Including yourself. You are beautiful. The people around you are beautiful. No one should be shamed for how they look. The next time you look at yourself in the mirror, be amazed at how gorgeous you are. And tell the people around you how beautiful they are. Don&#8217;t allow them to blow it off and say things like, &#8220;Oh, I look like a cow in this top&#8221; or whatever, either. Nope. Not today, buckaroos. Tell them they&#8217;re beautiful AGAIN. Until they actually believe it.</p>
<p>Then, all of that stuff? Do quadruple that for your kids. Make sure your kids enter the world with the strongest self-esteem possible. They&#8217;re going to need it, and you can help them with that.</p>
<p>We might be surrounded by shame, but we can combat that with love. Is that the opposite of shame? Don&#8217;t care. For our purposes it is.</p>
<p>Love you guys. You&#8217;re gorgeous. Every last one of you.</p>
<p><a href="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/beautiful.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7853" alt="" src="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/beautiful.jpg?w=490"   /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/7842/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/7842/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=7842&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://lucysfootball.com/2013/03/23/youre-gonna-carry-that-weight-carry-that-weight-a-long-time/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>95</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/cf9b29af05b1a3a436100c948157b6bc?s=96&#38;d=retro&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lucysfootball</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/goddess.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/fatshaming.jpg?w=300" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/radicalidea.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/fathatebingo.jpg?w=210" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/business.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/kate.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">She also really likes bikini shots, so it was hard to find a photo of her clothed. Hell, good for her. She is smoking hot.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/children.jpg?w=300" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/children1.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/smith.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DEFINITELY taking up way too much room. He should have purchased the WHOLE DAMN PLANE. *eyeroll*</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/article-about-how.png?w=300" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://lucysfootball.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/beautiful.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Love, Loved, Light</title>
		<link>http://thecougarden.wordpress.com/2013/02/24/love-loved-light/</link>
		<comments>http://thecougarden.wordpress.com/2013/02/24/love-loved-light/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2013 19:29:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>denmother</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cougar Musings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Emotion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interpersonal relationship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Relationship]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thecougarden.wordpress.com/?p=932</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It seems all around me long-term relationships, marriages and families are, or have, or continue to blow up.  From posts in the blogging world to my friends and acquaintances and even in my own personal experience, there seems to be so much crap and residual crap floating around.  It has all definitely changed my traditional [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=932&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://thecougarden.wordpress.com/2013/02/24/love-loved-light/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>27</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/9d719b266af098c7c33435b49cb3b7ce?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">denmother2012</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Unleashing &#8220;Django Unchained&#8221;: Epiphanies for White America</title>
		<link>http://peculiarfaith.com/2013/01/31/unleashing-django-unchained-epiphanies-for-white-america/</link>
		<comments>http://peculiarfaith.com/2013/01/31/unleashing-django-unchained-epiphanies-for-white-america/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 18:03:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>The Rev. Dr. Jay</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Current Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Liturgy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Theology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Epiphany]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Incarnation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quentin Tarantino]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Racism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Slavery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[violence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[White Guilt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[white supremacy]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://peculiarfaith.com/?p=670</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[White Guilt won’t solve anything. Neither will White Denial. Trying to figure out where one sits on that spectrum is a distinct privilege for white people, like me. People of color don’t have those moments of luxury, those moments when they get to pause and wonder about all the complexities of a social and political [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=670&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>White Guilt won’t solve anything. Neither will White Denial. Trying to figure out where one sits on that spectrum is a distinct privilege for white people, like me. People of color don’t have those moments of luxury, those moments when they get to pause and wonder about all the complexities of a social and political system designed to favor white people and white communities.</p>
<p>As I sat in a dark theater watching <a href="http://www.latimes.com/entertainment/movies/moviesnow/la-et-mn-quentin-tarantino-django-unchained-20121215,0,436017.story" target="_blank"><i>Django Unchained</i></a> last week I was glad for little light. What I watched belongs in shadows and in dark corners and all those places where human beings rightly cower in the face of horror. Watching that film I felt assaulted by violence, torn by conflicting loyalties, wrenched by poignant moments of tenderness, amused by reversals of fortune, and appalled by the human capacity to act with unspeakable cruelty. Yet none of that compares to what African Americans feel when watching the same film. Of that, at least, I am certain.<a href="http://queerlychristian.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/django.jpg"><img class="alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-672" style="margin:3px;" alt="django" src="http://queerlychristian.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/django.jpg?w=189&#038;h=126" width="189" height="126" /></a></p>
<p>I’m eager to learn from my African American colleagues and friends about their responses to that Quentin Tarantino film. It is of course <a href="http://www.tarantino.info/" target="_blank">quintessentially Tarantino</a> – ridiculously violent, comically absurd, and horribly distasteful. For all its excess, the film prompted me to discern anew how to live as a white person in a society still reeling from the legacy of racial brutality.</p>
<p>I worry and I fret that even half of the violence or even a portion of the denial of human dignity portrayed in that film captures the historical reality of institutional slavery. But that’s White Guilt talking and it’s not helpful. Equally unhelpful is to suppose that all that horror is neatly sequestered in the shrouds of history and has nothing to do with us today. That’s White Denial talking.</p>
<p>If <i>Django</i><a href="http://queerlychristian.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/django2.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-673" style="margin:3px;" alt="django2" src="http://queerlychristian.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/django2.jpg?w=116&#038;h=175" width="116" height="175" /></a><i> Unchained</i> is going to contribute anything more than Oscar-worthy performances all of us will need to unleash its dangerous message. And <i>Django</i> is dangerous in the same way the Christian Gospel is dangerous, and for this reason: flesh matters.</p>
<p>Tarantino would seem to elicit precisely the opposite as we see flesh flayed, beaten, punctured, ripped apart, bleeding, and generally abused in nearly every manner imaginable. Perhaps that’s the wake-up call Christian communities need if we’re going to take our incarnational faith more seriously – to take human flesh more seriously.</p>
<p><a href="http://queerlychristian.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/epiphany_magi2.jpg"><img class="alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-671" style="margin:3px;" alt="epiphany_magi2" src="http://queerlychristian.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/epiphany_magi2.jpg?w=168&#038;h=205" width="168" height="205" /></a>I saw <i>Django</i> in this Christian liturgical season following The Epiphany – the feast of the manifestation of God’s Word made flesh. This season in concert with that film poses some gut-wrenching questions for white Christians like me. What kind of “flesh” do we mean, really? How is my white flesh consistently considered better than other kinds of flesh, not just abstractly or theoretically but concretely, in the communities where I work, worship, and play? What can and what should I do about that?</p>
<p>This liturgical season began with the story of the Magi traveling far from home, asking questions, and offering gifts when they arrived. White people committed to dismantling systemic racism can follow that same pattern by leaving our comfort zones, learning what we need to know by asking uncomfortable questions, and then offering ourselves to the divine mission of respecting and celebrating <i><span style="text-decoration:underline;">all</span></i> and not just some flesh.</p>
<p>Regardless of the cinematic merits of <i>Django Unchained</i>, unleashing its insights in this season following the Epiphany and leading into Lent could provoke some profound conversations and conversions. I like to remember that those words – “conversation” and “conversion” – come from the same linguistic root. Engaging in genuine conversation makes us vulnerable to life-changing insights, exactly what all of us need in a society built on white supremacy. (One of those insights might link the portrayal of violence to the problem of violence, though Tarantino himself <a href="http://www.theatlanticwire.com/entertainment/2013/01/quentin-tarantino-violence-quotes/60900/" target="_blank">rather testily disagrees</a>.)</p>
<p>At the very least <i>Django</i> beckons white people to consider why and how our white flesh still matters more than any other kind – and that would surely be an epiphany worthy of this peculiar season.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/670/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/670/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=670&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://peculiarfaith.com/2013/01/31/unleashing-django-unchained-epiphanies-for-white-america/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/68e85119a90b638953cfcd48e3567f14?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">drjayson</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://queerlychristian.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/django.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">django</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://queerlychristian.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/django2.jpg?w=99" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">django2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://queerlychristian.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/epiphany_magi2.jpg?w=123" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">epiphany_magi2</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Stand Up.</title>
		<link>http://zebragarden.me/2013/03/26/stand-up/</link>
		<comments>http://zebragarden.me/2013/03/26/stand-up/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 19:25:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ashley Austrew</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Daily]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Random thoughts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[activism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[current events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LGBT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marriage equality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[same sex marriage]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://zebragarden.me/?p=271</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Love is love. At least that&#8217;s what everyone keeps saying. You might have seen a lot of these around today: &#160; It&#8217;s a symbol posted by people in an effort to show support for marriage equality as the Supreme Court begins hearings regarding two same-sex marriage laws. Love is love. For the record, I agree. But, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=271&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Love is love. At least that&#8217;s what everyone keeps saying.</p>
<p>You might have seen a lot of these around today:</p>
<p><a href="http://zebragarden.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/10030_10151327284357823_871712261_n.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-272" alt="10030_10151327284357823_871712261_n" src="http://zebragarden.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/10030_10151327284357823_871712261_n.jpg?w=500&#038;h=498" width="500" height="498" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a symbol posted by people in an effort to show support for marriage equality as the Supreme Court begins hearings regarding two same-sex marriage laws.</p>
<p>Love is love.</p>
<p>For the record, I agree. But, I think the marriage equality issue goes deeper than that. It&#8217;s about love, sure, but even more than that, it&#8217;s about our willingness to deny a sense of humanity to anyone we perceive as different, other. We do it to people of different races. We do it to fat people. We do it to gay people. We do it to anyone that threatens our sense of what is normal, what is good.</p>
<p>But what&#8217;s so great about &#8220;normal&#8221;? What&#8217;s so special about it? If our world is really going to hell in a hand basket, as many will tell you it is, is change really to blame? Or is it our inability to accept change, our indifference to the suffering of others, and our unwillingness to adapt that is really leading us astray?</p>
<p>I&#8217;m not normally a participant in anything that requires me to change my Facebook photo because normally it&#8217;s stupid, and normally it is in regards to things for which a Facebook photo cannot make one damn bit of difference. But, I&#8217;m participating in this because support is 90% of the battle. Support might even be 100% of the battle. Silence is what got us here in the first place.</p>
<p>When someone says they do not believe same sex couples have the right to marry, what they are ultimately saying is, &#8220;I believe certain people are less human than I am because of who they love.&#8221; And they feel comfortable saying that because we&#8217;ve created a world where saying things like that is okay. You have a choice whether or not you want to see another person as equal to you.</p>
<p>I don&#8217;t know about you, but I&#8217;m sick of living in that world.</p>
<p>I don&#8217;t want to live in a world where someone gets to decide whether or not I&#8217;m worthy of basic decency, of dignity because of how I look, who I love, how much money I have, what religion I am, what color my skin is. Love is love, but it&#8217;s not about love. It is about so much more than love. It&#8217;s about humanity. I don&#8217;t need to know anything about you&#8211;least of all the gender of the person you&#8217;ve decided to spend your life with&#8211;in order to know that I have respect for the divinely human spirit that dwells within you.</p>
<p>If you have some kind of social media account, please participate. And don&#8217;t be afraid to engage the people who disagree with you. Stand up for people because that&#8217;s all it is. It&#8217;s not about anything more complicated than that.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s just standing up for people. For their right to be seen as people.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/271/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/271/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=271&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://zebragarden.me/2013/03/26/stand-up/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>40</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f20e47c07a4b963e2c5f946ffa07f3cb?s=96&#38;d=retro&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ashaustrew</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://zebragarden.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/10030_10151327284357823_871712261_n.jpg?w=500" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">10030_10151327284357823_871712261_n</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Cambodian Travel Diary</title>
		<link>http://invadercee.wordpress.com/2013/03/10/cambodia-day-1-siem-reap/</link>
		<comments>http://invadercee.wordpress.com/2013/03/10/cambodia-day-1-siem-reap/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2013 04:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>invadercee</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cambodia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cambodia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[siem reap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://invadercee.wordpress.com/?p=487</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Compared to the usual long-haul flights to Europe, a nine-ish hour flight to Cambodia feels like a breeze. Landing at the quaint little Siem Reap airport, I step off the plane and into the blazing Cambodia heat and humidity. Home for the next few days will be the Soria Moria hotel. Clean, functional and the [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=487&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Compared to the usual long-haul flights to Europe, a nine-ish hour flight to Cambodia feels like a breeze. Landing at the quaint little Siem Reap airport, I step off the plane and into the blazing Cambodia heat and humidity.</p>
<p>Home for the next few days will be the <a href="http://thesoriamoria.com/" target="_blank">Soria Moria</a> hotel. Clean, functional and the staff are friendly and helpful.</p>
<p>I have arrived at lunch-time which means there&#8217;s no delay in selecting where I will have my first Khmer meal. I choose a restaurant that seems to have a healthy mix of tourists and locals dining there and order a green mango salad and a coconut shake. The salad is a nice mix of sweet and salty flavours that will be a hallmark of the meals to come. I also slowly become obsessed with drinking coconuts over the course of the next few weeks.</p>
<p>Belly full, I do a quick lap of the Old Market. Cheap souvenirs and trinkets abound. The vendors are friendly, but very polite. There is none of the persistant nagging that comes with markets in other countries. It&#8217;s a nice change and fun to barter as I pick up a few small gifts for friends back home.</p>
<div id="attachment_488" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 460px"><img class="size-full wp-image-488" alt="Old Market, Siem Reap" src="http://invadercee.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/cambodia-1-of-179.jpg?w=450&#038;h=299" width="450" height="299" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Old Market, Siem Reap</p></div>
<p>I&#8217;ve worked up a pretty good sweat by now so heeding advice from a friend, I indulge in a coconut ice-cream cone at the <a href="http://www.tripadvisor.com.au/Restaurant_Review-g297390-d1133338-Reviews-The_Blue_Pumpkin-Siem_Reap_Siem_Reap_Province.html" target="_blank">Blue Pumpkin</a>. Feeling refreshed from the air-con and sugar rush, I meet a tuk-tuk driver named Choi who drives me about a kilometre up the road (it&#8217;s way to hot to walk!) to the <a href="http://www.angkornationalmuseum.com/" target="_blank">Angkor National Museum</a>.</p>
<div id="attachment_489" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 460px"><img class="size-full wp-image-489" alt="Choi's Tuk-Tuk" src="http://invadercee.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/cambodia-5-of-179.jpg?w=450&#038;h=299" width="450" height="299" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Choi&#8217;s Tuk-Tuk</p></div>
<p>The museum is divided into a number of &#8216;galleries&#8217;, each dealing with a particular aspect of the history, art and religion of the Angkor Empire. It&#8217;s a good introduction to the culture and an easy way to spend a few hours reading sign posts and inspecting artifacts.</p>
<p>By the time I&#8217;m finished at the museum, it&#8217;s time to meet my tour group at the rooftop bar of my hotel. Given my limited time and lack of familiarity with the Khmer language, I chose to do a <a href="http://www.geckosadventures.com/south-east-asia/cambodia/its-a-jungle-out-there-2013" target="_blank">Geckos Tour</a> for part of my trip. I breathe a small sigh of relief after meeting our tour leader, Borey and the rest of the group who are all friendly.</p>
<p>After dinner of <em>loc lak </em>(marinated and stir-fried cubes of beef served with rice and a sauce made of lime juice, salt and black Kampot pepper), I share a drink at <a href="http://www.redpianocambodia.com/" target="_blank">The Red Piano</a> on Pub Street &#8211; the main hub &#8211; with some folks from the tour group. I realise how comparatively cheap food and drink in Cambodia is.</p>
<p>Angelina Jolie apparently frequented The Red Piano while filming Tomb Raider, so it seems apropos to order a <em>Tomb Raider</em> cocktail (cointreau, lime juice and tonic). It&#8217;s surprisingly, pretty good.</p>
<h4><em>Read more:</em></h4>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://invadercee.wordpress.com/2013/03/10/cambodia-day-1-siem-reap/">Cambodia travel diary: Day 1</a></li>
<li><a href="https://invadercee.wordpress.com/2013/03/11/cambodia-day-2-angkor-wat/">Cambodia travel diary: Day 2</a></li>
<li><a href="https://invadercee.wordpress.com/2013/03/12/cambodia-day-3-banteay-srei/">Cambodia travel diary: Day 3</a></li>
<li><a href="https://invadercee.wordpress.com/2013/03/13/cambodia-day-4-phnom-penh/">Cambodia travel diary: Day 4</a></li>
<li><a href="https://invadercee.wordpress.com/2013/03/14/cambodia-day-5-phnom-penh/">Cambodia travel diary: Day 5</a></li>
<li><a href="https://invadercee.wordpress.com/2013/03/15/cambodia-day-6-chambok-homestay/">Cambodia travel diary: Day 6</a></li>
<li><a href="https://invadercee.wordpress.com/2013/03/16/cambodia-day-7-sihanoukville/">Cambodia travel diary: Day 7</a></li>
<li><a href="https://invadercee.wordpress.com/2013/03/17/cambodia-day-8-ream-national-park/">Cambodia travel diary: Day 8</a></li>
<li><a href="https://invadercee.wordpress.com/2013/03/18/cambodia-day-9-phnom-penh/">Cambodia travel diary: Day 9</a></li>
<li><a href="https://invadercee.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/cambodia-day-10-phnom-penh/">Cambodia travel diary: Day 10</a></li>
<li><a href="https://invadercee.wordpress.com/2013/03/20/cambodia-day-11-kampot/">Cambodia travel diary: Day 11</a></li>
<li><a href="https://invadercee.wordpress.com/2013/03/21/cambodia-day-12-home/">Cambodia travel diary: Day 12</a></li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="http://photoblog.tinysparrows.com/#cambodia" target="_blank">Full Cambodia photo gallery here »</a></h3>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/487/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/487/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=487&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://invadercee.wordpress.com/2013/03/10/cambodia-day-1-siem-reap/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/09f839cf1ee6f8cba04444584841f5f4?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">invadercee</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://invadercee.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/cambodia-1-of-179.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Old Market, Siem Reap</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://invadercee.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/cambodia-5-of-179.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Choi&#039;s Tuk-Tuk</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Shelf of Shame</title>
		<link>http://wordsforworms.com/2013/03/19/top-ten-tuesday-the-shelf-of-shame/</link>
		<comments>http://wordsforworms.com/2013/03/19/top-ten-tuesday-the-shelf-of-shame/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 13:00:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Words for Worms</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Classics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Historical Fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Ten Tuesday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Books I bought but haven't read]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top ten tuesday]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://wordsforworms.com/?p=1625</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Greetings, Bookworms! You know when you&#8217;re in a bookstore, browsing, and you get sucked in by picking up a title in the bargain bin? How about when you have grand intentions of bettering yourself and pick up a pile o&#8217; classics only to watch them collect dust on your shelves? We&#8217;ve all got the shelf [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1625&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Greetings, Bookworms!</p>
<p>You know when you&#8217;re in a bookstore, browsing, and you get sucked in by picking up a title in the bargain bin? How about when you have grand intentions of bettering yourself and pick up a pile o&#8217; classics only to watch them collect dust on your shelves? We&#8217;ve all got the shelf of shame. And the ladies at the <a href="http://brokeandbookish.blogspot.com/p/top-ten-tuesday-other-features.html" target="_blank">Broke and the Bookish</a>? They want us to own up to it. Today&#8217;s Top Ten Tuesday: Stuff I Bought But Never Read.</p>
<p><a href="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/toptentuesday.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-898" alt="toptentuesday" src="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/toptentuesday.jpg?w=320&#038;h=178" width="320" height="178" /></a>1. <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Madame-Bovary-ebook/dp/B0084A6XBS/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1363655836&amp;sr=1-1&amp;keywords=madame+bovary" target="_blank"><em>Madame Bovary</em></a> by Gustave Flaubert. Sometimes (okay, a lot of times) I get self important and think that I will be able to appreciate even the most highbrow of classics. That&#8217;s when I buy things like <em>Madame Bovary </em>and then watch them moulder on my shelves for an eternity. I mean, I SHOULD like this. A doctor&#8217;s wife has adulterous affairs? I mean, hello <a title="The Greatest Sleep Aids Disguised as Books" href="http://wordsforworms.com/2012/08/24/the-greatest-sleep-aids-disguised-as-books/" target="_blank"><em>Anna Karenina</em></a>. How&#8217;s it going, <a title="Banned Books Week: Lady Chatterley’s Lover by DH Lawrence" href="http://wordsforworms.com/2012/10/04/banned-books-week-lady-chatterlys-lover-by-dh-lawrence/" target="_blank"><em>Lady Chatterley</em></a>? Why did I never get down with <em>Madame Bovary</em>? No idea.</p>
<p>2. <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Heart-of-Darkness-ebook/dp/B0084AMNWQ/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1363655803&amp;sr=1-1&amp;keywords=heart+of+darkness" target="_blank"><em>Heart of Darkness </em></a>by Joseph Conrad. This is always on smart people&#8217;s lists of favorite books. I&#8217;m highly susceptible to peer pressure whilst making decisions inside the Barnes and Noble&#8230; Amazon doesn&#8217;t judge me the way a hipster cashier would!</p>
<p>3. <a href="http://www.amazon.com/The-Mayor-of-Casterbridge-ebook/dp/B0084AYLK8/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1363655757&amp;sr=1-1&amp;keywords=the+mayor+of+casterbridge" target="_blank"><em>The Mayor of Casterbridge </em></a>by Thomas Hardy. I bought this because <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Tess-of-the-dUrbervilles-ebook/dp/B0084B0CKA/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1363655867&amp;sr=1-1&amp;keywords=tess+of+the+d%27urbervilles+kindle+free" target="_blank"><em>Tess of the d&#8217;Urbervilles </em></a>was so fantastic. However&#8230; The lack of female main character and/or the really unappealing portrait of what I assume to be the &#8220;mayor&#8221; on the cover has kept me from actually bending the spine of this one.</p>
<p>4. <em><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Count-Cristo-Illustrated-Edition-ebook/dp/B007M5QT10/ref=sr_1_2?s=digital-text&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1363655965&amp;sr=1-2&amp;keywords=count+of+monte+cristo+kindle+free" target="_blank">The Count of Monte Cristo </a></em>by Alexandre Dumas. I really do want to read this&#8230; It&#8217;s just so THICK. I&#8217;m not easily intimidated by big books, but this sucker is the size of <a title="Do You Hear The People Sing? (Give Them ALL THE OSCARS!)" href="http://wordsforworms.com/2012/12/30/do-you-hear-the-people-sing-give-them-all-the-oscars/" target="_blank"><em>Les Miserables,</em></a> but lacks a magnificent soundtrack to play in my head&#8230; And no Gavroche.</p>
<div id="attachment_1626" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 472px"><a href="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_3298.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-1626" alt="IMG_3298" src="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_3298-e1363656351913.jpg?w=462&#038;h=344" width="462" height="344" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The Classics&#8230; Of Shame.</p></div>
<p>5. <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Secret-History-Pink-Carnation-ebook/dp/B000PC0SFK/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1363656574&amp;sr=1-1&amp;keywords=the+secret+history+of+the+pink+carnation" target="_blank"><em>The Secret History of the Pink Carnation</em></a> by Lauren Willig. It&#8217;s historical fiction with a pretty cover. I couldn&#8217;t be expected to resist the purchase, and yet&#8230; Still unread.</p>
<p>6. <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Shakespeares-Wife-P-S-ebook/dp/B0013TPVII/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1363656765&amp;sr=1-1&amp;keywords=shakespeare%27s+wife" target="_blank"><em>Shakespeare&#8217;s Wife </em></a>by Germaine Greer. It&#8217;s historical fiction about, uh, Shakespeare&#8217;s wife. You know. Anne Hathaway. The one that didn&#8217;t win an Oscar. I found it in a bargain bin. I really loved the movie <em>Shakespeare in Love, </em>so perhaps I just don&#8217;t want to hear the sad tale of the wife who was left behind when the dashing Joseph Fiennes fell for a not-yet-openly-pretentious Gwyneth Paltrow. Siiigh.</p>
<p>7. <em><a href="http://www.amazon.com/The-Meaning-Night-Confession-ebook/dp/B0015VTPDG/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1363657072&amp;sr=1-1&amp;keywords=the+meaning+of+night" target="_blank">The Meaning of Night </a></em>by Michael Cox. I bought this because it&#8217;s historical fiction. I&#8217;ve been putting off reading it because it&#8217;s about a Victorian era murderer. I&#8217;m not big on crime novels, even historical ones. I frequently question my bargain bin judgement.</p>
<div id="attachment_1627" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 472px"><a href="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_7873.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-1627 " alt="You can see the bargain stickers! " src="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_7873.jpg?w=462&#038;h=344" width="462" height="344" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">You can see the bargain stickers!</p></div>
<p style="text-align:left;">8. <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Ladder-Years-A-Novel-ebook/dp/B003E8AIEI/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1363657500&amp;sr=1-1&amp;keywords=ladder+of+years" target="_blank"><em>Ladder of Years </em></a>by Anne Tyler. I bought this with <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Dinner-Homesick-Restaurant-Ballantine-ebook/dp/B004GTLKIW/ref=sr_1_2?s=digital-text&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1363657478&amp;sr=1-2&amp;keywords=dinner+at+the+homesick+restaurant+by+anne+tyler" target="_blank"><em>Dinner At The Homesick</em> <em>Restaurant </em></a>because I thought they sounded smart and fabulous. I read <em>Dinner At The Homesick Restaurant </em>and didn&#8217;t love it, so I didn&#8217;t bother with the other one on the shelf.</p>
<p>9. <em><a href="http://www.amazon.com/A-Taxonomy-Barnacles-Novel/dp/0312426518/ref=sr_1_cc_1?s=aps&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1363657557&amp;sr=1-1-catcorr&amp;keywords=a+taxonomy+of+barnacles" target="_blank">A Taxonomy of Barnacles </a></em>by Galt Niederhoffer. Yeah. I bought this solely for the AWESOME title. I didn&#8217;t even read the abstract. Maybe I should. Maybe I will. Who knows?</p>
<p>10. <a href="http://www.amazon.com/House-Sand-Fog-Andre-Dubus/dp/0393338118/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1363657643&amp;sr=1-1&amp;keywords=house+of+sand+and+fog" target="_blank"><em>House of Sand and Fog </em></a>by Andre Dubus III. There was an Oprah sticker, and I am not immune to the influence of The Oprah. I don&#8217;t know why I haven&#8217;t read it. STOP JUDGING ME, OPRAH!</p>
<div id="attachment_1628" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 472px"><a href="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_4883.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-1628" alt="IMG_4883" src="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_4883-e1363657878210.jpg?w=462&#038;h=344" width="462" height="344" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Haven&#8217;t read these. Scandalous.</p></div>
<p style="text-align:left;">Alright, Bookworms. You know you&#8217;ve got some of these bad boys on your shelves. I want to hear about them so I don&#8217;t feel so alone. Spill it!</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1625/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1625/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1625&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://wordsforworms.com/2013/03/19/top-ten-tuesday-the-shelf-of-shame/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>97</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/5d13100a03f9d0fc63e2c99c0ba2c7f2?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">wordsforworms</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/toptentuesday.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">toptentuesday</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_3298-e1363656351913.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_3298</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_7873.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">You can see the bargain stickers! </media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://wordsforworms.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_4883-e1363657878210.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_4883</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Rainbow In Your Hands</title>
		<link>http://elodieunderglass.com/2013/03/12/the-rainbow-in-your-hands-protocols-for-hand-painting-yarn/</link>
		<comments>http://elodieunderglass.com/2013/03/12/the-rainbow-in-your-hands-protocols-for-hand-painting-yarn/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2013 10:26:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>elodieunderglass</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Arts Is Serious Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[By Cunning and Craft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DIY for Science Princesses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life In General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[a day in the life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[art and science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[art is serious business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[color]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crafts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creativity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[D.I.Y.]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DIY for ladylike woodland creatures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elodie what did you do this weekend]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fiber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[getting your shit together]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[handmade]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inspiration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[knitting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rainbows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the fine and delicate art of unfucking yourself]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yarn]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://elodieunderglass.wordpress.com/?p=1276</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[What did you do this weekend, Elodie? Nothing much. Met the Awkward Army, put the world to rights. Learned a bit of materials science and inadvertently created a new kind of polystyrene plastic in my kitchen. Made a rainbow. The richly glowing skein in Figure One is a sumptuous, hand-painted rainbow yarn that I dyed [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1276&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_1277" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 495px"><a href="http://elodieunderglass.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_0385-e1363033933439.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-1277" alt="this is an artsy craft blog now. artsy craft blogs are cool, right? ...?" src="http://elodieunderglass.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_0385-e1363033933439.jpg?w=485&#038;h=266" width="485" height="266" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text"><strong>Figure One.</strong></p></div>
<p><em>What did you do this weekend, Elodie?</em></p>
<p>Nothing much. Met the Awkward Army, put the world to rights. Learned a bit of materials science and inadvertently created a new kind of polystyrene plastic in my kitchen.</p>
<p>Made a rainbow.</p>
<div id="attachment_1278" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 495px"><a href="http://elodieunderglass.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_0370.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-1278" alt="IMG_0370" src="http://elodieunderglass.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_0370.jpg?w=485&#038;h=364" width="485" height="364" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">In the aftermath of the unicorn dissection&#8230;</p></div>
<p>The richly glowing skein in <strong>Figure One</strong> is a sumptuous, hand-painted rainbow yarn that I dyed myself. With food coloring. And SCIENCE. You won&#8217;t find colors like that in a store&#8230;</p>
<p>And at the risk of becoming a craft blog (SCIENCE CRAFTS!) I&#8217;m going to tell you how to do it.</p>
<h2>.</h2>
<h2><span id="more-1276"></span></h2>
<h2></h2>
<p>Knitting is an exhausting hobby. You&#8217;ll knit a few hats and socks, and then suddenly nothing will do but you have to make a Loch Ness Monster, a colony of plushy starfish and a squishy dinosaur hat for every baby in your social circle that you vaguely like. Then you start accumulating yarn, and so you start looking for patterns to make with it, and suddenly you find yourself in the corners of the Internet where people spin their own wool out of otters and hand-dye it with berries foraged from fairy forests. (I am exaggerating slightly because I am jealous.)</p>
<p>Now, the idea of hand-dyeing raised my eyebrows, because I love bright colors and handmade things, and who <em>wouldn&#8217;t</em> want to have beautiful yarn in their very favorite colors? After all, most commercially available fibers give the impression that their dyes were picked out by half-blind woodlice, paddling vaguely at a color chart with their uncoordinated paws.</p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 360px"><img alt="" src="http://www.countryfarm-lifestyles.com/images/woodlouse.jpg" width="350" height="273" /><p class="wp-caption-text">&#8220;Yaaay! More bum-colored yarn! In acrylic! For reasons!&#8221;</p></div>
<p>So when I heard rumors that animal fibers can be dyed safely and effectively with simple <em>food coloring</em>, I perked up and took notice. The creative Earth Mother in me immediately decided that this was the best idea since homemade apple-and-rosemary jelly. The scientist in me itched to test new protocols and optimize chemical reactions, while the businesswoman quietly drew up plans to create a finished product that would appeal to others. The researcher in me lunged to the fore as she usually does, plunging eagerly into descriptions and definitions, learning about medieval terms like <em>mordants </em>and intriguing techniques like <em>breaking black, </em>diving into ancient manuscripts from various cultures and learning about <em>cochineal</em> and <em>amphoteric materials</em>. Eventually, she emerged with what she&#8217;d determined to be a good starting point, a nice blog post entitled &#8220;<a href="http://peasoupoftheday.blogspot.co.uk/2008/01/how-to-dye-yarn-with-food-colouring-and.html">How to Dye Yarn with Food Coloring and Small Children.&#8221;<br />
</a></p>
<p>The principles of home-dying yarn are simple. You need a heat source, like a microwave, but presumably other things will do just as well. Get some wool &#8211; pure, pale wool is best; superwash wool is even better. Synthetic fibers won&#8217;t dye permanently with food coloring. Grab some acid (acetic acid, in the humble household form of vinegar, will do.) Snag some food dyes, preferably nice chemical-y American ones that haven&#8217;t gone all European and &#8220;natural&#8221; &#8211; the hippie-dippie kiddie colors available in British supermarkets simply won&#8217;t do. You need <em>unnatural</em> food dye &#8211; as American as possible. I used it as an excuse to buy a nice pack of high-quality Wilton gel, since I can keep using the materials, worth their weight in rainbow cakes. (You can also use Kool-Aid, but since I&#8217;ve never touched the stuff in my life and don&#8217;t think that it actually exists on this side of the Atlantic.) The Wilton arrived in the mail, filling me with all of the joy that young Elodie used to feel upon getting a new box of paints. <em>Shiny. Colorful. Bursting with possibilities. AND MINE, ALL MINE.</em></p>
<p>Hypothesis: I can make something more beautiful with these colors than I could ever buy. I can make something more suited to my taste than anyone could ever design for me. And hopefully, I can dye yarn with food coloring.</p>
<div id="attachment_1279" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 235px"><a href="http://elodieunderglass.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_0341.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1279" alt="IMG_0341" src="http://elodieunderglass.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_0341.jpg?w=225&#038;h=300" width="225" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Dr Glass insisted that the packaging of the Wilton Icing Colors was meant to evoke the artistic works of Damien Hirst. I refused to believe that a paleontologist could know more about art than me. I, whose first degree was in Humanities! I, who was raised by a tribe of Fine-Arts-art-history-and-humanities-majoring wolves!</p></div>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 180px"><img class="  " alt="" src="http://blog.seattlepi.com/art/files/library/Hirst_Chiken.JPG" width="170" height="252" /><p class="wp-caption-text">&#8230; But after a long discussion that involved a lot of Googling, I began to see his point.</p></div>
<p>Most of the dyes that professional fiber artists use are acid dyes, which latch readily onto the fabric. Food coloring, which is intended for gentler purposes, needs to be set with acid. Luckily, our home kitchens are stuffed full of acid. Vinegar will do the trick. The only pale non-staining vinegar we had in the house was apple cider vinegar, which I sloshed into a bowl, adding water to a random dilution, and admired the effect and the smell. After a quick test skein indicated that the overall protocol created a permanent set dye, I was ready to run with the big dogs. Wolves.</p>
<p>I skeined and tied my yarn, fifty grams of a beautiful creamy Merino superwash, and arranged it attractively in the bowl of acid.</p>
<div id="attachment_1282" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 235px"><a href="http://elodieunderglass.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_0354.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1282" alt="IMG_0354" src="http://elodieunderglass.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_0354.jpg?w=225&#038;h=300" width="225" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Craft blogs always include dreamy macro close-ups with the objects in the distance being really blurry. Here&#8217;s one of those.</p></div>
<p>The <span style="text-decoration:line-through;">BATH OF ACID</span> gentle soak in vinegar was meant to soften it up a little, you know? <span style="text-decoration:line-through;">TO MAKE IT READY TO TALK</span> To create the ideal chemical conditions to bond permanently with the sweet, gentle cupcake dye.</p>
<div id="attachment_1281" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 235px"><a href="http://elodieunderglass.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_0353.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1281" alt="IMG_0353" src="http://elodieunderglass.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_0353.jpg?w=225&#038;h=300" width="225" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Pour your yarn a nice bath and seduce it a little.</p></div>
<p>Then I laid the yarn out on plastic, over a floor that I didn&#8217;t mind cleaning.</p>
<div id="attachment_1283" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://elodieunderglass.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_0355.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1283" alt="Most craft blogs suggest that you laminate your entire kitchen before doing this project. I half-assed with a posh bag. " src="http://elodieunderglass.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_0355.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Most craft blogs suggest that you laminate your entire kitchen before doing this project. I half-assed with a posh bag.</p></div>
<p>Thankfully, Dr Glass keeps the household in lab gloves, so the next steps caused minimal damage to the kitchen. Using a butterknife like a palette knife, I took slabs of concentrated gel paste, mixed a few of them to create my absolute favorite colors, and set to work rubbing them into the skeined yarn.</p>
<p>This is one reason why it&#8217;s great to pick superwash yarn for hand-dying. As everyone knows, the long, rough, jagged edges of animal protein fibers love to cling to each other, and if you heat and agitate them they&#8217;ll felt, or become a solid material. Superwash yarn can be machine-washed and rubbed without felting.</p>
<div id="attachment_1284" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://elodieunderglass.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_0359.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1284" alt="IMG_0359" src="http://elodieunderglass.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_0359.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Parts of this project looked disturbing.</p></div>
<p style="text-align:left;">I wanted a rainbow with lots of variation and variegation, and beautiful transitions between colors. My favorite colors are deep jewel tones, so I decided to err on the side of Too Much Paste rather than too little, aiming for a saturated, rich product. For the transitions, I combined the colors I&#8217;d mixed as well as rubbing and blending the colors together where they met. I didn&#8217;t end up with much yellow in the end&#8230;.</p>
<div id="attachment_1285" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://elodieunderglass.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_0366.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1285" alt="IMG_0366" src="http://elodieunderglass.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_0366.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">DELICIOUS RAINBOW!</p></div>
<p style="text-align:left;">Now it was time to permanently set the dye with heat. Unfortunately, Dr Glass wandered off so we don&#8217;t have pictures, but basically I wrapped it in clingfilm to prevent the colors from bleeding, arranged it in a bowl and zapped it on high heat for five minutes at a time. I kept the yarn slightly damp so that it wouldn&#8217;t burn. After a few rounds of this, the kitchen smelled faintly of damp sheep, and I proclaimed the yarn done.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">I rinsed it in cold running water to finalize the setting of the stain. And let me tell you, food coloring + acid + heat creates a beautiful permanent dye&#8230; but a hell of a lot of unbound color still rinsed out. I went pretty wild with those super-concentrated gel pastes, so if you ever try this experiment at home, you can probably use a lot less.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">But you know what? Fuck it. I didn&#8217;t want pasty-ass pissant colors on my rainbow yarn. I wanted life, vibrancy, saturation. Hold too much passion and ambition back and you&#8217;ll crumple in on yourself; your inner pilot light will go out; you&#8217;ll lose your chin and your mouth will pucker like a cat&#8217;s butt. SLAP ON THE PASTE, DARE TO FAIL! BETTER TO FAIL GLORIOUSLY THAN TO WIN AT BEING BORING. Colors take more work than beige, but they&#8217;re worth infinitely more: it&#8217;s the only way to live.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">This will tell you a lot about my personality, and also about <em>just how much dye</em> I forced into that yarn. It bled beautifully for several minutes. The jewel-colored water ran through my fingers like child&#8217;s magic. I felt like I&#8217;d slaughtered a unicorn, or performed some kind of splendid alchemy. The color was more pleasant than paint; clear and pure, the light went right through it, and it didn&#8217;t stick to my hands.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">And the dye held fast.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">When I held the finished product up, it looked like something too bright and lovely to be real.</p>
<div id="attachment_1286" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 235px"><a href="http://elodieunderglass.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_0379.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1286" alt="IMG_0379" src="http://elodieunderglass.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_0379.jpg?w=225&#038;h=300" width="225" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Look what I caught!</p></div>
<p style="text-align:left;">The camera actually couldn&#8217;t deal with it. It&#8217;s a brand new camera, specially purchased for such purposes, and it almost couldn&#8217;t manage these colors.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">I laid the skein flat on a radiator to dry and went to bed on it. In the morning, it was even more beautiful. My most beloved colors &#8211; rich autumn oranges, wine reds, deep teals, passionate purples &#8211; were all so lovely that I only regretted not owning a dress in each perfect shade.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><a href="http://elodieunderglass.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_0386.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-1287" alt="IMG_0386" src="http://elodieunderglass.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_0386.jpg?w=547&#038;h=730" width="547" height="730" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">I was particularly pleased that I got some good variegation in the different strands of yarn for each color. When knitted, this will produce a lovely depth and texture, adding complexity to the knit. Plus, it looks handmade. Why bother spending your love and labor on something that will look perfect &#8211; mass-produced, homogenous? Make something that&#8217;s got<em> you</em> in it.</p>
<div id="attachment_1288" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 374px"><a href="http://elodieunderglass.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_0387.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-1288" alt="IMG_0387" src="http://elodieunderglass.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_0387.jpg?w=364&#038;h=485" width="364" height="485" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Deep greens and blues are the colors I choose&#8230;.</p></div>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://elodieunderglass.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_0389.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-1290" alt="IMG_0389" src="http://elodieunderglass.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_0389.jpg?w=364&#038;h=485" width="364" height="485" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://elodieunderglass.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_0402.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-1289" alt="IMG_0402" src="http://elodieunderglass.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_0402.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" width="300" height="225" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><strong>Results:</strong> I declare this protocol a success.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Now I just need to make something out of it.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><strong>References:</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><a href="http://www.dummies.com/how-to/content/tips-for-handpainting-fiber-with-dye.html">1. Tips for Handpainting Fiber with Dye</a></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">2. &#8220;<a href="http://peasoupoftheday.blogspot.co.uk/2008/01/how-to-dye-yarn-with-food-colouring-and.html">How to Dye Yarn with Food Coloring and Small Children.&#8221;</a></p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><a href="http://www.dyeyouryarn.com/instructions.html">3. Dye Your Yarn</a></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">
<p style="text-align:left;">===</p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><strong>ETA March 26 2013</strong>: This post got Freshly Pressed! How exciting! It will probably go live in a few days.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">
New visitor? Stopping by for the first time? Welcome.<em> </em>I am a revolutionary scientist princess and this is my personal science/humor blog. Popular posts include <a title="Cups Runneth Over: Love, Lifestyle, and Clothing Tips for Large-Busted Ladies" href="http://elodieunderglass.wordpress.com/2012/09/05/cups-runneth-over-love-lifestyle-and-clothing-tips-for-large-busted-ladies/">&#8220;Cups Runneth Over: Love, Lifestyle and Clothing Tips for Large-Busted Ladies&#8221;</a> and the ever-humorous Illustrated Compendiums Of Search Terms (<a href="http://elodieunderglass.wordpress.com/2012/11/01/elodies-compendium-of-illustrated-search-terms/">Part One</a>/<a href="http://elodieunderglass.wordpress.com/2013/02/27/elodies-compendium-of-illustrated-search-terms-volume-ii/">Part Two</a>.) I have guest-blogged on <a href="http://captainawkward.com/">Captain Awkward</a> (<a href="http://captainawkward.com/2012/11/07/391-how-to-train-your-rageasaurus/">Here </a>and <a href="http://captainawkward.com/2013/01/24/437/">here</a>). I am currently collecting anecdotes and experiences from women and minority groups in STEM fields &#8211; if this is you, please share yours &#8211; and I can always be reached at the <a title="Contact!" href="http://elodieunderglass.wordpress.com/contact/">Contact!</a> form,<a href="http://facebook.com/ElodieUnderGlass"> Facebook</a> and <a href="http://twitter.com/elodieglass">Twitter. </a></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Spammers, I warmly encourage you to stop by my <em>first</em> Freshly Pressed Post, &#8220;<a href="http://elodieunderglass.wordpress.com/2012/10/26/youre-a-strange-man-charlie-darwin/">You&#8217;re a Strange Man, Charlie Darwin.</a>&#8221; You must be aware that when one gets FP&#8217;ed, one is swamped by a howling swarm of insincere folks who wish to spam one with links to their<em> profoundly</em> uninteresting blogs. One is supremely uninterested in spam, and considers it only fit for target practice and revenge. Please<em></em> keep this in mind.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Love,</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Elodie</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://elodieunderglass.com/category/arts-is-serious-business/'>Arts Is Serious Business</a>, <a href='http://elodieunderglass.com/category/blogging/'>Blogging</a>, <a href='http://elodieunderglass.com/category/by-cunning-and-craft/'>By Cunning and Craft</a>, <a href='http://elodieunderglass.com/category/diy-for-science-princesses/'>DIY for Science Princesses</a>, <a href='http://elodieunderglass.com/category/life-in-general/'>Life In General</a>, <a href='http://elodieunderglass.com/category/science-2/'>Science</a> Tagged: <a href='http://elodieunderglass.com/tag/a-day-in-the-life/'>a day in the life</a>, <a href='http://elodieunderglass.com/tag/art-and-science/'>art and science</a>, <a href='http://elodieunderglass.com/tag/art-is-serious-business/'>art is serious business</a>, <a href='http://elodieunderglass.com/tag/color/'>color</a>, <a href='http://elodieunderglass.com/tag/crafts/'>crafts</a>, <a href='http://elodieunderglass.com/tag/creativity/'>creativity</a>, <a href='http://elodieunderglass.com/tag/d-i-y/'>D.I.Y.</a>, <a href='http://elodieunderglass.com/tag/diy/'>diy</a>, <a href='http://elodieunderglass.com/tag/diy-for-ladylike-woodland-creatures/'>DIY for ladylike woodland creatures</a>, <a href='http://elodieunderglass.com/tag/elodie-what-did-you-do-this-weekend/'>Elodie what did you do this weekend</a>, <a href='http://elodieunderglass.com/tag/fiber/'>fiber</a>, <a href='http://elodieunderglass.com/tag/getting-your-shit-together/'>getting your shit together</a>, <a href='http://elodieunderglass.com/tag/handmade/'>handmade</a>, <a href='http://elodieunderglass.com/tag/inspiration/'>inspiration</a>, <a href='http://elodieunderglass.com/tag/knitting/'>knitting</a>, <a href='http://elodieunderglass.com/tag/rainbows/'>rainbows</a>, <a href='http://elodieunderglass.com/tag/the-fine-and-delicate-art-of-unfucking-yourself/'>the fine and delicate art of unfucking yourself</a>, <a href='http://elodieunderglass.com/tag/yarn/'>yarn</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1276/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1276/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1276&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://elodieunderglass.com/2013/03/12/the-rainbow-in-your-hands-protocols-for-hand-painting-yarn/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>38</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/e550741cd901ad8dcea8544e6ec8669e?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">elodieunderglass</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://elodieunderglass.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_0385-e1363033933439.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">this is an artsy craft blog now. artsy craft blogs are cool, right? ...?</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://elodieunderglass.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_0370.jpg?w=808" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0370</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://www.countryfarm-lifestyles.com/images/woodlouse.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://elodieunderglass.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_0341.jpg?w=225" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0341</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://blog.seattlepi.com/art/files/library/Hirst_Chiken.JPG" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://elodieunderglass.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_0354.jpg?w=225" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0354</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://elodieunderglass.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_0353.jpg?w=225" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0353</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://elodieunderglass.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_0355.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Most craft blogs suggest that you laminate your entire kitchen before doing this project. I half-assed with a posh bag. </media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://elodieunderglass.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_0359.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0359</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://elodieunderglass.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_0366.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0366</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://elodieunderglass.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_0379.jpg?w=225" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0379</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://elodieunderglass.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_0386.jpg?w=606" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0386</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://elodieunderglass.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_0387.jpg?w=606" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0387</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://elodieunderglass.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_0389.jpg?w=606" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0389</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://elodieunderglass.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_0402.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0402</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>More Philadelphia Stories</title>
		<link>http://tanglethis.wordpress.com/2012/10/27/more-philadelphia-stories/</link>
		<comments>http://tanglethis.wordpress.com/2012/10/27/more-philadelphia-stories/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2012 00:33:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tanglethis</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Navelgazing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Overheard in Philly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Urbanality]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tanglethis.wordpress.com/?p=1090</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Last night I went to a house party where I only knew one person.  I hadn&#8217;t been to the house before, so I had the address in my hand as I walked quickly through the dark. Just around the corner from where I thought the house party should be, I passed another house party in [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1090&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last night I went to a house party where I only knew one person.  I hadn&#8217;t been to the house before, so I had the address in my hand as I walked quickly through the dark. Just around the corner from where I thought the house party should be, I passed another house party in full swing: I could see rooms full of costumed people standing and laughing, plastic cups in hand.</p>
<p>For a moment I thought about walking in. It could just as easily have been the party I was going to, and I would know almost as many people there.</p>
<p>But I found the right party just around the corner. I poured myself some of the applejack cocktail I&#8217;d brought and scanned the room. By the time the one person I knew appeared, I&#8217;d already met several other guests, including a kindred spirit who also &#8220;didn&#8217;t know anyone here.&#8221; The next three people I met all knew someone else I already knew, out in the world beyond this party. We all had plenty to say to each other but before too long half of these new acquaintances and I were dancing energetically in the room set aside for that purpose, sweaty and happy. I was very glad I went.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">*</p>
<p>On my way home, I passed a group of men talking loudly next to a church. As I walked by, they began talking to me, theatrically abashed and fauxpologizing. Then I realized that they weren&#8217;t having an impromptu party in the churchyard, they were having an impromptu pee in the churchyard.</p>
<p>&#8220;Are you <em>serious</em>,&#8221; I exclaimed, &#8220;there are a <em>million</em> bars around and they all <em>have bathrooms </em>you know!&#8221;</p>
<p>Noises of agreement and disagreement. They were just as drunk as I was, and we were all rather loud and performatively staging this referendum. One of them suggested that there was no good reason <em>not</em> to pee in the churchyard.</p>
<p>&#8220;Yes there <em>is</em>,&#8221; I insisted, full of italics. &#8220;I <em>live</em> here and I don&#8217;t want <em>pee</em> in my <em>neighborhood!</em>&#8220;</p>
<p>Ah, touché. They conceded the point but the damage was already done, and I resumed my walk home. &#8220;You&#8217;re just going to walk away?&#8221; asked their primary interlocutor plaintively. &#8220;<em>Yes</em>,&#8221; I said firmly, &#8220;but I hope you all have a good night. Somewhere else. Where there are <em>bathrooms</em>.&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">*</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">I still haven&#8217;t received my new debit card from the bank to replace the one that go shut off after the ATM fiasco earlier this month, and I haven&#8217;t made it to the bank for cash. However, my cute July haircut had grown entirely out of control, and so I found myself headed to a hair salon sight unseen purely on the strengths that it was nearby, inexpensive, and accepted my credit card.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">The stylist thought I looked familiar. I couldn&#8217;t think why. He asked me if I used to hang out at Double Shots, a coffee shop in Old City. I did indeed, a long time ago when I was new to Philly and wi-fi wasn&#8217;t as prevalent as it is now. I hoofed it to Double Shots to work on my grad school homework because it was the nearest cafe with wi-fi that I knew of, and because I thought one or two of the baristas were cute. Now that I remembered the time and place, I remembered the stylist coming up to me, admiring my hair (it was very long then), showing me his book and talking about what he&#8217;d like to do with my hair (in a professional capacity, I mean). At that age, I had established a routine of cutting my hair once every three years, so I didn&#8217;t think I&#8217;d need his services.  I saw him once or twice after that, I don&#8217;t really remember. He remembered me vividly, including the fact that I occasionally dyed my hair pink.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">It was strange to be remembered like this. Just recently I&#8217;d been feeling like everything that happened in my twenties was a dream, that I&#8217;d moved to Philadelphia to chase a dream, that I&#8217;d dreamed my way through the first few foggy years of grad school, alternately timid and brazen, not yet fully formed  yet full of nonsense. Not that I think the reverse is now true; I&#8217;m certainly related to that earlier version, but it&#8217;s hard to believe she existed. <em>Did I really say that? How did I ever fall in love with such a person? Why did I think this or that was important? How could I have done such a thing?</em> But I existed. I left imprints on the world. I had flesh and fabulous pink hair.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Well, now I have a hangover and a fresh haircut, and the reminder (that I need regularly) to be present here, in this moment.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1090/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1090/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1090&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tanglethis.wordpress.com/2012/10/27/more-philadelphia-stories/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/06a2e3645c048116d4e950635bb66bac?s=96&#38;d=wavatar" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tanglethis</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Introvert Fairy Tales: The Princess and the Pea</title>
		<link>http://introvertfairytales.com/2013/01/31/introvert-fairy-tales-the-princess-and-the-pea/</link>
		<comments>http://introvertfairytales.com/2013/01/31/introvert-fairy-tales-the-princess-and-the-pea/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2013 23:15:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sophie</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fairy tales]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[introvert]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[princess]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://introvertfairytales.com/?p=104</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It wasn&#8217;t that the chairs were uncomfortable. After shelling out for what had been billed as a &#8220;Premium Cinema Experience&#8221; they were practically four poster beds. The red velvet was new and plush, the back and headrest were at the ideal angle for viewing the screen and the armrests were sturdy enough to keep distance [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=104&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It wasn&#8217;t that the chairs were uncomfortable. After shelling out for what had been billed as a &#8220;Premium Cinema Experience&#8221; they were practically four poster beds. The red velvet was new and plush, the back and headrest were at the ideal angle for viewing the screen and the armrests were sturdy enough to keep distance enough between strangers (and movable enough to close that distance for other purposes if and as required). Even the film itself was living up to expectations.</p>
<p>No, the problem wasn&#8217;t the upholstery. The problem was the people. The people who brought in food in crinkly wrappers. The people who couldn&#8217;t go more than three scenes without illuminating their phones, creating for the people behind them the galaxy&#8217;s most transient and irritating constellations. The people who slurped. The people who rustled. The people who TALKED.</p>
<p>Some time thereafter a small, experimental screening series started at the cinema. They never played on the larger screens and maybe they never would be in the theatres with the hydraulic seats, but the &#8220;Silent Movies&#8221; sessions became a modest success. The rules were simple: you could laugh at something funny, gasp at something shocking or discretely cry at something sad, but otherwise you were silent. The premium ticket price went to paying the ushers who ejected those who preferred, shall we say, a more interactive cinematic experience.</p>
<p>Not everyone understood the appeal, but those who did went all the time.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/104/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/104/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=104&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://introvertfairytales.com/2013/01/31/introvert-fairy-tales-the-princess-and-the-pea/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>23</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/4d582374a5335c5ed9df397623bab01b?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">postcardsandpaperbacks</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Personal Appeal to Britain\&#8217;s Politicians: Fuel Poverty is Killing People</title>
		<link>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/24/a-personal-appeal-to-britains-politicians-wake-up-from-your-warm-dreams-fuel-poverty-is-killing-people/</link>
		<comments>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/24/a-personal-appeal-to-britains-politicians-wake-up-from-your-warm-dreams-fuel-poverty-is-killing-people/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 12:53:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tallbloke</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[atmosphere]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Carbon cycle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[climate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Clouds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gravity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Incompetence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Natural Variation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ocean dynamics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Philosophy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robber Barons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shale gas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Solar physics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[solar system dynamics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tides]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/?p=11842</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[“The most revolutionary thing one can do always is to proclaim loudly what is happening.” Rosa Luxemburg There are times when I find it hard to speak politely. I left school at sixteen and worked on the shop-floor of a large engineering works for ten years, gaining a higher national qualification in mechanical and production [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=11842&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;"><em>“The most revolutionary thing one can do always is to proclaim loudly what is happening.”</em><br />
<em>Rosa Luxemburg</em><br />
<a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/tod_kaiser.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-11843" alt="tod_kaiser" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/tod_kaiser.jpg?w=266&#038;h=255" width="266" height="255" /></a></p>
<p>There are times when I find it hard to speak politely. I left school at sixteen and worked on the shop-floor of a large engineering works for ten years, gaining a higher national qualification in mechanical and production engineering along the way before getting the chance to study for a degree in the History and Philosophy of Science. While I worked in heavy industry, I learned some choice ways of expressing myself which are basic, direct, and hurt the sensibilities of those who have spent their lives in polite company, although they got the job done effectively. So I sometimes struggle to find the right tone at those times when a message needs communicating forcefully to people in a position to influence policy, but without having them recoil and ignore things they don&#8217;t want to contemplate.</p>
<p>But the time for niceties has passed. Britain&#8217;s people face a looming disaster of epic proportion. Britain&#8217;s political class needs to act swiftly to minimise the damage which cannot be wholly averted at this late stage. Successive governments have set the stage for the impending denouement, so this is not a partisan rant, but a cross-party appeal to common sense. People are <a href="http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/15/government-protect-wintering-birds-but-not-pensioners/">dying by the thousand</a> as a direct result of <a href="http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/23/christopher-booker-its-payback-time-for-britains-insane-energy-policy/">botched energy policy</a> and we must act to save lives. Now.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s clear some of the undergrowth so we can see the shape of the problem. Firstly, we&#8217;ll deal with the climate scare.</p>
<p><span id="more-11842"></span><strong>The Climate Question</strong></p>
<p>There is no &#8216;enhanced greenhouse effect&#8217; from rising levels of co2 in the atmosphere. Carbon dioxide is an essential trace gas with little radiative effect compared with the enormous quantity of water vapour in the air. The hydrological cycle has massive redundant capacity to provide a negative feedback to any increase in radiative forcing from additional airborne co2. In any case it is <a href="http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2012/09/12/is-the-airborne-co2-fraction-temperature-dependent/">by no means certain</a> that the majority of the increase in airborne co2 is <a href="http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2012/04/18/uncertainty-the-origin-of-the-increase-in-atmospheric-co2/">of human origin</a>.</p>
<p>The real drivers of climatic change; the cyclically varying make-up of radiation from the Sun, the tidal effects on ocean circulation caused by the Moon&#8217;s declination cycle, and the Earth&#8217;s tectonic and seismic responses to the changing disposition of the rest of the solar system masses, induce near repeating <a href="http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2011/06/30/further-terrestrial-evidence-of-planetary-cycles-affecting-climate/">cyclic patterns</a> in Earth&#8217;s ever-changing climatic history. Through the decomposition of the complex signal into <a href="http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2011/02/21/tallbloke-and-tim-channon-a-cycles-analysis-approach-to-predicting-solar-activity/">simpler sinusoidal components</a>, we are able to better determine their origin, and predict future changes.</p>
<p>The indications are that the Sun is going into a phase of low activity levels. This is likely to increase cloudiness and reduce sunshine hours. That will induce surface cooling for several decades to come.</p>
<p><strong>The Energy Issue</strong></p>
<p>Supplying society&#8217;s need for high quality securely distributed energy is paramount to our well being. Clean water supply, food, health, education, and all of modern society&#8217;s benefits stem from our production of energy. Cleaner air is a desirable aspiration, but it cannot take priority over basic requirements on which peoples lives depend. The emissions from coal burning power stations are not particularly toxic at the levels they are ingested, and some of the by-products, such as sulphur are of direct benefit to agriculture. Acid rain destroying Scandinavian forest is a long debunked myth. Sulphur dioxide doesn&#8217;t make us ill. Hypothermia kills people, especially old people who have paid their dues to society and have the right to a warm home in retirement.</p>
<p><strong>The Engineer&#8217;s Solution</strong></p>
<p>Take a leaf out of Germany&#8217;s book and Commence building modern replacements for Britain&#8217;s aging coal fired generation capacity NOW, with whatever heavy industrial capacity we have left. Frack for gas NOW. Get the Americans in to do it if necessary, but don&#8217;t offer our tax money, we pay enough for gas as it is. Just cut the red tape and they will come to work willingly, without subsidy. Re-open any viable coal mines we still have, and start building some new ones.</p>
<p><strong>The Political Situation</strong></p>
<p>It&#8217;s time to encourage the British Government to grow some bollocks and tell the unelected incompetents in Brussels to FUCK OFF.  Then it won&#8217;t be able to use the excuse that the European Large Plant Directive prevents us from solving our URGENT energy crisis in the most time efficient and self reliant way. Repeal the <a href="http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/24/major-uk-newspaper-calls-for-repeal-of-climate-change-act/">Climate Change Act</a> immediately, if not sooner. Use the money the European Union has been embezzling from us without providing audited accounts for the last two decades. Stop giving our tax money to thieves, NOW. If the British establishment doesn&#8217;t heed the warning, it will be brought down by cold, angry people voting for a populist party with no administrative experience. While it would be fun, it&#8217;s unlikely to solve the energy crisis which is upon us. The<a href="http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/22/gerard-wynn-uk-carbon-tax-to-be-levied-from-april-fools-day-get-ready-for-more-fuel-bill-hikes/"> new Carbon Tax</a> is an obvious ploy to steal more money from a cold population and will not be tolerated.</p>
<p><strong>Summary for Policy Makers</strong></p>
<p>Stop dicking around, the eyes of the people are upon you. If you don&#8217;t move fast to fix the mess you&#8217;ve created, their collective boot will be up your collective arse, and since the Labour and Conservative parties are the two cheeks of the same arse, pointing the finger at each other in parliament won&#8217;t appease the taxpayer.  You are our paid servants, not our masters, so shape up, or ship out.</p>
<p>I knew I wouldn&#8217;t be able to keep up the polite language once I started &#8216;the political bit&#8217;, oh well&#8230;</p>
<div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 610px"><img alt="" src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/BGIIN8_CUAENRFb.jpg" width="600" height="399" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Queensbury West Yorkshire this morning. &#8220;Our children aren&#8217;t going to know what snow is&#8221; &#8211; Dr David Viner, Govt climate advisor 2002</p></div>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/11842/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/11842/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=11842&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/24/a-personal-appeal-to-britains-politicians-wake-up-from-your-warm-dreams-fuel-poverty-is-killing-people/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>108</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/588acaa8d65126df21f9f213074b937a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tallbloke</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/tod_kaiser.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tod_kaiser</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/BGIIN8_CUAENRFb.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
