<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2012 20:02:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Daytripping to the Dead Sea</title>
		<link>http://comedytravelwriting.wordpress.com/2012/10/01/daytripping-to-the-dead-sea-with-a-jordanian-and-his-family/</link>
		<comments>http://comedytravelwriting.wordpress.com/2012/10/01/daytripping-to-the-dead-sea-with-a-jordanian-and-his-family/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 15:45:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>ambigram0</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[day trip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dead sea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hostel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jordan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[middle east]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[resort]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://comedytravelwriting.wordpress.com/?p=131</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I was reluctantly forced into a hostel in Amman, Jordan, but I ended up doing a day trip to the Dead Sea with the hostel owner and his family. I say day trip, but Khaled assured me it&#8217;d be best if we left about three in the afternoon. &#8220;Too hot, too hot,&#8221; he told me [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=131&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I was reluctantly forced into a hostel in Amman, Jordan, but I ended up doing a day trip to the Dead Sea with the hostel owner and his family. I say day trip, but Khaled assured me it&#8217;d be best if we left about three in the afternoon. &#8220;Too hot, too hot,&#8221; he told me repeatedly. &#8220;During morning it okay but at 12 it too hot even for us. You pale, you fry like egg.&#8221; The Jordanian hostel owner grinned at me as I sat in the hostel&#8217;s communal area next to the breeze of a fan.</p>
<p>If Khaled hadn&#8217;t been so damnably nice and if he wasn&#8217;t going to drive me to the Dead Sea later, I might&#8217;ve been annoyed. I&#8217;d been in this part of the world for over a month now and I thought my skin was taking on a nice healthy UV-blasted tone. Here&#8217;s a picture of me from Petra the day before:</p>
<p><a href="http://comedytravelwriting.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/hill-at-petra.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-133" title="After Hike to Petra Viewpoint" src="http://comedytravelwriting.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/hill-at-petra.jpg?w=1024&h=663" alt="Looking Over Petra" width="1024" height="663" /></a></p>
<p>If I was pale, that one kid I knew at school must&#8217;ve been Albino 2.0.</p>
<p>I passed the early afternoon wandering the area around the hostel, which was located in the centre of the city. Everything seemed bland now. The market/souq crowds were a nuisance rather than the magical unity of vibrant lives that they had been in Jerusalem and Akko. I just wanted to elbow everyone in the ribs and step on as many toes as I could. And that one guy who smashed right into me in a rush to buy his pastries? I wanted to ram that piece of cake right up his&#8211;</p>
<p>Would you look at that? Nearly three already! I stopped dreaming up ways of murdering these probably lovely Jordanians and headed back to the hostel.</p>
<p>Khaled was on the stairs and babbled to me, &#8220;Come! Come! Hurry!&#8221; so I raced up the stairs, shoved a towel and some swim shorts in my backpack, and headed back out into the heat. Thankfully Khaled&#8217;s car was air-conditioned. It seemed to be the only thing that did work, although the radio did cooperate after a few swift thumps. &#8220;Piece of&#8211; how do you say in English?&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Trash?&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Piece of shit, yes.&#8221;</p>
<p>I shrugged. We drove out of the city to a little suburb. He lived with his family in a really cute neighbourhood, a very &#8220;American dream&#8221; kind of area, if America was middle-eastern and Arabic-speaking. Get your head around that one, rednecks. We changed cars to something a little more functional and practical &#8211; a silver seven-seater Nissan. I turned around in my seat and was surprised to notice two little girls and a wife sitting behind me.</p>
<p>&#8220;Oh, err, hi,&#8221; I said.</p>
<p>&#8220;Hello English,&#8221; the little girls said. The wife just looked at me like I was some kind of museum curiosity, a Roman jug perhaps, or maybe a 5th-century Japanese bowl.</p>
<p>We drove for 20 minutes and then Khaled stopped the car in a two-lane road. He didn&#8217;t pull to one side or anything, just stopped in his lane. He got out and went into the tiny store that was basically a big metal shed by the side of the road. He came back out with a bunch of bananas and a handful of ice creams. He gave us all one of each. No, wait, he gave me an ice cream and two bananas. Quite a number of car horns were blaring behind us but Khaled stood in front of the car and waved happily at everyone.</p>
<p>I should mention here that he wasn&#8217;t taking me along with his family out of the kindness of his heart. No, it was in fact the case that I was paying the petrol money that enabled him to take his family out for the afternoon. Quite a lot of petrol money, I might add, but if it was paying for ice creams for us all I wasn&#8217;t going to begrudge him anything &#8212; a child&#8217;s smile is one of life&#8217;s most beautiful things, particularly if there&#8217;s ice cream all round it. Aww.</p>
<p><a href="http://comedytravelwriting.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/walking-to-the-dead-sea.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-136" title="Walking to the Dead Sea" src="http://comedytravelwriting.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/walking-to-the-dead-sea.jpg?w=1024&h=680" alt="Walking to the Dead Sea" width="1024" height="680" /></a></p>
<p>We got to the Dead Sea resort and I was stung for $16. Jordanians get in for $1 apiece and kids were probably free. It&#8217;s a good system I suppose but not every tourist has money dripping out of their ears  to form large puddles at their feet. I headed in and left Khaled and his family at the swimming pool &#8212; his wife and kids apparently hated the Dead Sea itself. I hopped into the changing rooms and changed into my swim shorts and shoved everything else into my backpack. There were no lockers so I brought the backpack with me. I headed downstairs and out to the Dead Sea. Everyone else hopped, skipped and jumped across the burning hot sand but I&#8217;d wisely kept my shoes on to this point.</p>
<p>I left my socks, shoes and backpack at the water&#8217;s edge &#8212; I&#8217;m a trusting person and I wasn&#8217;t expecting anyone to take a liking to my backpack &#8212; and headed into the murky Dead Sea.</p>
<p><a href="http://comedytravelwriting.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/dead-sea-resort.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-137" title="Dead Sea Resort" src="http://comedytravelwriting.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/dead-sea-resort.jpg?w=1024&h=680" alt="Dead Sea Resort" width="1024" height="680" /></a></p>
<p>Let me tell you, floating in water at the lowest point on earth is neat. It would&#8217;ve been better without the &#8220;holiday resort&#8221; feel to it but access to the Dead Sea is controlled (fenced off in most non-resort locations) and I had no real means of getting here without assistance anyway, so I owed Khaled a lot.</p>
<p><a href="http://comedytravelwriting.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/floating-in-dead-sea.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-138" title="Floating in the Dead Sea" src="http://comedytravelwriting.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/floating-in-dead-sea.jpg?w=1024&h=582" alt="Floating in the Dead Sea" width="1024" height="582" /></a></p>
<p>It&#8217;s hard to explain what the sensation of floating is like. It&#8217;s relaxing, definitely, because you&#8217;re not expending any energy to keep yourself like that. It&#8217;s like lying down on the comfiest couch in the world, one that changes shape to suit you. But despite what that picture might suggest, it&#8217;s not so comfy as to give you a boner (that&#8217;s just air bubbles, I swear).</p>
<p>Floating in the Dead Sea is an experience you&#8217;ll just have to enjoy for yourself, but whatever you do, don&#8217;t get the water in your eyes. It happened to me twice, I&#8217;m not sure how, but goddamn does it sting. Imagine cutting yourself then pouring a spoonful of salt into the open wound, then imagine the wound was in your eye. All right, it&#8217;s not quite that bad, but I couldn&#8217;t open my eye for about 10 minutes after the incident without being in saline agony. It burns, man, it burns.</p>
<p>You can also scoop up the mud at the bottom of the Sea and rub it over yourself for some weird health reasons. I rubbed the thick, sludgy stuff over myself and ended up looking like Bigfoot&#8217;s anorexic cousin.</p>
<p>I stayed in the water a good few hours and then headed up to the pool. I swam for a while and watched the sun set.</p>
<p><a href="http://comedytravelwriting.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/sunset-in-the-pool.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-139" title="Sunset at the Dead Sea" src="http://comedytravelwriting.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/sunset-in-the-pool.jpg?w=1024&h=594" alt="Sunset at a Dead Sea Resort" width="1024" height="594" /></a></p>
<p>Then it was time to go.</p>
<p>The kids fell asleep in the back of the car looking entirely content with everything. They&#8217;d enjoyed a great afternoon out of doing homework or playing in the house. As I watched the Jordanian landscape change from rural back to urban, I remembered day trips out from when I was a kid &#8211; to Wicksteed Park or to the beach or caravanning in Wales watching the rain batter the windows as we played Uno or Monopoly. Me and my brother always fell asleep in the back of the car on the ride home, tired and content. I realised that, despite the language and the country and the climate and a thousand other things, this culture was entirely familiar.</p>
<p>The world isn&#8217;t as big as we think it is.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/131/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/131/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=131&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://comedytravelwriting.wordpress.com/2012/10/01/daytripping-to-the-dead-sea-with-a-jordanian-and-his-family/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>16</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://comedytravelwriting.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/sunset-in-the-pool.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://comedytravelwriting.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/sunset-in-the-pool.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Sunset at the Dead Sea</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/72fe32ae0306c26e48c93b3e4d3c1e03?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ambigram0</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://comedytravelwriting.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/hill-at-petra.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">After Hike to Petra Viewpoint</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://comedytravelwriting.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/walking-to-the-dead-sea.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Walking to the Dead Sea</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://comedytravelwriting.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/dead-sea-resort.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Dead Sea Resort</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://comedytravelwriting.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/floating-in-dead-sea.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Floating in the Dead Sea</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://comedytravelwriting.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/sunset-in-the-pool.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Sunset at the Dead Sea</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Choosing Regular Rejection By the Animal Kingdom</title>
		<link>http://krahnpix.wordpress.com/2012/10/01/choosing-regular-rejection/</link>
		<comments>http://krahnpix.wordpress.com/2012/10/01/choosing-regular-rejection/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 16:11:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>lylekrahn</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[humour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wildlife]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[doe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mule deer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outdoors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Saskatchewan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wild animal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wildlife]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://krahnpix.wordpress.com/?p=1173</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[After considerable self analysis, I have determined that I am neither scary nor obsessed with popularity. Both theories get put to the test regularly while photographing skittish animals. Wildlife may tolerate my presence from a distance but only until I’m almost close enough to take a photo. Then the place clears out like I am [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1173&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After considerable self analysis, I have determined that I am neither scary nor obsessed with popularity. Both theories get put to the test regularly while photographing skittish animals.</p>
<p>Wildlife may tolerate my presence from a distance but only until I’m almost close enough to take a photo. Then the place clears out like I am a skunk that raised its tail. The longer my lens, the sooner this happens. I have no idea how they do all that math so quickly!</p>
<p>I could dress up in camouflage and hide but since I have also determined I am a confident person, I choose regular rejection instead.</p>
<p>I have learned to not take this personally. I just delete many photos of blurry animal butts rapidly leaving the scene. I will confess it gets tiresome watching wildlife flee as if their life depended on it. You would think I was scary!</p>
<p>But every once in awhile, a wild creature will be curious about what I am doing. That’s what happened with these two deer last week. As I walked around to find an unobstructed view, they turned to watch me and struck this interesting pose. In fading light, I had to quickly fire away before the young deer quickly lost interest and turned away.</p>
<p>Now it’s one thing to be wrongly perceived as a threat – it’s quite another to be considered boring. I wonder if there’s a support group for that?</p>
<p><a href="http://krahnpix.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/t6c8813.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-1174" title="_T6C8813" src="http://krahnpix.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/t6c8813.jpg" alt="mule deer, doe, fawn, Saskatchewan, " width="510" height="340" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1173/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1173/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1173&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://krahnpix.wordpress.com/2012/10/01/choosing-regular-rejection/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>26</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/2cbfa6c7a03fb28cdb12704f8a737619?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lylekrahn</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://krahnpix.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/t6c8813.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">_T6C8813</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Four Ways to Stop Mean People By Creeping Them Out</title>
		<link>http://imissyouwheniblink.com/2012/09/25/four-simple-ways-to-freak-out-mean-people/</link>
		<comments>http://imissyouwheniblink.com/2012/09/25/four-simple-ways-to-freak-out-mean-people/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2012 11:26:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>When I Blink</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Socializing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[face tricks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hugging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mean people]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mind games]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://imissyouwheniblink.com/?p=1139</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Let’s tackle an issue everyone has to deal with sometime: Jerks. Whether it’s the guy at work who lords his higher spot on the totem pole over everyone else, or the girl who gossips loudly about other people, or perhaps the meat-head who makes fun of a shy person with a lisp. Assholes are out [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1139&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Let’s tackle an issue everyone has to deal with sometime: Jerks.</p>
<p>Whether it’s the guy at work who lords his higher spot on the totem pole over everyone else, or the girl who gossips loudly about other people, or perhaps the meat-head who makes fun of a shy person with a lisp. Assholes are out there. And they always will be.</p>
<p>It’s best to be prepared.</p>
<p>I don’t like confrontation, so believe you me, I’m not recommending we get up in the face of every jackass who says or does something mean. In fact, the key to these moves isn’t direct conflict at all. It&#8217;s all about understatement. The idea here is to throw the person psychologically off balance with weird, quiet, out-of-context reactions to their bad behavior. Even better, do it in front of a crowd, just to make the meanie extra uncomfortable.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">* * *</p>
<p><strong>1. Shhh…</strong></p>
<p>I just love this one. It’s great for when the person is blithering on arrogantly about their super-high standardized test scores or their naturally smooth hair or their golf prowess or whatever.</p>
<p>And it&#8217;s easy: As the person is droning on about who-cares-what, just gaze into their eyes and mash your finger against their lips and whisper, <em>“shhhhhhhh.”</em></p>
<p>But not in a “shut up” way. In a <em>“please, my dear, say no more, for I can hear the words of your heart even when your lips are not moving,” </em>way<em>.</em></p>
<p>(“But that reaction makes no sense,” you might say. Yes. That’s the point. Assholes don’t like it when they try to goad people into one reaction but get another.)</p>
<div id="attachment_1143" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 490px"><a href="http://imissyouwheniblink.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/slide13.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1143 " title="Dumb and Dumber" src="http://imissyouwheniblink.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/slide13.jpg" alt="Dumb and Dumber" width="480" height="360" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Shhhh&#8230; Say no more. Your words enter my spirit through the air without sound.</p></div>
<p style="text-align:center;">* * *</p>
<p><strong>2. One Slow Tear</strong></p>
<p>This is another good one for when you&#8217;re held hostage by an endless rant.</p>
<p>It’s NOT full-on crying you’re going for here. No quivering lip, no sobs, no sound. In fact, no facial expression at all. Make your face completely blank. You’re a statue, devoid of feeling… THEN! Conjure one single tear and let it spill out of your unblinking eye and roll down your face. Even the most self-absorbed snotmonkey cannot help but be put off guard by your show of strangely emotionless emotion in response to his monologue on why he hates waiters who touch his plate.</p>
<p>This move is absolutely creeptastic, but it does take a lot of facial control. I recommend practicing it in the mirror every morning. You never know when you’ll need it.</p>
<div id="attachment_1144" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 490px"><a href="http://imissyouwheniblink.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/slide2.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1144 " title="Litter is sad." src="http://imissyouwheniblink.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/slide2.jpg" alt="Litter is sad" width="480" height="360" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Remember the Crying Indian? Pretend you&#8217;re him and someone just told you about litter. Channel stone-faced, contained non-rage.</p></div>
<p style="text-align:center;">* * *</p>
<p><strong>3. The Unrelated Question</strong></p>
<p>This is best for when the mean person has just delivered what they believe to be a real zinger. Right when they’re basking in the afterglow of their one-liner and they’re waiting for everyone to high-five them for their cleverness – that’s your moment. Just wait a beat or two, blink a few times, and then pose a total non-sequitur, like this:</p>
<p><em>“I can’t help but wonder… Are the invisible eyeballs of our ancestors watching us from the clouds?”</em></p>
<div id="attachment_1145" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 460px"><a href="http://imissyouwheniblink.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/slide3.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1145   " title="&quot;So, if you're from Africa, why are you white?&quot;" src="http://imissyouwheniblink.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/slide3.jpg" alt="&quot;So, if you're from Africa, why are you white?&quot;" width="450" height="338" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Think Amanda Seyfried&#8217;s character in Mean Girls and how she threw everyone off balance with her spacey questions.</p></div>
<p style="text-align:center;">* * *</p>
<p><strong>4. Unexpected Affection</strong></p>
<p>I’ll give you a money-back guarantee on this one. When it comes to taking the wind out of some bastard&#8217;s sails, this does not fail. Now, it could get you punched. But everything comes with risks.</p>
<p>The best way to time it is to wait until the person says something completely snide and awful to or about someone. The kind of thing that <em>should </em>make everyone around them haul off and slap them across the mouth, but never does, because people like this seem to have a force-field of compliance around them.</p>
<p>You go in for a <span style="text-decoration:underline;">hug</span>.</p>
<p>I recommend leaning in for an extra-long moment of uncomfortable bonding. Again, it&#8217;s dissonance we&#8217;re after here. That person is trying to get a rise out of everyone by acting like a prick. Instead, you’re going to be a freaky, huggy love monster.</p>
<p>Then just step back and maybe stir your drink and start whistling. Look up like nothing just happened. If they start up again, just hug again. Hug and hug and hug.</p>
<div id="attachment_1146" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 490px"><a href="http://imissyouwheniblink.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/slide4.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1146 " title="Talladega Nights: An Allegorical Piece of Cinema for the Ages" src="http://imissyouwheniblink.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/slide4.jpg" alt="Talladega Nights: An Allegorical Piece of Cinema for the Ages" width="480" height="360" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Hug thine enemy.</p></div>
<p>Good luck.</p>
<p>* * *</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">UPDATE: Greetings to new friends who are here from WordPress! It&#8217;s an honor to be featured on <a href="http://wordpress.com/#!/fresh/">Freshly Pressed</a>, and I&#8217;m delighted to make your acquaintance. Won&#8217;t you stick around? Stop by the <a href="http://imissyouwheniblink.com/">main page of I Miss You When I Blink</a>, where you can subscribe by email, join the fun on <a href="https://www.facebook.com/IMissYouWhenIBlink">Facebook</a> &amp; <a href="https://twitter.com/WhenIBlink">Twitter</a>, and check out some more reader favorites. Thank you!</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://imissyouwheniblink.com/category/advice/'>Advice</a>, <a href='http://imissyouwheniblink.com/category/life/'>Life</a>, <a href='http://imissyouwheniblink.com/category/socializing/'>Socializing</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1139/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1139/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1139&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://imissyouwheniblink.com/2012/09/25/four-simple-ways-to-freak-out-mean-people/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>87</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/49866833f4463934328bc8a50fcfeb0d?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">imissyouwheniblink</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://imissyouwheniblink.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/slide13.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Dumb and Dumber</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://imissyouwheniblink.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/slide2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Litter is sad.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://imissyouwheniblink.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/slide3.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">&#34;So, if you&#039;re from Africa, why are you white?&#34;</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://imissyouwheniblink.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/slide4.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Talladega Nights: An Allegorical Piece of Cinema for the Ages</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>My Budget Plan</title>
		<link>http://theneiloffencolumn.wordpress.com/2012/09/30/my-budget-plan/</link>
		<comments>http://theneiloffencolumn.wordpress.com/2012/09/30/my-budget-plan/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2012 13:35:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>theneiloffencolumn</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[budget]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[column]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[political speech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[satire]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://theneiloffencolumn.wordpress.com/?p=402</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[My fellow Americans, the budget plan I am proposing is designed to curb big spending, shore up our finances, reduce our deficit and get rid of robo calls during dinner time. Plus, you can dance to it. This is a fiscal plan that will put us back on an even keel, even if we don’t [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=402&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>My fellow Americans, the budget plan I am proposing is designed to curb big spending, shore up our finances, reduce our deficit and get rid of robo calls during dinner time. Plus, you can dance to it. </p>
<p>This is a fiscal plan that will put us back on an even keel, even if we don’t know what a keel is. While continuing to keep tax rates at a level comparable with taxi rates, it will prevent a shutdown of major opportunities, such as occasionally going to the movies, and even maybe buying the large-size popcorn while we are there. </p>
<p>On the other hand, in the interest of fiscal prudence, we may have to cut back down to the medium-sized popcorn, which nevertheless remains big enough for Belgium.</p>
<p>Let me quickly describe the highlights of my budget plan:</p>
<p>Only buy Breyer’s mint chocolate chip ice cream when it’s a buy-one, get-one free special offer. Unless it’s been a really bad day and the gallon size has been medically prescribed. </p>
<p>Reduce spending on vegetables that didn’t exist when we were kids or have names that sound vaguely foreign. </p>
<p>Cut disaster assistance program by $1,289 because how likely is it that our HVAC will break down again, for the third consecutive year, on the Fourth of July when it’s 103 degrees outside? </p>
<p>Increase spending on products that are gluten-free so we won’t have to spend any more on gluten. </p>
<p>Try to avoid any additional root canal procedures, particularly on holiday weekends.</p>
<p>Don’t go out to dinner at restaurants where the waiter announces his name and explains that he’s here to serve us this evening when, of course, we thought he was talking to us because he was here to serve someone else. </p>
<p>When figuring out the tip at a restaurant, don’t round upwards just because it’s easier to figure out 20 percent than to do 15 percent and have to walk out quickly after paying. </p>
<p>Put in place an 0.6 percent across-the-board decrease for most domestic programs, particularly across-the-board games that have been undisturbed on the top shelf of the downstairs closet since we moved into this house eight years ago.</p>
<p>Add an additional $25 in emergency spending, just in case we once again get tired of having to mow the front lawn and the homeowners’ association conducts a candlelight vigil around our house and forces us to hire the neighbor’s teenage son again and overpay him for the work we should be doing. </p>
<p>Decrease spending in technology sector by 14.9 percent because of inability to effectively use touchpad on new laptop computer and concerns over being the last person in America not on Facebook. </p>
<p>I am convinced that my budget plan, which includes both spending cuts and free cupcakes for anyone who can figure out how many zeroes there are in the national debt, will be the answer. Now we just have to figure out the question. </p>
<div> </div>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/402/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/402/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=402&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://theneiloffencolumn.wordpress.com/2012/09/30/my-budget-plan/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>16</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/84c3b2b53aec5ce9291094ca6be06b88?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">theneiloffencolumn</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Acute Stress Disorder in Beatrix Potter’s Peter Rabbit</title>
		<link>http://petergalenmassey.com/2012/09/30/acute-stress-disorder-in-beatrix-potters-peter-rabbit/</link>
		<comments>http://petergalenmassey.com/2012/09/30/acute-stress-disorder-in-beatrix-potters-peter-rabbit/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2012 15:27:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Peter Galen Massey</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Beatrix Potter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[literature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://petergalenmassey.com/?p=961</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Before Beatrix Potter became the author of children’s books such as The Tale of Peter Rabbit (1902), she was a gifted natural historian and scientist. So it’s not a surprise that Ms. Potter’s illustrations closely resemble the animals on which her characters are based or that she writes unsentimental stories that display a strong understanding [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=961&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://petergalenmassey.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/the-tale-of-peter-rabbit.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-962" title="The Tale of Peter Rabbit by Beatrix Potter" src="http://petergalenmassey.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/the-tale-of-peter-rabbit.jpg?w=224&h=300" alt="The Tale of Peter Rabbit by Beatrix Potter" width="224" height="300" /></a>Before Beatrix Potter became the author of children’s books such as <em>The Tale of Peter Rabbit</em> (1902), she was a gifted natural historian and scientist.</p>
<p>So it’s not a surprise that Ms. Potter’s illustrations closely resemble the animals on which her characters are based or that she writes unsentimental stories that display a strong understanding of human (rather than animal) psychology.</p>
<p>This is certainly the case with Beatrix Potter’s most famous character, Peter Rabbit, whose trauma in Mr. McGregor’s garden is so realistically portrayed that cheeky amateurs with access to the Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders (DSM IV) could diagnose him with Acute Stress Disorder if they liked.</p>
<p>In <em>The Tale of Peter Rabbit</em>, Peter’s mother tells him not to go into Mr. McGregor’s garden because “your father had an accident there; he was put in a pie by Mrs. McGregor.”</p>
<p>This does not deter Peter, who runs straight to the garden and encounters Mr. McGregor. In the subsequent chase, Peter loses his shoes and coat and catches cold while hiding in a watering can. Peter escapes and his mother puts him to bed with a dose of camomile tea.</p>
<p>Trauma is a cause of Acute Stress Disorder, and I think this experience qualifies as a traumatic event according to the DSM-IV because Peter was both “confronted with an event that involved actual or threatened death” and responded with “intense fear [and] helplessness.”</p>
<p>We see the symptoms of Acute Stress Disorder in <em>The Tale of Benjamin Bunny</em>, which picks up Peter’s story the next day.</p>
<p>As the book opens, Peter’s cousin Benjamin finds him “sitting by himself” looking “poorly” and “dressed in a red cotton pocket-handkerchief.”</p>
<p>Benjamin leads his cousin away toward the McGregor’s garden without either agreement or resistance from Peter.</p>
<p>From this description, we can find in Peter (1) an absence of emotional responsiveness and a reduction in awareness of surroundings and (2) anhedonia or lack of interest in activities that used to bring enjoyment, both of which are characteristic of Acute Stress Disorder.</p>
<p><a href="http://petergalenmassey.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/bunny.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-963" title="bunny" src="http://petergalenmassey.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/bunny.jpg?w=226&h=300" alt="The Tale of Benjamin Bunny by Beatrix Potter" width="226" height="300" /></a>Once in the garden, Peter Rabbit displays three more important symptoms: (3) poor concentration, (4) marked symptoms of anxiety, and (5) increased arousal, hypervigilence, and an exaggerated startle response.</p>
<p>There are three instances of poor concentration in the tale. First, Peter falls “down head first” from the pear tree he and Benjamin are using to enter the garden. Peter and Benjamin pick onions as a present for Peter’s mother, but Peter drops half the onions at one point in the tale and drops the others a little later.</p>
<p>Peter is also clearly anxious and hypervigilent during his return visit to Mr. McGregor’s garden. While Benjamin is collecting the onions, Ms. Potter notes “Peter did not seem to be enjoying himself; he kept hearing noises.”</p>
<p>Peter also doesn’t join Benjamin in eating Mr. McGregor’s lettuces either, instead saying that “he should like to go home.” When the two rabbits walk among Mr. McGregor’s flowerpots, frames, and tubs, “Peter heard noises worse than ever, his eyes were as big as lolly-pops!”</p>
<p>It is in this emotional state that Peter and Benjamin are trapped under a basket by one of the McGregor’s cats for five hours. Ms. Potter writes it was “quite dark” and the “smell of onions was fearful” under the basket. Both Peter Rabbit and Benjamin Bunny cry.</p>
<p>The little rabbits are saved by Benjamin’s father, old Mr. Benjamin Bunny, who cuffs and kicks the cat into the greenhouse, then whips both Benjamin and Peter with a switch.</p>
<p>Peter returns home, where his mother forgives him because she “was so glad to see he had found his shoes and coat” and all seems to end well. The last drawing in the story shows Peter folding up the pocket-handkerchief with the help of one of his sisters.</p>
<p>But Peter’s trauma isn’t resolved as much as it is ignored, and the ambiguity of this resolution hangs over the end of the story. I suspect that the effects of Peter’s untreated trauma will linger for years, making it hard for Peter to find stable employment as an adult and perhaps leading to the self-medicating abuse of rabbit tobacco.</p>
<p>Peter Rabbit isn’t the only psychologically realistic character who experiences trauma in Beatrix Potter’s stories. Mr. Jeremy Fisher is nearly eaten by a trout and resolves never to go fishing again. Jemima Puddle-Duck’s eggs are saved from a fox by the collie dog Kep, only to be gobbled up by puppies before Kep can stop them.</p>
<p>Even Mrs. Tittlemouse, who is threatened by no more than a series of unwanted visitors in her sandy house, lives under the constraints imposed by her obsession with cleanliness and order.</p>
<p>Beatrix Potter’s dispassionate examination of life’s menace has earn her books readers for more than one hundred years. I have to ask, however: “Why do we let children read them?”</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/961/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/961/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=961&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://petergalenmassey.com/2012/09/30/acute-stress-disorder-in-beatrix-potters-peter-rabbit/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>45</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/3b6b63a6169e765d860a5705c2d0898c?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">petermassey</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://petergalenmassey.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/the-tale-of-peter-rabbit.jpg?w=224" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The Tale of Peter Rabbit by Beatrix Potter</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://petergalenmassey.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/bunny.jpg?w=226" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bunny</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Levitation Is for L\&#8217;hovers</title>
		<link>http://extrawellrounded.wordpress.com/2012/09/28/levitation/</link>
		<comments>http://extrawellrounded.wordpress.com/2012/09/28/levitation/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2012 19:39:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>extrawellrounded</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Physics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electromagnets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[levitation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[maglev]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[magnetic levitation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[superconductors]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://extrawellrounded.wordpress.com/?p=25</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[When you hear the word levitation, maybe you think of something like this: I’m not saying that’s not real. (But it would not be inaccurate to say that it isn’t not unreal.) Let’s leave magical powers out of this, though. I want to talk about the sort of levitation achieved by science. Humans have found [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=25&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="text-align:center;">When you hear the word levitation, maybe you think of something like this:</span></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Harry_Kellar"><img class="aligncenter" src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/Z7-A4TwgkinhI5Z1kq3wCloj_nKTLbVuKifgyz6kmFXBuAwtdVg2G0mH57AC51cR7a8HAgY0zZxDyKz6DsLj_kLQFEMFO6YwHR4MuYsIxCItgLxo8yfb" alt="" width="238" height="317" /></a></p>
<p>I’m not saying that’s not real. (But it would not be inaccurate to say that it isn’t not unreal.)</p>
<p>Let’s leave magical powers out of this, though. I want to talk about the sort of levitation achieved by science.</p>
<p>Humans have found a handful of ways to force objects to defy gravity, and I’m going to tell you about one: magnetic levitation.</p>
<p>Ever heard of a maglev train? It uses electromagnets to run without touching the tracks, cutting down on friction (allowing for faster starts and stops) and wear-n-tear (theoretically making it less expensive to maintain). In order for this to work, the train has to hover at exactly the right distance from the track: 15 mm. That’s about the width of a woman’s thumb. The downside? No more nostalgic penny-smushing (possibly outweighed by the cool factor of a LEVITATING TRAIN).</p>
<p>Some maglevs actually use electrodynamic levitation, which involves superconducting electromagnets.</p>
<p><em>[SIREN SOUND! SIREN SOUND!]</em></p>
<p>Whoops, sorry&#8230;looks like the Too Many Fancy Scientific Words (TMFSW) alarm just went off. Let’s break this down a bit.</p>
<p><strong>What’s an electromagnet?</strong></p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">It’s a magnet that uses electricity to produce its magnetic field.</p>
<p><strong>What is a superconducting electromagnet?</strong></p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">An uber-strong electromagnet produced by electric current from superconducting wire.</p>
<p><strong>Superconducting wire?</strong></p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">Yeah. It just means the wire, when brought to extremely low temperatures, can carry a bunch more electrical current than regular wires. This allows it to create really strong magnetic fields.</p>
<p>Is everybody good? Can we turn the TMFSW alarm off now?</p>
<p><em>[SILENCE.]</em></p>
<p>Excellent. Now, where was I?</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Ah, yes. Some maglevs use superconducting magnets for levitation and propulsion. You know how when you put two magnets together at the wrong ends, they’ll push apart? A much stronger version of that force is what makes these maglevs hover and go. Here’s a basic view of how that works (remember, opposites attract, so North will push apart from North):<br />
<img class="aligncenter" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/89RU_q6s-01w6zj81IHjD6mi3u52fYxHUJudaLVtrqPe78SrzJnTiP6JdpW_naLCbPNSueAwMjONay2yxWZGYAUjdX5XxY4AQKaAM9Y_2xt4yClcyndi" alt="" width="305" height="183" /></p>
<p>When you think about how heavy a train is, it makes sense that these magnets would have to be outrageously strong to levitate one. Thus, superconducting electromagnets instead of, say, <a title="Magna-Doodle" href="http://images5.fanpop.com/image/photos/30500000/Magna-Doodle-whatever-happened-to-30552018-640-481.jpg" target="_blank">Magna-Doodle</a> dust.</p>
<p>Are you impressed yet?</p>
<p>No?</p>
<p>Fine. Just watch <a title="Quantum Levitation" href="http://www.wired.com/wiredscience/2011/10/quantum-levitation/" target="_blank">this video</a>. If you’re not in awe of levitation after that, we’ll see about resurrecting Kellar for one last show.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/25/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/25/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=25&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://extrawellrounded.wordpress.com/2012/09/28/levitation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>23</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/d902555869afe9601c4e579cf785ae40?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">extrawellrounded</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/Z7-A4TwgkinhI5Z1kq3wCloj_nKTLbVuKifgyz6kmFXBuAwtdVg2G0mH57AC51cR7a8HAgY0zZxDyKz6DsLj_kLQFEMFO6YwHR4MuYsIxCItgLxo8yfb" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/89RU_q6s-01w6zj81IHjD6mi3u52fYxHUJudaLVtrqPe78SrzJnTiP6JdpW_naLCbPNSueAwMjONay2yxWZGYAUjdX5XxY4AQKaAM9Y_2xt4yClcyndi" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Formula and Function: A Critical Lens for Formula in Serial Works</title>
		<link>http://altairandvega.wordpress.com/2012/09/21/formula-and-function-a-critical-lens-for-formula-in-serial-works/</link>
		<comments>http://altairandvega.wordpress.com/2012/09/21/formula-and-function-a-critical-lens-for-formula-in-serial-works/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2012 04:41:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>8C</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Editorials]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Modern Visual Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cartoons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[formula]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gravity falls]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hyouka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[knox's ten commandments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[psychology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[revolutionary girl utena]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scooby doo where are you]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tatami galaxy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yojouhan shinwa taikei]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://altairandvega.wordpress.com/?p=5661</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It is often observed that works of an episodic nature tend to fall into predictable patterns over time. Plot structures, character personalities and so forth tend to develop comfortable, consistent shapes, often called &#8220;formulas&#8221;. Many works, of course, use formula and repetition to a specific end—e.g. in service of a specific thematic goal. Yuasa leverages formula [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=5661&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://www.pixiv.net/member_illust.php?mode=medium&amp;illust_id=29686102"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5857" title="三柳 - 私と明石さん" src="http://altairandvega.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/296861021-e1348286019448.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="240" /></a></p>
<p>It is often observed that works of an episodic nature tend to fall into predictable patterns over time. Plot structures, character personalities and so forth tend to develop comfortable, consistent shapes, often called &#8220;formulas&#8221;. Many works, of course, use formula and repetition to a specific end—e.g. in service of a specific thematic goal. Yuasa leverages formula in <em>The Tatami Galaxy</em> to viscerally drive home the work&#8217;s thesis; <a href="http://gargarstegosaurus.wordpress.com/2009/07/11/empty-movement-recycled-animation-in-utena/" target="_blank">untold</a> <a href="http://www.shamefulotakusecret.com/2009/11/10/the-revolution-will-be-televised-over-and-over-repetition-in-utena/" target="_blank">volumes</a> <a href="http://superfani.com/2012/06/18/utena-v-echo/" target="_blank">have</a> been filled dissecting its use in <em>Revolutionary Girl Utena. </em>But what I mean to discuss here is the function that repetition serves more generally as a narrative, not thematic, device—we arrive at formulas because if something worked once, it&#8217;s likely to work again. Repetition, used carefully, can enhance a work as much as effective photography or musical score.</p>
<p><span id="more-5661"></span></p>
<p>Perhaps the most pervasive example of this in episodic mediums is the opening and ending title sequence. The title sequence is nigh-universal in film and animation, and tends to take a very particular form in animated television series. On a basic, functional level, an average competent opening sequence communicates the content and tone of a work (and the most basic, functional opening sequences <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ibPCLMH1NM4" target="_blank">do little else</a>). But if information were the only intent, opening sequences wouldn&#8217;t need to be nearly so intricate; and, in fact, many excellent title sequences fail to meaningfully communicate much of the &#8220;content&#8221; of a work. This is because the key function of the title sequence is not to communicate <em>information</em>, but <em>instinct</em>.</p>
<p>As Jim Emerson <a href="http://blogs.suntimes.com/scanners/2006/06/movies_101_opening_shots.html" target="_blank">puts it</a>, &#8221;Any good movie teaches you how to watch it.&#8221; The serial work takes this a step further: rather than <em>teaching</em> the viewer, it <em>trains</em> them. This is ideal, given that serial works are (a.) generally shorter than films and so don&#8217;t have the time to instruct the viewer from scratch for each installment, and (b.) made up of many separate, similarly-shaped installments, so any critical tools the work presents once are quite likely to be employed again. Thus, repetition serves a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Classical_conditioning" target="_blank">Pavlovian</a> function: the serial work encodes its key ideas into formulaic elements, and so trains the viewer to understand them, in a sort of emotional shorthand. The recurring title sequence often serves as a &#8220;lexicon&#8221;, re-indexing all of the key elements in the viewer&#8217;s mind. Many of these associations are personal or nostalgic, as explored in A&amp;V&#8217;s earlier <a href="http://altairandvega.wordpress.com/category/that-lingering-feeling/" target="_blank">That Lingering Feeling</a> series.<em><br />
</em></p>
<span style="text-align:center; display: block;"><a href="http://altairandvega.wordpress.com/2012/09/21/formula-and-function-a-critical-lens-for-formula-in-serial-works/"><img src="http://img.youtube.com/vi/tctX771EQeA/2.jpg" alt="" /></a></span>
<p>This is demonstrated excellently in the opening sequence to the animated series <em>Gravity Falls</em>. It contains purely functional elements such as introduction of the setting, characters and so forth, but <em>Gravity Falls</em>&#8216; opening sequence also primes the viewer&#8217;s expectations in remarkably subtle ways. It begins with three ominous establishing shots, with minimal musical accompaniment, before two more lighthearted shots which establish the characters and &#8220;main&#8221; setting. As it continues, the sequence progressively mixes humorous and ominous elements, setting the stage for the series&#8217; precise blend of overt cartoon humor and quietly disconcerting horror. The opening is also riddled with occult and conspiracy theory imagery, contributing to an underlying, perhaps subliminal sense of alienation—a central recurring theme in the work proper.</p>
<p>Moreover, for serial animation in particular, the title sequence has become so fundamental that its formula can be observed not just at the level of a given work but of the medium as a whole. In the same way that a given title sequence trains its viewers to watch a particular show, title sequences in aggregate train us to experience entire cultural bodies of work in a specific way. Anime openings often reuse established <em>clichés</em> because, as <em>clichés</em> do, they make up the most primitive and fundamental media culture training the viewer has.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.pixiv.net/member_illust.php?mode=medium&amp;illust_id=28700365"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-5864" title="iberia - つぼみちゃん" src="http://altairandvega.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/28700365.png?w=300&h=211" alt="" width="300" height="211" /></a></p>
<p>One can apply this same analytic principle to other common formulaic concepts; take, for example, the transformation sequence common to the magical girl genre. The transformation is often as semiotically-dense as a title sequence; its intricacy and length re-focus the viewer&#8217;s attention. This is vital given its location in the script, i.e. the division between <em>girl</em> and <em>magical girl</em>. It acts as a transition both textually in the logic of the work, and subtextually as a means of softening the effect of the quick change in tone. It also develops its own shorthand with the viewer, creating the same sort of Pavlovian response. This is why magical girl anime tend to shorten the transformation sequence in later episodes—the greater pomp and circumstance early on is needed in order to condition the viewer, but once that conditioning has taken hold it can be recalled with less effort.</p>
<p>To abstract a step further, many works are of course formulaic at the story level. Mystery and detective stories, for example, are often formulaic, and also provide a good example of the pragmatic efficiency of formula. The classic cartoon <em>Scooby Doo</em><em>, Where Are You?</em> is well known for its very formulaic format—to the point of frequent parody.  But the series earned its status as a classic because of—not in spite of—its well-designed and extremely satisfying formula. <a href="http://lateralaction.com/articles/be-original/" target="_blank"><em>Scooby Doo</em>&#8216;s obvious is its talent</a>. Training the viewer to expect given story elements to work in predictable ways—settings, mysteries, villains—allows Hanna-Barbera to focus on executing those elements cleverly and enjoyably.</p>
<p>In fact, this correlation of formula and satisfaction is taken to its logical extreme in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Golden_Age_of_Detective_Fiction" target="_blank">Knox&#8217;s Ten Commandments</a>, <a href="http://altairandvega.wordpress.com/2012/07/05/notes-on-hyouka-as-an-exploration-of-detective-fiction-a-database-post/" target="_blank">as discussed here previously in relation to <em>Hyouka</em></a>. Golden-age detective fiction comprised an entire genre of literature explicitly defined by a rigid set of formulas. They are often framed as rules to a <em>game</em>, rather than formulas for writing. In golden age detective fiction, enjoyment is placed explicitly before originality as an artistic priority—and it achieves this through formula.</p>
<p>Formula is of course only a tool, and it can of course be used incorrectly. If a formulaic element fails to be sufficiently elegant or superliminally satisfying , it can distract the viewer from appreciating the formula&#8217;s deeper narrative functions. &#8221;Formula&#8221; in fiction is often maligned, but imprecisely so: the problem is not recurring elements per se—a location is a recurring element, a character is a recurring element—but careless or unengaging use thereof.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5661/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5661/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=5661&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://altairandvega.wordpress.com/2012/09/21/formula-and-function-a-critical-lens-for-formula-in-serial-works/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>27</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/e82ae6f870af55a80984b372585070a2?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">dukexc</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://altairandvega.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/296861021-e1348286019448.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">三柳 - 私と明石さん</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://altairandvega.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/28700365.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">iberia - つぼみちゃん</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Brave Little Knight&#8217;s Final Appearance</title>
		<link>http://anansithepoet.com/2012/09/27/the-brave-little-knights-final-appearance/</link>
		<comments>http://anansithepoet.com/2012/09/27/the-brave-little-knights-final-appearance/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2012 22:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Anansi the Poet</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Poetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fairy tale]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[myth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brave little knight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chaos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[order]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cleanliness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entropy]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://marchsteinman.wordpress.com/?p=835</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The Mundane For sarahpotter Late at night, the roads in the Brave Little Knight&#8217;s room are far from safe. Paved with the broken bones of old toys and potholes the size of mounds of clothes, the streets bespeak a ghost town where the townspeople don&#8217;t drink the water for fear of disease and would rather [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=835&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://marchsteinman.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/20120927-182449.jpg"><img src="http://marchsteinman.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/20120927-182449.jpg" alt="20120927-182449.jpg" class="alignnone size-full" /></a></p>
<p>The Mundane<br />
<em><strong>For</strong></em> <a href="http://sarahpotterwrites.wordpress.com/"><strong>sarahpotter</strong><em></em></a></p>
<p>Late at night, the roads<br />
in the Brave Little Knight&#8217;s room<br />
are far from safe.</p>
<p>Paved with the broken bones of old toys<br />
and potholes the size of mounds of clothes,<br />
the streets bespeak a ghost town<br />
where the townspeople<br />
don&#8217;t drink the water for fear of disease<br />
and would rather eat mousetrap bait<br />
than take a chance on the pavement.</p>
<p>The are some evenings when<br />
dust bunnies roll by<br />
on the empty sidewalks,<br />
but even they do not stay for long;<br />
for the room was claimed by the Gods of Dirt,<br />
and our sire&#8217;s bedchamber is decorated<br />
with the casualties of a battle<br />
waged since before the squire&#8217;s birth:</p>
<p>An unpaired sock breathed his last<br />
ages ago on the mantelpiece,<br />
yet his body remains as a haunting reminder<br />
of a more sanitary time.</p>
<p>There sits an unwanted Christmas gift-<br />
contortionist in the corner of the room-<br />
and a lonely page of a book-never-opened<br />
looms under a mirror.</p>
<p>Little do they know,<br />
the beasts below,<br />
the demons that feast on debris and grow,<br />
those evil imps of entropy unknown will be<br />
beaten clean by the hygienic hero.</p>
<p>Twice a year or so, the knight awakens in his<br />
sleeping quarters to find a room<br />
run by the untidy mafia<br />
and hardly a square inch of floor space<br />
to place his feet upon.</p>
<p>Like always, the errant-child is surprised<br />
to discover that a crime was committed<br />
right under his nose,<br />
and though he should have smelled<br />
that something was off,<br />
the brave boy didn&#8217;t even notice.</p>
<p>Without hesitation,<br />
he takes up his weapon of war:<br />
A trusty vacuum cleaner steed<br />
complete with swiffer attachment.</p>
<p>With the power of Mr. Clean,<br />
Scrubbing bubbles and Bounty combined,<br />
the brave vanquisher of mayhem<br />
sends messmakers running behind piles of laundry.</p>
<p>The disorder demons won&#8217;t<br />
accept defeat easily though,<br />
and even when the Quixote dispatches<br />
his four horsemen of sanitation<br />
into the trenches of clothes,<br />
he comes up empty handed.</p>
<p>This game of smoke and mirrors<br />
between chaos and order<br />
is hardly close to checkmate;<br />
although the fate of all life<br />
is eventual disarray,<br />
at least the brave knight<br />
has kept his bedlam at bay.<br />
At least until next spring.</p>
<p><strong>Edit:</strong> Welcome all you knew folks, so glad you made it! And you came all the way for poetry, braving lag and poor uploading rates; I really appreciate it. </p>
<p>Feel free to wander around, hijack my comments section, or make me feel awesome by thumbs-upping (new word?) anything you fancy! </p>
<p>For more Brave Little Knight, you can click:</p>
<p><strong><a href="http://anansithepoet.com/2012/07/23/the-tale-of-the-brave-little-knight-part-i/">here</a></strong> (Part I)<br />
Or <strong><a href="http://anansithepoet.com/2012/07/24/here-there-be-the-tale-of-the-blk-ii-where-he-comes-face-to-face-with-matilda/">here</a></strong> (Part II)<br />
Or <strong><a href="http://anansithepoet.com/2012/07/26/the-tale-of-the-brave-little-knight-part-iii-where-he-meets-a-tarot-reading/">here</a></strong> (Part III)<br />
Or even <strong><a href="http://anansithepoet.com/2012/08/28/let-down-you-hair-and-chillax-a-bit-the-brave-little-knight-returns/">here</a></strong> (Part IV)</p>
<p>For everything else, you can use the navigation/compass/astrolabe/magic stuff yonder&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;-&gt;;;</p>
<p>Please enjoy, and don&#8217;t hesitate to leave your fingerprint in this little realm of cyberspace.</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://anansithepoet.com/category/poetry/humor-poetry/'>Humor</a>, <a href='http://anansithepoet.com/category/life-2/'>Life</a>, <a href='http://anansithepoet.com/category/poetry/'>Poetry</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/835/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/835/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=835&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://anansithepoet.com/2012/09/27/the-brave-little-knights-final-appearance/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>24</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/b81ac726930fc7f72aa4f1446979d928?s=96&#38;d=&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">marchsteinman</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://marchsteinman.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/20120927-182449.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">20120927-182449.jpg</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>All Is Fair In Love And Free Beats</title>
		<link>http://sampleface.wordpress.com/2012/09/28/all-is-fair-in-love-and-free-beats/</link>
		<comments>http://sampleface.wordpress.com/2012/09/28/all-is-fair-in-love-and-free-beats/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2012 16:40:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>starchildluke</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Electronic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hip Hop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Samples]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[free]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[free beats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://sampleface.wordpress.com/?p=1131</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve decided to give you all a full length post for a change. I hadn&#8217;t planned on writing this but a Twitter event triggered the urge. While on Facebook, I noticed a screengrab of a tweet a person named CaptainNoFreeBeats sent to a fellow producer friend of mine (I&#8217;ve covered his name out of courtesy). You [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1131&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://sampleface.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/free-beats.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1138" title="Free Beats" src="http://sampleface.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/free-beats.png" alt="" width="500" height="278" /></a></p>
<p>I&#8217;ve decided to give you all a full length post for a change. I hadn&#8217;t planned on writing this but a Twitter event triggered the urge. While on Facebook, I noticed a screengrab of a tweet a person named <a href="http://twitter.com/_stopfreebeats">CaptainNoFreeBeats</a> sent to a fellow producer friend of mine (I&#8217;ve covered his name out of courtesy).</p>
<p><a href="http://sampleface.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/tweet1.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1134" title="tweet1" src="http://sampleface.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/tweet1.png" alt="" width="253" height="380" /></a></p>
<p>You can find some more of his drivel <a href="http://storify.com/starchildluke/all-is-fair-in-love-and-free-beats">here</a>. Now, I&#8217;m a producer myself and for the most part, I give beats away for free, whether it be for fans or for rappers I trust. I also sample. Now, I haven&#8217;t got the kind of budget Kanye West has so I can&#8217;t just start putting my music anywhere and everywhere for large sums, hence the &#8220;freeness&#8221;. My main problem with this guy&#8217;s mantra is his ideology that music has always been business and by giving away free beats, this damages business and music. This is <strong>all wrong</strong>. Music <strong>industry</strong> is all about business because it&#8217;s the industry. Music has always been about the culture that creates it, the emotions conveyed through it and because of it. These two things should never be confused but unfortunately they are everyday.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s an ongoing non-battle between making the most money out of your ideas and giving your ideas away for free. The former is thrown in our faces by the successful media-savvy entrepreneurs you see on TV and in the newspapers telling us how THEY weren&#8217;t affected by the recession because they were intelligent enough to know how to avoid it, to &#8220;ride the storm&#8221;. We&#8217;re told this is the way to go if we want to get out of the deep black hole those same money hungry people put us in. On the other side, we have the &#8220;crazy radical new thinkers&#8221; who do this crazy radical new thing where they <em>give their work away for free</em> (or a low cost, because there&#8217;s no such thing as a free lunch). People like Prince, for example, are seen by some as weird and social pariahs and free ideas just add to this media mystique they have created for him. He was once quoted as saying:</p>
<blockquote>
<h2>If you give away an idea, you still own that idea. In fact, giving it away strengthens it. Why do people feel they have to take credit for everything they do? Ego, that’s the only reason.</h2>
</blockquote>
<p>I live by this. Sort of. I admire those who live by it and it works for them. Unfortunately, the industry won&#8217;t allow this unless you, paradoxically, have the money to fall back on should it fail. Most ideas you hear in hip hop tracks these days don&#8217;t come out of thin air; originality in sound is all but dead in places other than the originality in inspiration. How many times have you heard those 9th Wonder snares in a track? Or a full 808 kit used in a trap song? However, nobody is really making the kind of music someone like Flying Lotus puts together. When you give it some thought, a lot of these artists would probably work for free and give their music away if money didn&#8217;t have such a chokehold on their movements, and a lot of them do.</p>
<p>Instead of attacking those who give music away for free and tarring &#8220;good&#8221; and &#8220;bad&#8221; producers with the same brush by doing so, we should question the quality of the poor generic music being giving away for money. Is a free beat really the disease sucking goodness out of music or does Nicki Minaj&#8217;s discography need to be scrutinised? There are plenty more issues within hip hop (and music) such as misogyny and violence before we can give this non-battle some brainpower. Look at the culture and the history and how sampling without the tight pressures of copyright shaped the golden age &#8211; it was all about the love and the message sent out. Now we&#8217;re stuck with illiterate, terrible hashtag rapping, tight zebra-printed legging wearing, money waving, fauxhemian pandering, constantly collaborating rappers asking for beats to &#8220;kill&#8221;. But perhaps that&#8217;s another debate for another day. I&#8217;ll let you know when I&#8217;m free&#8230; or should I add a cost to my time?</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1131/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1131/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1131&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://sampleface.wordpress.com/2012/09/28/all-is-fair-in-love-and-free-beats/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>31</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://sampleface.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/free-beats.png?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://sampleface.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/free-beats.png?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Free Beats</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/d0a4c84475fefa98b060ca88391f6223?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Starchild</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://sampleface.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/free-beats.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Free Beats</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://sampleface.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/tweet1.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tweet1</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>New Experience #38: Family Yoga Class</title>
		<link>http://52brandnew.com/2012/09/27/new-experience-38-family-yoga-class/</link>
		<comments>http://52brandnew.com/2012/09/27/new-experience-38-family-yoga-class/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2012 22:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>52BrandNew</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[The 52 Experiences]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bucket list]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children and yoga]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new experience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parents]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yoga]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://52brandnew.com/?p=1034</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Yoga is one of the ways I like to relax.  Occasionally my kids will see me doing a few yoga poses in the living room and join me for a downward dog or two.  Leah especially loves yoga  and likes to show off her tree pose from time to time. When I saw that one [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1034&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://52brandnew.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/040.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1038" title="Family Yoga Class" src="http://52brandnew.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/040.jpg" alt="New Experience 38 Family Yoga" width="640" height="699" /></a>Yoga is one of the ways I like to relax.  Occasionally my kids will see me doing a few yoga poses in the living room and join me for a downward dog or two.  Leah especially loves yoga  and likes to show off her tree pose from time to time.</p>
<p>When I saw that one of my favorite yoga studios, <a title="Princeton Center for Yoga and Health" href="http://www.princetonyoga.com/">Princeton Center for Health and Yoga</a>, was offering a Family Yoga class as a special event, I knew it would be a great new experience for use to try.</p>
<p>I am so glad we went.  The class far exceeded my expectations.  I thought we&#8217;d do a few animal poses and call it a day, but the class was far more organized and incorporated more of yoga&#8217;s relaxation benefits than I thought it would.</p>
<p>When we entered the studio, the instructor, Loring Nagle, told us to get a mat and a Focus Friend.  I had no idea what a Focus Friend was for, but my kids loved the selection of small stuffed animals.  Luke chose an octopus, and Leah took a frog on a lily pad.</p>
<p><a href="http://52brandnew.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/036.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1040" title="Focus Friend" src="http://52brandnew.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/036.jpg" alt="holding a focus friend" width="640" height="699" /></a>We arranged our mats in a semicircle and started with an introductory song that celebrated each person in the group.  We stretched a bit to warm up and then prepared to do Leah&#8217;s favorite, the tree pose.  Loring told us to place our Focus Friends a few feet in front of us so we could stare at them as we balanced on one foot.  It worked so well that I may need to bring a Focus Friend to the next yoga class I go to on my own!</p>
<p>As the class continued, I was very impressed with the way Loring brought the perfect mix of playfulness and concentration to the class.  I suppose that all yoga classes should bring those two elements, but it is especially important when teaching children.  Bring too much playfulness, and the kids will get silly and have a hard time settling down.  Bring too much concentration, and the class might seem more like work than relaxation.   I need to remember to stay as calm and serene as a yoga instructor in my daily interactions with my children.  They responded so well to Loring&#8217;s style.</p>
<p>Both Luke and Leah had fun during the class.  Luke enjoyed doing Sun Salutations to music.  Leah liked doing the cat/cow stretches and making a forest of trees during the Tree Pose.</p>
<p><a href="http://52brandnew.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/038.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1039" title="child in downward dog pose" src="http://52brandnew.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/038.jpg" alt="family yoga class" width="640" height="699" /></a>I love watching my children in their role as students.  I also had an opportunity to do this when we took a <a title="cooking class" href="http://52brandnew.com/2012/08/30/new-experience-34-cooking-class/">cooking class</a>, and it is interesting to see a side of them I don&#8217;t often get to see.  Luke is a very serious student.  The concentration on his face was visible as he touched every finger to his thumb during a meditation exercise.  Leah aims to please.  She raised her hand every time the instructor asked a question, even if she had no answer.</p>
<p>The class ended the way a traditional yoga class ends, with savasana (also called corpse pose).  We stretched out on our backs on the floor.  Loring instructed us to place our Focus Friend on our bellies and watch it move up and down as we breathed in and out.  She came around to each person and massaged a little lavender-scented lotion on our feet.  Leah turned to me and said, &#8220;That felt SO good!&#8221; Luke also commented on how much he liked the foot massage.</p>
<p>We all left class feeling both relaxed and energized.  I just wish we could take a Family Yoga class more often!</p>
<p><strong>If you enjoyed this article, you&#8217;ll also like:</strong></p>
<p><a title="camden children's garden" href="http://52brandnew.com/2012/08/28/new-experience-33-visited-camden-childrens-garden/">New Experience #33:  Visited Camden Children&#8217;s Garden</a></p>
<p><a title="trading virtual experiences for real ones" href="http://52brandnew.com/2012/07/30/trading-virtual-experiences-for-real-ones/">Trading Virtual Experiences for Real Ones</a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1034/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1034/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1034&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://52brandnew.com/2012/09/27/new-experience-38-family-yoga-class/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>42</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f8e7ea9201686e3d45013db885b06088?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F0.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">52brandnew</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://52brandnew.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/040.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Family Yoga Class</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://52brandnew.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/036.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Focus Friend</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://52brandnew.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/038.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">child in downward dog pose</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>