<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2012 22:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Weighty Matters: Groupon &amp; LivingSocial</title>
		<link>http://hangryhippo.com/2012/11/20/weighty-matters-groupon-livingsocial/</link>
		<comments>http://hangryhippo.com/2012/11/20/weighty-matters-groupon-livingsocial/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2012 18:21:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>hangryhippo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Body Image]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weight Loss]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weighty Matters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beauty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://hangryhippo.com/?p=1543</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;Here&#8217;s to your Health!&#8221; was the subject line of an email that Groupon sent me earlier this month. For those of you completely out of the loop, Groupon and LivingSocial are sites that offer daily deals all over the country (and world, at this point) at restaurants, retailers, and service providers. When they first broke [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1543&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;Here&#8217;s to your Health!&#8221; was the subject line of an email that Groupon sent me earlier this month.</p>
<p>For those of you completely out of the loop, <a href="http://www.groupon.com">Groupon</a> and <a href="http://www.livingsocial.com">LivingSocial </a>are sites that offer daily deals all over the country (and world, at this point) at restaurants, retailers, and service providers. When they first broke a few years ago, I was a little obsessed. With my friends and family, I took advantage of everything from plane flying lessons to spa treatments, trying new restaurants and yoga studios all over the darn place and it was fabulous. Bur recently, due to much less funds in my life, and a sort of &#8220;been there, done that&#8221; attitude (except skydiving&#8230;still open to trying that), I am no longer really that involved in their deals but I still get their daily emails.</p>
<p>So back to that early November email. I was intrigued by the &#8220;Here&#8217;s to your Health!&#8221; slogan, so I clicked on the link. And here is what they were offering in terms of &#8220;health&#8221;: Massage, Electro-Slim Body Sculpting Sessions, Fat Reducing Treatment, Cellulite Reduction Treatments, and Medical Spa Treatments. Ok. So, 3/5 of those are specifically weight-oriented&#8230;and not even &#8220;health&#8221; weight oriented (such as fitness or nutrition classes) but &#8220;image&#8221; weight oriented (&#8220;<a href="http://www.groupon.com/deals/walker-plastic-surgery-4">Surgeon uses Cellulaze laser fiber to liquefy fat pockets in order to smooth cellulite-ridden skin</a>&#8220;). Yes, Groupon does offer plenty of fitness deals and from time to time I see a nutrition oriented deal (such as a juice diet). But, even now, just clicking over to the <a href="http://www.groupon.com/browse/washington-dc?category=health">&#8220;Health&#8221; section of Groupon</a> right now, out of approximately 49 deals, 15 of them are specifically weight related (that&#8217;s almost 1/3) and many of the remaining are botox/face tightening/teeth whitening/injection related.</p>
<div id="attachment_1544" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 450px"><a href="http://hangryhippo.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/groupon-slimming-pool.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1544" title="groupon slimming pool" alt="" src="http://hangryhippo.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/groupon-slimming-pool.jpg?w=590"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Don&#8217;t these people just look so natural and happy after partaking in a &#8220;body slimming&#8221; laser surgery deal from Groupon?</p></div>
<p>Now what&#8217;s the big deal? Cellulite is a problem, right? It&#8217;s something that affects so many of us, so why shouldn&#8217;t we get to save bucks on taking care of it? Well, here&#8217;s the big deal: this is what consumerist America thinks are &#8220;health&#8221; issues that we need taken care of. This is what we are being peddled day to day in our inbox: cellulite? GET RID OF IT! excess fat? LASER IT OFF! don&#8217;t want to work out? USE AN <a href="http://www.groupon.com/deals/change-for-life-wellness-aesthetics-3?pt=aUKvCwTAAAADkKG0tC4x7Z3U6Jx8rhBAN">OBSCURE NONINVASIVE &#8220;BODY SCULPTING&#8221; TREATMENT</a> TO CONTOUR THE BODY WITH NO DOWNTIME! (seriously, I&#8217;ve actually seen signs advertising this exact same procedure on the side of the road in Pennsylvania&#8230;that&#8217;s how legit it is). And so, deeper into our psyche seeps &#8220;You are not good enough how you are. You need to fix every flaw that you have and get a discount while doing it.&#8221; As if dealing with the media bombardment on a regular basis were not enough (explain to me how this <a href="http://www.dlisted.com/topics/victorias-secret">&#8220;fashion&#8221; show </a>is even still in existence, please, and how these models are functioning human beings), now we are bombarded directly in our inboxes with ridiculous and extravagant &#8220;image&#8221; consciousness as purported &#8220;health&#8221; issues. How <em>exactly </em>is this &#8220;health&#8221;? Sure, it could be argued that in order for you to need cellulite treatment in the first place, you must be overweight and therefore unhealthy but&#8230;that&#8217;s simply false. Plenty of <a href="http://www.livestrong.com/article/176747-what-are-the-causes-of-severe-cellulite-in-thin-people/">thin people have cellulite</a>  (even <a href="http://www.savvyspice.com/2011/04/legs-legs-legs-tricks-to-flawless-looking-legs.html">Kate Moss</a>, for goodness sakes!) due to genetics, aging, etc. It&#8217;s a damn fact of life that, just like most other things in existence, can be countered (at least somewhat) by healthy diet and exercise. Or, if you&#8217;re to believe Groupon, spending absurd amounts of hard-earned money (yes, even with the discounts) on obscure laser treatments. By advertising these treatments in their &#8220;health&#8221; section instead of under &#8220;beauty,&#8221; it intentionally makes the consumers feel that we are not taking care of ourselves (not &#8220;being healthy,&#8221; which I hope we all know at this point is a <a href="http://hangryhippo.com/2011/12/09/health-and-inspirationlissa-rankin/">holistic process, involving body, mind, and spirit</a>) if we do not opt to get laser surgery or cellulite treatment. And this is simply misleading and detrimental.</p>
<p>The point is: we cannot escape the constant pressure to look perfect, no matter where we go (if it&#8217;s not enough to see unattainable images of &#8220;beauty&#8221; plastered all over magazine covers at drugstores and newstands, now it&#8217;s coming straight to our inboxes!) but we can choose to ignore it and focus on our own <em>actual</em> health and well-being instead. We can choose to empower ourselves. We can choose to focus our time, energy, and resources on creating an actually healthy lifestyle for ourselves as individuals. Also, please notice that all these deals are specifically oriented towards women&#8230;as usual (yes, I know the picture above features a man, but he is the <em>only </em>one in all the pictures found, and I just loved that he was enjoying the pool next to his newly-lasered lover). As if we don&#8217;t have enough to worry about without stressing out about whether or not we should indulge in a cellulite treatment. Let&#8217;s get real, folks. The more time we are wasting focusing on stupid junk (sidenote: this is literal junkmail to me and may as well go to my spam folder with the likes of, for men, &#8220;enlarge your willie in one night!&#8221;) like this that the for-profit, commercial weightloss industry feeds us, the less we are spending on battling patriarchy and absurd social pressures. The weight loss industry continually uses body image as a hook to get women to spend their money on products or treatments by making us feel negative about ourselves and less than perfect. Don&#8217;t buy into (or buy at all, literally or figuratively) the hype.</p>
<p>(Image courtesy of <a href="groupon.com">Groupon</a>)</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1543/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1543/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1543&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://hangryhippo.com/2012/11/20/weighty-matters-groupon-livingsocial/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/29819bd34b983b14269c621682065aba?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">hangryhippo</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hangryhippo.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/groupon-slimming-pool.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">groupon slimming pool</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>You’ll Get Nothing and Like It.</title>
		<link>http://booksnobbery.wordpress.com/2012/11/20/youll-get-nothing-and-like-it/</link>
		<comments>http://booksnobbery.wordpress.com/2012/11/20/youll-get-nothing-and-like-it/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2012 16:15:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>sj</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dear Santa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holidays]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[letters to santa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parenting]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://booksnobbery.wordpress.com/?p=3959</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Me:  Hey, we should write letters to Santa, shouldn&#8217;t we? 6y/o:  YES!  Here&#8217;s a pen! Me:  No, I meant you should write it. 6y/o:  Santa can&#8217;t read my handwriting.  You write for me, please? Me:  Well, since you said please. Me:  Okay, how do you want to open this?  You can&#8217;t just say &#8220;Bring me [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3959&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://booksnobbery.wordpress.com/2012/11/20/youll-get-nothing-and-like-it/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>57</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/0985dfb8973ec02712669a26dbc87ec3?s=96&#38;d=retro&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">booksnobbery</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://booksnobbery.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/sjxmas.png" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://booksnobbery.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dear_santa_1.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Dear Santa</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://booksnobbery.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dear_santa_2.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Dear Santa 2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://booksnobbery.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dear_santa_3.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Dear Santa 3</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://booksnobbery.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dear_santa_4.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Dear Santa 4</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://booksnobbery.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dear_santa_5.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Dear Santa 5</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://booksnobbery.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dear_santa_6.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Dear_Santa_6</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://booksnobbery.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dear_santa_7.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Dear Santa 7</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://booksnobbery.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dear_santa_8.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Dear Santa 8</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Okay, So I Noticed the Conflict . . .</title>
		<link>http://circlesinthesky.wordpress.com/2012/11/19/okay-so-i-noticed-the-conflict/</link>
		<comments>http://circlesinthesky.wordpress.com/2012/11/19/okay-so-i-noticed-the-conflict/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2012 23:29:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Nora</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://circlesinthesky.wordpress.com/?p=57</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[During my research methods class last Wednesday evening, we received news that Hamas’s military leader, Ahmed Jabari, had been assassinated by an Israeli air strike.   As the conflict between Gaza militants and Israel escalated over the next day, my friends and I decided to move ahead with our weekend plans to go to Jerusalem.  We [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=57&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>During my research methods class last Wednesday evening, we received news that Hamas’s military leader, Ahmed Jabari, had been assassinated by an Israeli air strike.   As the conflict between Gaza militants and Israel escalated over the next day, my friends and I decided to move ahead with our weekend plans to go to Jerusalem.  We reassured ourselves that we would be safe in the center of the country and reminded ourselves that, as all Israelis and Palestinians know, we couldn’t just stop living because of a remote threat.</p>
<p>After Friday afternoon prayers ended in Jerusalem’s Old City, I joined a huge mass of people moving out of Damascus Gate into East Jerusalem to see what kind of demonstration against Israeli action in Gaza might ensue.</p>
<p><a href="http://circlesinthesky.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dsc_0386.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-58" title="DSC_0386" alt="" src="http://circlesinthesky.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dsc_0386.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=685" height="685" width="1024" /></a>I thought some kind of demonstration was in the works because riot police had been loitering outside the Old City for several hours.  Maybe 20 people were chanting, but most people – myself included – were just trying to move away from the demonstrators.   For a few minutes, Palestinians chanted, an IDF surveillance helicopter circled overhead, and Israeli riot police and members of the press observed from a distance.</p>
<p><a href="http://circlesinthesky.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dsc_0407.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-59" title="DSC_0407" alt="" src="http://circlesinthesky.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dsc_0407.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=685" height="685" width="1024" /></a>I have no idea how the violence started.  All it takes is one person to feel physically threatened and shove someone else, and things begin to escalate.  There’s no way I can accurately interpret the actions of either side, so I’ll just stick to what I witnessed as objectively as I can.  Young, unarmed Palestinian men trying to run away from the demonstration were apprehended by police officers in full riot gear (helmets, body armor, batons, guns, sound grenades), usually three or four officers to a protester.</p>
<p><a href="http://circlesinthesky.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dsc_0462.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-60" title="DSC_0462" alt="" src="http://circlesinthesky.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dsc_0462.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=685" height="685" width="1024" /></a>Many of the Palestinian women present got close to these scuffles to yell at the officers, and when they were knocked down, the crowd got angrier.  At one point, a girl a few feet away from me was elbowed in the face by a police officer wrestling with a protester; later, I saw an elderly Palestinian couple get knocked down by a crowd swarming toward a young man being arrested.</p>
<p><a href="http://circlesinthesky.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dsc_0469.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-61" title="DSC_0469" alt="" src="http://circlesinthesky.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dsc_0469.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=685" height="685" width="1024" /></a>By the time the protest quieted down, I had seen probably four or five young men being frog-marched to the nearby jail.</p>
<p>I don’t think the behavior I observed was significantly different from riot police conduct anywhere else in the world, but I wonder about what contributed to the violence.  What would have happened if the riot police officer hadn’t been close enough to the crowd to get shoved – why couldn’t he watch from a distance?  What makes a teenage boy so blindly mad that he charges three or four fully armed soldiers who weren’t directly provoking him?  Why are nearly one hundred Israeli officers in riot gear so paranoid about twenty shouting Palestinians?</p>
<p><a href="http://circlesinthesky.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dsc_0495.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-62" title="DSC_0495" alt="" src="http://circlesinthesky.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dsc_0495.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=685" height="685" width="1024" /></a>(On a more apolitical note, why are all Israeli police horses big, black, and Friesian-y?)</p>
<p>We returned to the Old City a couple hours later to see the Shabbat celebrations begin at the Western Wall.  A few minutes after sundown, we heard Jerusalem’s first air raid sirens since 1970, followed by several explosions in the distance.  (Rumor has it that I shouted some expletives at that point, but I can’t imagine myself ever using foul language).  My friends and I held hands and ran with the crowd of panicked tourists and worshippers to the closest form of shelter, which was a small cave on the opposite side of the plaza from the Western Wall.</p>
<p>We inadvertently picked the cave that was filled with hysterical teenage girls, but I can’t say I was more composed than any of them.  I clung to my friends and thought about what my mom would say if she could see me now, just a few hours after I had promised her there was no way a rocket could reach Jerusalem.  I thought about how completely vulnerable I was, and how the true terror came from having no clue what was going on.  Were there more rockets coming?  Had they been intercepted by Israel’s defense system?  Had they caused any casualties?  Were we in the right kind of shelter?</p>
<p><a href="http://circlesinthesky.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dsc_0592.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-63" title="DSC_0592" alt="" src="http://circlesinthesky.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dsc_0592.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=685" height="685" width="1024" /></a>After a few minutes, everyone in our cave started to dash across the plaza to a more fortified tunnel, and we followed.  We crowded together in the tunnel waiting for information – at this point we learned that a rocket had landed near the Gush Etzion settlement in the West Bank, but there were no casualties.  Totally shaken, we decided to head for Bethlehem, which seemed as safe as anywhere else we could get to on Shabbat after Israeli transportation shuts down.</p>
<p>Our friends in Bethlehem told us that lots of young men were rushing to the Separation Wall to protest the Israeli operation in Gaza.  They were throwing rocks, and the IDF soldiers were responding with tear gas and rubber bullets.  Several times during the two days in Bethlehem, we heard Palestinian ambulances rushing injured protesters to hospitals.  I, however, had had enough of protests for a few days and spent my time in Bethlehem catching up with some dear friends.  If you’re reading this, please take a bit of time from reading news of Gaza and south Israel to learn about protests in the West Bank.  Hundreds have been arrested (including <a title="this" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ccXjtQBspBE" target="_blank">this</a> unconscious young man in Nabi Saleh, who was simultaneously denied medical attention), and many Palestinians have been injured.</p>
<p><a href="http://circlesinthesky.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dsc_0611.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-64" title="DSC_0611" alt="" src="http://circlesinthesky.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dsc_0611.jpg?w=685&#038;h=1024" height="1024" width="685" /></a></p>
<p>(Marian, Kate, Emma and I had quite the bonding experience this weekend).</p>
<p>I am now completely out of rocket distance in Haifa, but still find myself struggling to process my thoughts about this weekend (and now you, reader, have the great joy of watching me try and do it!).</p>
<p>One thing I know is that life is hard in Gaza.  From 2007 until 2010, Gaza was under such a strict blockade that the import of a ridiculous array of goods was forbidden.  It’s true that Israel eased the blockade in 2010, but this has done little to change the very low quality of life in Gaza.  Schools are overcrowded, freedom of movement is severely limited, unemployment is high, no building materials have been allowed in since Operation Cast Lead decimated infrastructure in 2009, and the process of getting permission to leave Gaza for medical treatment continues to be inefficient and deadly.  Israeli civilians and soldiers have the security of advanced military technology – a defense shield that stops nearly all missiles headed for populated areas and fortified shelters stocked with supplies in or near most homes – while Gazan civilians have none of these luxuries.  They are undeniably more vulnerable than their Israeli counterparts.  It&#8217;s hard to see how these conditions that are so closely linked to Israeli policies foster anything but animosity for Israel.</p>
<p>I wouldn’t have written this two months ago, but I do think that Israel has a dilemma here – on a different scale from the difficulties Gazans face just trying to live every day, but a dilemma nonetheless.  The Israeli government has made some peaceful overtures toward Gaza: it withdrew settlers in 2006, and eased its blockade in 2010.  As many Israelis see it, these concessions have been met with more and more rockets being launched into southern Israel.  I think many Israelis feel exasperated – they hate seeing Israel dragged through the mud in the international media, but they don’t know another way for the Israeli government to stop the rockets.  My Israeli friends aren’t warmongers, and they’re legitimately scared for their friends and family who have been called to active duty near the Gaza border.</p>
<p>The conversations I’ve had about these issues since returning to Haifa have been emotional, to say the least. Often, talking about life in Gaza is incorrectly interpreted as a denial that Israel has a right to self-defense. Friends whose political beliefs I respect are blindly re-posting political cartoons that are racist, de-humanizing oversimplifications of a tragic and deeply complex issue.  It is appallingly stupid to suggest that Jews in Kiryat Malachi died because they are Zionist occupiers, or that the four children of the al Dalou family died because their parents didn’t love them enough to move them away from Hamas militants.</p>
<p>Discussing possible alternatives to Jabari’s assassination or the military operation is immediately written off as anti-Israel.  I don’t know the answers – nobody does – but for the life of me, I can’t see how this operation in Gaza is a sustainable form of self-defense for Israel.  Hamas will regroup after this bombardment, it will gain more support from civilians in Gaza and from international actors, and it will strike Israel again.  Laying the framework for future attacks isn’t self-defense, and it endangers civilians in Israel and in Gaza.  I don’t believe all nonviolent options for peace are exhausted, and I don’t accept that the killing of Hamas operatives is ever so imperative that targeting errors resulting in the death of innocent civilians should be tolerated.</p>
<p>Yours in peace/salaam/shalom,</p>
<p>Nora</p>
<p>PS. I have some really smart friends here, and you should check out their blogs for other takes on what happened this weekend and some cool ideas in general: <a title="Lauren" href="http://viewfrommountcarmel.wordpress.com/2012/11/19/fallout/" target="_blank">Lauren</a> and <a title="Aaron" href="http://aheathenintheholyland.blogspot.co.il/2012/11/experiential-learning.html" target="_blank">Aaron</a> were both in Tel Aviv/Jaffa; <a title="Emma" href="http://emmaheidtman.wordpress.com/2012/11/19/all-you-need-is-love-or-a-bomb-shelter/" target="_blank">Emma</a> was with me.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/57/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/57/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=57&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://circlesinthesky.wordpress.com/2012/11/19/okay-so-i-noticed-the-conflict/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>18</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/b464e01c820f3bc474f21235c2ed3b0e?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">norakopping</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://circlesinthesky.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dsc_0386.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0386</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://circlesinthesky.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dsc_0407.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0407</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://circlesinthesky.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dsc_0462.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0462</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://circlesinthesky.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dsc_0469.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0469</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://circlesinthesky.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dsc_0495.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0495</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://circlesinthesky.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dsc_0592.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0592</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://circlesinthesky.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dsc_0611.jpg?w=685" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0611</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rudolph the Red-Nosed Doormat</title>
		<link>http://thethrowdown.wordpress.com/2012/11/19/rudolph-the-red-nosed-doormat/</link>
		<comments>http://thethrowdown.wordpress.com/2012/11/19/rudolph-the-red-nosed-doormat/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2012 20:14:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>JB Maddawg</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Mishmosh Ranting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bullying]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comedy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Musings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reindeer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Santa Claus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[t.v.]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thanksgiving]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thethrowdown.wordpress.com/?p=2507</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[POSTING BY JB MADDAWG If there&#8217;s one universal theme that is central to Rankin/Bass&#8217; 1964 classic children&#8217;s television special, Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer, it&#8217;s conform.  Conform, or be exiled to the harsh gulag of society&#8217;s outer circle, which in this particular case, is an island of freak toys that are ruled over by some kind [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2507&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>POSTING BY JB MADDAWG</p>
<div id="attachment_2508" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 480px"><a href="http://thethrowdown.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/rudolph-red-nosed-reindeer-007.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-2508 alignleft" title="" alt="" src="http://thethrowdown.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/rudolph-red-nosed-reindeer-007.jpg?w=590"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">&#8220;Oh, NOW you need me. Assholes.&#8221;</p></div>
<p>If there&#8217;s one universal theme that is central to Rankin/Bass&#8217; 1964 classic children&#8217;s television special, <em>Rudolph the</em> <em>Red-Nosed Reindeer</em>, it&#8217;s conform.  Conform, or be exiled to the harsh gulag of society&#8217;s outer circle, which in this particular case, is an island of freak toys that are ruled over by some kind of flying lion thing.  Not good.</p>
<p>Obviously the creators of one of the most viewed holiday specials in the history of television didn&#8217;t set out to prove that point, but alas, there it is.  Rudolph is supposed to represent one&#8217;s ability to overcome personal short comings and become useful and productive amongst society.  In short, Rudolph&#8217;s unique gift ends up making him one of the most revered protagonists in history.  Of course, this is all after his father made excuses and attempted to cover up his own unbearable embarrassment of his only son.  Look, when the one and only Santa Claus is getting pissed off at your kid because his nose is a different color, reason goes out the window.</p>
<p>Obviously a show written almost 50 years ago is going to get a bit dated, but as a parent, I think even back then someone would have had the stones to stand up and say, &#8220;you know, maybe we could throttle the &#8216;whole world hates you&#8217; message down a bit&#8221;.  We get it.  Nobody loves Rudolph.  Everyone is united in the global hatred of Rudolph&#8230;that is until a giant abominable snowmonster captures the whole family for dinner.  And Santa Claus has to cancel his Christmas run because he wasn&#8217;t a forward enough thinker to <em>expect a blizzard in December</em>.  Sure, no Christmas presents will irk more than a few folks, Kringle. The reindeer with the off-color nose not looking so bad now, eh?  It all comes back home to Rudolph.  They bullied, ostracised and exiled him right up until everyone up in Christmas town realized he was the only guy with a shred of common sense.   Reminds me of the old saying, &#8220;be careful who you step on as you climb up the ladder, you&#8217;re gonna face the same people on your way back down.&#8221;  Rudolph should have sat his furry ass in the snow and watched as the big, crazy yeti devoured the town.</p>
<p>Obviously, the show is based on the classic song of the same name but all that compares here is the fact that Rudolph wasn&#8217;t allowed to join in any &#8220;reindeer games&#8221; whatever the hell those are.  The whole business of Rudy&#8217;s dad and Santa knocking him was completely an angle of the t.v. show.  Not to mention the reindeer coach that sounds like Don Adams on helium that goes apeshit when he finds out Rudy isn&#8217;t &#8220;normal&#8221;.  Let&#8217;s face it.  The only thing holding the poor guy together is the fact that Clarice, the little girl reindeer,  finds him cute.  Even she&#8217;s got a bit of an attitude, however, telling Rudolph &#8220;I don&#8217;t mind&#8221; in reference to his odd nose.  Well, good to hear his physical affliction won&#8217;t inconvenience you in any way, little girl reindeer.  And your rendition of &#8220;There&#8217;s Always Tomorrow&#8221; is a bit pitchy, just a heads up.</p>
<p>All this may seem like minor nit picking, but the best message for everyone (after cutting through all the bullying) is how Rudolph is only fully accepted by the two friends he makes along his walkabout,  Hermey the elf and Yukon Cornelius. That&#8217;s right, justification comes in the form of a little elf that shirks the whole toy industry to become a dentist, and a guy that hunts the frozen tundra for silver and gold by licking the end of a frozen pick axe.  The guy&#8217;s skin graft bills alone have gotta be astronomical, but I digress.  The two accept Rudolph, unconditionally.  Why?  Because it&#8217;s the heart of a message we can all relate to.  No matter how much of a weirdo we&#8217;re all labled as, everyone in eyesight is just as fucked up as we are.  Let&#8217;s see NBC put that in &#8220;The More You Know&#8221; segment.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s all 51:45 of the Rudolph special, just so I can beat CBS to airing it, which will probably be as soon as Thanksgiving dinner is finished.</p>
<p><span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='640' height='390' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/K5sYJfIYOF8?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span></p>
<br /> Tagged: <a href='http://thethrowdown.wordpress.com/tag/bullying/'>bullying</a>, <a href='http://thethrowdown.wordpress.com/tag/christmas/'>Christmas</a>, <a href='http://thethrowdown.wordpress.com/tag/comedy/'>comedy</a>, <a href='http://thethrowdown.wordpress.com/tag/entertainment/'>entertainment</a>, <a href='http://thethrowdown.wordpress.com/tag/humor/'>humor</a>, <a href='http://thethrowdown.wordpress.com/tag/life/'>life</a>, <a href='http://thethrowdown.wordpress.com/tag/musings/'>Musings</a>, <a href='http://thethrowdown.wordpress.com/tag/reindeer/'>reindeer</a>, <a href='http://thethrowdown.wordpress.com/tag/rudolph-the-red-nosed-reindeer/'>Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer</a>, <a href='http://thethrowdown.wordpress.com/tag/santa-claus/'>Santa Claus</a>, <a href='http://thethrowdown.wordpress.com/tag/tv/'>t.v.</a>, <a href='http://thethrowdown.wordpress.com/tag/television/'>Television</a>, <a href='http://thethrowdown.wordpress.com/tag/thanksgiving/'>Thanksgiving</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2507/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2507/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2507/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2507/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2507/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2507/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2507/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2507/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2507/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2507/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2507/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2507/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2507/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2507/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2507&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thethrowdown.wordpress.com/2012/11/19/rudolph-the-red-nosed-doormat/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>16</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/844ab0abf242e45ef6b37e36790653cf?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F2.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=R" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Maddog</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thethrowdown.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/rudolph-red-nosed-reindeer-007.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Day 318: Haunted by the Magic Mirror</title>
		<link>http://cherylhuffer.com/2012/11/19/day-318-haunted-by-the-magic-mirror/</link>
		<comments>http://cherylhuffer.com/2012/11/19/day-318-haunted-by-the-magic-mirror/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2012 10:31:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>cherylhuffer</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reflection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dreams]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life Experience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opportunity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Motivation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[high school]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Random]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Romper Room]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cherylhuffer.com/?p=4012</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I blame my overly anxious need for acceptance on Romper Room.  Do you know it?  Did you ever watch it?  Romper Room was a syndicated and franchised preschool learning program that was popular in the 1970s.  Before Nick Jr., before Sprout, before Playhouse Disney, we watched Romper Room. The structure of the program was similar [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4012&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://cherylhuffer.com/2012/11/19/day-318-haunted-by-the-magic-mirror/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>42</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/d74db466aa7704296a672a80a6d4030e?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cherylhuffer</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cherylhuffer.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/magic_mirror.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Magic_MIrror</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>GIRLS(?)</title>
		<link>http://yoursarcasticfriend.com/2012/11/19/girls/</link>
		<comments>http://yoursarcasticfriend.com/2012/11/19/girls/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2012 19:20:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Your Sarcastic Friend</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[The Critical Stuff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GIRLS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HBO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lena dunham]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://yoursarcasticfriend.com/?p=484</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#160; I&#8217;m going to suggest something seemingly outrageous: GIRLS isn&#8217;t that great. Hear me out. No one was looking forward to GIRLS more than me. Actually that&#8217;s probably not true (hyperbole strikes again!) but I was definitely looking forward to it. The first few episodes were a delight. Look at these GIRLS in all capitals! They&#8217;re my age! Sometimes they say juvenile regrettable things [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=484&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://memilliken.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/screen-shot-2012-11-19-at-2-08-22-pm.png"><img class="size-medium wp-image-487 aligncenter" title="Screen Shot 2012-11-19 at 2.08.22 PM" alt="" src="http://memilliken.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/screen-shot-2012-11-19-at-2-08-22-pm.png?w=300&#038;h=162" height="162" width="300" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>I&#8217;m going to suggest something seemingly outrageous: <i>GIRLS</i> isn&#8217;t that great.</p>
<p>Hear me out.</p>
<p>No one was looking forward to <i>GIRLS</i> more than me. Actually that&#8217;s probably not true (hyperbole strikes again!) but I was definitely looking forward to it.</p>
<p>The first few episodes were a delight. Look at these <i>GIRLS</i> in all capitals! They&#8217;re my age!<i> </i>Sometimes they say juvenile regrettable things and make mistakes and try to act cool when they&#8217;re really shattering to pieces inside! Hannah has a normal body! They masturbate! I can relate! I can relate to it all!</p>
<p>And then I couldn&#8217;t anymore.</p>
<p>Perhaps I don&#8217;t have enough experience with girls my age even though I am one or maybe in the time I lived in Brooklyn as a 22 year old I missed out on the lifestyle the show depicts. By the fifth episode of <i>GIRLS</i>, I was forced to admit it was nothing more than a <i>Sex and the City </i>wolf in an edgier, younger sheep&#8217;s clothing most likely from Free People.</p>
<p>The show is a great show. It&#8217;s entertaining, it&#8217;s well written, it&#8217;s starkly and sometimes frighteningly honest. It&#8217;s a breath of fresh air. I really just think the title is inaccurate.</p>
<p><i>GIRLS</i> isn&#8217;t girls. It&#8217;s stereotypes of girls, specifically of white girls living their white lives whitily. I don&#8217;t think <i>GIRLS</i> is representative of post-college &#8220;girls&#8221; at all. In fact, as a post-college person with lady parts, I find the title almost insulting. Hannah is 24 years old and she expects her parents to support her living in Brooklyn. She has an emotionally and often sexually abusive boyfriend whom she tolerates for reasons unknown to me (that face!). Marnie, the responsible one, is uptight and filled with anxiety. Shoshanna&#8217;s &#8220;biggest baggage&#8221; is that she&#8217;s a virgin (THE HORROR!) and wait&#8230;did I just hear that &#8220;all adventurous women&#8221; have HPV? Here I pictured adventurous women volunteering at orphanages in western Africa or jumping out of planes. Silly me?</p>
<p>Is that, as Peggy Lee once crooned, all there is? Do we just have <i>GIRLS </i>to represent us as females living in our twenties? We&#8217;re not women, you guys. We&#8217;re girls! We&#8217;re just taller children with hips and tits navigating our twenties &#8220;one mistake at a time.&#8221; We don&#8217;t support ourselves. Responsibility isn&#8217;t fun. We don&#8217;t make decisions based on what would benefit us in our future or what would impact others. Boys our age are either intimidating or unfuckable wimps. Oh, and we live in Brooklyn.</p>
<p>I have often heard Lena Dunham described as <a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=lena+dunham+voice+of+a+generation&amp;rlz=1C1CHFA_enUS484US485&amp;aq=0&amp;oq=lena+dunham+voice+of&amp;sugexp=chrome,mod=5&amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;ie=UTF-8">&#8220;the voice of our generation.&#8221;</a> I hope that&#8217;s not true, because I can say with certainty that she doesn&#8217;t speak for me. To me, the image <i>GIRLS</i> paints of actual girls is a little muddled. I know &#8220;girls&#8221; who help support their families. Girls with children. Girls in the military. Girls who own houses. Girls who <i>build </i>houses. Teachers, girlfriends, mothers, engineers, wives, single girls, artists, volunteers, pilots, daughters, nurses, virgins, sluts (hey, no bad thing to regularly have sex when a girl isn&#8217;t in a relationship), etc., etc., etc.</p>
<p>We aren&#8217;t girls, HBO. We&#8217;re women. I&#8217;m fairly certain we&#8217;ll be navigating our lives &#8220;one mistake at a time&#8221; for the rest of it. Let&#8217;s give <i>GIRLS</i> the credit it deserves as a TV show, but let&#8217;s not forget it doesn&#8217;t necessarily represent all twenty-something females (people with lady parts, if you will).</p>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<p><a href="http://memilliken.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/screen-shot-2012-11-19-at-2-08-39-pm.png"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-490" title="Screen Shot 2012-11-19 at 2.08.39 PM" alt="" src="http://memilliken.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/screen-shot-2012-11-19-at-2-08-39-pm.png?w=300&#038;h=169" height="169" width="300" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Like this post? Check <a href="http://yoursarcasticfriend.com/2011/12/09/hotmess/">this one</a> out.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/484/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/484/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=484&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://yoursarcasticfriend.com/2012/11/19/girls/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>25</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/ec4277ede5b0343a7ffa8c8c68077440?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F2.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">memilliken</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://memilliken.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/screen-shot-2012-11-19-at-2-08-22-pm.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen Shot 2012-11-19 at 2.08.22 PM</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://memilliken.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/screen-shot-2012-11-19-at-2-08-39-pm.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen Shot 2012-11-19 at 2.08.39 PM</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why I Can’t Get Down With Black Friday</title>
		<link>http://fridayschildblog.wordpress.com/2012/11/19/why-i-cant-get-down-with-black-friday/</link>
		<comments>http://fridayschildblog.wordpress.com/2012/11/19/why-i-cant-get-down-with-black-friday/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2012 22:30:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>fridayschildblog</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Living Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Black Friday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[style]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thanksgiving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Xbox]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fridayschildblog.wordpress.com/?p=600</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[For a lot of Americans, Thanksgiving isn&#8217;t so much about the good food and time off of work (hopefully. If not, sorry! I’ve been there). It’s really about the anticipation and build-up to what has become the main event: Black Friday. Listen, if you love Black Friday, cool. If you love standing in long lines with family [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=600&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For a lot of Americans, Thanksgiving isn&#8217;t so much about the good food and time off of work (hopefully. If not, sorry! I’ve been there). It’s really about the anticipation and build-up to what has become the main event: Black Friday.</p>
<p>Listen, if you love Black Friday, cool. If you love standing in long lines with family and friends, trampling down old ladies and biting children for the shiniest Xbox* in the store, and the thrill of feeling like you got a screaming deal, I can respect that.</p>
<p>But I have never, nor do I plan to ever, participate in Black Friday. Here’s why I prefer sleeping off my turkey hangover at home.</p>
<p><span id="more-600"></span></p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://commons.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Kyiv_traffic_jam.JPG" target="_blank"><img class="zemanta-img-inserted zemanta-img-configured" title="Traffic jam on Okipnoj str in Kyiv" alt="Traffic jam on Okipnoj str in Kyiv" src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/5/54/Kyiv_traffic_jam.JPG/300px-Kyiv_traffic_jam.JPG" height="199" width="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Traffic jam (Photo credit: Wikipedia)</p></div>
<p><b>The traffic</b><br />
First of all, I live in a pretty small city. So it’s not a little town, but it’s no Chicago or New York. Generally, the traffic is on a spectrum from no-one-on-the-road to annoying-but-tolerable. But I have made the mistake of venturing out for some groceries on Black Friday before. And even in my small city, traffic is BACKED UP, y’all. I’m talkin’ cars stopped in intersections, further slowing traffic on the cross streets. No available parking spaces at any store, anywhere. Stop and go conditions, even on the side roads. No thank you.</p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://commons.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:DCUSA.Gallery11.BB%26BBlackFriday.Wikipedia.jpg" target="_blank"><img class="zemanta-img-inserted zemanta-img-configured" title="English: DC USA, Bed Bath &amp; Beyond, Black Friday" alt="English: DC USA, Bed Bath &amp; Beyond, Black Friday" src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/7/7d/DCUSA.Gallery11.BB%26BBlackFriday.Wikipedia.jpg/300px-DCUSA.Gallery11.BB%26BBlackFriday.Wikipedia.jpg" height="225" width="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">DC USA, Bed Bath &amp; Beyond, Black Friday (Photo credit: Wikipedia)</p></div>
<p><b>The crowds</b><br />
This one really goes hand-in-hand with the traffic. As noted before, I once ventured out for groceries on Black Friday, reasoning that all the people were going to be in retail stores, not markets, and that no one but me needs groceries the day after Thanksgiving. WRONG. There was no pushing my cart down the aisles. Let me paint a picture for you: old, confused ladies comparing different types of rice in the middle of aisle three; overly taxed mothers wrangling sugared-up toddlers who are running under others’ cart wheels in aisle seven (bless their souls!); that <i>one person</i> who just lifted the wrong tomato in the pile of produce, sending the rest of them tumbling to the floor. No getting around that place whatsoever.<br />
And once I finally obtained whatever it was I was looking for, the line at every. available. register. stretched clear up to Terre Haute (in the words of my favorite Christmas movie narrator).<br />
Why deal with all of that? There’s a reason I didn&#8217;t move to a large city. Crowds aren&#8217;t for me.</p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 126px"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/25965014@N00/4457299109" target="_blank"><img class="zemanta-img-inserted zemanta-img-configured" title="JCPenney" alt="JCPenney" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4005/4457299109_ca5ef8548c_m.jpg" height="240" width="116" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">JCPenney (Photo credit: dklimke)</p></div>
<p><b>The money</b><br />
OK, I realize that some stores do put things on a legitimately good sale on Black Friday. However, most items are not anywhere near as good a bargain as Big Marketing wants you to think they are. USA Today reported <a href="http://usatoday30.usatoday.com/money/industries/retail/2010-11-15-walmart-toys-r-us-black-friday_N.htm">here</a> that “very few customers are actually the beneficiaries of Black Friday deals,” meaning that those awesome “doorbusters” are actually in extremely short supply, and if you don’t get your hands on one (and you probably won’t), you’re not getting a deal at all. And, it’s been proven time and again that the prices on everything else in the store are probably actually higher than at other times of the year.</p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://commons.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Black-friday-walmart-bfcom.jpg" target="_blank"><img class="zemanta-img-inserted zemanta-img-configured" title="Black Friday shoppers at Walmart" alt="Black Friday shoppers at Walmart" src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/5/57/Black-friday-walmart-bfcom.jpg/300px-Black-friday-walmart-bfcom.jpg" height="263" width="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Black Friday shoppers at Walmart (Photo credit: Wikipedia)</p></div>
<p><b>The consumerism</b><br />
I’m just plain old fed up with typical American consumerism. I refuse to buy into the idea that my family needs Christmas presents piled as high as the ceiling, or that we need to buy for everyone in our extended family to express our love for them, or that we need the latest electronics/toys/home decorations/etc. I did buy into that for awhile, and of course I do have wants. But the crazed pushing and shoving (over a tickle-me-Elmo for goodness’ sake) is not okay with me. I won’t add to it or take part in it in any way.</p>
<p>In short, I think that the intent behind Black Friday, which is to buy as much crap as possible, as fast as possible, with as few dollars as possible, is just not for me. I prefer to be careful and thoughtful with my purchases. I prefer to spend money on experiences rather than things. And I prefer to pare my Christmas celebrations down to enjoying my family’s company and a nice meal. So I won’t be participating in Black Friday this year, or any year (probably. I also never say never).</p>
<p>What about you? Do you line up at the mall doors on Black Friday (or Thursday)?</p>
<p><b> </b></p>
<h6>*I just want to note that Microsoft Word recognizes the word “Xbox”. Does that tell you anything about the regard to which we now hold our electronics? Is it beautiful? Is it sad? I don’t know. That is a question for another day, apparently.</h6>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/600/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/600/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=600&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://fridayschildblog.wordpress.com/2012/11/19/why-i-cant-get-down-with-black-friday/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>87</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/2b5fb036d773283fc424cb1210c3f8df?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">fridayschildblog</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/5/54/Kyiv_traffic_jam.JPG/300px-Kyiv_traffic_jam.JPG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Traffic jam on Okipnoj str in Kyiv</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/7/7d/DCUSA.Gallery11.BB%26BBlackFriday.Wikipedia.jpg/300px-DCUSA.Gallery11.BB%26BBlackFriday.Wikipedia.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">English: DC USA, Bed Bath &#38; Beyond, Black Friday</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4005/4457299109_ca5ef8548c_m.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">JCPenney</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/5/57/Black-friday-walmart-bfcom.jpg/300px-Black-friday-walmart-bfcom.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Black Friday shoppers at Walmart</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Single Page</title>
		<link>http://daddysan.wordpress.com/2012/11/15/a-single-page/</link>
		<comments>http://daddysan.wordpress.com/2012/11/15/a-single-page/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2012 04:56:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>daddysan</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tyke]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://daddysan.wordpress.com/?p=1794</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Dearest buddy, Yesterday, after a protracted battle over television rights, you managed to negotiate a one-hour deal for the afternoon. We obliged and retired to our room to read. I came out for a drink of water and was surprised to not hear the usual raucous sounds of Curious George or Yo Gabba Gabba. Instead, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1794&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dearest buddy,</p>
<p>Yesterday, after a protracted battle over television rights, you managed to negotiate a one-hour deal for the afternoon. We obliged and retired to our room to read. I came out for a drink of water and was surprised to not hear the usual raucous sounds of Curious George or Yo Gabba Gabba. Instead, there was silence. A beam of afternoon sunshine streamed in through the window illuminating a small patch of floor where you sat quietly. Reading a book. Whispering each word along your steady and determined progress through the sentence. I remember not paying attention to what the book was about, I was simply transfixed by the sight I&#8217;ve just described. In a few short moments you took me back to some of my childhood&#8217;s happiest memories.</p>
<p>You probably don&#8217;t realize what an important moment this is, for you and for your parents. We started to get you to read words a short while ago. It was gratifying to see you work your way up from letters to sounds to rhyming words. Your grandparents were here when they taught you those. Everyone would be delighted when you&#8217;d shout out the word to the accompanying picture. Cat, mat, rat. But today, is something truly special. You&#8217;ve realized the power these innocuous groups of letters can summon when they become groups of words. Every word a small, yet stable stone that&#8217;s leading you over a marsh of ignorance to the safety of land.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s in books I&#8217;ve found entertainment, solace, learning, discovery and intrigue. And this was even before I turned ten. I devoured books at a rate that alarmed my parents. I remember spending summer vacations at my grandfather&#8217;s place in Mumbai, waking up every morning with the eager anticipation of a trip to the local library. Let me assure you that the library was the closest thing to paradise I&#8217;d ever seen. It was full of musty books, the best kind in my opinion. Withered pages bearing colors of rust and overuse. And behind those wilting spines a treasure of juvenile adventures. The Hardy Boys, Nancy Drew, Agatha Christie (I still love Poirot, by the way), Famous Five. I used to start reading the book on my way back home, bumping into the merciless sea of humanity that is Dadar. Dad would be at the end of his tether by the time we returned. I&#8217;d bring back a book and be done with it by night. This went on for a week until dad decided to check if there was a point to wading through crowds every morning for my books. He picked up a Poirot I&#8217;d acquired that morning, randomly chose a page and asked me questions about the plot. I answered correctly. He was stunned. He never questioned me again and cheerfully accompanied me to the library after that.</p>
<p>Over time, that glorious habit has been replaced by staring at excel sheets and writing concise one-liners in a short span of time for important people with even shorter attention spans. I stare at screens all day and it seems books have kept pace with our robotization, for they too are an integral part of those screens. I stay informed through thousands of words flitting across my screen, neatly organized into 140-character morsels. I educate myself and analyze through longform articles or by reading the musings of some very smart people I&#8217;m privileged to know. But once in a while, I&#8217;ll shut down those screens, settle into bed with a glass of scotch, a reading light and open a book. Not turn it on, or switch it on. Open it.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s how I&#8217;d like you to read your books too. You&#8217;re no stranger to iPhones and iPads and you even asked me what a &#8220;Kindle&#8221; is. It&#8217;s only a matter of time. But there are some things about the books I knew that I want you to know. They are what we aspire to be. Books have a spine, and they give you one. Books are opened, and they do that to your mind. Each turn of a page is a symbolic act of moving onto something new and undiscovered, but never forgetting where you&#8217;ve come from. When you encounter a difficult word, I&#8217;ve taught you to &#8220;break it up&#8221;, so you make a chopping gesture and bring your little hand down on the offender. But it stays there, resolute, challenging you to get through it. Remember, you cannot destroy words, so be careful of what you write and what you allow yourself to read.</p>
<p>A few days ago you came across the word &#8220;comfortable&#8221; and struggled to pronounce it. Eventually you settled on &#8220;confontable&#8221; and asked me what it meant. I told you it meant &#8220;warm and cozy&#8221;. Tonight as I tucked you into bed you kept shuffling around restlessly. When I impatiently queried your motives, you stopped for a second and said you&#8217;re &#8220;trying to get confontable&#8221;. What made me feel very confontable was that you learned that from a book.</p>
<p>I want to share so many books with you. I&#8217;m delighted at the prospect of debating motives, the sanctity of events, the morality of characters in books both of us have read. Like I did when dad handed me a copy of Allen Drury&#8217;s Advise and Consent. For a short while, I fell in love with politics because we debated it. Dad may not remember that conversation, but I do. I look forward to creating many such memories with you.</p>
<p>And so I hope a book always accompanies you wherever you go. Because those thousand miles always begin with a single page.</p>
<p>Love</p>
<p>Dad</p>
<p><em>This post was featured on WordPress&#8217; Freshly Pressed page.</em></p>
<br /> Tagged: <a href='http://daddysan.wordpress.com/tag/books/'>Books</a>, <a href='http://daddysan.wordpress.com/tag/tyke/'>Tyke</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1794/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1794/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1794&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://daddysan.wordpress.com/2012/11/15/a-single-page/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>71</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/7ece2659abff353e64730cd5ab5341c1?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">daddysan</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Desperately Seeking Senses</title>
		<link>http://autisticson.wordpress.com/2012/11/18/desperately-seeking-senses/</link>
		<comments>http://autisticson.wordpress.com/2012/11/18/desperately-seeking-senses/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2012 00:10:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>B's Dad</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[asd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aspergers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[autism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[disability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[special needs]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://autisticson.wordpress.com/?p=1400</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[My number one heart-stopping moment  of the week happened this Sunday. It beats the moment my son almost ran into the road a couple of weeks ago (looking back, I think he would have stopped in time, whether that woman had screamed at him or not). We had a house full of visiting relatives. In [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1400&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://autisticson.wordpress.com/2012/11/18/desperately-seeking-senses/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>35</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/70e4bce77595d85e2cb94cdcfbe64117?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">craigholden</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Fifth Is Two Sine Curves</title>
		<link>http://juststimming.wordpress.com/2012/10/31/a-fifth-is-two-sine-curves/</link>
		<comments>http://juststimming.wordpress.com/2012/10/31/a-fifth-is-two-sine-curves/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 02:02:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Julia</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[autism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[language]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-narrating zoo exhibit]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://juststimming.wordpress.com/?p=131</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[(This post could be seen as a self-narrating zoo-exhibit with bonus spot-the-theory-of-mind. I hope you&#8217;ll take it as a follow-up to The Obsessive Joy Of Autism, as equally about the experiences of visual processing impairments and synesthesia as about ~autism, and as a case study in the inadequacy of traditional verbal language. If I&#8217;d been [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=131&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>(This post could be seen as a self-narrating zoo-exhibit with bonus spot-the-theory-of-mind. I hope you&#8217;ll take it as a follow-up to The Obsessive Joy Of Autism, as equally about the experiences of visual processing impairments and synesthesia as about ~autism, and as a case study in the inadequacy of traditional verbal language. If I&#8217;d been taught earlier that experiences which exist independent of words are still meaningful and sufficient, I never would have had to write this.)</p>
<p>(This whole essay represents a dozen years of heartache, a fractured self-image knit back together, and the entire reason why I will never, ever talk about the instinctive simplicity of video editing.)</p>
<p>(Note: as is typical of my writings, pieces are rarely finished in the same day they are started. The voice lesson I refer to as &#8220;today&#8221; is in reality long past; in fact, due to circumstances regrettably beyond my control, it turned out to be my last. I have been unable to further explore the discovery my voice teacher and I made, and it aches.)</p>
<p>(This entire piece is written in a voice I don&#8217;t very much care for. My apologies.)</p>
<p>(I can either keep apologizing in parentheses for a lifetime, or just tell it to you.)</p>
<p>A fifth is two sine curves, and this is the most beautiful thing.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve had a dozen years of classical musical training, and I&#8217;ve been playing with calculus for about the same amount of time. I don&#8217;t talk about either of these things with much frequency. I don&#8217;t like to sing in front of people, and I have a passionate love affair with math but hated and barely passed my classes in high school. I drink up <a href="http://io9.com/5947852/this-is-a-hexaflexagon-its-about-to-blow-your-mind?fb_action_ids=4695156737637%2C10151465733434097&amp;fb_action_types=og.likes&amp;fb_source=other_multiline&amp;action_object_map=%7B%224695156737637%22%3A114534322033392%2C%2210151465733434097%22%3A114534322033392%7D&amp;action_type_map=%7B%224695156737637%22%3A%22og.likes%22%2C%2210151465733434097%22%3A%22og.likes%22%7D&amp;action_ref_map">geometry videos on youtube</a>, and once a week I go to my voice teacher&#8217;s house and sing for the best hour of the week, and these things are secrets. Very few people know how important music and math are to me, and that&#8217;s been a deliberate choice on my part.</p>
<p>I don&#8217;t talk about the most sacred things, because it&#8217;s the fastest way to destroy them.</p>
<p>I have an intense and embodied relationship with music. Music is a lot like people, and songs are linguistic and therefore social exercises. Music teases and tells and remembers and reflects and transforms and encodes and transmits. I experience music kinesthetically, emotionally, and intimately. It is shattering.</p>
<p>I know a lot about music. I hate talking about it, because the things I know aren&#8217;t the same as the things you know.</p>
<p>My left hand doesn&#8217;t have enough coordination to permit me to play any instruments. I can, and do, sing, and I&#8217;ve spent 12 years learning to do so with surgical precision. I can&#8217;t sight-sing&#8211;I can peel apart the layers of a piece for theory, no problem, but identifying pitch and tempo and dynamic and a note&#8217;s place in the overall piece, and integrating those elements, factoring in timbre and placement, and singing them, in realtime, is simply not possible with my visual processing impairments. I rely on an ear I&#8217;ve spent years training&#8211;if there&#8217;s one other singer, or a pianist accompanying, I can do a passable imitation of first-time sight-singing even pieces I&#8217;ve never heard before. </p>
<p>Ever since I first joined an (auditioned, highly-selective, then-prestigious) youth choir at age eight, I&#8217;ve known that I do music wrong. At first, that took the form of being shamed for moving when I sang&#8211;music shouldn&#8217;t be a physical, embodied, tactile experience. In later years, my inability to process visually rapidly enough to sight-sing, and my difficulty holding a harmony, made rehearsal a living hell. Yet I was never kicked out, because I could still sing circles around 2/3 of the other singers, and it wasn&#8217;t that I couldn&#8217;t harmonize, just that I might sing any one of a range of acceptable harmonies and not necessarily the one I was arbitrarily assigned (or the one the composer had written,) and as long as I didn&#8217;t talk about it, no one knew I couldn&#8217;t sight-sing. (I did, of course, talk about it; lying didn&#8217;t occur to me until later years.) I trained my ear, led the 1st sopranos because the melodic options are necessarily restricted and usually sensical, kept my joy at things I had the wrong words for to myself, and kept singing.</p>
<p>(My life goes on<br />
in endless song<br />
how can I keep from singing?)</p>
<p>It destroyed me. I loved this, I was so good at it, it <em>felt</em> good and right and perfect, and yet any attempts to communicate about this were miserable failures. Singing is the only time I ever feel at home in my body, and yet I felt like a fraud; sure I could learn a new song faster than anyone using only my ear, but I couldn&#8217;t sight-sing. Clearly this was some elaborate hoax I&#8217;d engineered, clearly I didn&#8217;t have any real aptitude, and clearly, my decision not to pursue college or career in music or performance was the only ethical option.</p>
<p>Despite this, despite the guilt and shame and confusion, I&#8217;ve kept going to weekly lessons. It&#8217;s an hour, just me and my teacher and a piano, and as we pull songs apart and test what my throat can do, the songs resonate between my ribs. It is, essentially, an hour of breathing exercises,  so it&#8217;s the most effective therapy I&#8217;ve ever had. And I&#8217;ve kept going, and today, finally, after 12 years, we figured it out.</p>
<p>There were signs. The music teacher at my high school had almost worked it out; he&#8217;d play two notes, and I&#8217;d hear a third, and not every student could. He talked about harmonics and melodic structure; I listened, and adored him, but had trouble talking to him. With my voice teacher, I complained that the standard system of music notation was nonsensical, bearing no correspondence to the way music actually worked, and relied on a flagrant disregard for basic arithmetic. I struggled with the idea that a fourth is supposed to sound &#8220;smaller&#8221; than a fifth, and though I could sing any note back perfectly, I couldn&#8217;t tell you which notes were higher or lower. None of the language used to communicate about music made any kind of sense to me. The spatial metaphors simply would not map. I had my own rich, dynamic, embodied and  visiospatial experience of music, I could feel and see the music <em>move</em>, and sheet music couldn&#8217;t come close.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ll tell you what my teacher and I learned today, but first I need to give away my other secret: math.</p>
<p>My history with mathematics is, if possible, even more tortured and rapturous and bewildering than my relationship with music. As a small child, I was in love with arithmetic; my mental calculation abilities are noted on my earliest evaluations (and dismissed, of course, as splinter skills.) One of my earliest memories is of not being able to explain to a concerned teacher <em>why</em> 2+3=5. &#8220;Because it is,&#8221; I said. &#8220;And it&#8217;s beautiful. It just fits.&#8221; Manipulatives were meaningless for me&#8211;my eyes couldn&#8217;t process them easily, and they didn&#8217;t bear any relation to the ladders and scales of numbers in my head. I simply had to close my eyes, and think of an equation, and I would feel myself swing from number to number, landing effortlessly and securely on the answer. Easier than walking.</p>
<p>(There&#8217;s a hint to the eventual reveal, there.)</p>
<p>While I had some small troubles learning the language for arithmetic (especially for fractions, which are fun and clever enough as pointless rituals but <em>beautiful</em> when you realize that they actually signify multiplication and division, that you are performing meta math,) mathematics was an easy joy. Note, please, that I am talking about the <a href="http://www.maa.org/devlin/LockhartsLament.pdf">art of mathematics</a>, not the drivel and formulas we&#8217;re drilled on in school. Mathematics really <em>is</em> an art, and it&#8217;s inherently playful. It&#8217;s a game of &#8220;what if&#8221; and &#8220;how can I.&#8221; And when I was eight years old (and still now,) what I wanted most to figure out was how I could model, and therefore predict, events in the world around me. In particular, I was fascinated by the rate at which raindrops crossed and accumulated on my car window as my mom drove me to therapy.</p>
<p>So I invented the fundamental theorem of calculus. </p>
<p>I didn&#8217;t know I was doing this at the time, of course. I didn&#8217;t know what algebra was yet; if I&#8217;d heard of calculus, I thought it was about calculators, which I found woefully inefficient. I&#8217;d never heard of Liebnitz, and Newton had only been hit on the head by a terrifying apple, as far as I knew. I didn&#8217;t use the greek alphabet or sigma notation; I didn&#8217;t use any notation at all. I just ran some dimensional transformations in my head, checked my model for accuracy, and had a nice visual to keep myself comforted when my hands needed to be still.</p>
<p>Eight years later, my AP Calculus/Physics class was asked to prove the relationship between derivatives and integrals, and I got up and drew the model, and not a single one of my classmates understood. After a moment of studying what I did, Mr. Morris said, &#8220;spoiler alert, Julia just skipped to the end of the lesson and proved the fundamental theorem of calculus.&#8221;</p>
<p>I can&#8217;t draw it for you now; I lost the image, along with some of my more unusual human-calculator prowess, when my psychiatrist put me on the anti-psych medication regimen that ended in me dropping out of college. But I could then, and before that day, I hadn&#8217;t realized that my classmates couldn&#8217;t see that basic, innate relationship, the reason why calculus is beautiful enough to ache. I didn&#8217;t have the language for it, had never even heard of the fundamental theorem until my teacher told me that was what I&#8217;d done. I&#8217;d just been amusing myself with models and transformations, when I should have been paying attention in class.</p>
<p>See, that&#8217;s the thing. I struggled in math class from Algebra 1 on. I never actually took the AP calculus exam&#8211;Mr. Morris thought I&#8217;d do fine, but since I was technically auditing his class, I didn&#8217;t want to try and sit for it. And this is where the agony comes in.</p>
<p>Much like music, the way I experience and represent mathematics cognitively is fundamentally different from the conventional language we are taught for it. With arithmetic, this difference only really caused difficulty when new terms were being introduced. But 2+3 is always 5, and I had enough innate understanding and motivation to preserver through even the most ridiculous name choices. </p>
<p>This all fell apart when I got to algebra. It&#8217;s not that I lacked understanding&#8211;I&#8217;d been solving for the missing number since I was nine, and the only hardship I&#8217;d had there was, again, in comprehending the linguistic absurdity of mixing letters and numbers and shifting the missing piece to the left side of the equation. As soon as I got over that, I immediately started attempting to teach the game to anyone around me, including my four-year-old sister. Algebra wasn&#8217;t the issue. The way we represented it, modeled it, and talked about it? That was a nightmare.</p>
<p>Graphs on a cartesian plane have a lot of meaning for me&#8211;for another purpose (clue.) They also bear absolutely no relation to the kinesthetic and visual models I see when I craft algebraic equations. Zero. None. And I couldn&#8217;t articulate this in high school, anymore than I could make myself care about pitch or slope whether the equation came in point-slope or some other form. I didn&#8217;t understand why we were talking about graphs at all. It wasn&#8217;t until algebra 2 that someone explained to me that all of our equations were supposed to be models for those lines.</p>
<p>I was enraged.</p>
<p>I still am, thinking about it. What a <em>stupid</em> waste of my time. Who the fuck cared about <em>lines</em>? I wanted to know how to model the age distribution of my peers around me and how it shifted in relation to me as we moved through the grades, how to fit equilateral triangles with a side length of 2in inside a hexagon with 6in sides as efficiently as possible, how to predict prime numbers. Why on <em>earth</em> would I make an equation for a line I couldn&#8217;t even make my hands draw reliably half the time?I wouldn&#8217;t! This possibility had never occurred to me! I had better things to do!</p>
<p>So I didn&#8217;t care about graphs. Later, in college, my math major friend would teach me the theory behind linear algebra in half an hour, and I would concede that graphs were pretty fucking intense, but in high school, all I knew was that I was being asked to humor, to <em>indulge</em> teachers who were never sure if I was a genius or in the wrong class in their fetish with graphs that my eyes, more often than not, couldn&#8217;t even process as a whole.</p>
<p>It did not go well.</p>
<p>There were parts of algebra, of course, that I loved. I enjoyed modeling numeric patterns (&#8220;series,&#8221; I was told, and &#8220;summations,&#8221; I just called it numbers) like 2n + 7, and there were moments when the graphs for these, or for my favorite exponents, lined up with the stacks of numbers I saw in my head, and the graph became, fleetingly, meaningful. (It was argued that graphs themselves were by definition simply visual models of numeric patterns, and therefore should have been my favorite thing. I defy anyone to look at something like THIS</p>
<p><img src="http://ic.pics.livejournal.com/crown_of_weeds/36853894/22795/22795_1000.jpg" alt="graph of 2n + 7"></p>
<p>and honestly tell me that they instinctively see either 2n + 7 or 9, 11, 13, 15, etc. in that.) Systems of equations were a game that made me laugh and resembled the way I&#8217;d play with numbers in my notebook margins when we were supposed to be caring about matrices. Matrices were for our calculators; I was a human calculator, insulted by their existence. </p>
<p>My first three algebra teachers understood none of this. I did well in algebra one, as long as I wasn&#8217;t asked to graph anything; as far as I was concerned, I was doing slightly fancier arithmetic and then humoring Mr. Morris by labeling things as he wished. Algebra 2 was all about graphing though, and it made me want to die&#8211;and now, in an exciting plot twist, the equations had gotten long enough, and the graphs complex enough, that my visual process started undermining me, scrambling letters and transposing numbers and fragmenting graphs, and with it, my grade. But I passed, by the skin of my teeth, and had a brief reprieve in geometry, and then got a better teacher for precalculus who, in the last two weeks of class, realized I had a language processing problem. We stayed after school one day and hacked enough accommodations that I could FINALLY start to use the conventional vocabulary and start training my eyes to read equations like stories again, the way 2+3=5 is, and then graph the story out accordingly. Just in time for the bonus unit on calculus.</p>
<p>I looked at a derivative for the first time, and my models and raindrops and joy came rushing back, and I was in heaven.</p>
<p>Derivatives and integrals made sense because the transformations they undergo are multi-dimensional, just as the ones I assign my models are. But I didn&#8217;t ace calculus. I took an introductory course at Stanford the summer before my senior year of high school and passed on sheer intuition despite missing 1/3 of the classes, but the first few tests I took in my AP class came back with failing grades.</p>
<p>My teacher and I worked it out. It was, as always, a visual processing issue: permitted to solve an equation on a white board, standing up, with more space than I could possibly use, colored markers, writing as large as I needed, and only one problem presented at a time, I could earn 100%. Give me the same test, <em>after I&#8217;d already taken it on the whiteboard,</em> but this time package it as a two-page test on an 8&#215;11 inches sheet of paper, and I&#8217;d get a 40%. </p>
<p>It seemed easy enough to accommodate: let me take my tests on a whiteboard, with my teacher dictating each problem to me one at a time, and I could be the best in the class. The beauty of reasonable accommodation! But it wasn&#8217;t that easy; the teachers were working to contract in protest of their current salary, so my teacher couldn&#8217;t stay after school or come in early to test me. If I&#8217;d had an IEP I would have been protected, but my parents were told that students with IEPs weren&#8217;t permitted to take AP classes. The solution, the administration declared, was that I would audit the class. I could sit in on every class, do every lab and homework, receive no credit, have my motivation and self-esteem destroyed by a year of failing every test but doing any in-class problem on the board perfectly, teach my class the fundamental theorem of calculus but be humiliated every day by my inability to correctly read and copy equations off a sheet of paper, and everybody won.</p>
<p>I don&#8217;t remember much of the class. I was an anxious, humiliated, depressive mess, unable to concentrate, still haunted by graphs. It was a combined calculus/physics class: I loved the modeling, but my language processing made the word problems we were given for physics exhausting. There are bright memories, of course&#8211;drawing out the fundamental theorem, hacking labs, solving problems at the board, practicing integrals with Tommy for fun, tutoring a classmate over Facebook chat for a test that I failed with a record- breaking amount of transcription errors but she got an A+ on. But I hesitate to call myself mathematically inclined now, and that needlessly hellish year is why.</p>
<p>Math and music are some of the most sacred and meaningful things in the world to me. I don&#8217;t talk about them, because that requires a 12-year trauma history and interfacing with a language that treats these two things exactly opposite of how the should be.</p>
<p>(Do you know the secret, yet?)</p>
<p>This is what I learned, at the last music lesson I ever took: I see musical compositions as the graphs I spent years being tortured with perversions of, and I move through numbers like a song.</p>
<p>The spatial metaphors we traditionally use for music (notes are higher or lower; a second is a whole step, a third is two whole steps, etc.) fall apart for me not only because of their flagrant disregard for basic mathematics, but also because my primary concept of music lies in harmonics: in the spaces between tonic and supertonic, in the beats of the frequency of a given pitch, and all the different ways we can stretch and collapse and layer and color them. This is what I see, this is what I hear (and the two are, in this instance, the same,) every time music plays. Sheet music is as pale an imitation of this as a graph of y=3x is of the multiplication table. And yet, the transformations I drag my models through, the process of solving an equation (and I&#8217;ve never been much of one for solving, really; just give me a model and I&#8217;m happy, and maybe that was the problem with algebra all along,) is actually perfectly encapsulated by the language and metaphors musicians use to interpret sheet music.</p>
<p>And I just wish that once, at some point, just <em>once</em> during those long twelve years, someone said to me &#8220;this language isn&#8217;t working for you. Let&#8217;s find a new one.&#8221; Because then I could have told you, at eight years old, before I could even conjugate reliably or deviate from my scripts, that:</p>
<p>this is what C sounds like:</p>
<p><img src="http://ic.pics.livejournal.com/crown_of_weeds/36853894/23721/23721_1000.jpg" alt="sine curve"></p>
<p>this is what G sounds like:</p>
<p><img src="http://ic.pics.livejournal.com/crown_of_weeds/36853894/23214/23214_1000.jpg" alt="sine curve"></p>
<p>this is what a fifth sounds like:</p>
<p><img src="http://ic.pics.livejournal.com/crown_of_weeds/36853894/23445/23445_1000.jpg" alt="two overlapping sine curves"></p>
<p>and this, Mrs. Lowenthall,  is why 2+3=5:</p>
<p><img src="http://ic.pics.livejournal.com/crown_of_weeds/36853894/24051/24051_1000.jpg" alt="sheet music"></p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://juststimming.wordpress.com/category/autism/'>autism</a>, <a href='http://juststimming.wordpress.com/category/language/'>language</a>, <a href='http://juststimming.wordpress.com/category/personal/'>personal</a>, <a href='http://juststimming.wordpress.com/category/self-narrating-zoo-exhibit/'>self-narrating zoo exhibit</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/131/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/131/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=131&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://juststimming.wordpress.com/2012/10/31/a-fifth-is-two-sine-curves/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>37</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/562259612abdb3838fdda54c7f386108?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">juststimming</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ic.pics.livejournal.com/crown_of_weeds/36853894/22795/22795_1000.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">graph of 2n + 7</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ic.pics.livejournal.com/crown_of_weeds/36853894/23721/23721_1000.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sine curve</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ic.pics.livejournal.com/crown_of_weeds/36853894/23214/23214_1000.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sine curve</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ic.pics.livejournal.com/crown_of_weeds/36853894/23445/23445_1000.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">two overlapping sine curves</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ic.pics.livejournal.com/crown_of_weeds/36853894/24051/24051_1000.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sheet music</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>