<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2013 20:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Public Art and the Case of Henry Moore\&#8217;s Outdoor Sculpture</title>
		<link>http://chelseapierce.wordpress.com/2013/02/01/cultural-stewardship-public-art-and-the-case-of-henry-moores-outdoor-sculpture/</link>
		<comments>http://chelseapierce.wordpress.com/2013/02/01/cultural-stewardship-public-art-and-the-case-of-henry-moores-outdoor-sculpture/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 22:09:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>chelseapierce</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[museums]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sculpture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[public art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[london]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UK]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Henry Moore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sale]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[news]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://chelseapierce.wordpress.com/?p=377</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Figure 1. Moore’s Draped Seated Woman. From The Guardian.  A recent article in the Guardian newspaper has raised questions regarding the democratization of art and institutional responsibilities in the stewardship of public cultural patrimony. In regards to public art, it is often difficult who is responsible for its care and maintenance. In light of the [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=377&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone" alt="" src="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2012/11/7/1352318511537/Henry-Moores-sculpture-Dr-008.jpg" width="460" height="276" /></p>
<p>Figure 1. Moore’s <i>Draped Seated Woman</i><i>. </i>From<i> The Guardian. </i></p>
<p>A recent article in the <i>Guardian</i> newspaper has raised questions regarding the democratization of art and institutional responsibilities in the stewardship of public cultural patrimony. In regards to public art, it is often difficult who is responsible for its care and maintenance. In light of the global economic recession, it is clear that the cultural sector is in desperate need of funding. Difficult decisions have been made to maintain budgets such as a London council’s proposal to sell a statue by Henry Moore. What must be determined is how far cultural institutions’ responsibilities extend as stewards of public art, and furthermore, who in the public has the right to lay claim.</p>
<p>In the case of a Henry Moore sculpture, which is located outdoors for public access, many problems have surfaced regarding the future of its care. Arguments have ensued from the council and members of the public over maintaining the statue&#8217;s current location and the artist&#8217;s original intent. This case—while not directly involving a museum—still pertains to museums’ and other cultural institutions’ responsibilities to their public regarding the ownership and care of art, and also demonstrates elitism within the cultural sector. Therefore, I will present the case as follows to serve as a precedent for future dilemmas over selling a piece of long-standing material culture for shortsighted revenue and determine how future cases can be mediated through the multi-vocality of stakeholders.</p>
<p>In summary, this case pertains to an article detailing the potential sale of Henry Moore’s <i>Draped Seated Woman</i><a title="" href="#_ftn1"><b>[1]</b></a><i>,</i> located outdoors within a “socially deprived” area of East London<a title="" href="#_ftn2">[2]</a>. East London Council has proposed the sale of the sculpture after a £100 million cut to their budget. The £20 million estimate for the statue’s worth in consideration with additional savings in maintenance and insurance costs has propelled the council to take such actions. Additionally, the council maintains that the sculpture’s current location makes it susceptible to graffiti and other damage.</p>
<p>However, members of the “cultural elite,”<a title="" href="#_ftn3">[3]</a> such as film director Danny Boyle and Tate Gallery Director Sir Nicholas Serota have made arguments in a letter to the council for the sculpture’s retention with the support of the artist’s daughter, Mary Moore. Boyle and Serota argue that the £20 million estimate is inflated, as the price would be an all-time high for a Moore sculpture. They appraise the sculpture at £5 million, which would not significantly improve the council’s budget. Furthermore, Serota and Boyle contend that the sale of the sculpture contradicts the artist’s original intent, using Mary Moore’s testimony to corroborate such claims. The article describes Moore as a “life-long socialist”<a title="" href="#_ftn4">[4]</a> who accepted a much lower price for his work than collectors would have offered under the agreement that the sculpture would remain in an area of low socio-economic status for the residents’ own enrichment. Mary Moore purports that her father believed in the importance of art in everyday life and would want it to remain in a public space. Boyle proposes a solution for the statue to be moved to an outdoor Olympic Park facility in East London, where the sculpture would remain in sight, thus protecting it from potential damage, yet allowing the work to still be accessible to the public.</p>
<p>In order to mediate these arguments, several factors must be considered such as cultural institutions’ roles in proper stewardship. This involves a discourse on ethics: Is it ethical to sell objects of cultural patrimony for revenue? Furthermore, who has the right to make such decisions? The news article’s description of Boyle and Serota as “cultural elite” raises questions of authority as well as cultural paternalism. Lastly, in concern of ethics, how far do cultural institutions’ adherence to artists’ original intent extend?</p>
<p>Tristram Besterman’s article <i>Museum Ethics</i> provides a workable definition of ethics that can be used in this case study. Besterman states, “ethics is an expression of social responsibility” and explains that “ethics defines the relationship of the museum with people, not with things.”<a title="" href="#_ftn5">[5]</a> Therefore, in this definition, the council’s ethical role is to identify the stakeholders of the sculpture and address each party’s opinions and requests. Obviously, the residents of East London are the primary stakeholders, as the sculpture is a part of their daily lives and is located within their tax-paying district. Secondly, the “cultural elite,” represented by Serota and Boyle, are stakeholders as well. Demonstrated by their public claims, they are concerned parties and have proposed counterarguments and solutions. Also, Mary Moore represents the artist as a stakeholder and upholds what she believes to be her father’s original intention for the sculpture. Lastly, the East London Council is also a stakeholder, as it is the present steward of the sculpture and has been charged with the sculpture’s maintenance and care.</p>
<p>Besterman goes on to explain that within museums, “collections are part of the public realm” and that it is the stewards’ role to ensure that the collections remain accessible to the public.<a title="" href="#_ftn6">[6]</a>  While the Henry Moore sculpture does not exist within a museum, it is part of a collection of public art and monuments. Ian Leith of the Public Monuments and Sculpture Association, a non-profit organization that raises awareness of the value of public art, believes that the Henry Moore sculpture in question belongs to “the greatest national gallery of all—which is outdoors—and it&#8217;s completely undefined.”<a title="" href="#_ftn7">[7]</a> Consequently, these same questions of ethical stewardship within museums apply to the Henry Moore sculpture and should be treated in a similar way.</p>
<p>Clearly, the main issue in this argument is money, or the lack thereof, which is an issue that museums face today. Detailed in a more recent article pertaining to the Henry Moore sale, are other sales of public art in the United Kingdom such as the Bolton Council’s sale of several works of art by artists such as Picasso and John Everett Millais. Gloucester City Council, Newcastle City Council and Leicestershire County Council have also made similar sales of their public art collections.<a title="" href="#_ftn8">[8]</a> Besterman explains how many museums in the United States “trade-up” or sell some of their objects as sources for revenue, but that this practice is frowned upon in the UK.<a title="" href="#_ftn9">[9]</a> Therefore it is interesting to see that the stance on sales for public art differ from sales of museum assets.</p>
<p>I feel the underlying problem here is that public art is not valued in the same way as art within museums is, nor is there a clear steward to advocate for the collection of public art in consideration of the public’s interests. There seems to be a need for a museum-like institution to take charge of public art and manage the collection in an institutional manner. Vera Zolberg’s article <i>An Elite Experience for Everyone </i>explains how museums have to justify their purpose to the public and their need for public funding by providing statistics in attendance.<a title="" href="#_ftn10">[10]</a> How can a collection of public art justify its purpose? By evaluating the stakeholders’ claims to <i>Draped Seated Woman</i>, perhaps the public’s claim to such works and the status of public art can be negotiated and serve in future cases.</p>
<p>Boyle and Serota seem to be arguing for the residents of East London, whose opinions have not been addressed in the articles surrounding this case. As their voices and opinions have not been heard, it is difficult to determine their stance on the sale of the sculpture. Is it ethical for Boyle and Serota, members of the “cultural elite,” to make assumptions for the voiceless residents of East London? Their arguments for the retention of the sculpture imply more than simple altruism. Their stance and positions of authority allude to issues of elitism in museums, a topic that has received much attention in the last 50 years. Stephen Weil explains how museums have portrayed their institutions as “philanthropic,” “charitable,” and “benevolent.” <a title="" href="#_ftn11">[11]</a> These words imply that museums come from higher ground than that of their public and that their role is to extend their knowledge downwards to the masses through actions of “social enterprise”<a title="" href="#_ftn12">[12]</a>. The inferred authority of the museum stems back to the origins of museums and digresses from our topic, yet it is important to keep in mind that museums and by extension museum professionals and other cultural sector leaders maintain a level of authority.</p>
<p>Nonetheless, Boyle and Serota’s arguments maintain the notion that members of the elite can determine what is appropriate for the public. This draws on Zolberg’s discourse on “cultural literacy,” or the summary of Pierre Bourdieu’s ideas that differing groups of people hold different levels of cultural capital. This capital is based on their <i>habitus</i> or cultural baggage, based on socio-political and economic status.<a title="" href="#_ftn13">[13]</a> In short, peoples’ cultural knowledge or appreciation is determined by their social and economic backgrounds. As members of the elite typically hold more cultural capital, it is assumed to be their right and role to determine what is best for those of smaller cultural capital.</p>
<p>Returning to the case at hand, the <i>Guardian</i> article makes clear the site of the sculpture is in a “socially deprived” area.<a title="" href="#_ftn14">[14]</a> Thus, Boyle and Serota argue that the retention of the sculpture’s location is crucial to the residents’ cultural enrichment and appreciation. Mary Moore supplements these claims with her testimony of her father’s agreement on the location as crucial to promoting the democratization of art. But is it the cultural elite or artist’s daughter’s place to make such determinations? The East London Council (ELC) would argue it is not. Speaking more for the residents than Serota and Boyle, the ELC seems to be making difficult decisions for the good of the residents. In identifying their shortage of money, the sale of the sculpture could be perceived as a way to lift the financial burden and perhaps maintain some benefits that would be otherwise cut if the statue stays in place. But the ELC is not just thinking of the money; the council obviously feels that for the residents, the Henry Moore holds no cultural capital, hence the vandalism and thefts of such public monuments. A recent article details the council’s final decision to ignore the advisement of Boyle and Serota and place the sculpture at auction.<a title="" href="#_ftn15">[15]</a> As the fate of this sculpture seems decided, I feel responsible to provide alternative solutions for future propositions.</p>
<p>Returning to my previous thoughts on the perceived lack of value for public art, I feel that some form of a non-profit similar to the Public Monuments and Sculpture Association should take stewardship of the outdoor collection. In doing so, new acquisitions can be thoughtfully assessed with regards to expenses and the sales of public works could be avoided. A more defined budget would also be set in place for the maintenance and protection of the works. Also, a museum-like institution would assumedly adhere to a similar code of ethics, and thus decisions regarding stakeholders can be mediated properly. It is important that the public gets a say in the future of its patrimony, and as museums are shifting their missions more towards public needs, more voices are being heard. Therefore, a non-profit acting as stewards of public art would consider the public’s needs more effectively, and hopefully in the future, public art will be withheld from the budgetary chopping block.</p>
<div>
<hr align="left" size="1" width="33%" />
<div>
<p><a title="" href="#_ftnref1">[1]</a> See Figure 1</p>
<p><a title="" href="#_ftnref2">[2]</a> (Alberge 2012)</p>
</div>
<div>
<p><a title="" href="#_ftnref3">[3]</a> Ibid.</p>
</div>
<div>
<p><a title="" href="#_ftnref4">[4]</a> Ibid.</p>
</div>
<div>
<p><a title="" href="#_ftnref5">[5]</a> (Besterman 2008)</p>
</div>
<div>
<p><a title="" href="#_ftnref6">[6]</a> (Besterman 2008)</p>
</div>
<div>
<p><a title="" href="#_ftnref7">[7]</a> (Alberge 2012)</p>
</div>
<div>
<p><a title="" href="#_ftnref8">[8]</a> (Hill 2012)</p>
</div>
<div>
<p><a title="" href="#_ftnref9">[9]</a> (Besterman 2008)</p>
</div>
<div>
<p><a title="" href="#_ftnref10">[10]</a> (Zolberg 1994)</p>
</div>
<div>
<p><a title="" href="#_ftnref11">[11]</a> (Weil 1999)</p>
</div>
<div>
<p><a title="" href="#_ftnref12">[12]</a> Ibid.</p>
</div>
<div>
<p><a title="" href="#_ftnref13">[13]</a> (Zolberg 1994)</p>
</div>
<div>
<p><a title="" href="#_ftnref14">[14]</a> (Alberge 2012)</p>
</div>
<div>
<p><a title="" href="#_ftnref15">[15]</a> (Hill 2012)</p>
<h1 align="center">Works Cited</h1>
<p>Alberge, Dayla. “Britain&#8217;s Cultural Elite Battles to Halt Sale of Henry Moore Sculpture<i>.</i>” Prod. <i>The Guardian</i>. London, November 3, 2012.</p>
<p>Besterman, Tristram. &#8220;Museum Ethics.&#8221; In <i>A Companion to Museum Studies</i>, by Sharon Macdonald, 431-441. Chichester: Wiley, 2008.</p>
<p>Hill, Amelia. “Henry Moore sculpture Decision Raises Fears for Public Art.&#8221; <i>The Guardian.</i> London, November 7, 2012.</p>
<p>Weil, Stephen. &#8220;From Being About Something to Being for Somebody.&#8221; In <i>Reinventing the Museum</i>, by Gail Anderson, 170-188. Lanham: AltaMira Press, 1999.</p>
<p>Zolberg, Vera. &#8220;An Elite Experience for Everyone.&#8221; In <i>Museum Culture: Histories, Discourses, Spectacles</i>, by D. Sherman and I. Rogoff, 49-63. Minneapolis: University of Minnesota Press, 1994.</p>
</div>
</div>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/377/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/377/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=377&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://chelseapierce.wordpress.com/2013/02/01/cultural-stewardship-public-art-and-the-case-of-henry-moores-outdoor-sculpture/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/30b0c6e2fe30538c9129edef79a71822?s=96&#38;d=identicon" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">chelseapierce</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://static.guim.co.uk/sys-images/Guardian/Pix/pictures/2012/11/7/1352318511537/Henry-Moores-sculpture-Dr-008.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Newspaper Stories Are Too Long, Except When They’re Too Short</title>
		<link>http://stevebuttry.wordpress.com/2013/01/29/newspaper-stories-are-too-long-except-when-theyre-too-short/</link>
		<comments>http://stevebuttry.wordpress.com/2013/01/29/newspaper-stories-are-too-long-except-when-theyre-too-short/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 14:35:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Steve Buttry</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alan Mutter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brady Dennis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gene Weingarten]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Grantland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jim Gannon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joe McGuff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Longreads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York Times]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Roy Wenzl]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Atlantic]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://stevebuttry.wordpress.com/?p=10799</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Alan Mutter makes a point that I&#8217;ve been hearing editors make most of my career: Most newspaper stories are too long. I&#8217;m sure he&#8217;s right. But some newspaper stories are too short. And story length is way down the list of problems facing the newspaper business. I remember when I was at the Des Moines [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=10799&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Alan Mutter makes a point that I&#8217;ve been hearing editors make most of my career: <a title="Most newspaper stories are too long" href="http://newsosaur.blogspot.ca/2013/01/most-newspaper-stories-are-still-too.html">Most newspaper stories are too long</a>.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m sure he&#8217;s right. But some newspaper stories are too short. And story length is way down the list of problems facing the newspaper business.</p>
<p>I remember when I was at the Des Moines Register, <a title="James P. Gannon" href="http://spectator.org/people/james-p-gannon/all">Jim Gannon</a>, who I believe was executive editor at the time, decreed that no story could be longer than he was tall. He was 5&#8217;10&#8243;, as I recall, so a story couldn&#8217;t be longer than 70 inches. 70 inches! Register reporters were writing so long that Gannon&#8217;s idea of introducing some discipline was to limit stories to 70 inches (and newspaper columns were wider then than they are today).<span id="more-10799"></span></p>
<p>When I was at the Kansas City Times, Editor <a title="Joe McGuff" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joe_McGuff">Joe McGuff</a> tried to hold stories to no more than 35 inches. But, he assured us (when President Ronald Reagan was in the news for defying Libyan dictator <a title="Muammar Gaddafi" href="http://topics.nytimes.com/top/reference/timestopics/people/q/muammar_el_qaddafi/index.html?8qa">Muammar Gaddafi</a>&#8216;s &#8220;Line of Death&#8221; in the <a title="Gulf of Sidra" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gulf_of_Sidra">Gulf of Sidra</a>) the limit was not a line of death; reporters could exceed it if they made the case to McGuff and got permission for a particular story.</p>
<p>At various times, editors have restricted jumps from page one, either forbidding them entirely or limiting them to one or two stories a day.</p>
<p>I support Mutter, Gannon, McGuff and lots of editors past and present in their quest to introduce more discipline in journalists&#8217; writing. I freely acknowledge that many of my blog posts run too long, without the limited space of print and without editors to help me trim an extraneous word here and a redundant paragraph there.</p>
<p>But frankly, the problem and the challenge (whether in my blog or in a newspaper or on a news website) is not how long the story is, but whether it&#8217;s worth the length. I can&#8217;t recall ever getting more reader response than I did from two stories that were 70 inches (about the <a title="Lessons in narrative journalism from the rescue of the twins" href="http://stevebuttry.wordpress.com/2011/01/17/lessons-in-narrative-journalism-from-the-rescue-of-the-twins/">rescue of twins who nearly froze</a>) and 200 inches long (about <a title="The Homecoming" href="http://www.scribd.com/doc/57824432/The-Homecoming">four people</a> in a <a title="The Homecoming" href="http://stevebuttry.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/homecoming.jpg">famous photograph of a World War II homecoming</a>). Those stories didn&#8217;t work because readers want long stories. They connected with readers because they were two of the best stories of my career and people enjoy reading <em>good </em>stories however long they are.</p>
<p>Good stories don&#8217;t have to be long. I&#8217;m not sure either the twins story or the homecoming story were as good as <a title="Roy Wenzl" href="http://www.goodreads.com/author/show/518382.Roy_Wenzl">Roy Wenzl</a>&#8216;s <a title="Baby's birth broke the speed limit" href="http://www.niemanstoryboard.org/2005/04/21/babys-birth-broke-the-speed-limit/">mystery child story</a> or <a title="Brady Dennis" href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/brady-dennis/2011/02/25/ABMgsCJ_page.html">Brady Dennis</a>&#8216; &#8220;<a title="After the sky fell" href="http://www.sptimes.com/2005/01/28/Tampabay/After_the_sky_fell.shtml">After the sky fell</a>&#8221; story, neither of which would top 20 inches in most newspapers. The length of a story isn&#8217;t what matters; it&#8217;s how well the story connects with readers.</p>
<p><a title="Longreads" href="http://longreads.com/">Longreads</a> and <a title="Grantland" href="http://www.grantland.com/">Grantland</a> are carving out their digital niches based on their faith in people&#8217;s interest in long, well-written stories. <a title="The Atlantic" href="http://www.theatlantic.com/">The Atlantic</a> doesn&#8217;t shy from presenting long stories that are worth the time to read. I&#8217;m confident that journalists and news organizations will continue writing good, long stories at the same time as newspapers fill their precious dwindling space with too many long stories that don&#8217;t merit the space.</p>
<p>I absolutely support Mutter&#8217;s call to tell stories with tables, charts, infographics and other tools when those are more appropriate storytelling tools than strings of paragraphs. The New York Times <a title="Snowfall" href="http://www.nytimes.com/projects/2012/snow-fall">Snowfall</a> project engaged readers successfully by using words and multimedia tools effectively. So did Gene Weingarten&#8217;s Pulitzer Prize-winning <a title="Pearls Before Breakfast" href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-dyn/content/article/2007/04/04/AR2007040401721.html">Pearls Before Breakfast</a>, which deftly inserted video clips into the text of a long narrative.</p>
<p>We have lots of data about how well stories connect. We know which stories readers are most likely to share with their friends and which they read for long times and which they skim quickly. We should learn from that data and try to write the types of stories that people are going to want to read and share. That&#8217;s way more important than worrying about how long or short a story is.</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://stevebuttry.wordpress.com/category/writing-2/'>Writing</a> Tagged: <a href='http://stevebuttry.wordpress.com/tag/alan-mutter/'>Alan Mutter</a>, <a href='http://stevebuttry.wordpress.com/tag/brady-dennis/'>Brady Dennis</a>, <a href='http://stevebuttry.wordpress.com/tag/gene-weingarten/'>Gene Weingarten</a>, <a href='http://stevebuttry.wordpress.com/tag/grantland/'>Grantland</a>, <a href='http://stevebuttry.wordpress.com/tag/jim-gannon/'>Jim Gannon</a>, <a href='http://stevebuttry.wordpress.com/tag/joe-mcguff/'>Joe McGuff</a>, <a href='http://stevebuttry.wordpress.com/tag/longreads/'>Longreads</a>, <a href='http://stevebuttry.wordpress.com/tag/new-york-times/'>New York Times</a>, <a href='http://stevebuttry.wordpress.com/tag/roy-wenzl/'>Roy Wenzl</a>, <a href='http://stevebuttry.wordpress.com/tag/the-atlantic/'>The Atlantic</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/10799/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/10799/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=10799&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://stevebuttry.wordpress.com/2013/01/29/newspaper-stories-are-too-long-except-when-theyre-too-short/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
		<georss:point>0.000000 0.000000</georss:point>
		<geo:lat>0.000000</geo:lat>
		<geo:long>0.000000</geo:long>
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/103c45b1efe7ffb01b96e614207363b0?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">stevebuttry</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily: Where&#8217;s the Crit?</title>
		<link>http://lettersfromyonder.com/2013/02/01/daily-wheres-the-crit/</link>
		<comments>http://lettersfromyonder.com/2013/02/01/daily-wheres-the-crit/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 19:35:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>J. E. Sherwood</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Daily]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aaron Swartz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Arts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christopher Hitchens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Colleges and Universities]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Criticism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Essay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[JSTOR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[literary journals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Literature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York Times]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Obama Campaign]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Open Access]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://lettersfromyonder.com/?p=502</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Crit, as in critical essay. Or, should I say, The Critical Essay (as if t&#8217;were royalty)? The answer is, they&#8217;re out there in abundance. On the one hand we have their inbred cousins the &#8220;Review,&#8221; and on the other, more rarely, we have the in-depth &#8220;Feature.&#8221; But both of these are like satellites to the proper planet [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=502&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://lettersfromyonder.com/2013/02/01/daily-wheres-the-crit/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://lettersfromyonder.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/the-critic.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://lettersfromyonder.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/the-critic.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">the-critic</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/ae2462292598e0c7fbbad6becf6caa50?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sher2669</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://www.academicsciences.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/How-to-write-a-critical-essay.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://graphics8.nytimes.com/images/2013/01/13/us/SWARTZ/SWARTZ-articleLarge.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://www.openlibhums.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/Tower-of-Books.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://lettersfromyonder.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/obama_yes_we_can.jpg?w=230" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Transcendence and the Limits of Science</title>
		<link>http://acculturated.com/2013/01/03/transcendence-and-the-limits-of-science/</link>
		<comments>http://acculturated.com/2013/01/03/transcendence-and-the-limits-of-science/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2013 14:05:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Emily Esfahani Smith</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Emily Esfahani Smith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[acculturated]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[atheism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emily esfahani smith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[god]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life of pi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oliver sacks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pop culture blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pop science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[richard gunderman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transcendence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virtues]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://acculturated.com/?p=6664</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[by Emily Esfahani Smith Religion, God, transcendence, spirituality: do these things exist independently of the human mind or are they products of neurochemical firings of the brain? When Saul had his revelatory experience on the road to Damascus, had he fallen under the spell of a seizure, as some have claimed, or was it a [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=6664&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>by Emily Esfahani Smith</em></p>
<p><a href="http://acculturated.com/2013/01/03/transcendence-and-the-limits-of-science/oliver-sacks/" rel="attachment wp-att-6668"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-6668" alt="Oliver Sacks" src="http://acculturated.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/oliver-sacks.jpg?w=300&#038;h=295" width="300" height="295" /></a></p>
<p>Religion, God, transcendence, spirituality: do these things exist independently of the human mind or are they products of neurochemical firings of the brain? When Saul had his revelatory experience on the road to Damascus, had he fallen under the spell of a seizure, as <a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/uknews/1427916/St-Paul-converted-by-epileptic-fit-suggests-BBC.html" target="_blank">some</a> have claimed, or was it a flash of the divine that caused his conversion to Christianity? When Fyodor Dostoevsky experienced the self-transcendent moment he describes below, was he momentarily elevated into a mysterious mystical realm or was he having a fit of temporal lobe epilepsy?</p>
<blockquote><p>The air was filled with a big noise and I tried to move. I felt the heaven was going down upon the earth and that it engulfed me. I have really touched God. He came into me myself, yes God exists, I cried, and I don&#8217;t remember anything else. You all, healthy people . . . can&#8217;t imagine the happiness which we epileptics feel during the second before our fit . . . I don&#8217;t know if this felicity lasts for seconds, hours or months, but believe me, for all the joys that life may bring, I would not exchange this one.</p></blockquote>
<p>Over at the <em>Atlantic</em>, two scientists and doctors&#8211;the renowned neurologist Oliver Sacks and radiologist Richard Gunderman&#8211;<a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/health/archive/2012/12/sensing-god-and-the-limits-of-neuroscience/266706/#" target="_blank">are debating</a> these fascinating questions.</p>
<p>In his new book <em>Hallucinations</em>, Oliver Sacks writes, “One must wonder to what extent hallucinatory experiences have given rise to our art, folklore, and even religion.” In his <a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/health/archive/2012/12/seeing-god-in-the-third-millennium/266134/" target="_blank">recent piece</a> for the <em>Atlantic</em> titled &#8220;Seeing God in the Third Millenium,&#8221; he went on to argue:</p>
<blockquote><p>Hallucinations, whether revelatory or banal, are not of supernatural origin; they are part of the normal range of human consciousness and experience. This is not to say that they cannot play a part in the spiritual life, or have great meaning for an individual. Yet while it is understandable that one might attribute value, ground beliefs, or construct narratives from them, hallucinations cannot provide evidence for the existence of any metaphysical beings or places. They provide evidence only of the brain&#8217;s power to create them.<span id="more-6664"></span></p></blockquote>
<p>When I interviewed Sacks <a href="http://www.washingtontimes.com/news/2012/nov/27/renowned-author-oliver-sacks-examines-life-through/#ixzz2GpxaqZfU" target="_blank">for a profile</a>, his words were slightly softer: “There is always a brain basis for these various religious states, although this says nothing of the meaning or value of hallucinations. I don’t think it’s at all reductive.&#8221;</p>
<p>In <a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/health/archive/2012/12/sensing-god-and-the-limits-of-neuroscience/266706/#" target="_blank">his piece</a> for the <em>Atlantic</em>, a response to Sacks, Gunderman suggests a more humble approach, citing the limits of neuroscience in unpacking mystical and religious experiences:</p>
<blockquote><p><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family:Georgia, 'times new roman', times, serif;color:#000000;">Before proceeding, we need to pause to consider what we mean by &#8220;transcendent.&#8221; Literally, &#8220;transcend&#8221; means to climb beyond. The idea of transcendence has deep roots in our culture. For example, the fourth president of the United States and principal author of the U.S. Constitution, James Madison, refers to the establishment of a new government as an act of &#8220;transcendent authority,&#8221; which the people alone have the right to perform. Likewise, one of the greatest American writers, Nathaniel Hawthorne, describes the voice of an improbable singer, &#8220;as if some transcendent musician should draw a soul-thrilling sweetness out a cracked instrument, which makes its physical imperfection heard in the mist of ethereal harmony.&#8221;</span></p>
<p><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-family:Georgia, 'times new roman', times, serif;color:#000000;">In the religious context, transcendence implies a reality that is not purely material. Are there things in this world that are real but not physical, in the sense that they have no mass, size, shape, location, or color, emit no sound, and cannot be touched, tasted, or smelled? A thorough-going materialist might deny that such things even exist, arguing that talk of God or gods is mere poppycock. From a materialistic point of view, references to the divine, as well as those to ethereal qualities such as love, beauty, and goodness, merely refer to patterns of human behavior, or what amounts to the same thing, patterns of electrochemical activity in the brain. In contrast, Jews, Christians, and Muslims assert that God&#8217;s transcendence is self-evident, since God created everything material.</span></p></blockquote>
<p><span style="color:#000000;font-family:Georgia, 'times new roman', times, serif;">The problem is that science only acknowledges the material world&#8211;the world that can be empirically perceived. But the transcendental reality that Dostoevsky, St. Paul, and many other spiritual mystics have experienced, is, by definition, outside the realms of time, space, and the other aspects of our physical world that science lays claim to. So apart from explaining transcendental experiences in terms of neurochemistry, what can science say about them? How do we bridge the divide between what science knows and what mystics claim without outright dismissing the validity of the latter&#8217;s religious experiences?</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;font-family:Georgia, 'times new roman', times, serif;">Gunderman hints at an answer: </span></p>
<blockquote><p>Perhaps we should not be too quick to abandon the transcendent. What if the transcendent is no different from any other aspect of human experience, in at least one crucial respect? Namely, that there are both false and true experiences of the transcendent, just as there are false and true experiences associated with the senses, with reason, and with feeling. Sometimes what we think to be the crying of a baby turns out to be the whine of a machine, what seems to be a proven conclusion turns out to be based on an erroneous assumption, and what we suppose to be love turns out to be merely a fleeting infatuation. If we are smart, we recognize that we are fallible. Yet our fallibility does not lead us to conclude that we can never truly experience, know, or feel anything.</p>
<p>Let us grant, at least provisionally, something that cannot be proved. Let us suppose for the moment that all human experiences, whether illusory or real, whether immanent or transcendent, are accompanied by neurochemical changes in the brain. Let us further suppose that no experience is possible without such neurochemical changes, and that individuals whose brains have ceased to function can experience nothing. Let us also grant that tinkering with neurochemistry alters experience, sometimes merely by changing its timbres and hues, but in other cases by causing us to experience things that clearly never happened. Would granting all of these points prove that all experiences of the transcendent are unreal?</p></blockquote>
<p>Gunderman goes on to talk about an experience that many of us have had: being moved by music: &#8220;A neurologist might come along and explain that I am merely experiencing the transduction of kinetic energy into electrical energy as processed by neurons in the auditory and higher associative cortices of the brain. And yet, there is something about the music that is hard to reckon in such terms. It would be like saying that a passionate embrace is merely the pressing of flesh on flesh.&#8221;</p>
<p>In the book <em>Why God Won&#8217;t Go Away</em>, neurologists Andrew Newberg and Eugene D&#8217;Aquili discuss these issues at length. They bring Gunderman&#8217;s example full circle, arguing that there may be reason to believe that some sort of transcendental reality actually exists. They write:</p>
<blockquote><p>In the narrowest scientific view, it would be possible to believe that we had reduced all spiritual transcendence&#8211;from the mildest case of religious uplift, to the profound states of union described by mystics&#8211;to a neurochemical commotion in the brain.</p>
<p>But our understanding of the brain would not allow us to rest with that conclusion. We knew, after all, that everything the mind experiences is tracked in the brain. A SPECT scan of an opera lover listening to Puccini, for example, would reduce &#8220;Nessun Dorma&#8221; to multicolored blotches, but that would not diminish the beauty of the aria. The music, and the enjoyment it provided, would still be very real. The memory of the music, too, and the emotional pull of the tragedy of <em>Turandot</em>, are real. Even if you were to &#8220;play&#8221; the music and drama again only in your mind, many of the same parts of the brain would be reactivated. Perhaps even your body would get the same goose bumps evoked by Puccini&#8217;s heartbreaking lyrical melody, its crescendos and pianissimos. You would clearly be hearing the music, but only inside your head. Yet the existence of the music and its nonverbal power are still, neurologically, quite real.</p>
<p>All perceptions exist in the mind. The earth beneath your feet, the chair you&#8217;re sitting in, the book you hold in your hands may all seem unquestionably solid and real, but they are known to you only as secondhand neurological perceptions, as blips and flashes racing along the neural pathways inside your skull. If you were to dismiss spiritual experience as &#8220;mere&#8221; neurological activities, you would also have to distrust all of your own brain&#8217;s perceptions of the material world. On the other hand, if we do trust our perceptions of the physical world, we have no rational reason to declare that spiritual experience is a fiction that is &#8220;only&#8221; in the mind.</p></blockquote>
<p>They go on to write: &#8220;At this point in our research, science had brought us as far as it could, and we were left with two mutually exclusive possibilities: either spiritual experience is nothing more than a neurological construct created by and contained within the brain, or the state of absolute union that the mystics describe does in fact exist and the mind has developed the capacity to perceive it.&#8221;</p>
<p>Like Gunderman, Newberg and D&#8217;Aquili acknowledge the limits of science. What exists beyond those limits we can never know. This brings to mind Pi Patel, the hero of the beautiful novel <em>Life of Pi</em>. Like the neurologists here, Pi straddles the worlds of science and religion. He is a mystic and a lover of all religions&#8211;and he is also a student of the natural world, zoology specifically. Speaking of an atheist science teacher he had as a boy who inspired him to study zoology at university, Pi says, &#8220;I felt a kinship with him. It was my first clue that atheists are my brothers and sisters of a different faith, and every word they speak speaks of faith. Like me, they go as far as the legs of reason will carry them&#8211;and then they leap.&#8221;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/6664/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/6664/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=6664&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://acculturated.com/2013/01/03/transcendence-and-the-limits-of-science/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/96e93e02a70683fb31960b1ea3b9e614?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">emilyd09</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://acculturated.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/oliver-sacks.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Oliver Sacks</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Can Men and Women Be Friends?</title>
		<link>http://captainawkward.com/2013/01/25/can-men-and-women-be-friends-an-essay-and-a-website-launch/</link>
		<comments>http://captainawkward.com/2013/01/25/can-men-and-women-be-friends-an-essay-and-a-website-launch/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2013 22:16:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>JenniferP</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Feminism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Friendship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[attraction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[can men and women be friends]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gender]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Relationships]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://captainawkward.com/?p=5074</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Yesterday I saw this Tweet.  The piece linked there asks the question: &#8220;Can married women have straight male friends?&#8221; and suggests that friendships between straight men and straight women can be very difficult, partially based on a study about how some men and women might view their friendships differently: Recently a study published in Scientific [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=5074&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday I saw <a title="Can married women have straight male friends?" href="https://twitter.com/Fem2pt0/status/294471003755659266" target="_blank">this Tweet</a>.  <a title="Role/Reboot: Can married women have single male friends?" href="http://www.rolereboot.org/sex-and-relationships/details/2013-01-can-married-women-have-single-male-friends" target="_blank">The piece</a> linked there asks the question: &#8220;Can married women have straight male friends?&#8221; and suggests that friendships between straight men and straight women can be very difficult, partially based on a study about how some men and women might view their friendships differently:</p>
<blockquote><p>Recently a study <a href="http://www.scientificamerican.com/article.cfm?id=men-and-women-cant-be-just-friends" target="_hplink">published in Scientific American</a> stated that women are much more likely to be able to keep male friends platonic, while men have a harder time. The article states that these friendships are masked by a cover-up of sexual impulses by one of the parties. It said that men were far more attracted to their female friends and assumed their female friends felt the same, when they didn&#8217;t. Females were far less attracted to their male friends, and they, too, assumed that the male friends felt the same as they did. So, when it comes to male/female relationships, there are a lot of mixed signals going on from both sides.</p></blockquote>
<p>First order of business: Studies like the one linked in the article are <strong>descriptive</strong>, not <strong>prescriptive</strong>. &#8220;<em>This happens sometimes</em>&#8221; does not mean &#8220;<em>This happens sometimes, and therefore you should ______,&#8221; </em>though they are nearly always presented that way by headline writers. &#8220;<em>This happens sometimes. Scientists studied it in a way that fits into my preconceptions and anxieties. Therefore you should ____</em>.&#8221;<em> </em>==&gt;A trend piece is born.</p>
<p>Sometimes, inevitably, we become attracted to our friends. They are awesome people, we are awesome people, and like attracts like. I do not see why this is a gendered issue. Attraction causes tensions in straight-lady/gay-lady friendships, too, right? And straight-man/gay-man friendships?</p>
<p>Should you become attracted to your friend of any gender, ask yourself:</p>
<ul>
<li>Is this person in a committed relationship that does not include room for me?</li>
<li>Do I want to speak up about my feelings and see if they are returned?</li>
</ul>
<p>If your friend is single or might be interested in you, and you want to speak up and see what happens, say &#8220;<em>Friend, would you maybe like to try dating and see if we&#8217;d be good at it?</em>&#8221; and see what they say. <a title="The Year of Living Awkwardly" href="http://captainawkward.com/2011/01/26/the-year-of-living-awkwardly/" target="_blank">Real friendships are not irrevocably ruined by such honesty</a>. <a title="Open Thread: Crushes" href="http://captainawkward.com/2013/01/07/open-thread-crushes/" target="_blank">I swear</a>.</p>
<p>If your friend is happily committed elsewhere, and/or you don&#8217;t think it&#8217;s a good idea to act on an attraction for whatever reason, having the attraction does not have to doom your friendship. <a title="I don't have a friend zone" href="http://captainawkward.com/2011/11/23/guest-post-i-dont-have-a-friend-zone-question-140/" target="_blank">Having an attraction</a> does not mean you have to do anything or say anything about it. <a title="If my friend has feelings for me, it is only logical that I return them." href="http://captainawkward.com/2012/03/24/211-if-my-friend-has-feelings-for-me-it-is-only-logical-that-i-return-them/" target="_blank">Someone else&#8217;s attraction (or possible attraction)</a> to you does not obligate you to do or feel anything in return. Even if such attraction is rare for you, <a title="Geek Relationship Fallacies" href="http://captainawkward.com/2012/04/16/geek-relationship-fallacies/" target="_blank">you&#8217;re not the only two members of your species</a>. Go ahead and have your secret PANTSFEELINGS. Then, when you see your friend, do not mention these feelings, hint at them, Firth them, probe for or exacerbate cracks in their current relationship, send FEELINGSMAIL, or give weird extra-long hugs where you smell their necks.</p>
<p>We talk a lot here about boundary-setting; this is a case for boundary-having. Feel whatever you feel! Then set boundaries with yourself about how you behave towards your friends. You could even say &#8220;<em>I need to take a little break from hanging out to work out some weird feelings I&#8217;m having, sorry to make it weird, I&#8217;ll see you in a month or two</em>&#8221; if you had to, and your friends would understand. Survive the temporary awkwardness, and stop imagining &#8220;attraction&#8221; as this mystical force that exists outside of human decisionmaking.</p>
<p>I am also confused as to why the writer seems to equate male friendships with &#8220;male attention.&#8221; This is one of the saddest sentences I&#8217;ve read in a while:</p>
<blockquote><p>I find it easier to get my other needs met from my girlfriends and the male attention I get outside of that is restricted to the few men that still try to pick up on me in the grocery store.</p></blockquote>
<p>Even if you buy the frankly terrible assumption that &#8220;male attention&#8221; is some kind of abstract need that women have in the first place, all &#8220;male attention&#8221; is not created equal.</p>
<p>My best friend from film school is named Zach. Zach is the kind of talented that means that someday you will all line up to buy tickets to the opening nights of his movies and talk about them in breathless, excited tones the way you now discuss your fondest artistic heroes. He is also fiercely loyal, honest, sensitive and considerate, a great listener, a generous collaborator, and effing hilarious. He moved away about a year ago, and I miss him pretty much daily.</p>
<p>I do not think that my friendship with Zach has ever included the kind of &#8220;male attention&#8221; one finds in grocery stores or, say, <a title="One-Sided Conversations on a Train" href="http://captainawkward.com/2012/09/15/conversations-on-a-train/">riding the Chicago Transit Authority</a>. Full attraction disclosure: Once I walked into a show where his band was playing and thought &#8220;<em>Whoa, that bass player is really ho-&#8230;.I mean, my friend Zach is really good at playing bass!</em>&#8221; If he ever had a similar passing thought of &#8220;<em>Whoa, that disheveled teacher is really ho- I mean, my friend Jennifer is very good at explaining stuff</em>&#8221; I do not know. If he did <strong>he sensibly kept that shit to himself like a grownup</strong>.</p>
<p>For anyone to try to tell me that one of the best and most productive and rewarding relationships I have ever had with a human being could possibly live or die by some pseudo-science about misplaced pantsfeelings, or put it in the <strong>highly</strong> dubious &#8220;ego-feeding&#8221; category of grocery store flirtations is beyond insulting. What a sad and reductive view of what human beings are to each other.</p>
<p>The author&#8217;s anxieties and choices about who to be friends with are obviously her own to have. But I don&#8217;t respect this way of forming the question and am so tired of seeing it asked. Advice about how to be friends, find love, and have sex that relies on gender essentialism is so very, very bad for us.</p>
<p>When I was growing up, my mom fell into this trap, big time even though she is an amazing, driven, brilliant, career-minded feminist who brooks no crap from anyone. She was hyper-vigilant and worried about any time I spent with boys. Even though I played on a nearly all-male soccer team. Even though men made up more than half our family, not to mention being half of everyone on the planet so, not actually avoidable. I was not allowed to invite male friends over, or go to their houses, and the question was always &#8220;<em>Will there be boys there?</em>&#8221; She would say &#8220;<em>It&#8217;s not that I don&#8217;t trust you, I just don&#8217;t trust<strong> them</strong>,</em>&#8221; or &#8220;<em>You never know <strong>what might happen</strong></em>&#8221; or &#8220;<em>You don&#8217;t want to get <strong>a reputation</strong></em>.&#8221; I wanted to know &#8211; WHAT? WHAT MIGHT HAPPEN? I know that she was very afraid that I would get pregnant and derail my plans for education and career stuff, but beyond that she would never be specific, there was just this generalized fear and I had to live with it. When I mentioned any boy comma friend, there was a lot of probing to see if he was a boynocommaorspacefriend and sudden restrictions on where I could go. The weirdest thing is, it was also coupled with a lot of advice on how I could make myself prettier &#8211; gift subscriptions to <em>Seventeen</em> and <em>Vogue</em>, admonishments to wear more makeup and stop stealing my dad&#8217;s flannel shirts and wearing unfeminine stompy shoes. Message: Be pretty, or at least, pretti<strong>er</strong>! So boys will like you and ask you to proms! But be very afraid of them and don&#8217;t spend time with them unless a parent is in-the-room supervising you!</p>
<p><strong>Content note:</strong> Brief discussion of long-ago sexual assault below cut. If you want to skip that and go directly to a definitive answer about whether men and women can be friends, click <a title="Can men and women be friends?" href="http://canmenandwomenbefriends.com/" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<p><span id="more-5074"></span></p>
<p>My freshman year in college, my mom&#8217;s worst fears about &#8220;what might happen&#8221; manifested, and a man raped me.</p>
<p>But you know who came to find me that night that I was drunk and had gotten separated from our group by someone sketchy? My guy friends.</p>
<p>You know who took me to the hospital and held my hand after a rape exam where the doctor invited a bunch of medical students into observe what collecting a rape kit is like without asking me if that was okay? Guy friends.</p>
<p>You know who always walked me home and made sure I got home okay after that night? Guy friends.</p>
<p>You know who lent me their class notes and studied with me and made sure I didn&#8217;t fall behind in my classes? Guy friends.</p>
<p>You know who hugged me and made me laugh and feel normal and like I could trust people again? Guy friends. One gave me his favorite Yoda action figure so I would always have someone to consult for wisdom and comfort. I carried Yoda in my pocket for the next three years and if I hadn&#8217;t lost him in a tragic pocket-lining-hole incident on the Czech-Polish border in 1995, I&#8217;d carry him still.</p>
<p>My ladies had my back too, don&#8217;t get me wrong. Both men and women <a title="#190: The Sandwich Means “I Love You”: A Valentine." href="http://captainawkward.com/2012/02/13/190-the-sandwich-means-i-love-you-a-valentine/" target="_blank">made me a lot of sandwiches</a> that year. BOTH men AND women, i.e. HUMAN BEINGS, took care of me and no one had to be afraid of each other or secretly in love.</p>
<p>My mom has esteemed colleagues, but I don&#8217;t know that she has any men besides my dad and her brother who she is emotionally close to. I think she came by her fears and views honestly as a reasonable byproduct of the upbringing she had in the 1950s and 1960s where it really was more usual for girls to be friends with girls and boys to be friends with boys (and LGBTQ people were totally invisible). I think next time we hang out I am going to ask her about friends, and friendship, and what she thinks about this stuff, but until then I will assume she&#8217;s happy with her choices.</p>
<p>As I am happy not living in the 1950s, or with 1950s expectations about who I am allowed to be friends with.</p>
<p>So my question, or I guess my frustration is: Who are these &#8220;<em>Men are like ___, Women are like ____, you should probably worry</em>&#8221; articles serving? Who are they targeted at? Who profits when we frame things like this, argue caution and worry, and cut ourselves off from each other? What possible end could be met or good created? Why are people invested in acting as if men and women are so radically different from each other, or so fragile, or that there is no benefit beyond sexual interest or &#8220;attention&#8221; (ugh) underlying our interactions? Why do people assume that attraction (and in this case, once again it&#8217;s <strong>male</strong> attraction that&#8217;s presented as being the important, insurmountable kind) is some powerful, mysterious force that automatically trumps everything about two people and their feelings and choices?</p>
<p>My life would be so much poorer if I bought into those anxieties. Wouldn&#8217;t yours? As one of my fellow &#8220;WTF?&#8221; Twitter brigade said yesterday,&#8221;<a title="I have male friends this isn't an anomaly" href="http://bikegroggery.blogspot.com/2013/01/i-have-male-friends-this-isnt-anomaly.html?m=1" target="_blank">To throw away the love and friendship of people based solely on their gender seems like a lonely way to go through life</a>.&#8221;</p>
<p>In the hopes of fighting this particular strain of ignorance, I have created a new website, called <a title="Can men and women be friends?" href="http://www.canmenandwomenbefriends.com" target="_blank">CanMenandWomenBeFriends.com</a>, dedicated to answering this question so that future generations can have a lasting, permanent answer to this question. Thank you for reading.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5074/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5074/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=5074&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://captainawkward.com/2013/01/25/can-men-and-women-be-friends-an-essay-and-a-website-launch/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>284</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/576f0315643c960709506320ae4268ce?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">JenniferP</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Liam’s Birthday Robohand!</title>
		<link>http://comingupshorthanded.com/2013/01/25/liams-birthday-robohand/</link>
		<comments>http://comingupshorthanded.com/2013/01/25/liams-birthday-robohand/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2013 14:50:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>comingupshorthanded</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ABS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amniotic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amputation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amputee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[band]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[child]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[finger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fingers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[free]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[functional]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hands]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ivan Owen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kid]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[makerbot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mechanical]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[no cost]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[open source]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prosthesis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prosthetic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[public domain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[replicator 2]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Richard Van As]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robohand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[syndrome]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thingiverse]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://comingupshorthanded.com/?p=489</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Liam is now the owner of a functional, comfortable device that increases what his right hand can accomplish. The evening before his birthday, Liam and his parents (Rory and Yolandi) stopped by Richard&#8217;s workshop to pick up the completed hand. Not only did this device cost $0 for Liam&#8217;s family, but the design itself is [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=489&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://comingupshorthanded.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/liam-with-new-hand.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-490" alt="Liam with new hand" src="http://comingupshorthanded.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/liam-with-new-hand.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>Liam is now the owner of a functional, comfortable device that increases what his right hand can accomplish. The evening before his birthday, Liam and his parents (Rory and Yolandi) stopped by Richard&#8217;s workshop to pick up the completed hand.</p>
<p>Not only did this device cost $0 for Liam&#8217;s family, but the design itself is now public-domain. There is no patent, the details of this design can be used freely by anyone. The specific CAD files used to print the components are available for free-download <a href="http://www.thingiverse.com/thing:44150">here</a>.</p>
<p>It was a long day, but Liam was kind enough to demonstrate using his new hand on video:</p>
<p><span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='640' height='390' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/4i4RpKYoeEw?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span><br />
And here he is just 3 days later, practicing and playing with his new hand:</p>
<span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='640' height='390' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/kB53-D_N8Uc?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span>
<p>Liam took his new hand with him to his doctor&#8217;s appointment today and also to school! His mother Yolandi says,</p>
<p><em>&#8220;Finish with Hand Clinic yay Dr&#8217;s are VERY impressed with Liam&#8217;s Robohand. No operations to be done as yet which is awesome. Amazing stuff to happen very soon. Liam has had so far an fantastic day not shy at all to show all his Robohand. His little school he goes to was a huge hit all the teacher&#8217;s &amp; kiddies were in awe <img src='http://s1.wp.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif' alt=';)' class='wp-smiley' />  its been a super duper day. Thank you all for the birthday wishes to Liam much appreciated xxx&#8221;</em></p>
<p>Richard and Ivan are deeply grateful for the support of their families (Beth Rademeyer Van As &amp; Jen Owen, you ladies are both indescribably awesome!), thankful for Rory &amp; Yolandi for taking a chance on two crazy guys with an idea and for all the people who have helped with this project.</p>
<p>A special thank you as well to <a href="http://www.makerbot.com/">Makerbot </a>for providing the machines that made it possible to produce light-weight, inexpensive components for Liam&#8217;s hand!</p>
<p>With what we have learned by working with Liam, we see this as just the <strong>beginning</strong>. From here we want to carry this forward, to find other &#8220;Liams&#8221; out there who could benefit from the designs and techniques we are exploring.</p>
<p>If you believe, as we do, that as many people should freely benefit from this as possible &amp; you would like to help make it happen, please visit our <a href="http://fundly.com/just-a-guy-with-an-idea-restoring-fingers">fundraising page</a>. Thank you!!!</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/489/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/489/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/489/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/489/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/489/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/489/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/489/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/489/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/489/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/489/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/489/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/489/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/489/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/489/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=489&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://comingupshorthanded.com/2013/01/25/liams-birthday-robohand/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>20</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/da23a85332382a9670b848bada4480b5?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">comingupshorthanded</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://comingupshorthanded.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/liam-with-new-hand.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Liam with new hand</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Artificial Puberty, Round Two</title>
		<link>http://killerboobies.wordpress.com/2013/01/30/989/</link>
		<comments>http://killerboobies.wordpress.com/2013/01/30/989/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 06:26:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Michelle</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recovery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Surgery]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://killerboobies.wordpress.com/?p=989</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[At age 25 with plenty of planned years of awesome boobage ahead of me, I never really considered not having reconstruction after my mastectomy. Although the reconstruction procedure added 4 hours to my surgery and meant considerably more pain and discomfort, there was and is something important to me about maintaining these bastions of my [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=989&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At age 25 with plenty of planned years of awesome boobage ahead of me, I never really considered not having reconstruction after my mastectomy. Although the reconstruction procedure added 4 hours to my surgery and meant considerably more pain and discomfort, there was and is something important to me about maintaining these bastions of my femininity &#8211; and I think it goes deeper than just wanting to look good in a tank top, although that&#8217;s certainly a consideration.</p>
<p>I found this beautiful quote in the book Reconstructing Aphrodite, a series of essays from women who decided to rebuild their bodies after the devastation of a mastectomy. It really spoke to me, and I hope it will speak to you too.</p>
<blockquote><p>From the moment I was diagnosed with breast cancer and faced a possible mastectomy, I knew I wanted reconstruction. This response was out of my own sense of art, symmetry, and aesthetic. It was the same response I would have to a tooth extraction or the loss of any body part. It speaks of how I approach an environment that to me is visually out-of-balance.</p>
<p>How could I be concerned about something so superficial while facing cancer? Perhaps because I did not believe that I had the worst disease in the world. Princess Diana said, &#8220;The worst disease in the world is the lack of love.&#8221; Mother Teresa said, &#8220;The worst disease in the world is to be nothing to nobody.&#8221;</p>
<p>I live in the abundant love of God amid friends and family who express God&#8217;s loving kindness. We are surrounded by survivors of all life&#8217;s troubles and grief, surrounded by hope, peace, and joy. I saw the choice for reconstruction as only one of the endless ways to create beauty in my world. It was my surgeon&#8217;s sense of art and beauty and her respect for the female form that gave me the confidence to pursue this path.</p></blockquote>
<p>Yesterday I had my second expander fill. I popped another Ativan beforehand, so that I could remain calm in the face of the MegaNeedle. Alas, I do not possess quite the same level of mental zen as the author of the above quote, although I have been doing a variety of yoga poses to ease my tense back. Child pose is THE BEST.</p>
<p>I was too calm about the fill, perhaps, because the MegaNeedle got the best of me this time. I felt everything as my right breast was punctured. I shouted out in alarm more than pain, because I was so surprised to have any sensation. The plastic surgeon apologized, but said it was good news, because it could herald the return of feeling in my breasts. Sweet! Maybe I won&#8217;t have to go the rest of my life unsure whether or not I&#8217;m having a nip-slip.<i><br />
</i></p>
<p>It&#8217;s quite weird to be numb across such a wide swath of my body. For example, I noticed that the DermaBond skin glue the surgeons used to close up my wounds &#8211; which, as I previously mentioned, looked like the Joker&#8217;s face &#8211; had started to crack, peel and fall off. I&#8217;m sure that if I had sensation, that would be unbearably itchy, but I can&#8217;t feel a thing. Side note: Can you believe that after surgery they still patch you up using things that can be found at OfficeMax? Staples, thread, glue? What year is this?</p>
<p>Anyway, the plastic surgeon noticed it, and accelerated the process by peeling off the remainder of the DermaBond with sterile tweezers. Again, I&#8217;m willing to bet this would be uncomfortable if I could feel it. When she was done, I was absolutely stunned. The dark, bumpy, scarlike appearance of my wound was approximately 95% due to the DermaBond itself. The actual scar is probably less than an 1/8 of an inch thick and is currently sort of a medium-pink, likely to fade to skin color within a couple of years. Although scar tissue is basically the least of my worries, considering that my life is literally on the line here, I can&#8217;t lie: I&#8217;m happy that I&#8217;ll be able to bare sideboob with abandon by 2015.</p>
<p>Every time I leave USC, I pass a promise on the wall:</p>
<p><a href="http://killerboobies.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/diseaseofthepast-copy.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-1006" alt="USC's Promise" src="http://killerboobies.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/diseaseofthepast-copy.jpg?w=580&#038;h=580" width="580" height="580" /></a></p>
<p>I never fail to marvel at the hundreds of thousands of scientists who work every day to heal people like me. After my diagnosis, I read the book <em>The Emperor of All Maladies,</em> a biological history of cancer written by an oncologist. It was like picking at a scab &#8211; painful at times, but equally addicting &#8211; and it gave me an enormous appreciation for all that we&#8217;ve been able to achieve in the long history of cancer. Gordie read it too, and is considering getting a tattoo of a crab in my honor. You guys, I SWOON.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/989/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/989/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=989&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://killerboobies.wordpress.com/2013/01/30/989/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>38</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/e40781bd79b3d7af653ac7193f2a5b66?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">myimportantopinion</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://killerboobies.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/diseaseofthepast-copy.jpg?w=580" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">USC&#039;s Promise</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Historical Revolution</title>
		<link>http://reneeapflughaupt.wordpress.com/2013/02/01/historical-revolution/</link>
		<comments>http://reneeapflughaupt.wordpress.com/2013/02/01/historical-revolution/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:50:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Renee Pflughaupt</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Arab Spring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Egypt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Identity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Libya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Revolution]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://reneeapflughaupt.wordpress.com/?p=195</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[For the past three years, uprisings and revolutions have dominated the headlines. The Arab Spring and its spirit of freedom touched many African and Middle-Eastern countries, including Egypt, Libya and now Syria. The clash of class, power and ideas still throbs throughout the region. Its people seek to take back not only their country, but [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=195&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_368" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 210px"><a href="http://reneeapflughaupt.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/leptis_magna_arch_of_septimus_severus.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-368" alt="Arch of Septimius Severus" src="http://reneeapflughaupt.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/leptis_magna_arch_of_septimus_severus.jpg?w=200&#038;h=300" width="200" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The Arch of Septimius Severus, located at Leptis Magna, is one of the many gems of Libyan history buried beneath the sands.</p></div>
<p>For the past three years, uprisings and revolutions have dominated the headlines. The Arab Spring and its spirit of freedom touched many African and Middle-Eastern countries, including Egypt, Libya and now Syria. The clash of class, power and ideas still throbs throughout the region. Its people seek to take back not only their country, but to take back their own story.</p>
<p>As Americans, we take our story and history for granted. Simply stating the word &#8220;history&#8221; brings to mind droning, bespectacled professors bearing dusty tomes. We don&#8217;t realize how much bigger history is than the classroom; in fact, it appears everyone but us sees that.</p>
<p>Muammar Qaddafi, when he rose to power in 1969, definitely knew the power of a nation&#8217;s story. And that story did not align with his own agenda. So he buried it. He buried it in the sand and in the wilderness, cutting off Libya from the rest of the world in the process. As knowledge would crack his vice-grip, his lackeys patrolled the classrooms, making sure the next generation committed to memory <em>The Green Book</em>, his tangled philosophy which displayed Libyan history in two stages: the dark days of Western imperialism and the enlightened age of the Brother Leader.</p>
<p>By the order of the Brother Leader, Libya&#8217;s rich cultural past faded away. Remnants of Italian and Roman architecture fell to be replaced by parking garages. The statue of Septimius Severus, Roman emperor who claimed Libya as his birthplace, disappeared from the main square, Martyr&#8217;s Square, in Tripoli. The glorious past of Libya as a cultural and economic crossroads was wiped away with the pen of a chaotic dictator.</p>
<p>But the people remember. They remember who they are and are not willing to give up their birthright &#8211; their identity and their potential.</p>
<p>Identity, which history teaches us, allows us to know who we are and where we came from. Without knowing where we come from, we cannot begin to understand where we are going. We, as Americans, are in danger of losing our history and identity; not at all because of a dictator, but because of our own lethargy.</p>
<p>History as a subject is almost a sham. In no other profession is the scholar&#8217;s knowledge and research so dramatically different from classroom lessons. Multitudes of myths and charming vignettes choke our history textbooks until they are no more meaningful than a packet of fairytales. Why do we still teach Columbus as the daring explorer, when in reality he was a seeker of riches and made no lasting contributions in discovery? Why do we look away from the massacres our ethno-centric ancestors (and brethren!) committed and still do commit to this very day? Why do we fail to acknowledge the truth of our nation&#8217;s mistakes (Vietnam being just one of the most glaringly obvious)?</p>
<p>More importantly, glossing over our nation&#8217;s true history keeps &#8220;the beast&#8221; asleep. The beast of the Republic, who desires to carve out equality for his fellow man, woman and child. Who desires for equal treatment between all races. Who desires his birthright of identity&#8230; and thus, the means to attain his true potential.</p>
<p>Because of this, I urge and challenge you to reconsider who you are and where you came from. Don&#8217;t depend on your elementary history lessons to do the job &#8211; they are as elementary as they are useless. Be skeptical. Observe. Forget about your few years on this terrestrial ball and consider: who are we, truly? Where have we been, and what have we done? And what can we now do, so that my brother, my sister, that all of humanity, may move forward?</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/195/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/195/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=195&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://reneeapflughaupt.wordpress.com/2013/02/01/historical-revolution/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>54</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/d5a71c4e413f47e83d7fe8bd5e387b40?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ofinkandcoffee</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://reneeapflughaupt.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/leptis_magna_arch_of_septimus_severus.jpg?w=200" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Arch of Septimius Severus</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bad Coffee Makes Me Sad</title>
		<link>http://ajviola.wordpress.com/2013/01/31/bad-coffee-makes-me-sad/</link>
		<comments>http://ajviola.wordpress.com/2013/01/31/bad-coffee-makes-me-sad/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 18:19:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>ajviola</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[coffee]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ajviola.wordpress.com/?p=196</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s no secret that I love coffee. Over the past couple of years my relationship with coffee has gone to a whole new level. We used to be just friends who would meet every once in a while and only when I was really tired. Also, I never really let coffee be itself around me. [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=196&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s no secret that I love coffee. Over the past couple of years my relationship with coffee has gone to a whole new level. We used to be just friends who would meet every once in a while and only when I was really tired. Also, I never really let coffee be itself around me. I always forced it to take on different appearances and flavors. I never allowed it to be who it really was. It was a very selfish relationship.</p>
<p>Things have changed now. I&#8217;ve repented of my ways and really feel like coffee and I have gotten to a level of our relationship that we can both be proud of.</p>
<p>Coffee represents something much stronger to me than flavor.</p>
<p>Even now as I write this I&#8217;m staring a 5lb bag of coffee that the coffee club I helped start (<a href="http://raleighcoffeeclub.com/" target="_blank">Raleigh Coffee Club</a>) purchased for an organization that works with the homeless and at-risk population here in Raleigh (<a href="http://lovewins.info/" target="_blank">Love Wins</a>). That&#8217;s the sort of thing coffee represents for me. Something much greater than a hot cup of black liquid.</p>
<p>It represents community. It represents hard work. It represents friendships. It represents love.</p>
<p>Every time I brew coffee at home, which takes me longer than most people, I&#8217;m not just trying to get caffeine in me&#8230;I&#8217;m participating in an act that not only supports people I care about, but supports employees and farmers I&#8217;ve never met, but because they are human I care about them.</p>
<p>It represents to local roasters that I&#8217;ve created such good friendships with. It represents the passion they have for their product.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s why bad coffee makes me sad.</p>
<p>Because I know how good it can be. And I don&#8217;t mean bad just on the basis of flavor and taste, which I&#8217;ve had my fair share of, but also bad in the sense of where it comes from and how the workers are treated where it&#8217;s roasted and farmed. When you drink &#8220;bad&#8221; coffee you are supporting that.</p>
<p>And I say without shame, what you buy, eat, drink and do shows what you support.</p>
<p>You can&#8217;t say you care about people and serve bad coffee. And again, I don&#8217;t just mean by flavor, because that is incredibly subjective&#8230;but having coffee that tastes good isn&#8217;t a bad idea either.</p>
<p>Don&#8217;t take this as a guilt trip, because I, by no means, buy every single thing that supports the right things&#8230;but I am making an effort.</p>
<p>Drink good coffee. Good tasting. Good supporting. Good.</p>
<p><a href="http://ajviola.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/20130131-213954.jpg"><img src="http://ajviola.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/20130131-213954.jpg?w=720" alt="20130131-213954.jpg" class="alignnone size-full" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/196/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/196/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=196&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://ajviola.wordpress.com/2013/01/31/bad-coffee-makes-me-sad/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>139</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c388f816d99175c83c9c980cb9ede326?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ajviola</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ajviola.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/20130131-213954.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">20130131-213954.jpg</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>First Rains: To Quench</title>
		<link>http://africafarandwide.wordpress.com/2013/01/29/first-rains-to-quench/</link>
		<comments>http://africafarandwide.wordpress.com/2013/01/29/first-rains-to-quench/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 20:29:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Africa far and wide</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Beira]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mozambique]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[african]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Expat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Floods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fotografia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lightning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photo essay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Storm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[volunteer]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://africafarandwide.wordpress.com/?p=738</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The rainy season has arrived in Mozambique. After a drought-stricken couple of years, I can almost hear the sigh of relief as plants, animals and people are soaked to the core with torrential rain. The excitement that comes with the first rains is almost contagious. The bull frogs start emerging from deep under, children enjoy [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=738&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://africafarandwide.wordpress.com/2013/01/29/first-rains-to-quench/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>86</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://africafarandwide.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/excitement.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://africafarandwide.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/excitement.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Excitement</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/9d942d5f591cb272290d76986e4bf953?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">africafarandwide</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://africafarandwide.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/storm-over-cane.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Storm over Cane</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://africafarandwide.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/hard-rain.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Hard Rain</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://africafarandwide.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/snail-explosion-copy.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Snail Explosion copy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://africafarandwide.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/water-lily-copy.jpg?w=112" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Water lily copy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://africafarandwide.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/paddy-baby-copy.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Paddy baby copy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://africafarandwide.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/netting-in-the-rain-copy.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Netting in the rain copy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://africafarandwide.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/rain-on-the-railway.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Rain on the Railway</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://africafarandwide.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the-railway-cane-cutter.jpg?w=112" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The Railway Cane cutter</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://africafarandwide.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/wet-bread.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Wet Bread</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://africafarandwide.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/men-at-work.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Men at work</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://africafarandwide.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/make-do-raincoat.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Make-do Raincoat</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://africafarandwide.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/first-rains.jpg?w=106" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">First rains</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://africafarandwide.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/bucket-shelter.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Bucket Shelter</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
