<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2012 00:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Why We Don&#8217;t Have Time for Jane Austen</title>
		<link>http://imaginationbyreality.wordpress.com/2012/10/27/why-we-dont-have-time-for-jane-austen/</link>
		<comments>http://imaginationbyreality.wordpress.com/2012/10/27/why-we-dont-have-time-for-jane-austen/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2012 11:47:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>achouan</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[characters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cultural studies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humanities]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jane Austen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[literature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[narrative]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[time]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TV show]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://imaginationbyreality.wordpress.com/?p=94</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A lot of people pine about going through separation anxiety with a recently finished book. I can&#8217;t say I go through that. If anything, I&#8217;m pretty excited when I finish any novel, no matter how good it was. My &#8220;To Read&#8221; list is always increasing faster than I can get through it. I am very [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=94&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A lot of people pine about going through separation anxiety with a recently finished book. I can&#8217;t say I go through that. If anything, I&#8217;m pretty excited when I finish any novel, no matter how good it was. My &#8220;To Read&#8221; list is always increasing faster than I can get through it. I am very much of a collector of cultural products. There&#8217;s always an overwhelmingly large pool of texts still out there; I get a high from finishing things and moving on to the next ones.</p>
<p>One of my greatest grievances with culture is that there is simply too much of it to possibly absorb it all. As a student in Cultural Studies, you face the great frustration of always possessing a minority of the knowledge you&#8217;re actually supposed to be dealing with. You constantly face surprised looks from people saying: &#8220;What? You haven&#8217;t read that book/seen that movie/heard of so and so&#8230;?&#8221; As if literature scholars didn&#8217;t have it bad enough already. Literature can only increase in its number of works. You&#8217;re constantly catching up with history, while trying to stay on top of contemporary scenes. The 20th century provided great leaps for Mankind and only great despair for Alexis&#8217; schedule. Presently, you need to stay on top of not only books but films, television, music, internet culture (insert here an exponentially dividing number of communities), video games, and who knows what other pop culture phenomenons you might be into.</p>
<p>Here, I come back to my petition to increase the number of hours in a day (scientists, any progress on slowing the rotation of the Earth?). 200 years ago, people had time for Jane Austen novels. First of all, literature had a much more restricted audience, people who had money, owned land, and had a lot of time to spare during the day. Secondly, written publications, whether books or newspapers, were the only kind of circulating stories you could enjoy at home. People had time to go through 300-page books of characters living circular lives where not much happened.</p>
<p>I can&#8217;t actually claim to be reading any Austen currently. The last time I had my hands on one of her books was a couple of years ago and I remember thinking the whole way through of all the other things I could be doing, as Marianne simply failed to get to the point with Mr. Willoughby. Don&#8217;t get me wrong, I&#8217;m not here to hate on Jane Austen, whom I do hope to eventually get around to in a more substantial way. My frustration with literature of previous ages is not only that it becomes more and more inaccessible as you go back in time, but even if you take the time to appreciate the language, it&#8217;s just too damn long.</p>
<p>I think a lot of our modern day short attention span comes from how fragmented our culture is. Books have not only condensed but gotten quicker. You can&#8217;t hope to tell a good story unless you&#8217;re constantly moving things forward. Same goes for movies. In the short century we&#8217;ve been making them, their rhythm has greatly accelerated. The average movie scene has decreased from over 4 minutes long in the 1950s to close to a minute today. In a video game, the character is always running and if you&#8217;re stuck in the same area for too long without a clear view of what you have to do, interest decreases quickly. TV has it worse, with constant breaks between programs, and 15-30 second flash ads conveying character, narrative and plot in fractions of time. That Cold FX lady can get over her illness, but she better not take more than 5 seconds to go from sick to healthy. We have the news to get to!</p>
<p>Speaking of the news, I have to say how confusing it is to watch the North American news for someone who is not accustomed to it. In France, we&#8217;ll have the newscast twice a day: around lunch and dinner time. Half an hour each. That&#8217;s it. And no one really bothers with the midday one, which is essentially fluff news. Sure, you&#8217;ll get the 24/7 news channels, but no one actually watches that unless they&#8217;re traders or retirees. For the majority of the population, you get you daily dose at 8 o&#8217;clock and probably tune off before the end, as the big pieces get through first. Now take CBC news, which I watched for about 2 years in my university dining hall whether I wanted to or not. Pieces last on average about 30 seconds. And they NEVER get to the point. The anchor only hints at what&#8217;s going on before moving on to the next headline. You have to be watching at the right time to get the extended coverage of a story. Otherwise, you just have to wait for the headlines cycle to come around again and see if they&#8217;ve updated anything.</p>
<p>I have a lot of gaps in my culture. I got an education in French literature, but am by no means educated in that area. English culture is just a vast umbrella term in which I have to be knowledgeable in English, American and Canadian texts (which are different things, unlike some Europeans might assume) not to mention the rest of Anglophone production throughout the world. For a long time it stressed me to constantly chase after all these media and cultures and never catch up to them. I think I may have come to terms now with the fact that there will always be more culture out of me than there is in me. Instead, I live by the motto that one book (film, TV show, etc.) read is one more accomplished. There is no end to that list, but the satisfaction comes in the form of accumulation. I never manage to absorb as much culture as I would like to each day, but I&#8217;ll keep fighting the clock and one of these days, when I feel further along this path and less pressed for time, I&#8217;ll be sure to invite Jane over for a cup of tea and hear what she has to say.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/94/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/94/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=94&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://imaginationbyreality.wordpress.com/2012/10/27/why-we-dont-have-time-for-jane-austen/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/589ef8b16709213d9922aef1b510549f?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">achouan</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nurturing Nature</title>
		<link>http://tonyalatorre.wordpress.com/2012/10/27/nurturing-nature/</link>
		<comments>http://tonyalatorre.wordpress.com/2012/10/27/nurturing-nature/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2012 12:41:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tonyalatorre</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[cat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christian Faith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gardening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Missions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uganda]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tonyalatorre.wordpress.com/?p=9807</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Growing food is as natural to a Ugandan as getting in the car to go to the grocery store is for an American. Gardening is called &#8220;digging&#8221; in Uganda. Children can’t remember being taught to grow food, they watch, copy and perfect their techniques over time. Some of the smaller children in our home have been [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=9807&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Growing food is as natural to a Ugandan as getting in the car to go to the grocery store is for an American. Gardening is called &#8220;digging&#8221; in Uganda. Children can’t remember being taught to grow food, they watch, copy and perfect their techniques over time. Some of the smaller children in our home have been given a few seeds from our garden and they dug out a corner at the house, bordered it with rocks they found, and planted their own crops. Every day when they come home from school they check on their babies, looking for growth, removing weeds, watering when necessary. One of the older boys decided to “fertilize” their tender plants by urinating on the garden. The plants burned up and died, and he got big trouble.  They started over like the good hardworking Ugandan children they are and now new plants are flourishing again. They are learning to nurture, develop patience, and appreciate participating in God’s nature. Christine was eager to show me her little beans that are growing. What joy she will have when Auntie Julie cooks them up and serves them to the family.</p>
<div id="attachment_9808" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://tonyalatorre.wordpress.com/2012/10/27/nurturing-nature/dsc_1962/" rel="attachment wp-att-9808"><img class="size-full wp-image-9808" title="christine" alt="" src="http://tonyalatorre.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/dsc_1962.jpg?w=500&#038;h=752" height="752" width="500" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Christine loves to dig. We are buying them all rubber boots this week for their safety.</p></div>
<p>Taking good care of something helps develop character. This is why the children love to run to the land and work in the garden on Saturdays. I believe children benefit greatly from having a pet. A plant might be a good start, but I’ve been introducing the idea of getting a kitten for the children. All of the adults, except Robert who is an animal lover, wrinkle their noses and say that cats are used by the witchdoctors and carry curses. I rolled my eyes. We are Christian, we don’t believe that nonsense. A kitten is born in the animal kingdom created by God and can’t carry a curse. Robert grew up with dogs and is eager to get a puppy. I told him I will bring dog training books for him so he can teach the children consistent training methods for raising a puppy. I selfishly want to be there to introduce the puppy. They want a German shepherd, which is a breed that is easily available, and a great guard dog at night. I am all for that! Someday we will bring home a puppy but not until we are all ready to train it with good manners.<a href="http://tonyalatorre.wordpress.com/2012/10/27/nurturing-nature/dsc_1981/" rel="attachment wp-att-9810"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-9810" title="pumpkin" alt="" src="http://tonyalatorre.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/dsc_1981.jpg?w=500&#038;h=332" height="332" width="500" /></a></p>
<p>One afternoon while George was filming Phiona for the video we walked to a quiet restaurant. She forbid me from watching her because I made her nervous so I walked around the garden. This little calico kitten came over and began purring and rubbing against my leg. I picked it up and we got acquainted  long enough for me to get attached. The people at the restaurant laughed when I asked if I could have it. In a place where the people hardly get enough to eat they don’t have much sympathy for an animal if it starves. I understand that, I really do. They find it offensive to listen to someone talk about a pet as if it were a person.  So they said yes I could have her, and then probably talked about how absurd Americans are with their pets. (we are.)</p>
<div id="attachment_9811" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://tonyalatorre.wordpress.com/2012/10/27/nurturing-nature/dsc_1990/" rel="attachment wp-att-9811"><img class="size-full wp-image-9811" title="ronald and ryan" alt="" src="http://tonyalatorre.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/dsc_1990.jpg?w=500&#038;h=752" height="752" width="500" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Ronald and Ryan</p></div>
<p>I didn’t take her home right away. I gently began to introduce the idea of bringing home a kitty to the family. The adults were unenthusiastic. Robert was willing to try though he has no experience with cats. The children were excited to have a pet. So after days of talking and setting rules, such as, no one picks the cat up, and how to gently shoo it away they were ready for their first pet. The main rule is they must sit and wait for kitty to come for petting. It will teach them patience and self control. And it will protect the cat from getting squeezed, scared, and ready to defend with claws.</p>
<p>On my last morning we stopped by the restaurant to get kitty, but she was nowhere to be found. Sad. They took Robert’s phone number and promised to call him when it reappears.</p>
<p>A lady from the restaurant took us to a woman who has a cat. We met her and there was a tiny baby kitten that looked just like my Coco at home. I wanted her so badly! We offered the old woman a lot of money to have the kitty and she said no way. The person who gave her the cat would be angry if it wasn’t there when they visited. I couldn’t believe it! In the same place where people beg me to take their children I couldn’t buy a cat. It was mind boggling. Phiona and Robert nearly ran over a cat one morning so they chased it down and brought it home. But this one was feral, unfriendly and afraid of everyone. She went to live on the land and help us with rodents.</p>
<div id="attachment_9812" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://tonyalatorre.wordpress.com/2012/10/27/nurturing-nature/dsc_1934/" rel="attachment wp-att-9812"><img class="size-full wp-image-9812" title="kitty" alt="" src="http://tonyalatorre.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/dsc_1934.jpg?w=500&#038;h=332" height="332" width="500" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">This is the one that wasn&#8217;t for sale.</p></div>
<p>On Sunday while I was in the air over the Atlantic ocean Robert got the call and picked up calico kitty from the restaurant to take home. Phiona named her Grace and the kids are crazy in love with her. After two days in her new home, kitty went missing for two days.  Everyone, even the naysayers were depressed at the loss. Robert found her three kilometers away and brought her home, and there was a great celebration! Everyone was happy to have kitty back, now she is Amazing Grace.</p>
<p>Teaching children to nurture whether it is plants or animals will help them develop good character traits. I know for me, when I am being quiet with my favorite animals it has an immediate calming effect on me. I am reminded that love is simple. A soft touch is a gift. Giving affection is good for the heart and can cure lonliness. Talking about feelings isn’t a cultural practice in Uganda. That doesn’t mean the feelings aren’t there. I have a “feeling” the children will work out some of their feelings by loving and nurturing both plants and pets. I’m happy that the kitty who found me found its way into our home with the children.</p>
<div id="attachment_9813" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://tonyalatorre.wordpress.com/2012/10/27/nurturing-nature/dsc_1312/" rel="attachment wp-att-9813"><img class="size-full wp-image-9813" title="grace" alt="" src="http://tonyalatorre.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/dsc_1312.jpg?w=500&#038;h=752" height="752" width="500" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">This is Phiona with our little Amazing Grace</p></div>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/9807/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/9807/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=9807&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tonyalatorre.wordpress.com/2012/10/27/nurturing-nature/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/d5fa68d888d03d05880c90c415437f5b?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tonyalatorre</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tonyalatorre.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/dsc_1962.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">christine</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tonyalatorre.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/dsc_1981.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">pumpkin</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tonyalatorre.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/dsc_1990.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ronald and ryan</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tonyalatorre.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/dsc_1934.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">kitty</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tonyalatorre.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/dsc_1312.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">grace</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sculpture By the Sea</title>
		<link>http://simplymarvelousreally.wordpress.com/2012/10/28/sculpture-by-the-sea/</link>
		<comments>http://simplymarvelousreally.wordpress.com/2012/10/28/sculpture-by-the-sea/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2012 13:10:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>ryan</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[artworks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beauty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creativity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[happiness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[modernism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[post modernism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sculpture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[truth]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://simplymarvelousreally.wordpress.com/?p=936</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[For 2 weeks each year in Sydney the 2km coastal walk from Bondi beach to Tamarama beach is transformed during the Sculpture by the Sea exhibition. This afternoon I checked it out, though so far I haven&#8217;t been able to see all the works &#8211; a return visit may be in order. I love this [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=936&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://simplymarvelousreally.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/100_0663_2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-937" title="Stephen Marr, the optimist" alt="" src="http://simplymarvelousreally.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/100_0663_2.jpg?w=500&#038;h=374" height="374" width="500" /></a></p>
<p>For 2 weeks each year in Sydney the 2km coastal walk from Bondi beach to Tamarama beach is transformed during the <a href="http://www.sculpturebythesea.com/Home.aspx" target="_blank">Sculpture by the Sea</a> exhibition. This afternoon I checked it out, though so far I haven&#8217;t been able to see all the works &#8211; a return visit may be in order. I love this exhibition. So too does the rest of Sydney, judging by the crowds even in the late afternoon. Each year at this time the coastal walk becomes jammed with people enjoying the elegant, the quirky and sometimes the downright weird, all with a beautiful seaside view. I love the crowds for this reason: instead of festering in some whitewashed gallery art is out in the public space and people are getting out there and enjoying it. The only drawback of so many people being there at once is the effect on the relationship between the sculptures, the space they&#8217;re placed in and the viewer &#8211; where I feel sculpture&#8217;s power really lies. Finding a quiet time for a viewing has its benefits.</p>
<p><a href="http://simplymarvelousreally.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/100_0649_2.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-938" title="Takahiro Hirata, dark night shine" alt="" src="http://simplymarvelousreally.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/100_0649_2.jpg?w=300&#038;h=224" height="224" width="300" /></a></p>
<p>Still, there&#8217;s something I love about going with the rest of the world too. It raises a question for me: What is it with art and the public? Why do I have this perception of most people scorning art and yet when something like this is put on it seems half the city &#8211; young, old, families and singles &#8211; turns up? Is it just that people &#8216;just like to go to things&#8217;, as someone put it to me this week? That is, do they not really care about the art at all, but just go along to whatever&#8217;s &#8216;happening&#8217; this weekend for something to do?</p>
<p>No doubt there are some. But I love the sort of thing I saw today. When a big name gets a show, like a Picasso or Rothko retrospective, I have a tendency, justified or not, to think a lot of people might be drawn just by the name, especially in Australia where the big names are displayed so rarely. But there are no big names in Bondi, yet people are really interested in the works. They take photographs, they laugh, they pick their favourites. They aren&#8217;t generally interested in the way we&#8217;re told interest in art is supposed to manifest itself: dispassionately deconstructing everything to find the deeper &#8216;meaning&#8217; in the work. Sadly there is still a strong sense for people that that&#8217;s exactly the way art has to be appreciated and the completely obtuse and indecipherable works that follow this artistic philosophy themselves only serve to continue enforcing this sense by alienating the very people they&#8217;re <a href="http://simplymarvelousreally.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/100_0658_2.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-942" title="Hilde Danielsen, upside down again" alt="" src="http://simplymarvelousreally.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/100_0658_2.jpg?w=300&#038;h=224" height="224" width="300" /></a>supposed to be communicating with. The great legacy of modern art has been to drive a wedge in people&#8217;s thinking between their life and visual creativity. But after people have stood mutely and impassively in front of them for a few moments (myself included) they move on to the stuff that&#8217;s actually cool and connects with them and their experience in some way, and often quite simply. It&#8217;s obvious in the comparison between works which always have a crowd of snap happy and grinning people around them (again myself included) and those which are left sadly alone. The works people love explore and re-imagine the beauty of this world or the human experience of living itself. The works I&#8217;ve snapped here were some of my favourites which I felt did just that.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://simplymarvelousreally.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/100_0644_2.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-944 aligncenter" title="Paul Kaptein, and in the endless pauses, there came a sound" alt="" src="http://simplymarvelousreally.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/100_0644_2.jpg?w=300&#038;h=224" height="224" width="300" /></a></p>
<p>The incessantly elitist and deconstructing nature of so much modern and post modern art (and talk about it) in the west has cultural and philosophical roots reaching back a couple of centuries , but the creative impulse has spanned human existence across cultures and centuries and has elsewhere always been much more closely tied to the lived experience of a culture&#8217;s people and their relationship with the wider world around them. I&#8217;ve said this before <a href="http://simplymarvelousreally.wordpress.com/2012/04/25/on-why-youre-an-art-lover/">here</a>.  &#8217;Art&#8217; wasn&#8217;t the intellectual domain of a specific subculture who were in the &#8216;know&#8217;. You didn&#8217;t need an &#8216;art appreciation course&#8217; (spare me) to engage with it. It reflected and still reflects <em>life</em>. In future posts I&#8217;d like to explore further how contemporary art is trying to reflect and speak to how we in the west tend to view the world and our lives, for I think there&#8217;s much to be said. But I wouldn&#8217;t hold your breath if I was you.</p>
<p>For now though, let me say that I think there is a real desire in people&#8217;s hearts for beauty and truth in the world, and for people to engage with and express it through acts of creativity. And there is a joy when it&#8217;s done.</p>
<p><strong>What do you think? Do people love good art or am I mistaken? Do you enjoy art, and if so, what do you love about it? </strong></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/936/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/936/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=936&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://simplymarvelousreally.wordpress.com/2012/10/28/sculpture-by-the-sea/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/d3125665fe96cf5321f488350f8e7b93?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">dirtwithbreath</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://simplymarvelousreally.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/100_0663_2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Stephen Marr, the optimist</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://simplymarvelousreally.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/100_0649_2.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Takahiro Hirata, dark night shine</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://simplymarvelousreally.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/100_0658_2.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Hilde Danielsen, upside down again</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://simplymarvelousreally.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/100_0644_2.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Paul Kaptein, and in the endless pauses, there came a sound</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Homage to the Muse</title>
		<link>http://calebhamm.wordpress.com/2012/09/06/homage-to-the-muse/</link>
		<comments>http://calebhamm.wordpress.com/2012/09/06/homage-to-the-muse/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2012 20:35:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>calebhamm</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Arts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Expression]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fine Arts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mixed Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Musical]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Paintings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spiritual]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[abstract]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[acrylics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[busker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cellist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fiddler]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[folk singer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[forest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gouache]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[musical subjects]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oil painting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[songwriter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[street musician]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[troubadour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[violinist]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://calebhamm.wordpress.com/?p=191</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Music has always played an integral role in my creative process. The Mood, the idea, the movement and style of all my work is strongly influenced by music of all genres. As a singer songwriter I occasionally find myself writing songs about art, so painting pictures with musical subjects only seems reciprocally fitting. Music has [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=191&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Music has always played an integral role in my creative process. The Mood, the idea, the movement and style of all my work is strongly influenced by music of all genres. As a singer songwriter I occasionally find myself writing songs about art, so painting pictures with musical subjects only seems reciprocally fitting. Music has the power to evoke endless emotions from its listener. Unbiased and never bound by labels and expectations, music is a powerful muse that forever expresses new creative avenues.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-179" title="The Fiddler" src="http://calebhamm.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/the-fiddler.jpg?w=489&#038;h=378" alt="" width="489" height="378" /></p>
<p>The Fiddler</p>
<p><a href="http://calebhamm.wordpress.com/2012/09/06/homage-to-the-muse/the-cellist/" rel="attachment wp-att-196"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-196" title="The Cellist" src="http://calebhamm.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/the-cellist-e1346961775822.jpg?w=488&#038;h=452" alt="" width="488" height="452" /></a></p>
<p>The Cellist</p>
<p><img class="alignnone  wp-image-200" title="The Rambler" src="http://calebhamm.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/the-rambler-e1346962013145.jpg?w=497&#038;h=495" alt="" width="497" height="495" /></p>
<p>The Rambler</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-206" title="Troubadour" src="http://calebhamm.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/troubadour.jpg?w=499&#038;h=857" alt="" width="499" height="857" /></p>
<p>Troubadour</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/191/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/191/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=191&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://calebhamm.wordpress.com/2012/09/06/homage-to-the-muse/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/ea0c66d40a47d5c3bf58dd49224858a7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">calebhamm</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://calebhamm.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/the-fiddler.jpg?w=800" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The Fiddler</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://calebhamm.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/the-cellist-e1346961775822.jpg?w=800" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The Cellist</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://calebhamm.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/the-rambler-e1346962013145.jpg?w=800" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The Rambler</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://calebhamm.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/troubadour.jpg?w=596" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Troubadour</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Sci-Fi?</title>
		<link>http://epicipseity.wordpress.com/2012/10/26/why-sci-fi/</link>
		<comments>http://epicipseity.wordpress.com/2012/10/26/why-sci-fi/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2012 16:03:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>epicipseity</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[change]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fantasy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[future]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[futurism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marvel universe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sci-fi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://epicipseity.wordpress.com/?p=132</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[My first short story was about a psychologist employed at a research facility in Southwestern Colorado. His employer was funded by the government to research ways to manipulate a human&#8217;s perceptions of his own reality through drugs and what was known as the Dream Room, basically a 30&#215;30 room with wall to wall 3D screens [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=132&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>My first short story was about a psychologist employed at a research facility in Southwestern Colorado. His employer was funded by the government to research ways to manipulate a human&#8217;s perceptions of his own reality through drugs and what was known as the Dream Room, basically a 30&#215;30 room with wall to wall 3D screens and interactive 4D holographic images. The patients were put into the room and then shown whatever series of images the researchers thought would work best to manipulate the patients&#8217; perception of reality.</p>
<p>It was garbage. I thought it was brilliant at the time though. And the last line, &#8220;Her smile faded over and over again, forever.&#8221; Well, I thought it was gold. I may let you read it sometime.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s science fiction. I didn&#8217;t think it so at the time, but everything I write is science fiction.</p>
<p>Is it a preference? A moral imperative? An uncontrollable urge?</p>
<p>I think it just happens that way. It&#8217;s the language by which I communicate difficult ideas to people I think may have more difficulty coming to terms with them than I do. Do I think I&#8217;m smarter than my readers? Absolutely not, and that&#8217;s why I prevent myself from writing some days. I&#8217;m afraid my readers are more intelligent than I am.</p>
<p>Consider H.G. Wells and Jules Verne &#8211; who some consider the Fathers of Science Fiction. Their works weren&#8217;t about the technology presented, it was about mankind and how he would react in the presence of such changes. Would he change? Or would he stagnate and impede the progress of his species?</p>
<p>You should read The Sleeper Awakes by H.G. Wells.</p>
<p>To me, science fiction is not about the setting, the characters, the technology. It&#8217;s not robots, aliens, spaceships, lasers. A work, to me, qualifies as science fiction if it poses a question that we have yet to answer as a species &#8211; that one day we <em>must</em> answer as a species.</p>
<p>The truth of our present is not in our past, it is in our future. Our worth should not be based on what we have done, but what we have the potential to do.</p>
<p>There is no greater commentary on both our past and present than our possible future.</p>
<p>We equate success to wealth, power, and fame &#8211; not vision, creativity, imagination.</p>
<p>We waste a great deal of time defending the traditions of generations long past as the road map to our future. We concern ourselves with where we sit in comparison with the rest of the world, and where we came from, when our lives should be dedicated to progress &#8211; the forward motion of our species into the frontier that lies just beyond where we&#8217;ve become comfortable existing.</p>
<p>The human species&#8217; worst enemy is the human species we were yesterday.</p>
<p>We have allowed this idea of permanence to pervade and infect our culture, whether social, civil, military, corporate, or spiritual. We find contentment and then vehemently protest the movement away from that comfort zone. That &#8230; is &#8230; stagnation. We find our cash cow, and then rail against the cash machine. We inherit a prime location, and we won&#8217;t part with it for FEAR that we might not find something better.</p>
<p>I listen to a lot of news radio and I&#8217;m disturbed by the amount of paid advertising the oil corporations are putting out there pushing and pushing for continued support of their livelihood, regardless of its effect on the environment, more advanced initiatives, cleaner technology. It sickens me. It is the equivalent of the horse trader sabotaging the steam engine. The pickaxe maker spreading rumors about the dangers of mining machinery. The abacus entrepreneur swearing that the calculator causes cancer. The Flat-Earth believer stoning Copernicus. The monotheist tribe slaughtering the polytheist tribe.</p>
<p>The Promethean flame evolves, and we must evolve with it, eagle be damned.</p>
<p><em>That</em> is why sci-fi.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/132/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/132/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=132&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://epicipseity.wordpress.com/2012/10/26/why-sci-fi/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/020c9262ced766dc8f6dccd9783b390b?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">epicipseity</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ten &#8220;Mainland Moments&#8221; in Hangzhou</title>
		<link>http://expatlingo.com/2012/10/27/ten-mainland-moments-in-hangzhou/</link>
		<comments>http://expatlingo.com/2012/10/27/ten-mainland-moments-in-hangzhou/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2012 13:57:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>expatlingo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[air pollution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beautiful]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cultural differences]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[expat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hangzhou]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hong Kong]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hong Kong vs. Mainland China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[living abroad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mainland China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel with children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[West Lake]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://expatlingo.com/?p=2694</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[My heart was happy to touch down in Mainland China after three and a half years away. My lungs recoiled. And my mind fully confirmed that Hong Kong is on another planet from &#8220;The Motherland.&#8221; Hangzhou itself surpassed my expectations. West Lake and the surrounding gardens are truly gorgeous. Exactly what you imagine &#8220;romantic,&#8221; &#8220;exotic,&#8221; [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2694&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_2695" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 533px"><a href="http://expatlingo.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/img_5750.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-2695" title="Sunset over West Lake, Hangzhou, China" alt="" src="http://expatlingo.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/img_5750.jpg?w=523&#038;h=392" height="392" width="523" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Sunset over undeniably beautiful West Lake, Hangzhou.</p></div>
<p>My heart was happy to touch down in Mainland China after three and a half years away. My lungs recoiled. And my mind fully confirmed that Hong Kong is on another planet from &#8220;The Motherland.&#8221;</p>
<p>Hangzhou itself surpassed my expectations. West Lake and the surrounding gardens are truly gorgeous. Exactly what you imagine &#8220;romantic,&#8221; &#8220;exotic,&#8221; &#8220;foreign&#8221; China is like: tall golden-spired pagodas, green willow trees hanging over lotus-ringed ponds, pavilions used as informal stages by Chinese classical musicians, charming tea houses, and elaborately carved wooden pleasure boats.</p>
<p>Unbelievably, none of it was marred by garbage cans in the shape of penguins or speakers in the shape of mushrooms blaring tinny music.</p>
<p>The main draw-backs were the matching-capped tour groups whose leaders amplified their talks by microphone, and the non-stop, over-the-top attention my two children drew. My one-year-old son &#8212; so long as no one tried to pick him up &#8212; took to it like Miss America, waving to everyone. My five-year-old daughter adopted a duck-and-weave approach to avoid the many hands reaching to stroke her hair and clouds of camera phones seeking to take her picture.</p>
<p>Good and bad, here are ten things that marked our week in Hangzhou and made the Mainland feel temporarily &#8220;like home&#8221; again:</p>
<ol>
<li><em><strong>Gawking at young women in hot pants with black nylons and half-boot/half-sandal-shoes and young men with big, coiffed hair.</strong></em> The fashions are like no other and a world apart from the understated black framed glasses and Converse sneakers that the youth of Hong Kong wear.</li>
<li><em><strong>The pleasure of reading simplified characters.</strong></em> Hey, look! That sign says they sell Hangzhou-produced, specialty products!</li>
<li><em><strong>Playing &#8220;stupid&#8221; as needed.</strong></em> Voice says: &#8220;Wo ting bu dong.&#8221; Internal dialogue says: &#8220;Yes I understand that you are asking what country I am from and if I like Hangzhou, but I have already had this conversation many, many times today and am pretending that I don&#8217;t understand. Though why you&#8217;d guess that I&#8217;m French is beyond me.&#8221;</li>
<li><em><strong>Opaque, brown air.</strong></em> A politically savvy meteorologist might charitably call it &#8220;haze&#8221;:<br />
<a href="http://expatlingo.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/img_5614.jpg"><img class="aligncenter" title="Brown, gloomy air in Hangzhou, China" alt="" src="http://expatlingo.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/img_5614.jpg?w=314&#038;h=418" height="418" width="314" /></a></li>
<li><em><strong>Non-stop construction.</strong></em> Looking at the city, rather than West Lake, one can see a forest of cranes. As in every Chinese city.</li>
<li><em><strong>Non-stop honking and &#8220;catch-as-catch-can&#8221; style of driving.</strong></em> &#8221;I drive a BMW so of course I can use the road shoulder to pass at-will&#8221; or &#8220;this one-way street is a trifling inconvenience to be ignored.&#8221;</li>
<li><em><strong>&#8220;Living out loud.&#8221;</strong></em> Tai chi is commonly practiced in public places, but the wide assortment of other public pursuits is astounding: swinging giant poles around within inches of a crowded walkway, ballroom dancing, group &#8220;jazz-style&#8221; dancing, and this flamboyant singing and dancing duo:<a href="http://expatlingo.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/img_5731.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2697" title="Hangzhou street performance" alt="" src="http://expatlingo.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/img_5731.jpg?w=523&#038;h=169" height="169" width="523" /></a></li>
<li><em><strong>Surprising English world choices.</strong></em> The glittery fashion clothing store called &#8220;Slavery&#8221; or the banner welcoming the &#8220;Mock Survey Consultants&#8221; to a local hotel.</li>
<li><em><strong>The Great Firewall of China.</strong></em> Sigh. At least I could access the New York Times for the first four days of the trip. Then it was gone. Of course I immediately sought to find out why: ah yes the story of Wen Jiabao&#8217;s family wealth.</li>
<li><em><strong>Knock-offs</strong><strong>.</strong><strong> </strong></em>SPR Coffee: the chain vaguely like Starbucks. The same dark green in the logo. And the same lighting pendants of any Starbucks circa 1998. With prices as high as the &#8220;real thing&#8221; and with the real thing now on almost every corner, I see the sun setting on the SPR empire.</li>
</ol>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2694/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2694/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2694&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://expatlingo.com/2012/10/27/ten-mainland-moments-in-hangzhou/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/543bb80438c3871018675ffbf378ee03?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">expatlingo</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://expatlingo.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/img_5750.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Sunset over West Lake, Hangzhou, China</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://expatlingo.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/img_5614.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Brown, gloomy air in Hangzhou, China</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://expatlingo.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/img_5731.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Hangzhou street performance</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Conserving Culture and Conserving Nature: Assets and Liabilities</title>
		<link>http://vincemichael.wordpress.com/2012/10/27/conserving-culture-and-conserving-nature-assets-and-liabilities/</link>
		<comments>http://vincemichael.wordpress.com/2012/10/27/conserving-culture-and-conserving-nature-assets-and-liabilities/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2012 03:16:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>vmichael</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Global Heritage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Global Heritage Fund]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[historic preservation; preservation economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[world heritage]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vincemichael.wordpress.com/?p=4221</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The World Heritage Convention is nearing the end of its 40th anniversary, and since what we do here at Global Heritage Fund is help preserve World Heritage Sites in developing countries, I have been fielding a lot of inquiries on the status of the World Heritage Convention. As in so many aspects of heritage conservation/historic [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4221&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The World Heritage Convention is nearing the end of its 40th anniversary, and since what we do here at <a href="http://www.globalheritagefund.org/">Global Heritage Fund</a> is help preserve World Heritage Sites in developing countries, I have been fielding a lot of inquiries on the status of the World Heritage Convention.  As in so many aspects of heritage conservation/historic preservation, I have seen evolution in the field.  In terms of sites inscribed on the World Heritage list, I would venture that we have seen some of the same shifts we have seen in &#8220;historic preservation&#8221; as a whole.</p>
<p><a href="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/world-her-glob1.jpg"><img src="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/world-her-glob1.jpg?w=450&#038;h=599" alt="" title="world her glob1" width="450" height="599" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4254" /></a></p>
<p>When World Heritage began in 1972, it focused, like the rest of the field, on iconic and visual landmarks that were clearly identified with their countries or cultures, places like the Taj Mahal and Machu Picchu and the Statue of Liberty<br />
<a href="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/taj-mahal2.jpg"><img src="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/taj-mahal2.jpg?w=450&#038;h=662" alt="" title="taj mahal2" width="450" height="662" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4223" /></a><br />
<em>Been there, done that (1986)</em><br />
<a href="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/the-great-view2s.jpg"><img src="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/the-great-view2s.jpg?w=450&#038;h=337" alt="" title="the great view2s" width="450" height="337" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4224" /></a><br />
<em>I shot this in January 2012</em><br />
<a href="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/statue-liberty.jpg"><img src="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/statue-liberty.jpg?w=450&#038;h=599" alt="" title="statue liberty" width="450" height="599" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4225" /></a><br />
<em>2010, summer</em></p>
<p>Interestingly, this focus on &#8220;monuments&#8221; which characterized much of our field well into the 1980s, also included natural areas.  Indeed, one of the curiosities of World Heritage status is that much of the world has used it to register key cultural sites that are architectural and artistic, like Versailles and Khajuraho and Suzhou&#8217;s gardens, while the U.S. used it mostly for national parks like Yellowstone and the Great Smoky Mountains, and very early historical sites like Cahokia Mounds and Independence Hall.<br />
<a href="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/versailles-ent.jpg"><img src="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/versailles-ent.jpg?w=450&#038;h=312" alt="" title="versailles ent" width="450" height="312" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4226" /></a><br />
<em>1982, my first trip to Europe</em><br />
<a href="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/khajuraho5_1.jpg"><img src="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/khajuraho5_1.jpg?w=450&#038;h=680" alt="" title="khajuraho5_1" width="450" height="680" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4227" /></a><br />
<em>1986 again.  Who knew the Internet existed in the 10th century?</em><br />
<a href="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/liongrv-gdn-pond-pavils.jpg"><img src="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/liongrv-gdn-pond-pavils.jpg?w=450&#038;h=337" alt="" title="Liongrv gdn pond pavilS" width="450" height="337" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4228" /></a><br />
<em>Dear Suzhou, Lion Grove gardens, just this last June</em><br />
<a href="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/girls-monks-mounds.jpg"><img src="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/girls-monks-mounds.jpg?w=450&#038;h=338" alt="" title="girls monks moundS" width="450" height="338" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4229" /></a><br />
<em>Monk&#8217;s Mounds, Cahokia, 2008</em><br />
<a href="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/ih-main-tower3.jpg"><img src="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/ih-main-tower3.jpg?w=450&#038;h=599" alt="" title="IH main tower3" width="450" height="599" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4230" /></a><br />
<em>Independence Hall in 2010.</em></p>
<p>The Europeans have even inscribed modern architecture on the World Heritage list, while the U.S. has only just gotten around to doing a Frank Lloyd Wright listing that is still being nominated.  The addition of modern architecture to the mission of heritage conservation happened early in Chicago, but only starting in the late 1980s elsewhere.<br />
<a href="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/troos-schroder-house0s.jpg"><img src="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/troos-schroder-house0s.jpg?w=450&#038;h=337" alt="" title="troos schroder house0s" width="450" height="337" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4231" /></a><br />
<em>Rietveld Schröderhuis, shot in 2010.  Man, that was a busy year</em></p>
<p>Now, there were many iconic places on the World Heritage list from the beginning that were collections of monuments, essentially historic districts, such as the city centers of places like Rome and Florence and Salzburg and L&#8217;viv and Quebec and Cusco.  City centers or historic districts make up a significant percentage of the sites, and even in an archaeologically rich country like Peru, your World Heritage Sites are as likely to be cities as they are archaeological sites.<br />
<a href="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/firenze82.jpg"><img src="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/firenze82.jpg?w=450&#038;h=315" alt="" title="firenze82" width="450" height="315" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4232" /></a><br />
<em>Firenze, 1982 again</em><br />
<a href="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/lviv-facades-twns1.jpg"><img src="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/lviv-facades-twns1.jpg?w=450&#038;h=338" alt="" title="lviv facades twnS" width="450" height="338" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4233" /></a><br />
<em>L&#8217;viv (L&#8217;viw) 2006</em><br />
<a href="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/cusco-main-plaza2s.jpg"><img src="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/cusco-main-plaza2s.jpg?w=450&#038;h=337" alt="" title="cusco main plaza2s" width="450" height="337" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4234" /></a><br />
<em>Cusco, January 2012</em></p>
<p>The criteria for these sites can be summarized by the phrase &#8220;outstanding universal value,&#8221; a phrase with meaning that has clearly shifted a bit over 40 years.  Just as our heritage practice has expanded beyond monuments to districts and cultural landscapes, so we have expanded beyond a European notion of the artifact to include Eastern ideas about intangible heritage.  China has proposed for inscription villages in Guizhou that we are currently investigating, and there the significance lies in their preservation of the intangible cultural heritage of minority groups like the Miao and Dong.  Many of the newer listings are described as &#8220;cultural landscapes.&#8221;  One of my favorites was the Wachau, a stretch of towns, vineyards and drop dead Baroque churches along the Danube River in Austria.<br />
<a href="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/stfmlk-stteepll.jpg"><img src="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/stfmlk-stteepll.jpg?w=450&#038;h=337" alt="" title="stfmlk stteepll" width="450" height="337" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4235" /></a><br />
<em>Stift Melk, 2005</em><br />
<a href="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/durnstein-ab.jpg"><img src="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/durnstein-ab.jpg?w=450&#038;h=337" alt="" title="durnstein ab" width="450" height="337" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4236" /></a><br />
<em>Durnstein, 2005</em><br />
<a href="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/steingkreis-alex-lauf.jpg"><img src="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/steingkreis-alex-lauf.jpg?w=450&#038;h=337" alt="" title="steingkreis alex lauf" width="450" height="337" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4237" /></a><br />
<em>Celtic stone circle in Nesselstauden, also 2005</em></p>
<p>Now, the World Heritage list has three categories: Cultural, Natural, and Mixed, and all three are still inscribed each year.  A lot of these are iconic as well, places like Ha Long Bay in Vietnam and the Great Barrier Reef in Australia.<br />
<a href="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/halong-bay1.jpg"><img src="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/halong-bay1.jpg?w=450&#038;h=652" alt="" title="halong bay" width="450" height="652" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4238" /></a><br />
<em>Halong Bay, Vietnam.  2001.  This is getting to be like a James Bond movie location list.</em></p>
<p>Archaeological sites are frequent on the list as well, both cultural ones, like Chavin de Huantar in Peru, where GHF has been working for almost a decade, and sites like the 2012 listing for a seam of dinosaur fossils in China. Another site we worked on, Catalhoyuk in Turkey, was inscribed this year, and our other project there, Göbekli Tepe, is very likely to be inscribed soon.  Archaeological sites require conservation from the moment they are unearthed, but they also reveal in their investigation their &#8220;outstanding universal value.&#8221;<br />
<a href="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/bldg-77_end-of-season_2010.jpg"><img src="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/bldg-77_end-of-season_2010.jpg?w=450&#038;h=298" alt="" title="Conservation of wall paintings and incised panel in Building 77" width="450" height="298" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4251" /></a><br />
<em>Catalhoyuk, Building 77, 2010.  Global Heritage Fund photo by Banu Aydinoglugil</em></p>
<p>I field a lot of questions from reporters about how World Heritage listing protects sites, and of course the answer is that the listing alone cannot restore or even protect sites, as the 2001 destruction of the Bamiyan Buddhas and the current destruction of Islamic World Heritage sites (by Islamic rebels &#8211; it&#8217;s complicated) in Mali at Djenne and Timbuktu proves.  Like any landmark status, World Heritage opens doors to funding, generates public and private support for protection, but relies of local laws for protection.  We learned this working in Lima, another historic city centre.  And of course, it has been in the news with the civill war in Syria.<br />
<a href="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/ancash-biggies.jpg"><img src="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/ancash-biggies.jpg?w=450&#038;h=289" alt="" title="ancash biggieS" width="450" height="289" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4239" /></a><br />
<em>Barrios Altos, Lima, 2012</em></p>
<p>World Heritage status can also generate tourism, as sites like Lijiang in China have demonstrated.  In fact, it can generate too much, as both Machu Picchu and Angkor have learned.<br />
<a href="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/lijiang-st19b.jpg"><img src="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/lijiang-st19b.jpg?w=450&#038;h=599" alt="" title="lijiang st19b" width="450" height="599" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4240" /></a><br />
<em>Lijiang, 2008.  I was also there in 2004.</em><br />
<a href="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/city-to-terracess.jpg"><img src="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/city-to-terracess.jpg?w=450&#038;h=337" alt="" title="city to terracesS" width="450" height="337" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4241" /></a><br />
<em>Looking the other way at Machu Picchu.  Toward the terraces that made it all possible.  2012.</em><br />
<a href="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/view-to-galls-f-top26.jpg"><img src="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/view-to-galls-f-top26.jpg?w=450&#038;h=337" alt="" title="view to galls f top26" width="450" height="337" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4242" /></a><br />
<em>Crowding out Angkor Wat, 2012.  I guess this was a busy year too.</em></p>
<p>Natural.  Cultural.  I was sitting in the forest at home looking at the trees a few nights ago and I had a revelation about the difference between natural area conservation and historic preservation (heritage conservation).  It is an economic difference, that has significant implications for those of us who try to achieve these things.  Even more importantly, it has implications for how we raise money to achieve preservation of cultural sites.</p>
<p><a href="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/falun-mine9.jpg"><img src="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/falun-mine9.jpg?w=450&#038;h=337" alt="" title="falun mine9" width="450" height="337" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4243" /></a><br />
<em>One of my favorite World Heritage sites, Falun, a 300-year old open pit mine in Sweden.  Photo from 2007.</em></p>
<p>Because if you look at the tourism angle, or even the house museum angle, you might see a great parallel between natural area conservation and heritage conservation of things like archaeological sites or house museums.  Both require large infusions of cash and the only return they provide is from gate receipts, which typically only provide a fifth of the operating costs, not to mention capital costs.</p>
<p><a href="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/ellora-161.jpg"><img src="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/ellora-161.jpg?w=450&#038;h=308" alt="" title="ellora 16" width="450" height="308" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4244" /></a><br />
<em>Cave 16 (Kailasa) at Ellora, India.  1986.  My FAVORITE heritage site.  An entire temple, carved out of the side of the mountain from the top down.  Twice the scale of the Parthenon.  Way.  Wicked.  Cool.</em><br />
<a href="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/ellora-16abv.jpg"><img src="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/ellora-16abv.jpg?w=450&#038;h=675" alt="" title="ellora 16abv" width="450" height="675" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4245" /></a></p>
<p>It occured to me that when I help restore a historic World Heritage city like Pingyao, I am activating an asset.  It may take some capital infusion to get it going, as we did by restoring courtyard houses there, but now the municipality is sponsoring grants to restore more houses, and new projects are activating this rich walled city.  Pingyao is an asset, and it is an economic engine.<br />
<a href="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/py-market-towers.jpg"><img src="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/py-market-towers.jpg?w=450&#038;h=599" alt="" title="PY market towerS" width="450" height="599" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4246" /></a><br />
<em>VROOM VROOM!  June of this year.</em></p>
<p>Whereas if I am trying to save a wonderful natural landscape, I am working on the other side of the ledger.  Wetlands and rainforests are obviously important, but in economic terms they are a liability.  Now, having said that, I live in a place where real estate values are insane partly due to the amount of preserved natural areas.  This is the idea behind common pool resource theory: the value of the natural area is alienated to the surrounding real estate.  But to save it, you are still dealing with a liability, even if you tax all the surrounding property based on the increment it is earning from the conservation.</p>
<p>Natural area conservation is dealing with NON USE Value while much &#8211; most, I would argue &#8211; of historic preservation is dealing with USE Value.  Conserving a natural area is a permanent drain on fiscal resources, but as Pingyao demonstrates, once you get a capital infusion into an historic building or district, it becomes a productive member of the economy, and can often pay its own way.  Indeed, it should pay its own way.</p>
<p><a href="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/ks-vac-stores.jpg"><img src="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/ks-vac-stores.jpg?w=450&#038;h=337" alt="" title="ks vac stores" width="450" height="337" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4252" /></a><br />
<em>Krems, Austria, 2005</em><br />
What this means for organizations like mine is that not only is our mission different, but our way of raising funds is different, and can shift from a charitable to a business mode in a way conservation organizations can not.  This is the idea behind an idea I have been working on with our Board of Trustees called GHF 2.0, which posits that we can become a more efficient organization by leveraging conservation, archaeological, architectural and economic development expertise through a model that recognizes that we are saving assets, not liabilities, and that they can become generative economic assets.</p>
<p><a href="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/shuanglin-who-plq.jpg"><img src="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/shuanglin-who-plq.jpg?w=450&#038;h=337" alt="" title="shuanglin WHO plq" width="450" height="337" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-4255" /></a><br />
I don&#8217;t know if the World Heritage Convention thought of this in 1972 &#8211; I kind of doubt it, because we are still fighting our way out of the curatorial ghetto.  But in 29 3/4 years of practice, I have seen how these engines work and I will continue to tune and prime them in the effort to save sites of outstanding universal value in a way that insures their social, environmental, cultural and economic sustainability.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4221/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4221/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4221&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://vincemichael.wordpress.com/2012/10/27/conserving-culture-and-conserving-nature-assets-and-liabilities/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a0bc2a15cbbda804baccabc4868b7f08?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">vmichael</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/world-her-glob1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">world her glob1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/taj-mahal2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">taj mahal2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/the-great-view2s.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">the great view2s</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/statue-liberty.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">statue liberty</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/versailles-ent.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">versailles ent</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/khajuraho5_1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">khajuraho5_1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/liongrv-gdn-pond-pavils.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Liongrv gdn pond pavilS</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/girls-monks-mounds.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">girls monks moundS</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/ih-main-tower3.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IH main tower3</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/troos-schroder-house0s.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">troos schroder house0s</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/firenze82.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">firenze82</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/lviv-facades-twns1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lviv facades twnS</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/cusco-main-plaza2s.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cusco main plaza2s</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/stfmlk-stteepll.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">stfmlk stteepll</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/durnstein-ab.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">durnstein ab</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/steingkreis-alex-lauf.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">steingkreis alex lauf</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/halong-bay1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">halong bay</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/bldg-77_end-of-season_2010.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Conservation of wall paintings and incised panel in Building 77</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/ancash-biggies.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ancash biggieS</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/lijiang-st19b.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lijiang st19b</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/city-to-terracess.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">city to terracesS</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/view-to-galls-f-top26.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">view to galls f top26</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/falun-mine9.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">falun mine9</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/ellora-161.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ellora 16</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/ellora-16abv.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ellora 16abv</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/py-market-towers.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">PY market towerS</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/ks-vac-stores.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ks vac stores</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://vincemichael.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/shuanglin-who-plq.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">shuanglin WHO plq</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>My 2013 CrossFit Games</title>
		<link>http://juliefoucher.com/2012/10/27/my-2013-crossfit-games/</link>
		<comments>http://juliefoucher.com/2012/10/27/my-2013-crossfit-games/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2012 23:39:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>juliefoucher</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://juliefoucher.com/?p=179</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;How do you balance medical school and CrossFit?&#8221; This is the one question to which it seems everyone wants to know the answer. I usually just smile or laugh and remark with a similar expression of perplexity, &#8220;I don&#8217;t know either &#8211; I&#8217;m still trying to figure it out!&#8221; I could talk about time management [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=179&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>&#8220;How do you balance medical school and CrossFit?&#8221;</em> This is the one question to which it seems everyone wants to know the answer. I usually just smile or laugh and remark with a similar expression of perplexity, <em>&#8220;I don&#8217;t know either &#8211; I&#8217;m still trying to figure it out!&#8221;</em> I could talk about time management tips and strategies for maximizing efficiency, but those who are close to me know that I am <em>far</em> from mastering any of these skills. The truth of the matter is that in my experience, more importantly than time management, achieving balance begins with defining reasonable goals.</p>
<p>Last year, I entered medical school at the<a title="Cleveland Clinic Lerner College of Medicine" href="http://portals.clevelandclinic.org/cclcm/Home/tabid/4257/Default.aspx"> Cleveland Clinic Lerner College of Medicine </a>with a goal of also competing in the 2012 <a title="CrossFit Games" href="http://games.crossfit.com/">CrossFit Games</a>. With a good understanding of the first-year curriculum, I knew that it would be possible to dedicate the necessary time to training while still fulfilling my medical school requirements. Knowing that the path toward these two tasks I was simultaneously attempting to surmount would be physically, mentally, and emotionally draining, it was also important for me to spend time reflecting on why I wanted to pursue each one. As the year progressed, this reflection would prove invaluable as I reminded myself of these reasons with each moment of doubt, frustration, or exhaustion along the way, empowering me to steadily press forward.  The incredible support of family and close friends in and out of the gym also kept me focused and reminded me of what is truly most important in life.</p>
<p>Based purely on my own limited experience, here is my best advice for achieving balance:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Identify your goals and what motivates you, <em>deep down</em>, to achieve them.</strong> Why do you want to compete in the CrossFit Games? Or pursue a particular degree, or job? Will this reason be enough to sustain you when the path toward this goal becomes dark and windy?</li>
<li><strong>Decide how much time you have to dedicate to each goal.</strong> No matter who you are, there are only 24 hours in a day. My engineering degree is more than a year old now, but I can still do this math: the more goals you have, the less time you have to spend on each one. Family, friends, jobs, etc are <em>all</em> important &#8211; prioritize and make sure you spend time on the things that matter most to <em>you</em>.</li>
<li><strong><em>Work like crazy</em> with the time you have dedicated to each goal to reach and surpass it.</strong> Give 100% effort to whatever you are doing in each moment of time.*</li>
<li><strong>Have reasonable expectations.</strong>  If you only dedicate 3 hours per week to training, no matter how hard you work during those 3 hours it<em> might</em> be unreasonable to expect to stand on top of the podium at next year&#8217;s CrossFit Games (but hey, who&#8217;s to say?).</li>
<li><strong>Avoid the temptation to compare yourself to others</strong> who have completely different lives and sets of goals. If you are dedicating 3 hours per week of training it would be hard to compare yourself to another athlete in the CrossFit Games Open or Regionals who has the luxury of putting in 15 hours.  <em>Stand firm</em> in your original motivations and the goals you set for yourself and <em>celebrate each of your personal accomplishments.</em></li>
<li><strong>Take time to reflect.</strong> As you work steadily toward your goals, it is important to periodically stop and notice your progress. Notice whether your goals or motivations have changed, and re-direct as necessary.</li>
</ol>
<p><em>     *Note: This in itself is a lofty goal and one that I struggle most with! </em></p>
<p>Now comes the hard part: it is time to take my own advice. As I look toward the upcoming year, I again must define my goals and ask myself why I am choosing to pursue each one. This second year of medical school is a critical one in my program, with increased classroom commitments and a significant demand to prepare for the first medical board exam in June. As I pursue my goal of becoming the best physician I can be, this year stands out as one that will lay the groundwork for caring for patients in the future. Recognizing the importance of this goal and the time commitment  necessary to pursue it, I know that this year it must be prioritized above others, including competing in the 2013 <a title="CrossFit Games" href="http://games.crossfit.com/">CrossFit Games.</a> As much as it pains me to consider not competing in the sport I love, that has become a part of who I am and who I aspire to become, I know that in this particular year, I have another goal that has to take precedence. I have considered every possibility (believe me, <em>every</em> possibility), and I have decided that rather than giving half an effort to medical school and half an effort to the <a title="CrossFit Games" href="http://games.crossfit.com/">CrossFit Games</a> this year, I must shift my focus to dedicating a full effort to school and the board exam.</p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 278px"><a href="http://juliefoucher.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/photo-1.jpg"><img id="i-178" class="    " alt="" src="http://juliefoucher.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/photo-1.jpg?w=268&#038;h=311" height="311" width="268" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The USMLE Step 1 &#8211; My 2013 CrossFit Games</p></div>
<p>It is important to set our goals high and to push ourselves beyond what we think we are capable of so that we may ultimately reach our full potential.  I believe it is also important to remember that we are human &#8211; and that some goals are just too important to sacrifice. I would never want to look back on this year and my career and wonder whether I could have done better had I not been distracted by training for the <a title="CrossFit Games" href="http://games.crossfit.com/">CrossFit Games</a>. This year my goal is to crush the USMLE Step 1 exam, and in order to reach my full potential in this endeavor I know it requires me to sacrifice training for the 2013 <a title="CrossFit Games" href="http://games.crossfit.com/">CrossFit Games</a>. But don&#8217;t you worry &#8211; I&#8217;ve still got my eye on the top of the podium in 2014, and training for<em> that</em> particular goal starts today.  <img src='http://s1.wp.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif' alt=';)' class='wp-smiley' /> </p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/179/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/179/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=179&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://juliefoucher.com/2012/10/27/my-2013-crossfit-games/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>30</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/9fc0ed95646e97d10d223626385522c0?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">juliefoucher</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://juliefoucher.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/photo-1.jpg?w=1014" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>You Should Be Ashamed of Yourself</title>
		<link>http://jakefrackson.wordpress.com/2012/10/27/you-should-be-ashamed-of-yourself/</link>
		<comments>http://jakefrackson.wordpress.com/2012/10/27/you-should-be-ashamed-of-yourself/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2012 00:20:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>jakefrackson</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[philosophy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shame]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[society]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://jakefrackson.wordpress.com/?p=84</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Humanity is an organic, however, increasingly synthetic, concept. Constantly, human innovation is furthering this process. As a species, we are constantly moving away from our primal nature &#8211; for the better and the worse. An example of this is human guilt. Guilt, a natural quality to humans, has been manipulated into something foreign; we often [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=84&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Humanity is an organic, however, increasingly synthetic, concept. Constantly, human innovation is furthering this process. As a species, we are constantly moving away from our primal nature &#8211; for the better and the worse.</p>
<p>An example of this is human guilt. Guilt, a natural quality to humans, has been manipulated into something foreign; we often call this alien “shame.” This new emotion, or pseudo-emotion, has been manipulated in many ways. A variety of different goals have been achieved through the use of shame, everything from marketing campaigns to education. The latter, however, often goes unnoticed.</p>
<p>We shame students everyday into complying with our educational goals, and subconsciously we recognize this. Teachers see it constantly. A student will answer a question in a way that the teacher did not intend, so the teacher will tell the student that he is wrong. This student will immediately feel the shame of his blunder and it will manifest as embarrassment.</p>
<p>This embarrassment is sharp, yet temporary; however, the shame is personal, and persisting. Further, the shame compounds itself and slowly increases in degree. Throughout the course of a student&#8217;s education this shame can build.</p>
<p>An interesting thing about this shame though, is that it is often misinterpreted. Instead, students are often labelled as being unintelligent or even stupid. And that is a terrible mistake.</p>
<p>The recognition of failure is one thing, but there is a great difference between building off of failure and being fearful of failure. An aversion to failure is not what we need to instill in our students, rather, an understanding of failure. Being wrong needs to shift from being a flaw that needs to be remedied, to being part of a process.</p>
<p>Students gain nothing of benefit from shame. Apart from instilling an aversion to failure, shame promotes conformity, inhibits creativity and even inspires cowardice. When a student is shamed into believing he is unintelligent, a terrible change occurs: the student’s desires and ambitions fade, the student’s individuality and confidence withers, and the student becomes fearful of not meeting the standard.</p>
<p>Yet, we persist. Failure-free environments continue to be the “ideal,” and, in our pursuit of this “ideal,” we have caused, and are still causing, unimaginable harm. It is clear, change is necessary.</p>
<p>To contrast this failure-free environment, an environment where students can fail freely is required. This toxic condition needs to be remedied and in order to do this, an inversion of mass education is needed.</p>
<p>The idea that a failure is a “wrong answer,” must be revolutionized; a failure needs to be recognized as a step towards a goal. From this change, shame can be eliminated. If students inaccuracies shift from being something to be ashamed of, to simply a progression towards an ultimate goal, then this pseudo-emotion of shame would no longer be necessary.</p>
<p>The wrongs committed by shame would be able to be reversed: students could regain the vibrance of their desires and ambitions, students’ individuality and confidence could flourish, and the students would no longer need to be afraid of meeting the grade &#8211; the students could set their own standards for themselves.</p>
<p>Let this be the new ideal for education, and let the question be asked, “Who, really, should be ashamed of themselves?”</p>
<p>Jake Frackson, October 26, 2012</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/84/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/84/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=84&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://jakefrackson.wordpress.com/2012/10/27/you-should-be-ashamed-of-yourself/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>27</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/52a576542838330aa3ca4d0c5a0fb2c6?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jakefrackson</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Bitter Taste of Fish Sandwiches and Disappointment</title>
		<link>http://middleagebutch.wordpress.com/2012/10/26/the-bitter-taste-of-fish-sandwiches-and-disappointment/</link>
		<comments>http://middleagebutch.wordpress.com/2012/10/26/the-bitter-taste-of-fish-sandwiches-and-disappointment/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2012 21:41:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>middleagebutch</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fish sandwich]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lesbian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[relationships]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://middleagebutch.wordpress.com/?p=475</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As I mentioned in my previous post, W and I are going away for the night on Saturday.  We will be gambling, drinking alcohol, engaging in adult conversation and eating food that doesn&#8217;t come in disposable cardboard boxes or with a side of Ranch. As 2012 is winding down, this is probably it for us [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=475&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As I mentioned in my previous post, W and I are going away for the night on Saturday.  We will be gambling, drinking alcohol, engaging in adult conversation and eating food that doesn&#8217;t come in disposable cardboard boxes or with a side of Ranch.</p>
<p>As 2012 is winding down, this is probably it for us for the year as far as nights out without the kids.  So, there is a whole lot riding on this weekend.  We have to cram gobs of fun and romance and sexiness in a single night.  It&#8217;s a tall order.</p>
<p>I asked W if she thought the weekend would fall short of our sky-high expectations.</p>
<p>&#8220;Definitely not,&#8221; she said.</p>
<p>She is an optimist.</p>
<p>Me, not so much.</p>
<div id="attachment_478" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 283px"><a href="http://middleagebutch.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/imagescas8xflt.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-478" title="Friendly's sign" alt="" src="http://middleagebutch.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/imagescas8xflt.jpg?w=273&#038;h=184" height="184" width="273" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">My meal came without a happy ending.</p></div>
<p>High expectations and disappointment bring me back to the 80s.  (Everything brings me back to the 80s, if you haven&#8217;t noticed.)  I&#8217;m on a road trip with my college friends.  Hung-over in a major way.  We decide to stop at Friendly&#8217;s for lunch.</p>
<p>If you have ever had a serious hang-over (or a touch of &#8220;flu,&#8221; as we refer to it within my circle of friends), you know the importance of filling your tank with just the right food and beverage post why-did-I-wash-down-a-six-pack-of- pounders-with-that-bottle-of-Boone&#8217;s-Farm.</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>World&#8217;s greatest hang-over beverage:</strong> Yoo-Hoo</p>
<p><strong>World&#8217;s greatest hang-over food:</strong> Wendy&#8217;s single, ketchup only</p></blockquote>
<p>At Friendly&#8217;s, I carefully scour the menu.  I need protein.  And, liquid.  Lots of liquid.</p>
<div id="attachment_477" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 269px"><a href="http://middleagebutch.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/imagescamtl74g.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-477" title="Friendly's Fish-a-majig" alt="" src="http://middleagebutch.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/imagescamtl74g.jpg?w=259&#038;h=194" height="194" width="259" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Disappointment on a plate</p></div>
<p>I spot Friendly&#8217;s Fish-a-majig sandwich.  The name is jaunty and whimsical.  Just saying &#8220;Fish-a-majig&#8221; brings a slight smile to my lips that are still stained red from way too much sloe gin.  A fried fish sandwich would work, I think.  Yes, a Fish-a-majig.  That&#8217;s what I&#8217;ll have.  &#8221;A Fish-a-majig,&#8221; I say to myself with conviction.  I&#8217;m starting to rally already.</p>
<p>I order a Fish-a-majig, a vanilla Fribble and a bucket of water and wait for my fried fish sandwich to come.  I can already taste the soft, warm bun, the tang of tartar sauce, the crispy fish filet.</p>
<p>Fifteen minutes later when the waitress places a sad, flat sandwich in front of me, I tell her that she must be mistaken.  &#8221;I have ordered the Fish-a-majig,&#8221; I announce.  &#8220;You know, crisp, golden breaded fish,&#8221; I say.</p>
<p>Apparently, I&#8217;m the one who is mistaken.</p>
<p>The Fish-a-majig is a piece of fish bookended by two pieces of toasted white bread.  No soft, warm bun for this hung-over college student.</p>
<p>I can still taste the disappointment to this day.  It&#8217;s tart and tangy like tartar sauce.</p>
<p>Never mention Friendly&#8217;s Fish-a-majig sandwich to my college friends.  &#8220;If we have to hear about that fucking fish sandwich one more time,&#8221; they will tell you.  They are equal parts over dramatic and unsupportive.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m hoping that the weekend doesn&#8217;t turn out to be a 2012 Fish-a-majig.  So many high hopes and expectations, but in the end you&#8217;re left with nothing but toast and a soggy piece of processed fish.</p>
<p>I know what you&#8217;re all thinking.  If you think the weekend will be a Fish-a-majig, it will be a Fish-a-majig.  Self-fulfilling fish sandwiches and all.</p>
<div id="attachment_479" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 227px"><a href="http://middleagebutch.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/imagesca38i014.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-479" title="Joe Carter" alt="" src="http://middleagebutch.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/imagesca38i014.jpg?w=217&#038;h=233" height="233" width="217" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">You&#8217;re a human Fish-a-majig, Joe Carter</p></div>
<p>It&#8217;s funny that when I think of my top disappointments in life, the Fish-a-majig always swims to the top.  Not the nine-year marriage that ended in divorce or the civil union that crashed and burned less than a year after my girlfriend and I exchanged vows.  Or even the 1993 World Series when Joe Carter ended the Philadelphia Phillies&#8217; magical lightning-in-a-bottle season with a single swing of the bat.  Curse you, Joe Carter.</p>
<p>Truth be told, W and I have had very few Fish-a-majig moments in our relationship.  From the get-go, everything has always worked out the way that it was supposed to, which has been perfect.</p>
<p>And, I know the weekend will be perfect, too.</p>
<p>I guess I just like kvetching about a 30-year-old fish sandwich.</p>
<p>How about you?  Care to share a random moment of disappointment?</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/475/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/475/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=475&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://middleagebutch.wordpress.com/2012/10/26/the-bitter-taste-of-fish-sandwiches-and-disappointment/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>22</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/676d8072c6216bb85484ff7e35a4b6f3?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">middleagebutch</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://middleagebutch.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/imagescas8xflt.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Friendly&#039;s sign</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://middleagebutch.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/imagescamtl74g.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Friendly&#039;s Fish-a-majig</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://middleagebutch.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/imagesca38i014.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Joe Carter</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>