<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2011 16:07:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Against Waiting in Lines for Food</title>
		<link>http://thesmatter.wordpress.com/2011/08/08/against-waiting-in-lines-for-food/</link>
		<comments>http://thesmatter.wordpress.com/2011/08/08/against-waiting-in-lines-for-food/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2011 20:17:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Matt Rhodes</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Manifestos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bi rite]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blue bottle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chipotle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coffee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[four barrel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outside lands]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Paris]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Francisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vienna]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thesmatter.wordpress.com/?p=868</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Ladies and gentlemen: I have stood in line for a tasty morsel for the last time. All over San Francisco, I see overrated treats commanding ridiculous wait times. Blue Bottle coffee takes Dali-esque melting hours to acquire. The quality of our various ice creams seems to be determined solely by number of minutes brave fanboys [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=868&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ladies and gentlemen:</p>
<p>I have stood in line for a tasty morsel for the last time. All over San Francisco, I see overrated treats commanding ridiculous wait times. Blue Bottle coffee takes Dali-esque melting hours to acquire. The quality of our various ice creams seems to be determined solely by number of minutes brave fanboys are willing to wait in frigid summer temperatures for the sensual satisfaction of highly fattening sugar hitting their dystopian tongues. Why wouldn’t we pay $8 a pint after waiting for 45 minutes? It just makes sense.</p>
<p>Drive or stroll by any eatery that earns more than four stars on Yelp and you’ll find dozens of chilly hipsters conversing madly on the corner, eagerly waiting for their chance to ingest overhyped gastronomic bliss. Never has the blatant conformity of San Franciscan non-conformity looked so bittersweet, like the curvaceous delight of salted caramel at Bi-Rite Ice Creamery, which you can’t have in less than 30 minutes, any time of day.</p>
<p>A great business would be a business that sells stuff to people waiting in lines in San Francisco.</p>
<div id="attachment_870" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://thesmatter.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/humphry_popup.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-870" title="Humphry_Popup" src="http://thesmatter.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/humphry_popup.jpg?w=500&#038;h=333" alt="" width="500" height="333" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The service here is so slow. The ice cream must therefore be extra delicious and worthy of a Facebook check-in!</p></div>
<p>The very existence of a line connotes quality. But I grew up in an America where faster was better, where business success was a simple meritocracy built on pure speed. McDonalds and its faux meats in greasy drawers represented the pinnacle of culinary efficiency, the standard toward which all copycats strived.</p>
<p>In our righteous and rebellious effort to fight the evil trend of fast food, we of the slow movement have gone too far.</p>
<p>Over the years, we have built gorgeous machines to speed up the process of ingesting caffeine, but now the lethargic baristas of Blue Bottle have convinced us that slower is better, that pouring hot water through too few cups is somehow a necessary precursor to tastier coffee. I think it&#8217;s time we called it what it is: Slow and stupid from a business standpoint.</p>
<p>Four Barrel down in the Mission has it figured out a little better, with two separate lines and more than one barista. But here still the appetite for slow outweighs the ability to deliver the goods, equaling long lines. Not to mention your chance of being urinated upon in line is greater than 65 percent.</p>
<p>The problem: When too many yuppie geniuses stand on line, they think about all the world’s problems and how they could be solved. We’re like the great coffeehouse intellectuals of a bygone era, except those bright lads and lasses in Vienna and Paris actually drank coffee and therefore generated clear and energetic thoughts and ideas, while we fritter away our Sundays wondering how sweet life would be if we just had our latte and vegan doughnut <em>now</em>.</p>
<p>We childless professionals shouldn&#8217;t make every weekend like a self-imposed trip to Disneyland. That&#8217;s a different phase in life that we shan’t avoid, so why fast forward toward our future inevitable hell? We should be engorged on the quality of our simple lives, or demand or create new ways to do it faster. We have limited time before our own impending progeny overtake and destroy our souls.</p>
<p>Then we can bring our strollers into long lines at crowded farmers’ markets and small coffee shops to muck things up even worse for the foodie elite.</p>
<p>I want good brunch, and I want it now. But because I live in San Francisco I just can&#8217;t have it. This is a great problem for our supposedly free markets. We in San Francisco need to quit looking for and investing in the next Steve Jobs; we need the next Ray Kroc.</p>
<p>Ironically, Chipotle was the brainchild of a disgruntled San Francisco chef who felt we could bring fresh, tasty Mexican fare to the masses, faster. Now, Chipotle represents all that is wrong in America, a stark reminder that there are so few outlets of mid-tier culinary quality that even clueless myrmidons in the strip malls of America are forced to wait for access to delicious grub.</p>
<p>Maybe there’s a reason the economy is in the crapper. Maybe we’ve created a culture of conformity that anoints as our champions too few brands and thus strips us of our ability to spend money at the appropriate velocity.</p>
<p>Maybe I just need to spend less time in line thinking of derivative, insipid ideas for my blog, which you can always read <em>now</em>.</p>
<p>Nevertheless, let’s make this upcoming weekend in San Francisco special, The Weekend of No Lines. Many of you will be in line for too few bathrooms and too-pricey beers at the Outside Lands music festival, but the rest of us should power through a boycott. Let’s all just buy some groceries and enjoy nice quiet meals at home with our loved ones.</p>
<p>I’ll see you in a mind-boggling line at Whole Foods.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/868/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/868/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/868/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/868/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/868/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/868/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/868/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/868/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/868/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/868/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/868/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/868/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/868/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/868/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=868&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thesmatter.wordpress.com/2011/08/08/against-waiting-in-lines-for-food/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>15</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/99b979207137387dee2977830018a997?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Matt Rhodes</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thesmatter.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/humphry_popup.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Humphry_Popup</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Writer&#8217;s Guide to Pulling Teeth</title>
		<link>http://unsanityfiles.wordpress.com/2011/08/03/the-writers-guide-to-pulling-teeth/</link>
		<comments>http://unsanityfiles.wordpress.com/2011/08/03/the-writers-guide-to-pulling-teeth/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2011 12:57:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Albert Berg</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Albert Berg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pulling teeth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[teeth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tooth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[word dentist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writers block]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://unsanityfiles.wordpress.com/?p=1691</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I know how it is. You wake up. Or maybe you&#8217;re about to go to bed. Whenever it is, you sit down to write. You know what you want to say, you understand the turns the plot needs to take, and you&#8217;ve got a good handle on your characters. But when you actually start to [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=1691&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I know how it is. You wake up. Or maybe you&#8217;re about to go to bed. Whenever it is, you sit down to write.</p>
<p>You know what you want to say, you understand the turns the plot needs to take, and you&#8217;ve got a good handle on your characters. But when you actually start to write it feels like things Just. Aren&#8217;t. Working.</p>
<p>Your brain feels like sludge, the words dribble onto the screen like thick sewage, and you start to get depressed. You <em>know</em> you&#8217;re better than this. You can remember good days, great days even, when the story flowed out like a mighty river, when the only thing that could hold it back was the fact that you couldn&#8217;t type fast enough to get it all out.</p>
<p>How do I know all this? Well, the truth is, I&#8217;m clinging to the ceiling directly above you at this very moment, looking down on your foolish attempts with my segmented eyes.</p>
<p>Don&#8217;t look.</p>
<p>Wait, no, I&#8217;m sorry. What I meant to say is that I know your pain because I&#8217;ve gone through it too.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ll be sitting there trying to get the words out, and it&#8217;s like pulling teeth. I&#8217;m the word-dentist reaching into the mouth of creativity and yanking out sentences with a pair of vice grips. What&#8217;s that? Pain killers? You don&#8217;t need no stinking pain killers. Man up.</p>
<p>And you know what? That&#8217;s okay.</p>
<p>Not every day of writing needs to be fun or easy. Sometimes the flow just won&#8217;t happen like you want it to.  It doesn&#8217;t mean there&#8217;s anything wrong with you or your work. It just means that you need to slow down. Take your time. Let your mind have time to get it right.</p>
<p>This is something I&#8217;ve been personally coming to terms with more and more lately. I&#8217;ve been learning to stop beating myself up when things don&#8217;t go exactly as planned.</p>
<p>Because, on the one hand, we all know creativity boils down to a lot of hard work. But in your gung-ho fervor to sling those words, don&#8217;t forget that there&#8217;s something slightly magical about this whole process.</p>
<p>Maybe you think you&#8217;re ready to write, but some part of the back of your brain is telling you there&#8217;s something wrong. Maybe you haven&#8217;t sorted out the plot as well as you thought. Maybe your sleep deprived brain just doesn&#8217;t have the energy it needs.</p>
<p>Whatever. Like I said, it&#8217;s okay. Stop being miserable about the fact that you can&#8217;t hit a home run and focus on getting to first base.</p>
<p>And let me be perfectly transparent here: this advice isn&#8217;t really for you. It&#8217;s for me five years ago. It&#8217;s something I&#8217;ve been learning to deal with ever since I started writing. And after all that time I think I&#8217;m finally coming to the point where I can accept the good along with the bad, take the easy days and the hard days as they come.</p>
<p>But maybe you can get something out of it too. I hope so. If not, I&#8217;ll refund your money in full, cash, no questions asked.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ll hand it down to you from my spot on the ceiling.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter" src="http://gladioliworkbook.com/__imgsizer/stories/photos/e837d4d75cefbfdfa1224612f1c6fb37f26fb873.jpeg?h=600&amp;mode=fit&amp;q=85&amp;w=800&amp;s=RdcAScJZyxSeJCVj5R4vGw" alt="" width="500" height="375" /></p>
<p>P.S. I really dig the title &#8220;word dentist.&#8221; If I ever make it as a writer, I think that&#8217;s what I&#8217;m going to put in those little forms where it says &#8220;Occupation.&#8221;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1691/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1691/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1691/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1691/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1691/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1691/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1691/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1691/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1691/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1691/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1691/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1691/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1691/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1691/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=1691&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://unsanityfiles.wordpress.com/2011/08/03/the-writers-guide-to-pulling-teeth/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>48</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/1e9bc229557a3c7556a421a159536ef7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">alberg137</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gladioliworkbook.com/__imgsizer/stories/photos/e837d4d75cefbfdfa1224612f1c6fb37f26fb873.jpeg?h=600&#38;mode=fit&#38;q=85&#38;w=800&#38;s=RdcAScJZyxSeJCVj5R4vGw" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Day 28-homeless garden take 2</title>
		<link>http://365lifephotography.wordpress.com/2011/08/07/day-28-homeless-garden-take-2/</link>
		<comments>http://365lifephotography.wordpress.com/2011/08/07/day-28-homeless-garden-take-2/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2011 04:43:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>365lifephotography</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[California]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flowers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gardens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Homeless]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[People]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Santa Cruz]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://365lifephotography.wordpress.com/?p=228</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I say homeless garden &#8220;take 2&#8243; because the last time I went there, my camera was stolen hours later so all my photographs of that day were lost. However, that could be a good thing because these shots are a lot better. I ended up getting a camera almost twice as nice as my old [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=228&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://365lifephotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0298.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-229" title="IMG_0298" src="http://365lifephotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0298.jpg?w=490&#038;h=521" alt="" width="490" height="521" /></a>I say homeless garden &#8220;take 2&#8243; because the last time I went there, my camera was stolen hours later so all my photographs of that day were lost. However, that could be a good thing because these shots are a lot better.</p>
<p><a href="http://365lifephotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0289.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-230" title="IMG_0289" src="http://365lifephotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0289.jpg?w=490&#038;h=262" alt="" width="490" height="262" /></a>I ended up getting a camera almost twice as nice as my old one. I went from a 12 mega pixel sony alpha 330 with a 18-55 mm lens and a 50-200mm lens to a 18 mega pixel canon rebel t2i with a 18-55 mm lens and a 55-250 mm lens.</p>
<div id="attachment_231" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 500px"><a href="http://365lifephotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0299.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-231" title="IMG_0299" src="http://365lifephotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0299.jpg?w=490&#038;h=326" alt="" width="490" height="326" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Love the blur of the teddy bear sunflower in the background</p></div>
<p><a title="The Homeless Garden Project" href="http://www.homelessgardenproject.org/index.php" target="_blank">The Homeless Garden Project </a>in Santa Cruz, CA is a place where homeless citizens go to volunteer and in return receive job training. Some become staff at the garden shop. Basically, there is a open field filled with beautiful flowers and vegetables and it&#8217;s open to the community. A bouquet, that you pick yourself, is only about $4.</p>
<p><a href="http://365lifephotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0354.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-242" title="IMG_0354" src="http://365lifephotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0354.jpg?w=490&#038;h=326" alt="" width="490" height="326" /></a></p>
<p>The job training comes in the form of creating and maintaing beautiful gardens while also helping the community when they come to gather them. It teaches discipline and social skills.</p>
<p><a href="http://365lifephotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0300.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-232" title="IMG_0300" src="http://365lifephotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0300.jpg?w=490&#038;h=443" alt="" width="490" height="443" /></a>I&#8217;ve been having a blast with cropping and zooming. I can go much farther due to the increase in mega pixels in my new camera. I had a hard time choosing shots to post, so bear with me thru a few too many!</p>
<p><a href="http://365lifephotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0287.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-233" title="IMG_0287" src="http://365lifephotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0287.jpg?w=490&#038;h=492" alt="" width="490" height="492" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://365lifephotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0296.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-234" title="IMG_0296" src="http://365lifephotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0296.jpg?w=490&#038;h=268" alt="" width="490" height="268" /></a></p>
<div id="attachment_235" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 500px"><a href="http://365lifephotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0294.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-235" title="IMG_0294" src="http://365lifephotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0294.jpg?w=490&#038;h=306" alt="" width="490" height="306" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">They&#039;re teddy bear sunflowers were incredible</p></div>
<p><a href="http://365lifephotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0290.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-236" title="IMG_0290" src="http://365lifephotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0290.jpg?w=490&#038;h=281" alt="" width="490" height="281" /></a><a href="http://365lifephotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0322.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-237" title="IMG_0322" src="http://365lifephotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0322.jpg?w=490&#038;h=326" alt="" width="490" height="326" /></a><a href="http://365lifephotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0324.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-238" title="IMG_0324" src="http://365lifephotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0324.jpg?w=490&#038;h=402" alt="" width="490" height="402" /></a></p>
<div id="attachment_239" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 500px"><a href="http://365lifephotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0330.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-239" title="IMG_0330" src="http://365lifephotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0330.jpg?w=490&#038;h=326" alt="" width="490" height="326" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">This almost looks like the main flower has a reflection.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_240" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 500px"><a href="http://365lifephotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0341.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-240" title="IMG_0341" src="http://365lifephotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0341.jpg?w=490&#038;h=326" alt="" width="490" height="326" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">This one looks like it&#039;s giving the hand signal for love</p></div>
<p><a href="http://365lifephotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0351.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-241" title="IMG_0351" src="http://365lifephotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0351.jpg?w=490&#038;h=440" alt="" width="490" height="440" /></a><a href="http://365lifephotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0366.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-243" title="IMG_0366" src="http://365lifephotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0366.jpg?w=490&#038;h=326" alt="" width="490" height="326" /></a></p>
<div id="attachment_244" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 500px"><a href="http://365lifephotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0356.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-244" title="IMG_0356" src="http://365lifephotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0356.jpg?w=490&#038;h=326" alt="" width="490" height="326" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The first thing I thought of when I saw these was Rastafarians.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_245" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 500px"><a href="http://365lifephotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0362.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-245" title="IMG_0362" src="http://365lifephotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0362.jpg?w=490&#038;h=572" alt="" width="490" height="572" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">LOVE. Just by cropping, it turned a photo of a boring flower into what almost looks like an oil painting</p></div>
<p>While I do believe that powerful, worthy, meaningful, inspirational, impactful photography has a &#8220;heartbeat&#8221; or &#8220;soul&#8221; in it, or at least a message, I do believe that nature and other objects can be fun and beautiful. Peace!</p>
<br /> Tagged: <a href='http://365lifephotography.wordpress.com/tag/california/'>California</a>, <a href='http://365lifephotography.wordpress.com/tag/flowers/'>Flowers</a>, <a href='http://365lifephotography.wordpress.com/tag/gardens/'>Gardens</a>, <a href='http://365lifephotography.wordpress.com/tag/homeless/'>Homeless</a>, <a href='http://365lifephotography.wordpress.com/tag/nature/'>Nature</a>, <a href='http://365lifephotography.wordpress.com/tag/people/'>People</a>, <a href='http://365lifephotography.wordpress.com/tag/photography-2/'>Photography</a>, <a href='http://365lifephotography.wordpress.com/tag/santa-cruz/'>Santa Cruz</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/228/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/228/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/228/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/228/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/228/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/228/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/228/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/228/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/228/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/228/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/228/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/228/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/228/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/228/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=228&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://365lifephotography.wordpress.com/2011/08/07/day-28-homeless-garden-take-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/41da5cb6a6b72e598ecbc4e82b04fdad?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">365lifephotography</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://365lifephotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0298.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0298</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://365lifephotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0289.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0289</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://365lifephotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0299.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0299</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://365lifephotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0354.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0354</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://365lifephotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0300.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0300</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://365lifephotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0287.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0287</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://365lifephotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0296.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0296</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://365lifephotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0294.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0294</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://365lifephotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0290.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0290</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://365lifephotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0322.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0322</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://365lifephotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0324.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0324</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://365lifephotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0330.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0330</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://365lifephotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0341.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0341</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://365lifephotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0351.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0351</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://365lifephotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0366.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0366</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://365lifephotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0356.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0356</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://365lifephotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0362.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0362</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>out with the old&#8230;</title>
		<link>http://closetcast.com/2011/07/31/out-with-the-old/</link>
		<comments>http://closetcast.com/2011/07/31/out-with-the-old/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2011 18:45:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>ClosetCast</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Outfit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://closetcast.com/?p=382</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[today&#8217;s closetcast: refreshed So a few days ago I did a major closet cleanout. It feels nice to be honest with what I will actually wear and what I won&#8217;t. No sense holding on to things that just take up the limited space in my closet. I picked up this headband at Anthropologie this past [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=382&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>today&#8217;s closetcast: </strong>refreshed <a href="http://closetcast.files.wordpress.com/2011/07/dsc_00102.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-389" title="DSC_0010" src="http://closetcast.files.wordpress.com/2011/07/dsc_00102.jpg?w=685&#038;h=1024" alt="" width="685" height="1024" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://closetcast.files.wordpress.com/2011/07/dsc_00152.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-387" title="DSC_0015" src="http://closetcast.files.wordpress.com/2011/07/dsc_00152.jpg?w=830&#038;h=1024" alt="" width="830" height="1024" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://closetcast.files.wordpress.com/2011/07/dsc_00112.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-385" title="DSC_0011" src="http://closetcast.files.wordpress.com/2011/07/dsc_00112.jpg?w=685&#038;h=1024" alt="" width="685" height="1024" /></a></p>
<p>So a few days ago I did  a major closet cleanout. It feels nice to be honest with what I will actually wear and what I won&#8217;t. No sense holding on to things that just take up the limited space in my closet. I picked up this headband at Anthropologie this past weekend and have been wearing it non-stop. It&#8217;s a fun way to accessorize without jewelry.</p>
<p>The boots are a pair of Topshop Chelsea boots. So versatile and they sort of toughen up any outfit&#8230; I think they are perfect with a mini-skirt, like pictured here.</p>
<p><em>top: <a href="http://www.anthropologie.com/anthro/catalog/productdetail.jsp?id=21331350&amp;catId=CLOTHES-LOUNGEWEAR&amp;pushId=CLOTHES-LOUNGEWEAR&amp;popId=CLOTHES&amp;navCount=78&amp;color=010&amp;isProduct=true&amp;fromCategoryPage=true&amp;isSubcategory=true&amp;subCategoryId=CLOTHES-LOUNGEWEAR-TOPS&amp;templateType=subCategory">Anthropologie</a>, skirt: h&amp;m, shirt: Zara, boots: Topshop (similar <a href="http://us.topshop.com/webapp/wcs/stores/servlet/ProductDisplay?beginIndex=0&amp;viewAllFlag=&amp;catalogId=33060&amp;storeId=13052&amp;productId=2529009&amp;langId=-1&amp;categoryId=&amp;searchTerm=chelsea%20boots&amp;pageSize=20">here</a>), headband: <a href="http://www.anthropologie.com/anthro/catalog/productdetail.jsp?id=20971503&amp;catId=ACCESSORIES-HAIR&amp;pushId=ACCESSORIES-HAIR&amp;popId=JEWELRYACCESSORIES&amp;navCount=36&amp;color=030&amp;isProduct=true&amp;fromCategoryPage=true&amp;isSubcategory=true&amp;subCategoryId=ACCESSORIES-HAIR&amp;templateType=subCategory">Anthropologie</a>, watch: <a href="http://www.nixonnow.com/">Nixon</a>, bracelets: vintage and initialed bracelets <a href="http://www.alexandani.com/">Alex and Ani</a></em></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/382/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/382/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/382/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/382/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/382/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/382/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/382/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/382/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/382/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/382/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/382/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/382/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/382/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/382/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=382&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://closetcast.com/2011/07/31/out-with-the-old/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c110243ca6111cd1e3a36d8ea0c09125?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">closetsophisticate</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://closetcast.files.wordpress.com/2011/07/dsc_00102.jpg?w=685" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0010</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://closetcast.files.wordpress.com/2011/07/dsc_00152.jpg?w=830" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0015</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://closetcast.files.wordpress.com/2011/07/dsc_00112.jpg?w=685" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0011</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Five Reasons to Love Costa Rica</title>
		<link>http://dbdazedomain.wordpress.com/2011/07/17/five-reasons-to-love-costa-rica/</link>
		<comments>http://dbdazedomain.wordpress.com/2011/07/17/five-reasons-to-love-costa-rica/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2011 02:46:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>dbdaze</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exercise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Costa Rica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[friends]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[downsizing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Puerto Viejo]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dbdazedomain.wordpress.com/?p=1075</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Here are my top 5 Reasons To Love Costa Rica: Perpetual sunshine and warmth &#8212; yes, there is a rainy season but so far, we have had only a couple of days with prolonged rain.  Most of the rain has fallen during the evening while we sleep &#8212; the occasional daytime rain can be quickly [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=1075&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://dbdazedomain.wordpress.com/2011/07/17/five-reasons-to-love-costa-rica/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/3925f1bbff92a33e6317eb5bd82d2996?s=96&#38;d=wavatar&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">dbdaze</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dbdazedomain.files.wordpress.com/2011/07/dscn0679.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSCN0679</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dbdazedomain.files.wordpress.com/2011/07/costa-rican-frog.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Costa Rican Frog</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dbdazedomain.files.wordpress.com/2011/07/mariah-rastafarian.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mariah &#38; Rastafarian</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dbdazedomain.files.wordpress.com/2011/07/father-son.jpg?w=225" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">father and son</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dbdazedomain.files.wordpress.com/2011/07/dscn05991.jpg?w=225" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSCN0599</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Warren Buffett&#8217;s Ten Rules for Winning</title>
		<link>http://tienwong.wordpress.com/2011/07/11/warren-buffetts-ten-rules/</link>
		<comments>http://tienwong.wordpress.com/2011/07/11/warren-buffetts-ten-rules/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2011 07:28:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Tien Wong</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Investing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Leadership]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Management]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Success]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Winning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[general business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[investing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[risk reduction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[success]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Warren Buffett]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wealth creation]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tienwong.wordpress.com/?p=119</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[While enjoying a nice lunch with my Son at a Minneapolis Jimmy John&#8217;s sub shop this weekend, I saw this &#8220;WARREN BUFFETT&#8217;S TEN RULES&#8221; sign tacked to the wall. Unfortunately, I wasn&#8217;t able to take a glare-free or hi-res photo, so let me list out these Rules below (with my comments in bold Italics): No. 1: [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=119&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>While enjoying a nice lunch with my Son at a Minneapolis <strong>Jimmy John&#8217;s</strong> sub shop this weekend, I saw this <strong>&#8220;WARREN BUFFETT&#8217;S TEN RULES&#8221;</strong> sign tacked to the wall.</p>
<p><a href="http://tienwong.files.wordpress.com/2011/07/warren-buffetts-ten-rules.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-121" title="Warren Buffett's Ten Rules" src="http://tienwong.files.wordpress.com/2011/07/warren-buffetts-ten-rules.jpg?w=764&#038;h=1024" alt="" width="764" height="1024" /></a></p>
<p>Unfortunately, I wasn&#8217;t able to take a glare-free or hi-res photo, so let me list out these Rules below (<strong><em>with my comments in bold Italics</em></strong>):</p>
<p><strong>No. 1:  REINVEST YOUR PROFITS</strong> &#8211; When you first make money, you may be tempted to spend it.  Don&#8217;t.  Instead, reinvest the profits.  Buffett learned this early on. In high school, he and a pal bought a pinball machine to put in a barbershop. With the money they earned, they bought more machines until they had eight in different shops. When the friends sold the venture, Buffett used the proceeds to buy stocks and to start another business. <strong><em>No surprise that this is Rule #1.  He is the greatest investor of our time and one of the reasons is because he followed his own advice here.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong>No. 2:  BE WILLING TO BE DIFFERENT</strong> - Don’t base your decisions upon what everyone is saying or doing. When Buffett began managing money in 1956 with $100,000 cobbled together from a handful of investors, he was dubbed an oddball. He worked in Omaha, not on Wall Street, and he refused to tell his partners where he was putting their money. People predicted that he’d fall, but when he closed his partnership 14 years later, it was worth more than $100 million.  <strong><em>In short:  Don&#8217;t be afraid to be contrarian.  Time and time again, we see tremendously successful investors, businessmen, entrepreneurs take a contrarian approach.  Wasn&#8217;t it John D. Rockefeller who said the best time to buy is when there&#8217;s &#8220;blood in the streets&#8221;?</em></strong></p>
<p><strong>No. 3:  NEVER SUCK YOUR THUMB</strong> - Gather in advance any information you need to make a decision, and ask a friend or relative to make sure that you stick to a deadline. Buffett prides himself on swiftly making up his mind and acting on it. He calls any unnecessary sitting and thinking “thumb-sucking.”  <strong><em>Buffett invested $5 Billion in Goldman Sachs during the worst moments of the 2008 financial crisis when Wall Street appeared to be melting down.  He committed this money in a 15 minute (no thumb sucking here) phone call with Goldman CEO Lloyd Blankfein.  Result?  A $10 Billion profit in 30 months.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong>No. 4:  SPELL OUT THE DEAL BEFORE YOU START</strong> - Your bargaining leverage is always greatest before you begin a job – that’s when you have something to offer that the other party wants. Buffett learned this lesson the hard way as a kid, when his grandfather Earnest hired him and a friend to dig out the family grocery store after a blizzard. The boys spent five hours shoveling until they could barely straighten their frozen hands. Afterward, his grandfather gave the pair less that 90 cents to split.  <strong><em>This advice holds not only for jobs, but also for any kind of negotiation, investments, partnerships, JVs, etc.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong>No. 5:  WATCH SMALL EXPENSES</strong> - Buffett invests in business run by managers who obsess over the tiniest costs. He once acquired a company whose owner counted the sheets in rolls of 500-sheet toilet paper to see if he was being cheated (he was). He also admired a friend who painted only the side of his office building that faced the road.  <strong><em>I think the lesson is also that the devil&#8217;s in the details, and that little things mean a lot. The best organizations have a handle on all of the nuances and details of their operations.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong>No. 6:  LIMIT WHAT YOU BORROW</strong> - Buffett has never borrowed a significant amount – not to invest, not for a mortgage. He has gotten many heartrending letters from people who thought their borrowing was manageable but became overwhelmed by debt. His advice: Negotiate with creditors to pay what you can. Then, when you’re debt-free, work on saving some money that you can invest.  <strong><em>If our country had followed this advice, we wouldn&#8217;t be in the financial pickle we&#8217;re in now, that&#8217;s for sure.  Seems like Buffett is not only saying to limit what you borrow, but also very simply to be disciplined, and that&#8217;s a key success driver</em></strong></p>
<p><strong>No. 7:  BE PERSISTENT</strong> - With tenacity and ingenuity, you can win against a more established competitor. Buffett acquired the Nebraska Furniture Mart in 1983 because he liked the way its founder, Rose Blumkin, did business. A Russian immigrant, she built the mart from a pawnshop into the largest furniture store in North America. Her strategy was to undersell the big shots, and she was a merciless negotiator.  <strong><em>This is my favorite of the Buffett Rules.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong>No. 8:  KNOW WHEN TO QUIT</strong> - Once, when Buffett was a teen, he went to the racetrack. He bet on a race and lost. To recoup his funds, he bet on another race. He lost again, leaving him with close to nothing. He felt sick – he had squandered nearly a week’s earnings. Buffett never repeated that mistake.  <em><strong>The only one making money at the racetrack is the owner.  I bet he&#8217;s happy he learned this lesson at a young age.</strong></em></p>
<p><strong>No. 9:  ASSESS THE RISKS</strong> - In 1995, the employer of Buffett’s son, Howie, was accused by the FBI of price-fixing. Buffett advised Howie to imagine the worst- and best-case scenarios if he stayed with the company. His son quickly realized the risks of staying far outweighed any potential gains, and he quit the next day.  <strong><em>Continually assess current and future risks and mitigate those you can to help shape and control your future.</em></strong></p>
<p><strong>No. 10:  KNOW WHAT SUCCESS REALLY MEANS</strong> - Despite his wealth, Buffett does not measure success by dollars. In 2006, he pledged to give away almost his entire fortune to charities, primarily the Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation. He’s adamant about not funding monuments to himself – no Warren Buffett buildings or halls. “When you get to my age, you’ll measure your success in life by how many of the people you want to have love you actually do love you. That’s the ultimate test of how you lived your life.”  <strong><em>What a great definition of &#8220;success.&#8221;  After all the effort, the blood, sweat and tears, and the battle scars from the business and investment world, the Master defines his success so simply and elegantly.</em></strong></p>
<p>I can&#8217;t help but think that the world would be a better place, and the economy would be in much better shape if we all followed Warren Buffett&#8217;s Rules.</p>
<p>Hopefully, President Obama will continue to seek Mr. Buffett&#8217;s sage counsel and (I know this is a stretch) convince him to become our next Treasury Secretary when <strong>Tim Geithner</strong> (my Mandarin language TA at Dartmouth) retires.</p>
<p>Thanks for reading, and please leave a Comment below.  Which Buffett Rule is your favorite one? What kinds of things do you think Mr. Buffett would do if he were Treasury Secretary?</p>
<p>And <em><strong>please sign up for my Blog too</strong></em>!  (See the Signup box on the sidebar of my Home Page)</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/119/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/119/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/119/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/119/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/119/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/119/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/119/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/119/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/119/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/119/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/119/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/119/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/119/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/119/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=119&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tienwong.wordpress.com/2011/07/11/warren-buffetts-ten-rules/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>46</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/6847ad6f17f13557b8b69b86c06e004e?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tienwong</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tienwong.files.wordpress.com/2011/07/warren-buffetts-ten-rules.jpg?w=764" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Warren Buffett's Ten Rules</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Watch the Throne Review: Hip-Hop&#8217;s Thriller?</title>
		<link>http://culturevi.wordpress.com/2011/08/09/watch-the-throne-review-hip-hops-thriller/</link>
		<comments>http://culturevi.wordpress.com/2011/08/09/watch-the-throne-review-hip-hops-thriller/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2011 05:24:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>culturevi</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beyonce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[g.o.o.d. music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jay-z]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kanye west]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[maybach music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rick ross]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rihanna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[roc nation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self made]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wale]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[watch the throne]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://culturevi.wordpress.com/?p=658</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I really hate Lebron James. I think he really took the easy way out. He was scared to risk never winning a title. Didn’t want the responsibility. But let’s be fair &#8211; the guy made it to within one game of winning an NBA championship in his first year with his new team, but we [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=658&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I really hate Lebron James.</p>
<p>I think he really took the easy way out. He was scared to risk never winning a title. Didn’t want the responsibility. But let’s be fair &#8211; the guy made it to within one game of winning an NBA championship in his first year with his new team, but we act like the Heat went 4-78. But don’t you get the feeling that even if he had won, it wouldn’t have been enough? They would’ve questioned why it took seven games to close them out. Or why didn’t he score more points in the fourth quarter. Or say that it really doesn’t count because he didn’t have to face Kobe. It’s a no-win situation.</p>
<p>Welcome to <em>Watch the Throne</em>.</p>
<p>See, on a sports team, if you take one great player and add him to a team that has another, that equals two great players. Music doesn’t quite work that way. Artists don’t add on to each other, they merge and create an entirely new entity. I feel that many people had the perspective of “well Jay’s albums are great, and Kanye’s albums are great, so this one needs to be twice as good as those”. Michael Jackson couldn’t work with Prince and create an album twice as good as <em>Thriller</em>. Each album is it’s own artistic expression. A painting isn’t twice as good as another painting. Unlike the results in sports, musical greatness isn’t tangible.</p>
<p><em>*Sidenote: Also, I’ll refrain from the basic track-by-track type review. AllHipHop.com posted one about eight minutes after the album was released, so you can go there or to the hundred other sites that sum up a song with a quick recap, (ie. Yeezy and Hov rap about their unborn sons on the RZA-produced New Day) instead of offering an actual opinion about the album. My feeling is, you’ve already heard the songs by now, most likely, so you don’t need me to tell you what they’re about.</em></p>
<p>Having said all that, let me say that this is a very difficult album to rate because something like this has never really been done before. Two urban artists still at their peak (Jay maybe not at his lyrical peak, but certainly at the peak of his worldwide popularity), combining to create a single piece of work. Jay has attempted this- twice actually &#8211; with R. Kelly, to mixed results.</p>
<p>And that’s where I’ll begin the music portion of this review. The immediate difference between <em>Watch the Throne</em> and <em>Best of Both Worlds</em> is the cohesiveness of the album. While Jay and R were emailing sessions back and forth and completing the music from a distance, Jay and Kanye approached this in an old school fashion &#8211; they actually recorded it <em>together</em>.</p>
<p><em>*Sidenote pt. 2: I’m fully aware that flying to Paris and having studios set up in NYC hotel suites isn’t exactly ‘old school’, but I’m trying to make a point.</em></p>
<p>And that’s the first thing I noticed while listening to the album. Neither artist sounded out of place. Each had their own moments to shine. They traded back and forth lines a few times throughout the albums, and sometimes started their verse where the other left off, and for the most part stayed on topic. It never felt to me like a Jay-Z album featuring Kanye or a Kanye album featuring Jay-Z &#8211; although Kanye’s stamp is going to naturally be on it a bit more since he was also involved in much of the production. It truly felt like a Jay-Z &amp; Kanye West album. It was a new sound, albeit blending familiar styles from each artist. It’s quite an accomplishment, as the album could’ve easily fell into a <em>Blueprint 4</em> or <em>My Dark Twisted Fantasy 2</em> type feel. Though I will say that Jay would&#8217;ve never have made this album without Kanye&#8217;s influence, as Jay enjoys much more straight-forward music. But wasn&#8217;t that the point of doing a joint album? Jay convinced Kanye to scale back a bit and Kanye got Jay to experiment.</p>
<p>They also did something that another group of solo artists who came together to create an album couldn’t do &#8211; they kept the songs fresh and didn’t fall into a predictable pattern. One of the biggest flaws with the<em> Slaughterhouse</em> self-titled album was the lack of creativity. It was all four rapping on just about every song &#8211; four long verses &#8211; usually started and ended by the same people, with few exceptions. It was almost as if nobody in the group had the leadership skill to step in and cut somebody’s verse from a song or tell someone they aren’t going to be on a particular track. It was like everybody had to have equal time. Rapping and creating music are completely different skill sets.</p>
<p>Jay and Kanye didn’t fall into this trap, despite being two of the genre’s greatest artists. Egos could’ve easily gotten in the way. They didn’t though. They never felt like they were competing. It felt like music.</p>
<p>By the way &#8211; in the interest of full disclosure, I’ll admit that I’m a huge fan of both Jay and Kanye. Having said that, if my wife released a wack album next week, believe that I’d be the first one to post a review bashing the shit out of it. I don’t let personal feelings bleed into my journalistic integrity.</p>
<p>There were a lot of clever, tongue-in-cheek lines that can easily go over some listeners’ heads. They have such a nonchalant and flippant delivery that it sometimes seems as if they aren’t saying much at all. I’d actually suggest printing out some of these lyrics from <a href="http://www.ohhla.com">www.ohhla.com</a> and reading along. They’re actually saying some shit. They aren&#8217;t Lupe-caliber lyrics, but they aren&#8217;t trying for that. This album isn&#8217;t for people who study words, it&#8217;s for people who enjoy music. Just enough lyrics to keep the heavy hip-hop heads interested, but simple enough that the casual fan can appreciate and enjoy.</p>
<p>For artists who have together created such depth in their records as <em>This Can&#8217;t Be Life</em>, there&#8217;s a certain disappointment in the fact that they couldn&#8217;t expose themselves more. They talked plenty about the pitfalls of being rich and famous, but I often get the feelings that the authors of <em>Hey Mama </em>and <em>Regrets</em> could&#8217;ve crafted up a few more conceptual masterpieces if they weren&#8217;t so engulfed in taking over the world. There were also no clear cut, monster singles like <em>Empire State of Mind</em>.</p>
<p>The production was definitely a high point for the album. If you listen to the album once and send it to the recycle bin, you’re doing yourself a disservice. These are new sounds, not what you’re used to hearing. Because of that, it’s easy to dismiss it as “weak”. But these are some really incredible backdrops. The precision, the originality &#8211; and man, does it sound great in a top notch sound system! Professional (and aspiring non-professional) engineers and producers will really appreciate the level of detail in the beats. The mixing was top-notch, as one would expect. The drums, the bass lines, everything knocked. The beats were very creative and different from the current sound. That’s a good thing in the long term, but will turn some closed-minded people off early. It isn’t there fault &#8211; it’s how this generation of hip-hop fans were raised. We’re all about the Rick Ross style of repeating the same things that have worked over and over.</p>
<p>Watch the Throne had a nice variety of topics. Yes, Jay and Ye are rich, and they’re going to talk about being rich. Just as 50 Cent will talk about being gangster, Lupe will talk about being political, Mos Def will talk about being underground, and Rihanna will talk about enjoying candle wax being dripped on her handcuffed, naked body during sex. It’s part of their persona, part of who they are. To ignore it would be straying from their actual lives. But there is a good amount of subject matter as well. By now, you already know they have a song talking about their unborn sons, etc.. There is a lot of humility mixed in with the bravado. There’s also a lot of wittiness.</p>
<p>I have this weird thing about me. See, I actually appreciate when artists take chances and make music that expands beyond their comfort zone. Jay and Kanye could’ve easily made 12 versions of the Pete Rock produced <em>Joy</em> (which is actually one of my favorite records) and called it a day. And guess what? It probably would’ve been a great album. There are a lot of people who would’ve even liked it better than the current iteration. It would’ve been the safe choice. <em>So Appalled</em> works. <em>Who Gon Stop Me</em> takes some imagination.</p>
<p>I felt the same way about<em> 808s &amp; Heartbreaks</em> when it came out. Kanye could’ve built off the success of <em>Graduation</em> and made a similar sounding <em>Graduation 2</em> and had a smash. Instead, he chose to follow his artistic vision and create something new. Whether you liked <em>808s</em> or not is an entirely different blog post. Same with <em>Blueprint 2</em>. The easy thing would’ve been to create 12 more soulful, jazzy songs. Instead, BP2 had an entirely different sound. Jay once said <em>“Niggaz want my old shit? Buy my old albums”</em>. And unlike most fans in this cookie-cutter, “do-what-already-works”, scared to take chances, <em>“Maybach Music”</em> era of hip-hop, I actually appreciate artists who take risks.</p>
<p>So overall, how do I feel about Watch the Throne? I think it’s a great album. It isn’t hip-hop’s <em>Thriller.</em> It isn’t Going to cure cancer. Nor will it make everybody else stop rapping. It wasn’t Blueprints 1-3 plus Graduation multiplied by infinity, like some people were unrealistically expecting. If you just judge it as an album and not put it head to head with the Old Testament, you’ll realize it is filled with tremendous songs. <em>New Day</em> was probably my favorite song. <em>Welcome to the Jungle, Niggas in Paris, No Church in the Wild, Murder to Excellence, Made in America</em> and<em> Why I Love You</em> were all amazing songs. Try to find another album that has this many consistently strong songs. <em>Otis</em> and <em>That’s My Bitch</em> were heard prior to the release and those were also great additions. It’s difficult for me to find much fault with the album. Lyrically? This isn&#8217;t <em>Reasonable Doubt</em>. But it&#8217;s not supposed to be. This album wasn’t aimed towards the hustlers. It was geared towards a much larger audience. Nas has way too much life experience to ever recreate <em>illmatic</em>, so why hold Jay’s newer projects up against what he did as a fresh-faced kid in the mid-90s?</p>
<p>If you’re looking for strictly lyrics? Try a Skyzoo album (though Sky actually has great production too). Amazing stuff there. If you want just beats? Go with the last Rick Ross album. If you want something fresh and new? Give WTT a good listen.</p>
<p>Speaking of which &#8211; how come Rick Ross’ album was considered one of the best hip-hop albums of 2010, despite lame, unrealistic subject matter, copycat hooks and re-used beat ideas, yet Jay and Ye, despite having many different topics and sounds, are being hating on for talking about money on some of their songs. Unlike Ross, they actually <em>have </em>money (and have had for some time), so it’s at least believable.</p>
<p>Also, a huge kudos to Mike Dean and that entire staff for keeping this under wraps. It’s the first album in years that I’ve actually had the pleasure of anticipating and listening front to back, the way it was supposed to be heard. No leaks, no freestyles, no “not-quite-good-enough-for-the-album” throw-aways. I’ve been standing on my soapbox for years screaming against releasing subpar music just for the sake of exposure. This was refreshing. Reminded me of the days I&#8217;d wait on line (not online) on Monday night at Tower Records or Virgin Megastores awaiting a new release.</p>
<p>Could it have been better? Of course. What album couldn’t have. I felt the Beyonce assisted “Life Off” was far from special. I have nothing against those types of records, they just didn&#8217;t execute it well. With the exception of <em>Crazy in Love</em>, Jay and Bey&#8217;s chemistry on records just isn&#8217;t great. The sequencing on the album was good overall, with the exception of the aforementioned, which sounded out of place in between the incredible<em> No Church</em> and<em> Niggaz in Paris</em>. Jay didn’t sound quite as comfortable as normal, as Kanye really stepped up and put himself as a definite &#8220;1A&#8221; to Jay-Z’s &#8220;1&#8243;. Little Brother is as close to being an equal as he ever was. The only thing he&#8217;s lacking now is his own Reasonable Doubt. Not only was Kanye not overmatched lyrically, but he owned some of these records. Though he might’ve had a slightly better performance overall, he definitely did more to add to Jay’s legacy and GOAT claim. This successful collaboration was yet another accomplishment in Jay’s storied career. Kanye is trailing, but not by as much as he was just a few years ago. Though Kanye has more than established his own career, this might be considered a serious “coming out” party (pause if necessary), as he really hung line for line with hip-hop’s greatest living legend.</p>
<p>By the way &#8211; <em>Welcome to the Jungle</em> has the potential to be a <em>huge </em>record.</p>
<p>Top to bottom, it&#8217;s an extremely solid effort from two of rap’s best. I think they definitely laid the groundwork for a WTT 2. Other artists need to pay attention and learn from what they have created instead of attempting to compete or copy. Also, fans should really show a little respect. Hip-hop is full of copycats. Not to pick on <em>Self-Made,</em> but that’s a great example of the &#8220;paint-by-numbers&#8221; albums that are often released today. Take a successful formula and copy it 15 times until you have a hit. Jay and ‘Ye didn’t create 15 versions of <em>Power</em>. They took a chance. Whether you like the music or not, you should at least respect the fact that a few artists are still unafraid to delve into uncharted territory.</p>
<p>If I believed in ratings, I’d probably give Watch the Throne somewhere around an 8.75/10. Better than most of what’s out today, but not quite the hip-hop bible that people were hoping for (or rooting against, in many cases).</p>
<p>Follow me on twitter if you enjoyed this review: @culturevi</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/658/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/658/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/658/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/658/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/658/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/658/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/658/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/658/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/658/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/658/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/658/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/658/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/658/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/658/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=658&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://culturevi.wordpress.com/2011/08/09/watch-the-throne-review-hip-hops-thriller/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>22</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/79d19df2f777fd9f84f17f2ff8b6752f?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Culture VI</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Beautiful City of Bath &#8211; Part 2</title>
		<link>http://nickkontouphotography.wordpress.com/2010/11/28/the-beautiful-city-of-bath-part-2/</link>
		<comments>http://nickkontouphotography.wordpress.com/2010/11/28/the-beautiful-city-of-bath-part-2/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2010 11:23:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>kon2photography</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bath Abbey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bath Crescent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bath Gardens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Great Pulteney Street Bath]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kon2photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nick Kontou]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The City of Bath]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel Photography]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nickkontouphotography.wordpress.com/?p=119</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Travel photography in the City of Bath. Bath Abbey, Bath Crescent, Bath Lions, Bath Gardens. Photography by Nick Kontou of Kon2photography.<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=119&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Here are some more images from our recent visit to Bath. I work most weekends so it is always nice to get away when we can &#8211; even though I always take my camera with me! Personal shoots are a great way of keeping my photography fresh and they also give me ideas for shots that I can incorporate into my portrait and wedding shoots.</p>
<p><a href="http://nickkontouphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/bathblog12.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-120" title="Bath" src="http://nickkontouphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/bathblog12.jpg?w=497&#038;h=801" alt="" width="497" height="801" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://nickkontouphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/bathblog13.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-121" title="Bath" src="http://nickkontouphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/bathblog13.jpg?w=497&#038;h=749" alt="" width="497" height="749" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://nickkontouphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/bathblog14.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-122" title="Bath" src="http://nickkontouphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/bathblog14.jpg?w=497&#038;h=918" alt="" width="497" height="918" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://nickkontouphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/bathblog15.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-123" title="Bath" src="http://nickkontouphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/bathblog15.jpg?w=497&#038;h=775" alt="" width="497" height="775" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://nickkontouphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/bathblog16.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-124" title="Bath" src="http://nickkontouphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/bathblog16.jpg?w=497&#038;h=321" alt="" width="497" height="321" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://nickkontouphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/bathblog17.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-125" title="Bath" src="http://nickkontouphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/bathblog17.jpg?w=497&#038;h=737" alt="" width="497" height="737" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://nickkontouphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/bathblog18.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-126" title="Bath" src="http://nickkontouphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/bathblog18.jpg?w=497&#038;h=903" alt="" width="497" height="903" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://nickkontouphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/bathblog19.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-127" title="Bath" src="http://nickkontouphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/bathblog19.jpg?w=497&#038;h=228" alt="" width="497" height="228" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://nickkontouphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/bathblog20.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-128" title="Bath" src="http://nickkontouphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/bathblog20.jpg?w=497&#038;h=151" alt="" width="497" height="151" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://nickkontouphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/bathblog21.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-129" title="Bath" src="http://nickkontouphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/bathblog21.jpg?w=497&#038;h=430" alt="" width="497" height="430" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://nickkontouphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/bathblog22.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-130" title="Bath" src="http://nickkontouphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/bathblog22.jpg?w=497&#038;h=950" alt="" width="497" height="950" /></a></p>
<p>Images on this blog must not be copied or downloaded without the prior permission of Kon2photography.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/119/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/119/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/119/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/119/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/119/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/119/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/119/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/119/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/119/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/119/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/119/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/119/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/119/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/119/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=119&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://nickkontouphotography.wordpress.com/2010/11/28/the-beautiful-city-of-bath-part-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/1964538d1054b53ad2dcd5986363224b?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">kon2photography</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nickkontouphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/bathblog12.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Bath</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nickkontouphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/bathblog13.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Bath</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nickkontouphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/bathblog14.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Bath</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nickkontouphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/bathblog15.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Bath</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nickkontouphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/bathblog16.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Bath</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nickkontouphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/bathblog17.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Bath</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nickkontouphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/bathblog18.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Bath</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nickkontouphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/bathblog19.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Bath</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nickkontouphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/bathblog20.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Bath</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nickkontouphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/bathblog21.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Bath</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nickkontouphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/bathblog22.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Bath</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Practice Makes Awesome</title>
		<link>http://oliviabushphotography.wordpress.com/2011/08/05/practice-makes-awesome/</link>
		<comments>http://oliviabushphotography.wordpress.com/2011/08/05/practice-makes-awesome/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2011 20:10:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>olivia bush photography</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[action sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sequence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[X Games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[X Games 17]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://oliviabushphotography.wordpress.com/?p=601</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The day before the games started, I had the opportunity to take some shots at the practices that were going down. It was awesome to get a sneak peek of the events that would be happening that weekend. Ryan Decenzo Ryan Decenzo and Chaz Ortiz Danny Mayer PLG Rob Lorifice Jake Brown Looking out at [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=601&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The day before the games started, I had the opportunity to take some shots at the practices that were going down. It was awesome to get a sneak peek of the events that would be happening that weekend.</p>
<p><a href="http://oliviabushphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/072711_obush_xgames_432_2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-609" title="072711_obush_xgames_432_2" src="http://oliviabushphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/072711_obush_xgames_432_2.jpg?w=460&#038;h=302" alt="" width="460" height="302" /></a>Ryan Decenzo</p>
<p><a href="http://oliviabushphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/072711_obush_xgames_406.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-608" title="072711_obush_xgames_406" src="http://oliviabushphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/072711_obush_xgames_406.jpg?w=460&#038;h=692" alt="" width="460" height="692" /></a>Ryan Decenzo and Chaz Ortiz</p>
<p><a href="http://oliviabushphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/072711_obush_xgames_321.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-606" title="072711_obush_xgames_321" src="http://oliviabushphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/072711_obush_xgames_321.jpg?w=460&#038;h=630" alt="" width="460" height="630" /></a>Danny Mayer</p>
<p><a href="http://oliviabushphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/072711_obush_xgames_347.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-607" title="072711_obush_xgames_347" src="http://oliviabushphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/072711_obush_xgames_347.jpg?w=460&#038;h=647" alt="" width="460" height="647" /></a>PLG</p>
<p><a href="http://oliviabushphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/072711_obush_xgames_292.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-605" title="072711_obush_xgames_292" src="http://oliviabushphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/072711_obush_xgames_292.jpg?w=460&#038;h=692" alt="" width="460" height="692" /></a>Rob Lorifice</p>
<p><a href="http://oliviabushphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/072711_obush_xgames_284.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-604" title="072711_obush_xgames_284" src="http://oliviabushphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/072711_obush_xgames_284.jpg?w=460&#038;h=663" alt="" width="460" height="663" /></a>Jake Brown</p>
<p><a href="http://oliviabushphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/072711_obush_xgames_260.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-603" title="072711_obush_xgames_260" src="http://oliviabushphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/072711_obush_xgames_260.jpg?w=460&#038;h=305" alt="" width="460" height="305" /></a>Looking out at downtown LA from the top of the mega ramp</p>
<p>Hope you are digging these sneak peaks! You can still check out at many of my shots on the <a href="https://www.facebook.com/XGames" target="_blank">X Games facebook</a> before I post them here. Also, don’t forget to follow me on <a href="http://twitter.com/#!/livphoto22" target="_blank">twitter</a>, like my page on <a href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Olivia-Bush-Photography/166626526707762?ref=ts" target="_blank">facebook</a>, and if you want to see where I get some of my inspiration from check out my blog on <a href="http://oliviabush.tumblr.com/" target="_blank">tumblr</a>!!</p>
<p>Lots more to come so stay tuned!</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/601/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/601/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/601/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/601/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/601/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/601/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/601/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/601/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/601/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/601/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/601/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/601/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/601/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/601/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=601&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://oliviabushphotography.wordpress.com/2011/08/05/practice-makes-awesome/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c73ce3019f4f115cad979d9dd3132f6c?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">oliviabushphotography</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://oliviabushphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/072711_obush_xgames_432_2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">072711_obush_xgames_432_2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://oliviabushphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/072711_obush_xgames_406.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">072711_obush_xgames_406</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://oliviabushphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/072711_obush_xgames_321.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">072711_obush_xgames_321</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://oliviabushphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/072711_obush_xgames_347.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">072711_obush_xgames_347</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://oliviabushphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/072711_obush_xgames_292.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">072711_obush_xgames_292</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://oliviabushphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/072711_obush_xgames_284.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">072711_obush_xgames_284</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://oliviabushphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/072711_obush_xgames_260.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">072711_obush_xgames_260</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Edible Art: Escape to Iceland</title>
		<link>http://feedintothefeed.com/2011/07/18/edible-art-escape-to-iceland/</link>
		<comments>http://feedintothefeed.com/2011/07/18/edible-art-escape-to-iceland/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2011 17:34:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>The Feed</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Arts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Artist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Edible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food Art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Iceland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://feedintothefeed.wordpress.com/?p=137</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Considering a trip to Iceland? Eszter Burghardt, a Canadian based artist, creates a series of photographs entitled &#8220;Edible Vistas.&#8221;  She depicts these landscapes from wool but also, food.  Some of her ingredients to capture Iceland&#8217;s geography are poppy seeds, coco powder, coffee, milk, and chocolate cake crumbs. Feast your eyes on a few photos of [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=137&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Considering a trip to Iceland? <a href="http://www.eszterburghardt.com/page/b_i_o" target="_blank">Eszter Burghardt</a>, a Canadian based artist, creates a series of photographs entitled &#8220;<a href="http://www.eszterburghardt.com/gallery/edible_vistas/" target="_blank">Edible Vistas</a>.&#8221;  She depicts these landscapes from wool but also, food.  Some of her ingredients to capture Iceland&#8217;s geography are poppy seeds, coco powder, coffee, milk, and chocolate cake crumbs. Feast your eyes on a few photos of her delicious series.  To view more and other work by Burghardt, click <a href="http://www.eszterburghardt.com/" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<a href="http://feedintothefeed.com/2011/07/18/edible-art-escape-to-iceland/#gallery-1-slideshow">Click to view slideshow.</a>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/137/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/137/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/137/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/137/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/137/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/137/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/137/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/137/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/137/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/137/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/137/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/137/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/137/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/137/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=137&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://feedintothefeed.com/2011/07/18/edible-art-escape-to-iceland/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>26</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/0815b40c3d52528d94528684d7a3455f?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">feedintothefeed</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>