<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2012 23:02:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Making pinhole cameras from pretty much anything.</title>
		<link>http://backwardslion.wordpress.com/2012/08/02/making-pinhole-cameras-from-pretty-much-anything/</link>
		<comments>http://backwardslion.wordpress.com/2012/08/02/making-pinhole-cameras-from-pretty-much-anything/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2012 11:22:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>backwardslion</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[making art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photo stuff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science and maths]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[building stuff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://backwardslion.wordpress.com/?p=23</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[God knows, I like to teach people stuff. I also like obsolete tech that requires a minimum of interaction from modern conveniences, like electricity. I joke that the reasons for this is so I can document the end of the world, when people are fighting for generators and bartering for consumables like petrol and batteries, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=23&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>God knows, I like to teach people stuff. I also like obsolete tech that requires a minimum of interaction from modern conveniences, like electricity. I joke that the reasons for this is so I can document the end of the world, when people are fighting for generators and bartering for consumables like petrol and batteries, but some people look at me funny when I say things like that. Partially because they&#8217;re not entirely sure whether I&#8217;m joking or not.</p>
<p>Anyway, I was asked to do a pinhole photography workshop at <a href="http://exposureleeds.org/">Exposure Leeds</a>. I can teach people about obsolete tech, which is a total win in my book. I&#8217;ve been making pinhole cameras from mint tins and paint cans and syrup tins for a very long time, and I&#8217;ve shown many, many people how to make cameras from matchboxes. But I&#8217;ve done that before for Exposure Leeds, so wanted to do something slightly different. </p>
<p>Jon managed to get his hands on some coffee cans (thanks to <a href="http://www.nickclaiden.co.uk/">Nick Claiden</a>); you can make pinhole cameras from anything as long as it is light tight. I&#8217;ve seen people do it <a href="http://www.petapixel.com/2011/06/13/photographer-uses-mouth-as-a-camera/" />with their mouths</a>, with <a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/pictureshow/2011/06/01/130896843/pumpkincam">pumpkins</a>, even an <a href="http://www.petapixel.com/2011/05/20/worlds-largest-camera-big-enough-to-hold-an-airplane/">aircraft hanger</a>. The coffee cans were exactly the right size for a piece of 6&#215;4 photo paper, or if you were feeling confident you could mount a 6&#8243; strip of film in there. I had about an hour to show people how to make the cameras, use them, and get the contents developed, so I went with paper.</p>
<p><a href="http://backwardslion.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/imag0121.jpg"><img src="http://backwardslion.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/imag0121.jpg?w=300&h=169" alt="" title="IMAG0121" width="300" height="169" class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-24" /></a></p>
<p>They also had a screw top, so pretty easy to get in and out of.</p>
<p>First things first, you find the midpoint on the can, then drill a hole there, cover it in tin foil and tape it down with electrical tape. Then I take an acupuncture needle (which I know is no wider than 0.25mm) and poke a hole in the middle of the foil, just once, so light has a single aperture. (You can do whizzy things with multiple holes but it can make things a bit confusing if it&#8217;s the first time you&#8217;re doing it). </p>
<p><a href="http://backwardslion.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/imag0122.jpg"><img src="http://backwardslion.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/imag0122.jpg?w=300&h=169" alt="" title="IMAG0122" width="300" height="169" class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-25" /></a></p>
<p>That&#8217;s it. Gently cover the hole over with more electrical tape and you are now holding in your hand a very rudimentary camera. Next time you finish off a can of golden syrup, wash it out and have a go at this. </p>
<p>Next, you need to load it. I was using a dark bag but you can do this under a safelight if you like. Just pop a sheet of (unexposed) photosensitive paper in the can, and close the top. That&#8217;s it. Remember to do it in the dark or under a red light, and don&#8217;t expose your packet of paper to the light. I was using <a href="http://www.ilfordphoto.com/products/product.asp?n=26">multigrade</a> that expired in 1996 that I picked up on Ebay for a song &#8211; really, use whatever you can get your hands on for as little money as possible. This is bucket and vague hand-wavey photography which is all about art and nothing about exactitude and getting reproducable results. </p>
<p><a href="http://backwardslion.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/imag0123.jpg"><img src="http://backwardslion.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/imag0123.jpg?w=247&h=300" alt="" title="IMAG0123" width="247" height="300" class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-26" /></a></p>
<p>Now it&#8217;s all about the exposure. I worked out the aperture to be about f50 or so. Paper is about iso 3. Think about that for a second &#8211; if you&#8217;re indoors and shooting f22/100iso then you could have an exposure time lasting 30s or more. We&#8217;ve got half that size aperture and 1/5 of the film speed, so in the best case indoor photo exposure time will be 20 <i>minutes</i>. Also, there&#8217;s <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reciprocity_%28photography%29">reciprocity</a> to think about (but not too hard). Effectively you could make one of these, load it, put it on top of your wardrobe and <i>go to sleep for the night</i> without worrying about it overexposing. Ethereal photos are made this way.</p>
<p>So you take your camera, make a best guess as to exposure time, and leave it, with the tape covering the aperture off, for about that length of time. Then you take the camera into your darkroom (in our case a disabled loo rigged up with three developing trays loaded with dev, stop and fix, and a sink to rinse everything off in, as well as safelights) and because you&#8217;ve got no real idea as to exposure you just dunk it in the dev and whip it into the stop as soon as something shows up. Then into the fix, where you can leave it for as long as you like. Don&#8217;t forget these are negative images, so bright spots will be dark and dar spots will be bright. And also because of the way apertures work the image will be the wrong way round, left to right. So scan it, flip it and invert the B&amp;W, and you get results. And boy, did we get some results:</p>
<p>Indoor, 22m exposure. It&#8217;s <i>still</i> underexposed and overdeveloped as a result, but it&#8217;s not bad going.<br />
<div id="attachment_28" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/grainiac/7696359766/"><img src="http://backwardslion.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/7696359766_3d4f45e23a.jpg" alt="" title="7696359766_3d4f45e23a" width="500" height="359" class="size-full wp-image-28" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Image by Andrew Broad</p></div></p>
<p>Outdoors, 5m(ish) exposure. Look at that curviture on the brickwork at the bottom of the image! That&#8217;s an artefact due to the paper being curved in the can and flattened out &#8211; it acts like a massive fisheye lens.<br />
<div id="attachment_29" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/mossy76/7696738764/"><img src="http://backwardslion.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/7696738764_2b1b464d53.jpg" alt="" title="7696738764_2b1b464d53" width="500" height="357" class="size-full wp-image-29" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Image by Neil Brennan</p></div></p>
<p>One of my favourites is a 2-3m exposure of <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/19083292@N00/7693766322/">Holbeck reflected from Oli Wright</a> (seriously, click the link.)</p>
<p>So it was a bit of a success, the workshop. I think 17 people all had a go with making and shooting cameras and getting the results in under an hour, and although as the light dropped the indoor exposure times were taking a lot longer than we were hoping the whole experience was a lot of fun, and hopefully inspiring to the people who took part in it. <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/strawbleu/7694509748/">Personally, I had a whale of a time</a>. I hope I get to run these workshops again, one day soon.</p>
<p><i>If you&#8217;d like me to run this as a workshop then drop me an email for more details.</i></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/23/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/23/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=23&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://backwardslion.wordpress.com/2012/08/02/making-pinhole-cameras-from-pretty-much-anything/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c1ecebc36a4c482bec7105f26b05fdd5?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">backwardslion</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://backwardslion.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/imag0121.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMAG0121</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://backwardslion.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/imag0122.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMAG0122</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://backwardslion.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/imag0123.jpg?w=247" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMAG0123</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://backwardslion.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/7696359766_3d4f45e23a.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">7696359766_3d4f45e23a</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://backwardslion.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/7696738764_2b1b464d53.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">7696738764_2b1b464d53</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Contraceptives for you and you and you!</title>
		<link>http://awomanphenomenally.com/2012/08/01/contraceptive-for-you-and-you-and-you/</link>
		<comments>http://awomanphenomenally.com/2012/08/01/contraceptive-for-you-and-you-and-you/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 13:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>LisaO_too</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reproductive Rights]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://awomanphenomenally.com/?p=293</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Let me begin by saying I think it would totally be worth the federal government&#8217;s money to hire Oprah for a commercial advertising the new health insurance mandates. I can just see her saying, &#8220;That is contraception and preventative care for YOU and YOU and YOU.&#8221; Ah, a political commercial people would pay attention to [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=293&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Let me begin by saying I think it would totally be worth the federal government&#8217;s money to hire Oprah for a commercial advertising the new health insurance mandates. I can just see her saying, &#8220;That is contraception and preventative care for YOU and YOU and YOU.&#8221; Ah, a political commercial people would pay attention to &#8212; anything with Oprah and &#8220;free&#8221; giveaways.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter" title="Oprah" src="http://sphotos-a.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-prn1/527026_3512363610669_1392609224_n.jpg" alt="" width="400" height="400" /></p>
<p>In fact, beginning <strong>today</strong>, an estimated 47 million women will benefit from the changes  set forth in the Affordable Care Act (a.k.a. Obamacare). While free contraceptive is being highlighted, most insurance players are now required to offer a number of women&#8217;s preventive health services at <strong>no upfront cost</strong> (<a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/health/2012/08/01/157674061/under-health-law-no-cost-birth-control-starts-today?ft=1&amp;f=1001&amp;sc=tw&amp;utm_source=twitterfeed&amp;utm_medium=twitter">NPR</a>). According to Health and Human Services Secretary Kathleen Sebelius, &#8220;Surveys showed that more than half the women in this country delayed or avoided preventive care because of its cost.&#8221; Hopefully, the changes that go into affect today will help increase the number of women seeking preventative and basic care.</p>
<p>Of course, there is controversy surrounding this. You really thought that the GOP would let legislation with the words &#8220;birth control&#8221; in it pass without a hissy fit? I know, I know&#8230; I was hoping too. In order to prevent the law from being over turned, Obama issues an exception for all religiously-affiliated organizations to receive an additional year to institute these changes, while the Catholic church (and other religious organizations) reach a compromise with the administration. This resistance also helped build an uprising of private business owners who happen to be religious and don&#8217;t want to pay for a health benefit they say violates their beliefs. Why should their beliefs affect their employees&#8217; bodies? Didn&#8217;t we get passed that a long time ago when we decided men couldn&#8217;t vote for their wives? My thoughts: suck it up selfish bigots. Sadly, a Colorado federal judge decided last Friday that a family owned heating and air conditioning company does not have to follow the new rules for now. I am sure there will be more small lawsuits to follow as Obama administration tries to calm the Catholic church down from their fit (<a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/health/2012/05/21/153218446/catholic-groups-sue-obama-administration-over-birth-control-rule">NPR</a>). I would like to note there are many more important things that should be seen by the courts. And then Republicans wonder why bills aren&#8217;t being passed to increase jobs&#8230; because they keep appealing reproductive health bills!</p>
<h3><strong><span style="text-decoration:underline;">A short round-up of what you are now entitled to</span>:</strong></h3>
<p>- Your insurance company <strong>cannot drop you</strong> if you become ill. There are also <strong>no longer lifetime limits</strong> on care or limits on the amount of benefits in one year.</p>
<p>- Insurance companies can <strong>no longer require referrals</strong> or approval for obstetric or gynecological care.</p>
<p>- Now, at <strong>no cost</strong>, women under most insurance plans can receive<br />
mammograms every 1-2 years after 40;<br />
cervical cancer screenings;<br />
prenatal screenings &amp; tests;<br />
diabetes and blood pressure screenings/counseling;<br />
depression screenings;<br />
smoking/alcohol cessation programs;<br />
FDA-approved contraceptive;<br />
well women visits;<br />
Lactation consultation and supplies;<br />
Interpersonal &amp; domestic violence screening/counseling;<br />
Gestational diabetes screening;<br />
DNA co-testing for HPV;<br />
Counseling regarding STIs, including HIV;<br />
Screening for HIV.</p>
<p>- Children/young adults can be dependent&#8217;s on guardians&#8217; health insurance plans until <strong>age 26</strong> and for children 0-19, they cannot be denied based on pre-existing conditions.</p>
<p>- <strong>Medicare</strong> now covers annual check-ups, mammograms, and other preventive services at no-cost.</p>
<h3><span style="text-decoration:underline;"><strong>Starting in 2014,</strong></span></h3>
<p>- Insurance companies can <strong>no longer deny women coverage due to pre-existing conditions</strong> (i.e. C-section, breast or cervical cancer, care for domestic/sexual violence).</p>
<p>- <strong>Insurers can no longer charge women more than they do men for coverage!!!!</strong></p>
<p>- <strong>Maternity coverage</strong> must be included in insurance plans.</p>
<p>- Over 10 million women will gain coverage under <strong>expanded Medicaid eligibility</strong> (however, many states are trying to opt out of this).</p>
<p>- A <strong>competitive health marketplace</strong> will be available for Americans to shop for new plans.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration:underline;"><strong>A cute graphic from Center for America Progress summing up the changes:</strong></span></p>
<p><img class="aligncenter" title="Women's Health Infograph" src="http://thinkprogress.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/womens-health-infographic.jpg" alt="" width="550" height="1366" /></p>
<p>To clear up any confusion, <strong>your tax dollars are NOT paying for my birth control, your girlfriend&#8217;s birth control, or the lady down the street&#8217;s birth control. We are paying for our own my birth control</strong> through insurance premiums, not tax dollars. <a href="http://www.rhrealitycheck.org/article/2012/08/02/why-free-birth-control-is-not-free"><em><strong>What the Affordable Care Act does is help to start making our insurance policies more equitable, not tossing out contraceptives like candy at a parade.</strong></em></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/293/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/293/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/293/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/293/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/293/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/293/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/293/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/293/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/293/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/293/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/293/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/293/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/293/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/293/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=293&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://awomanphenomenally.com/2012/08/01/contraceptive-for-you-and-you-and-you/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>12</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/41ad71d8365a590f6e81650fe2667c2d?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lisaotoo</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://sphotos-a.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-prn1/527026_3512363610669_1392609224_n.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Oprah</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thinkprogress.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/womens-health-infographic.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Women&#039;s Health Infograph</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Giant Fish Sculptures Made From Discarded Plastic Bottles</title>
		<link>http://catinwater.com/2012/08/02/giant-fish-sculptures-made-from-discarded-plastic-bottles/</link>
		<comments>http://catinwater.com/2012/08/02/giant-fish-sculptures-made-from-discarded-plastic-bottles/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2012 14:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Grety</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Architecture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creative]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Discarded]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Giant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plastic Bottles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recycle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sculptures]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://catinwater.com/?p=1298</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[An art installation on Botafogo Beach in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil shows three gigantic fishes made from discarded plastic bottles. The slogan on a sign beside the installation loosely translates to, “recycle your attitude”. The sculptures were created to raise awareness for the recently completed United Nations Conference on Sustainable Development, dubbed Rio+20. Also, they [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1298&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://catinwater.com/2012/08/02/giant-fish-sculptures-made-from-discarded-plastic-bottles/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/65f640abd3a759a3c2a48373b21c10a0?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gretamazuraite</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ideastracker.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/giant-fish-made-from-plastic-bottles-rio20-botafogo-beach-1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">giant-fish-made-from-plastic-bottles-rio20-botafogo-beach-1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ideastracker.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/giant-fish-made-from-plastic-bottles-rio20-botafogo-beach-2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">giant-fish-made-from-plastic-bottles-rio20-botafogo-beach-2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ideastracker.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/giant-fish-sculptures-made-from-discarded-plastic-bottles-3.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Giant Fish Sculptures Made from Discarded Plastic Bottles 3</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ideastracker.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/giant-fish-sculptures-made-from-discarded-plastic-bottles-4.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Giant Fish Sculptures Made from Discarded Plastic Bottles 4</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ideastracker.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/giant-fish-sculptures-made-from-discarded-plastic-bottles-5.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Giant Fish Sculptures Made from Discarded Plastic Bottles 5</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ideastracker.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/giant-fish-sculptures-made-from-discarded-plastic-bottles-6.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Giant Fish Sculptures Made from Discarded Plastic Bottles 6</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ideastracker.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/giant-fish-sculptures-made-from-discarded-plastic-bottles-7.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Giant Fish Sculptures Made from Discarded Plastic Bottles 7</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ideastracker.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/giant-fish-sculptures-made-from-discarded-plastic-bottles-8.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Giant Fish Sculptures Made from Discarded Plastic Bottles 8</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ideastracker.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/giant-fish-sculptures-made-from-discarded-plastic-bottles-9.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Giant Fish Sculptures Made from Discarded Plastic Bottles 9</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ideastracker.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/giant-fish-sculptures-made-from-discarded-plastic-bottles-10.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Giant Fish Sculptures Made from Discarded Plastic Bottles 10</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ideastracker.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/giant-fish-sculptures-made-from-discarded-plastic-bottles-11.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Giant Fish Sculptures Made from Discarded Plastic Bottles 11</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>I Wanna Be a Cavewoman.  And I Wanna Be Legally Permitted to Club My Husband Whenever We Don’t Agree.</title>
		<link>http://loveandlunchmeat.com/2012/08/01/i-wanna-be-a-cavewoman-and-i-wanna-be-legally-permitted-to-club-my-husband-whenever-we-dont-agree/</link>
		<comments>http://loveandlunchmeat.com/2012/08/01/i-wanna-be-a-cavewoman-and-i-wanna-be-legally-permitted-to-club-my-husband-whenever-we-dont-agree/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 19:23:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Love &#38; Lunchmeat</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Motherhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Childbirth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pregnancy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nomenclature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Names]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://loveandlunchmeat.com/?p=2135</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Generally speaking, my husband and I are very lucky.  We agree on lots of things so there’s no need for us to battle.  However, on those rare occasions where we do disagree, we both play to win.  And if we get to mock each other in the process, that’s a HUGE bonus.  Funny is fair [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2135&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://loveandlunchmeat.com/2012/08/01/i-wanna-be-a-cavewoman-and-i-wanna-be-legally-permitted-to-club-my-husband-whenever-we-dont-agree/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/4560821f110d3079ba3cb28d6777bc48?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">loveandlunchmeat</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://loveandlunchmeat.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/pb220017.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">OLYMPUS DIGITAL CAMERA</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://loveandlunchmeat.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_43881.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_4388</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://loveandlunchmeat.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/pregnant.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">pregnant</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://loveandlunchmeat.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_5200.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_5200</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lady Gaga and Mystery Man Arrested After Hot Air Balloon Joy Ride*</title>
		<link>http://badlandsbadley.wordpress.com/2012/08/01/lady-gaga-and-mystery-man-arrested-after-hot-air-balloon-joy-ride/</link>
		<comments>http://badlandsbadley.wordpress.com/2012/08/01/lady-gaga-and-mystery-man-arrested-after-hot-air-balloon-joy-ride/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2012 04:09:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>badlandsbadley</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bieber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Boyfriend]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gaga]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Justin Bieber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lady Gaga]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Michael Vick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yahoo]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://badlandsbadley.wordpress.com/?p=3809</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There, on the front page of Yahoo, was what was sure to be the biggest news story of the year. “Bad-boy Actor Pummels Justin Bieber.” Finally, after tormenting the world for what seems like years, some actor had taken care of Bieber once and for all. It was probably Nicholas Cage. Cage doesn’t seem to [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3809&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://commons.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Lady_Gaga_covered_in_blood.jpg" target="_blank"><img class="zemanta-img-inserted zemanta-img-configured aligncenter" title="English: Lady Gaga covered in &quot;blood&quot;..." src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/b/bd/Lady_Gaga_covered_in_blood.jpg/300px-Lady_Gaga_covered_in_blood.jpg" alt="English: Lady Gaga covered in &quot;blood&quot;..." width="300" height="391" /></a></p>
<p>There, on the front page of Yahoo, was what was sure to be the biggest news story of the year.</p>
<p>“Bad-boy Actor Pummels Justin Bieber.”</p>
<p>Finally, after tormenting the world for what seems like years, some actor had taken care of Bieber once and for all. It was probably Nicholas Cage. Cage doesn’t seem to have a lot going on lately. Add that pent-up crazy to repeatedly hearing Bieber’s “Boyfriend,” and you have a situation prime for a Cage beat down.</p>
<p>Clearly, I had no choice but to click on the story.</p>
<p>Instead of a story describing Nicholas Cage screaming “Swaggie this!” as he unleashed a fury of fists on Bieber’s prepubescent face, I found a much less pleasant surprise. This was not a news story. This was just Bieber’s new video.</p>
<p>I had been sucked in by a misleading title. Some tricky writer at Yahoo had done their best to get more reads by crafting a perfectly sneaky headline.</p>
<p>After my initial disappointment dissipated, I came to realize something. I could also gain readers by using this technique. It doesn’t matter what I write. All that matters is the headline.</p>
<p>I began to study this headline carefully. All of the elements of a sensational story were there. You had an “important” figure. You had a terribly dramatic story. Combine the two and you are certain to get a great number of incredibly confused and mildly upset readers.</p>
<p>Finding someone more popular than Bieber for my headline would be hard. His soulful voice and ambiguous gender have made him the most popular singer in the world. In fact, only one other singer has the same level of voice and gender confusion as Bieber. Only one person could be as popular.</p>
<p>Lady Gaga.</p>
<p>While Bieber would have been enough to get a few clicks for Yahoo, they added a mystery. Who was the “bad-boy actor?” More than anything, I wanted to know who it was that beat him up. Even a person who could not care less about Bieber would be curious.</p>
<p>Following this, I added my own mystery. Whatever was going to happen, Gaga would be doing it with a mystery man. People would see it and immediately have a million questions. Is it her boyfriend? Is her boyfriend Justin Bieber? Is her boyfriend the one who beat up Justin Bieber? Does having a boyfriend make Lady Gaga a heterosexual or homosexual? These questions would lead to hundreds, nay, thousands of readers.</p>
<p>But what would Gaga and her mystery boy toy be doing? It has to be fantastical enough to draw people to it. If the headline had been “Bad-boy Actor Buys Justin Bieber an Ice Cream Cone,” no one would care. It has to be crazy.</p>
<p>Drug use is too common. Dog fighting is too Michael Vick. Wrestling zoo animals is too unbelievable. After a bit of work, I had it.</p>
<p>“Lady Gaga and Mystery Man Arrested After Hot Air Balloon Joy Ride*”</p>
<p>Of course, as a responsible journalist, I feel compelled to add the following disclaimer:</p>
<p><em>*Lady Gaga has not actually been linked to a mystery man and, to my knowledge, has never been arrested for any hot air balloon related crimes. It is a situation that is possible, though. Just imagine it. What a huge story that would be. I guess that’s probably why you clicked on this post in the first place. You thought you were about to read a huge story.</em></p>
<p><em>Now I feel slightly responsible to give you a real story. I just ate a Hershey’s Bliss bar for the first time and it’s pretty good. Not great, but pretty good. I know it’s not as good as the Gaga story, but at least you know of a pretty decent candy bar. I think we can all count this as a win.</em></p>
<h6 class="zemanta-related-title" style="font-size:1em;">Related Articles</h6>
<ul class="zemanta-article-ul">
<li class="zemanta-article-ul-li"><a href="http://www.thejc.com/news/uk-news/70698/justin-bieber-and-lady-gaga-cheer-aly-raisman-after-gold-medal-win" target="_blank">Justin Bieber and Lady Gaga cheer for Aly Raisman after gold medal win</a> (thejc.com)</li>
<li class="zemanta-article-ul-li"><a href="http://www.celebuzz.com/2012-07-28/fact-or-fiction-is-selena-gomez-dumping-justin-bieber-tom-cruise-trying-to-win-over-daughter-suri-kate-hudson-and-scarlett-johansson-feuding/" target="_blank">Fact or Fiction? Is Selena Gomez Dumping Justin Bieber, Tom Cruise Trying to Win Over Daughter Suri, Kate Hudson and Scarlett Johansson Feuding?</a> (celebuzz.com)</li>
</ul>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3809/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3809/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3809&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://badlandsbadley.wordpress.com/2012/08/01/lady-gaga-and-mystery-man-arrested-after-hot-air-balloon-joy-ride/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>26</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f8e44c94a11b63121bea68db40ecd125?s=96&#38;d=monsterid&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">badlandsbadley</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/b/bd/Lady_Gaga_covered_in_blood.jpg/300px-Lady_Gaga_covered_in_blood.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">English: Lady Gaga covered in &#34;blood&#34;...</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Another Day, Another Olympic Scandal: Corrupt Boxing Edition</title>
		<link>http://mildmanneredsportsenthusiast.com/2012/08/02/another-day-another-olympic-scandal-corrupt-boxing-edition/</link>
		<comments>http://mildmanneredsportsenthusiast.com/2012/08/02/another-day-another-olympic-scandal-corrupt-boxing-edition/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2012 17:08:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Teeblerone</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Boxing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Olympics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AIBA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Azerbaijan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corrupt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Japan]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mildmanneredsportsenthusiast.com/?p=1974</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#160; Yesterday, we talked about all the missteps that the Olympics had stumbled over so far in these games, highlighted by the four badminton teams who tried to lose intentionally. Well, today is a new day for these Olympic Games, a fresh start, a chance to really show us the best&#8230;oh, wait, no, nevermind. Just [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1974&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 550px"><img class=" " title="Olympic boxing" src="http://msnbcmedia.msn.com/j/MSNBC/Components/Photo/_new/pb-120802-boxing3-da.photoblog900.jpg" alt="" width="540" height="346" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Clearly the guy checking the mat for cracks is winning this fight</p></div>
<p>Yesterday, we talked about all the <a title="When Adults Playing Badminton Becomes “Nonsense”" href="http://mildmanneredsportsenthusiast.com/2012/08/01/when-adults-playing-badminton-becomes-nonsense/" target="_blank">missteps</a> that the Olympics had stumbled over so far in these games, highlighted by the four badminton teams who tried to lose intentionally. Well, today is a new day for these Olympic Games, a fresh start, a chance to really show us the best&#8230;oh, wait, no, nevermind. Just another scandal, this time in boxing, after Magomed Abdulhamidov of Azerbaijan was awarded the win over Japan&#8217;s Satoshi Shimizu 22-17 despite getting knocked down SIX TIMES in the third and final round. That&#8217;s not just a little fishy, that&#8217;s a beached whale in your living room level of suspicious.</p>
<p><span id="more-1974"></span></p>
<p>Shimizu sums up the general reaction to the decision pretty well. From <a title="Japan win appeal after controversial loss" href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/sport/0/olympics/19088420" target="_blank">BBC</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;I was shocked by the final scores. He fell down so many times,&#8221; Shimizu said.</p>
<p>&#8220;Why didn&#8217;t I win? I don&#8217;t understand.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>The crowd didn&#8217;t understand either, raining boos down on the ring and the judges who delivered such a ridiculous decision. So how did a boxer who hit the mat half a dozen times in three rounds walk away with a decisive victory? Well, with money, of course! Lots and lots of money.</p>
<p>According to reports from<a title="Allegations of deal to fix 2012 Olympic boxing medals" href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-15020658" target="_blank"> <em>BBC Newsnight</em> </a>last September, there was evidence of Azerbaijan paying millions of dollars fora  guarantee of Azerbaijani gold at the London Games. According to documents found by BBC, $9 million had been transferred, funneled through Switzerland, to a boxing organization, Word Series Boxing, which is owned by the AIBA, which oversees Olympic boxing. According to whistleblowers, they weren&#8217;t exactly stealthy about it.</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Ivan boasted to a few of us that there was no need to worry about World Series Boxing having the coin to pay its bills. As long as the Azeris got their medals, WSB would have the cash.&#8221;</p>
<p>Another said that Mr. Khodabakhsh cam in and said: &#8220;We are safe now &#8211; Azerbaijan came in &#8211; we have to give them medals for that.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;He was talking gold medals in London in return for millions of dollars of secret payments,&#8221; the insider added. &#8220;Medals are being sold so blatantly it&#8217;s amazing.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>As expected, Azerbaijan denied the allegations, and an AIBA committee found them groundless, calling the $9 million a &#8220;purely commercial investment.&#8221; Of course, why would a committe within the company receiving a huge payoff dig too deep into allegations of a huge payoff? I&#8217;m pretty sure if you looked up &#8220;conflict of interest&#8221; in the dictionary, a picture of these guys rolling around in money would be right next to it.</p>
<p>But I&#8217;m sure the AIBA thought that Azerbaijan would make it easier to slide them through by doing things like &#8220;training&#8221; and &#8220;not being terrible at boxing,&#8221; but the guarantee of gold seems to have dulled the drive of Abdulhamidov, at least, as he became one of the few people to get knocked down in Olympic competition, and possibly the only to ever get knocked down six times.</p>
<p>Japan rightfully immediately appealed this decision and thankfully the <a title="Satoshi Shimizu receives justing from the AIBA" href="http://www.boxingscene.com/satoshi-shimizu-receives-justice-from-aiba--55625" target="_blank">AIBA </a>did the right thing by upholding it, awarding the bout to Shimuzu. Of course, Abdulhamidov didn&#8217;t give them much choice. Their statement:</p>
<blockquote><p>After reviewing the video of Bout #105 involving Bantamweights Satoshi Shimizu (Japan) and Magomed Abdulhamidov (Azerbaijan), the Competition Jury made the following decision:</p>
<p>-The boxer from Azerbaijan fell down six (6) times during the 3rd round. According to our rules, the Referee should have counted at least three (3) times. In this case, following the AIBA Technical &amp; Competition Rules, the decision should have been RSC (Referee Stop Contest);</p>
<p>-Therefore the protest lodged by the Japanese corner is accepted and the result of this bout overturned.</p>
<p>AIBA official will consider on Thursday morning whether to sanction the referee of this bout.</p></blockquote>
<p>So, good news? Kind of. The decision to uphold the appeal isn&#8217;t because the judges giving the fight to a boxer who clearly didn&#8217;t win the fight is a ridiculous decision, it&#8217;s because the referee should have stopped the fight. So the AIBA gets their fall-guy (who was likely told not to stop the fight, if the allegations of a payoff are true), and the judges who watched a guy fall down a whole bunch of times and thought, &#8220;Yeah, that guy&#8217;s our winner,&#8221; get off without so much as a slap on the wrist.</p>
<p>Of course, now the AIBA has bigger problems on its hands. Azerbaijan is on line one, and they&#8217;d like to discuss their &#8220;investment.&#8221;</p>
<p>(pic <a href="http://msnbcmedia.msn.com/j/MSNBC/Components/Photo/_new/pb-120802-boxing3-da.photoblog900.jpg" target="_blank">via</a>)</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1974/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1974/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1974&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://mildmanneredsportsenthusiast.com/2012/08/02/another-day-another-olympic-scandal-corrupt-boxing-edition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>18</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/1a94312d235998544164325b3cf40b1a?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F1.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mildmanneredsportsenthusiast</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://msnbcmedia.msn.com/j/MSNBC/Components/Photo/_new/pb-120802-boxing3-da.photoblog900.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Olympic boxing</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Freshly Pressed&#8217;s Best Of July 2012</title>
		<link>http://en.blog.wordpress.com/2012/08/03/freshly-presseds-best-of-july-2012/</link>
		<comments>http://en.blog.wordpress.com/2012/08/03/freshly-presseds-best-of-july-2012/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2012 17:01:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Kevin Ohannessian</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Freshly Pressed]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://en.blog.wordpress.com/?p=11696</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The month of July has come and gone and we featured over 600 posts on Freshly Pressed. So here is a look back at ten of these stories: those we thought were the most interesting and those the WordPress.com community loved and engaged with the most. • Torridon Photographer Fraser McAlister shares the shots he [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=11696&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The month of July has come and gone and we featured over 600 posts on <a href="http://wordpress.com/#!/fresh/" target="_new">Freshly Pressed</a>. So here is a look back at ten of these stories: those we thought were the most interesting and those the WordPress.com community loved and engaged with the most.</p>
<h3>• <a href="https://mcalisterium.wordpress.com/2012/07/09/torridon/" target="_new">Torridon</a></h3>
<p>Photographer Fraser McAlister shares the shots he took on a trip to Scotland: photos of hills, lakes, insects, and more spotlight the country&#8217;s beauty. The unique green/gray palette made this photo series feel visceral.</p>
<p><a href="https://mcalisterium.wordpress.com/2012/07/09/torridon/" target="_new"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-11701" title="torridon scotland" src="http://en.blog.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/torridon-scotland.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<h3>• <a href="http://thepickledhedgehog.com/2012/07/17/crocheting-to-change-the-planet" target="_new">Crocheting to Change the Planet</a></h3>
<p>We get a glimpse at the Crochet Coral Reef project in St. Petersburg, Florida and learn about climate change&#8217;s effect on the biodiversity of the ocean. And how could you not love jellyfish made of yarn?</p>
<p><a href="http://thepickledhedgehog.com/2012/07/17/crocheting-to-change-the-planet" target="_new"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-11702" title="coral crochet" src="http://en.blog.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/coral-crochet.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="485" /></a></p>
<h3>• <a href="http://laughinglovingeating.wordpress.com/2012/07/18/why-blogging-scares-me-2/" target="_new">Why Blogging Scares Me</a></h3>
<p>A young blogger shares why she waited a month to put up the first post of her new blog devoted to life and food. Her honesty and openness left an impression on us.</p>
<p><a href="http://laughinglovingeating.wordpress.com/2012/07/18/why-blogging-scares-me-2/" target="_new"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-11704" title="sandwich" src="http://en.blog.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/sandwich.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="467" /></a></p>
<h3>• <a href="https://milesvenkman.wordpress.com/2012/07/21/an-open-letter-to-jessica-redfield/" target="_new">An Open Letter to Jessica Redfield</a></h3>
<p>Miles Venkman somberly compares his own experience with <em>The Dark Knight Rises</em> to that of the late Sports blogger. The shootings in Aurora left a mark on many communities, including WordPress.</p>
<p><a href="https://milesvenkman.wordpress.com/2012/07/21/an-open-letter-to-jessica-redfield/" target="_new"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-11705" title="jessica redfield" src="http://en.blog.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/redfield.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="253" /></a></p>
<h3>• <a href="https://findfabulous.wordpress.com/2012/07/22/dirty-thirty-the-list/" target="_new">Dirty Thirty: The List</a></h3>
<p>What would you like to accomplish before you hit the age of 30? One young woman shares her aspirations. Everyone should make lists like this and actually push to fulfill them.</p>
<p><a href="https://findfabulous.wordpress.com/2012/07/22/dirty-thirty-the-list/" target="_new"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-11707" title="dirty thirty" src="http://en.blog.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/thirty.jpg" alt="" width="491" height="326" /></a></p>
<h3>• <a href="http://unorthodoxepicure.com/2012/07/22/confession-no-51-why-sweat-the-big-things-worry-about-the-small-really-important-stuff/" target="_new">Why sweat the big things? Worry about the small (really important) stuff.</a></h3>
<p>This food blogger discusses what frustrates him in life, and shares a wonderful and unique sorbet recipe. As before, honest and thought-provoking writings about life really engage people.</p>
<p><a href="http://unorthodoxepicure.com/2012/07/22/confession-no-51-why-sweat-the-big-things-worry-about-the-small-really-important-stuff/" target="_new"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-11709" title="sorbet" src="http://en.blog.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/sorbet.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="443" /></a></p>
<h3>• <a href="http://sweetjellybean.com/2012/07/23/diy-monday-5-easy-steps-to-make-your-own-blog-header-give-it-a-go/" target="_new">5 Easy Steps To Make Your Own Blog Header!</a></h3>
<p>Donah takes us through how she created the images that top her blog page. It is a clear tutorial that can be helpful for many bloggers who are looking to improve their pages but aren&#8217;t sure how.</p>
<p><a href="http://sweetjellybean.com/2012/07/23/diy-monday-5-easy-steps-to-make-your-own-blog-header-give-it-a-go/" target="_new"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-11710" title="header" src="http://en.blog.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/header.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="325" /></a></p>
<h3>• <a href="http://anniecardi.com/2012/07/27/friday-fifteen-28/" target="_new">Friday Fifteen</a></h3>
<p>This bibliophile shares with us a handful of 15-word book reviews, focusing on books from the U.K. to celebrate the Olympics. It is a series, so check out his other quick reviews.</p>
<p><a href="http://anniecardi.com/2012/07/27/friday-fifteen-28/" target="_new"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-11711" title="book" src="http://en.blog.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/book.jpg" alt="" width="347" height="475" /></a></p>
<h3>• <a href="http://gnosticbent.wordpress.com/2012/07/27/10-things-that-suck-about-being-a-guy/" target="_new">10 Things That Suck About Being a Guy</a></h3>
<p>This sometimes earnest and sometimes tongue-in-cheek post highlights the pitfalls of masculinity. This post is quite universal; most of us men feel this way at sometime or another.</p>
<p><a href="http://gnosticbent.wordpress.com/2012/07/27/10-things-that-suck-about-being-a-guy/" target="_new"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-11712" title="crying" src="http://en.blog.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/crying.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="335" /></a></p>
<h3>• <a href="http://juliahass.wordpress.com/2012/07/28/the-olympics-are-fabulous-sometimes/" target="_new">The Olympics Are Fabulous (Sometimes)</a></h3>
<p>Lastly, Julia Hass shares her opinion on the Olympics&#8211;not the athletes or the sports events, but the teams&#8217; clothes. The nations&#8217; official uniforms were all quite different and quite intriguing.</p>
<p><a href="http://juliahass.wordpress.com/2012/07/28/the-olympics-are-fabulous-sometimes/" target="_new"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-11713" title="olympics parade" src="http://en.blog.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/olympics-parade.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="429" /></a></p>
<p><strong><em>What were your favorite Freshly Pressed items and blogs posts of the month?</em></strong></p>
<p>And for those who want more, check out <a href="http://wordpress.com/#!/fresh/" target="_new">Freshly Pressed</a>, follow our <a href="http://dailypost.wordpress.com/" target="_new">Daily Post</a> writing prompts and challenges, and browse our <a href="http://wordpress.com/#!/read/recommendations/" target="_new">Recommended Blogs</a> and <a href="http://wordpress.com/#!/read/topics/" target="_new">our blog topics</a>. For more info on how we choose posts for FP, peruse our <a href="http://en.support.wordpress.com/five-ways-to-get-featured-on-freshly-pressed/" target="_new">support documents</a>.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/11696/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/11696/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=11696&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://en.blog.wordpress.com/2012/08/03/freshly-presseds-best-of-july-2012/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/256519766ab944cbaf98c3a47722b82a?s=96&#38;d=retro" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">kevinohannessian</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://en.blog.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/torridon-scotland.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">torridon scotland</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://en.blog.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/coral-crochet.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">coral crochet</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://en.blog.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/sandwich.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sandwich</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://en.blog.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/redfield.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jessica redfield</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://en.blog.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/thirty.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">dirty thirty</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://en.blog.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/sorbet.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sorbet</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://en.blog.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/header.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">header</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://en.blog.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/book.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">book</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://en.blog.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/crying.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">crying</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://en.blog.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/olympics-parade.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">olympics parade</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8220;And They Call Me Barbarian&#8221;</title>
		<link>http://muslimreverie.wordpress.com/2012/08/02/and-they-call-me-barbarian/</link>
		<comments>http://muslimreverie.wordpress.com/2012/08/02/and-they-call-me-barbarian/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2012 02:46:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jehanzeb</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Anti-racism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Islamophobia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[azeem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[James Holmes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[morgan freeman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prince of thieves]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Racism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robin hood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Terrorism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the Joker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[White privilege]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[White supremacy]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://muslimreverie.wordpress.com/?p=1801</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Remember this scene from &#8220;Robin Hood: Prince of Thieves&#8221; (1991)*? After witnessing Robin deliberately lie to his own English folk about the number of enemies approaching them, the North African Muslim character Azeem reflects to himself and says, &#8220;And they call me barbarian.&#8221;  Here&#8217;s the clip for those who haven&#8217;t seen it or need their [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1801&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://muslimreverie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/azeem1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-1802" title="Azeem1" src="http://muslimreverie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/azeem1.jpg?w=286&h=428" alt="" width="286" height="428" /></a><br />
Remember this scene from <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0102798/" target="_blank"><strong>&#8220;Robin Hood: Prince of Thieves&#8221; (1991)*</strong></a>? After witnessing Robin deliberately lie to his own English folk about the number of enemies approaching them, the North African Muslim character Azeem reflects to himself and says, &#8220;And they call <em>me</em> barbarian.&#8221;  Here&#8217;s the clip for those who haven&#8217;t seen it or need their memories refreshed:</p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><span style="text-align:center; display: block;"><a href="http://muslimreverie.wordpress.com/2012/08/02/and-they-call-me-barbarian/"><img src="http://img.youtube.com/vi/xmqlmY93dx8/2.jpg" alt="" /></a></span></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Yeah, that&#8217;s my reaction whenever white non-Muslims like <a href="http://www.cbsnews.com/8301-201_162-57476449/james-holmes-24-identified-as-suspect-in-deadly-mass-shooting-at-colorado-movie-theater/" target="_blank"><strong>James Holmes</strong></a> go around shooting and killing innocent people. &#8220;And they call <em>us</em> (Muslims) terrorists,&#8221; I say.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Of course James Holmes, who indiscriminately <a href="http://bostonherald.com/news/national/central/view/20120720gunman_kills_14_injures_50_during_dark_knight_massacre_in_colorado" target="_blank"><strong>opened fire on moviegoers</strong></a> at the midnight screening of &#8220;The Dark Knight Rises&#8221; in Aurora, Colorado,  is not called a &#8220;terrorist&#8221; because that term is reserved for Muslims only. Instead, Holmes is pronounced &#8220;mentally ill,&#8221; an ableist and inaccurate narrative since most people struggling with mental illnesses <a href="http://www.alternet.org/newsandviews/article/1035722/understanding_the_colorado_shooting%3A_terrorism,_politics,_mental_illness_and_the_superhero_complex/" target="_blank"><strong>do not act out violently</strong></a>. Dismissed in the stereotyping of disabled bodies are the serious societal and political factors that contribute to the culture of violence in the United States. Meanwhile, white non-Muslim and able-bodied people never have to worry about being collectively blamed, stigmatized, racially profiled, or subjected to racist laws that target their entire race/community due to the violent actions of one man.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Even if some media outlets like NPR refer to Holmes as a terrorist, the narrative is still very different than how stories about Muslims are covered. When Muslims do it, the term &#8220;terrorist&#8221; is assigned to not just one person, but the entire community and religion. It&#8217;s heavily racialized and presented as an organized, &#8220;foreign&#8221; problem that threatens the existence of western civilization. White non-Muslim bodies like Holmes are ultimately seen as individuals, as &#8220;lone wolves,&#8221; and as &#8220;mentally ill.&#8221; The consequences of a white non-Muslim person committing an act of terror like this does not, as I pointed out, result in widespread, societal, and institutionalized discrimination against all white people.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">In other words, I highly doubt Sherlock Holmes is worried about his next movie not being a hit just because he shares the same last name as a white terrorist. I&#8217;m confident that people with the first name &#8220;James&#8221; won&#8217;t get harassed with offensive questions like, &#8220;Have you ever thought about changing your name after what happened in Colorado?&#8221; (in the same way men with the first name &#8220;Osama&#8221; are). Also, I&#8217;m pretty sure that people who dress up as the Joker for Halloween aren&#8217;t going to be stopped in the street by police officers and demanded to provide their photo IDs or an explanation of why they&#8217;re dressed as Batman&#8217;s arch-nemesis  (in case you didn&#8217;t know, <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/2012/07/20/james-holmes-i-am-the-joker-aurora-shooting-suspect-claimed-to-be-batman-nemesis-pictures_n_1690780.html" target="_blank"><strong>Holmes told the police, &#8220;I am the Joker&#8221;</strong></a>).</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">And let&#8217;s be honest about white non-Muslim privilege and power: a Muslim person wouldn&#8217;t have been able to <a href="http://abcnews.go.com/US/colorado-movie-theater-shooting-suspect-bought-guns-6000/story?id=16817842#.UBnTVKOo_r4" target="_blank"><strong>legally purchase vast amounts of firepower</strong></a> (4 guns, 6,000 rounds of ammunition) Holmes did without having a visit from the FBI. Are the NYPD-CIA spy teams considering to infiltrate white neighborhoods, Presbyterian churches (since Holmes was reported to have been <a href="http://global.christianpost.com/news/james-holmes-colorado-shooter-described-as-normal-christian-boy-amid-mental-health-investigation-photo-78623/" target="_blank"><strong>highly involved with his church</strong></a>), and schools in the same way they <a href="http://colorlines.com/archives/2012/02/first_came_the_shock_then.html" target="_blank"><strong>violated the rights of countless Muslims</strong></a> in New York, New Jersey, and Pennsylvania? Do World War II buffs who collect German military uniforms, firearms, and other weapons need to worry about their homes being searched without warrants?</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">White supremacist capitalist heteropatriarchy easily tells us that the answer is &#8220;no,&#8221; white non-Muslims do not need to be profiled or spied upon. Forget that James Holmes&#8217; terrorism reveals the failure of gun control in the US and forget that opening fire in a movie theater shows how vulnerable people are. The &#8220;real threat,&#8221; we are constantly reminded, is from the &#8220;illegal immigrants,&#8221; the racialized peoples, the Muslims from &#8220;over there&#8221; who have the &#8220;mission&#8221; to &#8220;destroy the west from within.&#8221; These &#8220;real threats&#8221; need to be monitored, but not the white people who buy guns, ballistics gear, and ridiculous amounts of ammunition.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Lastly, I came across articles on <a href="http://gawker.com/5929846/you-can-become-a-fan-of-james-holmes-on-facebook-but-you-shouldnt" target="_blank"><strong>Gawker</strong></a> and the <a href="http://www.nydailynews.com/news/national/meet-holmies-accused-dark-knight-shooter-a-weird-online-fan-club-article-1.1126496" target="_blank"><strong>New York Daily News</strong></a> about people who identify themselves as &#8220;Holmies,&#8221; or fans of James Holmes. They have <a href="http://mashable.com/2012/07/31/holmies-tumblr/?WT.mc_id=en_top_stories&amp;utm_campaign=Top%2BStories" target="_blank"><strong>Tumblr blogs, Facebook group pages, and YouTube videos</strong></a> in tribute of James Holmes. It is noteworthy to point out that these fans are predominately white and even try to emulate his manner of dress.  As one article put it, James Holmes has inspired &#8220;an online legion of &#8216;fans&#8217; who upload original artworks and photos of themselves sporting Holmes-inspired plaid shirts flannel and sipping Slurpees.&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">And they call <em>us</em> barbarians.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">* <em>Just a few thoughts on &#8220;Robin Hood: Prince of Thieves.&#8221; I agree with Jack Shaheen, author of <a href="http://www.reelbadarabs.com/" target="_blank"><strong>&#8220;Reel Bad Arabs,&#8221;</strong></a> that the character of Azeem represents one of the rare positive images we see of Muslims in Hollywood cinema. However, I also agree with Sumbul Ali-Karamali, author of <a href="http://www.muslimnextdoor.com/" target="_blank"><strong>&#8220;The Muslim Next Door,&#8221;</strong></a> that while Azeem is a hero, he is still otherized. I find the &#8220;devout mystical dude&#8221; and &#8220;loyal white man&#8217;s servant&#8221; portrayal of him to be really problematic and stereotypical, for sure. There are some moments when I appreciate how his character serves as a (often humorous) critique of romanticized European history (especially the Crusades) and the white imagination&#8217;s negative perception of Muslims and Islam.<br />
</em></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1801/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1801/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1801&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://muslimreverie.wordpress.com/2012/08/02/and-they-call-me-barbarian/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>77</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/5954a9d87c5790d214871a0ff3f97d43?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Jehanzeb</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://muslimreverie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/azeem1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Azeem1</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why $100,000 Teacher Salaries Make Sense</title>
		<link>http://mindfulstew.wordpress.com/2012/08/02/why-100000-teacher-salaries-make-sense/</link>
		<comments>http://mindfulstew.wordpress.com/2012/08/02/why-100000-teacher-salaries-make-sense/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2012 18:14:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bluegrasspb</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[No Stone Unturned]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Money]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[philosophy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[teacher salary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[teaching]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mindfulstew.wordpress.com/?p=495</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Many American educators&#8211;myself included&#8211;often remind ourselves and others that we didn&#8217;t enter education for the money.  I certainly don&#8217;t teach to become wealthy, but as I see outstanding educator colleagues and friends leave the classroom for higher-paying, often lower-stress jobs in education, I wonder what it would take to increase the tenure of experienced, skilled [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=495&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3><span style="color:#000000;">Many American educators&#8211;myself included&#8211;often remind ourselves and others that we didn&#8217;t enter education for the money.  I certainly don&#8217;t teach to become wealthy, but as I see outstanding educator colleagues and friends leave the classroom for higher-paying, often lower-stress jobs in education, I wonder what it would take to increase the tenure of experienced, skilled teachers.</span></h3>
<p><span style="color:#000000;"><a href="http://mindfulstew.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/richmoney1.jpg"><span style="color:#000000;"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-503" title="richmoney" src="http://mindfulstew.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/richmoney1.jpg?w=300&h=189" alt="" width="300" height="189" /></span></a></span></p>
<h3><span style="color:#000000;">And I wonder how long I will last, with increased financial responsibility coming with marriage and my own family down the line.</span></h3>
<h3><span style="color:#000000;">So what would it take to start attracting more talent into the teaching pool in the States?  It might boil down to greenbacks.  According to Prichard Committee for Academic Excellence Director Stu Silberman, dramatically increasing compensation could eventually lead to dramatically improved schools.</span></h3>
<h3><span style="color:#800000;">How about a starting salary for teachers of  $100,000?</span></h3>
<h3><span style="color:#000000;">Those numbers might seem ridiculous, especially for first-year professionals with a wild range of educational attainment and ability, yet Silberman argues that the idea is feasible in a recent blog post at <a href="http://blogs.edweek.org/edweek/engagement_and_reform/2012/07/want_more_quality_teachers_show_some_respect.html"><span style="color:#000000;">Education Week</span></a>:</span></h3>
<h3 style="text-align:center;"><span style="color:#000000;"><em>&#8230;if the entry-level salary is $100,000 (<a href="http://educationnext.org/how-to-pay-teachers-dramatically-more-within-budget/"><span style="color:#000000;">this is possible within current budgets</span></a>), what could we expect to happen? First, many top students who want to teach but now choose a different profession for financial reasons would bring their skills into the classroom for the benefit of our students. The appeal of higher salaries would allow universities to become more selective about the candidates they allow into their teacher preparation programs. As stronger talent entered the teaching workforce, student achievement would rise. The <a href="http://www.centerforpubliceducation.org/Main-Menu/Staffingstudents/Teacher-quality-and-student-achievement-At-a-glance/Teacher-quality-and-student-achievement-Research-review.html"><span style="color:#000000;">Center for Public Education</span></a> reports, &#8220;There is research that has shown that students of teachers who have greater academic ability&#8211;be it measured through SAT or ACT scores, GPA, IQ, tests of verbal ability, or selectivity of the college attended&#8211;perform better.&#8221; As achievement levels rise, we would have a stronger pool of future educators, thus continuing the upward spiral.</em></span></h3>
<h3 style="text-align:left;"><span style="color:#000000;">I agree with Silberman&#8217;s general premise, but I doubt we have the political will to undergo such a dramatic transformation of the profession.</span></h3>
<h3 style="text-align:left;"><span style="color:#000000;">And it is true that the talent pool of teacher candidates is currently diluted.  According to numbers released by Education Testing Services (ETS), education majors score well below average on the GRE compared to students in other fields.  The exception is secondary education majors, who score slightly above average.  American schools aren&#8217;t going to dramatically improve with&#8211;let&#8217;s face it&#8211;such a wild range of abilities standing in front of 30 tired, eager, excited, or belligerent students in schools across the land.  Test scores aren&#8217;t everything, but the numbers are a strong indicator of where teaching falls on a career prestige scale.</span></h3>
<h3><span style="color:#000000;">Speaking of prestige, Finland&#8217;s education system has recently received a bounty of praise, and it&#8217;s no surprise that the best and brightest there desire to become educators.  What do we have?  A glut of Teach for America applicants from our top colleges and universities, but many of these students aren&#8217;t looking into education long-term.  Just look at <a href="http://www.edweek.org/ew/articles/2011/10/04/kappan_donaldson.html"><span style="color:#000000;">retention rates</span></a>.</span></h3>
<h3><span style="color:#000000;">It&#8217;s a tough sell to drastically increase teacher salaries and increase qualification requirements.  But I&#8217;m sick and tired of politicians and citizens lamenting the fact that our public schools are a mess, when recruiting, training, and compensation systems are not set up to create and retain widespread teacher excellence.</span></h3>
<h3><span style="color:#000000;">Big challenges require bold solutions.  What do you think?</span></h3>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/495/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/495/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=495&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://mindfulstew.wordpress.com/2012/08/02/why-100000-teacher-salaries-make-sense/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>66</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/246f3fa7a529ab34795614bf00c8ca57?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bluegrasspb</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mindfulstew.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/richmoney1.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">richmoney</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Interview &#8211; Ope O talks iPhoneography</title>
		<link>http://slworkshops.wordpress.com/2012/08/01/the-interview-ope-o-talks-iphoneography/</link>
		<comments>http://slworkshops.wordpress.com/2012/08/01/the-interview-ope-o-talks-iphoneography/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 18:24:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>slworkshops</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Interview]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[greatarsenal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iPhoneography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Julian Hawkins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London 2012]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ope O]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photo workshop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography workshops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shadows and Light]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[street photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[urban landscape]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://slworkshops.wordpress.com/?p=554</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Ope O is a Londoner developing his career as a street photographer. Primarily he uses Nikon DSLR&#8217;s along with a Fuji X100 but over the last two years he&#8217;s been exploring the rapidly expanding and developing world of iPhoneography in tandem with his iPhone 4S. With this in mind we here at Shadows &#38; Light decided [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=554&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://web.stagram.com/n/greatarsenal/">Ope O</a> is a Londoner developing his career as a street photographer. Primarily he uses Nikon DSLR&#8217;s along with a Fuji X100 but over the last two years he&#8217;s been exploring the rapidly expanding and developing world of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Iphoneography">iPhoneography</a> in tandem with his iPhone 4S. With this in mind we here at Shadows &amp; Light decided to track down Ope O &amp; interrupt him for a short while from his all important work at <a href="http://www.london2012.com">London 2012</a> as part of the <a href="http://www.obs.es">Olympic Broadcasting Services (OBS)</a> operation.</p>
<p>Before we begin here&#8217;s a taste of some of Ope&#8217;s recent iPhoneography and you can see his work from the London Olympics under his <a href="http://web.stagram.com/n/greatarsenal/">greatarsenal</a> tag that&#8217;s happening on Instagram this very moment&#8230;</p>
<div id="attachment_568" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://slworkshops.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/you-can-observe-a-lot-by-just-watching-yogi-berra1.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-568  " title="http://instagr.am/p/MMY4YRwaqJ/" src="http://slworkshops.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/you-can-observe-a-lot-by-just-watching-yogi-berra1.jpg?w=300&h=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">&#8216;You can observe a lot by just watching&#8217; ~ Yogi Berra</p></div>
<div id="attachment_569" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://slworkshops.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/nothing-is-more-beautiful-than-a-line-that-brings-out-a-form-mary-beth.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-569" title="http://instagr.am/p/LyO9Cowaqt/" src="http://slworkshops.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/nothing-is-more-beautiful-than-a-line-that-brings-out-a-form-mary-beth.jpg?w=300&h=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">&#8216;Nothing is more beautiful than a line that brings out a form&#8217; ~ Mary Beth</p></div>
<p>S&amp;L. I&#8217;ve been following your work for some time both on Instagram and Facebook so it&#8217;s great to have the chance for a more in depth talk.</p>
<p>OO. That&#8217;s good.</p>
<p>S&amp;L. Let&#8217;s start by me asking what it is about iPhoneography that makes it so appealing to you as a photographic tool apart from just the ease of use and ability to remain relatively unseen?</p>
<p>OO. The quality of the photos is quiet impressive for a mobile phone. It&#8217;s easy to operate. Plus I often get questioned on instagram about what I&#8217;m using to take pictures, some people are amazed to find out its an iPhone.</p>
<p>S&amp;L. When you first started looking at iPhone photography and camera apps what led you to Instagram rather than, say Hipstamatic?</p>
<p>OO. Not many people were talking about it but I first heard about Instagram through social media.. And I decided to give it a ago after hearing more. I didn&#8217;t know about any other photography apps at that time as I was using an iPod touch then.</p>
<p>S&amp;L. What other camera apps have you tried &amp; what do you think of them?</p>
<p>OO. I&#8217;ve tried quiet a few including Camera +, VSCO Cam, Vintage Cam, Slow Shutter Cam and more. I&#8217;ve also gone through a lot of editing apps. I&#8217;ve still kept a few of these apps because each of them have different functions which I&#8217;m still interested in using, mostly to enhance the pictures I post on Instagram.</p>
<p>S&amp;L. I can see from your iPhone that you sometimes use a lens type attachment to enhance the existing lens. Tell me about it &amp; why you like it?</p>
<p>OO. I use a fisheye lens attachment occasionally. I really like the warped effect it gives to certain pictures. I would usually use it in tube stations where they have the long walk/pathways</p>
<div id="attachment_574" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://slworkshops.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_44871.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-574" title="http://instagr.am/p/K26DwTQarM/" src="http://slworkshops.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_44871.jpg?w=300&h=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">&#8216;When the road ahead seems too long, look back to see how far you’ve come&#8217; ~ Daniella Kessler</p></div>
<p>S&amp;L. Why have you stuck with Instagram or are you just a loyal customer?</p>
<p>OO. In my opinion Instagram is the best way for me to share photos on a mobile device, I tend to get a lot of feedback from other users and this motivates me to keep posting and also keeps my profile up out there.</p>
<p>S&amp;L. So would you say it&#8217;s the not just the app that works for you but the whole Instagram platform?</p>
<p>OO. Yeah, definitely.</p>
<div id="attachment_571" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://slworkshops.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/e2809ci-dreamed-a-thousand-new-paths-i-woke-and-walked-my-old-onee2809d.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-571 " title="http://instagr.am/p/L_WICTwaro/" src="http://slworkshops.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/e2809ci-dreamed-a-thousand-new-paths-i-woke-and-walked-my-old-onee2809d.jpg?w=300&h=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">&#8216;I dreamed a thousand new paths&#8230; I woke and walked my old one&#8217; ~ Chinese proverb</p></div>
<p>S&amp;L. You&#8217;ve mentioned that you feel iPhoneography is going to become a big thing in the immediate future. Can you elaborate?</p>
<p>OO. I tend to use all aspects of the app, sharing through Twitter and Facebook, etc. I&#8217;m always looking for ways to improve and with the current rise in iPhoneography there are plenty examples that I can learn from. A lot of pro photographers are starting to use this method in their work while others have won awards for it. I feel that these are the reasons it&#8217;ll become a bigger thing in the future which can only get better as the years go by.</p>
<div id="attachment_576" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://slworkshops.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/it-is-not-length-of-life-but-depth-of-life-ralph-waldo-emerson1.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-576" title="http://instagr.am/p/Ln4ILfQak5/" src="http://slworkshops.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/it-is-not-length-of-life-but-depth-of-life-ralph-waldo-emerson1.jpg?w=300&h=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">&#8216;It is not length of life, but depth of life&#8217; ~ Ralph Waldo Emerson</p></div>
<p>S&amp;L. Don&#8217;t you think though that in your pro-practice you&#8217;ll have problems convincing a client to accept &amp; thus pay for images generated on a phone? Will they take you/us seriously? Wont they argue that they could do it themselves &amp; therefore the value of your work &amp; what you can charge for it may be debased?</p>
<p>OO. Yes, I think those problems will always be there. There are still people unaware of the full scale of what can be achieved through iPhoneography. It isn&#8217;t just the picture, it&#8217;s the editing process which can boost your image to the point where it doesn&#8217;t even look like it was shot on an iPhone. It can only get better and when people start realising that, they&#8217;d start to give more time and effort to it and it will increase in value.</p>
<p>S&amp;L. And with all cameras good ones are never cheap and as pro&#8217;s we&#8217;re always under pressure to have the latest hardware and software and know how to use it.</p>
<p>OO. Too true!</p>
<p>S&amp;L. I&#8217;ve successfully printed out iPhone shots created with Hipstamatic &amp; Instagram full frame onto A3 and had some re-produced in print. Have you tried printing images that you&#8217;ve generated in this way? What do you think of the results &amp; what size prints have you made?</p>
<p>OO. I haven&#8217;t actually printed out any of my iPhone generated shots. It&#8217;s something I&#8217;ve thought about doing a couple of times but never got round to it so it&#8217;s high on my list.</p>
<p>S&amp;L. Do you think that dedicating just to Instagram is going to limit your scope of action?</p>
<p>OO. I don&#8217;t think so, everyone should know about it now. It currently has over 80 million users making it the number 1 camera app and I feel it&#8217;ll keep getting better with various updates. Plus they&#8217;re now integrating the use of other camera/editing apps with instagram making things easier.</p>
<div id="attachment_578" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://slworkshops.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/lost-time-is-never-found-again-benjamin-franklin.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-578 " title="http://instagr.am/p/L6NqUcwaoe/" src="http://slworkshops.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/lost-time-is-never-found-again-benjamin-franklin.jpg?w=300&h=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">&#8216;Lost time is never found again&#8217;. ~ Benjamin Franklin</p></div>
<p>S&amp;L. Earlier you said that the iPhoneographer can pass by relatively unnoticed, does that take us back to the way in which people like Cartier-Bresson worked &amp; the need to forever be on the lookout for the perfect moment?</p>
<p>OO. Yeah, it does quite a lot. When photographing people on the street I often wait to get that one shot. I&#8217;ll take more than two at least before I&#8217;m happy with what I&#8217;ve got.</p>
<p>S&amp;L. As you develop your own following under the soubriquet &#8216;<a href="http://web.stagram.com/n/greatarsenal/">greatarsenal</a>&#8216; do you see this as a purely a profile raising and marketing exercise or do you feel that it helps bring in commissions for your iPhoneography per se?</p>
<p>OO. When I started with <a href="http://web.stagram.com/n/greatarsenal/">Instagram</a>, I never really thought I&#8217;d gain as much attention from it because it was just a hobby, so choosing my name wasn&#8217;t really that important for me. I&#8217;ve chosen to stick with it now as I&#8217;ve been a user for quiet a while and that&#8217;s what many other users know me as. However my <a href="http://web.stagram.com/n/greatarsenal/">Instagram</a> profile cross-references to me as Ope O and so to my <a href="http://www.opeophotography.com">website</a> &amp; <a href="http://www.facebook.com/opeophotography">Facebook</a> profile. It all ties in really.</p>
<p>S&amp;L. So my final question has to be to ask where you find the quotes that tend to accompany your Instagrams?</p>
<p>OO. (smiles) Well, it&#8217;s like this really; I don&#8217;t really plan any of my Instagram shots, if I see something that I like and I could make a good image out of it I&#8217;ll shoot it, edit the shot, find a suitable quote (usually from <a href="http://brainyquote.com/">brainyquote.com</a>) then post it.</p>
<p>S&amp;L. Ok Ope, many thanks for your time, I&#8217;d better let you get back to your work on the <a href="http://www.london2012.com">London Olympics</a>.</p>
<p>The techie stuff: iPhone 4S, Instagram</p>
<p>All images © Ope O</p>
<p>The web links:</p>
<p><a href="http://web.stagram.com/n/greatarsenal/">Instagram user name: greatarsenal</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.facebook.com/opeophotography">www.facebook.com/opeophotography</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.opeophotography.com/">www.opeophotography.com</a></p>
<p>And the closing shot&#8230;</p>
<div id="attachment_581" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://slworkshops.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/life-is-an-attitude-art-is-an-expression-of-life-ideally-art-as-well-as-life-should-be-the-greatest-expression-possible-from-us-as-individuals-bobbie-kilpatrick.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-581" title="http://instagr.am/p/MWSkImwalO/" src="http://slworkshops.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/life-is-an-attitude-art-is-an-expression-of-life-ideally-art-as-well-as-life-should-be-the-greatest-expression-possible-from-us-as-individuals-bobbie-kilpatrick.jpg?w=300&h=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">&#8216;Life is an attitude. Art is an expression of life. Ideally, art as well as life should be the greatest expression possible from us as individuals&#8217; ~ Bobbie Kilpatrick</p></div>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/554/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/554/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=554&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://slworkshops.wordpress.com/2012/08/01/the-interview-ope-o-talks-iphoneography/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/3ed0f3058d2369bfa88e1cb7f6813456?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">slworkshops</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://slworkshops.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/you-can-observe-a-lot-by-just-watching-yogi-berra1.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">http://instagr.am/p/MMY4YRwaqJ/</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://slworkshops.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/nothing-is-more-beautiful-than-a-line-that-brings-out-a-form-mary-beth.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">http://instagr.am/p/LyO9Cowaqt/</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://slworkshops.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_44871.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">http://instagr.am/p/K26DwTQarM/</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://slworkshops.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/e2809ci-dreamed-a-thousand-new-paths-i-woke-and-walked-my-old-onee2809d.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">http://instagr.am/p/L_WICTwaro/</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://slworkshops.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/it-is-not-length-of-life-but-depth-of-life-ralph-waldo-emerson1.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">http://instagr.am/p/Ln4ILfQak5/</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://slworkshops.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/lost-time-is-never-found-again-benjamin-franklin.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">http://instagr.am/p/L6NqUcwaoe/</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://slworkshops.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/life-is-an-attitude-art-is-an-expression-of-life-ideally-art-as-well-as-life-should-be-the-greatest-expression-possible-from-us-as-individuals-bobbie-kilpatrick.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">http://instagr.am/p/MWSkImwalO/</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>