<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2013 21:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Loving My Body for Lent</title>
		<link>http://sarahoverthemoon.com/2013/02/20/lent-body-purity/</link>
		<comments>http://sarahoverthemoon.com/2013/02/20/lent-body-purity/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2013 19:01:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sarah Moon</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bodies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christianity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Modesty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[purity]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://sarahoverthemoon.com/?p=3373</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As a former fundamental Baptist, this is only my second year of observing Lent. Lent, when I was growing up, was one of those things that Catholics do because they don&#8217;t really believe in Jesus (I don&#8217;t think most Baptist preachers actually know any Catholics) and so they are enslaved to law and to rules and boundaries. [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3373&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As a former fundamental Baptist, this is only my second year of observing Lent. Lent, when I was growing up, was one of those things that <em>Catholics </em>do because they don&#8217;t really believe in Jesus (I don&#8217;t think most Baptist preachers actually know any Catholics) and so they are enslaved to law and to rules and boundaries.</p>
<p>I thought, as a Baptist, that I was so lucky to not be enslaved to rules like those Catholics were.</p>
<div class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 197px"><a href="http://sarahoverthemoon.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/199_27612667984_451_n.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image " id="i-3431" alt="Image" src="http://sarahoverthemoon.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/199_27612667984_451_n.jpg?w=187" width="187" height="299" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Photo by me.</p></div>
<p>Funny, considering the fact that when I was thinking this, I likely had on a skirt that had to go past the bottom of knee and a shirt that passed the &#8220;two-finger&#8221; test. I probably wore a silver ring on my left hand that bore the words &#8220;True Love Waits.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sitting their with a beam in my own eye, judging the Catholics and their Lent, I could not see how bound to rules I really was.</p>
<p>How bound to rules my <em>body </em>really was.</p>
<p><em>&#8220;Don&#8217;t cause your brothers to stumble.&#8221; </em></p>
<p><em>&#8220;I was addicted to porn because the girls in my youth group wore tight jeans.&#8221;</em></p>
<p>&#8220;<em>Music should speak to your heart, not your hips.&#8221;</em></p>
<p>&#8220;<em>A Christian man will be able to tell if a woman is not sexually pure. A good Christian man will not find an impure woman beautiful.&#8221; </em></p>
<p>&#8220;<em>When you give your body away, it is like letting someone test-drive you like a car and crash you.&#8221;</em></p>
<p>&#8220;<em>You do not have a soul. You are a soul. You have a body.&#8221; </em></p>
<p>&#8220;<em>Skin is sin.&#8221;</em><em><br />
</em></p>
<p>These are the words I heard over and over growing up. Skin is sin. Using my body is sin. My body itself is sin.</p>
<p>These were the words which kept me afraid of the body that was mine. The body that was <em>me. </em>These are the words that made me afraid of the awesome mass of cells and energy and chemical reactions that was my body. These are the words that made me afraid of any emotional or physical actions or reactions that were considered <em>bodily. </em></p>
<p>Sweating.</p>
<p>Crying.</p>
<p>A need for touch.</p>
<p>Dancing.</p>
<p>Exercising.</p>
<p>Sexual attraction.</p>
<p>I hid my body under layers of clothes. I crossed my arms and my legs and made myself as small as possible. I didn&#8217;t touch. Didn&#8217;t dance. I beat myself up whenever my body reacted to someone I found attracted. I heaped on guilt and shame and self-hatred whenever I touched myself.</p>
<p>And when I met my first boyfriend, and he began to treat my body like it belonged to him, I didn&#8217;t think I was allowed to stop. After all, my body didn&#8217;t belong to me, and I couldn&#8217;t use my body to fight back.</p>
<p>I carry over so much baggage from those years of disconnect from my body, from myself. <strong>Though I spent my years as a fundamentalist bragging about the freedom I supposedly had in Christ, that freedom was for my soul alone.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Not my body.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Never my body.</strong></p>
<p>Yet, as my blogger friend Suzannah Paul says in this wonderful piece (made even more wonderful because of a reference to one of my favorite genres of music):</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>Our physical selves were knit by God to be wholly entwined with our spirituality,</strong> and the latter doesn’t trump the former. In the Nicene Creed, we affirm the resurrection of the dead. Even in heaven we’ll have bodies, and it makes little sense to live spiritual lives divorced from our bodily ones here on earth. [Emphasis mine]</p></blockquote>
<p><strong>So, for Lent this year, I&#8217;m setting my body free.</strong></p>
<p>I&#8217;m setting it free from the hatred that I have directed toward it for years and years. I&#8217;m setting it free from any responsibility that the church tries to put on it for the sins of men. I&#8217;m setting it free from Platonic associations with the carnal, the base, the non-transcendent.</p>
<p><strong>I&#8217;m embracing my body for what it is&#8211;one of the amazing manifestations of a universe filled with divine wisdom. Also, me. My body is me. </strong></p>
<p>I&#8217;m loving my body for Lent. I&#8217;m letting me be me.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3373/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3373/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3373&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://sarahoverthemoon.com/2013/02/20/lent-body-purity/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/765850ca202460c5eb6454545ec399e2?s=96&#38;d=retro&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sarahoverthemoon</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://sarahoverthemoon.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/199_27612667984_451_n.jpg?w=187" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Writing Motivated Characters</title>
		<link>http://ericjohnbaker.wordpress.com/2013/02/20/writing-motivated-characters/</link>
		<comments>http://ericjohnbaker.wordpress.com/2013/02/20/writing-motivated-characters/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2013 00:17:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>ericjbaker</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[On writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eric J Baker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[intermediate writers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Literary characters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[motivation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prose]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing for beginners]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zombies]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ericjohnbaker.wordpress.com/?p=502</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Prose is a mixture of technique and artfulness. In my previous posts, I’ve felt confident enough to talk about aspects of the writing craft that are, in my view, technique oriented. Creating good characters, on the other hand, seems like an art form to me.  Let&#8217;s see if I can take the fun out of it [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=502&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Prose is a mixture of technique and artfulness. In my previous posts, I’ve felt confident enough to talk about aspects of the writing craft that are, in my view, technique oriented. Creating good characters, on the other hand, seems like an art form to me.  Let&#8217;s see if I can take the fun out of it and get technical!</p>
<p><a href="http://ericjohnbaker.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/turtle.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-513" alt="turtle" src="http://ericjohnbaker.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/turtle.jpg?w=538&#038;h=399" width="538" height="399" /></a></p>
<p>Each writer has her own way of building characters, but we all share the same goal of making those literary creations authentic and interesting. Where to start? First I want to consider the major components of a character. I&#8217;m no expert, so feel free to add your thoughts or tell me what I missed:</p>
<p>1. History</p>
<p>2. <strong>Motivation </strong>(Today&#8217;s topic. I knew it would come up!)</p>
<p>3. Dialog</p>
<p>4. Action</p>
<p>In regard to history or backstory, many writers create bios of each character, especially for stories with complex family trees, royal bloodlines, or a multi-generational timeline. Others are comfortable with a general sense of their characters’ pasts. When it comes to dialog and action, our literary creations must say and do things that are consistent with who they are.</p>
<p>Which brings us to motivation. We, as writers, should ask ourselves what our heroes, villains, and supporting cast members want to accomplish. Although bit players can be purely functional, our stars must have objectives. Why write a story about them if they have nothing to do?</p>
<p>But is an external objective enough on its own to make someone real or interesting? Think about yourself. I&#8217;m sure you have goals, but you also have the push and pull of your intrinsic nature, which sometimes helps you and other times holds you back. For example, I know I am motivated to control outcomes, and I don&#8217;t like surprises. I relax like a turtle does a back stroke: Very poorly. On the other hand, I&#8217;m empathetic and see value in other perspectives. If you put me in a zombie apocalypse story, I&#8217;ll be the guy telling all the knuckleheads to calm down so we can make a survival plan in a logical, collaborative manner. I have a goal &#8211; to survive the zombie onslaught &#8211; and an intrinsic nature, which is to impose order and control while still respecting others&#8217; views.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s my formula for character motivation:</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">External motivation (goal) + internal motivation (intrinsic nature)</p>
<p>Internally, each of us is a cauldron of motivations that are often invisible to others. However,when the stakes are high, our intrinsic natures come to the fore. Going back to the zombie scenario, I can&#8217;t be the controlling guy with the diplomatic personality in one scene and the hysterical guy who loses his temper every five minutes in the next. A more plausible dynamic is for me to be frozen by inaction when I&#8217;ve imposed my plan but the zombies manage to breach the fortress anyway, since (warning: theme coming) efforts to control outcomes in life are ultimately futile. As I&#8217;m being devoured by the undead, perhaps I can say, &#8220;You know, I learned a valuable lesson here about living in the moment!&#8221;</p>
<div id="attachment_515" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 234px"><a href="http://ericjohnbaker.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/brains.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-515" alt="Motivation: Find lunch" src="http://ericjohnbaker.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/brains.jpg?w=224&#038;h=300" width="224" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Motivation: Find lunch</p></div>
<p>Think about the people you know, dig below the surface, and imagine why they act the way they do. Have you ever met someone who puts people down to make up for her own lack of self-esteem? How about someone who tries too hard to please the boss because she needs validation as a human being and doesn&#8217;t know how to find it in herself? Combine those internal qualities, give the character an external goal (getting the heroine fired), and – <i>voilà</i> – you’ve got a secondary villain. The main villain is a serial killer hiding in the air ducts, by the way.</p>
<p>Here is a tiny sampling of intrinsic motivations that can be combined with others and, when coupled with an external goal, make one&#8217;s literary offspring more authentic:</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Wanting to win at all costs and dreading failure</span>. This character often makes the people around him miserable with all his ups and downs, and the world is all about him.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Striving to win approval and craving attention</span>. This person may seek praise from authority figures and try to make others feel guilty. Passive aggressiveness, in other words.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Seeking variety and distraction</span>. This character can get lost in what he’s doing and let people down who were counting on him.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Avoiding social interaction</span>. No one knows what’s really going on behind her nerd glasses!</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Assuming all people see things the way you do</span>. He buys his wife a football. She wanted <i>Sex and the City: Season 1</i> on DVD.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Trying to get everything done yesterday</span>. She’s so wired, she makes the people around her tired just looking at her.</p>
<p>A character is bland if all he has is an external goal.  He needs dimensions. The next time our hero and his sidekick go on a quest to retrieve a magic sword, let&#8217;s make the hero a controlling, pushy type with no concern for others’ feelings, and depict the sidekick as an unassertive people-pleaser who gets walked on. The sidekick shouldn&#8217;t exist simply to help the hero find the sword. Give her a reason to overcome her anxieties and stand up for herself&#8230; even better if doing so is integral to the plot. While we&#8217;re at it, let&#8217;s teach the  hero a humbling lesson in empathy as he looks for that stupid sword.</p>
<p>On second thought, don’t make the sword stupid. People won’t want to read that.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">****************************</p>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=502&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://ericjohnbaker.wordpress.com/2013/02/20/writing-motivated-characters/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>57</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/0eba7d66842da0318e3fbed7de47fb57?s=96&#38;d=wavatar&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ericjbaker</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ericjohnbaker.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/turtle.jpg?w=538" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">turtle</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ericjohnbaker.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/brains.jpg?w=224" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Motivation: Find lunch</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Villains Part II&#8211;The Rose Tree</title>
		<link>http://terahvandusen.wordpress.com/2013/02/23/villans-part-ii-the-rose-tree/</link>
		<comments>http://terahvandusen.wordpress.com/2013/02/23/villans-part-ii-the-rose-tree/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2013 12:15:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Terah Van Dusen</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Memoir]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Childhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rural America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sexual abuse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://terahvandusen.wordpress.com/?p=2893</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[On either side of the front door to the inky, smelly, dilapidated mansion were two hedge plants, taller than a very tall man and as wide as our pick-up. Now, hedge smells a certain way. Hedge smells a helk of a lot better than old folk, chewing tobacco and black coffee in oily mugs. I still lean in and smell a hedge whenever I get [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2893&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://terahvandusen.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/old-door-linda-mcrae.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-2898" alt="old-door-linda-mcrae" src="http://terahvandusen.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/old-door-linda-mcrae.jpg?w=204&#038;h=300" width="204" height="300" /></a>On either side of the front door to the inky, smelly, dilapidated mansion were two hedge plants, taller than a very tall man and as wide as our pick-up. Now, hedge smells a certain way. Hedge smells a helk of a lot better than old folk, chewing tobacco and black coffee in oily mugs. I still lean in and smell a hedge whenever I get the chance, whenever I pass one by. I used to walk out of that smelly house and immediately bury my nose in the hedge.</p>
<p>For me hedge smells like freedom. The way a car radio sounds like freedom. The way my own personal set of apartment keys feels like freedom. The way an attractive man looks like freedom, foolishly. The way a cigarette tastes like freedom. I&#8217;d edit the illusions but they are my truths. These are the things in which I have identified freedom. Recognizing their traps and tricks, I have let at least one go. But I shall never let go of the rest.</p>
<p>As soon as the bitter note of hedge would meet my little girl nose I knew I was free. Free until dark. When I had to go back inside.</p>
<p>At first, shell-shocked, I would go as far from the mansion as I could. For a while my little bare legs would take me up creek to a bridge where I&#8217;d sit and watch the iridescent water saunter on by me. Hunter Creek. My dad was the first to show me Hunter Creek, of course. My dad showed me enough trails enough times that<a href="http://terahvandusen.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/art2.jpg?w=246"><img class="alignleft  wp-image-2907" alt="art2" src="http://terahvandusen.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/art2.jpg?w=197&#038;h=240" width="197" height="240" /></a> I knew how get to my Grandpa John&#8217;s house on Fizer Road, about two miles away&#8211;both by street and by trail. I also knew how to get to the elementary school and to the mouth of the Klamath River. I could probably get to the Mini-Mart too. I knew the best blackberry patches and where to find a mud bog so thick it could pass for quicksand. I told a couple boys in my first-grade class about the quicksand but they didn&#8217;t believe me. Boys were always challenging me. They thought I lied about things. The boys would stare at me for a good long while before excluding me from their games of kickball and football and other boy sports. I was always stuck between the boys and the girls but more drawn to the boy games and the boy talk. The playground attendant would tell me &#8217;you can&#8217;t play football &#8217;cause you&#8217;ll scrape up your bare knees even worse. Come over here and play with the girls.&#8217; Later I would stop wearing dresses and only wear jeans and stir-ups. As means to play with the boys.</p>
<p><a href="http://terahvandusen.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/favim_com-8091.jpg?w=230"><img class=" wp-image-2894  alignright" alt="Favim_com-8091" src="http://terahvandusen.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/favim_com-8091.jpg?w=230&#038;h=299" width="230" height="299" /></a></p>
<p>Despite all the special places my dad showed me, places he&#8217;d gone to &#8220;when he was a boy&#8221;, I finally found my special place&#8211;a rose tree right in front of the mansion. It was a place where me and my best friend and cat, Kitty Rose, could both go. And dummies never saw us there. Hiding in plain sight, she and I, up in The Rose Tree.</p>
<p>The Rose Tree had a trunk about as big a&#8217; round as my dad and branches as thick as necks. The bark was smooth and dusty. Until I met The Rose Tree I thought roses only grew on bushes. I also thought &#8216;every rose had it&#8217;s thorn&#8217; that&#8217;s because I heard the song &#8216;Every Rose Has It&#8217;s Thorn&#8217;. So when we first started goin&#8217; up there I would be weary, always looking for thorns. But there just weren&#8217;t any. Talk about magic.</p>
<p>I&#8217;d watch the old folk walk by, Kitty Rose and I perched at the top of The Rose Tree. The villains would mutter to themselves and look out to the fields, the hillside, the barn. They were looking for something, and I always wondered what. I knew it wasn&#8217;t me &#8217;cause I didn&#8217;t matter til bedtime.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2893/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2893/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2893&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://terahvandusen.wordpress.com/2013/02/23/villans-part-ii-the-rose-tree/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/89a4e77772b8c27d90e7a51790ea1a9f?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">terahvandusen</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://terahvandusen.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/old-door-linda-mcrae.jpg?w=204" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">old-door-linda-mcrae</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://terahvandusen.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/art2.jpg?w=246" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">art2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://terahvandusen.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/favim_com-8091.jpg?w=230" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Favim_com-8091</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Idiocy of Racism</title>
		<link>http://blackwomenunchecked.com/2013/02/25/the-idiocy-of-racism-the-onion-calls-quvenzhane-wallis-the-c-word/</link>
		<comments>http://blackwomenunchecked.com/2013/02/25/the-idiocy-of-racism-the-onion-calls-quvenzhane-wallis-the-c-word/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 14:48:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Shani Ealey</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quvenzhane wallis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[racist tweet by the onion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the onion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the onion and the c-word]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the onion's racist tweet]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blackwomenunchecked.com/?p=1348</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It is a beautiful day. The sun is shining and I am feeling good. Real good. That is until I read a text saying “Have you seen this shit The Onion tweeted?” I raise a quizzical eyebrow and proceed to discover the latest foolishness that finds its home on Twitter. I was thinking maybe it [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1348&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://blackwomenunchecked.com/2013/02/25/the-idiocy-of-racism-the-onion-calls-quvenzhane-wallis-the-c-word/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>49</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://blackwomenunchecked.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/quvenzhane-wallisslider-fr.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://blackwomenunchecked.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/quvenzhane-wallisslider-fr.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">quvenzhane-wallisSLIDER FR</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/d8851f0f0e3acc9ec58fafacf00b5bc0?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">shaniealey</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://blackwomenunchecked.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/quvenzhane-wallis1.jpg?w=560" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Source: thegrio.com</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://blackwomenunchecked.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/enhanced-buzz-22908-1361772105-5.jpg?w=560" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Source: Buzzfeed.com</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Should I Have Been Offended?</title>
		<link>http://southernmaninindy.wordpress.com/2013/02/25/on-macfarlane-and-the-oscars-should-i-have-been-offended/</link>
		<comments>http://southernmaninindy.wordpress.com/2013/02/25/on-macfarlane-and-the-oscars-should-i-have-been-offended/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 18:29:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Andrew Heaton</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[academy awards telecast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[baseball]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oscars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[racism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[seth macfarlane]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sexism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the onion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[twitter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wallis]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://southernmaninindy.wordpress.com/?p=666</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences was in a bind. The ratings for the Academy Awards telecast have been going down for years. Most people chalked that up to a show that reveled in an old-Hollywood environment that younger viewers had no desire to engage. They had tried to rectify this in the [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=666&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://southernmaninindy.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/oscars-seth-macfarlane_510x411.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-667" alt="oscars-seth-macfarlane_510x411" src="http://southernmaninindy.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/oscars-seth-macfarlane_510x411.jpg?w=300&#038;h=241" width="300" height="241" /></a>The Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences was in a bind. The ratings for the Academy Awards telecast have been going down for years. Most people chalked that up to a show that reveled in an old-Hollywood environment that younger viewers had no desire to engage. They had tried to rectify this in the past by bringing in the youthful team of Anne Hathaway and James Franco two years ago. Unfortunately  they forgot to stipulate in Mr. Franco&#8217;s contract that he had to actually care when he showed up, and that performance was a bomb. They over-corrected last year by bringing in Billy Crystal, whose face seems to have been worked over no less than 20 times by plastic surgeons, and whose act seems about as timely as a &#8220;Take my wife, please!&#8221; joke. The &#8220;youth block&#8221; yawned and changed the channel.</p>
<p>So the Academy decided to take a pretty dramatic turn for this years show by selecting <a title="Seth MacFarlane" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Seth_MacFarlane#Guest_appearances" target="_blank">Seth MacFarlane</a> to host. Seth MacFarlane was pretty hot at that moment the decision was announced, having just finished making a half a billion dollars worldwide for <a href="http://www.boxofficemojo.com/movies/?id=ted.htm" target="_blank">&#8216;Ted&#8217;</a> (you read that right, over $500,000,000), as well as having just wrapped a very well-received hosting gig on &#8216;Saturday Night Live&#8217;. The real, key, though, is that because of his most famous product, &#8216;Family Guy&#8217;, MacFarlane would be a host that would directly tap the 18-34 demo that the Oscars just could not get their hands around.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s not to say that MacFarlane was a safe or easy choice by any means. His resume was &#8216;Family Guy&#8217;, &#8216;Ted&#8217;, and . . . well, that&#8217;s pretty much it. (I&#8217;m wrapping all of his Fox animated shows under the &#8216;Family Guy&#8217; banner). His short resume is combined with the type of humor that is directly associated with &#8216;Family Guy&#8217; and &#8216;Ted&#8217;, which is to say NOT Billy Crystal&#8217;s style of humor. &#8216;Family Guy&#8217; is known for pushing the boundaries on all levels, and so there was quite a fear of just how far MacFarlane might go. This was combined with a large number of people who simply associated MacFarlane with the humor of his shows, and were going to bring in a lot of preconceived baggage about the host before the show even started.</p>
<p>Based on all of the reviews since then, I&#8217;d say that this is exactly what happened. <a title="Review: Seth MacFarlane's Oscars a self-indulgent mix" href="http://www.usatoday.com/story/life/movies/2013/02/24/bianco-oscar-review/1943985/" target="_blank">USA Today said</a>, &#8220;Awash in self-indulgence, neither he nor his 3-hour-and-35-minute show ever seemed to hit a comfortable, confident stride . . . .&#8221; On the other hand, the <a title="MacFarlane relaxed, confident as Oscars host" href="http://www.chicagotribune.com/entertainment/movies/oscars/chi-oscars-live-20130224,0,961348.story" target="_blank">Chicago Tribune wrote</a>, &#8220;Showing considerable poise, MacFarlane . . . opened with a series of jokes that were bona fide winners, landing on just the right tone: confident but not cocksure.&#8221; In the middle was <a title="MacFarlane Hosts an Oscar Show for All Ages" href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/02/25/movies/awardsseason/macfarlane-hosts-an-oscar-show-for-all-ages.html?_r=0" target="_blank">The New York Times</a>, much more critical of the overall pace and music selection of the show than Mr. MacFarlane, wrote, &#8220;Mr. MacFarlane didn’t ruin the show. But the show almost ruined the Oscars.&#8221;</p>
<p>So the responses turned out to be pretty much exactly what MacFarlane was already prepared for, and I as well. He was as polarizing in reviews as he was coming into the show to begin with, so no real shock. However, as I began reading real-time reviews last night, another theme started popping up, one that I was a little more taken aback by &#8211; this show was amazingly sexist?</p>
<p><strong><em>The Sexisim/Racisim Blind Spot</em></strong></p>
<p>The Atlantic was the first publication to really give a full-throated thrashing of the show, with an article published almost before the show was even over, titled, &#8220;<a title="The Banality of Seth MacFarlane's Sexism and Racism at the Oscars" href="http://www.chicagotribune.com/entertainment/movies/oscars/chi-oscars-live-20130224,0,961348.story" target="_blank">The Banality of Seth MacFarlane&#8217;s Sexism and Racism at the Oscars</a>.&#8221; This was followed fairly soon after by this Buzzfeed post: &#8220;<a title="9 Sexist Things That Happened At The Oscars" href="http://www.buzzfeed.com/hillaryreinsberg/sexist-things-at-the-oscars" target="_blank">9 Sexist Things That Happened at The Oscars.</a>&#8221; I found both of these articles immediately confusing, because at no point during the show&#8217;s telecast was I struck by the thought that anything I had seen was sexist. I also didn&#8217;t find it particularly racist, though his use of race in &#8220;Django&#8221; and &#8220;Lincoln&#8221; related jokes, I could at least see where that allegation could come from. The sexism charge, though, had me truly confused.</p>
<p>For full disclosure, I am a white, 30-year-old male who was raised in a pretty Conservative (the big C mean&#8217;s I&#8217;m talking about politically) household. I grew up in a Conservative environment, and in all honesty, never really lived in any environment that could be considered mildly liberal until I moved to the Bay Area this past June. I say all of this to acknowledge that I would be the first to admit that there can be times when I have a &#8220;blind spot&#8221; to certain sexist/racist issues. It&#8217;s a &#8220;blind spot&#8221; much in the same way a car&#8217;s blind spot work. It&#8217;s not that I can never see it or even don&#8217;t want to, but sometimes I have to take a second look and really pay attention before I see where an offended party might be coming from with their allegation.</p>
<p>So it&#8217;s with that disclosure in mind that I decided to take a serious look at the allegations against the show and MacFarlane. I reviewed all nine of the item&#8217;s on Buzzfeeds list. After a serious, careful consideration, my conclusion? I still don&#8217;t see it. The &#8220;Boobs&#8221; song was purposefully sexist in a meta-way, and the actress reactions were all pre-taped, illustrating that they were more than game for the joke. The Quvenzhane Wallis/Clooney joke was a joke about Clooney liking to date young women. The Chris Brown joke doesn&#8217;t offend me because CHRIS BROWN IS AWFUL AND DOESN&#8217;T DESERVE TO BE LEFT ALONE ABOUT SAVAGELY BEATING RIHANNA. The Anniston/Tatum joke was only calling her a possible stripper in as much as it was reminding us all that Tatum was once a stripper. That joke would have worked as well if he&#8217;d had a male co-presenter instead of Anniston. The dieting joke was really no different than every other &#8220;ladies trying to fit in Oscar dresses&#8221; jokes that have been made for the last 84 years of the show. The Kardashians joke wasn&#8217;t about women, it was about the Kardashians. Is anyone really in a mood to come to their defense? The Nicholson joke allegation is simply about the fact that Nicholson is known to be a scoundrel. The Salma Hayek joke might have been sexist if the setup didn&#8217;t also include Javier Bardem, who I&#8217;m pretty sure is not a women.</p>
<p>So of the 9 jokes that Buzzfeed labeled as sexist, the only one I&#8217;d probably give a slight nod to is the Chastain/&#8217;Zero Dark Thirty&#8217; joke, because, well, yeah, that was just a joke about women. With all of that said, though, again, I&#8217;m fully admitting that I can have a blind-spot on these issues. However, I&#8217;ve already begun asking some women who are colleagues and former classmates, and so far, I&#8217;m not finding many people defending the &#8220;sexist&#8221; allegations. I&#8217;d also note that two of the writers who wrote the more positive reviews that I linked to earlier were women. If you were offended by these jokes, though, please feel free to describe it below in the comments. I will not argue with you about it or try to talk you out of your perception of the show/jokes; I truly want to see and understand where other people who might have been offended are coming from regarding these jokes.</p>
<p><em><strong>Final Review</strong></em></p>
<p>So with ALL of that said, what was my opinion of the show? As you may imagine, I really enjoyed it. Aside from the fact that MacFarlane is my new-school doppleganger (<a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=donny+osmond&amp;hl=en&amp;safe=off&amp;source=lnms&amp;tbm=isch&amp;sa=X&amp;ei=zKkrUeG9BOOQiALO54GgCw&amp;ved=0CAoQ_AUoAQ&amp;biw=1280&amp;bih=896#imgrc=g0RQG17gRgHKvM%3A%3BrPT5A85eNrCsGM%3Bhttp%253A%252F%252Fgridirongoddess.net%252Fwp-content%252Fuploads%252F2010%252F08%252Fdonny_osmond_001_101106.jpg%3Bhttp%253A%252F%252Fgridirongoddess.net%252Ftag%252Fdonny-osmond%252F%3B300%3B375" target="_blank">Donny Osmond</a> my old-school one), I thought he brought to the table just the right mix of edginess combined with respect for old-school Hollywood. This shouldn&#8217;t be surprising, as this is a guy with a love for 50&#8242;s and 60&#8242;s era Hollywood (he put out an album of old standards in 2011, &#8216;Music Is Better Than Words&#8217;, that was nominated for 2 Grammys). He regularly holds large galas at his Hollywood home and brings in Big Band orchestras.</p>
<p>The style of joke delivery that USA Today and other described as &#8220;awkward&#8221; and &#8220;nervous&#8221; was anything but that; being somewhat bashful/playful with the delivery of a heart-spearing joke is his style. Hell, it&#8217;s really the comedic style of my entire generation. We like to give over-the-line jokes because we want to push the edge, but we want to signal that it&#8217;s a joke through our body language because we&#8217;re really not a mean or hateful generation (if anything, we&#8217;re one of the most open, loving, and respectful generations), and MacFarlane&#8217;s comedic style is the essence of that. Every interview he&#8217;s ever given has shown him to be a genuinely kind and likable person. Most people looked to the &#8216;Saturday Night Live&#8217; gig as a preview of what to expect, but I thought the better indicators were his performances as host of the Comedy Central Roasts of David Hasselhoff, Donald Trump, and Charlie Sheen. What&#8217;s funny about those performances was that they made my wife, who HATES &#8216;Family Guy&#8217;, somewhat develop a crush on Mr. MacFarlane and the charming way he twists the verbal knife.</p>
<p>They won&#8217;t have him back I bet, but I appreciate the Academy giving him the stage last night, and I enjoyed what he did with it.</p>
<p><strong>Thoughts at the Closing Bell:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><span style="line-height:13px;">So while I have obviously defended MacFarlane, I will NOT be defending <a title="The Onion Called Quvenzhané Wallis A Horrible Word" href="http://www.buzzfeed.com/kateaurthur/the-onion-called-quvenzhane-wallis-a-horrible-word" target="_blank">The Onion after their move last night regarding Quvenzhane Wallis</a>. I mean . . . yikes. I&#8217;m a habitual line-stepper, and that&#8217;s a bridge too far even for me. </span></li>
<li>All signs point to <a title="Most economists see 'sequestration' budget cuts as unavoidable" href="http://www.latimes.com/business/la-fi-mo-sequestration-economists-survey-20130225,0,7211387.story" target="_blank">Sequestration happening, folks.</a> Did you enjoy the recession in 2009? Because we might be saddling up for seconds.</li>
<li>Spring Training has started! I listened to a Spring Training game on the radio yesterday, and my life already feels brighter and happier. BASEBALLLLLLLLLLLLLLLLLLL. (Awww, but ain&#8217;t that America!)</li>
<li>So let me just acknowledge that, yes, it&#8217;s been 100 years since I last wrote a post. Actually, it&#8217;s been almost 3 months, which is one of my longest streaks since law school killed my blogging for awhile. I can&#8217;t say for sure what&#8217;s kept me from writing. I will say that some of the blame, though, lies with Twitter and Facebook. When I first started blogging after I graduated from college and moved 1000 miles away from home, blogging was my way to keep family and friends updated and connected. Now, though, I often find myself starting to write a post, only to think, &#8220;Huh, I kinda already talked about that on Twitter and Facebook.&#8221; I will say that I started and stopped gun-control posts at least three times, each time stopping and going, &#8220;Ughhh, I just don&#8217;t want to go here.&#8221;</li>
</ul>
<p>That&#8217;s all for now, kids. One love to you all.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/666/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/666/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=666&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://southernmaninindy.wordpress.com/2013/02/25/on-macfarlane-and-the-oscars-should-i-have-been-offended/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>81</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/87e23a0d9a600ff31f9b42587d9178b8?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">andyheaton (said quickly, as one word)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://southernmaninindy.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/oscars-seth-macfarlane_510x411.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">oscars-seth-macfarlane_510x411</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bitter Pill: Why Medical Bills Are Killing Us</title>
		<link>http://healthland.time.com/2013/02/20/bitter-pill-why-medical-bills-are-killing-us/</link>
		<comments>http://healthland.time.com/2013/02/20/bitter-pill-why-medical-bills-are-killing-us/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2013 01:42:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Christine Lim</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Health Care]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health Insurance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Policy & Industry]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://healthland.time.com/?p=80659</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Corrections Appended: February 26, 2013 1. Routine Care, Unforgettable Bills When Sean Recchi, a 42-year-old from Lancaster, Ohio, was told last March that he had non-Hodgkin’s lymphoma, his wife Stephanie knew she had to get him to MD Anderson Cancer Center in Houston. Stephanie’s father had been treated there 10 years earlier, and she and [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=80659&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://healthland.time.com/2013/02/20/bitter-pill-why-medical-bills-are-killing-us/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://timewellness.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/1500_cover_03041.jpg?w=240" />
		<media:content url="http://timewellness.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/1500_cover_03041.jpg?w=240" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">TIME Magazine Cover, Mar. 4, 2012</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/3b01e022cef5411570e897eb6a138f88?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">christinelim</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://timewellness.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/seanrecchi.jpg?w=302" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Sean Recchi</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://timewellness.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/gauze.jpg?w=272" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Gauze Pads</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Beef Stroganoff</title>
		<link>http://illbeoutinaminute.com/2013/02/24/beef-stroganoff/</link>
		<comments>http://illbeoutinaminute.com/2013/02/24/beef-stroganoff/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 02:31:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tracy fulks</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[deep thoughts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shit that happens to me]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beef stroganoff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[catharsis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chemotherapy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[death]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dying]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grieving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[loss]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[saying goodbye to a parent]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://illbeoutinaminute.com/?p=2947</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I remember the light of the refrigerator spilling out across my mother’s kitchen floor as I stood, overwhelmed and frozen, staring at the contents. The half-empty gallon of milk, the bag of limp and withered celery in the vegetable drawer, the carton of eggs. The unopened garlic and herb dip stared at me, as if [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2947&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://illbeoutinaminute.com/2013/02/24/beef-stroganoff/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>111</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/649d317949ebd458d40cb4d082ad0117?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tracyfulks</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tracyfulks.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/mom.jpg?w=319" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mom</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Broken People</title>
		<link>http://thinkingaloudx.wordpress.com/2013/02/22/broken-people/</link>
		<comments>http://thinkingaloudx.wordpress.com/2013/02/22/broken-people/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2013 22:24:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>patrickthompsonx</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ethics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Idols]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jimmy Savile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Light Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oscar Pisorius]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reeva Steenkamp]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thinkingaloudx.wordpress.com/?p=68</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Oscar Pistorius, charged this last week with the murder of his girlfriend, is a flawed person. Highly competitive and driven with –as has emerged in the days since Reeva Steenkamp died – a love of the finer things in life his success has allowed him to enjoy.  He is a man, almost like the archetypal [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=68&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Oscar Pistorius, charged this last week with the murder of his girlfriend, is a flawed person. Highly competitive and driven with –as has emerged in the days since Reeva Steenkamp died – a love of the finer things in life his success has allowed him to enjoy.  He is a man, almost like the archetypal European playboy, with a fondness for guns, fast cars and speedboats. But why shouldn&#8217;t he be? After all, Pistorius is the &#8216;fastest man on no legs&#8217; as it has been crudely put; an international icon both for his sporting achievements and his large personality. To suggest that anyone could achieve this status without a compulsive, neurotic drive to succeed and an ego that must be able to soak up praise and criticism in equal measure is to be naive. Equally, why should we not expect such success, achieved by a man still in his twenties, to have gone to his head?</p>
<p>And yet Pistorius&#8217;s flaws have been wheeled before us these last few days as if to offer some explanation for the actions he is accused of. Next to every article about a &#8216;hero fallen,&#8217; there is a snide sidebar talking about his &#8216;darker side&#8217; or listing events such as his 2009 speedboat crash, vague innuendo about &#8216;domestic incidents&#8217; and the reprinting of quotes on guns from old transcriptions of interviews that were ignored at the time. Aspects of Pistorius the man that were once part of his &#8216;character&#8217; or &#8216;charisma&#8217; are now half-shaped accusations hanging over him, fed to the people en masse as if they provide some explanation for a murder.</p>
<p>In his essay <em>Light Entertainment </em>published in the London Review of Books, Andrew O&#8217;Hagan brilliantly details how the media can build up a man to be perfect, the model of a light entertainer, and how society at large, in its search for whole, unbroken role models goes merrily along with this. O&#8217;Hagan is writing about Lionel Gamlin (once one of the BBC’s leading &#8216;light entertainers&#8217;), sexual abuse at the BBC and by extension, Jimmy Saville. Despite this, the salient point is relevant when discussing Pistorius or any other individual that finds themselves standing upon the pedestal of public adulation.</p>
<p>Being perfect sells. It sells newspapers and magazines and it sells an image. The only thing that is better than perfection in the eyes of the media is if great adversity has had to be crossed first (such as the adversity of losing both your legs beneath the knees as a toddler). Whether you are winning Paralympic gold a few weeks after becoming the first disabled person to compete in the Olympics, or spending a great part of your life &#8216;fixing it&#8217; for children, the media has no interest in exploring the darker sides of your character. In turn the consumers of this golden haze have no interest in knowing the cobwebbed corners of a celebrity&#8217;s life.  One cannot hope to make a role model out of someone who shares your flaws so they are brushed under the proverbial rug, left to moulder and grow out of the public imagination; until one day they come out, they always come out, and everyone acts shocked. <em>Why did no one notice? </em>is the cry that goes up, conveniently forgetting that no one wanted to ask or ever to look.</p>
<p>The difference between Pistorius and Saville is of course that by the time the media turned on the entertainer he was already dead and had already committed his crimes. Pistorius is alive and, at least in the eyes of the law, innocent until proven guilty. Whatever the media prints about Saville is, however traumatic, old news and serves only to shovel more dirt upon an already filthy reputation. What we are witnessing in the treatment of Oscar Pistorius is another, far more loathsome event, the trial by media of a man already undergoing trial by a court of law. Every detail of his life will be picked over and &#8216;inside sources&#8217; (surely the most hollow and fake term in journalism) will tell of shocking new developments, many of which have already proven to be factually inaccurate, or flaws in the man&#8217;s personality that we all missed, which should have told us this was coming.</p>
<p>This entire show, for a show or performance is all it is, will be played out in an outraged, condescending tone that will ignore every scrap of print or film from previous years that painted Pistorius as his public alter ego –the &#8216;Blade Runner&#8217; who had overcome adversity to stand atop his own sport and stride, quite literally, where no other amputee had gone before. In its stead will be a new public face for Pistorius, the man who was <em>always </em>going to do something like this. If the papers run out of stories they will turn upon the victim too, although with <em>The Sun going</em> to print with Steenkamp’s near naked body on its front page the day after her death perhaps they already have.</p>
<p>What will we, the readers, say about the new Pistorius? We will, for the most part, accept it. To do otherwise is to admit that for the past four, five, six years we have idolised a man who, whatever we thought, was not perfect. We could never have &#8216;seen this coming&#8217; but if we join the retrospective hunt for evidence of a psychopathy beneath calm exterior we can ignore the need to admit our part in the affair. Perhaps for those who truly adored Oscar Pistorius it might even feel good to tear through his past life and sit glued to the coverage of his trial.</p>
<p>Pisotrius is not unique in the treatment he has received from the public. Actors, politicians, writers and the celebrities of reality television are all targets of our admiration. The list of public figures that have been raised to impossible heights by a public that has then watched them fall is a long one. We, the British have become masters of this art and we are also the world leaders in ignore our role in this sordid media cycle.</p>
<p>The best example of this is the treatment of Diana Spencer (better known as the Princess of Wales), a woman whose public image could not have been purer had she grown wings and ascended to heaven. The media, driven by the public’s desire to live her life for themselves through the printed press, pursued Diana quite literally to her death. The outpouring of public grief that followed was described by Christopher Hitchens as an example of Britain’s ‘fetish’ of the Royal Family. In this Hitchens is wrong, for while we as a people may have a strange and unhealthy attachment to the House of Windsor, the tributes and flowers that marked the weeks after her death were more actions of a guilty public conscience. Even now, over a decade on from the Parisian car crash that killed Diana it is the paparazzi that are blamed for her death (discounting conspiracy theories) and the fact is quietly ignored that had the public not demanded photos of the ex-Princess in every edition of the news, she would not have been so hounded. Whatever happens to Pistorius, he is destined to be another individual in a line of public figures whose fall from grace will continue to be a shock to us as long as we refuse to admit that such people are, like us, not perfect but broken in some way. That is not to say that one should not admire public figures for their qualities but that we must realise that the athletes and singers, writers and actors and King and Queens that give the world so much colour are just as human and you or me. To expect them to be perfect and not to feel the same pain or sadness that we do is inhuman at best.</p>
<br /> Tagged: <a href='http://thinkingaloudx.wordpress.com/tag/idols/'>Idols</a>, <a href='http://thinkingaloudx.wordpress.com/tag/jimmy-savile/'>Jimmy Savile</a>, <a href='http://thinkingaloudx.wordpress.com/tag/light-entertainment/'>Light Entertainment</a>, <a href='http://thinkingaloudx.wordpress.com/tag/media/'>Media</a>, <a href='http://thinkingaloudx.wordpress.com/tag/oscar-pisorius/'>Oscar Pisorius</a>, <a href='http://thinkingaloudx.wordpress.com/tag/reeva-steenkamp/'>Reeva Steenkamp</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/68/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/68/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=68&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thinkingaloudx.wordpress.com/2013/02/22/broken-people/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>17</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/37622b305e37dc587c1f708e6bfc639f?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">patrickthompsonx</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Post-It Poems: Falling Star</title>
		<link>http://wrongside.me/2013/02/24/post-it-poems-falling-star/</link>
		<comments>http://wrongside.me/2013/02/24/post-it-poems-falling-star/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2013 17:04:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Fiona</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Poetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wrongside]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fiona mccoll]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mine]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://wrongside.me/?p=4073</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#160; Now we’ll see if “I love you’s” fell too swiftly. Waiting in the quiet hours I remember - This is how silence is built One minute after another adding up to nothing.<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4073&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-4074" alt="Post It Poems" src="http://wrongside1.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/post-it-poems1.jpg?w=720"   /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align:center;">Now we’ll see<br />
if “I love you’s”<br />
fell too swiftly.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">Waiting in the quiet hours<br />
I remember -</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">This is how<br />
silence is built<br />
One minute after another<br />
adding up to nothing.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">
</blockquote>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4073/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4073/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4073&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://wrongside.me/2013/02/24/post-it-poems-falling-star/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>32</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/35cb712dcab5bb29713a623a9052db3e?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Fiona</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://wrongside1.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/post-it-poems1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Post It Poems</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Media Bias 101</title>
		<link>http://quinersdiner.com/2013/02/23/media-bias-101/</link>
		<comments>http://quinersdiner.com/2013/02/23/media-bias-101/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2013 14:45:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>quinersdiner</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[John Boehner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media bias]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[President Obama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ray LaHood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sequester]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://quinersdiner.com/?p=8779</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A simple story in the Des Register about the impact of the coming sequester on Iowa airports had a subtle bias to it.<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=8779&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://quinersdiner.com/2013/02/23/media-bias-101/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>26</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/0ccf9e55b371023aefdeacd24fc2af41?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">quinersdiner</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://quinersdiner.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/freshly-pressed-header.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">FRESHLY PRESSED header</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
