<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 22:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>The Wild Thornberrys Revisited</title>
		<link>http://mittenskittens.wordpress.com/2012/11/14/the-wild-thornberrys-revisited/</link>
		<comments>http://mittenskittens.wordpress.com/2012/11/14/the-wild-thornberrys-revisited/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2012 01:24:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>jessmittens</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Humour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cartoons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Donnie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[essay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the Wild Thornberrys]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mittenskittens.wordpress.com/?p=1567</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Going back to those favourite cartoons you watched as a child normally leads to a lot of strange and confused realisations about that show. You may pick out now-obvious sexual innuendo (I&#8217;ll never forget the moment in Bee Movie when the grandpa bee shouts &#8220;I did it with a grasshopper once, her crazy legs had [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1567&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Going back to those favourite cartoons you watched as a child normally leads to a lot of strange and confused realisations about that show. You may pick out now-obvious sexual innuendo (I&#8217;ll never forget the moment in <em>Bee Movie</em> when the grandpa bee shouts &#8220;I did it with a grasshopper once, her crazy legs had me up all night long!&#8221;), adult humour, jokes that reference something you&#8217;ve since seen / read / heard so can finally understand, and sometimes, the shows are downright creepy and you wonder how you ever sat through an episode at the age of 7 without crying.</p>
<p>Well, recently I went back to one of my old favourites,<em> The Wild Thornberrys </em>because as far as my memory was concerned, that show was awesome. Or, in the words of Nigel, I thought it was smashing!</p>
<p><a href="http://mittenskittens.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/tumblr_md0aikh4zj1rie0uao1_500.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1572" title="tumblr_md0aikh4ZJ1rie0uao1_500" alt="" src="http://mittenskittens.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/tumblr_md0aikh4zj1rie0uao1_500.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>For the most part, it really is. I really like <em>The Wild Thornberrys</em>. It&#8217;s colourful, captivating, has talking animals (yes!) and you learn facts about said talking animals. No, my wonder at how I never noticed some things as a child began during an episode when a gas station man had a captured hyena that he taunted with meat. His creepy line was, &#8220;Wanna see him dance?&#8221;</p>
<p><a href="http://mittenskittens.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/tumblr_mcsol5p5cp1rceklro1_500.gif"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1576" title="tumblr_mcsol5P5Cp1rceklro1_500" alt="" src="http://mittenskittens.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/tumblr_mcsol5p5cp1rceklro1_500.gif?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>I was also annoyed when, for the 3rd episode in a row, Eliza mucked shit up again. I wanted to face palm<em> her</em> face. That girl thinks she is always right &#8211; and doesn&#8217;t just leave it at thinking she&#8217;s right, she acts on it. She&#8217;s freeing hyenas willynilly, ditching Donnie, running through wildebeest, playing with cheetahs dying of thirst and wondering why they&#8217;ve turned on her with the plans of making her lunch&#8230; Eliza thinks mostly of herself and assumes every animal she meets will love her and can&#8217;t stand it when somebody likes Debbie. She&#8217;s a loose cannon, who nearly gets herself and the family killed multiple times, all while sighing, squeaking and <em>complaining</em> nonstop.</p>
<p><a href="http://mittenskittens.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/tumblr_m7mqburnb01qhnqajo1_5001.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-1574" title="tumblr_m7mqburNb01qhnqajo1_500" alt="" src="http://mittenskittens.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/tumblr_m7mqburnb01qhnqajo1_5001.jpg?w=300&#038;h=226" height="226" width="300" /></a>When I was a kid, I thought Debbie was an over-reacting, whiny teenage brat. Little did I realise, that Debbie acts this way because she lives with a group of people who isolate her, ignore her, ridicule her, and force her to live in an environment devoid of any safety, comfort, education options or anything she is interested in. Every time Debbie purchases a CD player or &#8216;boom box&#8217;, Donnie, Darwin or Eliza either break it or throw it in water. This goes for everything Debbie buys &#8211; and she buys these things in an attempt to feel a part of the world she so desperately misses. Besides, teenager living in a van with your family non-stop? We&#8217;d all go crazy.</p>
<p><a href="http://mittenskittens.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/char_40321.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-1575" title="char_40321" alt="" src="http://mittenskittens.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/char_40321.jpg?w=590"   /></a>When it comes to Donnie I only have questions. Yes, after his parents were killed he was raised by an Orangutan for a year or two, but why oh why, does that mean he is irreversibly insane? Perhaps it is to do with the fact that Donnie is never disciplined (aside from the occasional scream from Debbie) nor does he receive education (Honestly, the boy isn&#8217;t speaking English yet and you&#8217;ve had him with you for 2 years? I think it&#8217;s time to work on that, sign language?) And also because he has never left the wilderness. No wonder the boy can&#8217;t move on from his dead parents and Orangutan mother &#8211; he still lives in it!</p>
<p>The mother of the group, Marianne, is constantly depressed over whether or not she&#8217;s bonding correctly with her daughters, yet never does much to correct this due to the constraints of her job. She&#8217;s also insanely jealous of any woman who comes close to Nigel, which makes me worry for her ability to trust. This inability to bond or trust possibly comes from her overly critical mother who feels the need to make Marianne feel bad about well, everything. Except for at the very end of the show when they need to make everything happy again. You know.</p>
<p>There are a few things you could say about Nigel Thornberry, as far as shortcomings go, but after everything I&#8217;d just like to wrap his whole bit up with saying he&#8217;s still awesome.</p>
<p><a href="http://mittenskittens.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/tumblr_mdg4814p8w1ro8ysbo1_500.gif"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1571" title="tumblr_mdg4814p8w1ro8ysbo1_500" alt="" src="http://mittenskittens.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/tumblr_mdg4814p8w1ro8ysbo1_500.gif?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p><em>The Wild Thornberrys</em>. I thought things were normal until I was older, I liked Eliza until I realised how impossible she is to like, I worry for Donnie and I feel a sense of pity for Debbie. Who would have thought. My only question is, are these things really there? Or now that I&#8217;m older and more cynical, and worn, do I just see them?</p>
<p>It doesn&#8217;t really matter. What matters is that I&#8217;m writing a critical essay on a kid&#8217;s television program. What happened to my life?</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1567/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1567/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1567&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://mittenskittens.wordpress.com/2012/11/14/the-wild-thornberrys-revisited/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/fb23f6e342ed51997452bf51989cd153?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jessicamittens</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mittenskittens.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/tumblr_md0aikh4zj1rie0uao1_500.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tumblr_md0aikh4ZJ1rie0uao1_500</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mittenskittens.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/tumblr_mcsol5p5cp1rceklro1_500.gif" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tumblr_mcsol5P5Cp1rceklro1_500</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mittenskittens.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/tumblr_m7mqburnb01qhnqajo1_5001.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tumblr_m7mqburNb01qhnqajo1_500</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mittenskittens.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/char_40321.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">char_40321</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mittenskittens.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/tumblr_mdg4814p8w1ro8ysbo1_500.gif" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tumblr_mdg4814p8w1ro8ysbo1_500</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is Cursive Handwriting Dead?</title>
		<link>http://robincoyle.wordpress.com/2012/11/26/is-cursive-handwriting-dead/</link>
		<comments>http://robincoyle.wordpress.com/2012/11/26/is-cursive-handwriting-dead/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2012 19:53:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>robincoyle</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[In Search . . .]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cursive Handwriting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://robincoyle.wordpress.com/?p=3243</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[An article in today’s paper gave me pause. Cursive handwriting has one foot in the grave. A debate wages as 45 states adopt school curriculum guidelines for 2014 that exclude cursive handwriting, but do require keyboard proficiency by the time students exit elementary school. You can read the full article here, but some highlights are: [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3243&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://robincoyle.wordpress.com/2012/11/26/is-cursive-handwriting-dead/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>127</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/14283005e07cab680c3897d0a7d7cfb2?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">robincoyle</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/5/59/Cursive.png/300px-Cursive.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">English: I made it myself (Sotakeit)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://robincoyle.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/thank-you-note.jpg?w=225" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Thank you note</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://img.zemanta.com/zemified_e.png?x-id=ce4e2f5e-c977-4cf5-b00c-fc2df7c89bf9" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Enhanced by Zemanta</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Little Ones That Stole My Heart</title>
		<link>http://newmemories2012.wordpress.com/2012/11/29/the-little-ones-that-stole-my-heart/</link>
		<comments>http://newmemories2012.wordpress.com/2012/11/29/the-little-ones-that-stole-my-heart/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2012 13:25:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>robertoandnea</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mysore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yoga]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://newmemories2012.wordpress.com/?p=672</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The main reason I come to Mysore is to practice yoga with my teacher.  The couple of hours spent in the yoga shala in the wee hours of the morning are the highlight of the day. I’ve been coming here for seven years now. While it’s the yoga that keeps me coming back each year, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=672&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:justify;">The main reason I come to Mysore is to practice yoga with my teacher.  The couple of hours spent in the yoga shala in the wee hours of the morning are the highlight of the day. I’ve been coming here for seven years now. While it’s the yoga that keeps me coming back each year, there are other things that make my Mysore time special.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">In 2008, I arrived in Mysore with a broken heart. I had just said goodbye to someone I loved dearly. I knew my yoga practice and the community of friends here would help. But I also knew I needed to keep myself busy and resist the urge to wallow in self-pity. Over the previous two years I had spent more than 12 months in India. It was time to give back to the country that had given me so much.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">I started teaching English in the afternoons to some young children in a poor Muslim area of the city through an organisation called Pratham. One day my contact there, Mahesh, told me about a small children’s home that was very under resourced. I visited the home  &#8211; the space was tiny and the children were shy and sombre. Their ages ranged from 12 to 2 years and most had been rescued from the streets.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><a href="http://newmemories2012.wordpress.com/2012/11/29/the-little-ones-that-stole-my-heart/susmita/" rel="attachment wp-att-673"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-673" alt="" src="http://newmemories2012.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/susmita.jpg?w=604&#038;h=453" height="453" width="604" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><em>(After a few visits I wanted to learn their names so I took a series of these headshot photos. I didn&#8217;t realise then how fun it would be to look back and see how they have grown!)</em></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">I wasn’t sure what I could do to help. With the philosophy of something is better than nothing I started to visit them a couple of days a week in the afternoons. We sang songs, played games and anything else I could think of to entertain them (one day they even played musical statues to the accompaniment of my amateur flute playing &#8211; actually it was probably quite a few days!)</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><a href="http://newmemories2012.wordpress.com/2012/11/29/the-little-ones-that-stole-my-heart/kids-dancing/" rel="attachment wp-att-674"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-674" alt="" src="http://newmemories2012.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/kids-dancing.jpg?w=720&#038;h=540" height="540" width="720" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Other friends started to get involved and the support for the home snowballed. Funds were raised and donated. Activities became more ambitious from trips to the zoo, playtimes in the park to kirtans on the rooftop.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><a href="http://newmemories2012.wordpress.com/2012/11/29/the-little-ones-that-stole-my-heart/zoo/" rel="attachment wp-att-675"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-675" alt="" src="http://newmemories2012.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/zoo.jpg?w=604&#038;h=404" height="404" width="604" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><em>(I love this shot taken on a trip to the zoo!)</em></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://newmemories2012.wordpress.com/2012/11/29/the-little-ones-that-stole-my-heart/fund-raising-concert/" rel="attachment wp-att-676"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-676" alt="" src="http://newmemories2012.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/fund-raising-concert.jpg?w=720&#038;h=540" height="540" width="720" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><em>(The kids love it when Mark Robberds visits for kirtan. This was a particularly special night in 2010.)</em></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Support for the home really ramped up in early 2011 when a fellow yoga student Chris Ebbe relocated to Mysore fulltime. Thanks to the ongoing commitment of Chris, Warren and Flora, as well as other volunteers and donors. the kids now have regular yoga classes, English tutoring, fresh fruit and vegetables, dental and medical check-ups.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Some of the children I first met in 2008 have left the home but many are still there. It’s been lovely to see them grow and develop their personalities over the last five years. They are a special bunch. They steal the hearts of everyone they meet with their big eyes, wide smiles and non-stop antics. They are definitely more precocious than when I first met them. To be completely honest, sometimes in the afternoon when I am feeling a bit worn out, I don’t always feel like honouring my tutoring commitments. But no matter how tired I feel sitting in the rickshaw on the way there, I always feel energised and very happy on the way back.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">I once said to Chris, after he was telling me about some of the programs he had started for them, “Wow the kids are so lucky to have you here in Mysore.” He responded without a moment’s hesitation – “No I am lucky to have them.”</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">I couldn’t have said it better myself.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><a href="http://newmemories2012.wordpress.com/2012/11/29/the-little-ones-that-stole-my-heart/nea-and-sushmita/" rel="attachment wp-att-677"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-677" alt="" src="http://newmemories2012.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/nea-and-sushmita.jpg?w=300&#038;h=200" height="200" width="300" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><em>(Me with Sushmita just recently  - she has become quite the little madame since I first met her!)</em></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/672/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/672/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=672&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://newmemories2012.wordpress.com/2012/11/29/the-little-ones-that-stole-my-heart/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://newmemories2012.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/kids-dancing.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://newmemories2012.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/kids-dancing.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">kids dancing</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c32d23246669632760a2d29a2d5c31ff?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">robertoandnea</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://newmemories2012.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/susmita.jpg?w=604" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://newmemories2012.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/kids-dancing.jpg?w=720" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://newmemories2012.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/zoo.jpg?w=604" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://newmemories2012.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/fund-raising-concert.jpg?w=720" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://newmemories2012.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/nea-and-sushmita.jpg?w=300" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Economy</title>
		<link>http://conversationswithjapan.wordpress.com/2012/11/29/the-economy/</link>
		<comments>http://conversationswithjapan.wordpress.com/2012/11/29/the-economy/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2012 13:30:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>conversationswithjapan</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bubble]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[china]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[graphs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jobs]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://conversationswithjapan.wordpress.com/?p=144</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Me: Hi Japan. What’s going on with your economy? Japan: The usual. Why? Me: I keep hearing that it’s “stagnating” or “stagflating” or “sluggish” or a “train wreck”. Japan: It is. Me: And there’s a “lost generation” that can’t find really amazing jobs and earn buckets of cash every month. Japan: They can’t. Me: And [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=144&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><b>Me</b>: Hi Japan. What’s going on with your economy?</p>
<p><b>Japan</b>: The usual. Why?</p>
<p><b>Me</b>: I keep hearing that it’s “stagnating” or “stagflating” or “sluggish” or a “train wreck”.</p>
<p><b>Japan</b>: It is.</p>
<p><b>Me</b>: And there’s a “lost generation” that can’t find really amazing jobs and earn buckets of cash every month.</p>
<p><b>Japan</b>: They can’t.</p>
<p><b>Me</b>: And your GDP isn’t seventeen double digits above the baseline macro index for economic growth forecasts in the second half of the Dow Smith fiscal trimester.</p>
<p><b>Japan</b>: Something tells me you’re not an economist.</p>
<p><b>Me</b>: All of this must have had lots of very negative impacts on your society.</p>
<p><b>Japan</b>: Oh yes. Absolutely.</p>
<p><b>Me</b>: Such as?</p>
<p><b>Japan</b>: Well, as you said finding a decent job these days is tough.</p>
<p><b>Me</b>: Right<i>. </i>Finding a job isn’t easy. What else?</p>
<p><b>Japan</b>: People are earning less now. Wages have come down dramatically since the 90s.</p>
<p><b>Me</b>: How much were people earning before?</p>
<p><b>Japan</b>: Oh, shit loads. Business men got their bonuses delivered in wheel barrows.</p>
<p><b>Me</b>: And it’s subsequently come down to normal levels since the bubble burst?</p>
<p><b>Japan</b>: Yeah, i guess.</p>
<p><b>Me</b>: And what other major society-breaking, life-affecting problems have occurred since then?</p>
<p><b>Japan</b>: Well, erm, there&#8217;s the, er&#8230;let me think&#8230;</p>
<p><b>Me</b>: &#8230;</p>
<p><b>Japan</b>: &#8230;</p>
<p><b>Me</b>: Haven’t you still got one of the highest life expectancies in the world with some of the healthiest people even with your half-arsed smoking laws and steep suicide rates?</p>
<p><b>Japan</b>: Er&#8230;yeah. I think so.</p>
<p><b>Me</b>: And you’ve got one of the highest rates of literacy and numeracy and low rates or alcoholism and drug abuse.</p>
<p><b>Japan</b>: Yeah&#8230;but this year’s growth forecast isn’t looking great. Again.</p>
<p><b>Me</b>: Aren’t your crime and incarceration rates are really low? Don’t you have universal health care and an absence of obesity?</p>
<p><b>Japan</b>: Yeah, but last years’ numbers weren’t good at all. Just look at those graphs.</p>
<p><b>Me</b>: You’ve got low rates of teenage pregnancy and mental illness. You’ve got the best public transport infrastructure on earth that can take people to all corners of you quickly and cleanly.</p>
<p><b>Japan</b>: Yeah, look, you’re totally missing the point.</p>
<p><b>Me</b>: Sure, you’re not perfect and your financial system isn’t anywhere within driving distance of being in awesome tip-top shape, apparently, but all of the above has continued whilst your economy has “faltered” and “stuttered”. Daily life is still pretty comfortable isn’t it? Has any of this really changed? How have you suffered?</p>
<p><b>Japan</b>: Well, i’ve been left behind. China’s now the second biggest economy in the world. I’m number three.</p>
<p><b>Me</b>: And?</p>
<p><b>Japan</b>: Well, they’ve overtaken me.</p>
<p><b>Me</b>: So?</p>
<p><b>Japan</b>: So, well, erm, their economy is bigger than mine.</p>
<p><b>Me</b>: And that means it’s a better place to live?</p>
<p><b>Japan</b>: China? God no. Have you seen it? It’s a fantastic mess.</p>
<p><b>Me</b>: Right.</p>
<p><b>Japan</b>: But their graphs do look good. I mean, you can’t beat looking at an economic graph and statistics for finding out how nice a country is to live in, can you?</p>
<p><b>Me</b>: Have you ever thought of looking at some other graphs and statistics?</p>
<p><b>Japan</b>: Hell no. What would that tell me?</p>
<p><b>Me</b>: Well&#8230;who knows?</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/144/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/144/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=144&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://conversationswithjapan.wordpress.com/2012/11/29/the-economy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/9bad801c8345ceef5a881c253432e5a3?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">conversationswithjapan</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Beyond Fan Fiction, a Personal Account</title>
		<link>http://sillyverse.com/2012/11/26/beyond-fan-fiction-a-personal-account/</link>
		<comments>http://sillyverse.com/2012/11/26/beyond-fan-fiction-a-personal-account/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2012 19:45:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Brian Bixby</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Dragon Lady]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fan fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inspiration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Japanese dragon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[memoir]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://sillyverse.wordpress.com/?p=385</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As I mentioned in my post a week ago, my story telling was inspired by the example of my father reading to us kids and telling us his stories. However, inspiration is not enough. One has to take the initiative, and start working out stories of one&#8217;s own. I have had trouble falling asleep since [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=385&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As I mentioned in <a href="http://sillyverse.com/2012/11/19/teller-of-tales/">my post a week ago</a>, my story telling was inspired by the example of my father reading to us kids and telling us his stories. However, inspiration is not enough. One has to take the initiative, and start working out stories of one&#8217;s own.</p>
<p>I have had trouble falling asleep since as far back as I can remember. As a child, I slept in a bedroom that had a closet that contained other people&#8217;s clothes. So I rarely went into it, and its contents were unfamiliar to me. I would lie awake at night, and wonder just what might be lurking in the closet. Or maybe under the bed. It would take me forever to fall asleep.</p>
<p>I needed a way to distract myself. So, when I was in elementary school, I began thinking up stories as I lay there, trying to get to sleep.</p>
<p>I wasn&#8217;t original enough to make up my own stories from scratch. I needed something to get me started. So I did what millions of others have done. I engaged in dreaming up fan fiction, although I didn&#8217;t know that was what it was called. Give me a little credit for creativity, though. I didn&#8217;t just start with one source; I combined two. There was what I guess would be called a young adult novel by <a href="http://www.loisduncan.arquettes.com/index.htm">Lois Duncan</a> entitled <em>Ransom</em> that had just come out about children on a school bus being kidnapped. (I was nine when I read it, hardly a young adult, but I read well above my age level in those days.) And there was a television series, <em>The Green Hornet</em>, which was similar to the <em>Batman</em> series of the same era, but much, much less campy, more straightforward. (Here&#8217;s a <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uuoNLnrPlFM">link to its opening credits</a>, which gives you an idea of what it was about, and why it might inspire a nine-year-old. Don&#8217;t confuse this with the recent movie remake.) So I took the book and the TV series, recast myself as a Green Hornet clone, assigned the Kato role to the girl on whom I had a secret crush, and went out to foil the bad guys in <em>Ransom</em>. And imagining that story helped me to get to sleep.</p>
<p>Well, you can only tell yourself the same story so many times before it gets old and shopworn. I set out to solve other crimes, to right other wrongs. But I never got that far from being the Green Hornet. No, breaking away, becoming original, that took time. It also took yet another television series, the <em>Dark Shadows</em> gothic soap opera, for that step. The main protagonist in <em>Dark Shadows</em> was a vampire who was trying to do good, but compelled by his nature to do evil. It was a challenging concept for a subteen boy. That time around, I didn&#8217;t just borrow the stories and cast myself in the lead. I made up an entire universe. I was going to dream <em>my</em> dreams. In truth, my universe and characters were threadbare copies at first. They weren&#8217;t complete copies, though. I introduced differences. To start with, my lead character was not a vampire, even though he was a deeply conflicted individual who dealt with the supernatural. Over time, those differences built up. Eventually, they became my creations, with very little debt to the originals.</p>
<p>One of the engines for my original development of stories has been the age-old question, &#8220;How did it get that way?&#8221; I&#8217;d work out a story in my head, and once I had it worked out, I&#8217;d start wondering about what happened before. And there&#8217;s <em>always</em> something that happened before. Asking this question made me a historian by inclination long before I became a professionally-trained one. Trying to answer that question (and its counterpart, &#8220;What happened afterwards?&#8221;) meant I had to think about the motivations and social conditions that created any story I developed. For example, those of you reading my story <a href="http://sillyverse.wordpress.com/the-dragon-lady-of-stockbridge/dls-ch-1/"><em>The Dragon Lady of Stockbridge</em></a> as I post it, know it is set in the year 1886, and that Abigail Lane is one of its principal characters. Abigail was created to help explain elements in another story I have written, a story set in the year 2000!</p>
<p>That story set in the year 2000 represented the last crucial step I took in the transition from fan fiction in my head to original stories on the written page: writing. It doesn&#8217;t matter how lively your imagination is, you can&#8217;t write a good story unless you actually write it down. (Homer and Oscar Wilde are exceptions, I admit. If you&#8217;re in their league, don&#8217;t read my advice; send me yours!) Writing it down does three things for you. First, it forces you to actually define your story, set it in metaphorical concrete, make you translate your musings into something that has to have logic and coherence. Second, you have to consider how to tell the story, and what mechanics and strategies of writing you will use. To mention the most obvious example, because it is being written as a serial, <em>The Dragon Lady of Stockbridge</em> has to have some sort of climax at the end of every chapter, and I have had to try what for me are new strategies to create those. Third, you have to actually think about your audience. What you write has to be good enough to read, by someone. If it isn&#8217;t, you have to either revise, begin over, or admit you don&#8217;t really want to write. If it is, you then need to figure out how to reach your audience.</p>
<div id="attachment_386" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 170px"><a href="http://sillyverse.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/oscar_wilde_portrait.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-386" title="Oscar_Wilde_portrait" alt="" src="http://sillyverse.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/oscar_wilde_portrait.jpg?w=590"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">He&#8217;s an exception</p></div>
<p>The biggest day in my life as a writer was not creating that first story, back when I was a child. No, it was when I had the courage and desire to show my first written story to my girlfriend. That was the day I said I wanted to write something good enough for another reader, something good enough to be published. Writing in this blog has been another step. And if my protagonist, Rebecca Maxwell, carries a walking stick, just like the lead in <em>Dark Shadows</em>, I have the pleasure of knowing that it is only a resemblance, and that she and her story are entirely my creation, here for you to read.</p>
<div id="attachment_333" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 235px"><a href="http://sillyverse.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dragon-cane-ink2.png"><img class="size-medium wp-image-333" title="Dragon-cane-ink" alt="" src="http://sillyverse.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dragon-cane-ink2.png?w=225&#038;h=300" height="300" width="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Rebecca Farnsworth Maxwell&#8217;s walking stick &#8211; E.J. Barnes</p></div>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=385&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://sillyverse.com/2012/11/26/beyond-fan-fiction-a-personal-account/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>16</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/e0fa70f65f5676f04fa4198eeff03175?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sillyhughes</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://sillyverse.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/oscar_wilde_portrait.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Oscar_Wilde_portrait</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://sillyverse.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dragon-cane-ink2.png?w=225" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Dragon-cane-ink</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Having It All, or Losing My Mind?</title>
		<link>http://balanceandgrace.wordpress.com/2012/11/29/having-it-all-or-losing-my-mind/</link>
		<comments>http://balanceandgrace.wordpress.com/2012/11/29/having-it-all-or-losing-my-mind/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2012 01:50:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>balanceandgrace</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[change]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[balance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[motherhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[work-at-home moms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[work-life balance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[working from home]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://balanceandgrace.wordpress.com/?p=57</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The other day I did something I thought I would never do—I took a phone interview for a job I really wanted with a 4-month-old strapped to my chest. Before you resign to thinking I’m crazy, let me explain. I recently quit my marketing job in hopes of truly having it all—staying home to raise [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=57&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The other day I did something I thought I would never do—I took a phone interview for a job I really wanted with a 4-month-old strapped to my chest.</p>
<p>Before you resign to thinking I’m crazy, let me explain. I recently quit my marketing job in hopes of truly having it all—staying home to raise my new baby while securing satisfying (not scammy) at-home employment, getting back my bikini body, and having homemade dinner on the table every night.</p>
<p>In hindsight, go ahead and think it. I AM crazy. In the first couple of weeks since I&#8217;ve been home, I&#8217;ve been trying to take calls and speak with potential employers or clients at precisely the same moment my little bundle of joy starts to scream his head off. His crying may or may not be detected the person on the other end of the line, but for me it is slowly tearing away at my heart strings (and sanity) with each passing second and each labored wail.</p>
<p>“My baby needs me,” I think to myself desperately while not quite halfway engaging in the conversation. I lose track of what I’m saying, what they’re saying, and needless to say, I haven’t landed work from these fruitless and painful conversations. Luckily, he has remained asleep for enough of my work time that I&#8217;ve been able to get through a few successful calls and land a few jobs. But each call I wait with baited breath for the screaming to begin, and I can therefore never fully devote my thoughts to the matter at hand.</p>
<p>After all, as much as I want to be gainfully employed at the same time I stay home to raise my child, I always know in my heart that I’m a mom first. And it&#8217;s why his yells for me are so heart-wrenching—I feel just as I did when I was working a traditional 40 hours in an office—like I have to choose to put work before my son.</p>
<p>So that brings me to the baby carrier phone call debacle. My interview was at one, and like all my “phone call” days, I carefully planned his feeding and nap schedule to perfectly coincide with my phone call. But as anyone who has ever had a 4-month-old knows, they like to eat perfectly planned schedules for breakfast and throw them up all over your sweater.</p>
<div id="attachment_58" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://www.mobywrap.com/p-13-originals.aspx"><img class="size-medium wp-image-58 " alt="" src="http://balanceandgrace.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/moby-image.jpg?w=300&#038;h=300" height="300" width="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Not me&#8211;this is a lovely model using the fabulous (and sanity-saving) Moby wrap</p></div>
<p>As the time drew nearer, I heard him begin to stir in his crib. I couldn’t bear the thought of enduring the entire (important) conversation with him progressively screaming louder and louder. I knew I would be useless. I needed a plan B.</p>
<p>As I frantically paced the house thinking of ways to make him happy for one full hour while I took the call, it came to me. The only time he is (usually) completely satisfied and calm is when he is tucked in his little Moby baby wrap: attached to my chest. I thought it was risky, but it just might work.<br />
Initially, all was well. I could concentrate on the call because I knew my most precious job was taken care of. Baby was happy. Until he wasn&#8217;t.</p>
<p>About 25 minutes into the call, I notice the telltale signs of an impending tantrum. I panicked. What do I do if he starts to scream? What is my explanation? Here I am trying to convince this organization that I can easily balance remote work and maintain a professional demeanor, and I have an infant about to lose his mind directly into the phone.</p>
<p>Fortunately, the job to which I was applying involved mostly non-phone work and writing, so I thought it may be OK. And when the crying started, I dealt with it as graciously as humanly possible. He settled soon after I wrangled the binkie into his mouth and my interviewer seemed to accept my hasty apology.</p>
<p>I don’t know if I got the job, but at this point it’s not looking good. And that’s OK. I am continuing to learn how insanely tough and rewarding it is to be a mom, and how my strong motherly instinct continues to surprise me. As naturally ambitious as I am, I am far more passionate about being a mom than advancing my career.</p>
<p>Having it all may be tough, or it may be downright impossible. All I know is I am on a journey to find out.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/57/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/57/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=57&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://balanceandgrace.wordpress.com/2012/11/29/having-it-all-or-losing-my-mind/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/775c3a5511dd86f51aa9aaacdd4c6e5c?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">balanceandgrace</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://balanceandgrace.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/moby-image.jpg?w=300" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Animated GIF: The Antithesis of Mindfulness</title>
		<link>http://everydaygurus.com/2012/11/29/the-animated-gif-the-internets-version-of-premature-ejaculation/</link>
		<comments>http://everydaygurus.com/2012/11/29/the-animated-gif-the-internets-version-of-premature-ejaculation/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2012 15:08:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Kozo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Celluloid Gurus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Experiential Gurus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPchallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GIF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Graphics Interchange Format]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[happiness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Inspiration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mindfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[patience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spirituality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weekly Writing Challenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Youtube]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://everydaygurus.com/?p=485</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[People who like GIFs (a series of images that create the impression of movement) are the same folks who slow down on the freeway to try to catch a glimpse of something gruesome after a car wreck. Ok, that&#8217;s a bit of an over-generalization taken out of context meant to be incendiary, which is a [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=485&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://everydaygurus.com/2012/11/29/the-animated-gif-the-internets-version-of-premature-ejaculation/sparta_8b901e_186352-3/" rel="attachment wp-att-493"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-493" title="Sparta_8b901e_186352" alt="" src="http://mkozo.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/sparta_8b901e_1863522.gif?w=590"   /></a><br />
People who like GIFs (a series of images that create the impression of movement) are the same folks who slow down on the freeway to try to catch a glimpse of something gruesome after a car wreck. Ok, that&#8217;s a bit of an over-generalization taken out of context meant to be incendiary, which is a pretty good definition of an animated GIF.<span id="more-485"></span></p>
<p>There is a reason I&#8217;m on WordPress rather than Tumblr: I believe in writing. I believe in meticulously delving into an issue and exploring all possibilities and points of view. I believe in exposition rather than reductionism.</p>
<p>By definition, a GIF is reductive. It takes something that happens over time and reduces it to an easily consumed meme for short attention spans. Although <a title="cinemagraphs" href="http://www.tripwiremagazine.com/2011/07/cinemagraphs.html" target="_blank">some of these animations</a> can be witty, artistic, political, and/or hilarious, something gets lost in the splicing of these images that reveals a disturbing trend on the internet and in society in general.</p>
<p><a href="http://everydaygurus.com/2012/11/29/the-animated-gif-the-internets-version-of-premature-ejaculation/tumblr_mbafgsvej91rud5iso1_500/" rel="attachment wp-att-495"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-495" alt="" src="http://mkozo.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/tumblr_mbafgsvej91rud5iso1_500.gif?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>I get really annoyed driving in a car with my teenage cousins. They listen to a song on the radio that they &#8220;love,&#8221; and halfway through the song, they change the station until they find another song that they &#8220;love.&#8221; Since they never make it to the end of a song, there is no way in cyberspace that they are going to sit down and listen to an entire double record rock opera like <a class="zem_slink" title="The Who" href="http://www.thewho.com/" target="_blank" rel="homepage">The Who&#8217;s</a> <em><a class="zem_slink" title="Quadrophenia" href="http://www.rottentomatoes.com/m/quadrophenia" target="_blank" rel="rottentomatoes">Quadrophenia</a> </em>or <a class="zem_slink" title="Pink Floyd" href="http://pinkfloyd.com" target="_blank" rel="homepage">Pink Floyd</a>&#8216;s <em>The Wall. </em></p>
<p>It&#8217;s not their fault, of course. Youtube made the 3 minute video the standard. Post anything over three minutes and you run the risk of not being clicked on at all. I just did a search for <em>Quadrophenia </em>on Youtube and found the entire film in two parts. Part one got 99,041 views and part two got only 31,611 views. That means that two thirds of the viewers didn&#8217;t even stick around to hear &#8220;Love Reign O&#8217;er Me.&#8221; That&#8217;s like watching <em>Star Wars</em> and leaving the theater before the Death Star gets blown up.</p>
<p>Animated GIFs are like Youtube on crack cocaine. Most of the GIFs I found were less than 5 seconds long. If we looked at these numbers in a different context maybe we could get some well needed perspective. Less than three minutes would be considered a premature ejaculation by most experts and 99% of sexual partners. Imagine a sexual experience that lasted as long as the average animated GIF. I hate to say it, but that is where we are headed. Even GIF artist Pamela Reed of <a title="Reed+Rader" href="http://www.reedandrader.com/" target="_blank">Reed+Rader</a> admits, &#8220;We get bored really, really quick, and it&#8217;s always about doing the next thing&#8230;&#8221; Luckily, the GIF is on an infinite loop, so there is no refractory period, but I don&#8217;t know any man in the history of humankind who is built this way&#8211;even the fictional character <a class="zem_slink" title="Boogie Nights" href="http://www.rottentomatoes.com/m/boogie_nights" target="_blank" rel="rottentomatoes">Dirk Diggler</a> in <em>Boogie Nights </em>comes up short&#8211;no pun intended.</p>
<p><a href="http://everydaygurus.com/2012/11/29/the-animated-gif-the-internets-version-of-premature-ejaculation/tumblr_mdw5awrwq21rwcc6bo1_250/" rel="attachment wp-att-496"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-496" alt="I came" src="http://mkozo.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/tumblr_mdw5awrwq21rwcc6bo1_250.gif?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>All kidding aside, I&#8217;m seriously concerned with the effects of GIFs on our society. Even now, I am hesitant to click on the &#8220;Read more&#8221; link when I see &#8220;<a title="Rolbos blog" href="http://rolbos.wordpress.com/2012/11/26/the-unfortunate-pilgrim/" target="_blank">1,861 more words</a>&#8221; while scrolling down the Reader of blogs that I follow. Yet I know that, like my meditation practice, I will be glad I put the time and effort into doing something that does not come with instant gratification. I can&#8217;t imagine how impatient I will get after years of consuming 4 second GIFs.</p>
<p>Moreover, GIFs are antithetical to two of the practices that I feel are essential to happiness: mindfulness and patience. If you read my blog, you know that I try to appreciate and be grateful for every moment, no matter how <a title="Sleeping Guru" href="http://everydaygurus.com/2012/10/26/the-sleeping-guru-5-life-lessons-from-a-golden-child/" target="_blank">mundane</a>,<a title="Cross Walk Guru" href="http://everydaygurus.com/2012/10/19/cross-walk-guru-james-12-4/" target="_blank"> pedestrian</a>, or <a title="Spare the Child" href="http://everydaygurus.com/2012/11/07/spare-the-child/" target="_blank">painful</a>. GIFs literally rob us of moments of tenderness, subtlety, and appreciation, leaving us with just pornography. (I might have overused the sexual analogy there, but I blame it on the &#8220;I CAME&#8221; GIF that is looping over and over as I try to write this critique.)</p>
<p>Some of you also know that my favorite quote from the Bible is James 1:2-4.</p>
<blockquote><p>2 My brethren, count it all joy when ye fall into trials;<br />
3 Knowing this, that the trying of your faith worketh patience.<br />
4 But let patience have her perfect work, that ye may be perfect and entire, wanting nothing.</p></blockquote>
<p>I believe that we need to &#8220;worketh&#8221; patience in order to be &#8220;perfect and entire, wanting nothing.&#8221; GIFs &#8220;worketh&#8221; impatience and desire. We want more and more with less and less patience. Let me ask fellow bloggers who took up this <a title="Weekly Writing Challenge" href="http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2012/11/26/gap-animated-gifs/" target="_blank">Weekly Writing Challenge,</a> how many GIFs did you click on while writing your post? Didn&#8217;t it get addictive scrolling down a Tumblr page consuming all the available GIFs within seconds? Did you get sensory overload after a few pages? For some reason, while I was scrolling through page after page of GIFs, I started singing <a class="zem_slink" title="Green Day" href="http://www.greenday.com/" target="_blank" rel="homepage">Green Day&#8217;s</a> song &#8220;<a title="Green Day Longview" href="http://www.azlyrics.com/lyrics/greenday/longview.html" target="_blank">Longview</a>&#8220;:</p>
<blockquote><p>Sit around and watch the tube, but nothing&#8217;s on<br />
I change the channels for an hour or two<br />
Twiddle my thumbs just for a bit<br />
I&#8217;m sick of all the same old s*#t</p></blockquote>
<p>I don&#8217;t like how I&#8217;m feeling after a few hours of researching and writing this post, so I might go outside and find someone to hug. I do know, however, that I will never, ever, ever use GIFs in any of my posts ever.</p>
<p><a href="http://everydaygurus.com/2012/11/29/the-animated-gif-the-internets-version-of-premature-ejaculation/tumblr_m8jscyfwrh1rnujgp/" rel="attachment wp-att-506"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-506" alt="" src="http://mkozo.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/tumblr_m8jscyfwrh1rnujgp.gif?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>Thank you for reading, sharing, and/or smiling.</p>
<p><strong>Do you think I&#8217;m completely off base with this critique? One can argue that fast food has lead to the crisis of obesity in the US. What do you think the effects of &#8220;fast media&#8221; will be on our populace? Please share.</strong></p>
<h6 class="zemanta-related-title" style="font-size:1em;">Related articles</h6>
<ul class="zemanta-article-ul">
<li class="zemanta-article-ul-li"><a href="http://www.brit.co/gif-how-to/" target="_blank">Tech Basics: 5 Ways to Make An Animated GIF</a> (brit.co)</li>
<li class="zemanta-article-ul-li"><a title="Mirth and Motivation blog" href="http://eof737.wordpress.com/2012/11/26/inspiration-animated-gif-is-alive-and-kicking/">Mirth and Motivation</a></li>
<li class="zemanta-article-ul-li"><a title="dominicspeight" href="http://itsonlydominicspeight.wordpress.com/2012/11/26/are-animated-gifs-the-stuff-of-junior-highschool-hijinks-or-are-they-the-political-cartoons-of-the-new-millenium/" target="_blank">Itsonlydominicspeight</a></li>
<li class="zemanta-article-ul-li"><a title="Happy Homesteader" href="http://jimtxmiller.wordpress.com/2012/11/26/get-it-fast-gifs-for-a-nation-with-the-attention-span-of-a-monkey/" target="_blank">Happy Homesteader</a></li>
</ul>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/485/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/485/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=485&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://everydaygurus.com/2012/11/29/the-animated-gif-the-internets-version-of-premature-ejaculation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>36</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/e50f7cdc9815ab4e04153b29e482a651?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mkozo</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mkozo.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/sparta_8b901e_1863522.gif" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Sparta_8b901e_186352</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mkozo.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/tumblr_mbafgsvej91rud5iso1_500.gif" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://mkozo.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/tumblr_mdw5awrwq21rwcc6bo1_250.gif" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">I came</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mkozo.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/tumblr_m8jscyfwrh1rnujgp.gif" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Animated GIFs: Junk or Art?</title>
		<link>http://honestpuck.wordpress.com/2012/11/28/animated-gifs-junk-or-art/</link>
		<comments>http://honestpuck.wordpress.com/2012/11/28/animated-gifs-junk-or-art/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2012 21:31:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>honestpuck</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Computers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPchallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GIF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opinion]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://honestpuck.wordpress.com/?p=777</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Are animated GIFs the stuff of junior highschool hijinks or, are they the political cartoons of the new millenium? What do you think? This was the question from WordPress.com’s Mind The Gap. OK, let’s start with a little about graphic file formats. The file formats used on the web are changing. At one time the [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=777&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_778" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 625px"><a href="http://annstreetstudio.com/category/cinemagraphs/"><img class="size-full wp-image-778" title="Cinemagraph" alt="Cinemagraph" src="http://honestpuck.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/cinemagraph.gif?w=590"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text"><a href="http://annstreetstudio.com/category/cinemagraphs/">(c) Beck and Burg</a> Cinemagraph animated GIF from Jamie Beck and Kevin Burg</p></div>
<p>Are animated GIFs the stuff of junior highschool hijinks or, are they the political cartoons of the new millenium? What do you think? This was the question from WordPress.com’s <a href="http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2012/11/26/gap-animated-gifs/">Mind The Gap.</a></p>
<p>OK, let’s start with a little about graphic file formats. The file formats used on the web are changing. At one time the GIF was king. The format was developed by CompuServe, the first major commercial online service in the US. It is limited to just 256 different colours in each image. It’s a ”lossless” format in that no information is thrown out during the compression. Over time the low colour resolution meant it was overtaken by JPEG which offered more colour fidelity but does lose information when compressing the image. Now even JPEG is starting to wane and most people are changing to PNG, back to a lossless format.</p>
<p>There is one place where GIF still reigns, neither JPEG or PNG offer any ability to have those short animations of the animated GIF. This year the format celebrated it’s 25th birthday.</p>
<p>So does the animated GIF offer anything other than short animations of cats, dogs and babies doing amusing things? Can we find art or commentary in the format?</p>
<p>The truth falls somewhere in the middle. While the vast majority of them are just ”highschool hijinks” it is possible to find examples that are lifted above this. There are some that become art.</p>
<p>I’m a great believer in art, a lover of art. I also believe that art can be found in many places, not just hanging on the walls of large stone buildings titled ”Gallery”. I appreciate the art in many places such as paper folding, painted on building walls, on the stage of a theatre and in a well written novel just to name a few of my favourites.</p>
<p>I don’t know about political cartoons but photographer Jamie Beck and motion graphic artist Kevin Burg have used the GIF format to create what can only be described as art. Art is something that touches you, informs you, makes you think. Beck and Burg produce photographs with a small amount of movement that do just that.</p>
<p>They call them cinemagraphs, more than a picture but less than a video. They are like a moment in time brought to life in this file format. You can see them <a href="http://oh-so-coco.tumblr.com/tagged/cinemagraph">here</a> and <a href="http://annstreetstudio.com/category/cinemagraphs/">here</a>. These are photographic gems that could be done no other way than by animated GIF.</p>
<p>This trend of animated GIF as art is seemingly a new one but more and more artists are exploring it. While the work of Beck and Burg was the first I saw they are not alone. A <a href="http://www.designboom.com/tag/animated-gif-art/">search at DesignBoom</a> for articles tagged animated-gif-art brings up over a dozen other articles about artists exploring the use of the medium in interesting ways. Among them another favourite of mine, the <a href="http://www.designboom.com/art/painted-dancing-ballerina-gifs-by-ryan-enn-hughes/">DANSE$ project</a> from Ryan Enn Hughes that he describes as ”combining aspects of photography, motion pictures and painting in a digital environment.” Hughes work moves away from the realism of Beck and Burg into a style reminiscent of impressionist paintings.</p>
<p>Earlier this year <a href="http://thephotographersgallery.org.uk/">The Photographer’s Gallery</a> in London had an exhibition of animated GIFs.</p>
<p>“In a world where most Digital SLR cameras can shoot high definition video, digital technology raises questions concerning what a photograph is and how we make sense of it,” said Katrina Sluis, the curator of a digital series that begins with the animated GIF exhibit, in a statement. “Our opening show embraces the animated GIF as a uniquely screen-based image.”</p>
<p>Is the animated GIF the political cartoon of the new millenium? Perhaps not but this format is certainly more than high school hijinks. The web is as broad as it is deep and just like everything else; Instagram, Flickr, YouTube, Tumblr and even WordPress blogs; it is possible to find the juvenile, the silly and the amusing but it is also possible, in all of those places to find more — intelligence, taste, skill and yes, art.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/777/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/777/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=777&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://honestpuck.wordpress.com/2012/11/28/animated-gifs-junk-or-art/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://honestpuck.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/cinemagraph.gif?w=123" />
		<media:content url="http://honestpuck.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/cinemagraph.gif?w=123" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Cinemagraph</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/4a69236f4352d31b6943784132564ddc?s=96&#38;d=&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">honestpuck</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://honestpuck.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/cinemagraph.gif" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Cinemagraph</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Politics of Definitions</title>
		<link>http://bespectacledape.wordpress.com/2012/11/28/the-politics-of-definitions/</link>
		<comments>http://bespectacledape.wordpress.com/2012/11/28/the-politics-of-definitions/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2012 02:05:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bespectacledape</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arguments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sexuality]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://bespectacledape.wordpress.com/?p=143</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[So, the AP has asked its writers not to use the term &#8220;homophobe&#8221; to describe newsworthy folk opposing gay rights. This is part of the overall rejection of the term &#8220;homophobia,&#8221; a term that describes, depending on who you ask, the mindset or the condition of these folks. According to the Deputy Standards Editor there, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=143&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So, the AP has <a href="http://www.slate.com/articles/double_x/doublex/2012/11/the_ap_bans_homophobia_is_the_word_really_inaccurate.html">asked its writers</a> not to use the term &#8220;homophobe&#8221; to describe newsworthy folk opposing gay rights. This is part of the overall rejection of the term &#8220;homophobia,&#8221; a term that describes, depending on who you ask, the mindset or the condition of these folks.</p>
<p>According to the <a href="http://www.politico.com/blogs/media/2012/11/ap-nixes-homophobia-ethnic-cleansing-150315.html">Deputy Standards Editor</a> there, this choice has to do with accuracy: phobias are mental conditions &#8211; clear illnesses &#8211; and &#8220;homophobia&#8221; suggests a kind of pathological irrationality that could more neutrally and accurately be described by the term &#8220;anti-gay&#8221;.</p>
<p>Whether or not opposition to the existence of and/or extension of rights to gay people is pathological is something that&#8217;s up for debate &#8211; it certainly seems irrational in the sense that it&#8217;s primarily emotional, but there are lots of bad decisions we make that rely on emotion rather than logic, and we don&#8217;t call them pathological. And whether or not opposition to gay rights springs primarily from an irrational <em>fear</em>, specifically, is something that we can probably never know.</p>
<p>But the debate spurred by this linguistic retirement actually suggests a wider question: under what circumstances should we refer to groups by their own preferred term, and when is this inappropriate? It would make language meaningless to allow every person to define his or her actions, identities, and political beliefs in the most positively euphemistic terms: we don&#8217;t go around referring to serial killers as &#8220;retroactive pregnancy termination specialists&#8221; or thieves as &#8220;reappropriators&#8221;. </p>
<p>But at the same time, there&#8217;s a good reason why publications refer to descendants of the native peoples of the Americas as &#8220;American Indians,&#8221; and why we no longer refer to the Roma as &#8220;gypsies&#8221; &#8211; the terminology imposed on groups by outsiders can be extremely harmful and prejudicial, and the obvious answer is to let most groups identify themselves by their own preferred terms.</p>
<p>The first disjunction seems to be between that of actions and identities: people who drive can be fairly called motorists (in their context as automotive operators) and people who walk can be called pedestrians. Of course, we don&#8217;t mainly identify ourselves as motorists or pedestrians, and we are free to change our identification merely by stepping out of our vehicles. </p>
<p>On the other hand, I may want to define myself based on some immutable or difficult to adjust characteristic. Letting others define that characteristic in negative terms can be exceptionally cruel: prejudicial terminology that refers to my parentage, skin color, or other characteristic takes the power out of my hands and lets others unfairly judge me before they know me. It also makes one characteristic the <em>primary identifier</em>, something that can also be extremely unfair: I am, for example, diabetic, but it would be strange and unhelpful for people to know me primarily by that fact. Letting members of identity communities define their own terms, then, seems like a far more successful policy than letting outsiders define those groups.</p>
<p>But what about holders of a political philosophy or a belief? This seems to fall somewhere between action and identity: there are lots of people who see themselves as &#8220;Democrats,&#8221; and very few who see themselves as &#8220;tax-and-spend liberals&#8221;. Is it bigoted to refer to holders of a political belief by a term they do not choose for themselves? What about those active in the debate &#8211; those who act to make political speech?</p>
<p>I&#8217;m not sure there&#8217;s any hard-and-fast rule. Generally, it seems better to let opposing sides in controversial issues frame themselves in the best possible light: a kind of uneasy peace has been made between the &#8220;pro-life&#8221; and &#8220;pro-choice&#8221; camps in the abortion camp, with neither side having to bear the burden of being &#8220;anti-anything&#8221;. More confrontational terms like &#8220;anti-life&#8221; and &#8220;anti-choice&#8221; have only caught on in partisan circles.</p>
<p>In this case, though, there is a difference (however distasteful the distinction may be) between those who want to deny certain rights to a group and those who oppose the existence of that group. Perhaps, then, &#8220;homophobe&#8221; is too inaccurate a term to encompass the entire spectrum of anti-gay philosophy. Replacing it with a merely more euphemistic term may not help, though. And hopefully, it won&#8217;t be long before we don&#8217;t have to refer to this group in publication at all. </p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/143/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/143/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=143&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://bespectacledape.wordpress.com/2012/11/28/the-politics-of-definitions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/8391a30b9a6ff7b4f4b1ce068b11c304?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bespectacledape</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Richard Cohen: Jealous of Daniel Craig’s Bond — Strength and Intelligence</title>
		<link>http://douglasernstblog.com/2012/11/27/richard-cohen-jealous-of-daniel-craigs-bond-strength-and-intelligence/</link>
		<comments>http://douglasernstblog.com/2012/11/27/richard-cohen-jealous-of-daniel-craigs-bond-strength-and-intelligence/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2012 04:06:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Douglas Ernst</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hollywood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daniel Craig]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[James Bond]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Richard Cohen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Skyfall]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Washington Post]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://douglasernstblog.com/?p=4788</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In 2010 I brought up the sad truth that there are a lot of men who wish Alan Alda and George Clooney could have a baby that looked like Matt Damon, but with beta-male genes empowered by gamma radiation. They want to see The Hulk, but instead of getting really angry they want him to [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4788&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_4790" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 550px"><a href="http://dougernst.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/james-bond-skyfall1.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-4790" title="James Bond Skyfall" alt="" src="http://dougernst.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/james-bond-skyfall1.jpg?w=590"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The Washington Post&#8217;s Richard Cohen isn&#8217;t a fan of Daniel Craig&#8217;s muscular Bond. He&#8217;d prefer a more bookish version of 007. Since Skyfall quotes Tennyson, it&#8217;s only fitting to remind the author: &#8220;How dull it is to pause, to make an end, to rust unburnish’d, not to shine in use!&#8221; (Image: <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;v=6kw1UVovByw">YouTube</a>.)</p></div>
<p>In 2010 I brought up the sad truth that there are a lot of men who wish <a href="http://douglasernstblog.com/2010/08/01/stallone-and-you-stop-generation-beta-male-liberal-leg-crossers/">Alan Alda and George Clooney could have a baby </a>that looked like Matt Damon, but with beta-male genes empowered by gamma radiation. They want to see The Hulk, but instead of getting really angry they want him to cross his legs and purse his lips with incredible strength. <em>The Washington Post&#8217;s</em> Richard Cohen&#8217;s latest piece, <a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/richard-cohen-james-bond-and-the-new-sex-appeal/2012/11/26/098813e6-37f4-11e2-8a97-363b0f9a0ab3_story.html?wprss=rss_opinions">&#8216;James Bond and the new sex appeal,&#8217; </a>demonstrates quite nicely that he is one of those men:</p>
<blockquote><p>This Bond ripples with muscles. Craig is 44, but neither gravity nor age has done its evil work on him. Nothing about him looks natural, relaxed — a man in the prime of his life and enjoying it. Instead, I see a man chasing youth on a treadmill, performing sets and reps, a clean and press, a weighted knee raise, an incline pushup and, finally, something called an incline pec fly (don’t ask). I take these terms from the Daniel Craig Workout, which you can do, too, if your agent and publicist so insist. Otherwise, I recommend a book. &#8230;</p>
<p>“Skyfall” is a lot of fun — don’t get me wrong — but it still says something about our culture that, in the autumn of my years, I do not like. To appreciate what I mean, contrast this new Bond to Roger O. Thornhill, the charmingly hapless advertising man played by Cary Grant in “North by Northwest.” Like Bond, Thornhill pulls off some amazing physical feats — his mad frantic escape from the crop duster, the traverse of Mount Rushmore — and like Bond he wears an expensive suit. Unlike Bond, though, when he takes it off we do not see some marbleized man, an ersatz creation of some trainer, but a fit man, effortlessly athletic and just as effortlessly sophisticated. Of course, he knows his martinis, but he also knows how to send out a suit for swift hotel cleaning. He is a man of the world. &#8230;</p>
<p><strong>Every rippling muscle is a book not read, a movie not seen or a conversation not held.</strong> That’s why Sean Connery was my kind of Bond. He was 53 when he made his last Bond film, “Never Say Never Again.” Women loved him because he was sophisticated and he could handle a maitre d’ as well as a commie assassin. <strong>Western civilization was saved not on account of his pecs but on account of his cleverness and experience.</strong></p>
<p>I know the movie market skews young and kids want action, and I take it as a good thing that Daniel Craig’s Bond is older, world weary, and, in sports lingo, has slowed a step. <strong>But he still triumphs physically, not cleverly.</strong></p></blockquote>
<p>Speak for yourself, Richard. <em>Some of us make time to do our reps <span style="text-decoration:underline;">and</span> read books</em>. We discipline our bodies and our minds. Daniel Craig&#8217;s 007 is superior because he brings strength and intelligence to the table — a deadly combination that strikes fear into wannabe George Clooneys because a &#8220;marbleized man&#8221; reminds them of very real soldiers (<a href="http://douglasernstblog.com/2012/09/21/no-easy-day-the-firsthand-account-of-a-great-book/">Navy SEALs, perhaps?</a>) who can kill you with wits, fists, or marksmanship.</p>
<p>Richard Cohen may read a lot of books, but apparently many of them haven&#8217;t been historical in nature or he&#8217;d realize that Western Civilization owes plenty to men with &#8220;pecs.&#8221; And he claims to watch a lot of movies, but he seems to have fallen asleep during <em>Skyfall</em> because Bond is, in fact,<em> very clever</em>.</p>
<p>Who has to be more clever — the Bond who depends on exploding pens, or the Bond who must ultimately save the day with a hunting rifle and a knife? Who is more clever — the Bond who depends on ejector seats in his car, or the Bond who depends on his ability to recall — in a split second — the name of a decades-old metro stop in order to decrypt a digital map of subterranean London?</p>
<p>The insecurity masquerading as confidence displayed by men like Cohen is summed up perfectly in a conversation that 007 has with Q:</p>
<blockquote><p>Q: Well, I&#8217;ll hazard I can do more damage on my laptop sitting in my pajamas before my first cup of Earl Grey than you can do in a year in the field.<br />
James Bond: Oh, so why do you need me?<br />
Q: Every now and then a trigger has to be pulled.<br />
James Bond: Or not pulled. It&#8217;s hard to know which in your pajamas, Q.</p></blockquote>
<p>Mr. Cohen pines for the Bonds of yore because it allows him to pretend he, in a pair of designer Gucci frames, could play the part. Cohen would love to believe that it&#8217;s possible to regularly dine out at <a href="http://komirestaurant.com/"><em>Komi</em></a> and <a href="http://www.minibarbyjoseandres.com/"><em>Minibar</em></a>, drink Macallan Scotch, and still manage to save the day. &#8220;Clever&#8221; men with &#8220;first class temperaments&#8221; cling to the belief that it is their brainpower that can save Western Civilization (a &#8220;reset&#8221; with Russia here, an endorsement of the Muslim Brotherhood there), because deep down they know that the men who live in the shadows, pulling triggers, must work to keep their peak physical performance if they want to stay alive in the field.</p>
<p>I highly suggest seeing <em>Skyfall</em> if you haven&#8217;t already. It&#8217;s a great movie. I just wish M quoted more of Tennyson&#8217;s <em>Ulysses</em>; Mr. Cohen might have understood Craig&#8217;s 007 better if she had:</p>
<blockquote><p>How dull it is to pause, to make an end,<br />
<strong>To rust unburnish’d, not to shine in use!</strong><br />
As tho’ to breathe were life! Life piled on life &#8230;</p>
<p>We are not now that strength which in old days<br />
Moved earth and heaven, that which we are, we are;<br />
One equal temper of heroic hearts,<br />
Made weak by time and fate, but strong in will<br />
To strive, to seek, to find, and not to yield.</p></blockquote>
<div id="attachment_4797" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 550px"><a href="http://dougernst.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/douglas-ernst.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-4797" title="Douglas Ernst" alt="" src="http://dougernst.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/douglas-ernst.jpg?w=590"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Here&#8217;s a photo of yours truly to demonstrate that I practice what I preach.</p></div>
<span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='560' height='315' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/6kw1UVovByw?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4788/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4788/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4788&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://douglasernstblog.com/2012/11/27/richard-cohen-jealous-of-daniel-craigs-bond-strength-and-intelligence/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>28</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/0197eceb42e9bae0e9b8e8c4ebfebf7b?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">dougernst</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dougernst.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/james-bond-skyfall1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">James Bond Skyfall</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dougernst.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/douglas-ernst.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Douglas Ernst</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
