<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 21:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Meet Jamey</title>
		<link>http://alanatphotography.wordpress.com/2013/03/12/jamey/</link>
		<comments>http://alanatphotography.wordpress.com/2013/03/12/jamey/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2013 03:12:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>alanatphotography</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[affirmations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emotion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[honest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[insecurities]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pictures of you]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[positive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[raw]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[storytelling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tacoma photographer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://alanatphotography.wordpress.com/?p=645</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The blogs about women were long. Real long. For the sake of none of these women’s honest, heartfelt words and loving messages from their friends and family going unseen, I’m going to be posting each in a single blog every couple of days or so until I am able to finally get the teen session [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=645&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The blogs about women were long. Real long.</p>
<p>For the sake of none of these women’s honest, heartfelt words and loving messages from their friends and family going unseen, I’m going to be posting each in a single blog every couple of days or so until I am able to finally get the teen session executed and up to share. So that you can take just five minutes and read one woman’s “story” and maybe find comfort in the way you can relate/understand/empathize/etc.</p>
<p>They will be in no particular order…drawing numbers 1-18.<br />
Tonight’s number: #6.</p>
<p>I give you Jamey.</p>
<p><a href="http://alanatphotography.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/jameyblog.jpg"><img src="http://alanatphotography.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/jameyblog.jpg?w=560&#038;h=383" alt="jameyblog" width="560" height="383" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-491" /></a><br />
<strong>jamey&#8217;s words ~<br />
</strong><br />
<b>“</b><b>I thought for a long while about this project and what it was asking of me. I felt that sharing my easy to admit insecurities (not pretty enough, not thin enough, not educated enough, boobs, butt, hair, etc.) didn&#8217;t quite live up to what I interpreted as the heart of the project. I decided I was going to be stupid and brave and try and admit my greatest insecurity. So I thought about it&#8230;and then I thought about it some more&#8230;and then I realized what it is. Then I argued with myself about whether or not it was honest enough. Whether or not I was phrasing it correctly. I decided there was little I could do to change the way it sounds so, here goes: I don&#8217;t believe anyone can love me. I believe I am unlovable. I can say that to you now in the letter, that part is easy&#8230;but the hard part comes when you ask me to explain it. If I have to explain it, then I have to consider why, how, I feel that way&#8230;and while I now know why I feel that way, (guh) explaining it just makes me feel bad.”</b></p>
<p>jamey&#8217;s friends and family:</p>
<p>“Jamey is one of the best women I know. She has so many wonderful qualities, it is very hard to name just a few, but here goes… Jamey Voorhees Carter Rivera is one of the most intelligent women I know. She could be anything in the world she wants to be, and, thankfully for her children, she has chosen to be the best mother I know. She is understanding, demanding, loving and nurturing, in her own Jamey way. She knows the pain of a difficult childhood, and has made sure that her three children had someone that loves them unconditionally. This is the greatest gift any parent can give her kids. I turn to her for advice for my own children.  Jamey is one of the most beautiful women, who I don’t believe is truly aware of her beauty. She has a style that I only wish I could pull off. Despite the fact that she has her own unique style, that style never takes over her natural beauty. She has such a beautiful face. I have to put a lot of my beauty on. She is lucky enough to look gorgeous just as she is.  Finally, Jamey is one of the strongest women I know. She has seen a lot in her years, but rather than wallow in self pity, or let it keep her from enjoying life, she learns and grows from life’s experiences. To be able to be philosophical about life’s shitty experiences is so important. I think she knows that the sum total of her life has made her the incredible woman she is today. I admire Jamey and all the wonderful qualities that she has. I am thankful and proud to call her my friend.” &#8211; laura</p>
<p>“Jamey is a fierce and loyal friend. She&#8217;s a lioness – generous, impulsive, and never backs down from a fight. She is tender to those she loves, inquisitive and hard working. Most of all, she is a devoted Mother, who always puts her children first, and whose happiness and well being are her reason to get up in the morning. She is a good wife, and incredibly beautiful. She turns hardship into challenge, and is constantly evolving. She is also a hothead, crazy *ss wacko, and I love her all the more for it, because without this, she would be insufferably perfect. I&#8217;d give her any organ I could spare, and maybe a few I could not. I am very lucky she is in my life.” &#8211; diana</p>
<p>“Ok, let&#8217;s see&#8230; words to describe Jamey&#8230; thorough &#8212; she&#8217;s a friend that, if you got lice from your asshole kids, would help you deal with it (since the boyfriend wouldn&#8217;t). haha.  Kind, an avid recycler, spontaneous, funny&#8211; (as in HAHA but also sarcastic haha), brave, strong&#8211; (she could take a man down and stands up for her family and those she cares about), smart (hell, she homeschools Ethan) a great decorator, (we&#8217;ve all seen her house), animal lover (from her urban farming to cats and dogs and what else resides in the house, haha), good listener (she&#8217;ll let you vent but also gives you pros and cons about irrational crazy thoughts), humble, a great cook (all those years watching Food Network paid off), fun (just typing that makes me laugh&#8230;she&#8217;s a friggin&#8217; hoot) in love (I’m surprised they get out of bed)&#8230;..” &#8211; jooley</p>
<p>“CONFIDENT, BEAUTIFUL, A GREAT MOTHER, AND SHE IS GREAT AT BURYING YOUR DECEASED PETS WHEN YOU JUST CAN&#8217;T FIND THE COURAGE&#8230;.” &#8211; sara</p>
<p>“Lets see&#8230;I have known Jamey since we were 6yrs old. She is right in that I can share a thing or 2 or 50!  Jamey is loyal. Even when years passed between times that we spoke, she has my back.  Jamey might be the smartest chick I know (person, really). And I&#8217;m not just speaking of intelligence, although she has an abundance of that!  Jamey is so funny&#8230;always. She has one of the best senses of humor of anyone I know&#8230;&amp; I know some funny people!  Jamey&#8217;s heart is bigger than her person. She cares deeply about everyone she meets (even those who may not deserve it). She cares deeply about causes too &#8211; environment, children, animals, human rights&#8230; Jamey is strong. She has gone through things that would break most people and she keeps going, almost stronger after each thing. I am amazed everyday by the person she&#8217;s become.  She is an awesome mother. She&#8217;s kind of my &#8220;mom&#8221; idol. When I have a mothering issue, I often find myself thinking, &#8220;what would Jamey do?&#8221; I know this project isn&#8217;t about outer beauty, but she has that in spades as well&#8230; I could go on &amp; on about how amazing she is, but I will probably start crying and then I won&#8217;t be able to type.” &#8211; paige</p>
<p>“Hi Alana,  I could write an essay about my beloved Jamey and never be able to describe her adequately. But here is the mixed bag of qualities that I admire about her. I think what makes them so great is that they are so contrasting. She isn&#8217;t one way&#8230;Majestic, Decisive, Brave, Direct, Unflinching, Commanding, Fierce, Nurturing, Resourceful, Persuasive, Authentic, Tender, Protective, Brilliant.” &#8211; jillian</p>
<p>“Hey Alana&#8230; I don&#8217;t know&#8230;Jamey usually just makes fun of me&#8230;<br />
But seriously,  I think one of the best qualities of Jamey is her confidence. She is funny and sharp-witted. She is also a fantastic mother and very protective of her children.” &#8211; greg</p>
<p>“My wife sees a new world. She lives a new world. She spends every single day, at great personal, emotional risk to herself, living and feeling and loving as if the people she knows and loves are somehow better than we are; somehow kinder, and gentler, and funnier, and more caring, than we are, because that is how she is, and that is what it takes to evolve. Every breath is encouragement, to be better &#8211; to try and transcend. Jamey somehow manages to live in the big picture, seeing the past and considering the future, while living within each moment, and the macrocosmic power contained within each breath, each touch, each sound, each look. She lives and loves without a net, without hesitation, and with no expectation other than to be treated with the same love, the same hope, and the same promise she gives. Our kids, who &#8211; let&#8217;s be honest &#8211; get more from her than anyone else, are the best testimonial, as they are quickly growing to be even better &#8211; their kindness, tolerance, sensitivity and intellect are entirely their mothers fault.<br />
She&#8217;s also fucking hilarious &#8211; seriously, the funniest person I&#8217;ve ever known. Honestly, she&#8217;s so funny, she could be kind of a dick and I&#8217;d still think she was amazing. Bonus she&#8217;s not, right?” &#8211; ash</p>
<p>“Jamey… How would I describe her?  Charming, funny, bright, compassionate, a great mother, a good friend, diligent, hard working, thoughtful.” &#8211; rebecca</p>
<p>“Jamey Voorhees Carter Rivera is the kind of woman that deserves to have a four-name-long name. This chick is one of the absolute strongest women I know.  BUT, one of the things I especially love about her is that, while I rely on that strength of hers, she also lets those close to her see the other things that make her beautiful – her vulnerability and sensitivity.  The woman can cut a chicken’s head off, yell at the asshole down the street, and then come in and cry with me over the latest Parenthood.<br />
She is a friend to the death – incredibly and fiercely loyal – an ally that anyone would want on their side, while also being the secretly emotional woman you need that enveloping hug from that only she can give.  She is the friend that I know I can call on to attend a memorial for innocent children that we never knew, but feel their loss as if they were our own.  She is the one that will hold my hand at those times that I just need to FEEL.<br />
She is selflessly generous.<br />
She is a super devoted, loving, and protective mother (in the most balanced, perfect way).  One that I take many a lesson from in mommying, like how to be nurturing when it goes against your normal grain…<br />
She exudes love for her family and earns that love and respect back.<br />
She is super intelligent and very self-aware and aware of the world around her.  As dumb as the world can often be, she is not fazed.<br />
Have I said that she’s beautiful?  She is STUNNING.  The most fabulous tattoos, always the best hair, the best style (even when it’s a peacoat with yoga pants, she looks amazing), and just the way she carries herself – she exudes confidence.  People can’t help but stare at how gorgeous she is.  I think one of my favorite things to watch her do is to cover her mouth when she laughs, as her nose scrunches up all cute – I see this gorgeous woman transform into an adorable little girl for a minute.<br />
The chick is HILARIOUS.  I could go on for hours about this.  We have enjoyed many a night where we just end up in a heap of tears on her kitchen floor from laughing so hard.  There are probably pictures.  Indeed, there are pictures.  But they will never capture the actual extent of the hilarity.  For that, you must experience Jamey for yourself.  Everyone should be lucky enough to have that privilege.<br />
p.s. she&#8217;ll also watch The Cure dvd trilogy with me for many hours in one sitting&#8230;gotta love that!” &#8211; alana</p>
<p><strong>the original blogs (with backstory) can be found here: </p>
<p><a href="http://alanatphotography.wordpress.com/2013/02/11/women-raw-honest-loved-part-1-2/" rel="nofollow">http://alanatphotography.wordpress.com/2013/02/11/women-raw-honest-loved-part-1-2/</a></p>
<p><a href="http://alanatphotography.wordpress.com/2013/02/12/women-raw-honest-loved-part-2/" rel="nofollow">http://alanatphotography.wordpress.com/2013/02/12/women-raw-honest-loved-part-2/</a></strong><em></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/645/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/645/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=645&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://alanatphotography.wordpress.com/2013/03/12/jamey/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/3d11cee51cbdd63c35394bb47a7bddc2?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F0.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">alanatphotography</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://alanatphotography.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/jameyblog.jpg?w=560" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jameyblog</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>My Jesus Looks Like Jean-Paul Belmondo</title>
		<link>http://andynicastro.com/2013/03/16/my-jesus-looks-like-jean-paul-belmondo/</link>
		<comments>http://andynicastro.com/2013/03/16/my-jesus-looks-like-jean-paul-belmondo/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 23:10:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>andy nicastro</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[addiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Clergy Sex Abuse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drugs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jesus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[molestation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recovery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[religion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spirituality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[catholic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Catholic Church]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[catholicism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Central Valley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christ the King Church]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christianity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[god]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jean-paul belmondo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jesu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jesus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joseph]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oliver O'Grady]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opposing Views]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Priest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Religion & Spirituality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Roman Catholic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sacred Heart Church]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Saint Peter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sunday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Turlock]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://andynicastro.com/?p=560</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A long time ago, when I was very young, Jesus was my closest friend. I went to church every Sunday: first at Christ the King in Commack, New York, and later, after moving to California at the age of 10, Sacred Heart Church in dusty, then-rather-backwoods Turlock in the Central Valley. I can&#8217;t say I [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=560&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://andynicastro.com/2013/03/16/my-jesus-looks-like-jean-paul-belmondo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a95c4fba49f67dc8112c1084768212b6?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">andynicastro</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://andynicastro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/jesus-wallpapers-0114.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jesus-wallpapers-0114</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://andynicastro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/nanandandy.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">nanandandy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://andynicastro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/brownscapular-s2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">BrownScapular.S2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://andynicastro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/image.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://andynicastro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/breathless8.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">breathless8</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>There Should Be a Greeting Card for That</title>
		<link>http://wewillbeginagain.com/2013/03/07/there-should-be-a-greeting-card-for-that/</link>
		<comments>http://wewillbeginagain.com/2013/03/07/there-should-be-a-greeting-card-for-that/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 04:42:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>vbtulacro</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Victoria Tulacro]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://wewillbeginagain.com/?p=1615</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I am too young for a hearing aid.  I am also too blonde and too tall for a hearing aid.  Maybe I am too pretty for one too but not likely.  Mostly, I am too stubborn. Being hearing impaired is not something I share with a lot of people.  In fact, many of my friends and [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1615&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I am too young for a hearing aid.  I am also too blonde and too tall for a hearing aid.  Maybe I am too pretty for one too but not likely.  Mostly, I am too stubborn.</p>
<p>Being hearing impaired is not something I share with a lot of people.  In fact, many of my friends and co-workers probably do not know this about me.  It’s hard to say.  I am not totally deaf; I just struggle to hear out of one of my perfectly normal-looking ears.  The right one.  And my hearing is not totally gone—it’s like I have a thumb jammed in there or maybe a big toe.  I can hear sound, mumbles, tones.  If you stood on my right side and spoke to me, and we were in a quiet place, I would have no trouble at all.  But if we were in a restaurant and you sat to my right and asked me how my day was, I could hear your voice, but I would struggle to make sense of the words.</p>
<p>Sometimes, I can fake this moment.  Guess at what I should say.  Take context clues and answer appropriately.  This is how I navigate many of my non-hearing moments.  But if I cannot do this, I might smile at you and hope the moment passes—that maybe our waiter will ask if we’re ready to order.  Mostly though I just listen to the noise—and see what sense I can make of it all.  The clatter of plates, the murmur of fuzzy conversations nearby, a song overhead that I can almost hear the pitch of a note here and there.</p>
<p>Believe it or not, it is a hard thing to tell people, especially people who I have known for quite some time.  First, there is the occasion.  I feel like the right time never comes up.  <i>Hey, Vicki.  How are the kids?  Hey you</i>, I might reply, maybe even give a hug depending on the nature of our relationship.  <i>By the way, I can’t hear you.  Oh, I’m. . uh. . . well, I’m hearing impaired.  How long?  Um, jeez, since birth, I guess. . . I didn’t tell you because uh. . . uh. . .</i></p>
<p>Second, there are the questions.  <i>Why can’t I hear?</i>  I don’t know.  <i>Have I been tested?</i>  Yes, a couple dozen times.  <i>Is there anything the doctors can do?</i>  Yes, if I want a hearing aid.  <i>Why don’t I get one?</i>  Oh, because it’s $5,000, and then there’s the thing about being too young and pretty or prideful or whatever.</p>
<p>Sometimes I wish there were greeting cards for this kind of announcement.</p>
<p>Dear Friend,</p>
<p>Ever wonder why I look at off into space when you are talking?  No, really—it’s me.  Surprise!  I’m hearing impaired!</p>
<p>Love,</p>
<p>Me</p>
<p>Sometimes I wish there was a T-shirt that announced such things to the general, unsuspecting public.  A disclaimer so that I didn’t have to explain what I <i>thought</i> I heard.  Something so that I didn’t have to feel like I needed to justify my actions and/or lack thereof.</p>
<p>Take, for example, the grocery store last week when a hollowed out, dusty man approached me while I was pitching my goods into my car.  I could sense him approaching.  (Sadly, there are far too many older, dried-up desert men floating around the Stater Bros’ parking lot.  Most of them want money.  Some of them want rides or food for their animals or food for their families.)  And then, he started to talk.  At first, I continued with the task of chucking the heavy bags into the trunk.  Because I can’t hear well, I often approach the world in this manner—ignore.  But then he spoke again, this time, closer.  I could hear his voice, but the words were gravelly.  I could hear the tone—a question, so  I turned and said, <i>Sorry.  I don’t have any cash</i>.</p>
<p>Of course, this was not what he had asked, as evidenced by his souring grin.  I had guessed wrong and this angered him.  Then I noticed the squeegee.</p>
<p>“I didn’t <i>ask</i> you for a handout,” he shouted; the squeegee pumped up and down with the spit in his words.  “I <i>asked</i> you if you wanted your windows cleaned!  I ain’t no charity case!”</p>
<p>What was I to say?  <i>Sorry, I didn’t hear you and I just assumed. . . </i>It didn’t matter.  I was a jerk either way.  The man stormed off, shouting to the resting of the parking lot how he wasn’t asking for no charity—he was asking for work, goddamnit.</p>
<p>My mother-in-law recently got a hearing aid.  She hears everything now—right down to the cat drinking water from the toilet two rooms away.  But in exchange, whenever she talks, she hears her own voice blast across the room.  As a corrective measure, she has taken to mumbling.  But sadly, where she now hears, I can’t hear <i>her</i>.  I sat across her at dinner a few weeks ago and never once realized she was talking to me until my husband drove an elbow into my ribs.  I had been staring into space, taking in the architecture, the patrons, the closeness of one red-haired waitress and the bar tender with too much gel in his hair.</p>
<p>And that’s the other thing not hearing has done for me.  Oh sure, it gets me out of conversations I don’t <i>want</i> to hear, but it has allowed for a lifetime of retreat.  Growing up, when friends were hard to come by, I could always sit behind a tree and watch lips move, mouths burst open with laughter.  I filled the vacuum of their words and noises with my own.  I made up their lies and their jokes, their playground alliances and betrayals.</p>
<p>So when I think about hearing—really hearing the world—for all its nuance and crackle, I can’t help but to stick to my understanding of it.  So I can’t sing a song off the radio without mis-hearing most of the lyrics, but who cares if “sunset” isn’t actually “bun lift”?  (You’d be surprised how many songs containing “sunset” that “bun lift” is a surprising contextual equivalent.)  So what if I can’t hear my kids shouting across the house that so-and-so ruined their Lego House of Awesomeness?  So what if I can’t hear my husband calling me from the next room to hurry up they’re felling another tree on <i>Ax Men</i>?  There are some things not worth hearing.  The rest—well, the rest I’ll just have to make-do.  Or make-up.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1615/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1615/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1615&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://wewillbeginagain.com/2013/03/07/there-should-be-a-greeting-card-for-that/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/ba9af2d0e167cdaf196b0a4e3c196b33?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">vbtulacro</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How the 3/5ths Live.</title>
		<link>http://stacialbrown.com/2013/02/26/how-the-35ths-live/</link>
		<comments>http://stacialbrown.com/2013/02/26/how-the-35ths-live/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2013 14:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>slb</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Nonfiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[privilege]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quvenzhane Wallis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[racism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[survival]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[three-fifths compromise]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://stacialbrown.com/?p=2374</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[From an outsider&#8217;s perspective, say, from the purview of a citizen whose great-great-grandfathers were land owners, voters, arbiters of the unamended Constitution, we spend a lot of time lamenting. We deflect our own savagery by blaming it on their ancestors. Our hearing turns conveniently selective when they insist that they are not their ancestors. They [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2374&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>From an outsider&#8217;s perspective, say, from the purview of a citizen whose great-great-grandfathers were land owners, voters, arbiters of the unamended Constitution, we spend a lot of time lamenting. We deflect our own savagery by blaming it on their ancestors. Our hearing turns conveniently selective when they insist that <em>they</em> are <em>not</em> their ancestors. They know full well that, after our brief exchange &#8212; wherein they will glumly wonder, <em>How can black people be so unforgiving?</em> &#8212; they will go home and turn a key in the lock of a house they&#8217;ve either purchased outright or will pay off before the age of 30. They know how easily they qualified for their low-interest mortgage. They know their parents&#8217; pristine credit, ensured by their grandfather&#8217;s investments and assets, inherited from their great-grandfathers dividends, insured by their great-great-grandfather&#8217;s land ownership, made that possible.</p>
<p>And they know <em>our</em> great-great-grandparents &#8212; both of them &#8212; and their six- and seven- and nine-year-old children worked that land with no pay. They know neither generation had anything to hand down to our grandparents. They know we inherited not assets, but in most cases, debt. They know that if our parents benefited from the Cosby-fication of a Black Middle Class, it was as recently as the late 20th century and was not achieved without the splintering of entire communities. They know our gains can often be threatened &#8212; nay, <em>ravaged</em> &#8212; by the strong winds of a single recession.</p>
<p>They know that, when we are poor, it is not often because of bad breaks, bad investments, or passing on the right kinds of plentiful opportunities. It is because we were written into the annals of this country&#8217;s history as <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Three-Fifths_Compromise">3/5 human</a> and, centuries later, we are still seen by many as such.</p>
<p>It is because they get to deny this, even as it profits them, even as their satirical publications bandy about their particular brand of ironic hipster racism and they get to laugh, defend it, and call us (and our nine-year-old youngest-ever Best Actress Oscar nominee) oversensitive and incapable of comprehending satire &#8212; incapable, of course, because we are missing those vital two-fifths of humanity that house the white man&#8217;s funny bone, presumably.</p>
<p>And look at what white folks&#8217; humor hath wrought: renderings of our president, his wife, and their daughters as <a href="http://i512.photobucket.com/albums/t323/HappyGestapo/Stuff%20I%20find%20on%20the%20interwebz/obamamonkey.jpg">apes</a>, as <a href="http://jezebel.com/5234057/is-michelle-obama-being-treated-like-a-modern-day-sarah-bartmann">Hottentots</a>, as <a href="http://freerepublicwatch.wordpress.com/tag/free-republic-photoshops-malia-obamas-behind-and-calls-michelle-obama-ghetto-trash/">savages</a>; ridicule of our athletes as animals; co-opted use of an incendiary racial slur as <a href="http://www.nydailynews.com/entertainment/gossip/lisa-lampanelli-defends-calling-lena-dunham-n-a-article-1.1269084">a synonym for friend</a>; rampant Islamophobia; incessant hypersexualization of our <a href="http://campusprogress.org/articles/why_chelsea_handlers_black_penis_jokes_arent_funny/">men</a>, women, and <a href="http://www.vh1.com/celebrity/2013-02-25/seth-macfarlane-disses-celebs-video/">children</a>.</p>
<p>Forgive us our straight faces.</p>
<p>From our own vantage, we are exhausted. Too often, we are winded, expending so much oxygen on explaining in detail to those who surely must already know how our humanity has been impinged and why we are deserving of verbally unmolested heroes and schools that do not subscribe to a <a href="http://colorlines.com/archives/2012/11/school_prison_pipeline_meridian.html">playground-to-prison pipeline</a> for our children. We&#8217;re positively spent, managing the endless task of finding and heralding more First Black _____s to Ever ______, spent after having to point out that, if all things were equal, we would&#8217;ve stopped &#8220;pioneering&#8221; in fields they&#8217;ve dominated and from which we&#8217;ve been historically barred, ages ago.</p>
<p>If we decline an opportunity to attend their &#8220;healing racism&#8221; initiatives, if we remain silent when they ask us why we don&#8217;t have to wash our hair daily, if we sigh with deep exasperation when they say they &#8220;don&#8217;t see race&#8221; &#8212; even as nooses are still being hung at schools, crosses still burned on laws, sentencing still disproportionately favors harsher penalties for minority offenders, and the few black actors we&#8217;re allowed still can&#8217;t enjoy their nominations and awards the rest of us having to wonder if they&#8217;ve only been offered them because they played criminals, slaves, pimps, or domestics &#8212; we have our reasons.</p>
<p>And no, if you <em>can&#8217;t possibly imagine</em> what they are, we&#8217;ll waste no further air elucidating them for you.</p>
<p>We have our own means of navigating what this country has apportioned us &#8212; and they are intricate, communal, and, at times, quite deeply flawed. But if we are to always be treated as abstractions, having the form of humanness but not the entitlements thereof, we will continue to keep our ways clandestine and our cards close to the vest. We will accept their apologies as publicly as they issue them, while being as slow to trust their sincerity in private as they are to believe we&#8217;re owed them in the first place.</p>
<p>It is not so difficult, overcoming. You need only have ancestors whose flesh was cracked open like melon rind and torn from their limbs by hounds. You need only have children who can continue to smile when adults, hiding behind anonymity, call them the kinds of names they are never allowed to repeat. You need only have the grace to accept &#8220;heartfelt remorse&#8221; from people whose ability to produce such was made suspect the moment they thought to offend your children, in such particularly callous ways to begin with.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ve grown good at it. It is the one thing privilege cannot buy. <i><br />
</i></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2374/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2374/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2374&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://stacialbrown.com/2013/02/26/how-the-35ths-live/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/ba738a82ca1b1e4e357fafcb449dba5b?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">slb</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>An Atlantic Island in Winter.</title>
		<link>http://dominicstafford.wordpress.com/2013/01/05/an-atlantic-island-in-winter/</link>
		<comments>http://dominicstafford.wordpress.com/2013/01/05/an-atlantic-island-in-winter/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2013 21:46:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dominic Stafford Photography</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Photo Essay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dominic Stafford]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Madeira]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dominicstafford.wordpress.com/?p=747</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=747&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_62191.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-748" alt="IMG_6219" src="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_62191.jpg?w=500&#038;h=333" width="500" height="333" /></a><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-749" alt="IMG_6285" src="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_62851.jpg?w=500&#038;h=333" width="500" height="333" /><a href="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_7126.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-801" alt="IMG_7126" src="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_7126.jpg?w=500&#038;h=333" width="500" height="333" /></a> <a href="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_65231.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-750" alt="IMG_6523" src="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_65231.jpg?w=500&#038;h=335" width="500" height="335" /></a> <a href="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_65901.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-751" alt="IMG_6590" src="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_65901.jpg?w=500&#038;h=333" width="500" height="333" /></a> <a href="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_66491.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-752" alt="IMG_6649" src="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_66491.jpg?w=500&#038;h=333" width="500" height="333" /></a> <a href="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_6684a1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-753" alt="IMG_6684a" src="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_6684a1.jpg?w=500&#038;h=333" width="500" height="333" /></a> <a href="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_6703.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-754" alt="IMG_6703" src="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_6703.jpg?w=500&#038;h=333" width="500" height="333" /></a> <a href="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_6735.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-755" alt="IMG_6735" src="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_6735.jpg?w=500&#038;h=333" width="500" height="333" /></a> <a href="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_67611.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-756" alt="IMG_6761" src="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_67611.jpg?w=500&#038;h=333" width="500" height="333" /></a> <a href="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_6915.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-757" alt="IMG_6915" src="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_6915.jpg?w=500&#038;h=333" width="500" height="333" /></a> <a href="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_69541.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-758" alt="IMG_6954" src="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_69541.jpg?w=500&#038;h=333" width="500" height="333" /></a> <a href="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_70081.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-759" alt="IMG_7008" src="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_70081.jpg?w=500&#038;h=333" width="500" height="333" /></a> <a href="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_7158.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-760" alt="IMG_7158" src="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_7158.jpg?w=500&#038;h=333" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/747/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/747/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=747&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://dominicstafford.wordpress.com/2013/01/05/an-atlantic-island-in-winter/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
		<georss:point>0.000000 0.000000</georss:point>
		<geo:lat>0.000000</geo:lat>
		<geo:long>0.000000</geo:long>
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/23230f27fe68d659b1b9366be1760b2c?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">dominicstafford</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_62191.jpg?w=500" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_6219</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_62851.jpg?w=500" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_6285</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_7126.jpg?w=500" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_7126</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_65231.jpg?w=500" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_6523</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_65901.jpg?w=500" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_6590</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_66491.jpg?w=500" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_6649</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_6684a1.jpg?w=500" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_6684a</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_6703.jpg?w=500" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_6703</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_6735.jpg?w=500" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_6735</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_67611.jpg?w=500" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_6761</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_6915.jpg?w=500" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_6915</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_69541.jpg?w=500" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_6954</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_70081.jpg?w=500" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_7008</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_7158.jpg?w=500" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_7158</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Art for Life&#8217;s Sake</title>
		<link>http://mumbojumbosoph.wordpress.com/2013/03/15/art-for-lifes-sake/</link>
		<comments>http://mumbojumbosoph.wordpress.com/2013/03/15/art-for-lifes-sake/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 23:08:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>mumbo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Arty Mumbo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London Mumbo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mumbo Obsessions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mumbojumbosheepism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Abramovic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Great Wall of China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Artist is Present]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ulay]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mumbojumbosoph.wordpress.com/?p=4554</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This piece has been doing the rounds on Facebook: [Marina Abramovic and Ulay started an intense love story in the 70s, performing art out of the van they lived in. When they felt the relationship had run its course, they decided to walk the Great Wall of China, each from one end, meeting for one [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4554&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This piece has been doing the rounds on Facebook:</p>
<p><em>[Marina Abramovic and Ulay started an intense love story in the 70s, performing art out of the van they lived in. When they felt the relationship had run its course, they decided to walk the Great Wall of China, each from one end, meeting for one last big hug in the middle and never seeing each other again.</em></p>
<p><em>At her 2010 MoMa retrospective Marina performed ‘The Artist Is Present’ as part of the show, where she shared a minute of silence with each stranger who sat in front of her. Ulay arrived without her knowing and this is what happened...]</em></p>
<span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='640' height='390' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/XNcWRbh8wQA?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span>
<p>The way it taps into the pain of love is its immediate appeal, when there are no words that can salve the disappointment of a deep connection rent.</p>
<p>If an artist is someone <em>creating</em> (as opposed, for this purpose, to the naturalist who <em>allows</em>) then artists who make themselves the substance of their art somehow represent the apotheosis of artifice.</p>
<p>Meaning, that I think of the act of art as presenting an idea or a combination of ideas in such a way that a new perspective is offered, on some or any thing in this thing we call life.</p>
<p>To then live this out with deliberate focus- to invest in it personal integrity and have the impulse to share it- is special, and appeals to me in its total re-interpretation or re-imagination of the mundane.</p>
<p>The very idea of sharing a moment&#8217;s silence with strangers is compelling; to do it with a loved one intense; to do it with an estranged loved one- wow. (This may not have been Abramovic&#8217;s intention but she embraced it.)</p>
<p>Shortly afterwards I came across this prequel, which I really enjoyed on a number of levels:</p>
<span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='640' height='390' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/O6dF8Gjm-X8?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span>
<p>I love the simplicity and grandiosity of the Great Wall of China project.</p>
<p>I love the nature of their artistic relationship, so perilously close to self-parody.</p>
<p>And I love that it backed up all the non-verbal cues communicated in its sequel, namely that when they parted he (at least nominally) held the power.</p>
<p>(Funny, though, how he does not resist the urge to let slip his grading of the gravity of her betrayal with a friend, even in the context of his own more lasting transgression.)</p>
<p>I experienced many feelings when I watched these two short clips but what I&#8217;d like to share is a fantasy.</p>
<p>I would have liked to be the translator who was to become Ulay&#8217;s bride- the demon minx who tore apart the Art World&#8217;s collaborative darlings, trudging around with a bulging belly just as Abramovic shrank into desolation.</p>
<p>Imagining for a sweet second that all the timings were right, after <em>The Artist is Present</em> I would have installed two gigantic photographs and a pedestal; the first, a photograph of Abravomovic and Ulay in their heyday; the second, a photograph of a pregnant me; and lastly, a real life pregnant me sitting on the pedestal.</p>
<p>In front of them all would be a paint splurter.</p>
<p>And all the people who had spent a silent minute with Abramovic would be invited to take a splurgy shot at one of the two photographs or at the pregnant me.</p>
<p>It would have been a comment on judgment and cathartic anger and honesty, all in one.</p>
<p>I think I would have felt more a part of their Art Thing and maybe a bit less guilty when I had the Ulay baby.</p>
<p>And I would have felt sorry for the people who felt justified at having a pop at the real me and the babe.</p>
<p>Because you can love the idea of something (an image of the happy couple) and hate the idea of something (an image of the one who tore them apart) but if you hate real people that&#8217;s sad, even if mediated through art.</p>
<p>And I would have felt scared of the people who would have liked to have a pop at the real me and the babe but thought it would look bad, because they would be sad but cowardly too, and outside of the gallery walls those people might be dangerous.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4554/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4554/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4554&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://mumbojumbosoph.wordpress.com/2013/03/15/art-for-lifes-sake/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/6ee51438ccd5fd7da9f9ac4f4847b9e4?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mumbo</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Insulated in India</title>
		<link>http://aliceshikembel.wordpress.com/2013/03/15/insulated-in-india/</link>
		<comments>http://aliceshikembel.wordpress.com/2013/03/15/insulated-in-india/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 11:23:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>aliceshikembel</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adventure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[semester at sea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://aliceshikembel.wordpress.com/?p=936</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The sights of India: an elderly man straining to pedal his bicycle, pulling a load the size of a Smart Car behind him.  A camel, walking along the road, pulling a cart.  Bursts of color from the saris of women walking by. Samosas bobbing in a huge bowl of bubbling oil.  Women trudging along a [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=936&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The sights of India: an elderly man straining to pedal his bicycle, pulling a load the size of a Smart Car behind him.  A camel, walking along the road, pulling a cart.  Bursts of color from the saris of women walking by. Samosas bobbing in a huge bowl of bubbling oil.  Women trudging along a dirt trail with huge bundles of straw balanced on their heads.  Feral pigs rooting around in mounds of trash.  A man suffering from elephantitis, feet swollen to the size of cocker spaniels.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, we witnessed most of these sights from behind the windows of our air-conditioned bus.  Intimidated by the thought of traveling independently in India, I had signed us up for a three-night excursion titled, “Trains, Palaces, and Elephants,” figuring that it would be a good place to rely on Semester at Sea to take care of the logistics of an overnight trip.  Little did I know what was in store.</p>
<p>After our ship arrived in Cochin, we rode a bus for an hour and a half to the airport, where we proceeded to wait for two hours before flying for four hours to Delhi (with one stop).  Another hour on a bus through rush hour traffic brought us to our hotel, where we had to wait until 8 pm for dinner to be served.  The next morning, we received a wakeup call at 4 am and spent a total of ten hours that day traveling by bus and train, with short stops at the Taj Mahal and the Agra Fort, finally ending up in Jaipur for a late dinner.</p>
<p>Our third day was more palatable, as we spent all of our time visiting sites in Jaipur, but our last day involved a 4:30 am wakeup call for our flight to Mumbai, where we had a two-hour layover before flying back to Cochin.  Another ninety minutes on the bus, and we arrived back at the ship.</p>
<p>Grueling and non-child-friendly travel schedule aside, I found myself dissatisfied for other reasons as well.  I had been expecting, even hoping, for the “assault on the senses” that people had described when visiting India for the first time.  But in an air-conditioned bus, raised up above the level of most other vehicles on the road, there was very little to assault the senses other than the lightly scented “refreshing wet wipes” that were served to us on a tray each time we boarded.  Sleeping and eating in the Crowne Plaza, Radisson, and Ramada hotels certainly didn’t help.  And being herded around with a group of seventy mostly Caucasian people set us apart even more.</p>
<p>Even our shopping experiences were disappointingly sterile; our guides discouraged us from having any contact with the hawkers outside the tourist attractions, and instead made several unscheduled stops (supposedly in response to requests from the students) to large warehouses filled with neatly folded scarves, saris, wall hangings, blankets, and all manner of other handicrafts.  We filed through the echoing halls with hushed voices, and despite the inflated prices, most of us felt pressured to purchase items since it was our only opportunity to shop.  We undoubtedly earned our guides a hefty commission.</p>
<p>During one of our long bus rides, as I gazed out the window, the view outside was partially obscured by my own reflection in the glass.  I thought it a fitting symbol of my frustration. Remaining trapped inside the confines of the bus and following the rushed and rigid itinerary of our tour left me feeling insulated from India, blocked from experiencing the world outside of myself that I longed for.  Disgruntled by the lack of authenticity of our tour, I couldn&#8217;t wait for it to be over so we could make the best of our two remaining days in India.*</p>
<p>Fortunately, the time on our own in Cochin redeemed the disappointment of the previous few days.  With the help of a rickshaw driver, we explored Fort Kochi, visiting historical sites, eating at a delicious vegetarian restaurant packed with locals, browsing local markets, drinking masala chai with shopkeepers, and getting haircuts for the boys at a “Gents Beauty Parlor” for thirty rupees (about sixty cents) a piece.</p>
<p>Like most of the countries we have visited, our time in India felt like a teaser, leaving me wanting more.  I would come back in a second.  And I would plan our trip myself.</p>
<p><a href="http://aliceshikembel.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_6582.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-943" alt="IMG_6582" src="http://aliceshikembel.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_6582.jpg?w=460&#038;h=306" width="460" height="306" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://aliceshikembel.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_6889.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-944" alt="IMG_6889" src="http://aliceshikembel.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_6889.jpg?w=460&#038;h=690" width="460" height="690" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://aliceshikembel.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_6890.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-945" alt="IMG_6890" src="http://aliceshikembel.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_6890.jpg?w=460&#038;h=690" width="460" height="690" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://aliceshikembel.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_7468.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-947" alt="IMG_7468" src="http://aliceshikembel.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_7468.jpg?w=460&#038;h=306" width="460" height="306" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://aliceshikembel.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_7517.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-948" alt="IMG_7517" src="http://aliceshikembel.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_7517.jpg?w=460&#038;h=306" width="460" height="306" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://aliceshikembel.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_7623.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-950" alt="IMG_7623" src="http://aliceshikembel.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_7623.jpg?w=460&#038;h=306" width="460" height="306" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://aliceshikembel.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_7701.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-951" alt="IMG_7701" src="http://aliceshikembel.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_7701.jpg?w=460&#038;h=306" width="460" height="306" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://aliceshikembel.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_7709.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-953" alt="IMG_7709" src="http://aliceshikembel.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_7709.jpg?w=460&#038;h=306" width="460" height="306" /></a></p>
<p>*Our experience does not represent the majority of Semester at Sea Field Programs.  Our fellow travelers emphasized that they had been on spectacular overnight trips with SAS, and this one just happened to be sub-par.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/936/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/936/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=936&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://aliceshikembel.wordpress.com/2013/03/15/insulated-in-india/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>22</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/d83bacc5152248968bfe74090c9ca4f8?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">aliceshikembel</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://aliceshikembel.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_6582.jpg?w=460" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_6582</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://aliceshikembel.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_6889.jpg?w=460" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_6889</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://aliceshikembel.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_6890.jpg?w=460" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_6890</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://aliceshikembel.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_7468.jpg?w=460" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_7468</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://aliceshikembel.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_7517.jpg?w=460" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_7517</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://aliceshikembel.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_7623.jpg?w=460" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_7623</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://aliceshikembel.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_7701.jpg?w=460" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_7701</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://aliceshikembel.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_7709.jpg?w=460" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_7709</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Life After Cancer</title>
		<link>http://nicoleskibolaesq.wordpress.com/2013/03/15/life-after-cancer/</link>
		<comments>http://nicoleskibolaesq.wordpress.com/2013/03/15/life-after-cancer/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 17:18:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Nicole Skibola</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cancer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ESS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life after cancer]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nicoleskibolaesq.wordpress.com/?p=552</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s a sunny day in Birmingham, Alabama. I woke up this morning, the cool air floating over my blankets like fog, and I laid there, eyes closed, listening to the sound of birds chirping outside. Some mornings I wake up with a noose around my heart, the reminder of what I have lost and how [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=552&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://nicoleskibolaesq.wordpress.com/2013/03/15/life-after-cancer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>26</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a778ac621a9fca801f89ba5f48a2a173?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">nicoleskibola</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memes as Mediums for Cultural Messages</title>
		<link>http://ischooligans.wordpress.com/2013/03/14/the-meme-as-a-medium-for-cultural-messages/</link>
		<comments>http://ischooligans.wordpress.com/2013/03/14/the-meme-as-a-medium-for-cultural-messages/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2013 19:38:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jessica</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Archives]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Musings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[archives]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital objects]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meme]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ischooligans.wordpress.com/?p=428</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I gained inspiration for this blog post over the past week or so while taking breaks from essay-writing and studying. I&#8217;ve grown accustomed to daily Memes popping up on my news feed on Facebook. When I first started seeing them many months ago, I&#8217;ll admit, I was uncertain as to what they were. Why were [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=428&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://ischooligans.wordpress.com/2013/03/14/the-meme-as-a-medium-for-cultural-messages/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>48</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/3b33e2bd706f62de9006080757fe24dd?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ischooligan</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ischooligans.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/memegrumpycat.jpeg?w=540" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ischooligans.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/touch-my-cake.jpg?w=440" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ischooligans.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/fragonard.jpg?w=233" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">fragonard</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Behind Duty and Impudence (1839)</title>
		<link>http://rcvscharitabletrustlibrary.wordpress.com/2013/03/15/edwin_landseer/</link>
		<comments>http://rcvscharitabletrustlibrary.wordpress.com/2013/03/15/edwin_landseer/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 18:07:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>alisonrcvs</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Archives]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artworks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Edwin Landseer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Royal painter]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rcvscharitabletrustlibrary.wordpress.com/?p=1309</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The RCVS headquarters tidy-up has revealed another gem, and led us to discover the fascinating story of a troubled man. Eight large prints of paintings by Sir Edwin Henry Landseer (1802-1873), depicting animals and bucolic scenes, have been discovered. Landseer (1802-1873), an English painter, was renowned for his paintings of horses and dogs. Included in his [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1309&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:justify;">The RCVS headquarters tidy-up has revealed <a title="A model hoof" href="http://rcvscharitabletrustlibrary.wordpress.com/2013/01/16/a-model-hoof/" target="_blank">another</a> gem, and led us to discover the fascinating story of a troubled man. Eight large prints of paintings by Sir Edwin Henry Landseer (1802-1873), depicting animals and bucolic scenes, have been discovered.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><a title="Edwin Henry Landseer" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Edwin_Henry_Landseer" target="_blank">Landseer</a> (1802-1873), an English painter, was renowned for his paintings of horses and dogs. Included in his artistic achievements are the lion sculptures in Trafalgar Square. His dog paintings of the 1830&#8242;s are by far his most popular work, ‘Dignity and Impudence’ (1839) being the most famous of all.</p>
<div id="attachment_1310" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 256px"><a href="http://rcvscharitabletrustlibrary.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/dutyimpudence.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1310" alt="Edwin Landseers 'Dignity and impudence' 1839" src="http://rcvscharitabletrustlibrary.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/dutyimpudence.jpg?w=246&#038;h=300" width="246" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Dignity and Impudence (1839)</p></div>
<p style="text-align:justify;">The two dogs in the life sized ‘portrait’ belonged to Jacob Bell, a chemist, who commissioned the work. The bloodhound is called Grafton and the West Highland terrier is named Scratch. Landseer cleverly parodies the Dutch portraiture style, where the subject is framed by either a window or a door, with a hand hanging over the edge. According to the <a title="The Tate" href="http://www.tate.org.uk/art/artworks/landseer-dignity-and-impudence-n00604/text-summary" target="_blank">Tate’s</a> summary of Landseer’s painting, Grafton was quite the bohemian and was a visitor at several artists’ studios in London but Scratch was Bell’s favourite of the two dogs. Apparently, Bell made a bet with the owner of a poodle that his West Highland terrier was the better looking of the two. Landseer was to be the judge, he took one look at Scratch and announced, without any prompting, &#8216;Oh what a beauty!&#8217;</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Bell and Landseer’s lifelong friendship was founded on a mutual love of animals. Eventually Landseer came to rely on Bell as a business advisor, being ill equipped to deal with every day business matters. Along with Landseer’s brother James, Bell oversaw the commission and sale of his portraits, securing the very best prices. He took on rather more duties than a normal business manager might, as he was heavily involved in the rebuilding of Landseer’s home and helped him to purchase land.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Landseer was the youngest son of an engraver and initially developed his talents with his father. He was later sent, along with his two brothers, to study under Benjamin Robert Haydon, the historical painter, in 1815. It was Haydon who encouraged Landseer to study animal anatomy. His early paintings benefit from his excellent anatomical knowledge and portray a variety of moral messages which contributed to his popularity with his Victorian audience. His later work was marred by his sentimentality and the humanization of his animal subjects.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="line-height:1.5;">Landseer had social as well as professional success; his friends included Dickens and Thackeray. He moved freely in aristocratic circles and enjoyed royal patronage in the 1840s.  A favourite painter of Queen Victoria’s, she described Landseer as being ‘very good looking although rather short’. Landseer visited Balmoral in 1850 to paint a portrait of the royal family. The painting was never finished, and the failure of his first royal commission greatly contributed to his deteriorating mental health.</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">In 1840, Landseer suffered a severe mental breakdown, thought to be triggered by the <a title="The Duchess of Bedford" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anna_Russell,_Duchess_of_Bedford" target="_blank">Duchess of Bedford&#8217;s</a> refusal of his marriage proposal (Incidentally, the Duchess was the originator of the very British concept of ‘afternoon tea’!). For the rest of Landseer’s life he was plagued by severe bouts of depression, exacerbated by his alcohol and drug use. His family had him declared insane in July 1872. Landseer died a year later on 1 October, 1873. The country mourned the loss greatly, shops and houses lowered their blinds, flags were hung at half mast and crowds lined the street to watch his funeral procession.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">See our full collection of Edwin Landseer’s prints on our <a title="RCVS Charitable Trust Facebook" href="https://www.facebook.com/RCVSCharitableTrust" target="_blank">Facebook</a> page.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1309/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1309/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1309&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://rcvscharitabletrustlibrary.wordpress.com/2013/03/15/edwin_landseer/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/82b11d77fde70a0555471b463a3b732e?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">alisonrcvs</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://rcvscharitabletrustlibrary.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/dutyimpudence.jpg?w=246" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Edwin Landseers &#039;Dignity and impudence&#039; 1839</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
