<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2012 18:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Zombies and the Modern Historical Experience</title>
		<link>http://themoreibelieve.wordpress.com/2012/08/03/zombies-and-the-modern-historical-experience/</link>
		<comments>http://themoreibelieve.wordpress.com/2012/08/03/zombies-and-the-modern-historical-experience/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2012 07:13:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jonathan Harper</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Zombies]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://themoreibelieve.wordpress.com/?p=250</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Zombies are everywhere. Well, not quite literally. Still, the resurgence of this cultural phenomena over the last few years has been striking. We have seen the popularization of zombies in video games, ranging anywhere from the simultaneously unimaginative and infinitely lucrative Left For Dead series to the infinite genius of the low budget indie game [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=250&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Zombies are everywhere. Well, not quite literally. Still, the resurgence of this cultural phenomena over the last few years has been striking. We have seen the popularization of zombies in video games, ranging anywhere from the simultaneously unimaginative and infinitely lucrative <em>Left For Dead</em> series to the infinite genius of the low budget indie game <a title="You get to drive over zombies. Ooops, I just ruined the ending..." href="http://www.zombiedriver.com" target="_blank"><em>Zombie Driver</em></a>. Films on zombies have become a contagion much more virulent than the fictional creatures themselves. <a title="Popular culture references is about wikipedia's only trusted subject area." href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_zombie_films" target="_blank">The wikipedia page supposedly summarizing all available zombie cinematography</a> is striking insofar as how much the 2000s predominate this genre. Some, such as<em> </em>2<em>8 Days Later</em><em>, 28 Weeks Later, </em>and <em>28 Years Later</em> (okay, just kidding on that last one &#8211; still, a geriatric ward would make for an original zombie flick) are of the more serious genre. Others, most notably <em>Shaun of the Dead </em>and the irresistibly charming <a title="Witty, charming, heartwarming, gory - what's not to like?" href="http://www.amazon.ca/Zombieland-Bilingual-Woody-Harrelson/dp/B002XLGOF4/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1343977595&amp;sr=8-1" target="_blank"><em>Zombieland</em></a>, are satirical in nature. Print literature has not been immune to this phenomenon, as demonstrated by the widely read <em><a title="Never read it. Never intend to. Bite me zombie-lovers. Actually, don't. It would be incredibly disconcerting, in spite of the obvious irony." href="http://www.amazon.ca/World-War-Oral-History-Zombie/dp/0307346617/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1343973037&amp;sr=8-1" target="_blank">World War Z</a> </em>and its less popular predecessor <a title="That's right, it was a book first. A surprisingly profound one, I've been told." href="http://www.amazon.ca/I-Am-Legend-Richard-Matheson/dp/031286504X/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1343973345&amp;sr=1-1" target="_blank"><em>I Am Legend</em></a>. The zombie apocalypse has even chewed its way into mainstream TV with the emergence of the hit show <em>The Walking Dead</em>.</p>
<p>So zombies are popular. What of it? Well, I find the emergence of this particular issue fascinating, insofar as it points to a curious cultural obsession with the concept of a zombie disaster. Many people in modern western culture are inescapably fascinated by the concept of a small group of survivors struggling against shambling hordes of the undead, despite this being &#8211; to the best of my knowledge &#8211; an event without any historical precedent. Given the rather inferior quality of a great many of these productions (<em>Zombieland </em>remains a notable exception) it seems likely that it is something inherent within the zombie theme itself that renders it so culturally poignant.</p>
<p>The zombies themselves are unlikely to be the crux of this issue. Few people could claim intellectual kinship with a shambling horde of the undead, and fewer still are driven to devour the flesh of their neighbours. Thus it would seem that the zombies are merely a literary device which are used as a foil for the true protagonists of any zombie flick: the survivors. As one of my friends once cleverly observed, the true walking dead in the television production of the same name are those that have yet to succumb to the torrent of undeath.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">These survivors must have some fascinating quality which we are drawn to. There is something in their struggle to continue on that is associated with meaning in the collective mindset of this generation. What is there in a small knit group of people trying to not die that appeals to us? Surely not the profound nature of their cause, nor the brilliance of their tactics, and certainly not their compassion. Instead, I would argue, they have a quality born of necessity which we oftentimes lack in our modern context: community.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">We live in oddly communal-less world. Superficially, at least, this appears to not be the case. The internet teaches us that we have dozens, if not hundreds, of friends. After all, Facebook wouldn&#8217;t call them &#8216;friend requests&#8217; if most of the people on there were acquaintances at best, would it? Furthermore, we can maintain regular contact with our actual kith and kin over astonishing distances. At the local level humanity lives in more numerous clusters than at any time prior to this. We&#8217;re surrounded by people, immersed in people, smothered by people. So surely we have community.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Yet for all these boons, community simply isn&#8217;t a large part of many people&#8217;s lives. A summer of working for a local museum has made me acutely aware of how codependent people were even a hundred years ago. They forged communal bonds via religious, economic, social, and even simply geographical ties. They often met regularly with gatherings of people with whom they shared some form of common purpose. Not the mutual selfishness one often finds at parties these days (&#8216;we&#8217;re all bored and lonely, so we all came here to cure ourselves of this ill&#8217;), but a need to submerge oneself within some larger whole. Yet these days we lack these communal links that were once so prevalent. In large part this results from the removal of dependence. One hundred years ago, a farm would benefit greatly from cooperating with its neighbours and gathering together behind communal activities. These days I don&#8217;t need to talk to my neighbours, help out with town projects, or get together for anything beyond an occasional isolated social event with no larger purpose than the fleeting fellowship behind it. Hell, stores even offer to let me purchase my groceries without human interaction. We need no community, so we oftentimes have failed to strive for it.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">The survivors of zombie ravaged hypothetical-Earth, by contrast, must band together to survive. The alternative is simply to get eaten, an unsavoury result for all but the zombies. Hence they are forced into a situation which creates teamwork, camaraderie, and authentic &#8211; if oftentimes fleeting &#8211; relationships. Now I&#8217;m not saying that zombie survivors are frequently depicted as brilliantly orchestrated crew. Oftentimes they are half-hazard, ineffective, squabbling, and downright dysfunctional. But therein lies the brilliance of the matter: that is what a real community is. Authentic community is not achieving seamless perfection, but rather the struggle to learn to live with and love each other despite our imperfections.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">My point in all this is not to call for a Taoist return to the old village lifestyle, nor do I wish to ruin your enjoyment of your favourite flesh eating fiends. Instead, I would simply like to observe that in our journey into the twenty-first century, we ought to remember Chesterton&#8217;s prescient words: &#8220;The fatal metaphor of progress, which means leaving things behind us, has utterly obscured the real idea of growth, which means leaving things inside us.&#8221; We must remember not simply to progress away from the past, but to grow by holding onto those items of value which our predecessors have gifted us. Our rapidly changing society is hardly built for such introspection, but we ought to draw upon some of the more valuable aspects of the past. For the Church, I believe this speaks not only to our need to create communities in Christ at the local level, but to go beyond this and support non-Christian communities, so that we might share the echo of life in abundance with our nearby neighbours, regardless of their given creed.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><em>________________________________________________________________<br />
Caveat Lector: </em>I am not a fan of most zombie flicks, with the exception of my beloved <em>Zombieland, </em>so do bear in mind that I have merely a passing familiarity with the specifics of several of the films and games mentioned above.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Appendix</span> (because blog posts need more of these):<br />
This is one of my favourite quotes pertaining to modernity, as it comes from a Vietnamese literati who witnessed the transition from traditional rural community to urbanized Western society occur within his lifetime:</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align:left;">&#8220;‎Our lives now lie within the sphere of &#8216;I.&#8217; Having lost breadth, we seek depth. But the deeper we go, the colder it gets.&#8221;<br />
-Hoai Thanh on Western individualism (1941)</p>
</blockquote>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/250/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/250/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=250&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://themoreibelieve.wordpress.com/2012/08/03/zombies-and-the-modern-historical-experience/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/359bdce1eca97e7eee56811613849b25?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F0.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jonathanharper</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>If You Want to Write, Don&#8217;t Barf on Your Readers</title>
		<link>http://petemonaco.com/2012/08/02/writing-group/</link>
		<comments>http://petemonaco.com/2012/08/02/writing-group/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2012 01:37:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>petermonaco</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funnies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[barf]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[critiques]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[critiquing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[editing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[p90x]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tony Horton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing group]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://petemonaco.com/?p=144</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[If you want your written word to appeal to others, you need one thing. Readers. But not just any readers. You need a writing group. If you&#8217;re unfamiliar, a writing group is friends or relatives, willing or locked in your basement, who critique your work on a regular basis. They will also hold you accountable [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=144&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you want your written word to appeal to others, you need one thing.</p>
<p>Readers.</p>
<p>But not just any readers.</p>
<p>You need a writing group.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;re unfamiliar, a writing group is friends or relatives, willing or locked in your basement, who critique your work on a regular basis. They will also hold you accountable for completing new work for them to appraise.</p>
<p>One of the hardest parts of writing for me and I think most people, is establishing a level of consistency.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s like working out. You need to do it enough that you establish a solid foundation. It&#8217;s why for so many people <a title="Don’t Eat Breakfast and Lose 8% Body Fat" href="http://petemonaco.com/2012/07/24/intermittent-fasting-results1/">P90X turns into P12X</a>.</p>
<p>And that&#8217;s what a writing group is perfect for. Imagine you knew Tony Horton was going to rip the covers off your bed and do squats on your chest until you went and worked out with him. I almost guarantee that if everyone received that kind of personal attention, there&#8217;d be a lot of slim guys and gals with confused muscles&#8230; or whatever he does to them.</p>
<p>Your writing group pushes you, doesn&#8217;t let you miss a week, doesn&#8217;t let you turn in a sorry excuse for a submission and demands you do better with every one.</p>
<p>Frankly, I sorely underestimated the power of a writing group. I have a pretty high opinion of myself and my writing and doubted the feedback would be useful. I have since recanted.</p>
<p>The problem is, the scenes you envision ONLY exist in your head. The backdrop is already set, characters are detailed and dressed appropriately (unless you are writing a nakie scene), their actions are effortlessly natural (unless you are writing a first time nakie scene).</p>
<p><a href="http://petermonaco.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/scenes.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-180" title="scenes" src="http://petermonaco.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/scenes.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="381" /></a></p>
<p>Yet when you try to gather your thoughts on paper, you&#8217;ll miss things. Lots of things. And even when you re-read it, you&#8217;ll miss them again. Because you already know what is supposed to happen, the words you write supplement, rather than create, the scene.</p>
<p>Time for an extremely graphic and accurate analogy.</p>
<p>I just finished a delicious lunch consisting of a raspberry donut, a <a title="Ode to Rockstar" href="http://petemonaco.com/2012/07/25/ode-to-rockstar/">Rockstar</a>, a burrito and a <a title="Raw Milk = Delicious" href="http://petemonaco.com/2012/07/19/raw-milk-delicious/">glass of raw milk</a>. If Tony Horton burst through my kitchen wall and punched my stomach, I&#8217;d spew everywhere.</p>
<p>If a stranger then came and examined my sick, he&#8217;d have a lot of guesses at what I had just eaten. But they wouldn&#8217;t quite be right. To me, the bits and pieces of my rainbow yawn would paint a perfect picture of my diet, but only because I had the lunch menu to sort it all out.</p>
<p>A writing group is the compromise, the bystanders plugging their nose while pointing to the  milk carton, the empty Rockstar can and the jelly dripping from my fingers.</p>
<p>And that&#8217;s about enough of that analogy&#8230;.</p>
<p>Basically, as I&#8217;ve mentioned before with <a title="Imaginary Friends: Cultivating a Character" href="http://petemonaco.com/2012/07/18/imaginary-friends/">character building</a>, it&#8217;s your job to get things right for your reader and a writing group is the easiest way to accomplish that task.</p>
<p>Don&#8217;t make reader&#8217;s guess, don&#8217;t make them assume.</p>
<p>Don&#8217;t make them feel like they&#8217;re sifting through barf.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/144/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/144/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=144&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://petemonaco.com/2012/08/02/writing-group/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>27</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/224c1e35366a328a961945251dd019cd?s=96&#38;d=retro&#38;r=R" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">petermonaco</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://petermonaco.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/scenes.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">scenes</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Book Wreaths</title>
		<link>http://thebowtiebutterfly.com/2012/08/02/book-wreaths/</link>
		<comments>http://thebowtiebutterfly.com/2012/08/02/book-wreaths/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2012 20:38:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>TheBowTieButterFly</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crafts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[decor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DIY]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family Fun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fashion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recycle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reuse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[style]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[urban life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[paper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[seasonal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wreaths]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thebowtiebutterfly.com/?p=591</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The tutorial for this piece of gorgeousness can be found at Living With Lindsay. Estimated cost? $2. Heck yes. Katydid &#38; Kid whipped up this feather-esque wreath after being inspired by Living With Lindsay&#8217;s above creation.  This mod magazine wreath comes courtesy of Jason of Rag and Bone Bindery. I can&#8217;t see step-by-step instructions on the page, but one [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=591&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><a href="http://thebowtiebutterfly.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/wreath1.jpg"><img src="http://thebowtiebutterfly.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/wreath1.jpg?w=265&h=400" alt="" width="265" height="400" border="0" /></a></div>
<p>The tutorial for this piece of gorgeousness can be found at <a href="http://livingwithlindsay.com/2009/11/librarians-please-avert-your-eyes.html">Living With Lindsay</a>. Estimated cost? $2. Heck yes.</p>
<div><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_2nMwt1rt5Cs/TOs8EoTf7TI/AAAAAAAAA9c/Oz7T4PvLr2c/s1600/wreath2.JPG"><img src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_2nMwt1rt5Cs/TOs8EoTf7TI/AAAAAAAAA9c/Oz7T4PvLr2c/s400/wreath2.JPG" alt="" width="400" height="266" border="0" /></a></div>
<p><a href="http://www.katydidandkid.com/2009/12/recycled-book-wreath-tutorial.html">Katydid &amp; Kid</a> whipped up this feather-esque wreath after being inspired by Living With Lindsay&#8217;s above creation. <a name="more"></a></p>
<div><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_2nMwt1rt5Cs/TOs87SAG3ZI/AAAAAAAAA9g/h-OP8O3caug/s1600/wreath3.jpg"><img src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_2nMwt1rt5Cs/TOs87SAG3ZI/AAAAAAAAA9g/h-OP8O3caug/s400/wreath3.jpg" alt="" width="315" height="400" border="0" /></a></div>
<p>This <a href="http://www.ragandbone.com/blog/?p=1444">mod magazine wreath</a> comes courtesy of Jason of Rag and Bone Bindery. I can&#8217;t see step-by-step instructions on the page, but one of the commenters put together her own version and posted her tutorial<a href="http://extremecards.blogspot.com/2010/01/magazine-page-mirror-frame.html">here</a>.</p>
<div><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_2nMwt1rt5Cs/TOs-tQefyyI/AAAAAAAAA9k/8RhCdFJNqnk/s1600/wreath4.jpg"><img src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_2nMwt1rt5Cs/TOs-tQefyyI/AAAAAAAAA9k/8RhCdFJNqnk/s400/wreath4.jpg" alt="" width="400" height="390" border="0" /></a></div>
<p>But if you&#8217;d rather just skip the cutting, scrunching, curling and gluing, then <a href="http://extremecards.blogspot.com/2010/01/magazine-page-mirror-frame.html">SimpleJoysPaperie</a> has a selection of beautiful book wreaths ready-made for you.</p>
<p>And here&#8217;s a little more inspiration:</p>
<div><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_2nMwt1rt5Cs/TOs_1Dr9WsI/AAAAAAAAA9o/cKEqpJ03LM0/s1600/wreath5.jpg"><img src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_2nMwt1rt5Cs/TOs_1Dr9WsI/AAAAAAAAA9o/cKEqpJ03LM0/s400/wreath5.jpg" alt="" width="396" height="400" border="0" /></a></div>
<div><a href="http://thebowtiebutterfly.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/wreath6.jpg"><img src="http://thebowtiebutterfly.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/wreath6.jpg?w=298&h=400" alt="" width="298" height="400" border="0" /></a></div>
<div>[via <a href="http://ohsocrafty.blogspot.com/2007/10/book-page-wreath.html">Oh So Crafty</a>]</div>
<div></div>
<div><a href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_2nMwt1rt5Cs/TOtAYbUrMdI/AAAAAAAAA9w/F4GdnvoBnfk/s1600/wreath7.jpg"><img src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_2nMwt1rt5Cs/TOtAYbUrMdI/AAAAAAAAA9w/F4GdnvoBnfk/s400/wreath7.jpg" alt="" width="400" height="266" border="0" /></a></div>
<div> [via <a href="http://jonesdesigncompany.com/create/book-page-wreaths/">jones design company</a>]</div>
<div></div>
<div><a href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_2nMwt1rt5Cs/TOtBJytk_XI/AAAAAAAAA90/Mm2L6vbodik/s1600/wreath11.JPG"><img src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_2nMwt1rt5Cs/TOtBJytk_XI/AAAAAAAAA90/Mm2L6vbodik/s400/wreath11.JPG" alt="" width="400" height="300" border="0" /></a></div>
<div>  [via <a href="http://yarner.blogspot.com/2010/10/book-wreath.html">I'm a Yarner</a>]</div>
<div></div>
<div><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_2nMwt1rt5Cs/TOtBKcdvT2I/AAAAAAAAA94/4MHqBoXa1iE/s1600/wreath10.jpg"><img src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_2nMwt1rt5Cs/TOtBKcdvT2I/AAAAAAAAA94/4MHqBoXa1iE/s400/wreath10.jpg" alt="" width="266" height="400" border="0" /></a></div>
<div>  [via <a href="http://jonesdesigncompany.com/create/book-page-wreaths/">jones design company</a>]</div>
<div><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_2nMwt1rt5Cs/TOtBNdLNxiI/AAAAAAAAA98/oehcZX_-bBg/s1600/wreath9.jpg"><img src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_2nMwt1rt5Cs/TOtBNdLNxiI/AAAAAAAAA98/oehcZX_-bBg/s400/wreath9.jpg" alt="" width="400" height="266" border="0" /></a></div>
<div>  [via <a href="http://jonesdesigncompany.com/create/book-page-wreaths/">jones design company</a>]</div>
<div><a href="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_2nMwt1rt5Cs/TOtBNzu1MjI/AAAAAAAAA-A/ktX41jq0y9U/s1600/wreath8.jpg"><img src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_2nMwt1rt5Cs/TOtBNzu1MjI/AAAAAAAAA-A/ktX41jq0y9U/s400/wreath8.jpg" alt="" width="400" height="266" border="0" /></a></div>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/591/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/591/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=591&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thebowtiebutterfly.com/2012/08/02/book-wreaths/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>32</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/6ffdc78912e47d21152a804429696935?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">thebowtiebutterfly</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thebowtiebutterfly.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/wreath1.jpg?w=199" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_2nMwt1rt5Cs/TOs8EoTf7TI/AAAAAAAAA9c/Oz7T4PvLr2c/s400/wreath2.JPG" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_2nMwt1rt5Cs/TOs87SAG3ZI/AAAAAAAAA9g/h-OP8O3caug/s400/wreath3.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_2nMwt1rt5Cs/TOs-tQefyyI/AAAAAAAAA9k/8RhCdFJNqnk/s400/wreath4.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_2nMwt1rt5Cs/TOs_1Dr9WsI/AAAAAAAAA9o/cKEqpJ03LM0/s400/wreath5.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://thebowtiebutterfly.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/wreath6.jpg?w=224" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_2nMwt1rt5Cs/TOtAYbUrMdI/AAAAAAAAA9w/F4GdnvoBnfk/s400/wreath7.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_2nMwt1rt5Cs/TOtBJytk_XI/AAAAAAAAA90/Mm2L6vbodik/s400/wreath11.JPG" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_2nMwt1rt5Cs/TOtBKcdvT2I/AAAAAAAAA94/4MHqBoXa1iE/s400/wreath10.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_2nMwt1rt5Cs/TOtBNdLNxiI/AAAAAAAAA98/oehcZX_-bBg/s400/wreath9.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/_2nMwt1rt5Cs/TOtBNzu1MjI/AAAAAAAAA-A/ktX41jq0y9U/s400/wreath8.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Top 10 Movies You Should Not Watch Alone</title>
		<link>http://dangerouslee.biz/2012/08/02/top-10-movies-you-should-not-watch-alone/</link>
		<comments>http://dangerouslee.biz/2012/08/02/top-10-movies-you-should-not-watch-alone/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2012 14:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dangerous Lee</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Guest Bloggers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Movie Theatre]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alfred Hitchcock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[arts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dish Network]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[John Cusack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lord of the Flies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sunshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Texas Chainsaw Massacre]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Ring (1927 film)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[William Golding]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dangerouslee.biz/?p=13707</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Considering watching a movie tonight? Well, you’d do well to avoid these movies! At the very least, call a friend over, stat! The Birds: We start with a classic. Alfred Hitchcock pretty much outdid himself with this scary movie, which although is pretty old compared to the rest of the movies in the list, still [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=13707&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://dangerouslee.biz/2012/08/02/top-10-movies-you-should-not-watch-alone/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://dangerouslee.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/the-exorcist-73209.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://dangerouslee.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/the-exorcist-73209.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">the-exorcist</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/b88af3439a6a9afce43a7a3901285041?s=96&#38;d=monsterid&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Dangerous Lee</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dangerouslee.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/the-exorcist-73209.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">the-exorcist</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Home of the Classics: Athens, Greece</title>
		<link>http://absoluteambrosia.wordpress.com/2012/08/02/home-of-the-classics-athens-greece/</link>
		<comments>http://absoluteambrosia.wordpress.com/2012/08/02/home-of-the-classics-athens-greece/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2012 21:32:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Absolute_Ambrosia</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Acropolis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Athens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Greece]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Moussaka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ocotopus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Slwo Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://absoluteambrosia.wordpress.com/?p=1337</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Greece gets all of the oohs and ahs when I share my travels, and with good reason. Athens acted as the take off point where our Boston flight connected to our Tel-Aviv flight so my time there was a bit segmented. Despite our time limit  Shann and I were able to visit the Acropolis, a [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1337&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;">Greece gets all of the <em>oohs</em> and <em>ahs</em> when I share my travels, and with good reason. Athens acted as the take off point where our Boston flight connected to our Tel-Aviv flight so my time there was a bit segmented.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://absoluteambrosia.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/athens8.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1345" title="Athens8" src="http://absoluteambrosia.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/athens8.jpg" alt="" width="480" height="270" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">Despite our time limit  Shann and I were able to visit the Acropolis, a rocky hill on which the Parthenon is located. Like the astounding view from the Acropolis, the Parthenon, the Theater of Dionysus, and the Erechtheion were beyond impressive.</p>
<p><a href="http://absoluteambrosia.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/athens6.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1343" title="Athens6" src="http://absoluteambrosia.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/athens6.jpg" alt="" width="480" height="270" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://absoluteambrosia.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/athens11.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1348" title="athens11" src="http://absoluteambrosia.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/athens11.jpg" alt="" width="480" height="350" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">Some time during our few hours in the city we visited the main market in Plaka, the city center of Athens. The market was relatively small but boasted the best (and least smelly) collection of pristine seafood I&#8217;ve ever seen.  Red mullet, sardines, octopus, sea urchins, clams, mussels, squid and a cornucopia of other creatures were splayed on beds of ice mounted in front of prideful vendors. As if the Mediterranean seafood was not enough, the nuts, legumes, lentils and dried fruit proved why the Greek diet is considered one of the best in the world.</p>
<div id="attachment_1340" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 490px"><a href="http://absoluteambrosia.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/athens3.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1340" title="Athens3" src="http://absoluteambrosia.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/athens3.jpg" alt="" width="480" height="270" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Along with all of the seafood, pig hooves and whole rabbits were also being auctioned off with great excitement.</p></div>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://absoluteambrosia.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/athens4.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1341" title="Athens4" src="http://absoluteambrosia.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/athens4.jpg" alt="" width="480" height="335" /></a><a href="http://absoluteambrosia.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/athens2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1339" title="Athens2" src="http://absoluteambrosia.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/athens2.jpg" alt="" width="480" height="270" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://absoluteambrosia.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dsc06688.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1349" title="DSC06688" src="http://absoluteambrosia.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dsc06688.jpg" alt="" width="480" height="314" /></a>After some trekking we were ready to eat so we headed back to a tall staircase that was nestled between more taverns and cafes than anyone could imagine. There we ate at Sissifo&#8217;s Tavern and were not at all disappointed. To quiet our stomachs that were still sour from the thought of airplane food, we indulged in grilled octopus (a local specialty), eggplant stuffed with soft cheese and basil, vine leaves in a lemon sauce and boiled wild greens drenched in extra virgin olive oil topped off with crusty bread and a couple glasses of the house red.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://absoluteambrosia.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/athens5.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1342" title="Athens5" src="http://absoluteambrosia.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/athens5.jpg" alt="" width="480" height="270" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">Aside from the food,  Athens did not strike me as memorable until I spent the night. With the mass amounts of tourists, the daylight hours felt a bit artificial. After dark the artificial Athens dissolved into the beauty we found roaming the back allies hoping to stumble upon a quality spot to get drinks and dinner with the locals. Quickly I found myself wishing we had more time in the city.</p>
<div id="attachment_1347" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 490px"><a href="http://absoluteambrosia.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/athens10.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1347" title="athens10" src="http://absoluteambrosia.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/athens10.jpg" alt="" width="480" height="270" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The heat of summer in Athens is intense, but makes for a perfect place to grow just about anything.</p></div>
<p style="text-align:center;">It was then, our only night in Athens, that I tried Moussaka, a Greek specialty with some serious competition behind it. Moussaka is a compilation of  fried eggplant and ground meat topped with a fluffy Bechamel sauce. Each tavern claims they make the best Moussaka, and each time all you can do is smile, nod and tell them you&#8217;d like to judge for yourself. The Moussaka we had in Athens was the only Moussaka we ate, but I bet it was just as they said it was; <em>easily the best in all of Athens. </em></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://absoluteambrosia.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/athens9.jpg"><img title="Athens9" src="http://absoluteambrosia.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/athens9.jpg?w=480&h=270" alt="" width="480" height="270" /></a>There is more of Greece, both islands of Santorini (Thira) and Crete, to come!</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://absoluteambrosia.wordpress.com/category/europe/'>Europe</a>, <a href='http://absoluteambrosia.wordpress.com/category/ideas/'>Ideas</a>, <a href='http://absoluteambrosia.wordpress.com/category/travel/'>Travel</a> Tagged: <a href='http://absoluteambrosia.wordpress.com/tag/acropolis/'>Acropolis</a>, <a href='http://absoluteambrosia.wordpress.com/tag/athens/'>Athens</a>, <a href='http://absoluteambrosia.wordpress.com/tag/greece/'>Greece</a>, <a href='http://absoluteambrosia.wordpress.com/tag/moussaka/'>Moussaka</a>, <a href='http://absoluteambrosia.wordpress.com/tag/ocotopus/'>Ocotopus</a>, <a href='http://absoluteambrosia.wordpress.com/tag/slwo-food/'>Slwo Food</a>, <a href='http://absoluteambrosia.wordpress.com/tag/travel-2/'>travel</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1337/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1337/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1337&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://absoluteambrosia.wordpress.com/2012/08/02/home-of-the-classics-athens-greece/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c5cffa57579da60680cfa755bdde82fb?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">absoluteambrosia</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://absoluteambrosia.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/athens8.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Athens8</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://absoluteambrosia.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/athens6.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Athens6</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://absoluteambrosia.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/athens11.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">athens11</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://absoluteambrosia.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/athens3.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Athens3</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://absoluteambrosia.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/athens4.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Athens4</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://absoluteambrosia.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/athens2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Athens2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://absoluteambrosia.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dsc06688.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC06688</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://absoluteambrosia.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/athens5.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Athens5</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://absoluteambrosia.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/athens10.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">athens10</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://absoluteambrosia.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/athens9.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Athens9</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What helps you write?</title>
		<link>http://gwynncompton.wordpress.com/2012/08/02/what-helps-you-write/</link>
		<comments>http://gwynncompton.wordpress.com/2012/08/02/what-helps-you-write/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2012 14:15:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>gwynncompton</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cinema]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Creativity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[literature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[soundtracks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[walking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writer's block]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://gwynncompton.wordpress.com/?p=202</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Writers often talk about being &#8220;in the mood&#8221; to write. Whether it&#8217;s a mood, zone, state of mind or whatever you want to call it, trying to stimulate your creativity is a key part of writing. While there&#8217;s no cure for Writer&#8217;s Block that I&#8217;ve encountered, I have found there are things that help keep [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=202&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://gwynncompton.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/vines.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-203" title="vines" src="http://gwynncompton.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/vines.jpg" alt="" width="470" height="705" /></a><br />
Writers often talk about being &#8220;in the mood&#8221; to write. Whether it&#8217;s a mood, zone, state of mind or whatever you want to call it, trying to stimulate your creativity is a key part of writing. While there&#8217;s no cure for Writer&#8217;s Block that I&#8217;ve encountered, I have found there are things that help keep me focused on a project, especially when I get some momentum going.</p>
<p><strong><em>Music</em><br />
</strong>Listening to music, especially classical music or original film scores, always tends to transport me away from where I&#8217;m sitting and into the world of my characters. I do have to be careful though, if I end up listening to the scores from Star Wars or Doctor Who I&#8217;ll start to write in a style more similar to those stories. So instead I try to listen to music that doesn&#8217;t have a distinctive sound to it, even if it is a film score. Steve Jablonsky&#8217;s score to the Transformers films and Two Steps From Hell&#8217;s positional music are two great examples. Despite being attached to the Transformers franchise, Jablonsky&#8217;s score isn&#8217;t as iconic as something like the Imperial March from Star Wars. Yet it&#8217;s still a great soundtrack that tells a sweeping, action packed story. Whereas Two Steps From Hell are permanently stuck in epic gear. You&#8217;ve likely heard their music before as it&#8217;s heavily used in film and game trailers, as well as in reality TV shows when they want to artificially build drama.</p>
<p><strong><em>Walking</em><br />
</strong>I don&#8217;t mean just walking around the block, I mean go walking somewhere beautiful. Back in Wellington I loved going to Khandallah Park, or to the Zealandia Wildlife Sanctuary back in Wellington. Both were idyllic settings where you could get away from the usual hustle and bustle of the real world. In Melbourne I struggled a bit more, purely because of how built up Melbourne is, but the Yarra River Trail or a walk around Albert Park managed to suffice when I could make it to them. However London is a different beast. I haven&#8217;t found anywhere yet that feels like you&#8217;re able to get away from the crowds. Even at Battersea Park where I go running most days, there&#8217;s still enough people there to make it feel busy. And that sort of thing does suck my creativity dry. And there&#8217;s only so long you can sit at home listening to inspiring music before you need a different stimulus. Being able to break it up by swapping your surroundings and working through your ideas is something used in a lot of creative endeavours.</p>
<p><em><strong>Go to the</strong></em><strong> movies</strong><strong><br />
</strong>Admittedly this is something I need to do more of. I find that the way movies are designed to overwhelm your senses through sight and sound can help to spark a creative energy. You realise that this was someone&#8217;s idea, someone elses story, and it&#8217;s been turned into an amazing piece of cinema. Well you hope it has been anyway, I mean it could be a disaster of a movie&#8230; then you&#8217;d be thinking about the poor wretch of a writer who has just seen their dream destroyed. But let&#8217;s not try to think about that. Having recently seen Prometheus and The Dark Knight Rises, I can assure you that both left me feeling inspired and ready to get to work on my writing.</p>
<p>So what do you use to be inspired, to get your head in a creative space and keep it there?</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/202/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/202/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=202&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://gwynncompton.wordpress.com/2012/08/02/what-helps-you-write/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/b50b3d260a7f8964e7e9fd8bff882965?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gwynncompton</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gwynncompton.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/vines.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">vines</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Amazing Homemade Pickles in 3 Days!</title>
		<link>http://thenotsosupermama.com/2012/08/02/amazing-homemade-pickles-in-3-days/</link>
		<comments>http://thenotsosupermama.com/2012/08/02/amazing-homemade-pickles-in-3-days/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2012 20:38:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>heathersegars</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[canning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[homemade]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pickles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recipe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[snack]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thenotsosupermama.com/?p=1160</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Yes, you read right.  3 days!  I LOVE pickles.  My last pregnancy I ate an entire jar of pickles and a pint of ice cream for dinner on more than one occasion.  When they are small and crisp and a bit of spice to them- WOW!  But, I never thought of making them myself.  It [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1160&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://thenotsosupermama.com/2012/08/02/amazing-homemade-pickles-in-3-days/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>22</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/540ec79e706e7aa39733d2c3154e9c31?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">heathersegars</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thenotsosupermama.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/pickles.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">pickles</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thenotsosupermama.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_7740.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_7740</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thenotsosupermama.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_77341.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_7734</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The boy who gave me the middle finger</title>
		<link>http://saddlebackmountainfarm.wordpress.com/2012/08/02/the-boy-who-gave-me-the-middle-finger/</link>
		<comments>http://saddlebackmountainfarm.wordpress.com/2012/08/02/the-boy-who-gave-me-the-middle-finger/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2012 21:09:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>small farms matter big</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[farm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[homesteading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thinking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[farmers market]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[small farm]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://saddlebackmountainfarm.wordpress.com/?p=247</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Recently at one of the farmers markets I sell at, a woman and a teenage boy approached my stand, paused for a moment to whisper  together, and then stepped forward. The boy was maybe seventeen, the woman in her mid-sixties.  I couldn’t place their relationship. The boy spoke for them, and he was shy. “We [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=247&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://saddlebackmountainfarm.wordpress.com/2012/08/02/the-boy-who-gave-me-the-middle-finger/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>27</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a8b6f2f175f751f6fb3402d42e3445eb?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">saddlebackmountainfarm</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sunday Doodle</title>
		<link>http://bluepaperlantern.wordpress.com/2012/07/22/sunday-doodle/</link>
		<comments>http://bluepaperlantern.wordpress.com/2012/07/22/sunday-doodle/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2012 05:01:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Maeve</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ballet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coffee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[doodle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flower]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[graphic design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ipad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pointe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sketch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sunday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weekend]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://bluepaperlantern.wordpress.com/?p=2939</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As all great Sundays are spent, I spent most of mine on the couch, doodling on the iPad. It really is quite convenient when you don&#8217;t want to get up and grab all of you materials, sharpen pencils, and all that jazz. So basically, it&#8217;s really quite convenient when you&#8217;re lazy. But today, some great stuff [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2939&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://bluepaperlantern.wordpress.com/2012/07/22/sunday-doodle/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>51</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://bluepaperlantern.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/untitled-artwork-2012-07-22-09-29-00-946-pm.jpg?w=110" />
		<media:content url="http://bluepaperlantern.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/untitled-artwork-2012-07-22-09-29-00-946-pm.jpg?w=110" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Untitled artwork 2012-07-22 (09.29.00-946 PM)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/9f4d5a8fa91aa4b68709d59cf03eb1fa?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mobriant0</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://bluepaperlantern.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/untitled-artwork-2012-07-22-07-37-09-579-pm.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Untitled artwork 2012-07-22 (07.37.09-579 PM)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://bluepaperlantern.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/untitled-artwork-2012-07-22-12-33-08-658-pm1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Untitled artwork 2012-07-22 (12.33.08-658 PM)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://bluepaperlantern.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/untitled-artwork-2012-07-22-07-50-51-655-pm.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Untitled artwork 2012-07-22 (07.50.51-655 PM)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://bluepaperlantern.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/untitled-artwork-2012-07-22-08-38-09-146-pm.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Untitled artwork 2012-07-22 (08.38.09-146 PM)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://bluepaperlantern.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/untitled-artwork-2012-07-22-07-36-16-202-pm.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Untitled artwork 2012-07-22 (07.36.16-202 PM)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://bluepaperlantern.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/untitled-artwork-2012-07-22-09-29-00-946-pm.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Untitled artwork 2012-07-22 (09.29.00-946 PM)</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Turning Pages: A Confession of Paperback Abuse</title>
		<link>http://writervsworld.wordpress.com/2012/08/02/turning-pages-a-confession-of-paperback-abuse/</link>
		<comments>http://writervsworld.wordpress.com/2012/08/02/turning-pages-a-confession-of-paperback-abuse/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2012 21:15:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Writer</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[E-readers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kindle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kindle Fire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Swiping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Traveling]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://writervsworld.wordpress.com/?p=139</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Something really scary happened the other day. I was sitting, reading a wonderful book (not on an E-reader) and I tried to turn the page by swiping. I am ashamed to admit it, doubly so as an English Major. But, like all sins, one must purge herself in order to be considered clean (I&#8217;m not [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=139&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_144" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 308px"><a href="http://writervsworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/books.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-144" title="A glorious shelf of books" src="http://writervsworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/books.jpg?w=298&h=300" alt="" width="298" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">A glorious shelf of books (found on Google Images)</p></div>
<p>Something really scary happened the other day. I was sitting, reading a wonderful book (not on an E-reader) and I tried to turn the page by swiping. I am ashamed to admit it, doubly so as an English Major. But, like all sins, one must purge herself in order to be considered clean (I&#8217;m not sure where this religious theme is coming from, but we&#8217;ll roll with it).</p>
<p>For the longest time I was anti E-reader. There is just something wonderful about handling a book. It enhances the reading experience. There&#8217;s nothing like the smell of a new book or the crack the spine makes as you open it, taking notes in the margins or dog-earing the pages to mark your spot. You can&#8217;t get that with an E-reader.</p>
<p>Plus, it connects us to the past. The invention of the printing press and the subsequent ability to mass produce books is such a rich and important part of human history. Taking away a book is like taking away handwriting in cursive (We&#8217;ll leave that one for another post).</p>
<p>And then&#8230;I moved out of my parents&#8217; house. Prepping for the move, I got rid of TONS of books because there was no space for them in my new apartment.  I kept those that were most precious and either boxed them up or took them with me. It was only then that I finally conceded to the idea of an E-reader.</p>
<p>For Christmas, I got the new Kindle Fire™. I instantly downloaded tons of free classics with the goal of filling in the holes of my literary repertoire. Since then, I have happily jumped back and forth between book and Kindle.</p>
<p>The Kindle is great for the gym because it lays flat and I can increase the font size while I ellipticate (yes I made that word up). It&#8217;s also perfect for vacations because I don&#8217;t have to try to pack enough books to keep me occupied. I am a <span style="text-decoration:underline;">voracious</span> reader. On my last vacation, I read 4.5 books in 8 days. And that does not mean I skimmed or did not take the time to enjoy each one. I read all day long at the beach and before I fell asleep at night. (Note: The Kindle Fire is hard to see in the sunlight.)</p>
<p>But, when book and Kindle merged in my subconscious and I swiped my finger across the paper page of a real book, I had to pause. Such an action is a repudiation of all my training and my passions. I have become a hypocrite, a practitioner of convenience. I have rejected one of the things I hold most dear: the book. And I want to be a published author. How embarrassing.</p>
<p>And so, now that I have confessed my sin to you, dear reader, it&#8217;s time for redemption. I think the only way to redeem myself is to go to a book store and buy 5 books. Now THAT&#8217;S a punishment I can live with! So this weekend, I will be spending a good portion of Saturday walking the stacks at a local bookstore and begging my beloved friends for their forgiveness.</p>
<p>Thank you for listening.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/139/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/139/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=139&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://writervsworld.wordpress.com/2012/08/02/turning-pages-a-confession-of-paperback-abuse/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>114</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/74907b00192a47260899eff9b6011bb0?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">booksinprint</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://writervsworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/books.jpg?w=298" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">A glorious shelf of books</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>