<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2012 22:02:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>The Band Scar</title>
		<link>http://moderngeorgeandmary.com/2012/09/09/bandscar/</link>
		<comments>http://moderngeorgeandmary.com/2012/09/09/bandscar/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2012 17:05:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>moderngeorgeandmary</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Main]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[band]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[couples]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grief]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[motherhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mothering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Norman Rockwell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parethood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[regrets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trumpet]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://moderngeorgeandmary.com/?p=247</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[When I was a younger woman, I used to relish the time in a relationship when I collected my paramour’s scar stories. I would lightly trace the scars on hands, feet, arms, legs and coyly inquire where they had come from, how they were acquired. Those physical scars always seemed to lead to a discussion [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=247&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When I was a younger woman, I used to relish the time in a relationship when I collected my paramour’s scar stories. I would lightly trace the scars on hands, feet, arms, legs and coyly inquire where they had come from, how they were acquired.<a href="http://moderngeorgeandmary.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/band-aid-retro.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-248" title="band aid retro" src="http://moderngeorgeandmary.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/band-aid-retro.jpg" alt="" width="320" height="320" /></a></p>
<p>Those physical scars always seemed to lead to a discussion ripe with the knowledge I was really after – what their emotional scars were and where they hid. As a naïve, infatuated young adult, these were scars I mistakenly thought I could help heal.</p>
<p>Of course, I know all of Mr. Bailey’s scars now. Being a bit clumsy, he’s got a number of them. When we were first married, they all represented adventures or amusing stories he had before me. Now, a good number of the scars represent shared memories – a gash on his wrist a week before our second Christmas together, slightly raised bumps across his broad knuckles from accidentally punching a hole in our ceiling, celebrating our team winning a trip to the Super Bowl.</p>
<p>After so much in-utero anxiety about their health, the first time they laid my pink and perfect babies in my arms, I cried over their unblemished skin, tears I hoped would bless and protect them from any harm.</p>
<p>I remember the moment Prima received the cut that is now a straight, slim two-inch scar on the front of her left hand. I think of that moment every time I catch sight of the scar.</p>
<p>But what really keeps me up at night is the mental gymnastics I do pondering where and how Prima’s and Secondo’s emotional scars will bloom. As any good parent does, I contemplate my role in creating them, which, let’s be honest, always pertains.</p>
<p>Prima and Secondo have already experienced the death of two grandparents, before the</p>
<div id="attachment_249" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 285px"><a href="http://moderngeorgeandmary.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/bloom-finding-beauty-skinned-knees.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-249" title="Bloom finding beauty skinned knees" src="http://moderngeorgeandmary.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/bloom-finding-beauty-skinned-knees.jpg" alt="" width="275" height="183" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Photo by Kelly Hampton, from the blog, Enjoying the Small Things, www.kellyhampton.com</p></div>
<p>age of 10. A grandfather before Secondo was born, so the scars carried there belong to Mr. Bailey and I; a grandmother just a year ago. For a year, they only rarely spoke of her keen love for her granddaughters, her sparkling smile, the way she made them feel better when they were sick and handwrote thank you notes praising them for small kindnesses they had offered her. But since that year has slipped by in a confusing fog, they’ve begun to ask me to tell them stories, and to explain again why they lost her.</p>
<p>They’ve also lost a teacher, two great-grandparents, and two great uncles, in some cases, quite suddenly.</p>
<p>So I am aware of those scars and try my mother-bear best to prevent smaller losses – friends or routines or cherished playthings – from causing further damage.</p>
<p>Recently, Prima came home from school in an absolute fervor. The band teacher had <a href="http://moderngeorgeandmary.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/playing-trumpet.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-250" title="Playing trumpet" src="http://moderngeorgeandmary.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/playing-trumpet.jpg" alt="" width="365" height="430" /></a>visited the classroom and she was now on fire to join the band and play the trumpet. Having paid for guitar lessons over the summer that seemed to go well but resulted in a distain for practicing and an interest in a thousand other activities, we were less than enthusiastic. Then we took a look at the costs, and the other activities she was already committed to, we decided to postpone the band for another day.</p>
<p>Prima was completely devastated. There were tears, gnashing of teeth, casting of stones, spasmodic jumping up and down and sad faces for days. Her big brown eyes became orbs of betrayal when she expertly cast them upon us, welling.</p>
<p>I calculated how deep this cut would be. I worried it would result in a lifelong scar. I hoped the band scar might be treated with the happy moments we were also providing: birthday parties! Soccer games! Specialized tutoring! A study hall with her teacher while the other kids were at band! Not so much.</p>
<p>But then, the tide of tears seemed to stem and Prima once again found her happy place. She’s a pleasant child by nature, and I breathed a sigh of relief.</p>
<p>Several days later, I was tucking her and Secondo into their bunk beds. We said our nightly prayer and then I asked each child to tell me who they wanted to pray for. Prima mentioned family and friends, then paused.</p>
<p>“I also want to pray for all of the children who want to do band but their parents won’t let them,” she intoned, reverently.</p>
<p>The dim night light shielded my shocked face as I managed to choke out, “OK. Secondo! Who do you want to pray for?”</p>
<p>So, chalk up another scar. It’s clearly not the first, and certainly not the last.</p>
<p>But maybe, (I can dream) it might be the worst for a little awhile.</p>
<div id="attachment_251" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 360px"><a href="http://moderngeorgeandmary.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/trumpet-playing-boy-norman-rockwell.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-251" title="trumpet playing boy  norman rockwell" src="http://moderngeorgeandmary.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/trumpet-playing-boy-norman-rockwell.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="377" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">You won&#8217;t find this scene in the Bailey household these days, much to Prima&#8217;s chagrin.</p></div>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/247/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/247/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=247&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://moderngeorgeandmary.com/2012/09/09/bandscar/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f17af23f7fe2dd9dc9ed6d5da2ba71ab?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">moderngeorgeandmary</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://moderngeorgeandmary.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/band-aid-retro.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">band aid retro</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://moderngeorgeandmary.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/bloom-finding-beauty-skinned-knees.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Bloom finding beauty skinned knees</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://moderngeorgeandmary.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/playing-trumpet.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Playing trumpet</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://moderngeorgeandmary.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/trumpet-playing-boy-norman-rockwell.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">trumpet playing boy  norman rockwell</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Redefining \&#8221;Alive\&#8221;</title>
		<link>http://makingchampagne.wordpress.com/2012/09/08/defining/</link>
		<comments>http://makingchampagne.wordpress.com/2012/09/08/defining/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2012 21:34:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bardlj</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[etymology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[linguistics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[philosophy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[words]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://makingchampagne.wordpress.com/?p=186</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There&#8217;s a word I&#8217;m looking for: Alive. It&#8217;s a word somebody said to me once, maybe two. Two syllables, just two meaningless exhalations of breath. Two notes of this language that can be played minor and major, but never intentionally—it seems to break little differently upon the ears of each person. “Alive”—say it to yourself [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=186&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There&#8217;s a word I&#8217;m looking for: Alive.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a word somebody said to me once, maybe two. Two syllables, just two meaningless exhalations of breath. Two notes of this language that can be played minor and major, but never intentionally—it seems to break little differently upon the ears of each person.</p>
<p>“Alive”—say it to yourself now, whisper it, feel it on your lips, your tongue, taste what you hear it to be. Alive. Mouth it if prying ears are seated too close, this is for you.</p>
<p>Alive.</p>
<p>Alive means breathing. Alive means thinking. Alive means excitement. Alive means wasteless, Alive means untapped discovery. Alive means pain, that pit that gathers in your gut when you have to choose. Alive means a world, you know, the one you sense, at least sometimes. Alive means something beyond you, something you can see, feel, touch, love.</p>
<p>This is<em> everyone&#8217;s </em>“Alive”</p>
<p>But what do all those words mean? Not Alive? Alive?</p>
<p>It&#8217;s just a word now. Alive. A-live. Alive doesn&#8217;t mean Alive any more. Alive is too broad. If Alive means everything, it&#8217;s useless. What do you hear when I say it?</p>
<p>Here—“Alive”. What did you hear? Alive? How about Alive? I didn&#8217;t hear Alive, I just heard Alive. When I hear Alive as Alive, and you hear Alive as Alive, what does Alive mean anymore? Everything, conceivably, or nothing, if you prefer. Meaningless, I say. Just a word, two syllables, five letters, a word. Just Alive, whatever that means.</p>
<p>Alive means happy. Alive means cake. Alive means drying paint. Alive means Zip-Lock. Alive means pre-cooked. Alive means strawberry. Alive means kiss. Alive means kidney cancer. Alive means stale marker tips, left out to dry. Alive means Alive. Say it again—Alive.</p>
<p>What does it mean when I say that word now?</p>
<p>“Alive”. What do you taste?</p>
<p>A – the start, the beginning, a letter.</p>
<p>L – another.</p>
<p>I – self, yet nothing. A piece, and the only perceivable whole. Both, more. Nothing.</p>
<p>V – a symbol, a letter rarely spoken alone. V. A name. V. Twenty-two.</p>
<p>E – the silent helper, a noise, shriek, just another, just more often, you know, statistically.</p>
<p>Alive. What does it mean now? Letters? Noises, sound? Say it again. Alive. Do you taste it anymore, or does it fade like the after-fear of struck lightening. There was something, there was power, but now? Just the shakes and memories half-forgotten in seconds.</p>
<p>Alive. Hear the shock, the crash? Hear anything?</p>
<p>Alive. Does that even mean “word” anymore, or is it just, you know—</p>
<p>Alive?</p>
<p>It&#8217;s nothing now, Alive. Just. Alive. And that&#8217;s it, isn&#8217;t it. Let me say it again:</p>
<p>“Alive”.</p>
<p>Here comes the fear. If Alive is just Alive, what does anything mean? If one word can fail, where lies the stability of words? Just empty promises, right? Just Alive.</p>
<p>Alive is lying there, lost in a sort of singularity. Lost in Alive. Alive means losing meaning. What did I tell you about things outside of time, outside of Alive, our Alive? They pause, sort of, suspended of rules, laws, definitions. Alive just means Alive here, and that&#8217;s all it needs to mean. Rejoice, we have brought Alive back to a stable nothingness, just—</p>
<p>Alive.</p>
<p>But now, when I say the word Alive, it still means something, doesn&#8217;t it, at least to you. Alive can mean everything and nothing to everyone else, its outrageous, meaningless nature clear. But it still means something in your reality, doesn&#8217;t it?</p>
<p>What if I were to tell you that to invoke the meaningless sounds and letters that make up Alive is to burst the singularity, just for a moment, and in that moment, your Alive is Alive, whatever you decide Alive means. Just, Alive. You say it, and despite what I taste, it only means what Alive means to you in that timeless snapshot moment. As the color fades into the next moment, Alive becomes a singularity once more, a well of nothingness until I say it.</p>
<p>“Alive”. I taste that soft contentment just behind the glow of eyes, maybe yours, lost in a singularity of its own—a moment without time and rules, taking place during that stall between the clock&#8217;s next tick. Just warmth, just mystery, just understanding, just love, just a heartbeat, two, all at the same moment. A glow of pure yellow flowing into being through endless words, endless letters, syllables. Endless Alives.</p>
<p>This is the moment of Prestige. You see the Alive I have put out before you. With all your mind, you have recreated my Alive in yours. But it&#8217;s still not your Alive, not quite. But it&#8217;s the only real Alive in this moment.</p>
<p>When each of us says Alive, we create new meanings for Alive, meanings wiped clean immediately after, save what we see them as. “Alive” may fail in giving me the sure taste of your Alive, and you the taste of mine, but that becomes no longer the point, see?</p>
<p>“Alive” is for the one who said it, them only. The magic comes from the beauty that “Alive” really creates an Alive somewhere. Words, letters, sounds, all just ways of building every Alive. I can spell Alive as Comfort, or Smile, or Persistence, or Dlksj. It&#8217;s still means exactly what I what I wanted it to taste like, regardless of what it means to you.</p>
<p>You can show me Alive, film an Alive, draw an Alive, sing an Alive, play an Alive, but until I see Alive come to life in your eyes, Alive has been robbed of its full potential for you.</p>
<p>Say it one more time, loud enough for me to hear.</p>
<p>Alive. Say it with me.</p>
<p>“Alive”. Do you taste it? Did your Alive come Alive, so to say?</p>
<p>Alive.</p>
<p>Alive.</p>
<p>Alive!</p>
<p><a href="http://makingchampagne.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/idea.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-191" title="exactly" src="http://makingchampagne.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/idea.jpg" alt="" width="420" height="299" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/186/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/186/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=186&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://makingchampagne.wordpress.com/2012/09/08/defining/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>27</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/e0b8aa7343fa06ca3e5d358a16fff8b9?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bardlj</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://makingchampagne.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/idea.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">exactly</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The End of Brand Exceptionalism?</title>
		<link>http://ideationz.me/2012/09/08/the-end-of-brand-exceptionalism/</link>
		<comments>http://ideationz.me/2012/09/08/the-end-of-brand-exceptionalism/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2012 01:49:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Rick Pulito</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Branding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Change]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Consumerism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Creative Process]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Innovation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[branding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exceptional]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exceptionalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[future]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gen Y]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ideationz.me/?p=1382</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The idea has been mounting within me for months, that the age of exceptionalism as an objective has ebbed, to be replaced with a far different value. The adage, “build a better mousetrap and the world will beat a path to your door” is no longer relevant. In fact, not only is an exceptional product or [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1382&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://ideationz.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/exceptional3.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1383" title="exceptional3" src="http://ideationz.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/exceptional3.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="374" /></a></p>
<p>The idea has been mounting within me for months, that the age of exceptionalism as an objective has ebbed, to be replaced with a far different value. The adage, “build a better mousetrap and the world will beat a path to your door” is no longer relevant. In fact, not only is an exceptional product or service unnecessary, it may be a detriment, an impediment to market acceptance.</p>
<p>For those who built careers defining progress in measures of efficiency, productivity, reliability, accuracy, or alternative metrics of similar ilk, the realization that these values are of declining import is hard to grasp, let alone accept. In their place, we often find that with globalization comes a lowering of the standard that defines excellence. In many instances, the bar has been eliminated. It is no longer about bringing a better product to market, it is all about creating more, louder, longer lasting and far-reaching buzz.</p>
<p>I saw this coming years ago, when I was cutting my teeth in the music business. The migration from analog to the far more convenient (if sonically inferior) digital format, and with it the continual dumbing-down of sound quality was one bellwether. Portability trumped the desire to hear subtleties and nuances of the recorded sound. The shift continues today.</p>
<p>The explosion of digital media, and the wide-open door that allows anyone with a PC or a Mac to become a “musical artist” brought with it an exponential updraft in content, accessibility and availability. This is true of most art forms, from video to animation to illustration to poetry or prose. The reality is that there are more inspired, creative artists who can seek their audience, but finding them within a rising tide of mediocrity has brought a significant challenge. It is not sufficient to be &#8220;better&#8221;. It is better to be noticed.</p>
<p>So what does this have to do with your brand, your product or your service? In an expanding universe of maudlin and marginal, the truly exceptional become harder to identify, to locate with confidence and certainty. Given that, what do consumers do? They look to each other for guidance. They place trust in lifelines such as “ask the audience” or “phone a friend”.</p>
<p>Visibility is valued above serviceability. Image dwarfs substance. Sharp-edged creativity will shred innovative engineering. The masses will be less concerned that what they consume may be unhealthy for them, forgiving that which is lacking so as to feel a part of a community of users. Sound too harsh to be true?</p>
<p>I read that 40%+ of Gen Y survey respondents said they would live without a car before they would be without an internet connection. What does that tell you about what is important? To be wired to the vagaries of trends supersedes mobility?  That is only one data point, granted. But every picture tells a story, don’t it?</p>
<p>Q: At what moment did you become certain that the age of exceptionalism was ending?<br />
A: The first time I heard the term, “famous for being famous.”</p>
<p>This is a topic for a book, not a blog post. But it is important to think about what message you are conveying…what really matters to your consumer…on what basis you relate to your market… It isn’t about “new and improved” anymore. It’s about being “liked” and that means that your brand has to make others feel “liked” as a result of associating with you. In a future post, we will undertake the question, “can being exceptional in 2012 spell doom for your product?” Food for thought. Would love to hear what you have to say on the subject.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1382/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1382/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1382&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://ideationz.me/2012/09/08/the-end-of-brand-exceptionalism/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>64</slash:comments>
		<georss:point>44.864900 -93.361000</georss:point>
		<geo:lat>44.864900</geo:lat>
		<geo:long>-93.361000</geo:long>
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/b9a1208fd6d64f2a14ac873df063a1a8?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">rickpulito</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ideationz.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/exceptional3.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">exceptional3</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lessons Learned From a 9/11 Survivor</title>
		<link>http://nittygrittydirtman.wordpress.com/2012/09/09/lessons-learned-from-a-911-survivor/</link>
		<comments>http://nittygrittydirtman.wordpress.com/2012/09/09/lessons-learned-from-a-911-survivor/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2012 18:49:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Kevin</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Inspiration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nitty Gritty Dirt Man]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Palms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[September 11]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inspiration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nitty gritty dirt man]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[palms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[september 11]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nittygrittydirtman.wordpress.com/?p=4217</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[September 8th was Joe’s birthday, and we headed into NYC to celebrate.  We did the same thing eleven years ago, and on that particular day, the air had the first hints of autumn crispness. We commented all day how especially blue the sky appeared, and how clearly we could see all of the buildings. Three [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4217&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://nittygrittydirtman.wordpress.com/2012/09/09/lessons-learned-from-a-911-survivor/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>146</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/d39cd4611c1052f7526666111dbc60a6?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">santakev</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nittygrittydirtman.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_1581.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">9/11 Memorial</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nittygrittydirtman.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_1583.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Freedom Tower</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nittygrittydirtman.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_1586.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Kevin Donnelly</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nittygrittydirtman.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_1582.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">9/11 Memorial</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nittygrittydirtman.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_1585.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Survivor Tree</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nittygrittydirtman.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_1591.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The Palm Court</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Creating Our Universe</title>
		<link>http://jeffhirz.wordpress.com/2012/09/09/creating-our-universe/</link>
		<comments>http://jeffhirz.wordpress.com/2012/09/09/creating-our-universe/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2012 17:59:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jeff Hirz</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[philosophy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[experience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[happiness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[running]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the tao of pooh]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://jeffhirz.wordpress.com/?p=1598</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[We learn from an early age how to create the world around us. We learn labels, we learn definitions, we learn classifications, sub-classifications and distinctions. A toddler learns that a tree is called a tree, a cloud is called a cloud, and Mama and Dada are called Mom and Dad. An adolescent learns the difference [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1598&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We learn from an early age how to create the world around us. We learn labels, we learn definitions, we learn classifications, sub-classifications and distinctions. A toddler learns that a tree is called a tree, a cloud is called a cloud, and Mama and Dada are called Mom and Dad. An adolescent learns the difference between rich and poor, strong and weak, nice and mean. An adult learns what class warfare is, what God is, and what antidisestablishmentarianism could possibly mean.</p>
<p>But at what point does this really continue to benefit us?</p>
<h2>the death of the senses</h2>
<p>There is an economic principle called the law of diminishing returns. It means, in terms that I can understand, that the more we continue to invest in something, the less we get out of it (see Wikipedia for a MUCH more accurate definition). A marathoner plodding along an 18-week training regimen sees more marked improvement in the early stages of training than in the later stages. Early on, his average race pace may drop from nine-minute miles to eight-minute miles in the space of just a few determined weeks, while in the last few weeks of high-intensity training he will see much less of an improvement than that. Granted, it&#8217;s still marked improvement, but the point stands: the return isn&#8217;t as great.</p>
<p>So how does this apply to labels? To definitions? To distinctions? How do we measure returns on something like learning? The truth is, most people don&#8217;t even try. Learning is a wonderful thing &#8211; I believe lifelong learning should be a cornerstone of everyone&#8217;s daily experience. But after a point in the learning process &#8211; for most of us, in our teenage years &#8211; it becomes easy to lose sight of true value. So if we really tried measuring the returns on learning, we&#8217;d realize that there are things that are more important. Thus, we accrue knowledge for the sake of accruing knowledge. We learn what a tree is but then forget to experience the tree. Think about it: when was the last time you touched, <em>and felt</em>, a tree? Felt its bark, listened as its branches swayed in the wind, smelled its leaves? Go outside and touch a tree. Right now. I&#8217;ll wait . . .</p>
<p>Back already? Good. Carrying on. . . as one of my favorite books, <span style="text-decoration:underline;color:#0000ff;"><strong><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Way-Peaceful-Warrior-Changes-Lives/dp/0915811898"><span style="color:#0000ff;text-decoration:underline;">The Way of the Peaceful Warrior</span></a></strong></span>, says, &#8220;The birth of the mind is the death of the senses.&#8221;</p>
<h2>p&#8217;u, the uncarved block</h2>
<p>Moments in life can trigger the resurgence of this child-like appreciation for the world around us:</p>
<ul>
<li>Having a child</li>
<li>A near-death experience</li>
<li>A religious experience</li>
<li>Emerging from an emotional depression</li>
</ul>
<p>But it should be natural (shouldn&#8217;t it?), as human beings gifted with life on this wonderful earth, to consciously appreciate the universe around us during what we deem mundane experience. During the ordinary moments. To appreciate the universe, not necessarily in the form in which we initially created it, but rather through direct experience. To sense directly, without thought, opinion or interpretation. To simply be.</p>
<p>Much like <span style="text-decoration:underline;color:#0000ff;"><strong><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Tao_of_Pooh"><span style="color:#0000ff;text-decoration:underline;">Winnie the Pooh</span></a></strong></span>. Open to, but unburdened by, experience.</p>
<p><a href="http://jeffhirz.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/winnie-the-pooh2.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1610" title="winnie the pooh" src="http://jeffhirz.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/winnie-the-pooh2.png" alt="winnie the pooh, the tao of pooh" width="220" height="229" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1598/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1598/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1598&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://jeffhirz.wordpress.com/2012/09/09/creating-our-universe/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>32</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/87c9bd086c3e40c599cc61af9906fe52?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jeffhirz</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jeffhirz.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/winnie-the-pooh2.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">winnie the pooh</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remembering 9-11</title>
		<link>http://foiegraschick.wordpress.com/2012/09/09/remembering/</link>
		<comments>http://foiegraschick.wordpress.com/2012/09/09/remembering/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2012 00:42:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>foiegraschica</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Manhattan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[9-11]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York City]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[September 11]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twin Towers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Washington Square]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[World Trade Center]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://foiegraschick.wordpress.com/?p=339</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[With Labor Day weekend behind us, routines and activities have come back to their normal hum. Fresh school supplies, a cup of joe before dashing out the door for work, listening to the morning news on the car radio. But in a few days, those routines will be interrupted briefly as we&#8217;re reminded once more [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=339&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://foiegraschick.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/new_york_washington_square_park.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-350" title="new_york_washington_square_park" src="http://foiegraschick.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/new_york_washington_square_park.jpg" alt="" width="529" height="352" /></a></p>
<p>With Labor Day weekend behind us, routines and activities have come back to their normal hum. Fresh school supplies, a cup of joe before dashing out the door for work, listening to the morning news on the car radio. But in a few days, those routines will be interrupted briefly as we&#8217;re reminded once more of the awful tragedy of 9-11.</p>
<p><a href="http://foiegraschick.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/ny-times-2.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-347" title="NY Times 2" src="http://foiegraschick.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/ny-times-2.jpg" alt="" width="529" height="867" /></a></p>
<p>This is my first time writing anything about 9-11. I&#8217;ve often struggled with the words to describe the emotions of that dark day. I was not in the path of the falling towers, and I didn&#8217;t know anyone personally who died in that terrible disaster, but I vividly remember the confusion and uncertainty in the days and months that followed.</p>
<p>I arrived in New York City during the summer of 1994, eager to start college and even more excited at the prospects of living away from home for the first time in a big city. As I walked down from my Fifth Avenue dorm towards the heart of the NYU campus, I could always see the Twin Towers framed by the grand arch in Washington Square.</p>
<p><a href="http://foiegraschick.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/wsq.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-355" title="WSQ" src="http://foiegraschick.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/wsq.jpg?w=400&h=600" alt="" width="400" height="600" /></a></p>
<p>As New York City gradually became my home, the Towers were always part of my geography; they served as a compass of sorts in the days before smartphones were invented&#8211;the Empire State Building was uptown, the Towers were downtown. Events were often held on the plaza at the foot of the soaring Towers; one night I watched office workers dancing to the upbeat sounds of salsa music. When I lived in Brooklyn, it was a habit of mine to gaze at the twinkling lights of downtown as I commuted home and the Q train roared over the Manhattan Bridge; the Towers stood majestically, keeping watch over New York City.</p>
<p><a href="http://foiegraschick.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/twin-towers.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-358" title="Twin Towers" src="http://foiegraschick.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/twin-towers.jpg" alt="" width="529" height="349" /></a></p>
<p>I was student teaching first grade at a school in Chelsea in 2001, and the first few days of school had gone off without a hitch, until one day, when one of my students&#8217; parents arrived at the door to pick up her son soon after the morning started. Whispers were exchanged between her and my cooperating teacher, and Caleb started to collect his things to go home. Within the next hour, more parents arrived to pick up their children. I was told that there was an explosion at the World Trade Center, but I also remembered the 1993 bombing while in high school and, like the jaded New Yorker I was becoming, didn&#8217;t think much of it at first. When I was told the Towers were gone, I was in disbelief.</p>
<p><em>What do you mean, gone? How can two huge buildings just be GONE?</em></p>
<p>One of the teachers printed out a photo from an Internet news-site, and my eyes widened from the fiery image of a plane striking one of the Towers. What was happening? What did all this mean?</p>
<p>A few children were still remaining in the classroom, and we reassured them that everything would be okay, their families were on their way. In the mind of a five year-old, the notion of not getting picked up and being the only kid left behind in school is scary; I could tell my students were trying hard not to cry. Fortunately, all them were reunited with their parents that day.</p>
<p><a href="http://foiegraschick.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/ps11.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-348" title="ps11" src="http://foiegraschick.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/ps11.jpg" alt="" width="529" height="379" /></a></p>
<p>As I packed up my belongings to leave, I was told subway service had been severely affected. My plan was to stay overnight at my then-boyfriend&#8217;s parents&#8217; place in the Lower East Side. I left the cheery halls of the school building, pushed open its metal entrance doors and was confronted with a heavy silence. There were people outside, but the silence was just strangely deafening. I began the long cross-town walk from Chelsea towards Delancey Street.</p>
<p>I was puzzled by the frequent appearance of police cars and fire trucks from Long Island and New Jersey whizzing past me with blaring sirens. Occasionally a National Guard vehicle would plow through. Not a taxi cab was in sight. What was going on?</p>
<p>I spotted a crowd in the middle of Fifth Avenue as I neared my old Greenwich Village stomping grounds. They were all looking downtown, and when I approached them, I followed their gaze.</p>
<p>I caught my breath and my jaw dropped.</p>
<p>I quickly called my sister on my cell phone. She worked downtown on Broad Street, very close to the World Trade Center site. All I got was her voicemail at work and her home answering machine. I started to frantically re-dial her numbers again and again.</p>
<p>As I neared Union Square, I remember standing in front of what was then Bradlee&#8217;s Discount Store, which is today a Whole Foods Market. My phone started ringing. It was my mother. Despite the scratchy reception, my mother was speaking very loudly into the phone, asking if I was alright and where was my sister. I replied that I had been repeatedly trying to reach her, but did not let the worry creep into my voice. My mother had been woken up by a phone call from my aunt, telling her to turn on the TV. When she saw what had happened, she immediately began trying to reach us. Cellphones were still new to me at the time and I wasn&#8217;t in the habit of checking my phone throughout the day. Times have changed.</p>
<p><a href="http://foiegraschick.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/washington-square-3.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-351" title="Washington Square 3" src="http://foiegraschick.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/washington-square-3.jpg" alt="" width="529" height="362" /></a></p>
<p>I let out a big sigh of relief when I finally got through to my sister, who had gotten into Manhattan by train but, like so many others that day, had to walk back over the Brooklyn Bridge. It took her three hours to get home, and she got herself a cellphone not long after 9-11.</p>
<p>I quickened my pace and hurried towards my in-laws&#8217; place. My boyfriend was working in New Jersey at the time and they were only letting people out of the city, not in. His office was generous enough to rent him a hotel room where he could stay the night until the George Washington Bridge was re-opened again. Until then, he couldn&#8217;t get home.</p>
<p>As I first watched CNN footage of the planes going into the Towers, my eyes were riveted to the television. The videos were played over and over, and my heart was filled with unexplainable emotions. Were we under attack? Would there be more attacks tomorrow? Was it even safe to go outside?</p>
<p>When subway service resumed, I made my way home. The trains that normally traveled over East River bridges were re-routed through tunnels and were running at a markedly slower pace. But the smell. I will never forget that harsh smell as my train snaked its way underneath downtown. It smelled like burnt metal, melted plastic, and sulfurous gases all rolled into one. The conductor advised us to keep the windows closed. Some people covered their noses and mouths. It was the quietest subway ride of my life.</p>
<p>I will never forget the images of downtown the first day trains were allowed to cross bridges again. As my train thrust itself into the bright September sun, all of my fellow passengers were agape at the gray cloud hovering over lower Manhattan. Except this time it wasn&#8217;t fog. It was smoke. And the smell was still there. The contrast between a gorgeous autumn morning in New York and the hell that had unfolded was all so surreal.</p>
<p><a href="http://foiegraschick.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/twin-towers-smoke.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-344" title="Twin Towers Smoke" src="http://foiegraschick.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/twin-towers-smoke.jpg" alt="" width="529" height="356" /></a></p>
<p>My memories of the months that followed 9-11 are, surprisingly, a blur. I do remember thousands of fliers with photos of missing loved ones being plastered all over the city. Guidance counselors were available at my school in case students wanted to talk. I was finishing up my last year of grad school and buried myself in studies. I didn&#8217;t know how or what to feel, but I knew that life had to continue and the world would never be the same again. I married my boyfriend of seven years the following year.</p>
<p>The events of 9-11 marked the end of an optimistic, more innocent time for me. Each person experienced 9-11 in different ways, but for those of us who were old enough to remember the details of such a horrible event, it was a moment of pause for the entire nation. We drew closer to our family and friends, we counted our blessings. I&#8217;m actually glad that there was no Twitter or cellphone photos back then; I wouldn&#8217;t have been able to stand the constant chatter and minute-by-minute updates. Those sad and terrible images should stay in the past, but never be forgotten.</p>
<p>I wrote about Louis Armstrong in my last post. His song, &#8220;What a Wonderful World&#8221;, was a song I taught to my students that year. It might seem inappropriate to sing during a time of such sorrow, but for my first grade students, it was a comforting song. I was grateful to have taught those students during that time, because their innocence and unstoppable curiosity about the world reminded me that the sun will still rise each day, birds will still greet you in the morning with song, and life does go on.</p>
<p><a href="http://foiegraschick.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/tribute_in_light.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-359" title="Tribute in Light" src="http://foiegraschick.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/tribute_in_light.jpg" alt="" width="529" height="351" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://foiegraschick.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/reflecting-pool.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-360" title="Reflecting Pool" src="http://foiegraschick.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/reflecting-pool.jpg" alt="" width="529" height="316" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/339/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/339/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=339&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://foiegraschick.wordpress.com/2012/09/09/remembering/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>35</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/d8534a779332a28c7cb2074114a63b2d?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">foiegraschica</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://foiegraschick.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/new_york_washington_square_park.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">new_york_washington_square_park</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://foiegraschick.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/ny-times-2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">NY Times 2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://foiegraschick.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/wsq.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">WSQ</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://foiegraschick.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/twin-towers.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Twin Towers</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://foiegraschick.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/ps11.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ps11</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://foiegraschick.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/washington-square-3.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Washington Square 3</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://foiegraschick.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/twin-towers-smoke.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Twin Towers Smoke</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://foiegraschick.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/tribute_in_light.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Tribute in Light</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://foiegraschick.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/reflecting-pool.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Reflecting Pool</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Isaac Newton and the Paralympic Apples</title>
		<link>http://mefoley.wordpress.com/2012/09/09/isaac-newton-paralympics/</link>
		<comments>http://mefoley.wordpress.com/2012/09/09/isaac-newton-paralympics/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2012 15:01:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>mefoley</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Arts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[britain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[England]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[history]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[london]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mefoley.wordpress.com/?p=4349</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Olympic sports have continued here; the Paralympics don&#8217;t end until tonight. British viewers saw the full Paralympic opening ceremony, and we’ve had 4 channels showing events live all day long. I gather that in the US, NBC showed only about 5 hours of the Paralympic action, total—hard to believe. The Paralympics&#8217; opening ceremony, like the [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4349&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_4354" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://mefoley.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/apple-dancers-small.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-4354" title="apple dancers (Small)" src="http://mefoley.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/apple-dancers-small.jpg?w=300&h=167" alt="" width="300" height="167" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Apple dancers at the opening ceremony of the 2012 Paralympics</p></div>
<p>Olympic sports have continued here; the Paralympics don&#8217;t end until tonight. British viewers saw the full Paralympic opening ceremony, and we’ve had 4 channels showing events live all day long. I gather that in the US, NBC showed only about 5 hours of the Paralympic action, total—hard to believe.</p>
<div id="attachment_4356" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://mefoley.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/apple-entrance-small.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-4356" title="apple entrance (Small)" src="http://mefoley.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/apple-entrance-small.jpg?w=300&h=165" alt="" width="300" height="165" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">A performer enters, riding in her wheelchair on a gigantic apple, which sits on a book. Books made up another theme of the ceremony, representing, among other works, The <em>Universal Declaration of Human Rights</em>, and Newton&#8217;s <em>Principia Mathematica</em></p></div>
<p>The Paralympics&#8217; opening ceremony, like the Olympic ceremony, tackled a revolution, in this case the scientific revolution. The connection between Newton&#8217;s apple—represented in many forms, including the real apples given to each spectator on arrival—and the Paralympics might not be obvious, though when you watch some of the people who run on those remarkable blades instead of feet, it&#8217;s clear that science and technology underpin some events. But I&#8217;d guess that the choice of theme had much to do with the contemporary world’s most famous disabled person being British and a scientist: Stephen Hawking, who narrated the production.</p>
<div id="attachment_4359" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://mefoley.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/hawking-1-small.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-4359" title="Hawking 1 (Small)" src="http://mefoley.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/hawking-1-small.jpg?w=300&h=164" alt="" width="300" height="164" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Professor Hawking, looking very small on the main set in the enormous arena</p></div>
<p>The UK can&#8217;t actually claim that the scientific revolution began here—can&#8217;t leave out Copernicus for starters, and he was Polish—but I guarantee you that a good proportion of the population finds that the phrase &#8220;scientific revolution&#8221; brings to mind that apple hitting Isaac Newton on the head 100 years after Copernicus. Newton wasn&#8217;t actually conked on the head, but there <em>was</em> an apple tree, he <em>did</em> watch an apple fall and, watching it, wondered why apples always fall down and never out to the side or something, a bit of daydreaming that led to the universal law of gravitation. Descendants of Newton&#8217;s apple tree still grow in the same orchard at his home in Lincolnshire, which I visited just a couple of days before those apple-wielding performers (see illustrations) appeared on my TV/telly, so I&#8217;m using that as an excuse to write about Newton in the middle of my streak of Olympic-ceremony posts.</p>
<div id="attachment_4360" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://mefoley.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/singers-1-small.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-4360" title="singers 1 (Small)" src="http://mefoley.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/singers-1-small.jpg?w=300&h=165" alt="" width="300" height="165" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">A 430-voice chorus sings <em>Principia</em> , a violently discordant piece by composer Errollyn Wallen inspired by Newton&#8217;s work</p></div>
<p>Isaac Newton was born prematurely at Woolsthorpe Manor on Christmas Day 1642, so small that the nurse said he could fit into a quart jug (in the US we&#8217;d have said <em>pitcher</em>; Brits think <em>pitcher</em> is as quaint and old-fashioned as Americans think <em>jug</em> is). Servants sent out for supplies for the baby sat down and goofed off rather than hurry, as they didn&#8217;t expect him to be alive when they got back anyway.</p>
<div id="attachment_4363" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://mefoley.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dsc_0265_pt-small.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-4363" title="DSC_0265_pt (Small)" src="http://mefoley.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dsc_0265_pt-small.jpg?w=300&h=199" alt="" width="300" height="199" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Woolsthorpe Manor, Lincolnshire, where Isaac Newton was born, grew up, and did some of his most famous work.</p></div>
<p>On the other hand, local superstition at the time held that it was lucky to be born on Christmas Day. It was also supposed to be lucky to be born after the death of your father, as odd as that sounds, and the baby&#8217;s father had died a few months before. When his mother, Hannah, remarried, she left three-year-old Isaac at Woolsthorpe Manor with his grandmother. Lots of books will tell you that this meant her new husband didn&#8217;t accept his step-son, but the National Trust (historic preservation group that maintains the house) says it&#8217;s more likely that Hannah shrewdly left her son in the Newton home to make sure no one questioned his right to inherit the place.</p>
<div id="attachment_4364" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://mefoley.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dsc_0256_pt-small.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-4364" title="DSC_0256_pt (Small)" src="http://mefoley.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dsc_0256_pt-small.jpg?w=300&h=199" alt="" width="300" height="199" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The farm at Woolsthorpe Manor</p></div>
<p>When he was older, his mother also demanded he do his familial duty and work on the farm—Woolsthorpe Manor sounds grand, but it was really just a glorified farmhouse. Had that worked out, he might have remained illiterate like his father, who never learned to write his own name. (There&#8217;s a grid of small cup-shaped gouges on a plaster wall at Woolsthorpe Manor that historians think is an inventory of livestock; presumably that was how you kept track if you couldn&#8217;t read or write.) But Newton&#8217;s mother found she could lead a scientific genius to the land, but she couldn&#8217;t make him cultivate it.</p>
<div id="attachment_4366" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 209px"><a href="http://mefoley.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dsc_0266_pt-small.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-4366" title="DSC_0266_pt (Small)" src="http://mefoley.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dsc_0266_pt-small.jpg?w=199&h=300" alt="" width="199" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Newton, first scientist ever knighted, was granted a coat of arms; claiming descent from a certain baron, he was allowed to adopt that baron&#8217;s ancient symbol. The crossed bones are not uncommon on arms and don&#8217;t imply piracy; National Trust staff suggested they are sheep bones, as the family made its money in sheep.</p></div>
<p>In the end, she allowed him to go to school, and from school to Cambridge, where she expressed her feelings about his choice not to be a farmer by giving him so little money that he had to work as a servant for richer students. It doesn&#8217;t seem to have mattered much. The only thing that could keep him away from Cambridge was the plague, which closed the place down in 1665.</p>
<div id="attachment_4365" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://mefoley.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dsc_0263_pt-small.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-4365" title="DSC_0263_pt (Small)" src="http://mefoley.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dsc_0263_pt-small.jpg?w=300&h=199" alt="" width="300" height="199" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">A descendant of the apple tree, one of several in the orchard that lies just outside the front door at Woolsthorpe Manor. Newton identified the tree from which the famous apple fell, and even though it was blown over in a gale in the 19th century, grafts were taken so the &#8220;same&#8221; tree is growing strong. The variety is Flower of Kent. and it&#8217;s a cooking apple.</p></div>
<p>So Newton went back to the farm and sat there by himself, totally revolutionizing science, later saying &#8220;I was in the prime of my age for invention&#8221;. He not only saw the apple fall and worked out his theory of gravitation, but developed the three Laws of Motion, invented calculus, worked out principles of mechanics and of planetary motion, and did famous experiments with light. His work always began with observation, and he was such an inveterate experimenter that, rather less famously, he stuck a blunt needle into his eye to see how pressing on his retina would alter his vision.</p>
<div id="attachment_4371" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://mefoley.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/apples-1-small-adj.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-4371" title="apples 1 (Small) ADJ" src="http://mefoley.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/apples-1-small-adj.jpg?w=300&h=180" alt="" width="300" height="180" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Performers pull giant apples into the stadium</p></div>
<p>A trip to Woolsthorpe Manor includes a chance to see the window that Newton covered, leaving only a small opening so that he could direct sunlight through a prism and break white light up into colours. Newton didn&#8217;t invent the prism; people knew them from way back. Ships used prisms to let light in below decks, for one thing, and Newton bought his prism at a country fair, maybe sold as toy for children. In any case, before Newton, people thought that prisms added colour to light, and that all colours were mixtures of dark and light, so that (I&#8217;m not making this up) one theorist said that red was produced by the purest white light with the least amount of dark mixed in (I know, I know) and black was pure darkness, but if there was just a little light mixed into the darkness, you got a sort of dull blue. Newton used a second prism to bend the light again, merging the colours to produce white light, which pretty much knocked the ol&#8217; prisms-apply-colours theory off the table (and at least it didn&#8217;t require any of that needle-in-the-eye business).</p>
<div id="attachment_4372" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://mefoley.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/floating-apple-2-small.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-4372" title="floating apple 2 (Small)" src="http://mefoley.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/floating-apple-2-small.jpg?w=300&h=169" alt="" width="300" height="169" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">A giant apple floats in.  Before Newton, people thought objects contained more or less of properties called gravity and levity, which made those objects heavy or light.  This, then, is an apple full of levity, I suppose.</p></div>
<p>Isaac Newton ended up the Lucasian Professor of Mathematics at Cambridge, an extremely prestigious position. One of his professors had the job, but resigned so Newton could have it; he was <em>that</em> good. Three-hundred and ten years later, Stephen Hawking got the job*, which leads us back to the opening ceremony of the Paralympics, in all its apple-y glory.</p>
<p>Apples floated in on wires. Performers rode in on gigantic apples, dragged in enormous apples on carts, tossed around beachball-sized apples, juggled apples. On cue, everyone in the stadium bit into their free apples for one thunderous communal crunch.</p>
<div id="attachment_4378" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://mefoley.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/floating-apples-small.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-4378" title="floating apples (Small)" src="http://mefoley.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/floating-apples-small.jpg?w=300&h=166" alt="" width="300" height="166" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Apples everywhere&#8230;</p></div>
<p>And Professor Hawking told us via his synthetic voice that “There is no such thing as a standard or run-of-the-mill human being”. True, but some are less run-of-the-mill than others, and watching Paralympic athletes you can&#8217;t help but be majorly impressed. I&#8217;m going to miss the games. (I&#8217;ve already looked up a wheelchair basketball team near me and hope to go see them play.) But at the moment, I&#8217;m looking forward to tonight&#8217;s closing ceremony. Just in case there&#8217;s audience participation, I&#8217;ve got some apples standing by.</p>
<p>* Lucasian professors are required to retire at 67, so Professor Hawking left the Lucasian Chair in 2009, replaced by physicist Michael Green.</p>
<p><em>Photos of Woolsthorpe Manor are mine; others are screenshots from the broadcast of the opening ceremony of the Paralympic</em>s</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4349/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4349/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4349&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://mefoley.wordpress.com/2012/09/09/isaac-newton-paralympics/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>22</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/ff94afbcf5c8e669740b37cb9e3df92f?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mefoley</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mefoley.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/apple-dancers-small.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">apple dancers (Small)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mefoley.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/apple-entrance-small.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">apple entrance (Small)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mefoley.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/hawking-1-small.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Hawking 1 (Small)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mefoley.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/singers-1-small.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">singers 1 (Small)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mefoley.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dsc_0265_pt-small.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0265_pt (Small)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mefoley.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dsc_0256_pt-small.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0256_pt (Small)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mefoley.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dsc_0266_pt-small.jpg?w=199" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0266_pt (Small)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mefoley.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dsc_0263_pt-small.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0263_pt (Small)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mefoley.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/apples-1-small-adj.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">apples 1 (Small) ADJ</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mefoley.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/floating-apple-2-small.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">floating apple 2 (Small)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mefoley.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/floating-apples-small.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">floating apples (Small)</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>By Any Means Necessary: Welcome to the Border State</title>
		<link>http://maxdunbar.wordpress.com/2012/09/09/by-any-means-necessary-welcome-to-the-border-state/</link>
		<comments>http://maxdunbar.wordpress.com/2012/09/09/by-any-means-necessary-welcome-to-the-border-state/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2012 15:01:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>maxdunbar</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Manchester]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Political]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://maxdunbar.wordpress.com/?p=5576</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The decision to revoke London Met&#8217;s ability to teach international students is a curious one. Closing down bogus colleges and visa mills is one thing. Deporting three thousand students is quite another. What was the rationale for this? A UKBA spokesman told the Guardian about &#8216;serious and systemic failings&#8217; that meant that &#8216;Allowing London Metropolitan [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=5576&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a title="The decision to revoke London Met's ability to teach international students" href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/education/2012/aug/30/border-agency-international-students-threat">The decision to revoke London Met&#8217;s ability to teach international students</a> is a curious one. Closing down bogus colleges and visa mills is one thing. Deporting three thousand students is quite another. What was the rationale for this? A UKBA spokesman told the <em>Guardian </em>about &#8216;serious and systemic failings&#8217; that meant that &#8216;Allowing London Metropolitan University to continue to sponsor and teach international students was not an option.&#8217; Universities minister David Willetts said that &#8216;It is important that genuine students who are affected through no fault of their own are offered prompt advice and help.&#8217; Defending the UKBA, conservative writer Ed West <a title="points out that" href="http://blogs.telegraph.co.uk/news/edwest/100178565/student-visas-the-government-continues-to-do-the-right-thing-over-immigration/">points out</a>: &#8217;Student migration is now the largest route for non-European migrants to take, and has been so since 2008&#8242;.</p>
<p>It appears that this is purely a numbers game. And I like Willetts&#8217;s emphasis on &#8216;genuine&#8217; students. Again, people paying a visa mill is one thing. But are we now defining a &#8216;bogus&#8217; student as someone who applies to a UK university with the intention of living in the UK, making use of his degree and contributing to society? I thought we all had to go into education with that kind of vocational motive in mind?</p>
<p>When I first moved to South Manchester the bars were full of American, European and Asian accents heard on the streets and ringing in the twilight of the early evening balcony at Trof Fallowfield. The city would be an emptier place without them. As West points out, London Met is a bad university, 118th out of 120th in the tables. But there&#8217;s nothing I can see that would stop the UKBA applying these restrictions to every university in the UK. Universities already have to recruit UKBA compliance officers. A lecturer told me recently that she regularly receives &#8217;warning emails to keep my registers up to date cause of UKBA.&#8217; This has clearly been mainstreamed and HE professionals are now expected to help track down those the UKBA say are &#8216;illegal&#8217;.</p>
<p>And it was clear from the <a title="Commons debate on this " href="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm201213/cmhansrd/cm120903/debtext/120903-0001.htm">Commons debate on this</a> that London Met is basically a pilot. Potential high flier Tory Amber Rudd got up and said: &#8216;Reducing immigration levels is important to my constituents, who welcomed the admission by the Leader of the Opposition earlier in the year that there had been uncontrolled immigration under the previous Government. May I urge the Minister, therefore, to reform all routes of entry into the UK, including the student visa route, in order to build on the reductions he has already achieved?&#8217;</p>
<p>We have a border agency that hectors universities that they should be doing the UKBA&#8217;s job for them, and is trying to turn Britain&#8217;s universities into a compliance arm of the UKBA. With the coalition&#8217;s obsessive numbers game it is inevitable that bright people from other countries will conclude that it&#8217;s not worth the hassle of trying to study here. I mean, it&#8217;s not like Britain&#8217;s the only country that has good universities. For all the rhetoric about preserving British culture, the UKBA pursues numbers and process at the expense of Britain&#8217;s cultural reputation. <em>Private Eye&#8217;s </em>Lunchtime O&#8217;Boulez column compiles numerous stories of travelling classical musicians hassled and messed around by border police, to the extent that the game just ain&#8217;t worth the candle. So we can deport a few lazy engineering students but not any of the <a title="almost 400 suspected war criminals currently living in this country" href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/law/2011/feb/04/britain-home-to-400-war-criminals">almost 400 suspected war criminals currently living in this country</a>. Doesn&#8217;t it help you sleep soundly in your bed that your borders are guarded by people with such investigative rigour and common sense?</p>
<p>We&#8217;re always being told that we &#8216;can&#8217;t talk about immigration.&#8217; On Thursday there was another parliamentary debate. <a title="Guess which policy area" href="http://www.publications.parliament.uk/pa/cm201213/cmhansrd/cm120906/debtext/120906-0002.htm#12090626000001">Guess which policy area</a>. It was triggered by a Migration Watch e-petition that urged the government to &#8216;take all necessary steps to reduce immigration to a level that will stabilise the UK’s population as close as possible to its present level and, certainly, significantly below 70 million.&#8217; This was picked up by Tory Nicholas Soames and tedious Merseyside Blue Labourite, Frank Field. The Commons passed this motion.</p>
<p>The anti-migration obsessives will froth and moan, but they can be strangely coy in places. They will highlight real or imagined problems, but maintain a reluctance to answer the basic question: &#8216;What would you do about it?&#8217; The SNP&#8217;s Pete Wishart was one of the few dissenting voices in the chamber that day. He asked a very good question:</p>
<blockquote><p>This nasty little motion mentions &#8216;all necessary steps&#8217;. Does he realise how authoritarian that sounds? The right hon. Member for Mid Sussex mentioned four steps, but what other &#8216;necessary steps&#8217; would the right hon. Member for Birkenhead (Mr Field) propose?</p></blockquote>
<p>I would add a few questions for Field, Soames, Migration Watch, the Daily Mail, Telegraph Blogs and all the others who invest so much emotion and energy in opposing immigration.</p>
<p>- When you say &#8216;all necessary steps&#8217;, what exactly do you mean by that? Could you explain what these steps are and how this would work in practice?</p>
<p>- Who would the &#8216;necessary steps&#8217; apply to? Do you want to cut the numbers of refugees, economic migrants, students or family migrants? What is the selection criteria here?</p>
<p>- You go on about your love for the free market, yet you advocate protectionist policies that would prevent other people competing with your sons and daughters for jobs and university places. Could you explain the contradiction.</p>
<p>- Following on from that, if you close the doors to migrants, <a title="will you be able to find the young workers" href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/commentisfree/2011/may/23/future-policy-elderly-care-on-own">will you be able to find the young workers</a> that we need to sustain an ageing population with subsidised pensions and social care? Do you think that autarky is a sustainable economic policy in a globalised world?</p>
<p>- You say that there are not just economic, but also cultural problems with immigration. For example, you quote an IPPR report that claims &#8216;It is no exaggeration to say that immigration under new Labour has changed the face of the country.&#8217; How would you address this in practice? Would you want to deport people with ILR, who have been naturalised, second and third generation immigrants, people who came over on the Windrush? Would there be a kind of social engineering experiment to recreate Britain in the late 1950s? Just how far with this do you want to go?</p>
<p>- You are concerned about population growth and certainly we have problems with overcrowded housing and schools. It&#8217;s not clear that these are the fault of immigrants alone but never mind that. But have you considered that the population scares of the 1970s turned out to be completely unfounded and that the consequences of having a declining population are <a title="little more difficult to deal with" href="http://blogs.spectator.co.uk/alex-massie/2012/07/britain-is-not-full/">a little more difficult to deal with</a>?</p>
<p>- You moan that you have been called a racist for talking about immigration, and you suffer from the &#8217;fear of saying something that would be called politically incorrect and thus being labelled as racist or anti-immigrant by the media.&#8217; It&#8217;s okay, we are all friends here, no one&#8217;s accusing you of anything and we&#8217;ll take it for granted that you are not racist. But isn&#8217;t it true that the restrictions you propose will disproportionately affect people with different colour skin? Do you accept that <em>some </em>criticism of immigration is demonstrably racist and that all racist parties in this country are committed to stamping out immigration?</p>
<p>- Is there a lower level of immigration that you would be happy with?</p>
<p><img title="immigration" src="http://maxdunbar.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/immigration1.jpg?w=450&h=281" alt="" width="450" height="281" /></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5576/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5576/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=5576&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://maxdunbar.wordpress.com/2012/09/09/by-any-means-necessary-welcome-to-the-border-state/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>16</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/8370387cb091e49f97f1f881bf13c0f4?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Max Dunbar</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://maxdunbar.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/immigration1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">immigration</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Vietnamese Chicken Curry</title>
		<link>http://thelemursarehungry.wordpress.com/2012/09/09/vietnamese-chicken-curry/</link>
		<comments>http://thelemursarehungry.wordpress.com/2012/09/09/vietnamese-chicken-curry/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2012 09:21:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>hungrylemur</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[ingredients]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[local foods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vietnamese food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ca ri ga]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chicken]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[curry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dinner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Saigon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vietnam]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thelemursarehungry.wordpress.com/?p=1523</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[By the time Mr Lemur and I hit Saigon on our tour of Southern Vietnam, you might think we&#8217;d have been all marketed out, but Ben Thanh market revitalised us. At first it felt a bit unwieldy with lots of stalls selling cheap clothes, fake plastic fruit and assorted tschotschkes, not to mention the Viet [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1523&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://thelemursarehungry.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/spice-stall-hcmc.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1524" title="spice-stall-HCMC" src="http://thelemursarehungry.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/spice-stall-hcmc.jpg" alt="" width="490" height="325" /></a></p>
<p>By the time Mr Lemur and I hit Saigon on our tour of Southern Vietnam, you might think we&#8217;d have been all marketed out, but Ben Thanh market revitalised us. At first it felt a bit unwieldy with lots of stalls selling cheap clothes, fake plastic fruit and assorted tschotschkes, not to mention the Viet ladies who have no problem whatsoever grabbing you and pushing you aside if you are in their way. (Seriously, they make little old Italian ladies seem reticent.) But we soon warmed to the cheery rudeness of the atmosphere and enjoyed a pretty good pork chop bun for breakfast. Since we were nearing the end of our time in Asia, I felt justified in attempting a bit of food shopping. While it was sadly not feasible to carry home any of the pickled fish I enjoyed in Chau Doc, it did seem reasonable to pick up some dried shrimp and spices. Ben Thanh had some lovely looking shrimp stalls where I&#8217;m fairly certain I was ripped off, and pushy coffee vendors who clearly dealt with tourists a lot. But the spice stall was not set up for tourism and, as you can see above, its proprietor was just a little daunting.<span id="more-1523"></span></p>
<p><a href="http://thelemursarehungry.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/nice-lady-hcmc.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1525" title="nice-lady-HCMC" src="http://thelemursarehungry.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/nice-lady-hcmc.jpg" alt="" width="490" height="326" /></a></p>
<p>I wanted some powdered ca ri ga mix, as Vietnamese curries are very specific and it struck me that this would be kind of a good staple to have in the storecupboard. Luckily, one of the customers took pity on me and decided to help out. You can see the Vietnamese phrasebook in my hand there &#8211; never has a book been less useful. It&#8217;s no insult to the good people at Lonely Planet, as the book is well thought out and does its best, but dear gods, nobody <em>ever</em> understood a single word of Vietnamese that came out of my mouth. This little interaction was a testiment to the magical powers of cross-cultural communication; one of those occasions where you somehow exchange meaning with someone despite sharing absolutely no common language. Shopping for food tends to bring this out in people – maybe it&#8217;s the cultural centrality of food, or the practicality of having lots of things to point at &#8211; but I love &#8216;talking&#8217; to people like this in markets. With this nice lady&#8217;s help, I came home with a box of  curry powder for chicken.</p>
<p><a href="http://thelemursarehungry.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/viet-curry-powder.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1526" title="viet-curry-powder" src="http://thelemursarehungry.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/viet-curry-powder.jpg" alt="" width="490" height="326" /></a></p>
<p>I know someone is going to tell me you can buy the same brand in London and you probably can, but I was happy to have it recommended. I finally tried out the curry powder this week, making a more or less traditional Vietnamese ca ri ga. I omitted the usual potatoes but you can always put them in with the carrots if you like them more than I do! Vietnamese curry is lighter than, say, a southern Thai curry, with less coconut milk and a soupier consistency. Don&#8217;t let that put you off &#8211; the flavour is hearty and reassuring, good for a late summer evening.</p>
<p><strong>Vietnamese chicken curry</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>8 pieces of chicken (either a whole chicken jointed or a selection of thigh and leg pieces)</li>
<li>3 tbsp Vietnamese curry powder</li>
<li>1 tsp chili powder (or to taste)</li>
<li>3 shallots</li>
<li>4 stalks lemongrass</li>
<li>1 thumb ginger</li>
<li>2 cloves garlic</li>
<li>6 lime leaves</li>
<li>2 fresh red chilies, sliced</li>
<li>1/2 can coconut milk</li>
<li>1 onion, cut in thin wedges</li>
<li>2 carrots, thickly sliced</li>
<li>cilantro to garnish</li>
</ul>
<p>Start by rubbing 2 tbsp of curry powder over your chicken with a bit of salt and leaving for at least a half hour.</p>
<p><a href="http://thelemursarehungry.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/marinade-chicken.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1527" title="marinade-chicken" src="http://thelemursarehungry.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/marinade-chicken.jpg" alt="" width="490" height="326" /></a></p>
<p>While you wait, make the curry paste. Chop the garlic, ginger, shallots and lemongrass and either pound in a mortar and pestle or whizz in a mini-prep. Brown the chicken well in a large pan or wok &#8211; I use a flat-bottomed Le Creuset &#8211; until the aromas of the curry are released.</p>
<p><a href="http://thelemursarehungry.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/browning-chicken.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1528" title="browning-chicken" src="http://thelemursarehungry.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/browning-chicken.jpg" alt="" width="490" height="326" /></a></p>
<p>Next, add the curry paste to the chicken and fry a little till it no longer smells raw. Then add the remainder of the curry powder, chili powder to taste (I don&#8217;t like this dish to be too spicy so I go light on the dried chilies), the sliced fresh chilies and lime leaves. Stir briefly and add a cup of water (you might need a bit more depending on your pot). Bring to the boil and then simmer, covered, for 20 minutes.</p>
<p><a href="http://thelemursarehungry.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/viet-curry.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1529" title="viet-curry" src="http://thelemursarehungry.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/viet-curry.jpg" alt="" width="490" height="326" /></a></p>
<p>Add the onions, carrots and coconut milk and simmer for another 15 minutes or until the carrots are cooked. Garnish with a bit of chopped cilantro. Serve with rice or bread.</p>
<p><a href="http://thelemursarehungry.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/viet-chicken-curry1.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1530" title="viet-chicken-curry1" src="http://thelemursarehungry.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/viet-chicken-curry1.jpg" alt="" width="490" height="326" /></a></p>
<p>Serves 4.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1523/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1523/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1523&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thelemursarehungry.wordpress.com/2012/09/09/vietnamese-chicken-curry/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>32</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/699b96fce7138da0ea640613c8e03526?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">hungrylemur</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thelemursarehungry.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/spice-stall-hcmc.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">spice-stall-HCMC</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thelemursarehungry.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/nice-lady-hcmc.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">nice-lady-HCMC</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thelemursarehungry.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/viet-curry-powder.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">viet-curry-powder</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thelemursarehungry.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/marinade-chicken.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">marinade-chicken</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thelemursarehungry.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/browning-chicken.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">browning-chicken</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thelemursarehungry.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/viet-curry.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">viet-curry</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thelemursarehungry.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/viet-chicken-curry1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">viet-chicken-curry1</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ramblings of a Pregnant 20-Something: Third Trimester!</title>
		<link>http://kookykuckoo.com/2012/09/05/the-ramblings-of-a-pregnant-twenty-something-the-third-trimester/</link>
		<comments>http://kookykuckoo.com/2012/09/05/the-ramblings-of-a-pregnant-twenty-something-the-third-trimester/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2012 14:08:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Alexandra</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[The Nesting Diaries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Baby shower]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nesting Diaries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pregnancy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Third Trimester of Prgenancy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women's issues]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://kookykuckoo.com/?p=3230</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I’m writing this from the perspective of my last week of pregnancy before my due date. Last week was my final midwife appointment, and I took my Mum, mainly because I was desperate for her to meet my eccentric Midwife ‘J’ who didn’t disappointment… moments after meeting my Mum for example (who is from North [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3230&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://kookykuckoo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/pregnant-gah.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-3231 alignnone" title="pregnant-gah" src="http://kookykuckoo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/pregnant-gah.jpg" alt="" width="545" height="354" /></a></p>
<p>I’m writing this from the perspective of my last week of pregnancy before my due date. Last week was my final midwife appointment, and I took my Mum, mainly because I was desperate for her to meet my eccentric Midwife ‘J’ who didn’t disappointment… moments after meeting my Mum for example (who is from North London) ‘J’ proceeded to ask whether she was “visiting from Australia”. This is the woman who could potentially deliver my baby…</p>
<p>I read an article on the Daily Mail Online about how Drew Barrymore (who is also a couple of weeks off of her due date) is walking around looking distinctly miserable. I sympathise, and I respect her for still ‘walking around’, as the third trimester is very much like glimpsing into the life of an OAP. Lack of mobility, falling asleep in armchairs, proudly listening to Classic FM and waiting for visitors to arrive with offerings of donuts… I’ve stayed as active and as social as I could manage, but there comes a time when sitting in pubs nursing an orange and lemonade and attempting to stay upright on the London Underground becomes unappealing, and then impossible. A final day trip to London Zoo when I spend most of the time moving from bench to bench… pretending to be <em>really</em> interested in the lions when actually I just want another sit down really hammers home the reality that <em>this is it</em>…</p>
<p>Because the third trimester may bring ‘blooming’ but it also obviously brings ‘ballooning’, and I can’t emphasise how heavy that gorgeous bump will get. Assistance is required when getting off of a low couch, feet swell after walking around the block in the summer heat, flip- flops become your best friend…  and as August brings an awful heat-wave of tropical proportions I effectively spend an entire weekend attempting to stay deadly still, with an electric fan trained upon me.</p>
<p>From this sluggish perspective I realise that the date of my Baby Shower is rapidly approaching… I feel like cancelling at one point, after overhearing a family member sniffingly commenting that “baby showers are just an Americanism!” and frankly feeling too tired to even organise getting dressed in the mornings, let alone a party at my house. But I see it through, mainly because I’ve spent the last couple of months ordering pretty bunting and baby shower decorations from ebay, and because my Mum (henceforth known as ‘Supermum’) explains that she will handle all the food… all the drink… just about everything, whilst my best friend volunteers to organise the party games. On the day of the baby shower Supermum arrives with military precision, best friend in the world brings a bounty of party games, family and friends descend with offerings of homemade cakes and oblige with tea-making and frankly bringing the fun (read my post on <a title="My Utterly Scrumptious Baby Shower" href="http://kookykuckoo.com/2012/08/06/my-utterly-scrumptious-baby-shower/" target="_blank">Baby Shower Decorations here</a>). I forget entirely about present giving, because that’s not what the day is about for me (although I do receive some amazing presents!); it’s about getting an extraordinary bunch of women together, and realising what an incredible support network I’m going to have once this baby is born.</p>
<p>The final weeks, take on an odd surrealism, as I try and get my head around how soon there will be an actual baby in the cot, not just my laundry, and that two of us will become ‘three of us’. We attend antenatal classes, led by a frizzy haired and slightly dazed midwife in socks ‘n’ sandals. I realise that the anxieties I’ve been experiencing about labour and becoming a first time Mum are totally common. In fact we are the youngest couple in the class, possibly the most relaxed and after everything that’s happened to us I’m suddenly proud of what we have achieved in nine months. &#8220;But how do you even look after a baby?!!&#8221; one woman suddenly asks in a highly sweeping manner. To which the frizzy haired midwife merely responds &#8220;you&#8217;ll know how to look after your baby, it&#8217;s instinct.&#8221; So I approach ‘Motherhood’, yes feeling the fear, but confident that I can go ahead and do it anyway.</p>
<p><a href="http://kookykuckoo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/congratulations-on-nine-months-of-sobriety.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-3232 alignnone" title="Congratulations on nine months of sobriety" src="http://kookykuckoo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/congratulations-on-nine-months-of-sobriety.jpg" alt="" width="580" height="675" /></a></p>
<h2>Previous Posts:</h2>
<p><a href="http://kookykuckoo.com/2012/08/07/ramblings-of-a-pregnant-twenty-something-the-first-trimester/"><img class=" wp-image-3241 alignnone" title="Gerkins" src="http://kookykuckoo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/gerkins.jpg?w=113&h=130" alt="" width="113" height="130" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://kookykuckoo.com/2012/08/07/ramblings-of-a-pregnant-twenty-something-the-first-trimester/" target="_blank">The Ramblings of a Pregnant Twenty-Something //The First Trimester</a></p>
<p><a href="http://kookykuckoo.com/2012/08/16/the-ramblings-of-a-pregnant-twenty-something-the-second-trimester/"><img class="size-thumbnail wp-image-3240 alignnone" title="pregnant-gah" src="http://kookykuckoo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/pregnant-gah1.jpg?w=150&h=97" alt="" width="150" height="97" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://kookykuckoo.com/2012/08/16/the-ramblings-of-a-pregnant-twenty-something-the-second-trimester/" target="_blank">The Ramblings of a Pregnant Twenty-Something //The Second Trimester</a></p>
<p><a href="http://kookykuckoo.com/2012/08/06/my-utterly-scrumptious-baby-shower/"><img class=" wp-image-3239 alignnone" title="DSCF1589" src="http://kookykuckoo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dscf1589.jpg?w=127&h=102" alt="" width="127" height="102" /></a></p>
<p><a title="My Utterly Scrumptious Baby Shower" href="http://kookykuckoo.com/2012/08/06/my-utterly-scrumptious-baby-shower/" target="_blank">My Utterly Scrumptious Baby Shower</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://kookykuckoo.com/category/the-nesting-diaries/'>The Nesting Diaries</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3230/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3230/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3230&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://kookykuckoo.com/2012/09/05/the-ramblings-of-a-pregnant-twenty-something-the-third-trimester/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>19</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://kookykuckoo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/pregnant-gah.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://kookykuckoo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/pregnant-gah.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">pregnant-gah</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/cedf09b1e32e74b100a0fd2ce32f5706?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F0.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">kookykuckoo</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://kookykuckoo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/pregnant-gah.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">pregnant-gah</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://kookykuckoo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/congratulations-on-nine-months-of-sobriety.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Congratulations on nine months of sobriety</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://kookykuckoo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/gerkins.jpg?w=131" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Gerkins</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://kookykuckoo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/pregnant-gah1.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">pregnant-gah</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://kookykuckoo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dscf1589.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSCF1589</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>