<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 15:01:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>We Joined Costco</title>
		<link>http://thesurfingpizza.com/2011/04/06/we-joined-costco/</link>
		<comments>http://thesurfingpizza.com/2011/04/06/we-joined-costco/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 14:21:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>The Pizza</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Things I Write]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[costco]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thesurfingpizza.com/?p=6362</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Costco is the largest membership wholesaler club in the United States. For an annual membership fee, you are granted access into their warehouse of bulk items, buy outs, and tubs of butter the size of in-ground swimming pools. It&#8217;s part novelty, part insanity, and part the American Dream. But it&#8217;s more than that. Joining Costco [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=6362&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://iwantpizza.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/3535.jpg?w=480&#038;h=360" alt="" title="3535" width="480" height="360" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-6369" /></p>
<p>Costco is the largest membership wholesaler club in the United States.  For an annual membership fee, you are granted access into their warehouse of bulk items, buy outs, and tubs of butter the size of in-ground swimming pools. It&#8217;s part novelty, part insanity, and part the American Dream.  But it&#8217;s more than that.  Joining Costco is entering a new, perverse stage of life, one where you no longer show off your souped-up car or stereo to friends, but rather how many rolls of bulk-purchased toilet paper you can fit in the back room of your basement.</p>
<p>Hey, it wasn&#8217;t my idea. It was the girlfriend&#8217;s, who had been dropping subtle hints that she wanted to join Costco.  After all, she&#8217;s addicted to shopping, and Costco was like a designer drug.  I was hesitant.  How much is it to join?  Is it really worth it?  Will we able to consume buckets of yogurt and gallons of coffee creamer before their expiration dates?  Do expiration dates matter at Costco or is that just some silly thing grocery stores do?  And most importantly, where would we even put all of this food?</p>
<p>&#8220;We&#8217;ll build shelves,&#8221; the girlfriend said.  </p>
<p>Of course.  Shelves are always the solution.  It&#8217;s true.  There are really only two solutions to every problem in the world&#8212; alcohol and shelves.  Having a problem?  Just pick one of those.</p>
<p>WARNING: I do not recommend combining alcohol and building shelves.  Trust me.</p>
<p>My parents belonged to Costco in the 80s, when it was then known as the Price Club.  I remember it was exciting to go with them on Price Club shopping trips.  The most exciting part were the food stations set up around the store offering free samples on which we could stuff ourselves.  One time in particular, the free sample was something called &#8220;Chicken Chili,&#8221; which came in a can, and which my parents promptly bought a case of thirty-six cans.  </p>
<p>&#8220;Chicken Chili&#8221; was not so much a chili and not really even a soup.  It was more of a canned meat product, a slurry, or perhaps even a mystery paste.  It was goopy and dense and brown.  We ate it drizzled over nachos, we ate it as a dip, we ate it out of a bowl, we ate it on crackers.  Sometimes, we ate it straight from the can.  And after we finished the case, we never uttered the words &#8220;Chicken Chili&#8221; again.  </p>
<p>Eating thirty-six cans of a mystery meat went down as one of those dark family secrets that we weren&#8217;t allowed to talk about, alongside the time we visited Rob Roy&#8217;s Petting Farm, which we discovered didn&#8217;t have any animals to pet.  There was only a dog that looked like Benji wearing a bandanna, who energetically trotted up to us when we first pulled up to the farm.  He looked hungry.</p>
<p>&#8220;Oh, look at this cute dog that came to greet us,&#8221; my mother said.  &#8220;Do you think they train him to do that?&#8221;</p>
<p>Then we noticed there was nothing else around.  No employees.  No other visitors.  And particularly, no other animals. Just  this dog, an abandoned farm lot, a stable, and a house. The front door of the house was broken and hanging off the hinges.</p>
<p>&#8220;Hello?&#8221; my father bellowed.</p>
<p>&#8220;Johnny, I think this dog is trying to tell us something,&#8221; my mother said.</p>
<p>We walked around to the stable, which was mossy and splintered.  There was an empty cash register with the till gaping open, and a dilapidated assortment of old snackcakes and chips on a rusted rack.</p>
<p>&#8220;Maybe we should take this dog home with us,&#8221; my mother said.</p>
<p>My father ignored her, demanding we all &#8220;get back in the car right now! We&#8217;re leaving!&#8221;</p>
<p>The dog followed behind us.  Before we piled into the car, my mother, a picture-taking nut, decided to take a picture of the dog.  &#8220;For the family photo album,&#8221; she said nervously.  </p>
<p>And for the picture, the dog sat perfectly still.  He panted earnestly, as dogs do.  But the weird part was he looked directly and patiently at the lens, as though he knew his photo was being taken.  I never saw a dog do that before.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve said too much.  I fear somewhere the police are going to stumble upon my blog, discovering a new lead in the old &#8220;Rob Roy farm&#8221; case.  And between this and &#8220;Chicken Chili,&#8221; I&#8217;ve told all of the family secrets.  Sorry, Mom.  I&#8217;m a writer, and I have to scrape the bottom of the barrel for material.  I mean, it wasn&#8217;t like my sister was kidnapped by gypsies or my father was a drunken carnie.  Mom didn&#8217;t have multiple personalities and a vendetta against wire hangers.  Even our dog was boring. She never saved missing children in blizzards.  One time, she did barf blood.  She wasn&#8217;t allowed to eat people food after that.  </p>
<p>Nothing cool ever happens in the suburbs.  And that&#8217;s exactly how joining Costco ends up being an event worth writing about. The girlfriend wasn&#8217;t getting anywhere with me about the whole-joining-Costco thing.  I kept brushing it off, ignoring it, and talking her out of it by citing facts I&#8217;d completely made up.  So she decided to ramp it up.  She got her parents involved.</p>
<p>Her parents, who are avid (rabid?) Costco members, regularly go on &#8220;Costco dates.&#8221;  Sometimes, when they don&#8217;t feel like cooking dinner, they have &#8220;Costco buffet,&#8221; which involves going around to the free sample stations multiple times.  Her father, who is a crazed bargain hunter, goes on &#8220;Costco treasure hunts&#8221; as a pastime.  The girlfriend told them we were thinking about joining.  They jumped on it excitedly, planning a weekend trip for all of us to go.  They would take us, show us around the store, and tell us about the benefits.  But really, it was more than that.  It was an indoctrination experience.  The Costco Indoctrination.  </p>
<p>The towering automatic glass doors slid open for us.  Her father pulled out his Costco ID badge, and a gatekeeper ushered us in.  I felt horrified, and compelled, and for a brief moment, special.  We were no longer commoners or peasants or lowly bumpkins.  We were on the inside.  The automatic doors glided shut behind us.</p>
<p><img src="http://iwantpizza.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/17costco0-650.jpg?w=480&#038;h=360" alt="" title="17costco0.650" width="480" height="360" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-6374" /></p>
<p>The merchandise was arranged in looming piles, stacked up on plywood boards sitting on cinder blocks.</p>
<p> &#8220;See, it&#8217;s not just groceries,&#8221; the girlfriend pointed out, &#8220;we could buy TVs!  We could buy laptops!  We could buy marble lawn statues!&#8221;</p>
<p>For a moment, I stopped.  A giant marble lion would be cool in the front yard.  And he was available at heavily discounted price of only $988.  So they had &#8220;other stuff.&#8221;  And we love shopping for stuff.  We are big time stuff-needers.  Since we were doing some yard work that weekend, I mentioned that I could use a pair of work gloves.  Her father, beaming, and with a somewhat alarming elation, took me over to the outdoor section and showed me that I could get TEN PAIRS of yellow hide contractor work gloves for only fifteen bucks.  </p>
<p>&#8220;ONLY FIFTEEN BUCKS,&#8221; her father exclaimed.  </p>
<p>&#8220;Geez,&#8221; I hesitated.  &#8220;I really only need one pair.&#8221;  </p>
<p>And even then, I was only raking leaves&#8212;not re-paving the driveway.</p>
<p>&#8220;You want &#8216;em?&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Uh, you know, I was thinking I just need them for the raking&#8230;&#8221; I trailed off.</p>
<p>&#8220;FIFTEEN BUCKS!&#8221; he said again, pushing the package towards me.</p>
<p>Then we headed over the hose section.  Earlier in the day, I had picked up a garden hose and Hose Hideaway (TM) at Lowes, and just typing this sentence makes me realize I&#8217;m at a dramatically new point in my adult life.  Her father showed me the display of Costco hoses, asking me what I&#8217;d paid at Lowes. I began to feel nervous. Was this an interrogation?</p>
<p>&#8220;Uh, about $30,&#8221; I said, knocking off five dollars, so that it was the same price as the hoses in front of us. </p>
<p>&#8220;Oh, okay,&#8221; he said approvingly.  </p>
<p>Relief.</p>
<p>&#8220;But is yours reinforced like these?&#8221; he asked, reaching out to touch the hose.</p>
<p>&#8220;Yeah, I think, yeah probably,&#8221;  I said, having no idea what reinforced meant.  And at that moment I knew I had utterly failed at buying a hose.</p>
<p>The girlfriend found us, her hands almost shaking with excitement.</p>
<p>&#8220;They&#8217;re giving away free samples of dishwasher detergent,&#8221; she said, holding up the packet containing three samples.  Her father instantly began making a beeline towards the detergent table.  The girlfriend whispered to me to get a free sample for myself.  This was a coup.  She stashed both packets in her purse.  Clever girl.</p>
<p>Slowly, we made our way into the heart of darkness&#8212;er, heart of the store, the grocery section.  Eggs in cases of 180.  Salsa in jugs the size of small boats.  Five pound bags of shredded cheese.</p>
<p>&#8220;And when we entertain, it will be cheaper to buy it like this!&#8221; the girlfriend said.  I looked around at other patrons, who looked as though they were shopping for the apocalypse, packing their carts with bags of 48 hotdog rolls and half-gallon containers of artichoke dip.  I wondered if they were all entertaining.</p>
<p>Actually, one of Costco&#8217;s niche markets is selling food for apocalypse&#8212;or as they euphemistically call them, &#8220;Emergency Food Kits.&#8221;  But it&#8217;s not like these are a few cans of soup and freeze-dried vegertables.  Oh no.  These are heavyweight buckets built to withstand nuclear fallout.  A bucket contains 2,000 calories per person per day, enough for a month of survival, with a shelf life up to twenty years.  </p>
<p>Each bucket contains packets of just-add-water food. A Chef&#8217;s Banquet bucket, known as the &#8220;gourmet&#8221; food storage brand, has such delectables as &#8220;gourmet hashbrowns&#8221; and &#8220;pasta with alfredo,&#8221; which will set you back $99 and hold you over for one month.  A one-year supply goes for about $999, which is kind of a deal if you think about it.  And if you don&#8217;t want eat like a king, there&#8217;s always the five gallon bucket of pinto beans for $50.</p>
<p>One time, I read a book about a man who was so convinced of nuclear war that he became obsessed with digging a hole.  Every night, he feverishly dug the hole and thought about the end of the world.  He needed to make it big enough and deep enough to build a bomb shelter for him, his wife, and his kid.  But he became so singularly focused on the hole and saving his family that his wife took the kid and left him.  But even then, every night, he still kept digging.</p>
<p>Somehow, Costco reminded me of this.  That&#8217;s going to be me. Only I won&#8217;t be digging.  I&#8217;ll be building shelves.  To store the five gallon pail of pinto beans.</p>
<p>Alright, where do I sign up?</p>
<p>In Costco, everything begins and ends with a line.  There&#8217;s a line to get into the store. And of course, there&#8217;s the lines to check out, which feels more like a cattle drive.  There&#8217;s even a line to get out of the place.  And now we were waiting in the line to sign up for all of it.</p>
<p><img src="http://iwantpizza.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/costco.jpg?w=480&#038;h=360" alt="" title="costco" width="480" height="360" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-6378" /></p>
<p>A fat guy in pink shirt was thrilled to go over the details with us.  He even roped us into the &#8220;Executive Membership.&#8221;  While a regular membership was $50, there was a special on the $100-a-year Executive package, which also involved signing up for a credit card.  </p>
<p>&#8220;You&#8217;ll get a $75 credit back on your first statement,&#8221; he explained, &#8220;and at the end of year, you&#8217;ll also get another $50 rebate.  You&#8217;ll be ahead $25.&#8221;  He paused to let us soak it in. &#8220;<em>They&#8217;ve never</em> done this before,&#8221; he added breathlessly.  The girlfriend gripped the pen.</p>
<p>Finally, it was time to have photos taken for our picture IDs.  The girlfriend stood against the blue backdrop and smiled effortlessly, as naturally as though she were having her picture taken at the beach or at the park or after waiting six hours in line at the DMV to renew a driver&#8217;s license.  She just looks forward and a smile blossoms. It&#8217;s always that easy.</p>
<p>Then it was my turn.  It&#8217;s weird, but I can&#8217;t smile on cue.  I just don&#8217;t know how.  &#8220;Look right here, at the elephant!&#8221; the fat man in the pink shirt squealed, pointing to a small bean bag elephant flopped next to the camera.</p>
<p>&#8220;3&#8230;2&#8230;1&#8230;.Love that smirk!&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>Hey, maybe it won&#8217;t be that bad.  Maybe we&#8217;ll even save a few bucks. At the very least, we&#8217;ll never run out of toilet paper again.  And really, that&#8217;s something you can&#8217;t put a price on.</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://thesurfingpizza.com/category/things-i-write/'>Things I Write</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/6362/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/6362/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/6362/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/6362/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/6362/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/6362/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/6362/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/6362/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/6362/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/6362/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/6362/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/6362/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/6362/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/6362/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=6362&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thesurfingpizza.com/2011/04/06/we-joined-costco/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The Pizza</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://iwantpizza.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/3535.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">3535</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://iwantpizza.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/17costco0-650.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">17costco0.650</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://iwantpizza.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/costco.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">costco</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gardens, Temples, Shrines (1)</title>
		<link>http://ourmaninkorea.wordpress.com/2011/03/02/gardens-temples-shrines-1/</link>
		<comments>http://ourmaninkorea.wordpress.com/2011/03/02/gardens-temples-shrines-1/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2011 11:09:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>ourmaninkorea</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ourmaninkorea.wordpress.com/?p=182</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[These are the things which draw the visitors to Kyoto. I&#8217;ll take a break from the descriptive stuff and just set out some photos based on sets of similar sights &#8211; with brief explanations.  Enjoy. Shrines &#8211; radiant vermilion offset with white, animal statues and distinctive torii (gates). Kyoto&#8217;s Shinto shrines stand out from the [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=182&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_208" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 1034px"><a href="http://ourmaninkorea.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_0414.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-208" title="IMG_0414" src="http://ourmaninkorea.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_0414.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=768" alt="" width="1024" height="768" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Ginkakuji, the paler sister of the Golden Pavilion - and with far superior gardens</p></div>
<p>These are the things which draw the visitors to Kyoto. I&#8217;ll take a break from the descriptive stuff and just set out some photos based on sets of similar sights &#8211; with brief explanations.  Enjoy.</p>
<p><strong>Shrines &#8211; </strong>radiant vermilion offset with white, animal statues and distinctive <em>torii </em>(gates). Kyoto&#8217;s Shinto shrines stand out from the Buddhist temples as the sacred worship sites of Japan&#8217;s ancient and indigenous spiritual belief. Note that <em>jinja </em>is Japanese for shrine.</p>
<div id="attachment_183" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 1034px"><a href="http://ourmaninkorea.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc00709.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-183" title="DSC00709" src="http://ourmaninkorea.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc00709.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=768" alt="" width="1024" height="768" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Main gate of the Yasaka-jinja, one of Kyoto&#039;s most important shrines</p></div>
<div id="attachment_184" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 1034px"><a href="http://ourmaninkorea.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc00836.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-184" title="DSC00836" src="http://ourmaninkorea.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc00836.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=768" alt="" width="1024" height="768" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Mesmering corridors of torii trail through the silent forests around Fushimi-Inari-Taisha</p></div>
<div id="attachment_185" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 1034px"><a href="http://ourmaninkorea.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc00842.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-185" title="DSC00842" src="http://ourmaninkorea.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc00842.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=768" alt="" width="1024" height="768" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Viewed from the opposite direction, the torii are etched with words in Chinese script</p></div>
<div id="attachment_195" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 1034px"><a href="http://ourmaninkorea.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc00978.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-195" title="DSC00978" src="http://ourmaninkorea.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc00978.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=768" alt="" width="1024" height="768" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Drop a coin, ring the bell, clap; for kimono girls it&#039;s as good as three hail Marys.</p></div>
<p><strong>Temples &#8211; </strong>adorned with wonderful statues, carvings, ponds, art and amazing gardens, Kyoto&#8217;s Buddhist temples have long histories tangled up in political power struggles between the various schools of Buddhism and their powerful, secular patrons.</p>
<div id="attachment_187" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 1034px"><a href="http://ourmaninkorea.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc00694.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-187" title="DSC00694" src="http://ourmaninkorea.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc00694.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=768" alt="" width="1024" height="768" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Under the enormous eaves of Chion-in, one of the biggest Buddhist temples in town</p></div>
<div id="attachment_188" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 1034px"><a href="http://ourmaninkorea.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc00693.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-188" title="DSC00693" src="http://ourmaninkorea.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc00693.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=768" alt="" width="1024" height="768" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Eiko and Ikue demonstrate the correct way to purify oneself before entering a temple</p></div>
<div id="attachment_189" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 1034px"><a href="http://ourmaninkorea.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc00744.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-189" title="DSC00744" src="http://ourmaninkorea.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc00744.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=768" alt="" width="1024" height="768" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The mammoth Kiyomizu-dera</p></div>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 1034px"><a href="http://ourmaninkorea.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc00880.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-191" title="DSC00880" src="http://ourmaninkorea.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc00880.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=768" alt="" width="1024" height="768" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Kinkakuji - the famed Golden Pavilion</p></div>
<p><a href="http://ourmaninkorea.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc00996.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-193" title="DSC00996" src="http://ourmaninkorea.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc00996.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=768" alt="" width="1024" height="768" /></a><strong> </strong></p>
<p>Gardens &#8211; no space on this page, see next entry.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/182/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/182/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/182/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/182/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/182/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/182/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/182/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/182/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/182/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/182/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/182/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/182/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/182/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/182/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=182&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://ourmaninkorea.wordpress.com/2011/03/02/gardens-temples-shrines-1/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/6bf40b17d4c6ab6084fdb39f6f7f643a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ourmaninkorea</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ourmaninkorea.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_0414.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0414</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ourmaninkorea.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc00709.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC00709</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ourmaninkorea.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc00836.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC00836</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ourmaninkorea.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc00842.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC00842</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ourmaninkorea.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc00978.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC00978</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ourmaninkorea.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc00694.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC00694</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ourmaninkorea.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc00693.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC00693</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ourmaninkorea.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc00744.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC00744</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ourmaninkorea.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc00880.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC00880</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ourmaninkorea.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc00996.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC00996</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Challenge: Worldwide WordPress 5K</title>
		<link>http://gazingin.com/2011/04/05/the-challenge-worldwide-wordpress-5k/</link>
		<comments>http://gazingin.com/2011/04/05/the-challenge-worldwide-wordpress-5k/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 03:51:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sarah</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[5K]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fitness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[strolling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[walking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wwwp5k]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://gazingin.com/?p=3121</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This week the folks at WordPress are promoting a global 5K for April 10th but are encouraging everyone to do it when they have time &#8211; from the 4th through the 10th. Challenge Accepted! A 5K might seem daunting but all it is a hair over 3 miles. And you needn&#8217;t run, walking is just [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=3121&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://gazingin.com/2011/04/05/the-challenge-worldwide-wordpress-5k/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/b774b36a6a9871f86858a41d0cc21a83?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gazingin</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gazingin.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/5k.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">5K</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gazingin.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/5k2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">5K2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gazingin.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/5k3.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">5K3</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gazingin.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/5k4.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">5K4</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gazingin.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/5k5.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">5K5</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Newspapers and Social Media: Still Not Really Getting It</title>
		<link>http://gigaom.com/2011/04/05/newspapers-and-social-media-still-not-really-getting-it/</link>
		<comments>http://gigaom.com/2011/04/05/newspapers-and-social-media-still-not-really-getting-it/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2011 16:11:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Mathew Ingram</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[comments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newspapers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://gigaom.com/?p=326178</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Newspapers seem to have a hard time accepting the "social" part of social media -- a case in being the new policy introduced at a major Canadian newspaper, which tells its staff not to express personal opinions and not to respond to reader comments.<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=326178&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://gigaom2.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/2308371224_60e0cda6e8_z.png"><img src="http://gigaom2.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/2308371224_60e0cda6e8_z.png?w=300&#038;h=200" alt="" title="2308371224_60e0cda6e8_z" width="300" height="200" class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-287521" /></a></p>
<p><strong>Updated</strong>: Many traditional media entities have embraced social-media services like Twitter and Facebook and blogs &#8212; at least to some extent &#8212; as tools for reporting and journalism, using them to publish and curate news reports. But newspapers in particular seem to <a href="http://gigaom.com/2010/10/20/hey-washington-post-its-called-social-media/">have a hard time accepting the &#8220;social&#8221; part of these tools</a>, at least when it comes to letting their journalists engage with readers as human beings. A case in point is the new social-media policy introduced at a major newspaper in Canada, which tells its staff not to express personal opinions &#8212; even on their personal accounts or pages &#8212; and not to engage with readers in the comments.</p>
<p>The policy, which I received from a source close to <a href="http://thestar.com"><em>The Toronto Star</em></a> (the full version is embedded below), has a number of sensible things to say about using social media, including the fact that these tools &#8220;can be valuable sources for story ideas and contacts for journalists, and as a means of connecting directly with the communities we cover.&#8221; The paper also says that it &#8220;encourages journalists – reporters, columnists, photographers and editors – to take advantage of social media tools in their daily work.&#8221; But it warns that any comments posted using such tools &#8220;can be circulated beyond their intended audience.&#8221;</p>
<p>This all makes perfect sense. Social media is useful for journalism, and it does connect reporters to the communities they cover &#8212; better than just about anything else does. And yes, it is wise to be aware of the unintended consequences of even offhand remarks.</p>
<p><b>No talking about what you do</b></p>
<p>Then comes the part about being impartial and objective, and that&#8217;s when the trouble starts. The policy says staff should &#8220;never post information on social media that could undermine your credibility with the public or damage the Star’s reputation in any way, including as an impartial source of news.&#8221; And that&#8217;s not all &#8212; the document goes on to say that:</p>
<blockquote><p>Anything published on social media – whether on Star sites or personal platforms – cannot reveal information about content in development, newsroom issues or Star sources. Negative commentary about your colleagues or workplace will not be tolerated.</p></blockquote>
<p>In other words, no posting about stories that are being worked on, no comments on newsroom-related topics, no talking about people who might be used or are being used as sources for Star reporting. And this prohibition doesn&#8217;t just apply to Star accounts or services under the newspaper&#8217;s name &#8212; it applies to any comments that a reporter or editor might make on their own personal accounts as well. Obviously the paper doesn&#8217;t want staffers bad-mouthing each other or talking about sensitive internal issues (something the <em>New York Times</em> also confronted <del datetime="2011-04-05T18:54:18+00:00">last year</del> <a href="http://www.observer.com/2009/media/twitter-culture-wars-itimesi">in 2009</a>), but a blanket ban on anything related to content seems unnecessarily harsh, not to mention completely unrealistic. Of course, <a href="http://gigaom.com/2010/03/12/reuters-and-why-social-media-policies-dont-work/">the Star is far from alone in this</a>.</p>
<p><b>Never talk to your readers</b></p>
<p>It gets worse. The policy goes on to say that journalists who report for the Star &#8220;should not editorialize on the topics they cover,&#8221; because readers could could construe this as evidence that their news reporting is biased &#8212; and then tells reporters and editors that they shouldn&#8217;t respond to reader comments either. It says: </p>
<blockquote><p>As well, journalists should refrain from debating issues within the Star&#8217;s online comments forum to avoid any suggestion that they may be biased in their reporting.</p></blockquote>
<p><a href="http://gigaom2.files.wordpress.com/2010/09/2117512295_24e409bf9d_z.png"><img src="http://gigaom2.files.wordpress.com/2010/09/2117512295_24e409bf9d_z.png?w=210&#038;h=140" alt="" title="2117512295_24e409bf9d_z" width="210" height="140" class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-154908" /></a></p>
<p>This last prohibition is a classic case of missing the point completely. According to the Star, apparently, comments on news stories are something that exists to allow readers to talk amongst themselves, not something that a reporter or editor should get involved in. That&#8217;s just wrong. As someone who was intimately involved in social-media strategy for another major metropolitan newspaper in Canada (full disclosure: <a href="http://theglobeandmail.com">the paper</a> in question competes with <em>The Toronto Star</em> to some extent), one of the main features of having comments is the ability for readers to interact with writers and editors at the paper. </p>
<p>Treating the comments section as something that journalists shouldn&#8217;t get involved in turns it into a ghetto, and also <a href="http://gigaom.com/2011/03/07/why-facebook-is-not-the-cure-for-bad-comments/">contributes to the problems that many newspapers have</a> with flaming and trolls and other issues &#8212; why should anyone behave properly in a comment forum if none of the staff at the paper are going to bother getting involved?</p>
<p><b>Never express an opinion on anything</b></p>
<p>The Star is not the only media outlet making these kinds of errors &#8212; while they are happy to use social media to push their content, most major newspapers have failed to take advantage of these tools when it comes to building relationships with their readers. The <a href="http://www.niemanlab.org/2009/09/is-transparency-the-new-objectivity-2-visions-of-journos-on-social-media/">biggest single factor holding them back seems to be fear</a> &#8212; namely, a fear that they will no longer be seen as objective, something NYT executive editor Bill Keller reinforced in <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/03/27/magazine/mag-27lede-t.html?_r=2&#038;ref=magazine">a recent column</a>, in which he suggested that the paper was one of the few remaining holdouts in a world where everyone feels free to state their opinion.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s a news flash for Bill, and for the rest of the newspaper world: that particular genie is already out of the bottle and has been for some time now. As journalism professor Jay Rosen has argued, <a href="http://pressthink.org/2010/11/the-view-from-nowhere-questions-and-answers/">the &#8220;view from nowhere&#8221;</a> that mainstream media continues to defend is not only dying, but arguably does readers a disservice &#8212; since it often distorts the news in order to maintain a perfectly balanced view of events. Although some journalists have started to <a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2011/04/the-view-from-somewhere/73386/">admit they have personal interests and causes</a>, that remains rare.</p>
<p>But the main point being missed is that social media is powerful precisely <em>because it is personal</em>. If you remove the personal aspect, all you have is a glorified news release wire or RSS feed. The best way to make social media work is to allow reporters and editors to be themselves, to be human, and to engage with readers through Twitter and Facebook and comments and blogs. Is there a risk that someone might say something wrong? Of course there is. But without that human touch, there is no point in doing it at all.</p>
<p><strong>Update</strong>: Toronto Star spokesman Bob Hepburn got back to me and said that the paper&#8217;s policy was &#8220;well in line with what mainstream media organizations have always done. We&#8217;ve always placed some limitations on journalists in terms of them expressing their opinions, either in the newspaper or outside of the newspaper.&#8221;</p>
<p><script type="text/javascript">(function() { var scribd = document.createElement("script"); scribd.type = "text/javascript"; scribd.async = true; scribd.src = "http://www.scribd.com/javascripts/embed_code/inject.js"; var s = document.getElementsByTagName("script")[0]; s.parentNode.insertBefore(scribd, s); })();</script></p>
<p><em>Post and thumbnail photos <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/deed.en">courtesy</a> of Flickr users <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/phobia/2308371224/">Hans Gerwitz</a> and <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/zarkodrincic/2117512295/">Zarko Drincic</a></em></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/326178/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/326178/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/326178/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/326178/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/326178/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/326178/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/326178/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/326178/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/326178/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/326178/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/326178/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/326178/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/326178/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/326178/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=326178&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://gigaom.com/2011/04/05/newspapers-and-social-media-still-not-really-getting-it/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>30</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/0bdf7ab171ade0708a11fa3378e6d8cb?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F0.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mathewingram</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gigaom2.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/2308371224_60e0cda6e8_z.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2308371224_60e0cda6e8_z</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gigaom2.files.wordpress.com/2010/09/2117512295_24e409bf9d_z.png?w=210" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2117512295_24e409bf9d_z</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>mostly downtown, in black and white.</title>
		<link>http://ruinista.com/2011/03/21/mostly-downtown-in-black-and-white/</link>
		<comments>http://ruinista.com/2011/03/21/mostly-downtown-in-black-and-white/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2011 18:52:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Hong-An</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[friends]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nyc]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ruinista.com/?p=1827</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[- - - - - - - - - - - -Okay, so the very top one was taken at MoMA. And the bottom one is in Prospect Heights. But all of the other photographs &#8212; including ones of my deal friends Michael (visiting from Toronto) and Shannon, shot on Fuji Neopan 400 with the [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=1827&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1828" src="http://ruinista.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/moma-bw.jpg?w=600&#038;h=400" alt="" width="600" height="400" /></p>
<p><span style="color:#ffffff;">-</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#ffffff;">-</span></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1833" src="http://ruinista.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/michael-bw.jpg?w=600&#038;h=400" alt="" width="600" height="400" /></p>
<p><span style="color:#ffffff;">-</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#ffffff;">-</span></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1831" src="http://ruinista.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/chinatown-2-bw.jpg?w=600&#038;h=400" alt="" width="600" height="400" /></p>
<p><span style="color:#ffffff;">-</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#ffffff;">-</span></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1831" src="http://ruinista.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/shannon-bw.jpg?w=600&#038;h=400" alt="" width="600" height="400" /></p>
<p><span style="color:#ffffff;">-</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#ffffff;">-</span></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1831" src="http://ruinista.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/chinatown-1-bw.jpg?w=600&#038;h=400" alt="" width="600" height="400" /></p>
<p><span style="color:#ffffff;">-</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#ffffff;">-</span></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1831" src="http://ruinista.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/couch-bw.jpg?w=600&#038;h=400" alt="" width="600" height="400" /></p>
<p><span style="color:#ffffff;">-</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#ffffff;">-</span>Okay, so the very top one was taken at MoMA. And the bottom one is in Prospect Heights. But all of the other photographs &#8212; including ones of my deal friends Michael (visiting from Toronto) and Shannon, shot on Fuji Neopan 400 with the Zeiss Biogon, on Peter&#8217;s Leica &#8212; were taken below Houston Street. Leicas love black and white, goodness me!</p>
<p>Speaking of which: my Leica finally has a name. More on that soon.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1827/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1827/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1827/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1827/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1827/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1827/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1827/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1827/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1827/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1827/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1827/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1827/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1827/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1827/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=1827&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://ruinista.com/2011/03/21/mostly-downtown-in-black-and-white/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/a977f4c8374bc04de6c39670a4a3d854?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ruinista</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ruinista.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/moma-bw.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://ruinista.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/michael-bw.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://ruinista.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/chinatown-2-bw.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://ruinista.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/shannon-bw.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://ruinista.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/chinatown-1-bw.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://ruinista.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/couch-bw.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>On Students Grading Their Own Tests</title>
		<link>http://shiftingphases.com/2011/04/04/on-students-grading-their-own-tests/</link>
		<comments>http://shiftingphases.com/2011/04/04/on-students-grading-their-own-tests/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2011 03:59:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Mylene</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Classroom Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Grades]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Grades are not the point]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://shiftingphases.com/?p=757</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In the “why didn’t I think of this before” category: my students now grade their own quizzes. No, they don&#8217;t get to give themselves whatever mark they want.  Here&#8217;s how it goes. I used to learn a ton from going over their tests with a fine toothed comb, trying to figure out what they were [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=757&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the “why didn’t I think of this before” category: my students now grade their own quizzes. No, they don&#8217;t get to give themselves whatever mark they want.  Here&#8217;s how it goes.<strong><br />
</strong></p>
<p>I used to learn a ton from going over their tests with a fine toothed  comb, trying to figure out what they were having trouble with.  It  finally dawned on me that I didn’t need that learning opportunity nearly  as much as my students did. So my students now do quizzes like this.</p>
<ol>
<li>Write quiz.</li>
<li>Copy all answers to the provided answer sheet.</li>
<li>Hand in answer sheet to teacher.  Keep question sheet with all your work on it!</li>
<li>Twiddle thumbs for a few minutes waiting for everyone to finish.  Wish you could ask someone “what did you get for #5?”</li>
<li>All papers are in.  Burst at the seams and ask “what’s the answer to 5!?”</li>
<li>Participate in class or small-group discussion of questions and  answers.  Compare your problem-solving approach to others’.  Figure out  what you did right.  Figure out what you did wrong.  Make notes about  how to do #5 differently, since now that you’ve found your  misunderstandings or found new ways to tackle the question, you’re  already planning to reassess next Wednesday.</li>
<li>Put checkmarks on <a title="How I Grade" href="http://shiftingphases.com/how-i-grade/" target="_blank">skill sheet</a>.</li>
</ol>
<p>I love this because it allows the students to go over the problems  immediately after the test, during those 7 minutes of burning curiosity,  yet still have their own test paper in front of them.  They remember  what they did and why they did it (by tomorrow it’ll be gone into the  ether of “oh, just a careless mistake” or “I understand it now”).  The  downside is that they have to copy their answers from the question sheet  to the answer sheet, which can take time.  I collect the answer sheets  before the discussion/review, grade them on a complete/incomplete basis,  and update my gradebook.</p>
<p>Because each person needs to know whether their answer meets the  standard, they share.  This gets into a great discussion of the many  possible right answers.  If I hand the tests back already graded,  there’s no incentive to share.  Downside: you must risk speaking up and  exposing a possibly flawed answer.  Upside: everyone else is doing it.   Sometimes the top students get things wrong, and take a good-natured  drubbing, and it becomes more clear that smartness isn’t a magical  quality that enables you to skip the “learning” phase of the learning.</p>
<p>Every once in a while, I collect the work sheets after we’re done    reviewing.  It lets me see how they’re doing with grading their tests    and writing feedback to themselves.  It also lets me have a look at the    common misconceptions and confusions (although mostly I collect   in-class  work for that kind of intel).</p>
<p>Unexpected discovery: <strong>their negative self-talk shows up in their corrections</strong>.     I was blown away by the brutality of the things they were writing to    themselves.  (“Stop being a moron!”  “Stupid, stupid, stupid!”).     Collecting the work sheets gives me a chance to write back to them, try    to interrupt negative self-talk, and do some coaching about    self-assessment.</p>
<p>When they request reassessments, the web form I use has a spot for &#8220;What have you learned about this skill that you didn&#8217;t know before.&#8221;  The answers there are almost as enlightening, and have evolved from &#8220;I learned that I am stupid&#8221; to &#8220;I learned that capacitors in parallel do not get added up if they have been converted to reactance.&#8221;  All of these things become the beginnings of conversations.</p>
<br /> Tagged: <a href='http://shiftingphases.com/tag/classroom-life/'>Classroom Life</a>, <a href='http://shiftingphases.com/tag/grades/'>Grades</a>, <a href='http://shiftingphases.com/tag/grades-are-not-the-point/'>Grades are not the point</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/757/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/757/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/757/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/757/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/757/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/757/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/757/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/757/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/757/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/757/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/757/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/757/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/757/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/757/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=757&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://shiftingphases.com/2011/04/04/on-students-grading-their-own-tests/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/5514b25517fe51bf7db79aad86de3d70?s=96&#38;d=retro&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">shiftingphases</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Psycho-Bunnies and Fiction: Using Animals in Your Writing</title>
		<link>http://lanternhollow.wordpress.com/2011/04/05/psycho-bunnies-and-fiction-using-animals-in-your-writing/</link>
		<comments>http://lanternhollow.wordpress.com/2011/04/05/psycho-bunnies-and-fiction-using-animals-in-your-writing/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2011 04:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Melissa</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cliches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dragons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fantasy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lantern Hollow Press Authors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Melissa Rogers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing Hints and Helps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ALL THE BUNNIES]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[animals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[avoiding cliches in writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bunnies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dragons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fantasy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[more bunnies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[puppies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sheep]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing helps and hints]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://lanternhollow.wordpress.com/?p=3000</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Some of you are cat people and some of you are dog people.  Some of you don’t like either (you are sad, sad individuals).  I am definitely an animal person.  From hamsters to gerbils to dogs to cats to rabbits to Peking ducks,  my pets have been varied and interesting.  My current roommate and nemesis, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=3000&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_3001" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://lanternhollow.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/dscf3595.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-3001" title="Bella Bunny cute rabbit" src="http://lanternhollow.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/dscf3595.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Bella sleeps... dreaming of carrots... and world domination</p></div>
<p>Some of you are cat people and some of you are dog people.  Some of you don’t like either (you are sad, sad individuals).  I am definitely an animal person.  From hamsters to gerbils to dogs to cats to rabbits to Peking ducks,  my pets have been varied and interesting.  My current roommate and nemesis, Bella the Terrible, is a wonderful companion, mostly because her dark little bunny stare of doom is so utterly adorable.</p>
<p>Writing fiction often involves writing animals into the story.  Sometimes, it is a necessity.  Think about your typical fantasy novel.  Horses are pretty much a given.  You might put your characters on some other form of transportation if you are being excessively creative, but most likely they are riding horses.</p>
<div id="attachment_3004" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 235px"><a href="http://lanternhollow.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/dscf3347.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-3004" title="shih tzu yorkie maltese mix puppy eowyn" src="http://lanternhollow.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/dscf3347.jpg?w=225&#038;h=300" alt="" width="225" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Eowyn says: &quot;I can haz scene in your story?&quot;</p></div>
<p>Then, there are the hawks that your noble heroes ride with, their loyal companion hounds, the sardonic cats lounging throught the houses of magic-users, the dragons that lurk in caves (my <em>favorite!</em>), the savage wolves that plague the woods, and the various other creatures that come along to help or hinder the heroes and heroines along their journey.</p>
<p>We often put animals in our fantasy stories because they are necessary.  However, we also add them because they are fun.  They add color to the story.  You know what I’m talking about:</p>
<ul>
<li>The half-wolf/half-cocker spaniel named after an ancient hero whose massive teeth can shred a highway robber or bring down a convenient deer for dinner.  Of course, he’s also very good with children.</li>
<li>The grumpy, fat horse who steals food and sleeps on his back.</li>
<li>The enchanted bird companion who may or may not have once been a human but is now a sentient avian who carries messages and spies on the enemy</li>
</ul>
<p>I could go on.  Animal characters can be very entertaining.  They can also be annoying and very cliché if the writer is not exceedingly cautious.  Like the comic relief character that shows up for no apparent reason and cracks jokes at all the wrong moments, an animal side-kick can become an unwelcome addition to the story, and so if you choose to add one, do so with care.</p>
<div id="attachment_3002" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://lanternhollow.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/dscf2884.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-3002" title="White sheep with a black face" src="http://lanternhollow.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/dscf2884.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">This sheep is necessary for your plot.  Really.  You must include him in your story.  His name is Stanley, by the way.</p></div>
<p>Now, you could easily make the animal somehow integral to the plot.  Perhaps the sentient avian companion <em>was </em>human once and part of the hero’s quest is to return the bird to its former shape.  Just be sure that it is, in fact, a necessary, or at least believable, plot addition.</p>
<p>If you really only added the animal in as an interesting bit of variety to your story, take great care not to overdo your creature-character’s charm and adorableness or make your character spend too much time fawning, worrying, or thinking about said animal side-kick.  Otherwise, your reader might just hope that a stray arrow will take down the sentient avian, providing plenty of delightful angst while also ridding the story of an annoying distraction from the main plot.</p>
<p>I freely admit that my love of animals gives me the predisposition for tossing in the random animal character into my story.  <em>Mikaela </em>has her violently inclined horse Pride.  My <em>Dagger of Bane Story </em>had Lord Dervish, the werepoodle.  I’ve written two stories centered around Cupcake, the cat (or <em>is </em>he?), though he was a main character rather than an addition, so that probably doesn’t count.  I just happen to love animals and I am constantly resisting the urge to flood my stories with fabulous pets and creatures.</p>
<p>Using animals in stories is not wrong.  Rather, it is like so many things in writing: dangerous.  An animal that is integrated well into a story will be amusing or interesting enough that the reader will enjoy the moments that it enters the picture and perhaps wonder about it when it is absent.  A certain dragon in Stephanie’s story comes to mind, along with a squabbit in Brian’s.</p>
<div id="attachment_3003" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 271px"><a href="http://lanternhollow.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/dscf2954.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-3003" title="omg bunnies!" src="http://lanternhollow.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/dscf2954.jpg?w=261&#038;h=187" alt="" width="261" height="187" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Oh my gosh BUNNIES!  Must put bunnies in story.  ALL THE BUNNIES!</p></div>
<p>Animals have their place in stories.  Just don’t overdo it.  We don’t need to read the Saga of Freddy the Fluffiest Rabbit’s Cutest Moments Ever when we are expecting to hear about Alphonso the Awesomest Hero’s Quest to Save the World.</p>
<p>Okay… so maybe we <em>might </em>want to hear more about Freddy because, come on, a cute, fluffy rabbit!!!  But, for now, let Alphonso have his day and keep Freddy in the background.  (Or you could have Alphonso eat Freddy because, you know, he’s starving and he had to and we would weep, my friends, <em>weep! </em>Thus, providing delightful angst and drama to the story.)</p>
<p>So, my question for you:  What animals in fiction have you enjoyed as side-kicks to the heroes and what animals were, quite frankly, just annoyances?  (PS – You can’t use Narnia creatures.  They don’t count.)</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3000/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3000/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3000/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3000/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3000/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3000/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3000/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3000/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3000/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3000/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3000/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3000/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3000/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3000/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=3000&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://lanternhollow.wordpress.com/2011/04/05/psycho-bunnies-and-fiction-using-animals-in-your-writing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>20</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/bc0418cf89b1121d0bed9e8bcf4cc338?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">theninjabunny</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lanternhollow.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/dscf3595.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Bella Bunny cute rabbit</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lanternhollow.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/dscf3347.jpg?w=225" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">shih tzu yorkie maltese mix puppy eowyn</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lanternhollow.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/dscf2884.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">White sheep with a black face</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lanternhollow.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/dscf2954.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">omg bunnies!</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Paella &#8211; Fiesta in a pan till the morning after&#8230;</title>
		<link>http://purplecalabash.wordpress.com/2011/03/27/paella-fiesta-in-a-pan-till-the-morning-after/</link>
		<comments>http://purplecalabash.wordpress.com/2011/03/27/paella-fiesta-in-a-pan-till-the-morning-after/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2011 09:35:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ana le Roux</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA["food photography"]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chicken]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[feast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fiesta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mussels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oysters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[paella]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[party]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[picnic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recipe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[seafood]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://purplecalabash.wordpress.com/?p=524</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The great thing about food and recipes is that you can add one or two local ingredients of your own and a new recipe is born. I guess that is the way many great recipes come about today. Like music and ideas, not many are truly originals anymore. Paella is one of those traditional Spanish [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=524&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://purplecalabash.wordpress.com/2011/03/27/paella-fiesta-in-a-pan-till-the-morning-after/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/790f31afc8187f7a8652e97fd6a4f91b?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">analeroux</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://purplecalabash.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/paella-2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Paella</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://purplecalabash.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/lanterns1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Lanterns1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://purplecalabash.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/lanterns2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Lanterns2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://purplecalabash.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/paella-prawns.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Paella prawns</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Whoa, baby: DIY lampshades</title>
		<link>http://splashofsomething.com/2011/04/05/whoa-baby-diy-lampshades/</link>
		<comments>http://splashofsomething.com/2011/04/05/whoa-baby-diy-lampshades/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2011 15:50:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Katrina Tauchen</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Adventures in decorating]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://splashofsomething.com/?p=1410</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Last weekend, Jared and I skipped town and hopped over to Salt Lake City for a visit with our friends Daniel and Amber and their new baby boy. It was a great weekend trip. I brought home gobs of photos of the so-so-cute-you-can-hardly-believe-it little Levi, and poor Jared brought home a mean sunburn (courtesy of [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=1410&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://splashofsomething.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/lampshade1.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1413" title="Lampshade" src="http://splashofsomething.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/lampshade1.jpg?w=490&#038;h=326" alt="" width="490" height="326" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://splashofsomething.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/lampshade1.jpg"></a>Last weekend, Jared and I skipped town and hopped over to Salt Lake City for a visit with our friends Daniel and Amber and their new baby boy. It was a great weekend trip. I brought home gobs of photos of the so-so-cute-you-can-hardly-believe-it little Levi, and poor Jared brought home a mean sunburn (courtesy of skiing sans sunscreen on a 60-degree day. Lesson learned.)</p>
<p>Amidst the general Salt Lake City-ing and baby-loving business, Amber and I took a day to do a little DIYing with a pair of white lampshades she had up in Levi’s room. The baby room is crazy adorable: lots of blues, browns, whites and elephants. But Amber was hoping to jazz up the plain lampshades with a fun new fabric, so we hit up Michael’s for a few supplies and then swung by Jo-Ann’s, where Amber spotted the perfect fabric for our project. After ooing and ahhing about it for a few minutes, we realized it was a Dwell Studio design. Go figure. Those folks know their stuff.</p>
<p>If you have the burning desire to recover a lampshade in your place (baby room or otherwise), this is really worth giving a try. The project took us about an hour a shade, but with a few minor adjustments, you could probably get the job done a bit speedier. Here’s how we did it:</p>
<p><a href="http://splashofsomething.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/supplies1.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1414" title="Supplies" src="http://splashofsomething.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/supplies1.jpg?w=490&#038;h=326" alt="" width="490" height="326" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://splashofsomething.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/supplies1.jpg"></a>The supply list is fairly minimal: plain white (or another super light color) cylindrical lampshades, hot glue gun, high-temp hot glue (so it doesn’t melt the shade or fabric), measuring tape, scissors and ribbon.</p>
<p><a href="http://splashofsomething.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/supplies3.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1415" title="Supplies3" src="http://splashofsomething.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/supplies3.jpg?w=490&#038;h=326" alt="" width="490" height="326" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://splashofsomething.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/supplies3.jpg"></a>Important tip: This project would be a gazillion times simpler if you buy lampshades that are perfect cylinders (i.e. they are the same circumference on the top rim and bottom rim). The ones we used were slightly narrower on the top than the bottom, and though they turned out OK in the end, we did have to do a little tweaking and patchwork to make the final project presentable.</p>
<p><a href="http://splashofsomething.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/measuring.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1416" title="Measuring" src="http://splashofsomething.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/measuring.jpg?w=490&#038;h=326" alt="" width="490" height="326" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://splashofsomething.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/measuring.jpg"></a>Start by measuring the lampshade’s height and circumference, then add 2 inches to each. Those will be the measurements for your fabric pieces. For example, our shades were 6 ½ inches tall with a circumference of 30 ½ inches, so we cut our fabric into two 8 ½-by-32 ½-inch pieces.</p>
<p><a href="http://splashofsomething.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/wrapping.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1417" title="Wrapping" src="http://splashofsomething.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/wrapping.jpg?w=427&#038;h=640" alt="" width="427" height="640" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://splashofsomething.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/wrapping.jpg"></a>Using dots of hot glue, attach one end of the fabric along the seam of the lampshade. Again, this is much easier if the lampshade is a perfect cylinder; in that case you can run the fabric end straight along the seam. If your shade isn’t a perfect cylinder, you’ll have to start it at a wonkier angle. Do a few practice wraps before gluing to make sure the fabric will wrap properly.</p>
<p>Using dots of hot glue, slowly work your way around by gluing the fabric to the shade (to avoid lots of bumpy glue under the fabric, we kept most of the gluing to about an eighth of an inch from the shade’s top and bottom). Pull the fabric as tight as you can during this part of the process. If you have any visible wrinkles, it’s worth pulling it up and trying again. The tighter/smoother the fabric, the better (a.k.a. less homemade-y) your finished product will look.</p>
<p><a href="http://splashofsomething.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/lampshadeend.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1419" title="LampshadeEnd" src="http://splashofsomething.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/lampshadeend.jpg?w=490&#038;h=326" alt="" width="490" height="326" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://splashofsomething.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/lampshadeend.jpg"></a>If you are using a shade that’s slightly narrower on top, there’s a good chance you’ll be left with a less than perfect seam like us. We used a second fabric (a matching polka dot print) to make a vertical patch down the length of the shade. Just make sure you fold over the edges of the second fabric to make clean seams down the sides.</p>
<p><a href="http://splashofsomething.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/lampshadeends2.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1421" title="LampshadeEnds2" src="http://splashofsomething.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/lampshadeends2.jpg?w=490&#038;h=326" alt="" width="490" height="326" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://splashofsomething.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/lampshadeends2.jpg"></a>Once the fabric is all glued into place, you might be left with a rough-looking top. To fix this, we found matching green ribbon and lined the outside and inside of the top of the shade (we used hot glue again to attach it).</p>
<p><a href="http://splashofsomething.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/lampshade2.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1422" title="Lampshade2" src="http://splashofsomething.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/lampshade2.jpg?w=427&#038;h=640" alt="" width="427" height="640" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://splashofsomething.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/lampshade2.jpg"></a>A few hours later, and voilà! A totally custom shade that adds the perfect splash of color to an already adorable baby room!</p>
<p><a href="http://splashofsomething.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/fabric-in-frame.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1423" title="Fabric in Frame" src="http://splashofsomething.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/fabric-in-frame.jpg?w=490&#038;h=486" alt="" width="490" height="486" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://splashofsomething.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/fabric-in-frame.jpg"></a>And if you have any leftover fabric from your DIY shenanigans, you can stick it in a frame for automatic artwork. Woo hoo to that!</p>
<p>So what’s DIYing in your neck of the woods these days? Any new projects underway? Or ideas still in the planning stages? Any fellow lampshade coverers with tips to share? Let’s hear it!</p>
<p>XO,<br />
Katrina</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1410/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1410/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1410/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1410/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1410/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1410/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1410/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1410/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1410/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1410/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1410/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1410/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1410/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1410/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=1410&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://splashofsomething.com/2011/04/05/whoa-baby-diy-lampshades/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/a32e3525d16671a7fab3ef7f59372941?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">happygowritten</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://splashofsomething.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/lampshade1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Lampshade</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://splashofsomething.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/supplies1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Supplies</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://splashofsomething.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/supplies3.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Supplies3</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://splashofsomething.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/measuring.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Measuring</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://splashofsomething.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/wrapping.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Wrapping</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://splashofsomething.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/lampshadeend.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">LampshadeEnd</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://splashofsomething.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/lampshadeends2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">LampshadeEnds2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://splashofsomething.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/lampshade2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Lampshade2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://splashofsomething.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/fabric-in-frame.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Fabric in Frame</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Keep your eyes to yourself</title>
		<link>http://persquaremile.com/2011/03/29/keep-your-eyes-to-yourself/</link>
		<comments>http://persquaremile.com/2011/03/29/keep-your-eyes-to-yourself/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2011 15:51:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Tim De Chant</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cities]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Population]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Small Towns]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Suburbia]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://persquaremile.com/?p=925</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There’s an unwritten rule followed by nearly all city dwellers—never make eye contact. If you attempt to do so, your glance will be met with utter disregard. You do not exist, other than being an object to avoid. I learned this the hard way. Upon moving to San Francisco from Minnesota—the friendliest of all possible [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=925&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-928" title="Crowded sidewalk in New York City" src="http://persquaremile.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/crowded-sidwalk-new-york-city.jpg?w=600&#038;h=404" alt="Crowded sidewalk in New York City" width="600" height="404" /></p>
<p>There’s an unwritten rule followed by nearly all city dwellers—never make eye contact. If you attempt to do so, your glance will be met with utter disregard. You do not exist, other than being an object to avoid. I learned this the hard way. Upon moving to San Francisco from Minnesota—the friendliest of all possible places—I would attempt to make eye contact with strangers on the street out of courtesy. In Minnesota, this is commonplace. There, my glances were often met with a polite smile or a courteous “hello.” In San Francisco—even on streets that were anything but crowded—they were ignored with complete indifference.</p>
<p>Imagine, then, my surprise when I learned of San Francisco’s reputation as a friendly city. If San Francisco is considered friendly, I thought, then I’m steering clear of New York. I mused that such indifference to others must be an artifact of city life. That’s not to say there aren’t friendly people there—it’s true that San Franciscans are a generally genial bunch once you get them off the sidewalk, as are the New Yorkers I’ve met and nearly every other person from a big city. But when I’m in a small town, things sure do feel different. Walking down the street is no longer a sterile affair. It’s no family reunion, but it is degrees warmer than in cities. Still, my own experiences weren’t enough to convince me that this could be a universal trend.</p>
<p>Luckily, my hunch was proved correct the other day by a study which compared the rates of eye contact among people in central Philadelphia, suburban Bryn Mawr, and rural Parkesburg. The study’s authors parked two college students—a guy and a girl—outside a post office and a store in each location for two hours. The students counted the number of people who made eye contact and if anyone said “hello,” “how are you,” or the like. Lo and behold, rural Parkesburg held true to the small town stereotype. Between 70 and 80 percent of passersby glanced at the stationary students in the Parkesburg, while just 10 to 20 percent did in Philadelphia. Bryn Mawr’s pedestrians fell predictably in the middle, with around 40 to 50 percent making eye contact.</p>
<p>The rural types were also much more likely to say something to the strangers. One quarter of people in Parkesburg opened their mouths in greeting, while just three percent did for Bryn Mawr and Philadelphia combined. (The city center was by far the least friendly—only one person said something to each person at both the post office and the store.) In addition, everyone who did say something did make eye contact.</p>
<p>The study’s authors contemplated a few possible explanations for why the city dwellers were so hesitant to make eye contact. They favored the sensory overload hypothesis—that people in big cities are surrounded by too many people, noises, and other distractions—though they also speculated that city folk may fear strangers more or that small town people may be more curious about strangers. They also touched on the idea that city people are more hurried than either suburban or small town people. This notion has been covered both before and since by a number of different researchers. In general, people in larger cities do tend to walk faster, so there may be some truth to this.</p>
<p>Whatever the reason, I admit I exhaled a slight sigh of relief when I discovered that science confirmed my suspicions. San Franciscans, New Yorkers, Londoners—no matter how friendly they are underneath, suffer the same aversion to eye contact as other big cities. Small towns do feel friendlier.</p>
<p><em>Sources:</em></p>
<p><span class="Z3988" title="ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Ajournal&amp;rft.jtitle=Environment+and+Behavior&amp;rft_id=info%3Adoi%2F10.1177%2F001391657794006&amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fresearchblogging.org&amp;rft.atitle=Eye+Contact+with+Strangers+in+City%2C+Suburb%2C+and+Small+Town&amp;rft.issn=0013-9165&amp;rft.date=1977&amp;rft.volume=9&amp;rft.issue=4&amp;rft.spage=547&amp;rft.epage=558&amp;rft.artnum=http%3A%2F%2Feab.sagepub.com%2Fcgi%2Fdoi%2F10.1177%2F001391657794006&amp;rft.au=Newman%2C+J.&amp;rft.au=McCauley%2C+C.&amp;rfe_dat=bpr3.included=1;bpr3.tags=Psychology%2CSocial+Science%2CSocial+Psychology%2C+Geography%2C+Sociology">Newman, J., &amp; McCauley, C. (1977). Eye Contact with Strangers in City, Suburb, and Small Town <span style="font-style:italic;">Environment and Behavior, 9</span> (4), 547-558 DOI: <a rev="review" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1177/001391657794006">10.1177/001391657794006</a></span></p>
<p><span class="Z3988" title="ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Ajournal&amp;rft.jtitle=Nature&amp;rft_id=info%3Adoi%2F10.1038%2F259557a0&amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fresearchblogging.org&amp;rft.atitle=The+pace+of+life&amp;rft.issn=0028-0836&amp;rft.date=1976&amp;rft.volume=259&amp;rft.issue=5544&amp;rft.spage=557&amp;rft.epage=559&amp;rft.artnum=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.nature.com%2Fdoifinder%2F10.1038%2F259557a0&amp;rft.au=Bornstein%2C+M.&amp;rft.au=Bornstein%2C+H.&amp;rfe_dat=bpr3.included=1;bpr3.tags=Social+Science%2CGeography%2C+Sociology">Bornstein, M., &amp; Bornstein, H. (1976). The pace of life <span style="font-style:italic;">Nature, 259</span> (5544), 557-559 DOI: <a rev="review" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/259557a0">10.1038/259557a0</a></span></p>
<p><span class="Z3988" title="ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Ajournal&amp;rft.jtitle=International+Journal+of+Psychology&amp;rft_id=info%3Adoi%2F10.1080%2F00207597908246715&amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fresearchblogging.org&amp;rft.atitle=The+Pace+of+Life%3A+Revisited&amp;rft.issn=0020-7594&amp;rft.date=1979&amp;rft.volume=14&amp;rft.issue=1&amp;rft.spage=83&amp;rft.epage=90&amp;rft.artnum=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.informaworld.com%2Fopenurl%3Fgenre%3Darticle%26doi%3D10.1080%2F00207597908246715%26magic%3Dcrossref%7C%7CD404A21C5BB053405B1A640AFFD44AE3&amp;rft.au=Bornstein%2C+M.&amp;rfe_dat=bpr3.included=1;bpr3.tags=Social+Science%2CGeography%2C+Sociology">Bornstein, M. (1979). The Pace of Life: Revisited <span style="font-style:italic;">International Journal of Psychology, 14</span> (1), 83-90 DOI: <a rev="review" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/00207597908246715">10.1080/00207597908246715</a></span></p>
<p><span class="Z3988" title="ctx_ver=Z39.88-2004&amp;rft_val_fmt=info%3Aofi%2Ffmt%3Akev%3Amtx%3Ajournal&amp;rft.jtitle=Behaviour&amp;rft_id=info%3Adoi%2F10.1163%2F156853992X00129&amp;rfr_id=info%3Asid%2Fresearchblogging.org&amp;rft.atitle=The+Pace+of+Life+-+Reanalysed%3A+Why+Does+Walking+Speed+of+Pedestrians+Correlate+With+City+Size%3F&amp;rft.issn=00057959&amp;rft.date=1992&amp;rft.volume=123&amp;rft.issue=1&amp;rft.spage=77&amp;rft.epage=83&amp;rft.artnum=http%3A%2F%2Fopenurl.ingenta.com%2Fcontent%2Fxref%3Fgenre%3Darticle%26issn%3D0005-7959%26volume%3D123%26issue%3D1%26spage%3D77&amp;rft.au=Wirtz%2C+P.&amp;rft.au=Ries%2C+G.&amp;rfe_dat=bpr3.included=1;bpr3.tags=Social+Science%2CGeography%2C+Sociology">Wirtz, P., &amp; Ries, G. (1992). The Pace of Life &#8211; Reanalysed: Why Does Walking Speed of Pedestrians Correlate With City Size? <span style="font-style:italic;">Behaviour, 123</span> (1), 77-83 DOI: <a rev="review" href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1163/156853992X00129">10.1163/156853992X00129</a></span></p>
<p><em>Photo by <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/en321/2943652353/" target="_blank">Susan NYC</a>.</em></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/925/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/925/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/925/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/925/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/925/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/925/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/925/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/925/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/925/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/925/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/925/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/925/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/925/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/925/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=925&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://persquaremile.com/2011/03/29/keep-your-eyes-to-yourself/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>101</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">timdechant</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://persquaremile.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/crowded-sidwalk-new-york-city.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Crowded sidewalk in New York City</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>