<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2012 00:02:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Breaking Bad &amp; Walter White’s “Song of Myself”</title>
		<link>http://filmrascal.wordpress.com/2012/09/03/breaking-bad-and-walter-whites-song-of-myself/</link>
		<comments>http://filmrascal.wordpress.com/2012/09/03/breaking-bad-and-walter-whites-song-of-myself/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2012 05:42:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>JoAnn, film rascal</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[breaking bad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[walt whitman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[walter white]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://filmrascal.wordpress.com/?p=416</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;Do I contradict myself? Very well then, I contradict myself. (I am large, I contain multitudes.)&#8221; &#8211; Walt Whitman, &#8220;Song of Myself&#8221; from Leaves of Grass Disclosure: As Jesse Pinkman might say, this writeup has mad spoilers for the half-season finale, yo. Read at your own risk. &#8220;Breaking Bad&#8221; has made many allusions to poet [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=416&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://filmrascal.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/episode-8-walt-034571-23459087-1934857015-654943546548-64565.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-424" title="episode-8-walt-034571-23459087-1934857015-654943546548-64565" src="http://filmrascal.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/episode-8-walt-034571-23459087-1934857015-654943546548-64565.jpg?w=348&h=245" alt="" width="348" height="245" /></a></p>
<p><em>&#8220;Do I contradict myself? Very well then, I contradict myself. (I am large, I contain multitudes.)&#8221; &#8211; Walt Whitman, &#8220;Song of Myself&#8221; from Leaves of Grass</em></p>
<p><strong>Disclosure: As Jesse Pinkman might say, this writeup has mad spoilers for the half-season finale, yo. Read at your own risk.</strong></p>
<p>&#8220;Breaking Bad&#8221; has made many allusions to poet Walt Whitman&#8217;s work and the show writers have connected these poems to the actions of the show&#8217;s anti-hero, the closely-named Walter White. In seasons 3 and 4, Walt&#8217;s relationship with his would-be-meth-lab-turned-murder victim Gale Boetticher is summed up in Gale&#8217;s notebook scribblings of &#8220;When I heard the learn&#8217;d astronomer.&#8221; These notes are later found by Walt&#8217;s DEA brother-in-law Hank, who wonders who the elusive &#8220;W.W.&#8221; is, and Walt quickly pins Gale&#8217;s notebook worship on the poet, and not on himself.</p>
<div id="attachment_425" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 150px"><a href="http://filmrascal.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/acf2964.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-425 " title="ACF2964" src="http://filmrascal.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/acf2964.jpg" alt="the original heisenberg?" width="140" height="168" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Walt Whitman, in a hat that Heisenberg would covet.</p></div>
<p>The Whitman influence was never as potent as last night&#8217;s half-season finale, &#8220;Gliding Over All,&#8221; when Hank finds out who the real &#8220;W.W.&#8221; is after he skims an inscribed copy of  &#8221;Leaves of Grass&#8221; (once given by Gale to Walter)  that was left rather carelessly in Walter&#8217;s bathroom, presumably left there by Walt (perhaps for some late-night commode sessions). The episode was all about Walter making his family &#8220;legitimate&#8221; (Michael Corleone-style) as he &#8220;Godfather&#8221;-ed a hit on Gus&#8217; old crew in jail and made good on his promise to Skyler that their family could reap safety and security in Walt&#8217;s meth-sowing.  The episode is named for a Whitman poem, and the title seems to reference Walter&#8217;s deity-like power in creating and controlling deaths around him:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;GLIDING o&#8217;er all, through all,<br />
Through Nature, Time, and Space,<br />
As a ship on the waters advancing,<br />
The voyage of the soul&#8211;not life alone,<br />
Death, many deaths I&#8217;ll sing.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>With all of these Whitman references, it&#8217;s not hard to imagine that perhaps Walter has been taking cues from <a href="http://www.english.illinois.edu/Maps/poets/s_z/whitman/song.htm">the poem &#8220;Song of Myself&#8221;</a> throughout this season and it would perhaps give better insight to his actions. &#8220;Song of Myself,&#8221; a poem found in &#8220;Leaves of Grass,&#8221; is a celebration of self &#8212; as an omniscient, universal form of self. By all means, I am no Whitman scholar or expert, but after reading this poem, it seems prescient in Walter&#8217;s actions this season. Let&#8217;s take a look at some of the lines, shall we?</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;I CELEBRATE myself, and sing myself,<br />
And what I assume you shall assume&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;If I worship one thing more than another it shall be the spread<br />
of my own body&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>This entire season has been about Walter assuming his alter-ego Heisenberg fulltime in the aftermath of Gus&#8217; murder. He becomes cocksure in his words and actions with his partners Jesse and Mike. Walter lords over Skyler and keeps her captive and complicit in their marriage. He buys himself expensive cars and flaunts large purchases to  Hank. Walter&#8217;s ego has become godlike.</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;I, now thirty-seven years old in perfect health begin,<br />
Hoping to cease not till death.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Walter is 51 years old and he&#8217;s nowhere near perfect health because of his yearlong battle with cancer &#8212; this much is true. However, he finds a certain stamina from continuing to cook meth. Even when he gets out of debt to Jesse and makes thousands (and later, presumably millions as evidenced by Skyler&#8217;s mad stacks of storage unit cash), Walter finds great joy in cooking and tries to drive his partners to continue even when it becomes increasingly dangerous to stay in the business. Walter has escaped death many times on the show, and he himself has been the cause or catalyst for death. Until last night&#8217;s episode, he probably would have continued cooking until his death, if not for Skyler&#8217;s insistence to stop.</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;I harbor for good or bad, I permit to speak at every hazard,<br />
Nature without check with original energy.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Walter&#8217;s narcissism is out of control this season. He threatens new business associates. And when his partners are out (Mike murdered by Walter&#8217;s hand and Jesse through his own decision to get the hell out), Walter is nature without check. &#8221;"There is no &#8216;we,&#8217; Jesse,&#8221; Walter tells his former partner in the final episode. &#8220;I am the only vote left.&#8221; This is never more clear when Walter orders a massive jail hit, seemingly inspired by &#8220;The Godfather&#8221; when Michael Corleone orders the deaths of the heads of the five Mob families. He&#8217;s taken cues from gangster movies this season, and has become a don, a god, in his own mind. Walter White is a mere mortal, but Heisenberg could live forever in the &#8220;empire-making business.&#8221;</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;I breathe the fragrance myself and know it and like it,<br />
The distillation would intoxicate me also, but I shall not let it.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;I will go to the bank by the wood and become undisguised<br />
and naked,<br />
I am mad for it to be in contact with me.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;I wear my hat as I please indoors or out.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;I carry the plenum of proof and every thing else in my face,<br />
With the hush of my lips I wholly confound the skeptic.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Walter&#8217;s anxiety over getting caught in the meth-making business has been one of his defining characteristics on the show. He&#8217;s gone to great lengths to keep his identity secret throughout the show, including wearing masks  (perhaps most notably when he and Jesse kidnapped Saul in season 2, and in the season 5 opener during the magnets heist). But throughout most of this season, his ego has made him not only thirsty for recognition, but seemingly untouchable and reckless with his identity getting caught up in this. Walter brings the methylamine supply to the car wash. He leaves Gale&#8217;s book in his bathroom with the damning inscription. He asks for recognition from other drug lords (&#8220;Say my name,&#8221; he demands in the penultimate season 5 episode to Declan, Mike&#8217;s meth contact. &#8220;You&#8217;re Heisenberg.&#8221; &#8220;You&#8217;re goddamn right.&#8221;). Perhaps the most symbolic imagery of Walter&#8217;s love of his alter-ego is when he chooses to wear his Heisenberg hat (once reserved only for drug deals) out in public throughout season 5.</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;What do you think has become of the young and old men?<br />
And what do you think has become of the women and children? &#8230; They are alive and well somewhere, The smallest sprout shows there is really no death &#8230; All goes onward and outward, nothing collapses &#8230;&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>The drug business is a dirty one, and Walter has to make justifications throughout the series for the deaths that happen. He tells Skyler that Gus&#8217; death was necessary. He tries to comfort Jesse that the deaths they&#8217;ve caused (including a child&#8217;s) were necessary to making it in their meth empire.</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Why should I pray? why should I venerate and be ceremonious?&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;I am given up by traitors,<br />
I talk wildly, I have lost my wits, I and nobody else am the<br />
greatest traitor,<br />
I went myself first to the headland, my own hands carried me<br />
there&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Enough! enough! enough!<br />
Somehow I have been stunn&#8217;d. Stand back!<br />
Give me a little time beyond my cuff&#8217;d head, slumbers,<br />
dreams, gaping,<br />
I discover myself on the verse of a usual mistake.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Walt refuses to kowtow to anyone throughout this season &#8212; to his partners, to his lawyer, to his wife&#8217;s pleas, to the new business associates.  And when others refuse to venerate Walter, he shuts them out of his world. He sees them as enemies. He&#8217;s cold to Jesse when his partner wants out. And when Mike tries to knock Walter down  few notches for not knowing &#8220;his place.&#8221; &#8220;You owe me that much,&#8221; Walt tells Mike when he demands gratitude and the names of the Gus&#8217; prisoned men. &#8220;I don&#8217;t own you a damn thing,&#8221; Mike gristles back. Walter impulsively kills Mike, and stunned at his actions, shows some remorse for doing so (&#8220;I&#8217;m sorry, Mike. This whole thing could have been avoided.&#8221;).</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;The pleasures of heaven are with me and the pains of hell are<br />
with me,<br />
The first I graft and increase upon myself, the latter I<br />
translate into a new tongue.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>This line from Whitman&#8217;s poem could very well speak to the season opener in which a flash-forward reveals Walter celebrating his 52nd birthday tearing up bacon (a Skyler birthday tradition to him) under a new alias and buying an assault rifle for some unknown reason. Walter&#8217;s birthdays have served as poignant reminders of how far he&#8217;s progressed on the show, and this vague flash-forward suggests he&#8217;s in a hell of his own making and he&#8217;s gearing up for some kind of showdown.</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Hurrah for positive science! long live exact demonstration!&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;He most honors my style who learns under it to destroy the<br />
teacher.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>I laughed when I saw this. This recalls all of Jesse&#8217;s &#8220;Yeah, science!&#8221; moments, including the magnet heist earlier this season. In addition, this also touches on Walter&#8217;s ego. He&#8217;s always been a softy when it comes to teaching; he revels in passing along his demonstration of chemistry to Jesse, to Gale and later to Todd. He likes recognition for his intelligence, a characteristic of his ego. We see it when he accidentally pushes Hank back to working on the Heisenberg case when he asserts that Gale was not the famed meth cook. It&#8217;s apparent when Walt keeps Gale&#8217;s copy of &#8220;Leaves of Grass&#8221; because it&#8217;s a reminder of someone once worshiping Walter&#8217;s mind. This may lead to his downfall, as Hank has now discovered that inscription.</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;I give the sign of democracy,<br />
By God! I will accept nothing which all cannot have their<br />
counterpart of on the same terms.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Walter negotiates a deal with Declan in which &#8220;everybody wins,&#8221; meaning Mike gets $5 million and out of the business. In the end, no one got what they wanted except for Walt. Mike loses money and gets killed; Jesse gets out but loses his share and his relationship with Walt.</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;I think I could turn and live with animals, they&#8217;re so placid<br />
and self-contain&#8217;d,<br />
I stand and look at them long and long.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;So they show their relations to me and I accept them,<br />
They bring me tokens of myself, they evince them plainly in<br />
their possession.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Walter spends a lot of time contemplating the existence of flies on this show; they&#8217;ve made appearances during key moments, like when Walter shuts down the lab in season 3 when he sees the fly as a contaminant. The fly seems to symbolize Walt&#8217;s sense of his own rottenness in being involved in the meth game. In season 5&#8242;s &#8220;Glided Over All,&#8221; he merely watches one for a few minutes after he&#8217;s killed Mike and makes no move to get rid of it this time. The fly is no longer a contaminant, but Walter is now the contaminated one and rotten.</p>
<p>And finally, there are many more lines in &#8220;Song of Myself&#8221; that could be applied here, but I will leave you with the most quoted ones:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Do I contradict myself?<br />
Very well then I contradict myself,<br />
(I am large, I contain multitudes.)&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Creator Vince Gilligan has said many times that &#8220;Breaking Bad&#8221; is about turning Mr. Chips into Scarface. Walter has wrestled with his identity during the entirety of the show &#8212; from a mild-mannered chemistry teacher with cancer to a meth kingpin. Now that he&#8217;s made his choice to go &#8220;legitimate&#8221; and give up the business presumably for good, it remains to be seen how his former Heisenberg identity will leave residue on Walter and his family, as Hank now knows the truth about the multitudes that Walter contains in his contradictory personality.</p>
<p><strong>What did you think of this finale, and the Walt Whitman references? What are you most looking forward to in the last half-season?</strong></p>
<p><em>&#8220;Breaking Bad&#8221; image <a href="http://blogs.amctv.com/photo-galleries/breaking-bad-season-5-episode-photos/episode-8-walt.php">via</a>. </em><em>Walt Whitman image <a href="http://www.poets.org/poet.php/prmPID/126">via</a>.</em></p>
<p><strong>Update, 4:45pm: </strong>I wasn&#8217;t able to catch the full inscription on first watch, but <a href="http://www.hitfix.com/whats-alan-watching/mid-season-finale-review-breaking-bad-gliding-over-all-the-bathroom-reader">Hitfix&#8217;s Alan Sepinwall</a> linked to a nice <a href="http://www.randomtuesday.com/archive/Breaking%20Bad/hank-finds-out.gif">gif </a>of Hank figuring out the identity of &#8220;W.W.&#8221; in the copy of &#8220;Leaves of Grass.&#8221; The inscription apparently reads:</p>
<p>&#8220;To my <em>other</em> favorite W.W.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s an honour working with you.</p>
<p>Fondly</p>
<p>G.B.&#8221;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/416/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/416/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=416&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://filmrascal.wordpress.com/2012/09/03/breaking-bad-and-walter-whites-song-of-myself/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/1483733418271a3440416cd633c2d5af?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">joannanderson</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://filmrascal.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/episode-8-walt-034571-23459087-1934857015-654943546548-64565.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">episode-8-walt-034571-23459087-1934857015-654943546548-64565</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://filmrascal.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/acf2964.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ACF2964</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Answer To Life, The Universe, and Everything</title>
		<link>http://adventuresinkevinworld.wordpress.com/2012/08/31/the-answer-to-life-the-universe-and-everything/</link>
		<comments>http://adventuresinkevinworld.wordpress.com/2012/08/31/the-answer-to-life-the-universe-and-everything/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 07:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>kevin meyers photography</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Alaska]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wrangell St. Elias National Park]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://adventuresinkevinworld.wordpress.com/?p=1221</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Wrangell St. Elias National Park is the biggest park in the U.S.  Denali National Park is 6 million acres, approximately the same size as Massachusetts -pretty big.  Wrangell, at 13.2 million acres, is well over twice as big.  As big as Vermont and Connecticut put together.  Bigger than Switzerland.  In a big state with lots [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1221&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Wrangell St. Elias National Park is the biggest park in the U.S.  Denali National Park is 6 million acres, approximately the same size as Massachusetts -pretty big.  Wrangell, at 13.2 million acres, is well over twice as big.  As big as Vermont and Connecticut put together.  Bigger than Switzerland.  In a big state with lots of space, it&#8217;s overwhelmingly huge.</p>
<p>As is most everything in it.  The Bagley ice field is 127 miles long and 6 miles wide.  The Malaspina Glacier is bigger than Rhode Island (a tiny state, true, but still!).  Mount St. Elias at 18,008 ft is the 3rd tallest peak in North America, and is tallest coastal mountain in the world.</p>
<p>Yadda yadda yadda.</p>
<p>How about some pretty pictures?</p>
<p>I left after work on Wednesday night, and drove for 4 hours until I was too tired to go on.  I slept in my car on the side of the Richardson Highway.  But while I was drifting off to sleep, the aurora made a grand entrance.  For an hour I shot images, and the scene was different literally every minute.</p>
<p><a href="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-017-version-2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1224" title="2012 Aug Wrangell Trip 017 - Version 2" src="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-017-version-2.jpg" alt="" width="982" height="653" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-021-version-2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1225" title="2012 Aug Wrangell Trip 021 - Version 2" src="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-021-version-2.jpg" alt="" width="982" height="653" /></a></p>
<p>Happy Birthday to me, indeed!  Thank you, Alaska!  That was my best northern lights show in 2 seasons here.</p>
<p>-</p>
<p>In the morning I continued on, but not without an adventure of a different kind first.  I discovered that I had somehow missed grabbing a stuff sack with socks &amp; underwear.  Three nights of no change of underwear and socks was not an option.   The tiny town of Glenallen however saved me &#8211; I found socks at the general store, and underwear at the Napa Auto Parts store.</p>
<p>Yes, you read that right.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s probably best not to ask why an auto parts store carries Hanes underwear.</p>
<p>-</p>
<p>After stopping at the visitor center and flirting with the cute ranger there &#8211; itwasmybirthdaysoIwasallowedtoandshestarteditdammit &#8211; I continued to the park.</p>
<p>Access to the park is challenging at best.  The 52 mile main access road is surrounded by private land, which means you&#8217;re driving in a national park that you can&#8217;t explore.  The road ends at the town of McCarthy, which means you pay private citizens to park and camp IN a national park.  And they take full advantage!</p>
<div id="attachment_1226" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 771px"><a href="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-041-version-2.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-1226 " title="2012 Aug Wrangell Trip 041 - Version 2" src="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-041-version-2.jpg?w=761&h=544" alt="" width="761" height="544" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">I think the park service pissed him off at some point. Just a guess.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_1238" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 661px"><a href="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-146-version-2.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1238" title="2012 Aug Wrangell Trip 146 - Version 2" src="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-146-version-2.jpg" alt="" width="651" height="912" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Ahh yes, the &#8220;Glacier View Campground.&#8221; $24/night. A very fragrant pit toilet. Not a glacier to be seen. And this is what he calls a campsite. Uneven ground, lots of plants.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_1232" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 919px"><a href="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-078-version-2.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1232" title="2012 Aug Wrangell Trip 078 - Version 2" src="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-078-version-2.jpg" alt="" width="909" height="606" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">While the campground didn&#8217;t offer up glacier views, it did have this view, which is nothing to sneeze at.</p></div>
<p>The town of McCarthy is certainly different if nothing else.  Only about 50 people live there, and it&#8217;s fully dependent on tourists.  Two tiny hotels, two small restaurants, two flightseeing businesses, one guiding business.  That&#8217;s about it.  It&#8217;s a little bit 3rd world.  On the plus side, people there are VERY friendly.</p>
<div id="attachment_1231" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 516px"><a href="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-065-version-2.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-1231" title="2012 Aug Wrangell Trip 065 - Version 2" src="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-065-version-2.jpg?w=506&h=710" alt="" width="506" height="710" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">I never tire of randomness like this.</p></div>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-062-version-2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-1230" title="2012 Aug Wrangell Trip 062 - Version 2" src="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-062-version-2.jpg?w=522&h=731" alt="" width="522" height="731" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-060-version-2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-1229" title="2012 Aug Wrangell Trip 060 - Version 2" src="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-060-version-2.jpg?w=502&h=702" alt="" width="502" height="702" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-056-version-2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-1228" title="2012 Aug Wrangell Trip 056 - Version 2" src="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-056-version-2.jpg?w=735&h=490" alt="" width="735" height="490" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-079-version-2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-1233" title="2012 Aug Wrangell Trip 079 - Version 2" src="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-079-version-2.jpg?w=613&h=438" alt="" width="613" height="438" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-081-version-2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-1234" title="2012 Aug Wrangell Trip 081 - Version 2" src="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-081-version-2.jpg?w=614&h=438" alt="" width="614" height="438" /></a></p>
<p>I tried to get on a flightseeing tour.  No luck.  One company was booked for the night, the other didn&#8217;t have any other paying guests until the next morning.</p>
<p>Score?  Park 1.  Kevin 0.  Not a good start to the birthday!</p>
<p>I had heard about ice caves in the Root Glacier, and that sounded pretty cool.  I also know that I&#8217;m not interested in exploring a glacier on my own, so I made my way to St. Elias Guides and booked a guide for a 4 hour trip the next day.</p>
<p>Park 1.  Kevin 1.</p>
<p>-</p>
<p>In the morning I tried again with flightseeing.  Another tourist was trying to convince them to fly, but they needed at least 2 guests to make money.  SCORE!  An hour later we were in the air.  Here&#8217;s a quick 1 minute best-of from the 90 minute flights.  Glaciers, glaciers, and more glaciers.  A fantastic flight with great scenery.</p>
<p><span style="text-align:center; display: block;"><a href="http://adventuresinkevinworld.wordpress.com/2012/08/31/the-answer-to-life-the-universe-and-everything/"><img src="http://img.youtube.com/vi/zUa262kR4BY/2.jpg" alt="" /></a></span></p>
<p>-</p>
<p>After the flight I immediately met the guide for my glacier adventure.  If you ever have the opportunity to check out ice caves in a glacier, DO IT!  Ridiculously beautiful, and just&#8230; cool.  Very cool (and I&#8217;m not trying to be coy with the words).</p>
<div id="attachment_1244" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 1034px"><a href="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-119-version-2.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-1244" title="2012 Aug Wrangell Trip 119 - Version 2" src="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-119-version-2.jpg?w=1024&h=731" alt="" width="1024" height="731" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Yeah, this may qualify as the coolest thing I did summer 2012.</p></div>
<p><a href="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-122-version-2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-1245" title="2012 Aug Wrangell Trip 122 - Version 2" src="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-122-version-2.jpg?w=1024&h=680" alt="" width="1024" height="680" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-132-version-2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-1246" title="2012 Aug Wrangell Trip 132 - Version 2" src="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-132-version-2.jpg?w=1024&h=680" alt="" width="1024" height="680" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-139-version-2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-1247" title="2012 Aug Wrangell Trip 139 - Version 2" src="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-139-version-2.jpg?w=1024&h=680" alt="" width="1024" height="680" /></a></p>
<p>-</p>
<p>The next day brought rain, so I skipped a planned hike and began my 7 hour drive.  Stopping of course, for pretty pictures along the way.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-185-version-2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-1253" title="2012 Aug Wrangell Trip 185 - Version 2" src="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-185-version-2.jpg?w=922&h=614" alt="" width="922" height="614" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-197-version-2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-1254" title="2012 Aug Wrangell Trip 197 - Version 2" src="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-197-version-2.jpg?w=922&h=614" alt="" width="922" height="614" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-206-version-3.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-1255" title="2012 Aug Wrangell Trip 206 - Version 3" src="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-206-version-3.jpg?w=1024&h=731" alt="" width="1024" height="731" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-208-version-2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-1256" title="2012 Aug Wrangell Trip 208 - Version 2" src="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-208-version-2.jpg?w=922&h=614" alt="" width="922" height="614" /></a></p>
<p>-</p>
<p>To conclude.  Why the title, you ask?  Since I turned 42 on this trip, it was very fitting.  If you don&#8217;t get that, read the book <span style="text-decoration:underline;">The Hitchhiker&#8217;s Guide To The Galaxy</span>!!!</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1221/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1221/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1221&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://adventuresinkevinworld.wordpress.com/2012/08/31/the-answer-to-life-the-universe-and-everything/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/8b4dcc1c7cb171f1099504fb2e2f86b4?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">kevinmeyersphoto</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-017-version-2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2012 Aug Wrangell Trip 017 - Version 2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-021-version-2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2012 Aug Wrangell Trip 021 - Version 2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-041-version-2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2012 Aug Wrangell Trip 041 - Version 2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-146-version-2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2012 Aug Wrangell Trip 146 - Version 2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-078-version-2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2012 Aug Wrangell Trip 078 - Version 2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-065-version-2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2012 Aug Wrangell Trip 065 - Version 2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-062-version-2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2012 Aug Wrangell Trip 062 - Version 2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-060-version-2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2012 Aug Wrangell Trip 060 - Version 2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-056-version-2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2012 Aug Wrangell Trip 056 - Version 2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-079-version-2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2012 Aug Wrangell Trip 079 - Version 2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-081-version-2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2012 Aug Wrangell Trip 081 - Version 2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-119-version-2.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2012 Aug Wrangell Trip 119 - Version 2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-122-version-2.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2012 Aug Wrangell Trip 122 - Version 2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-132-version-2.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2012 Aug Wrangell Trip 132 - Version 2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-139-version-2.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2012 Aug Wrangell Trip 139 - Version 2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-185-version-2.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2012 Aug Wrangell Trip 185 - Version 2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-197-version-2.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2012 Aug Wrangell Trip 197 - Version 2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-206-version-3.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2012 Aug Wrangell Trip 206 - Version 3</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://adventuresinkevinworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/2012-aug-wrangell-trip-208-version-2.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2012 Aug Wrangell Trip 208 - Version 2</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Number 9, Number 9, Number 9</title>
		<link>http://thoughtblossom.wordpress.com/2012/08/29/number-9-number-9-number-9/</link>
		<comments>http://thoughtblossom.wordpress.com/2012/08/29/number-9-number-9-number-9/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2012 14:28:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>thought blossom</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flowers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Landscape]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sunflowers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sunset]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Swan]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thoughtblossom.wordpress.com/?p=341</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Andy Warhol was able to change the way that society interpreted pop culture. He transformed everyday items into icons through the use of repetition and bold colors. Soon, what were once considered mere household products were now idolized as pieces of art.What if we were able to transform the way that society views nature in [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=341&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Andy Warhol was able to change the way that society interpreted pop culture. He transformed everyday items into icons through the use of repetition and bold colors. Soon, what were once considered mere household products were now idolized as pieces of art.What if we were able to transform the way that society views nature in a similar way?  Through the use of repetition, new creative patterns would appear from the earth, making trees no longer trees, but masterpieces.  We would garner a new-found respect for Mother Earth as we viewed her as a work of art, one not to be touched or disturbed.</p>
<p><strong>Thought blossom for the day:</strong> <em>Pop art isn&#8217;t bounded solely to the material world; get inspired and make your landscape into a piece of art by taking an innovative approach with your eyes or your lens.</em></p>

<a href='http://thoughtblossom.wordpress.com/2012/08/29/number-9-number-9-number-9/155420_1488982584778_6556696_n/' title='155420_1488982584778_6556696_n'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0'data-attachment-id="346" data-orig-file="http://thoughtblossom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/155420_1488982584778_6556696_n.jpg" data-orig-size="480,720" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:0,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:0,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:0,&quot;iso&quot;:0,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:0,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://thoughtblossom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/155420_1488982584778_6556696_n.jpg?w=200" data-large-file="http://thoughtblossom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/155420_1488982584778_6556696_n.jpg?w=480" width="100" height="150" src="http://thoughtblossom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/155420_1488982584778_6556696_n.jpg?w=100&h=150" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="155420_1488982584778_6556696_n" title="155420_1488982584778_6556696_n" /></a>
<a href='http://thoughtblossom.wordpress.com/2012/08/29/number-9-number-9-number-9/40631_1381579539769_1045534_n/' title='40631_1381579539769_1045534_n'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0'data-attachment-id="347" data-orig-file="http://thoughtblossom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/40631_1381579539769_1045534_n.jpg" data-orig-size="480,720" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:0,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:0,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:0,&quot;iso&quot;:0,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:0,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://thoughtblossom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/40631_1381579539769_1045534_n.jpg?w=200" data-large-file="http://thoughtblossom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/40631_1381579539769_1045534_n.jpg?w=480" width="100" height="150" src="http://thoughtblossom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/40631_1381579539769_1045534_n.jpg?w=100&h=150" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="40631_1381579539769_1045534_n" title="40631_1381579539769_1045534_n" /></a>
<a href='http://thoughtblossom.wordpress.com/2012/08/29/number-9-number-9-number-9/163031_1488985744857_2893668_n/' title='163031_1488985744857_2893668_n'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0'data-attachment-id="351" data-orig-file="http://thoughtblossom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/163031_1488985744857_2893668_n.jpg" data-orig-size="480,720" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:0,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:0,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:0,&quot;iso&quot;:0,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:0,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://thoughtblossom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/163031_1488985744857_2893668_n.jpg?w=200" data-large-file="http://thoughtblossom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/163031_1488985744857_2893668_n.jpg?w=480" width="100" height="150" src="http://thoughtblossom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/163031_1488985744857_2893668_n.jpg?w=100&h=150" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="163031_1488985744857_2893668_n" title="163031_1488985744857_2893668_n" /></a>
<a href='http://thoughtblossom.wordpress.com/2012/08/29/number-9-number-9-number-9/58061_1488983104791_8221712_n/' title='58061_1488983104791_8221712_n'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0'data-attachment-id="350" data-orig-file="http://thoughtblossom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/58061_1488983104791_8221712_n.jpg" data-orig-size="720,486" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:0,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:0,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:0,&quot;iso&quot;:0,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:0,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://thoughtblossom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/58061_1488983104791_8221712_n.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="http://thoughtblossom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/58061_1488983104791_8221712_n.jpg?w=720" width="150" height="101" src="http://thoughtblossom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/58061_1488983104791_8221712_n.jpg?w=150&h=101" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="58061_1488983104791_8221712_n" title="58061_1488983104791_8221712_n" /></a>
<a href='http://thoughtblossom.wordpress.com/2012/08/29/number-9-number-9-number-9/44494_1381569499518_3537129_n/' title='44494_1381569499518_3537129_n'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0'data-attachment-id="344" data-orig-file="http://thoughtblossom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/44494_1381569499518_3537129_n.jpg" data-orig-size="480,720" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:0,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:0,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:0,&quot;iso&quot;:0,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:0,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://thoughtblossom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/44494_1381569499518_3537129_n.jpg?w=200" data-large-file="http://thoughtblossom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/44494_1381569499518_3537129_n.jpg?w=480" width="100" height="150" src="http://thoughtblossom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/44494_1381569499518_3537129_n.jpg?w=100&h=150" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="44494_1381569499518_3537129_n" title="44494_1381569499518_3537129_n" /></a>
<a href='http://thoughtblossom.wordpress.com/2012/08/29/number-9-number-9-number-9/34800_1488985984863_7714576_n/' title='34800_1488985984863_7714576_n'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0'data-attachment-id="348" data-orig-file="http://thoughtblossom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/34800_1488985984863_7714576_n.jpg" data-orig-size="720,486" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:0,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:0,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:0,&quot;iso&quot;:0,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:0,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://thoughtblossom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/34800_1488985984863_7714576_n.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="http://thoughtblossom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/34800_1488985984863_7714576_n.jpg?w=720" width="150" height="101" src="http://thoughtblossom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/34800_1488985984863_7714576_n.jpg?w=150&h=101" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="34800_1488985984863_7714576_n" title="34800_1488985984863_7714576_n" /></a>
<a href='http://thoughtblossom.wordpress.com/2012/08/29/number-9-number-9-number-9/149052_1488985464850_428561_n/' title='149052_1488985464850_428561_n'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0'data-attachment-id="345" data-orig-file="http://thoughtblossom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/149052_1488985464850_428561_n.jpg" data-orig-size="720,480" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:0,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:0,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:0,&quot;iso&quot;:0,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:0,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://thoughtblossom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/149052_1488985464850_428561_n.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="http://thoughtblossom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/149052_1488985464850_428561_n.jpg?w=720" width="150" height="100" src="http://thoughtblossom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/149052_1488985464850_428561_n.jpg?w=150&h=100" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="149052_1488985464850_428561_n" title="149052_1488985464850_428561_n" /></a>
<a href='http://thoughtblossom.wordpress.com/2012/08/29/number-9-number-9-number-9/40982_1382040271287_4082978_n/' title='40982_1382040271287_4082978_n'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0'data-attachment-id="349" data-orig-file="http://thoughtblossom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/40982_1382040271287_4082978_n.jpg" data-orig-size="720,477" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:0,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:0,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:0,&quot;iso&quot;:0,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:0,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://thoughtblossom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/40982_1382040271287_4082978_n.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="http://thoughtblossom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/40982_1382040271287_4082978_n.jpg?w=720" width="150" height="99" src="http://thoughtblossom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/40982_1382040271287_4082978_n.jpg?w=150&h=99" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="40982_1382040271287_4082978_n" title="40982_1382040271287_4082978_n" /></a>
<a href='http://thoughtblossom.wordpress.com/2012/08/29/number-9-number-9-number-9/40982_1382040391290_7492554_n/' title='40982_1382040391290_7492554_n'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0'data-attachment-id="342" data-orig-file="http://thoughtblossom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/40982_1382040391290_7492554_n.jpg" data-orig-size="720,477" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:0,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:0,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:0,&quot;iso&quot;:0,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:0,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://thoughtblossom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/40982_1382040391290_7492554_n.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="http://thoughtblossom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/40982_1382040391290_7492554_n.jpg?w=720" width="150" height="99" src="http://thoughtblossom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/40982_1382040391290_7492554_n.jpg?w=150&h=99" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="40982_1382040391290_7492554_n" title="40982_1382040391290_7492554_n" /></a>
<a href='http://thoughtblossom.wordpress.com/2012/08/29/number-9-number-9-number-9/44338_1382046711448_6321430_n/' title='44338_1382046711448_6321430_n'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0'data-attachment-id="343" data-orig-file="http://thoughtblossom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/44338_1382046711448_6321430_n.jpg" data-orig-size="720,477" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:0,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:0,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:0,&quot;iso&quot;:0,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:0,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://thoughtblossom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/44338_1382046711448_6321430_n.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="http://thoughtblossom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/44338_1382046711448_6321430_n.jpg?w=720" width="150" height="99" src="http://thoughtblossom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/44338_1382046711448_6321430_n.jpg?w=150&h=99" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="44338_1382046711448_6321430_n" title="44338_1382046711448_6321430_n" /></a>

<p><strong>Photos taken with:</strong> Lomography Pop 9 camera and 35 mm film</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/341/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/341/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=341&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thoughtblossom.wordpress.com/2012/08/29/number-9-number-9-number-9/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://thoughtblossom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/58061_1488983104791_8221712_n.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://thoughtblossom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/58061_1488983104791_8221712_n.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">58061_1488983104791_8221712_n</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/7ebd28c0e7030ece09f9a1adb04a83b7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">thoughtblossom</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thoughtblossom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/155420_1488982584778_6556696_n.jpg?w=100" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">155420_1488982584778_6556696_n</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thoughtblossom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/40631_1381579539769_1045534_n.jpg?w=100" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">40631_1381579539769_1045534_n</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thoughtblossom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/163031_1488985744857_2893668_n.jpg?w=100" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">163031_1488985744857_2893668_n</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thoughtblossom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/44494_1381569499518_3537129_n.jpg?w=100" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">44494_1381569499518_3537129_n</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thoughtblossom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/149052_1488985464850_428561_n.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">149052_1488985464850_428561_n</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thoughtblossom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/40982_1382040271287_4082978_n.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">40982_1382040271287_4082978_n</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thoughtblossom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/34800_1488985984863_7714576_n.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">34800_1488985984863_7714576_n</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thoughtblossom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/40982_1382040391290_7492554_n.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">40982_1382040391290_7492554_n</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thoughtblossom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/44338_1382046711448_6321430_n.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">44338_1382046711448_6321430_n</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>My Secret Identity</title>
		<link>http://nopostergirl.com/2012/09/02/my-secret-identity/</link>
		<comments>http://nopostergirl.com/2012/09/02/my-secret-identity/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2012 01:29:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jocelyn</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Life Before]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ME/CFS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[career]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creeping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nostalgia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oracle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reunion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[school]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[secret identity]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nopostergirl.com/?p=1403</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[An old friend who is a serious comic book collector flattered me recently by likening me to the character Oracle. For those of you, like me, who aren&#8217;t intimately familiar with the DC universe, Oracle is the nom de guerre of Barbara Gordon, librarian, Commissioner Gordon&#8217;s daughter, and the former Batgirl. I will pardon if you [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1403&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An old friend who is a serious comic book collector flattered me recently by likening me to the character <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Barbara_Gordon">Oracle</a>. For those of you, like me, who aren&#8217;t intimately familiar with the DC universe, Oracle is the <em>nom de guerre</em> of Barbara Gordon, librarian, Commissioner Gordon&#8217;s daughter, and the former Batgirl.</p>
<p>I will pardon if you haven&#8217;t quite seen the likeness yet. And I promise I have a reason besides my own vanity for relating this.</p>
<p><a href="http://nopostergirl.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/oracle2.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-1417" title="Oracle" src="http://nopostergirl.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/oracle2.jpg?w=267&h=300" alt="" width="267" height="300" /></a>As Commissioner Gordon&#8217;s daughter, she is shot through the spinal cord by the Joker. Paralyzed from the waist down, she is relegated to a wheelchair, and retreats from her crime-fighting past. Eventually, though, in response to her straitened physical circumstances, she emerges from the shell the wounding has put her in and turns her prodigious intellect, remarkable memory, research abilities, and knowledge of computers to a <a href="http://www.oocities.org/batgirls_gotham/barbara_gordon2.html" target="_blank">new role as an information broker</a>, backing Batman, Nightwing (the former Robin), and the Birds of Prey and helping them succeed in fighting crime from behind the scenes.</p>
<p>While I feel like I&#8217;ve lost a fair number of IQ points and I&#8217;m not the hacker that Oracle is portrayed as, I do have pretty good Google-fu, a detail orientation, a gift for finding connections, a severely <a href="http://nopostergirl.com/2011/06/02/cheating-in-chase-community-giving-the-end/">overdeveloped sense of justice</a>, and a whole heck of a lot of time on my hands, being mostly bedridden. And as my energy level has improved a little in the last year, I&#8217;ve had the opportunity to help the above-mentioned friend with some computer- and web-based tasks, and that&#8217;s led me to take on some other low-stress outside projects.</p>
<p>Not for Batman. At least not yet. Sorry.</p>
<p>Next year will be my high school graduating class&#8217;s mumbly-mumpth reunion. Earlier in the summer, our class president re-activated a facebook group for us, and I asked him if I could help us start to prepare by looking people up on facebook. Barring a miracle, I won&#8217;t be able to go, of course, but I thought it would be nice to feel as if I contributed to helping others to enjoy the event.</p>
<div id="attachment_1418" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://nopostergirl.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/reunion.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1418" title="reunion" src="http://nopostergirl.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/reunion.jpg?w=300&h=200" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Theatre &amp; visual art folk at the last reunion. That&#8217;s me on the right. It&#8217;s sort of weird to me at this point to see pictures of myself well and standing up.</p></div>
<p>I&#8217;m sorry I won&#8217;t get a chance to go to the party, because I had a great time at the last one in 2003, dancing with the theatre/visual art/mod crowd to all our shared subcultures&#8217; alterna-hits, and at one point, one of the former art types, wearing a hot pink paisley shift and big stompy boots up to her knees, yelled over a Violent Femmes song into my ear, &#8220;ALL THE PEOPLE WHO MADE FUN OF ME FOR WEARING BLACK ALL THE TIME ARE WEARING BLACK TONIGHT!&#8221;</p>
<p>You can&#8217;t buy irony like that.</p>
<p>Anyway, I&#8217;d done something like this previously, looking 120 people up for my high school theatre&#8217;s facebook page, and it wasn&#8217;t difficult &#8211; a bit tedious, but it is fun to see what people have done with their lives. Okay, yes, it&#8217;s also fun because I&#8217;m a total creeper.</p>
<p>So that&#8217;s what I&#8217;ve been spending a chunk of my time doing of late, kicking up the old tendinitis in my hands in the process, which has kept me away from writing here. One of the things that&#8217;s hardest about being this sick is how utterly useless it makes you feel, so I love that I&#8217;m actually accomplishing something useful &#8211; something more than posting weird links and cat videos to my old friends on facebook.</p>
<p>I knew off the top of my head how big my graduating class was &#8211; 580+ people (I went to what was at the time the second-largest secondary school in Virginia). When I started typing the names into the spreadsheet from the yearbook, I figured it was going to be a big task, but I guess I didn&#8217;t figure on the difference in importance I&#8217;d internalize between looking up people to invite to a facebook page that there&#8217;s no real deadline on and the higher-stakes game of  tracking people down for A Big Reunion. And this task is a little tougher, because I have fewer mutual friends to help things along than I did with the theatre crowd.</p>
<p>Looking at profile after profile has been interesting &#8211; and has made me feel unexpectedly wistful. I&#8217;m not the kind of person for whom high school was the high point of my life, but because I was well then and I&#8217;m sick now, I think I probably look back on it with more nostalgia than I used to. It&#8217;s easier now to look past how much I resented the regimentation we were forced into and the depression I suffered at the time and just remember all the things my former vitality made possible.</p>
<p>And there is something about the fact that these are the people with whom our topics of conversation and shared experiences were the milestones of adolescence, what were to that point big events in our lives: our crazy driver&#8217;s ed road instructors, how long until the date we could get our licenses, how many times to take the SATs, if and where we&#8217;d managed to land summer jobs, surviving AP classes, pulling our hair out over college applications, anticipating prom, and the great launching and subsequent diaspora that was graduation.</p>
<p>Now, trying to pick out my classmates from the sometimes-sea of similar names on facebook, I find that we&#8217;re still living our lives in a similar kind of sync; the signs of being same-age peers from a shared hometown are good tells. I often bet right by choosing the profile that pictures one or sometimes two beaming children&#8217;s faces below a certain age, notes a government or defense career path, or shows allegiance to a Virginia university. I&#8217;ve been struck, too, by the progress many others have made in their careers. I guess it shouldn&#8217;t be surprising, as we&#8217;re all edging into our late 30s, but people are well into leadership in a lot of cases. And:</p>
<ul>
<li>The guy voted &#8220;Most Likely to Succeed&#8221; indeed has his own law practice.</li>
<li>&#8220;Most Eccentric&#8221; no longer has green hair and also works in law.</li>
<li>&#8220;Prettiest Eyes&#8221; is a newscaster, and in Googling her I discovered that there are whole websites devoted to saying offensive and degrading things about female newscasters, worse than you&#8217;d ever hear whispered behind the cover of a locker door.</li>
</ul>
<p>Never let it be said that creeping never taught anyone anything.</p>
<p>Yes, I know I&#8217;m getting a biased sample &#8211; people are probably not going to crow about their non-accomplishments, unhappy relationships, and mid-life crises on facebook, but it&#8217;s a cross-section of my peers, and for me personally, one of the things that <em>that</em> is another a reminder of a couple kinds of life progress that the disease slowed and then totally stymied. September always makes me feel a little wistful anyhow, because it&#8217;s been a transition point in my life so many times. This is just amplifying it.</p>
<p>But let&#8217;s not dwell on all that too long, right? I have <del>crime to fight</del> a spreadsheet to finish.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1403/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1403/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1403&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://nopostergirl.com/2012/09/02/my-secret-identity/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>15</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/b9339491d41ea9c778108f3869355795?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jocelmeow</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nopostergirl.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/oracle2.jpg?w=267" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Oracle</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nopostergirl.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/reunion.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">reunion</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Must-Read Memoirs</title>
		<link>http://susiemeserve.com/2012/09/03/must-read-memoirs/</link>
		<comments>http://susiemeserve.com/2012/09/03/must-read-memoirs/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2012 17:54:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Susie Meserve</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cheryl Strayed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[intimate details]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[memoir]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[must-read]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://susiemeserve.com/?p=756</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Having just finished Cheryl Strayed&#8217;s excellent memoir Wild (Knopf 2012), I&#8217;ve been thinking about all the great memoirs I&#8217;ve read in the past five years, since I started reading personal narrative accounts in earnest. It&#8217;s not news that in the past ten years or so memoirs have made a huge surge in popularity. What was [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=756&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_758" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 586px"><a href="http://susiemeserve.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dsci0449.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-758 " title="DSCI0449" src="http://susiemeserve.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dsci0449.jpg?w=576&h=432" alt="" width="576" height="432" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Roz Chast cartoon from the August 13 &amp; 20, 2012 issue of The New Yorker</p></div>
<p>Having just finished Cheryl Strayed&#8217;s excellent memoir <em>Wild</em> (Knopf 2012), I&#8217;ve been thinking about all the great memoirs I&#8217;ve read in the past five years, since I started reading personal narrative accounts in earnest. It&#8217;s not news that in the past ten years or so memoirs have made a huge surge in popularity. What was once a genre of dry, summarized accounts of the lives of famous people or family members has become a juicy canon of life stories that often follow novel-style trajectories. Memoirs have become so ubiquitous it&#8217;s impossible not to wonder why we&#8217;re drawn to these personal accounts, most with intimate details we once might have blushed to read about. Is this another sign of our penchant for oversharing (via Facebook, Twitter, etc.)? Maybe. But I&#8217;m less cynical about it: I think we love memoirs because our understanding of humanity is enhanced by personal accounts of hardship, failure, tragedy, love, and success. Maybe true stories hold the most weight and teach us the most about who we are.</p>
<p>I know that&#8217;s true for me. Since a writing teacher a few years back suggested I start reading as many memoirs as I could, I&#8217;ve had one on my shelf at all times. Here are a few of the ones that stayed with me the most, my list of &#8220;must-reads&#8221; (in no particular order).</p>
<p>1. <em><strong>Angela&#8217;s Ashes,</strong></em><strong> by Frank McCourt.</strong> Maybe someone has done a better job writing about coming of age in extreme poverty in Ireland in the mid 1900s, but not that I&#8217;m aware of. A beautiful, beautiful book.</p>
<p>2. <em><strong>Lucky,</strong></em><strong> by Alice Sebold.</strong> Once you read <em>Lucky</em> you learn the source of all of Sebold&#8217;s demons. A graphic violent event in the first few pages might hold you to your chair; I believe I started to sob, threw the book across the floor, then went and picked it up and finished reading.</p>
<p>3. <em><strong>Eat, Pray, Love,</strong></em><strong> by Elizabeth Gilbert.</strong> Hugely best-selling, this memoir has of course also been raked over the coals by many (<em>Eat, Pray, Shit</em> I heard someone call it the other day). I put this book on my list because I think Gilbert manages to capture the very real societal pressures that thirty-something American women feel to conform to marriage, child-rearing, and a certain life path. I think of it as a quiet memoir of rebellion—and she&#8217;s funny, too.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://susiemeserve.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dsci0438.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-759 aligncenter" title="DSCI0438" src="http://susiemeserve.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dsci0438.jpg?w=512&h=384" alt="" width="512" height="384" /></a></p>
<p>4. <em><strong>The Class Castle,</strong></em><strong> by Jeanette Walls.</strong> Just great. It details a childhood so shocking, at times you just have to shake your head.</p>
<p>5. <em><strong>This Boy&#8217;s Life,</strong></em><strong> by Tobias Wolff.</strong> Wolff may be the most controlled prose writer I have read. This is an example of a memoir that&#8217;s nothing but the facts. And the facts are intense.</p>
<p>6. <em><strong>The Burn Journals,</strong></em><strong> by Brent Runyon.</strong> I loved this memoir about a troubled kid trying to clown his way through a disfiguring depression. I first heard part of this memoir on <em>This American Life.</em></p>
<p>7.<em><strong>Truth &amp; Beauty,</strong></em><strong> by Ann Patchett.</strong> An interesting memoir because it isn’t about the author as much as it is about her dear friendship with the late writer Lucy Grealy. Incidentally, Grealy’s own memoir, <em>Autobiography of a Face,</em> is on my to-read list.</p>
<div id="attachment_760" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 522px"><a href="http://susiemeserve.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dsci0448.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-760 " title="DSCI0448" src="http://susiemeserve.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dsci0448.jpg?w=512&h=384" alt="" width="512" height="384" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Some memoirs I have known</p></div>
<p>8. <em><strong>The Year of Magical Thinking,</strong></em><strong> by Joan Didion.</strong> Inimitably Didion, this memoir is one of the quintessential memoirs of grief and death. Her sequel, <em>Blue Nights,</em> was for me (and for many critics) much less successful.</p>
<p>And if you get through those, you might try <em>Poser: My Life in Twenty-Three Yoga Poses</em> by Claire Dederer; <em>Made for You and Me,</em> by Caitlin Shetterly; <em>Expecting Adam: A True Story of Birth, Rebirth, and Everyday Magic,</em> by Martha Beck; <em>The Only Girl in the Car,</em> by Kathy Dobie; <em>Stop-Time,</em> by Frank Conroy; and <em>The Bill from My Father,</em> by Bernard Cooper.</p>
<p>Does anyone else read memoir? If so, what are your favorites?</p>
<p>This post first appeared on <a href="https://popcorntheblog.wordpress.com" target="_blank">popcorntheblog.</a> Like us on <a href="http://www.facebook.com/Popcorntheblog" target="_blank">Facebook! </a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/756/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/756/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=756&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://susiemeserve.com/2012/09/03/must-read-memoirs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>28</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/39cd0be1bd53474589c402337739fb48?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">susiemeserve</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://susiemeserve.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dsci0449.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSCI0449</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://susiemeserve.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dsci0438.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSCI0438</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://susiemeserve.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dsci0448.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSCI0448</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Days of Labor</title>
		<link>http://redtreetimes.com/2012/09/03/days-of-labor/</link>
		<comments>http://redtreetimes.com/2012/09/03/days-of-labor/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2012 11:32:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>redtreetimes</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Biographical]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dust Bowl]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exiles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[James Agee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Labor Day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Walker Evans]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://redtreetimes.com/?p=10120</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s another Labor Day here in America.  Just another holiday for most, one that marks the end of summer and the transition into autumn.  That&#8217;s what it was to me in my younger days.  But it began as a way of honoring the contributions of the working class to our country&#8217;s growth and progress.  From [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=10120&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://redtreetimes.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/the-exiles-memory-sm.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-10121" title="GC Myers- The Exile's Memory " src="http://redtreetimes.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/the-exiles-memory-sm.jpg?w=300&h=216" alt="" width="300" height="216" /></a>It&#8217;s another Labor Day here in America.  Just another holiday for most, one that marks the end of summer and the transition into autumn.  That&#8217;s what it was to me in my younger days.  But it began as a way of honoring the contributions of the working class to our country&#8217;s growth and progress.  From the fields and factories to the shipyards and mines, labor has been the backbone that held this country up.  The idea of labor has taken on added meaning for me as I became more and more aware of the importance of it in our history as well as its relevance to my own well-being and identity.</p>
<p>You see, I consider myself a working man, probably before I consider myself an artist.  I learned in my early days working in a factory and toiling as a laborer in other jobs the value of  being able to put my head down and focus on the task at hand.   I learned that effort was the one variable I could control and that effort often overcame my deficiencies.  I might not be as strong or smart or as talented as the next guy but I firmly believed that I could always outwork  him.    Effort brought out the most in whatever limited attributes I might possess.  I believe that any success I have achieved as an artist can be directly tied to these lessons learned with a shovel in hand and the sweat running down.</p>
<p>This value of labor is often portrayed in my work, most often in the form of rows of fields.  This   piece above, from my early <em>Exiles</em> series, always reminds me of the tenant farmers in the Dust Bowl-era photos of <strong>Walker Evans</strong> in the famous <strong>James Agee</strong> book, <strong><em>Let Us Now Praise Famous Men</em></strong>.  Labor and effort was all they knew.</p>
<p>I could go on and on here about the value of the labor movement in America and the great debt we owe to those ancestors who fought and died for the rights and protective  regulations which we take for granted today.  Too many of us don&#8217;t realize how difficult the battle was for these rights and how quickly they could erode without continued effort and vigilance.   So, enjoy your holiday but remember what it means.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/10120/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/10120/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=10120&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://redtreetimes.com/2012/09/03/days-of-labor/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/900c4e1c2664fa1904bbca78595514c3?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">redtreetimes</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://redtreetimes.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/the-exiles-memory-sm.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">GC Myers- The Exile&#039;s Memory </media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Factory Girls and Boys</title>
		<link>http://streetsofsalem.com/2012/08/31/factory-girls-and-boys/</link>
		<comments>http://streetsofsalem.com/2012/08/31/factory-girls-and-boys/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2012 11:37:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>daseger</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Commemorations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[holidays]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New England]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://streetsofsalem.com/?p=12651</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I always feel a bit sorry for myself on Labor Day weekend, as it&#8217;s back-to-school time and usually I am engaged in a mad dash to get my course syllabi done.  Of course this is ridiculous, as I have the cushiest job ever and most of the summer I&#8217;ve been free to do as I [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=12651&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I always feel a bit sorry for myself on Labor Day weekend, as it&#8217;s back-to-school time and usually I am engaged in a mad dash to get my course syllabi done.  Of course this is ridiculous, as I have the cushiest job ever and most of the summer I&#8217;ve been free to do as I liked.  It&#8217;s good to remind myself what <em>labor</em> really is, and nothing does that better than the photographs of Lewis Wickes Hine (1874-1940), who transitioned from educator to social activist, all the while armed with a camera.  In 1908 Hine became the official photographer for the National Child Labor Committee (NCLC) and began his life&#8217;s work:  documenting child labor across the United States. This was a time when <em>one</em><em> in six children between the ages of five and ten</em> worked outside the home in &#8220;gainful occupation&#8221;, and the percentage increases dramatically for children over the age of ten.  The members of the NCLC began a successful campaign to end child labor and Hine&#8217;s often-haunting photographs were their chief weapon.</p>
<p>In the fall of 1911, Hine was in New England, then at the height of its industrial history, documenting child labor in Boston, Lowell, New Bedford, Lawrence and Salem. There are 17 photographs of Salem children, all accessible at the <a class="zem_slink" title="Library of Congress" href="http://www.loc.gov" rel="homepage" target="_blank">Library of Congress</a>, which has a vast Hine collection. Most of the child laborers are shown outside of their place of work, presumably because their employers didn&#8217;t allow the conspicuous photographer inside. My favorite has always been this group of smiling girls, workers at the Cass &amp; Daley Shoe Factory on Goodhue Street.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.loc.gov/pictures/resource/nclc.04771/"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-12655" title="Factory Girls Hine" src="http://streetsofsalem.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/factory-girls-hine.jpg" alt="" width="490" height="355" /></a></p>
<p><strong>Caption:  <em>Group of girls working in Cass &amp; Daley Shoe Co., Salem.  Saw a number of children from 14 to 16 (apparently) and two or three probably under 14.  Smallest girl in photo is Odella Delisle.</em></strong></p>
<p>Smiling Salem girls, for the most part, a striking contrast to one of Hines&#8217; most famous child laborers, Addie Card of North Pownal, Vermont, captured in August of 1910.  Hines&#8217; captions for this photograph are perhaps even more poignant than the image: an <em>anaemic little spinner, 12 years. Girls</em> <em>in</em> <em>mill</em> <em>say</em> <em>she</em> <em>is</em> <em>ten</em> <em>years</em>. <em>She</em> <em>admitted</em> <em>to</em> <em>me</em> <em>she</em> <em>was</em> <em>twelve</em>; <em>that</em> <em>she</em> <em>started</em> <em>during</em> <em>school</em> <em>vacation</em> <em>and</em> <em>now</em> <em>would</em> &#8220;<em>stay</em>.&#8221;  Of course many have wondered what become of Addie Day:  here is <a href="http://www.morningsonmaplestreet.com/addiesearch1.html">one </a>exploration.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.loc.gov/pictures/item/ncl2004001719/PP/"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-12658" title="Factory Girl Card" src="http://streetsofsalem.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/factory-girl-card.jpg" alt="" width="484" height="640" /></a></p>
<p>Back in Salem, a few more of my favorite Hine photographs from the fall of 1911:  a group of somewhat serious boys outside the factory with some very serious men (the factory owners?) behind them, and young John Parent, quite alone despite the fact that there are people all around him.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.loc.gov/pictures/resource/nclc.02401/"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-12664" title="Factory boys" src="http://streetsofsalem.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/factory-boys.jpg" alt="" width="490" height="346" /></a></p>
<p><strong>Caption<em>:  Group, all working in #2 Spinning Room. Smallest boy (right hand end of front row) is Rene Barbin, 61 Perkins St. Next to Rene is Philip Beaulieu.  Next to Philip is Alfred Corriveau, 14 Perkins St. Smallest boy in back row is Willie Irwin, 16 Perkins St. Next smallest in back row is Ernest Dionne, 5 Prince St. </em></strong></p>
<p><a href="http://www.loc.gov/pictures/item/ncl2004003230/PP/"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-12669" title="Factory boy" src="http://streetsofsalem.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/factory-boy.jpg" alt="" width="490" height="336" /></a></p>
<p><strong>Caption<em>:  Boy is John Parent, 14 Congress St. Works in Spinning Room #2, Fifth Floor.</em></strong></p>
<p>There is only one Salem photograph in which Hine was allowed into the factory, where he photographed a ragged-yet-dignified Henry Fournier before some massive machinery.  I&#8217;m sure Hine wanted to get the machines in his photographs whenever possible, because they represent both the work and the potential <em>danger.  </em>A Smithsonian/National Archives traveling <a href="http://www.archives.gov/exhibits/twww/">exhibition </a>entitled <em>The Way We Work </em>(opening this weekend at <a class="zem_slink" title="Historic New England" href="http://www.historicnewengland.org/" rel="homepage" target="_blank">Historic New England</a>&#8216;s Governor John Langdon <a href="http://www.historicnewengland.org/collections-archives-exhibitions/traveling-exhibitions/copy_of_the-way-we-worked">House</a>) includes a Hine photograph of child laborers in Georgia that is particularly haunting with regard to danger:  small <em>barefoot</em> boys who appear as almost <em>part</em> of the machines on which they work.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.loc.gov/pictures/item/ncl2004003231/PP/"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-12673" title="Factory boy Fournier" src="http://streetsofsalem.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/factory-boy-fournier.jpg" alt="" width="490" height="348" /></a></p>
<p><strong>Caption<em>:  Henry Fourner [i.e., Fournier?], 261 Jefferson St., Castle Hill; has been sweeper and cleaner in #2 Spinning Room two months.</em> </strong></p>
<p><a href="http://streetsofsalem.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/factory-boys-1909-www.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-12679" title="Factory boys 1909 www" src="http://streetsofsalem.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/factory-boys-1909-www.jpg" alt="" width="490" height="352" /></a></p>
<p><strong>Caption<em>:  “Bibb Mill No. 1, Macon, Ga. Many youngsters here. Some boys and girls were so small they had to climb up on to the spinning frame to mend broken threads and  to put back the empty bobbins”.</em></strong></p>
<br /> Tagged: <a href='http://streetsofsalem.com/tag/commemorations/'>Commemorations</a>, <a href='http://streetsofsalem.com/tag/holidays/'>holidays</a>, <a href='http://streetsofsalem.com/tag/new-england/'>New England</a>, <a href='http://streetsofsalem.com/tag/photography/'>Photography</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/12651/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/12651/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=12651&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://streetsofsalem.com/2012/08/31/factory-girls-and-boys/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>17</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f234d2af3b4309bf4fd3de823f16392a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">daseger</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://streetsofsalem.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/factory-girls-hine.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Factory Girls Hine</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://streetsofsalem.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/factory-girl-card.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Factory Girl Card</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://streetsofsalem.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/factory-boys.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Factory boys</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://streetsofsalem.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/factory-boy.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Factory boy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://streetsofsalem.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/factory-boy-fournier.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Factory boy Fournier</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://streetsofsalem.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/factory-boys-1909-www.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Factory boys 1909 www</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nine Months on the Picket Line</title>
		<link>http://conchapman.wordpress.com/2012/09/03/nine-months-on-the-picket-line-2/</link>
		<comments>http://conchapman.wordpress.com/2012/09/03/nine-months-on-the-picket-line-2/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2012 13:33:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>conchapman</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blogroll]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[labor day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lockouts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[picketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[strikes]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://conchapman.wordpress.com/?p=9897</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It has been more than three decades since I returned to work from a noon union meeting to find myself, along with about twenty others, locked out of the printing plant where we worked.  Thus began a labor dispute that started in confusion, descended into torpor and ended in disarray. The difference between labor and [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=9897&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It has been more than three decades since I returned to work from a noon union meeting to find myself, along with about twenty others, locked out of the printing plant where we worked.  Thus began a labor dispute that started in confusion, descended into torpor and ended in disarray.</p>
<p><img src="http://t1.gstatic.com/images?q=tbn:ANd9GcRXDAkhwTCjrN87E_gFFdKKl621slloa31lqIlhaXPfCJBAHBC_" alt="" width="276" height="183" /></p>
<p>The difference between labor and management at the time the dispute started was miniscule; less than twenty-five cents an hour.  When a union rejects an employer’s last and final offer the employer is entitled to prevent employees from returning to work–hence the term “lock out,” which is now familiar to millions of Americans because Americans making millions–pro football and basketball players–have both been locked out in the past few years.</p>
<p>When we learned we’d been locked out, we organized a picket line, as was our right.  For five weekday shifts of three hours a day each union member would receive $100.  Not a big weekly wage, even in the mid-70′s, but if you found a part-time job or one with night hours, you could do all right.</p>
<p><a href="http://images.google.com/imgres?imgurl=http://media-2.web.britannica.com/eb-media/01/76201-004-E173401B.jpg&amp;imgrefurl=http://www.britannica.com/EBchecked/topic-art/16170/96533/Fred-Allen&amp;usg=__habUdlzKDkhw0200UQB8BiXA3nw=&amp;h=450&amp;w=353&amp;sz=19&amp;hl=en&amp;start=2&amp;um=1&amp;tbnid=ikaETjUClNGu2M:&amp;tbnh=127&amp;tbnw=100&amp;prev=/images%3Fq%3Dfred%2Ballen%26hl%3Den%26sa%3DN%26um%3D1"><img src="http://t0.gstatic.com/images?q=tbn:ikaETjUClNGu2M:http://media-2.web.britannica.com/eb-media/01/76201-004-E173401B.jpg" alt="" width="100" height="127" /></a><em><br />
Fred Allen</em></p>
<p>Our picket line was set up not on a city street but on Route 20 in central Massachusetts; to steal a formula from radio comedian Fred Allen, a nice place to visit if you’re a truck.  There are no sidewalks along that highway, which was originally the Boston Post Road, the first mail route between Boston and New York, and which subsequently developed into a major trucking route.  With no foot traffic, our picket line was visible only to cars and trucks speeding by, and we must have struck passers-by as pathetic, or even ridiculous.  The scenery rarely changed except for the weather and the flora; in the winter the field beside us was covered in snow, and in the summer a few blue cornflowers bloomed.  I recall once or twice people stopping their cars–at significant personal risk–to give us donuts.  More frequent were uplifted middle fingers–the state bird of Massachusetts.</p>
<p><img src="http://t0.gstatic.com/images?q=tbn:ANd9GcSCpkSWoO21mq_hrqPFxknoV6WeIBjJVCqpdnWjA13NyqInPLsd" alt="" width="160" height="112" /></p>
<p>In the United States picketing is legal as long as workers do not intimidate others or obstruct a public way; hence, the need to keep moving, so as not to block other’s passage.  As is the case with most employers, the owner of the printing company hired an off-duty policeman to make sure we complied with that requirement, but given that the only object likely to cross our picket line was a truck, we eventually worked out a compromise.  As long as we didn’t throw nails in the driveway, the cop wouldn’t force us to keep moving.</p>
<p><a href="http://images.google.com/imgres?imgurl=http://billsmovieemporium.files.wordpress.com/2009/03/waterfront2.jpg&amp;imgrefurl=http://billsmovieemporium.wordpress.com/category/on-the-waterfront/&amp;usg=__-pbC-kZd6DNOAQSv4iAncF7y_m4=&amp;h=378&amp;w=500&amp;sz=77&amp;hl=en&amp;start=4&amp;um=1&amp;tbnid=WoTw2-H3u3Px2M:&amp;tbnh=98&amp;tbnw=130&amp;prev=/images%3Fq%3Don%2Bthe%2Bwaterfront%26hl%3Den%26sa%3DN%26um%3D1"><img src="http://t0.gstatic.com/images?q=tbn:WoTw2-H3u3Px2M:http://billsmovieemporium.files.wordpress.com/2009/03/waterfront2.jpg" alt="" width="130" height="98" /></a><em><br />
Marlon Brando in “On the Waterfront”</em></p>
<p>In another, less isolated location, our picket line might have attracted students, politicians or even an entertainer or two; the young and idealistic, and those who live by publicity and like to make a show of solidarity with picketers.  A forlorn stretch of highway an hour’s drive from Boston is, as you can imagine, an inconvenient forum for grandstanding by elected officials and actors.</p>
<p>If you are planning on picking a fight with an employer, my recommendation is that you consider not merely location, but also the season.  Picket lines are manned (and womanned) by human beings, whose enthusiasm for concerted action may be expected to cool along with the temperature.  We chose the month of November to take a stand, which meant that we were soon walking in a New England winter.</p>
<p><a href="http://images.google.com/imgres?imgurl=http://www.mentalfloss.com/wp-content/uploads/2007/11/strike.jpg&amp;imgrefurl=http://www.mentalfloss.com/blogs//archives/18023&amp;usg=__KuqyxKY8EMErFP2mjXcQGmefJPs=&amp;h=364&amp;w=499&amp;sz=32&amp;hl=en&amp;start=1&amp;um=1&amp;tbnid=NLctoXk29ZmUuM:&amp;tbnh=95&amp;tbnw=130&amp;prev=/images%3Fq%3Dstrike%26hl%3Den%26sa%3DN%26um%3D1"><img src="http://t1.gstatic.com/images?q=tbn:NLctoXk29ZmUuM:http://www.mentalfloss.com/wp-content/uploads/2007/11/strike.jpg" alt="" width="130" height="95" /></a></p>
<p>You learn a lot about a person when you’re assigned to walk with them in the cold and they skip out on you; to paraphrase an old country song, when nobody shows up, I’ll know it’s you.  For the most part, such absences passed without comment.  Our shop steward, who received and handed out the strike pay, might give someone a look of disapproval as she handed over his weekly check, but she had kids, and couldn’t spend her off hours taking attendance, and we weren’t going to turn each other in; it would have made what was a boring task into an unpleasant one.</p>
<p>As one considers the various players in the drama that a picket line affords, the difference in economic status begins to grate.  The plant owner, who ultimately decided to sell his business, made out all right.  The union bosses drove nicer cars and had nicer clothes than we did.  The lawyers for the two sides, we were told, were paid hundreds of dollars an hour–a sum beyond our wildest dreams of avarice–and yet nothing of consequence ever seemed to happen as a result of their efforts.</p>
<p><a href="http://images.google.com/imgres?imgurl=http://64bitheadlines.files.wordpress.com/2008/04/strike2.jpg&amp;imgrefurl=http://64bitheadlines.wordpress.com/2008/04/10/strike/&amp;usg=__4Zi4cZTz-4hI1hgRTkIPxYfMVbs=&amp;h=380&amp;w=309&amp;sz=68&amp;hl=en&amp;start=2&amp;um=1&amp;tbnid=0vYMCPfaA6crgM:&amp;tbnh=123&amp;tbnw=100&amp;prev=/images%3Fq%3Dstrike%26hl%3Den%26sa%3DN%26um%3D1"><img src="http://t0.gstatic.com/images?q=tbn:0vYMCPfaA6crgM:http://64bitheadlines.files.wordpress.com/2008/04/strike2.jpg" alt="" width="100" height="123" /></a></p>
<p>Ultimately, running a union is a business, and the men who controlled our union weren’t going to pay us to picket forever.  Just as we had been locked out of the plant, we were eventually told that we would receive no more strike pay.  We could continue to walk the picket line, but there’d be no money in it.</p>
<p>At about that time the National Labor Relations Board handed down its decision; the owner was within his rights to lock us out, and our claims of unfair labor practices were denied.  We could go back to work at the hourly wages that had been in effect when the dispute started, but none of us would receive back pay–except for one man, Hector, who had not yet become a member of the union when the dispute started, nine months before.  The boss’s actions were deemed unfair in his case.</p>
<p><a href="http://images.google.com/imgres?imgurl=http://www.wired.com/images_blogs/autopia/images/2007/10/10/strike.jpg&amp;imgrefurl=http://www.wired.com/autopia/tag/manufacturing/page/3/&amp;usg=__BLgczvasZaVwHoDS23uhACqZteM=&amp;h=336&amp;w=450&amp;sz=27&amp;hl=en&amp;start=15&amp;um=1&amp;tbnid=AHoikF-73DagZM:&amp;tbnh=95&amp;tbnw=127&amp;prev=/images%3Fq%3Dstrike%26hl%3Den%26sa%3DN%26um%3D1"><img src="http://t2.gstatic.com/images?q=tbn:AHoikF-73DagZM:http://www.wired.com/images_blogs/autopia/images/2007/10/10/strike.jpg" alt="" width="127" height="95" /></a></p>
<p>I got nine months’ worth of strike pay for my time on the picket line, plus the material for a play that will be performed in New York at the <a href="http://thespisny.com/shows-2012/">Thespis Theatre Festival</a> on October 17th, 18th and 21st.  I suppose it’s ironic that the cast will be composed entirely of non-union actors.  I’ll pay them only what I can, not union scale, and will still lose money on it.</p>
<p>I also gained a few lessons which have proved useful over the years.  First, taking a stand on principle can be costly, and you can’t eat principle.  A good thing to know when you feel the urge to sacrifice yourself for a noble cause, or the theory of an armchair radical.  (That knowledge notwithstanding, I’ve taken the plunge a few times since in support of the cause of inner-city education.)</p>
<p>And second, if you pick cornflowers for your girlfriend, by the time you get to her apartment they will have lost their blue color and turned a mottled, grayish white.</p>
<p>The bloom fades from some bright ideas more quickly than others.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/9897/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/9897/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=9897&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://conchapman.wordpress.com/2012/09/03/nine-months-on-the-picket-line-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/7a112e9b6bbf284aef30918df187ff13?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Con Chapman</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://t1.gstatic.com/images?q=tbn:ANd9GcRXDAkhwTCjrN87E_gFFdKKl621slloa31lqIlhaXPfCJBAHBC_" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://t0.gstatic.com/images?q=tbn:ikaETjUClNGu2M:http://media-2.web.britannica.com/eb-media/01/76201-004-E173401B.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://t0.gstatic.com/images?q=tbn:ANd9GcSCpkSWoO21mq_hrqPFxknoV6WeIBjJVCqpdnWjA13NyqInPLsd" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://t0.gstatic.com/images?q=tbn:WoTw2-H3u3Px2M:http://billsmovieemporium.files.wordpress.com/2009/03/waterfront2.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://t1.gstatic.com/images?q=tbn:NLctoXk29ZmUuM:http://www.mentalfloss.com/wp-content/uploads/2007/11/strike.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://t0.gstatic.com/images?q=tbn:0vYMCPfaA6crgM:http://64bitheadlines.files.wordpress.com/2008/04/strike2.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://t2.gstatic.com/images?q=tbn:AHoikF-73DagZM:http://www.wired.com/images_blogs/autopia/images/2007/10/10/strike.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What’s a Teacher to Do? How Children Succeed</title>
		<link>http://siobhancurious.com/2012/09/03/whats-a-teacher-to-do-paul-toughs-how-children-succeed/</link>
		<comments>http://siobhancurious.com/2012/09/03/whats-a-teacher-to-do-paul-toughs-how-children-succeed/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2012 13:33:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Siobhan Curious</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[psychology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[society]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[character]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Failure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[How Children Succeed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York Times]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Paul Tough]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[teachers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://siobhancurious.com/?p=2738</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[When Paul Tough&#8217;s new book, How Children Succeed, arrived in my mailbox, I opened it with great anticipation.  I love Tough&#8217;s writing; his pieces on This American Life and in The New York Times have always impressed me with their warm, clear prose.  What&#8217;s more, last year, an excerpt from this book, published in the New York [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2738&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://siobhancurious.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/book-children-succeed.png"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-2741" title="book-children-succeed" src="http://siobhancurious.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/book-children-succeed.png" alt="" width="181" height="299" /></a>When <a href="http://www.paultough.com/the-books/how-children-succeed/" target="_blank">Paul Tough&#8217;s new book, <em>How Children Succeed</em>, </a>arrived in my mailbox, I opened it with great anticipation.  I love Tough&#8217;s writing; his pieces on <em>This American Life</em> and in <em>The New York Times </em>have always impressed me with their warm, clear prose.  What&#8217;s more, last year, an excerpt from this book, published in the <em>New York Times Magazine,</em> inspired me to turn around my approach to some serious classroom problems.</p>
<p>In that excerpt (taken from Chapter 2), Tough describes children from difficult backgrounds who nevertheless succeed in school and other endeavours because, he posits, they have developed certain character traits.  I chronicled my thoughts on that piece <a href="http://siobhancurious.com/2011/09/26/fail-better/" target="_blank">in a post called &#8220;Fail Better,&#8221; </a>and I then took his ideas to my students, some of whom were having a lot of difficulty.  I asked them to analyze some of the fictional characters we were reading about in terms of the important qualities Tough describes.  I then asked them to think about which of these qualities they possess themselves.  And I asked them to discuss his main assertion: that character, notably the trait he calls &#8220;grit,&#8221; is more important than intelligence when it comes to children&#8217;s success.</p>
<p>My students seemed convinced by this assertion.  So am I.  It forms the foundation of this book, in which Tough examines current research, as well as a few inspiring case studies, in order to support it.  He supports it very well, and puts together a powerful argument.  The upshot: character is more or less destiny, but character can be taught, or at least influenced.</p>
<p>Tough tells stories of students who have met with terrible adversity but have still managed to achieve impressive things: chess titles, admissions to competitive universities, or just a good GPA and graduation from high school.  He also speaks to people, particularly educators, who have made a difference along the way: curriculum designers, coaches, principals, teachers.  He outlines the qualities that researchers suggest divide children who succeed from children who don&#8217;t: curiosity, zest, optimism, gratitude, social intelligence, self-control, and <em>grit</em>, or a passionate desire to stick with a task until it is accomplished.</p>
<p>These characteristics are rooted in brain chemistry, Tough discovers, but they are not entirely innate &#8211; they are directly affected by a child&#8217;s environment, particularly a child&#8217;s exposure to stress and, on the other side, nurturance and support.  A child who lives in a stressful environment may have difficulty developing these qualities.  However, such a child, from such an environment, who is given the tools and confidence to face challenges may develop a stronger character than a child who faces little adversity.   A child who grows up in poverty but has a nurturing, supportive parent &#8211; one who encourages the child to tackle difficulties, praises success, and promotes the learning potential inherent in failure &#8211; may have more character tools than a middle-class or wealthy child whose parents protect him or her from every bump in the road.</p>
<p>I loved this book, and the stories it told about children who succeed against big odds and the people who help them.  The greatest satisfaction it offers is the knowledge that such children CAN be helped.  In the end, though, it left me feeling a bit sad.</p>
<p>Character can be nurtured.  Children are not doomed by their social circumstances or their genes.  Nevertheless, I&#8217;m not sure what my role is.  How much can teachers help, especially teachers who don&#8217;t meet children until they are no longer children at all?  The book left me with one lingering, powerful desire: to do some research of my own.</p>
<p>This research would involve examining sixteen-to-twenty-year-olds who have made it through high school, who have been admitted to CEGEP &#8211; granted, a CEGEP with famously forgiving standards &#8211; but who are still floundering.  That is to say, my students.  Is it too late?  Have their characters been formed?  Is it possible for them to now learn grit, curiosity, self-control etc.?  If so, am I in any position to inspire it in them?  According to some of the authorities Tough cites, &#8220;variations in teacher quality probably [account] for less than 10 percent of the gap between high- and low-performing students.&#8221; (191)  However, he also tells us that &#8220;transformative help&#8221; (196) can come from myriad sources &#8211; not just parents, but anyone with whom the child comes in contact.  His book gives us stories about people, mostly teachers, who have offered that kind of transformative help.  These stories are moving, but they also highlight the intensive energy and the depth of inner and outer resources teachers need in order to help these kids, preferably at early stages in the kids&#8217; education.</p>
<p>I would encourage any educator, community worker, parent, or person who cares about children and/or the state of our social world as a whole to read this book.  It is well-researched, wonderfully written and thought-provoking.  It also raises a powerful question that it does not answer.  It tells us that children, no matter what their background and innate capabilities, can succeed in school and the professional world.  It tells us that they cannot do it alone, but that we &#8211; the people who surround them &#8211; can help them.  It doesn&#8217;t give us, as individual teachers, a blueprint for how to do that, especially when we come along later in the game.  But it gives us some examples.  With a little grit and curiosity of our own, maybe we&#8217;ll be able to figure it out.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2738/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2738/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2738&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://siobhancurious.com/2012/09/03/whats-a-teacher-to-do-paul-toughs-how-children-succeed/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>16</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/4493fedc735dc9d9c22c2d8eea66b97e?s=96&#38;d=monsterid&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Siobhan Curious</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://siobhancurious.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/book-children-succeed.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">book-children-succeed</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Case for New Orleans</title>
		<link>http://thecaseforneworleans.wordpress.com/2012/09/01/the-case-for-the-greater-new-orleans-area-why-we-matter-and-why-we-should-exist/</link>
		<comments>http://thecaseforneworleans.wordpress.com/2012/09/01/the-case-for-the-greater-new-orleans-area-why-we-matter-and-why-we-should-exist/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:41:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>thecaseforneworleans</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thecaseforneworleans.wordpress.com/?p=5</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[After multiple hurricanes, severe flooding, staggering death tolls, expensive rebuilding price tags, and the likes, the critiques that New Orleans shouldn’t exist, be rebuilt, or similar sentiments, are gaining traction.  As Isaac just passed, people are voicing these opinions. Glenn Beck epitomizes this sentiment: “I find it hard to feel sorry for New Orleans.” &#8230; “We [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=5&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>After multiple hurricanes, severe flooding, staggering death tolls, expensive rebuilding price tags, and the likes, the critiques that New Orleans shouldn’t exist, be rebuilt, or similar sentiments, are gaining traction.  As Isaac just passed, people are voicing these opinions. Glenn Beck epitomizes this sentiment:</p>
<p>“I find it hard to feel sorry for New Orleans.” &#8230; “We should just walk away from that city. Why are we there?” … “I’m not sure if we should bother rebuilding it.” … “Why are we spending all this money in New Orleans? We shouldn’t spend a single dime of tax-payer money.” … “How much do I think should be spent on New Orleans? Zero. Nothing. Not a dime.” … “The Big Easy is a lost cause.”</p>
<p>So many from all over the political spectrum and various walks of life agree.  A lot less crazy people than Beck, as well.  These opinions may sound rational on the surface, but deeper analysis exposes its simplicity and absurdity.  I write this in a coffee shop, because my house has no electricity due to Hurricane Isaac, in an area that was obliterated by Hurricane Katrina. And less than ten minutes away from me houses in Braithwaite, Plaquemines Parish, are completely submerged.  Here’s my case:</p>
<p><strong>Cities at Risk</strong></p>
<p>New Orleans is nowhere near as much at risk to the problems we face and will face compared to other global cities.  According to a <a title="report" href="http://www.bloomberg.com/slideshow/2012-07-06/top-20-cities-with-billions-at-risk-from-climate-change.html#slide1">report</a> by the Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD), the rise of sea levels put multiple U.S. cities ahead of New Orleans in terms of risk.  The most at risk city in the world is Miami, followed closely by New York City and Newark.  Even around the world, the OECD puts Chinese cities Shanghai, Guangzhou, Tianjin, Hong Kong, and Ningbo more at risk than New Orleans.  Kolkata, Mumbai, Tokyo, and Bangkok were also ahead of New Orleans on the list.  So the notion that New Orleans is the most doomed city in the world and should simply be abandoned is unfounded.  In order for such sentiment to be logical, one must conclude that these cities should not exist as well, even more so than New Orleans.  If not, the hierarchy of what cities deserve the “right to exist” is illogical.  Nonetheless, who determines such a decision anyway?</p>
<p>Cities around the world are at risk from all sorts of disasters.  If you live in an earthquake prone area, you build infrastructure to withstand heavy earthquakes.  Dozens of cities around the globe and in the U.S., like San Francisco and Los Angeles, are built on fault lines. Unfortunately, if you do not build up to a certain code, for whatever reason, an earthquake could be disastrous.  We witnessed this in the Haitian Earthquake of 2010, where over 300,000 people died and over a million were left homeless.  That earthquake registered a 7.0 on the Richter scale. However, in Chile, an earthquake in the same year registering at 8.8 hit the country, but the death toll and damage did not even compare to Haiti.  This is thanks to Chile&#8217;s seismic building code adapted by Salvador Allende in 1972.  The logic is the same with cities along the coast.</p>
<p><strong>Sea Level</strong></p>
<p>Many who make the argument that New Orleans should not exist due to sea level are missing some vital information needed to maintain consistency.  The average sea level in New Orleans is one to two feet below sea level.  The initial flooding of Hurricane Katrina had nothing to do with sea levels.  It was not a natural disaster, it was an engineering disaster.  It had everything to do with a failed and outdated levee system, purposefully built weak and unmaintained to save money (something I will elaborate on later).  A recent <a href="http://blog.nola.com/times-picayune/2007/04/study_bust_myth_that_new_orlea.html">study</a> from Xavier and Tulane shows that more of New Orleans is above sea level rather than below.  Many places that flooded during Katrina were above sea level, including the Lower 9<sup>th</sup> Ward.  Many of the most populated neighborhoods in New Orleans are above sea level: the French Quarter, Uptown (up to 20 feet above sea level in some instances), the Marigny, Bywater, Treme, City Park (which has the highest point of 27.5 feet), etc. Many places around the world that are well above sea level flood.  In 2008, a levee breached in Fernley, Nevada, which led up to almost 3,500 residents requiring emergency rescue as water reached up to six feet.  Fernley is a soaring 4,200 feet above sea level.</p>
<p>An area can be below sea level while being heavily protected.  24% of Holland is below sea level, yet the area remains dry due to an incredibly well-built levee system.  Rotterdam, Netherlands, contains areas of the city <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rotterdam#Geography">some 22 feet below sea level</a>, while the lowest part of New Orleans is seven feet (New Orleans East).  The Port of Rotterdam is the largest and busiest port in Europe, and second in the world.  Places around the world, from Israel to China and India to Germany, have areas with lower elevations than New Orleans.  The success of Rotterdam proves that such a feat is possible if done correctly.  It also proves the sea level argument is overly simplistic and not well researched.</p>
<p><strong>Levees and Pumping System</strong></p>
<p>Another typical argument centers on the selfish notion that tax-dollars should not go to pay for levees or pumping systems that protect other people, primarily in a place like New Orleans.  Many major cities around the world require sophisticated pumping systems to stay dry, from New York City to London, which has some of the largest and most refined pumping stations in the world.  These people fail to realize that 43% of the U.S. population lives in a county/parish that depends on federally funded levees to stay dry, according to the <a title="report" href="http://www.infrastructurereportcard.org/fact-sheet/levees">report</a> “The National Levee Challenge: Report of the Interagency Levee Policy Review Committee” by the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA).  28 states require levees.  To deny New Orleans levees seems outright insensitive and unsympathetic.</p>
<p>Before we continue, the main purpose of this article is not about Hurricane Katrina, but so many naysayers point to the event as evidence why New Orleans is a pointless cause, so myths surrounding it must be addressed and squashed.  Many of our levees are built due to the fact that the Army Corps of Engineers (ACOE) built canals through our neighborhoods and the wetlands for oil and shipping industries to shorten the route to the Gulf of Mexico.  They put profit over people and the people protested it.  The Mississippi River Gulf Outlet (MRGO) was built in the ‘60s to help cargo ships reach the Gulf quicker.  The local residents, especially in St. Bernard Parish, protested it from the start, rejecting the notion that it would bring economic booms (which it never did).  I remember as a kid going over the bridge that crosses the Industrial Canal, or the &#8220;Green Bridge,&#8221; and seeing my father point in the general direction of MRGO and saying that if it does not close, it is going to drown us.</p>
<p>The MRGO mixed fresh water with salt water, which caused massive wetland erosion further eradicating our natural barriers against hurricanes, grew wider than the Panama Canal, caused us millions for dredging purposes, and was hardly used.  In 2005, the MRGO caused massive flooding in the 9<sup>th</sup> Ward and St. Bernard Parish, and funneled water to other canals connected to it which led to the flooding of Lakeview, the New Orleans East, and other areas of the city.  The flooding did not come from the Mississippi River, but the canals undemocratically built around the city.  After the citizens were proved correct, the government closed the MRGO after Hurricane Katrina.  A little too late after at least 1,836 people lost their lives.  To suggest multinational corporations and the federal government should be allowed to build these canals yet the people who lived here for centuries are not allowed to have protection from those canals is both callous and illogical.</p>
<p>The reason these canals flooded in the first place was due to poorly built levees by the ACOE.  In 1985, the ACOE research branch funded an investigation, dubbed the “<a title="E-99" href="http://www.iwr.usace.army.mil/docs/hpdc/docs/19880600_E-99_Sheet_Pile_Wall_Field_Load_Test_Report.pdf)">E-99</a>” test, and concluded the levees will certainly fail if a major hurricane hits New Orleans.  Feeling it was too expensive; the ACOE did absolutely nothing to fix the situation.  The levee failures ended up costing more than $100 billion in damage, when fixing the levees would&#8217;ve just cost millions.  In 2006, the Chief of Engineers for the ACOE, Carl Strock, admitted the ACOE had a “catastrophic failure” in regards to the levees.  He resigned soon after.  In 2009, the ACOE was found guilty for the poorly built levees.  <a href="http://www.scribd.com/doc/22738551/JUDGE-CORPS-LIABLE-FOR-HURRICANE-KATRINA-FLOODING">U.S. District Judge Stanwood Duval, Jr. stated</a>, “&#8230;the corps not only knew, but admitted by 1988, that the MRGO threatened human life&#8230; and yet it did not act in time to prevent the catastrophic disaster that ensued with the onslaught of Hurricane Katrina.”</p>
<p>The flooding of New Orleans was an engineering disaster, not a natural one, which could’ve been prevented with properly built and maintained levee and pumping systems.  Unfortunately, the media and politicians continue to say the opposite, despite the overwhelming evidence, even at the highest levels of government.  President Obama stated at one point, “I think that Katrina was really a wake-up call for the country &#8212; about our need to fulfill our commitments to our fellow citizens, a recognition that there but for the grace of God go I, that all of us can fall prey to these kinds of <em>natural disasters</em>.”</p>
<p>Many other major cities rely on levees as well: Detroit, Louisville, Nashville, Pittsburgh, Memphis, Baltimore, Kansas City, Portland, Seattle, Honolulu, Washington D.C., Omaha, Jacksonville, Savannah, Albuquerque, Tampa Bay, and especially Sacramento, who has the most at-risk levee system in the U.S.  Why should anyone in New Orleans, or any of these cities, not have functionally levees?</p>
<p>(For more information about New Orleans levees visit www.levees.org.)</p>
<p><strong>Port and Economy</strong></p>
<p>Now that we dispelled those myths, we have not even touched on the surface about the positives of New Orleans.  Economically, the <a href="http://portno.com/pno_pages/about_overview.htm">Port of New Orleans</a> is one of largest ports in the U.S. based on volume of cargo.  The Port of South Louisiana is the largest port in the Western Hemisphere.  Together, these ports make up one of the largest in the world.  New Orleans enjoys an incredibly strategic position located at the mouth of the Mississippi River, where it is wide enough to maintain intensive traffic.  It is the only deep-water port in the U.S. that serves six railroads and brings in iron, coffee, steel, coal, timber, chemicals, more than half of the nation’s grain exports, etc. to our nation.  If you lose New Orleans, you lose the port that brings us some of our most important supplies and raw materials.</p>
<p>We have other economies that help the U.S.  Metropolitan New Orleans is the center for the U.S. maritime industry.  We supply a significant portion the nation’s oil refining and petrochemical production.  Louisiana ranks 5<sup>th</sup> in oil production and much of it comes from the New Orleans area.  We are a city of higher learning, with over 50,000 students in the university system.  Our multi-billion dollar tourist industry is massive and one of the largest in the U.S.  We are also home to numerous headquarters for various companies.</p>
<p><strong>Culture</strong></p>
<p>To those from New Orleans, you do not need to read this, as I cannot possibly capture the soul of our culture in this short amount of text.  People wrote books on it and felt unsuccessful.  As Chris Rose, a famous local journalist, once put it:</p>
<p><em>“I&#8217;m not going to lay down in words the lure of this place. Every great writer in the land, from Faulkner to Twain to Rice to Ford, has tried to do it and fallen short. It is impossible to capture the essence, tolerance, and spirit of south Louisiana in words and to try is to roll down a road of clichés, bouncing over beignets and beads and brass bands and it just is what it is. It is home.”</em></p>
<p>New Orleans has a lure which brings people from all over the world to visit and settle.  My great-grandfather came from Sicily to New Orleans in the early 20<sup>th</sup> century and could not imagine living elsewhere.  We have some of the best food in the world.  Ever had etouffee, gumbo, jambalaya, shrimp and grits, muffulettas, po-boys, boiled crawfish, raw oysters, beignets, and the likes?   We love to eat, drink loads of alcohol, and have a great time.  We love the outdoors.  Ever rode on a boat and watched the sun come up through swampy trees while listening to the sounds of pure nature? Should I even mention the music or does that go without say?  We have Mardi Gras.  We have eclectic accents spread out around the city.  We have Spanish and French architecture not found in the rest of the U.S.  We are the epitome of a melting pot.  Our history is so extraordinarily rich with tales of success, tragedy, resistance, and triumph.  People are still charming and laid back, giving us the term “The Big Easy”.  It is addicting and captivating, and if you don’t live around here, it might be hard to understand.  But like Mr. Rose so eloquently put it, I won’t “capture the essence” realistically, so why bother continuing?</p>
<p>Perhaps a friend who was not born here can summarize it better:</p>
<p><em>&#8220;I remember seeing New Orleans for the first time when I was 14 and barely able to construct an abstract thought. I remember that moment because I had never in my life experienced a &#8216;knowing&#8217; that I was about to experience something magical. I LIVE for the strange synchronicity that New Orleans freely gives. I LIVE for stopping on the street to speak to whoever has something to say. I LIVE for New Orleans rhythm&#8230; rhythm that is full of life. Both good and bad. New Orleans is ALIVE! And anybody who believes different is a sad individual that has lost their own meaning.&#8221;</em></p>
<p><strong>Conclusion</strong></p>
<p>There are no logical and well thought-out reasons why New Orleans deserves to be left to drown.  It is a city that must and should be protected.  With rising sea levels and waters getting warmer, investing in smart building is the right thing to do, and we know it can be done.  We will continue to rebuild, preserve our heritage, live life to the fullest, and move forward.  It’s going to take a lot to wipe us off the map, and we are not going anywhere anytime soon.  Laissez les bon temps rouler!</p>
<p><em>-Chris Dier</em></p>
<p>&#8230; we may have our struggles, more than other places in the U.S., but pushing through them demonstrates our love for this area.</p>
<p><em>“People don&#8217;t live in New Orleans because it is easy. They live here because they are incapable of living anywhere else in the just same way.”</em> -Ian McNulty</p>
<p>And as my good friend Amanda Roark puts it, <em>&#8220;I&#8217;d rather struggle in New Orleans than make it anywhere else.&#8221;</em></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=5&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thecaseforneworleans.wordpress.com/2012/09/01/the-case-for-the-greater-new-orleans-area-why-we-matter-and-why-we-should-exist/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>54</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/fa7477cda64a8b41d5f883d95176b378?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">thecaseforneworleans</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>