<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2013 21:02:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Parenting Politics&#8230;In My House</title>
		<link>http://themamafesto.wordpress.com/2013/03/02/parenting-politics-in-my-house/</link>
		<comments>http://themamafesto.wordpress.com/2013/03/02/parenting-politics-in-my-house/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2013 18:37:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>The Mamafesto</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mommy Wars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marissa Mayer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PhD In Parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sheryl Sandberg]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://themamafesto.wordpress.com/?p=2379</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[With heavy media focus on Yahoo!&#8217;s Marissa Meyer and Facebook&#8217;s Sheryl Sandberg, it&#8217;s no wonder that the topic of motherhood is as newsworthy as ever. Yet, this focus seems very narrow, limiting the discussion solely to mothers and work, when in reality we could stand to broaden the conversation to both parents and how they manage [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2379&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With heavy media focus on Yahoo!&#8217;s Marissa Meyer and Facebook&#8217;s Sheryl Sandberg, it&#8217;s no wonder that the topic of motherhood is as newsworthy as ever. Yet, this focus seems very narrow, limiting the discussion solely to mothers and work, when in reality we could stand to <a href="http://www.thefrisky.com/2013-02-04/mommie-dearest-mom-vs-dad-who-takes-the-lead/" target="_blank">broaden the conversation to both parents and how they manage the work/life balance</a>. Motherhood doesn&#8217;t exist in a bubble, and if we want to discuss the challenges facing working mothers, it would behoove us to look at how entire families manage their balancing acts. I&#8217;m not the only one who&#8217;d like to see a shift in how we talk about these things.</p>
<p>My friend Annie from <a href="http://www.phdinparenting.com/" target="_blank">PhD In Parenting</a> -  who has written about <a href="http://www.phdinparenting.com/blog/2013/2/24/marissa-mayer-and-sheryl-sandberg-when-executive-women-keep.html" target="_blank">Meyer and Sandberg before</a> -  is eager for the focus on the work/life balance to move beyond a women&#8217;s issue to one that is a parenting issue. In hopes of widening the conversation, Annie has put out a call, asking for parents to write about their own households  and what the parenting split looks like within it. I asked Annie more about her motivation behind this call for stories:</p>
<blockquote><p>There are two things that prompted me. One is the continued focus on work/life balance as a women&#8217;s issue. I&#8217;d like to see it be a people&#8217;s issue. Why do women need to worry about whether their workplace has family friendly policies, while men (and men&#8217;s bosses) just assume they&#8217;ll keep on doing what they did in the same way they did before they had kids? The other reason is that I keep being told that equally shared parenting is impossible if the mom breastfeeds. I know that isn&#8217;t true (it wasn&#8217;t in our home) and I want to provide some examples for how you can breastfeed and still maintain equality.</p></blockquote>
<p>I&#8217;m all for adding more stories to the narrative of parenting, and said that I would be happy to share my own&#8230;</p>
<p>We need to start by going back in time, about ten years ago. I was teaching high school social studies and was the primary wage earner while MD was in school full time working on his doctorate. That&#8217;s the way our unit of two worked for four years. I paid the bills, and MD wracked them up (well, okay, he wracked up student loans, but we&#8217;re still paying for them, so&#8230;.). Then, just as he finished his program, we got pregnant. Literally, on the day he graduated, I woke up, peed on a stick and bam &#8211; we were having a baby!</p>
<p>We also decided to move out of state that summer. MD had a job waiting for him, and I was finishing up my Masters thesis, which I had began two years earlier (Yes. I simultaneously worked full time while working on my MA). At the time we moved, I was already 6 months pregnant, and couldn&#8217;t fathom starting over teaching at a new school only to leave 3 months in for maternity leave, so I opted to focus on my studies. MD, with his new job, was the primary wage earner now. Our roles were reversed but things went on as usual.</p>
<div id="attachment_2381" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://themamafesto.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/374_44891769987_5159_n.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-2381" alt="If by usual you mean hula hooping in the yard while pregnant. Then, yeah. The usual." src="http://themamafesto.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/374_44891769987_5159_n.jpg?w=300&#038;h=218" width="300" height="218" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">If by usual you mean hula hooping in the yard while pregnant. Then, yeah. The usual.</p></div>
<p>I firmly believe that it was because we had both been the sole wage earner at a point in our relationship that we were able to easily slide into an equitable parenting relationship. We had already done away with the traditional gender roles, so we didn&#8217;t fall into that trap either accidentally or willingly.</p>
<p>When the kiddo was born, I was in the editing phase of my thesis, and still focused on my academics. MD was working, but manage to scrap together a month off between paid family leave, paid vacation, and unpaid time off from work. I also firmly believe that MD having an entire month off from work helped solidify are more equitable parenting structure, and I can only imagine the benefits our family would have received had he been eligible for more. (Alas, in this country,<a href="http://themamafesto.wordpress.com/2012/05/15/distraction/" target="_blank"> we know that ain&#8217;t happening</a>).</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s a breakdown of parenting in the Norman Nathman household through the years:</p>
<p>-When the kiddo was a wee one, neither of us slept much, but we slept enough. We breastfed, which necessitated me being up with the kiddo at all hours of the night. However, in the beginning, he was also making a lot of wet and dirty diapers. Since I was the one up to feed him, MD was the one to deal with the diapers. I was able to fall asleep much faster/easier and MD is the master of going right back to deep sleep, so he was fine. Breaking up the nighttime parenting like that caused less resentment on either of our parts and assured that we both got some sleep &#8211; which is totally better than no sleep. I&#8217;ll be honest and say that co-sleeping was also key for us. I know it doesn&#8217;t work for everyone, but being able to roll over, get my son nursing and essentially fall back to sleep was huge in allowing me to feel like I wasn&#8217;t running on fumes 24/7.</p>
<div id="attachment_2383" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://themamafesto.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/374_44891809987_7197_n.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-2383" alt="Our family of 3(6 years ago!)" src="http://themamafesto.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/374_44891809987_7197_n.jpg?w=300&#038;h=218" width="300" height="218" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Our family of 3<br />(6 years ago!)</p></div>
<p>-While MD was home in that first month, pretty much everything else was equal &#8211; we shared meal prep, cleaning, baby stuff, etc&#8230; After he went to work, only a few things changed. I took on a bit more responsibility when it came to household chores, most notably laundry and grocery shopping, but everything else remained fairly equal.</p>
<p>- Babywearing was our savior. Seriously. I know not every baby enjoys being worn, but EZ was all about it. MD would pop the kiddo into a sling or mei tai and head off on a walk or go do the dishes. I could get things done while wearing him that I doubt I could have accomplished otherwise. Babywearing helped keep us sane well into the toddler years, and prevented many arguments about nap time &#8211; both between parents and parent &amp; child.</p>
<div id="attachment_2380" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://themamafesto.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/257_23668954987_2117_n.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-2380" alt="257_23668954987_2117_n" src="http://themamafesto.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/257_23668954987_2117_n.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">A father, his son, and an Ergo.</p></div>
<p>-Now, with the kiddo being 6 (SIX!) years old, and both of us working, it&#8217;s a little bit different but still pretty equal. We both have strange schedules &#8211; since I work primarily out of the home, my time is a bit more flexible, however MD only works 4 days a week, so he has some flexibility as well. We split school drop off/pick up between ourselves depending on who is home or who has appointments, etc&#8230; EZ has a few after school activities that also get split evenly depending on who is home (as in, if MD is off work, he&#8217;s the one taking the kiddo). Grocery shopping is an even split now as well, same goes for cooking. We each tackle cleaning in our own ways. I prefer to clean as I go, whereas MD enjoys doing one huge deep clean every 2 weeks or so. It balances the housework nicely and we manage to have a decently clean house (save for the hundreds of Lego pieces that still manage to fall under foot).</p>
<p>-When he&#8217;s home, MD is the go-to parent when it comes to bedtime, and I only do it when he&#8217;s working past 8 (which happens 2x/week). The kiddo is old enough to do bath time by himself and he also pitches in with some chores. I&#8217;m more than happy to have him see his father fold laundry, wash dishes, make dinner, as well as seeing me take out the trash, do minor fix-it type jobs around the house, etc&#8230;</p>
<p>-As I type this, on a Saturday morning, MD and EZ are downstairs playing Wii after having read books together. I&#8217;ve worked on our taxes and typed up this post. Our weekends are usually split between things we want to do and things we have to do &#8211; each of us gets some alone time if we want/need it.</p>
<p>I don&#8217;t think of our family as remarkable in any sense, but I do think we&#8217;re outside the norm when it comes to our parenting split. I don&#8217;t think of my husband as my son&#8217;s babysitter and he doesn&#8217;t see himself in that role either. Sure there are days when I take on the brunt of household chores or parenting responsibilities, but the pendulum swings both ways. Next weekend I&#8217;ll be gone for a couple of days, but I have no worries over what will happen while I&#8217;m away. MD doesn&#8217;t live up to or default to the &#8220;big oaf&#8221; daddy trap &#8211; it&#8217;s insulting to both of us. He&#8217;s a parent just as much as I am. Our parenting methods might differ, but our goals are the same.</p>
<p>I will say though, that we do get some pushback from those outside our family. MD&#8217;s place of work sometimes doesn&#8217;t understand why he tries to rearrange his schedule to be able to attend school or sports events. When he wanted to take a month off after the birth if EZ, he was met with a bit of resistance and a lot of bewilderment from his boss who couldn&#8217;t comprehend <em>why</em> MD would want to be home with his family. Also, because I work from home, there&#8217;s a lot of expectation from others that I take on <strong>all </strong>of the housework since &#8220;it&#8217;s just so convenient!&#8221; There is still definitely an overall attitude that women &#8211; by default &#8211; take on the majority of household chores, regardless of their work status. If a woman chooses to be a homemaker, then I can understand that thought, but otherwise? We all live here, we all pitch in, it&#8217;s as simple as that. We&#8217;re raising our son so that he understands the value of equality, both inside the home as well as outside of it.</p>
<p>However, I would be remiss if I didn&#8217;t mention our village that helps us out, made up of both biological family and chosen family. Our intentional community of friends and relatives help us out from carpooling, playmates, shared meals,<a href="http://themamafesto.wordpress.com/2011/10/21/self-care-it-takes-a-village/" target="_blank"> in times of need</a>, etc&#8230; That helps lighten the load for all of us. We are also fortunate to have work that, despite some unique challenges, affords us with a good degree of flexibility.</p>
<p>All that said &#8211; it&#8217;s far from perfect here. There are days where the house is littered with rumpled baskets of clean clothes because nobody feels like folding them. We probably eat take out more than we&#8217;d prefer simply because we get too lazy/busy to cook. I&#8217;m fairly certain my kitchen floors haven&#8217;t been washed in months (they look clean, so&#8230;) and there&#8217;s usually a dirty pot or dish in the sink. But, for the most part we&#8217;re happy, healthy, and usually have clean underwear, so I&#8217;d say we&#8217;re managing pretty well.</p>
<div id="attachment_2385" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 233px"><a href="http://themamafesto.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/264681_10150361102009988_3174731_n.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-2385" alt="Yeah, it can get messy, but we have fun. " src="http://themamafesto.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/264681_10150361102009988_3174731_n.jpg?w=223&#038;h=300" width="223" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Yeah, it can get messy, but we have fun.</p></div>
<p>What about you? What&#8217;s the situation like in your house? Are their two working parents? One parent working the other at home? Just one parent? What does the work/life balance look like in your home?</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2379/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2379/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2379&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://themamafesto.wordpress.com/2013/03/02/parenting-politics-in-my-house/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>22</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://themamafesto.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/374_44891809987_7197_n.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://themamafesto.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/374_44891809987_7197_n.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">374_44891809987_7197_n</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/de400df62df5592d2a3c647842246ff7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">themamafesto</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://themamafesto.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/374_44891769987_5159_n.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">If by usual you mean hula hooping in the yard while pregnant. Then, yeah. The usual.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://themamafesto.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/374_44891809987_7197_n.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Our family of 3(6 years ago!)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://themamafesto.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/257_23668954987_2117_n.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">257_23668954987_2117_n</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://themamafesto.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/264681_10150361102009988_3174731_n.jpg?w=223" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Yeah, it can get messy, but we have fun. </media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How To Buy A Wolf Shirt</title>
		<link>http://shutupdad.wordpress.com/2013/03/04/how-to-buy-a-wolf-shirt/</link>
		<comments>http://shutupdad.wordpress.com/2013/03/04/how-to-buy-a-wolf-shirt/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2013 14:55:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Andrew</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Random]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andrew Maxwell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comedy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gray wolf]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Moon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shut up dad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[T-shirt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thrift store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wolf pack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wolf shirt]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://shutupdad.wordpress.com/?p=2600</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As most of you know, purchasing a new wolf shirt can be an important and painstaking process.  As difficult or even more so than buying a new car, a new home, or adopting a child.  You want to find that perfect wolf shirt that will not only meet your functional needs, but your fashion needs [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2600&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As most of you know, purchasing a new wolf shirt can be an important and painstaking process.  As difficult or even more so than buying a new car, a new home, or adopting a child.  You want to find that perfect wolf shirt that will not only meet your functional needs, but your fashion needs as well.  From someone that understands that burden, I&#8217;ve done my best to narrow down the most essential factors to make your purchasing process go as smooth as possible.  I will use a shirt I recently bought as an example.</p>
<p><a href="http://shutupdad.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2628" alt="1" src="http://shutupdad.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/1.jpg?w=560&#038;h=746" width="560" height="746" /></a></p>
<p><strong>1.  Eye Placement</strong> &#8211; Always take notice of the placement of the wolf&#8217;s eyes.  Are they glowing?  Are they sad?  Are they wise?  There are many factors to consider, but those are some great starters.  You&#8217;ll notice on my shirt, the eyes are glowing and piercing. You can feel them in your very soul.  He is the alpha wolf.  And he knows you.  All of you.  Even the parts of you that you hide from the rest of the world.  But in addition to that omniscient gaze, notice the large size of the eyes.  Not to mention they are centrally located for optimal viewing pleasure.  Eye coverage to this degree is a rarity.  The previous owner of this shirt was a fool for donating it.  And so were the employees at the thrift store for selling this priceless article of clothing for so cheap.  But I wasn&#8217;t going to tell them that.</p>
<p><a href="http://shutupdad.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/3-e1362359201713.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2631" alt="3" src="http://shutupdad.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/3-e1362359201713.jpg?w=560&#038;h=420" width="560" height="420" /></a></p>
<p><b>2.  Pack Member Presence </b>-  I know this is a touchy subject with most wolf enthusiasts.  But in my opinion, the inclusion of the other pack members is non negotiable.  Yes a lone wolf is very &#8220;cool&#8221;, and that rustic solitude can definitely be a thing of great beauty.  But people who wear those shirts are simply lying to themselves and insulting our intelligence.  Wolves are pack animals.  They depend on it for survival.  If you see someone with one of these shirts, laugh at them and tell them &#8220;Nice fannypack, loser.&#8221; (They will definitely be wearing one). As you can see my shirt has the full pack located at the bottom.</p>
<p><a href="http://shutupdad.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/2-e1362359420808.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2634" alt="2" src="http://shutupdad.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/2-e1362359420808.jpg?w=560&#038;h=420" width="560" height="420" /></a></p>
<p><strong>3.  Moon Or Lack There Of -</strong> Ask me this same question tomorrow, and honestly my answer might be different.  I go back and forth on this.  Should there be a full moon in view somewhere on the shirt for it to be an authentic &#8220;wolf shirt&#8221;?  I mean yes, a big bright moon in the background can be hauntingly beautiful.  But is it necessary?  Are wolves not amazing in the daytime?  Does freshly killed prey taste any better bathed in moonlight?  See my point?  It&#8217;s a tough one.  My shirt does not have a moon on it, and that may bother some people.  But I could argue that the giant eye size would make up for it.</p>
<p><a href="http://shutupdad.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/whmn.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2619" alt="whmn" src="http://shutupdad.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/whmn.jpg?w=560&#038;h=420" width="560" height="420" /></a></p>
<p><b>4.  Dreamcatchers -</b>  Does a wolf shirt look better with a dreamcater on it?  Yes.  Everything looks better with dreamcatchers on them.  Am I disappointed that my shirt does not have one?  Of course I am.  But sitting around lamenting about it wouldn&#8217;t change anything.</p>
<p><a href="http://shutupdad.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/wdrct.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2615" alt="wdrct" src="http://shutupdad.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/wdrct.jpg?w=334&#038;h=447" width="334" height="447" /></a></p>
<p><b>5.  Additional Animals</b> &#8211; A common misconception is that having additional animals (i.e. eagles and bears) on a shirt, can actually enhance the shirt.  To me that is a moot point.  If you&#8217;re buying a wolf shirt, you need to focus on the above criteria.  If you need extra &#8220;animal power&#8221;, then you&#8217;re clearly not a wolf purist, and you&#8217;re reading the wrong blog.  Although eagles and bears are great, I&#8217;ve always been more of a wolf guy.  It&#8217;s not something I chose.  I was born that way.  So to me personally, I don&#8217;t think they belong on a wolf shirt.</p>
<p><a href="http://shutupdad.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/mbwsh.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2613" alt="mbwsh" src="http://shutupdad.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/mbwsh.jpg?w=290&#038;h=300" width="290" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>Well I hope this helped.  Buying those shirts will still be difficult, and I don&#8217;t envy you.  But at least you&#8217;ll have some fodder for the fire going in.  Oh and I almost forgot.  My shirt rating.  I give it four out of five fangs.  It almost reaches perfection, but misses slightly due to the lack of  dreamcatchers.  So I had to deduct a fang.  Happy hunting!</p>
<span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='420' height='315' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/Rk_sAHh9s08?version=3&#038;rel=0&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2600/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2600/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2600&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://shutupdad.wordpress.com/2013/03/04/how-to-buy-a-wolf-shirt/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>16</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/9cd235859fc9ee971196660fcdb32abd?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">shutupdad</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://shutupdad.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://shutupdad.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/3-e1362359201713.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">3</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://shutupdad.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/2-e1362359420808.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://shutupdad.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/whmn.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">whmn</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://shutupdad.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/wdrct.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">wdrct</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://shutupdad.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/mbwsh.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mbwsh</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Living Your Values</title>
		<link>http://leahwise.com/2013/03/04/march-3-homily/</link>
		<comments>http://leahwise.com/2013/03/04/march-3-homily/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2013 02:09:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>leahwise</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[thoughts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[action]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christianity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consumerism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[devotional]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[episcopal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[homily]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[march]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[morality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sermon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social justice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spiritual discipline]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the burning bush]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the parable of the fig tree]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://leahwise.com/?p=1737</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I was asked to do the homily for March 3rd&#8217;s evening service at the church I attend here in Charlottesville. Now that it&#8217;s done (and I managed not to faint or run away from the podium), I thought I&#8217;d share it here.  Readings: Exodus 3:1-15, Luke 13:1-9 In today’s biblical texts, we can trace a [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1737&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>I was asked to do the homily for March 3rd&#8217;s evening service at the church I attend here in Charlottesville. Now that it&#8217;s done (and I managed not to faint or run away from the podium), I thought I&#8217;d share it here. </em></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><em><a href="http://leahwise.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/moses.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1754" alt="moses and the burning bush" src="http://leahwise.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/moses.jpg?w=582&#038;h=488" width="582" height="488" /></a></em></p>
<p><strong>Readings:</strong> Exodus 3:1-15, Luke 13:1-9</p>
<p>In today’s biblical texts, we can trace a clear progression. It has to do with human responsibility. But it’s not an obligation we place on ourselves. It’s one God has compelled us toward since his first meeting with Moses in the burning bush and maybe even before.</p>
<p><b>It’s a responsibility to personal growth that turns to action. </b></p>
<p>The Exodus passage begins with Moses going about his daily tasks. In the Old Testament’s typically understated fashion, the text tells us that Moses is suddenly quite curious about a burning bush that is not consumed: “I must turn aside and look at this great sight.”</p>
<p>The commentary in the New Oxford Annotated Bible notes that the motif of <i>Divine Fire</i> is common in this period and that it: “arouses dread, for divine holiness is experienced as a mysterious power that threatens human existence.”</p>
<p>So we can assume that Moses approaches with some understanding of what he’s seeing. When God tells him, “You will set your people free,” he doesn’t need to waste time figuring out if it’s God; he doesn’t doubt. He knows.</p>
<p>And he is so in awe of the Divine that <b>he is afraid to look at God</b>.</p>
<p>Though many of us have heard this passage before, it struck me this time in that it shows an incredible measure of trust on God’s part. Though he has seen the pain and struggle of his people himself, though he has the power to show himself in a bush that isn’t consumed, <b>he tells Moses that HE will do it</b>. God, knowing that perhaps he is unsuitable to act as liaison to Pharaoh considering a general “DREAD” of the Divine, in a sense needs a human to implement his plan. And Moses doesn’t seem to be a random choice. He is the right person for the job.</p>
<p><b>The first step we take in living within God’s will is one we don’t take at all. It’s an acceptance to let the blazing fire – the passion &#8211; of God be kindled in us and the moral diligence to not let it be consumed by doubt, apathy, worry, or self absorption. It’s also the confidence that this passion will lead us forward in ways that suit us, even if not in ways that make us feel comfortable.</b></p>
<p>And that brings us to Luke.</p>
<p>In the first part of chapter 13, Jesus addresses our human tendency to turn a blind eye to those we perceive as the Other. He confronts a bias born of privilege, one that states that <b>My life is good because I’m a good person</b> and gets reiterated every time someone other than us or our loved ones suffer.</p>
<p>Jesus extends the work of his father in Exodus, who insisted that mere humans feel the passion of his people’s pain and DO SOMETHING about it. He says, “unless you repent you will all perish as they did.”</p>
<p>You’re not better. You’re not more righteous. You got out for now, but you have to do something with that.</p>
<p><b>His parable ties it all together</b>. God expects great things from us, but we’re just as led astray as a sterile fig tree. Jesus comes to us with grace. He gives us a second chance. He opens our eyes by coming not in the form of a burning bush that makes us turn away, but in the recognizable, comforting form of our own species. It had become clear that we were too consumed in fear to be consumed in God’s loving justice, so God became one of us to show us we could succeed. We see Christ and his mission and we don’t have to turn away – we can embrace it.</p>
<p>God came first with passion, with fury and movement and an impatient drive to protect his people. And he let one of us in. He gave us the power to do something and the motivation to do it. But, just like the disciples and Jesus’ listening crowds, we got lost again in our own concerns. And we saw suffering and only felt lucky not to be suffering, too. And we repeat the cycle daily.</p>
<p><b>But we aren&#8217;t better. We aren&#8217;t better because we’re Americans or Episcopalians or Liberals or Conservatives or Charlottesvillians or UVA students. We see suffering and do nothing. We aggressively consume products presented to us through slave labor &#8211; we ignore the bullying, prejudice, and apathy in our own communities and in our own hearts &#8211; and we consume ourselves in the process of curating and collecting things and experiences, gluttons to our wants. And we think it’s ok because we’ve told ourselves other people are worse than us. All the while, the burning fire God presented us with is burning out.</b></p>
<p>We know through today’s texts that we are no better than anyone else. We all come to this life as equals in both merit and guilt. We need this humility to see suffering and empathize with it. We also learn through Moses that God shows us suffering in the places where we have influence, where we can take action.</p>
<p>For instance, our lives as consumers have the power to change or destroy lives. Human beings – people like us – suffer long hours, poor wages, and poor working conditions in the futile attempt to make ends meet at the hands of American corporations fueled by American consumers. Instead of feeling lucky to be here, we should recognize that we aren’t better, that we are the same. And once that hits us, we should realize that WE have the collective power – and the moral obligation through the Bible’s teachings – to make changes to set the suffering free. We can only liberate ourselves when we liberate others.</p>
<p>If we <i>shut down</i> from the important moral responsibilities laid out before us, we deserve to perish. But we’re given a second chance because Jesus believes in us, believes that with a little prodding, we can bear fruit again, and stands by us as we turn away, as we deflate our egos, as we press on to equality and progress.</p>
<p>As Christians, we are tasked to do something with the fire of God in front of us, and through Christ, we can face it head-on and not turn away. We are commanded to “turn aside [from the things that distract us] and look at this great sight” of suffering on earth and change our habits, our minds, our hearts. <b>To set the slaves of unethical values, consumption, trafficking, patriarchy, hatred, and false conceptions of God free. We can only do that if we see that we are all the same, and that God is with us as we move toward equality under the banner of Christ’s grace and love. </b></p>
<p>I encourage you to assess your values and priorities during the remainder of the Lenten season and to make positive, visible, DIFFICULT changes in your own life.</p>
<h3><a href="http://secretaryofinnovation.com/2011/12/26/musing-johnny-appleseed-of-the-cosmos/">Image source</a>: Illustration from the 1897 Bible Pictures and What They Teach Us</h3>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1737/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1737/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1737&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://leahwise.com/2013/03/04/march-3-homily/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>12</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/7275a05d768352dff61930efe8206f99?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">leahwise</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://leahwise.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/moses.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">moses and the burning bush</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>\&#8221;Don\&#8217;t Know What You Got (Till It\&#8217;s Gone)\&#8221;</title>
		<link>http://mixedtapemasterpiece.wordpress.com/2013/03/04/radio-xvi-side-b-track-12-dont-know-what-you-got-till-its-gone-by-cinderella/</link>
		<comments>http://mixedtapemasterpiece.wordpress.com/2013/03/04/radio-xvi-side-b-track-12-dont-know-what-you-got-till-its-gone-by-cinderella/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2013 18:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Starstorm</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cinderella]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Radio XVI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adolescence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Don't Know What You Got (Till It's Gone)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[farm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Minnesota]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mixed tape]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nostalgia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[radio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[small town]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mixedtapemasterpiece.wordpress.com/?p=4055</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Oh, Cinderella, as I&#8217;ve mentioned before, this song was specifically made for high school dances.  The ladies loved to slow dance to this one.  And when it came to slow dancing, there was only one body part that I was acutely aware of:  my hands.  Because depending on where one&#8217;s hands were located on your [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4055&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://mixedtapemasterpiece.wordpress.com/2013/03/04/radio-xvi-side-b-track-12-dont-know-what-you-got-till-its-gone-by-cinderella/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://mixedtapemasterpiece.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/radioxvisidebtrack12dontknowwhatyougottilitsgone.mp3" length="7196084" type="audio/mpeg" />
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/bf06d8dc3ce99c9242bc4acf182577ca?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Starstorm</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mixedtapemasterpiece.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/cinderella-dont-know-what-you-got-till-its-gone.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Cinderella Dont Know What You Got Till Its Gone</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mixedtapemasterpiece.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/radioxvisidebtrack12dontknowwhatyougottilitsgone.mp3" medium="audio">
			<media:player url="http://mixedtapemasterpiece.wordpress.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf?soundFile=http://mixedtapemasterpiece.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/radioxvisidebtrack12dontknowwhatyougottilitsgone.mp3" />
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Looking at Photos</title>
		<link>http://njwv.wordpress.com/2013/03/04/looking-at-photos/</link>
		<comments>http://njwv.wordpress.com/2013/03/04/looking-at-photos/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2013 14:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>njwv</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://njwv.wordpress.com/?p=2425</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Every photographs tells a story, the old adage goes. It’s a wonderful cliché, it’s a horrible cliché, and it’s most certainly not true. What stories do these photographs of my grandfather tell me? Having looked at them for so long now (a few years) I’m still not an inch closer to knowing anything about the [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2425&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p style="text-align:left;">Every photographs tells a story, the old adage goes. It’s a wonderful cliché, it’s a horrible cliché, and it’s most certainly not true. What stories do these photographs of my grandfather tell me? Having looked at them for so long now (a few years) I’m still not an inch closer to knowing anything about the man.</p>
<p style="text-align:right;">—Joerg Colberg, Meditations on Photographs:<br />
<a href="http://jmcolberg.com/weblog/extended/archives/meditations_on_photographs_josef_nowak_by_an_unknown_photographer_1/">Josef Nowak by an unknown photographer</a></p>
</blockquote>
<p>I really liked this post since Colberg manages to put his thumb right on one of the things which bothers me most about a lot of photographs—in particular vernacular photographs. Between the rosy past which old photographs hint at and the way we’re trying to ape that look with hipstagram filters in digital photos, we’re trying and struggling to get our photos to tell a story through just their appearance.</p>
<p>Most photography has always been personal. We make personal images for our personal use. They help us remember and remind us of the past. They don’t tell a story, they prompt the stories. Each image in a scrapbook presents an opportunity for a relative to tell a story associated with it. But by themselves, the images don’t mean much.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a title="HI-4 by rlnv, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/rlnv/6890145573/"><img class="aligncenter" alt="HI-4" src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7069/6890145573_4584357f7a.jpg" width="500" height="356" /></a></p>
<p>Old images though do hold a special appeal. That they’ve survived means we tend to treat them as objects rather than images. They often look extremely neat and it’s a lot of fun to see the old fashions, etc. But even when we know who the subject is, they don’t really tell us much about them. When I looked through the <a href="http://njwv.wordpress.com/2012/02/24/hawaii-scans/">box of photos I brought back from Hawai‘i</a>, I found myself more interested in seeing bits of my cousins in the photos of my grandmother.</p>
<p>It was nice to get some background from my mother about who the people were. But none of those stories were <em>in</em> the photos.</p>
<blockquote><p>I submit that <strong>we have chosen to create and view faux-vintage photos because they seem more authentic and real</strong>. One does not need to be consciously aware of this when choosing the filter, hitting the “like” button on Facebook or reblogging on Tumblr. We have associated authenticity with the style of a vintage photo because, previously, vintage photos <em>were</em> <em>actually vintage</em>. They stood the test of time, they described a world past, and, as such, they earned a sense of importance.</p>
<p style="text-align:right;">—Nathan Jurgenson, <a href="http://thesocietypages.org/cyborgology/2011/05/14/the-faux-vintage-photo-full-essay-parts-i-ii-and-iii/">The Faux-Vintage Photo</a></p>
</blockquote>
<p>This sense of importance via survival can’t be ignored when thinking about how we look at photos. It’s the background context for everything. Pseudo-vintage filters took advantage of this by triggering a lot of the vintage feelings.* And I suspect that, while not fully articulated, a lot of the outrage about the filters** is the same reason why <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=f3xe-Wxio1o">we all hate hipsters</a>. We don’t like cultural capital to be appropriated without authenticity. It’s not exactly lying, but it triggers some of the same responses as lying does.</p>
<p><em>*Though it should be noted that there is something about real vintage photos which shines through even if they are <a href="http://njwv.wordpress.com/2012/08/29/instagram-experiment/">instagrammed later</a>. The mind is not fooled that easily.</em></p>
<p><em>**I have to admit that <a href="http://njwv.wordpress.com/2013/01/08/iphones-ipods-and-filters/">I find filters to be fun</a>.</em></p>
<p>At the same time, importance via survival also points at a key distinction between photography in the past and photography now. <a href="http://njwv.wordpress.com/2011/01/12/editing-and-art/">Photography is unique among the arts in that discards are both preserved and often indistinguishable from keepers.</a> Editing is hard. Time is a great editor and makes our jobs easier. Yes, there are boxes of prints and negatives in many attics. But many many more of those are lost or destroyed.</p>
<blockquote><p>As usually, photography’s chronic problem is to believe that its problems are acute. In this case, it seems that photography has, if not always, then from <em>nearly</em> the very beginning, been in the situation it is now: struggling to make sense of a staggering increase in the rate of production of photographs.</p>
<p style="text-align:right;">—1/125, <a href="http://one125.net/post/42945954083/pull-it-down-or-burn-it-up">Pull it Down or Burn it Up</a></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Which is where I think a lot of our anxiety about the current proliferation of images comes from. The anxiety is not new. What is new is the loss of our editor. If nothing can ever be deleted from the internet, mere survival is no longer noteworthy. We’re all looking into a future of billions of unedited images with no easy way of distinguishing keepers from discards. This is indeed scary.</p>
<p>At the same time, while we know what we’re walking into, we’re also unable to stop taking more and more photos even when what we’re photographing is, or has been, photographed better by someone else.</p>
<p>What are we actually looking at now?</p>
<blockquote class='twitter-tweet' lang='en'><p>President Obama &amp; @<a href="https://twitter.com/FLOTUS">FLOTUS</a> Michelle Obama dance together at the inaugural ball last night in Washington, DC: <a href="http://t.co/5m7As3Sy" rel="nofollow">http://t.co/5m7As3Sy</a></p>&mdash; <br />The White House (@whitehouse) <a href='http://twitter.com/#!/whitehouse/status/293868681656672256' data-datetime='2013-01-22T23:52:09+00:00'>January 22, 2013</a></blockquote>
<p>The foreground of this photo is amazing. Everyone is recording the scene on their personal devices. People are holding phones and camera up in the air hoping to get some sort of record of the scene. I can’t imagine that any of those are better than the official footage. It’s not like any of them will <a href="http://njwv.wordpress.com/2012/12/03/art-photographer/">have an opinion</a>.</p>
<p>In many ways, we’re no longer taking photos at all. We’re viewing, and reviewing, life through a viewfinder.</p>
<blockquote><p>We need a new vocabulary to deal with this. There’s the phenomenal use of pictures, and there’s photography as a self-conscious practice. They aren’t congruent anymore.</p>
<p style="text-align:right;">—Francis Hodgson, <a href="http://francishodgson.com/2013/02/20/photography-changes-everything/">Photography Changes Everything</a></p>
<p>The act of photographing, the gesture, has become part of our interaction with the world. You photograph just like you look. You know that you can never look at all of those photographs again (in all likelihood you never will—who has the time?), but it’s not about the photographs—it’s about the photographing. The act of photography might have turned into the equivalent of whistling a song, something you do, something that might or might not have beauty, a communicative act just as much as an affirmative act: I was there, and me being there means I had to photograph it.</p>
<p style="text-align:right;">—Joerg Colberg, Meditations on Photographs:<br />
<a href="http://jmcolberg.com/weblog/extended/archives/meditations_on_photographs_a_car_on_fire_at_the_mall_by_jmc/">A Car on Fire at the Mall by JM Colberg</a></p>
<p>While some people say that the art of photography is knowing what <em>not to shoot</em>, perhaps the art of experiencing life for a photographer may be knowing what <em>not to record</em>. Watching the world through a viewfinder certainly distances you from what’s going on in front of you.</p>
<p style="text-align:right;">—Jason Schlachet, <a href="http://schlachet.net/2011/01/recording-the-action-or-not/">Recording the Action, or not</a></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Life through the viewfinder indeed. Taking pictures is how we interact with the world now. It’s probably best that we distinguish taking pictures from photography the same way we distinguish using words from writing. Not everyone who uses a camera is, or intends to be, a photographer.* Many just want to take pictures to interact with the world.</p>
<p><em>*Flickr evidence of so many new DSLR owners wanting to “go pro” to the contrary. </em></p>
<p>“I was here.”</p>
<p>“I ate this.”</p>
<p>“So this happened.”</p>
<p>Most photos now have the same ephemeral quality of tweets and facebook status updates. Yes, they’ll live forever. But they’re not intended to be permanent record—even though we, collectively, should know better.</p>
<p>With the trend moving toward <a href="http://www.google.com/glass/start/">constant documentation</a>, it’s pretty clear that things are only going to get worse unless we can figure out how to edit.</p>
<p>Either that or we’ll start to turn off the cameras once we tire of recording everything. As much as photography is how we interact with our world now, it’s still used more for unique experiences. When something is new or novel, out come the cameras and out come the photos without anything truly interesting to say. This is <a href="http://njwv.wordpress.com/2013/02/18/human-zoo/">why travel photography often sucks</a>. And it’s <a href="http://njwv.wordpress.com/2011/01/15/bird-in-the-hand/">why most of my bird photos sucked</a>. And it’s why I haven’t been photographing my second-born child.</p>
<p>Once something becomes routine, the cameras get put away.</p>
<p>After the novelty is gone, the choices are to either work for the really interesting photos or experience things without being filtered by the camera.</p>
<p>I always enjoy this stage. When I’m only looking for specific things and no longer feel compelled to shoot everything, the act of photography becomes much more enjoyable even while I take fewer photos. <a href="http://njwv.wordpress.com/2012/05/28/zen/">Photography is zen. Taking photos is not.</a> But then I get the sense that I’m somewhat weird in this regard. I enjoy seeing potential and would happily forget to use my camera while I record a scene in my mind.</p>
<blockquote class='twitter-tweet' lang='en'><p>I think my biggest problem with Google Glass though is that I don&#039;t want to record what I see but rather what my mind sees.</p>&mdash; <br />nick (@vossbrink) <a href='http://twitter.com/#!/vossbrink/status/305150587513749504' data-datetime='2013-02-23T03:02:24+00:00'>February 23, 2013</a></blockquote>
<p>I don’t expect most other people to share my view though. I also don’t expect people to learn how to edit what we shoot.</p>
<p>So those of us who care about photography are left having to learn how to edit and share what we’ve edited. Or, in other words, <a href="http://njwv.wordpress.com/2012/10/29/looking-at-the-land/">follow Andy Adams’s lead</a>. Curation and critique, if done properly, is a legitimate creative outlet now. Instead of writing endlessly about “is photography dead” or “how do we handle all these images” or “are apps/photoshop/whatever cheating,” just a simple “I like these because” will help clear the noise.</p>
<blockquote class='twitter-tweet' lang='en'><p>Photography bloggers and writers, please repeat after me: We do not need a crisis in order to talk about good photography.</p>&mdash; <br />1/250 (@one250) <a href='http://twitter.com/#!/one250/status/306140654822629376' data-datetime='2013-02-25T20:36:34+00:00'>February 25, 2013</a></blockquote>
<p>Looking at photos is going to continue to be more and more difficult. Let’s help each other out and point out what we like and why. Especially the why. It can even be from your own photos.</p>
<p>One of my old posts is about the concept of <a href="http://njwv.wordpress.com/2011/02/26/photography-guide/">being a photography guide</a>. I’d forgotten about it until I was working on this post. It’s a concept I need to revisit. To the items in my post,* I’m adding the concept of just flagging “hey, this is interesting because.”</p>
<p><em>*Pointing out what’s worthwhile in a given body of work and helping people figure out exactly what it is they find appealing.</em></p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://njwv.wordpress.com/category/photography/'>photography</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2425/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2425/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2425&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://njwv.wordpress.com/2013/03/04/looking-at-photos/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/1c88d70c786a5faaac4f1be1cb19d455?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F1.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">njwv</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7069/6890145573_4584357f7a.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">HI-4</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Real Business of Travel Blogging</title>
		<link>http://mattkepnes.wordpress.com/2013/03/03/the-real-business-of-travel-blogging/</link>
		<comments>http://mattkepnes.wordpress.com/2013/03/03/the-real-business-of-travel-blogging/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 16:15:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>nomadicmatt</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blogging]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mattkepnes.wordpress.com/?p=143</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Towards the end of last year, I attended a number of travel blogging conferences and noticed a growing conversation about the professionalization of our little industry. As I listened to people talk, I kept silent. I didn’t want to get caught up in the debate. I hate inside baseball. However, on my recent trip to [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=143&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Towards the end of last year, I attended a number of travel blogging conferences and noticed a growing conversation about the professionalization of our little industry. </p>
<p>As I listened to people talk, I kept silent. I didn’t want to get caught up in the debate. I hate inside baseball. However, on my recent trip to Africa, while dealing with long 10 hour bus rides, I had a lot of time to think &#8212; and think about travel blogging and the state of the industry I did. </p>
<p>With all that time, I’ve decided to write. </p>
<p>And then I wrote some more.</p>
<p>And I hate wasting words so I decided to no longer stay silent but to talk about travel blogging and my opinion on what needs to be done. </p>
<p>Nothing I write here is meant to be taken personally; these are simply my thoughts on the business of blogging. I see too many people who should be successes but aren’t, and too many beginner bloggers being led astray, cutting off any chance of success they might have. </p>
<p>We all start from zero and the questions we should always ask ourselves are why did that person succeed? and how can I copy what works so I can too? </p>
<p>Well, here are my answers to those questions. <em>(Note: Just blog for fun? Don&#8217;t care about making a business out of it? Awesome. Keep doing that. This post isn&#8217;t for you though!)</em></p>
<h3>The Problem(s)</h3>
<p>There are many reasons why so few of us make it beyond our own walls. Compared to other niches, our world is very small with few top bloggers, few rising stars, and few people making lots of money. Travel is a multi-billion dollar industry, and we should have a bigger piece of that pie than we currently do. I think a lot more people should be bubbling to the top and as I look at what impedes our industry and what happens in other fields, I notice a couple of things: </p>
<p>First, travel blogging is inward focused. Too many bloggers write to other travel bloggers, talk to other travel bloggers, and network with other travel bloggers. On a personal level, that&#8217;s awesome. On a professional level, it&#8217;s limiting. Too few of us branch outside our industry. It is a giant circle jerk. There’s too much inside baseball on people’s blogs that only ever appeals to other bloggers. In short, we don’t think big enough. </p>
<p>Secondly, we don’t create businesses. Most of us, myself included, are former travelers who started blogging as a way to extend our travels. Most of us think “Hey, I travel and blog. I can definitely give other people advice on travel. I’m an expert.” And then with visions of being a travel writer in our minds, we join our fellow travel bloggers in&#8230;.taking press trips, selling links, and running sponsored posts &#8212; and then complaining about how hard it is to make money with a travel blog. But how many of us create business plans? Have a marketing strategy? Develop an expertise? Hire people? Contact traditional media? How many of you create products that compliment your expertise?  All businesses have staff, products, and plans. Too many think “If I blog, they will come.” They won’t.  Content may be king, but marketing is the queen &#8212; and, as any good chess player knows, queens are the real power.</p>
<p>Third, there is a huge sense of self-entitlement. I see so many people who say they are “travel writers” and “travel experts” and demand this or that but only have two readers, have never been linked or quoted in a major magazine, and are simply experts at taking press trips. Anyone who has spent five minutes in the Facebook groups can see this. It leads to a huge amount of infighting, name calling, gossiping, and a “what can you do for me?” attitude. It’s worse than high school and it’s a big roadblock to success. </p>
<p>Those three things create a negative feedback loop that keeps too many bloggers down.  As I’ve thought about the conversations I’ve heard over the last few months, I’ve come to realize that unless there is a paradigm shift in the way most bloggers think, few will last the industry contraction that is bound to occur when the novelty of travel blogging wears off and companies start to look closer at ROI and get more selective. It’s happened in other blogging niches and ours will be no exception. What goes up always goes down. </p>
<p>And that’s a shame, because there are so many good travel blogs out there that &#8212; with just a little push &#8212; could become huge and profitable successes. </p>
<h3>The Fix</h3>
<p>Why is it that, out of the thousands of bloggers, so few succeed?  It is true in any industry that a few will rise to the top, but the Internet is a large place and you could have a million followers and still be unknown. To millions, you could be the only travel blog out there. There’s no reason why we all can’t be big fishes in small ponds.  You would think for all his fame Tim Ferriss would be a household name, but ask most people who aren’t Internet junkies and they will have no clue as to who he is, nor will they be able to name his famous books. Yet he has tens of millions of readers and has sold millions of books.   </p>
<p>And the reason why our industry isn’t a smooth pyramid comes down to this one fact: only a tiny amount are actually running a business and developing a strategy. Think of a restaurant. You walk in, you sit down, and you’re handed a menu from which to order. That restaurant has something to offer you. You get food, it gets money for doing something that it loves &#8212; in this case, cooking food. </p>
<p>Now, let’s pretend every travel blogger is their own restaurant.  Ask yourself, what&#8217;s on your menu? </p>
<p>For too many of us, the answer is nothing. </p>
<p>All businesses sell something. Every top blog in every niche sells a “product”.  They have a number of selections from which customers can choose – whether it’s an e-book, a course, speaking engagements, print books, their freelance writing skills, consulting, or affiliate ad sales. Your blog is a store and you need to think of it as such. What can people buy when they come to yours? </p>
<p>Some tips:<br />
<strong>I. Be an expert</strong><br />
Go deep. Go niche. You cannot be a travel expert, just simply an expert in a style of travel. Travel is far too big of a field to be an expert in it all. That would be like someone saying they are a science expert. </p>
<p>I believe a lot of it goes back to the problem that so many of us come out of the traveler tradition that we look for ways to extend our travel and think “travel blogger” sounds cool. I went around the world, I know travel, I can help others. </p>
<p>A trip around the world does not make you an expert on anything related to travel. Yes, you know more than the average person but you are leagues away from being an expert. In the beginning, I thought I was and it took many humbling moments to realize I knew nothing and then it took me years of work and practice to actually become an expert on a type of travel.</p>
<p>What makes you passionate about travel? I love budget travel. I’m cheap, I hate spending money, and sitting around for 10 hours to learn how to find a cheaper flight sounds like a perfect Friday night to me.  I focused on that and absorbed everything I could about budget travel. I read books by other writers. I sought the advice of others. I made the focus of my travels revolve around the question “Where can I find the best deal?”</p>
<p>There is still a lot I don’t know and only a fool thinks he knows it all. I was a fool in the beginning. It wasn’t until I started to think about how to really grow my blog outside travel and was being constantly rejected that first year or so that I realized the problem was that I couldn’t provide the depth of knowledge required of an “expert.”</p>
<p>But expert doesn’t mean guru. It simply means a focus. Your blog should have a focus – a reoccurring theme that binds everything together. That can be anything from budget travel to adventure sports to cruises to simply stories about mishaps on the road. But you need a theme. If your blog is all over the place, you’ll lose readers. </p>
<p><strong>II. Learn from traditional writers</strong><br />
While <a href="http://www.nerdseyeview.com/blog/">Pam Mandel and I</a> don&#8217;t oven see eye to eye, <a href="http://www.nerdseyeview.com/blog/2012/09/28/some-things-about-tbex-europe/">I completely agree with her when she says that writing is important and bloggers should focus more on writing</a>.  It doesn’t get enough publicity in our industry but being able to tell good stories is simply the price of admission. It is the least you can do. After all, no one wants to come back to a blog with awful writing. We should all work to hone our skills; all good writers do. </p>
<p>And this is where blogging self-entitlement hurts us. Bloggers love to think they are the wave of the future and that print writers are passé. They think it’s all about social media, forgetting the fact that anyone can go out and buy 100,000 Twitter followers.  What matters is quality content (there is so much garbage all over the Internet) and by dismissing traditional writers we ignore the valuable lesson they can teach us: that to be a success you must have quality writing and a journalistic quality of depth to your stories.  How often do you see 2,500 word, detailed how-to posts? Or in-depth reporting on issues that quote sources? Or stories that really put you there?  </p>
<p>The best bloggers in any niche do that. They take the best lessons of the old media and combine it with the new &#8212; and are powerhouses because of it. Traditional writers are great at details and form and we can learn a lot from them. </p>
<p>I, for one, am taking two writing courses this year to improve my narrative writings. It’s not something I do a lot on my blog but when I do I want to be able to better express my experiences better. 99.999% of us are not natural writers, yet there is never a real discussion on writing or how to improve it. I’ve heard hardly anyone ever say “I’m signing up for this writing class to improve myself.” </p>
<p>Improve the quality of your writing and your readership will grow. </p>
<h3>The Fix: The Business Continues</h3>
<p>Think of yourself as a restaurant again. When people come to your place, what are you serving them?</p>
<p>Text links, sponsored trips, and copious press trips are not menu items. Doing those things are like saying “Ok, I need money and no one has come into the store yet so I’m going to rent out my store to the mob for a little bit.”  But what happens is the mob never leaves and the customers never come. </p>
<p>I can trace the rise and plateau of most bloggers (because, yes, I actually keep track) to the time they started selling text links. Now, I did them when I was starting out, and I still think that they are good money. Putting ads up on the sidebar labeled as such is not a problem. Putting something at the bottom of your post once in awhile isn’t going to kill you – trust me, your audience does want you to be profitable and succeed.  </p>
<p>But what I see is people becoming addicted to that money and simply doing that more and more because you need money to live and travel. And then I hear “Well, text links are the only way I make money, so I can’t stop.” If that is the case, maybe you shouldn’t be a blogger. Find a new industry. Get a desk job. If you really think there’s no way to make money outside links, you never will. If you just want to pay for your next flight, go nuts with links, but if your goal is to become a professional and earn a living, you are simply shooting yourself in the foot by doing this stuff. </p>
<p>Your audience reads you for you, not because you got some comped nights at a hotel or because they can take “cheap flights to Tenerife.”  Your audience knows those are unnatural and paid-for links and they do not appreciate them. You only have to look at the traffic and subscription rate of blogs that do this heavily and observe their lack of growth to see it doesn’t lead anywhere.  I get e-mails all the time telling me they used to read a lot of blogs but stopped because they became sponsored post, link, and press trip factories. </p>
<p>Your goal is to be the go-to travel expert, right? Someone whose writing people enjoy reading and whose content they trust. Every link on your site tells say to your reader “I trust this website and you should too.&#8221; It’s your recommendation. Readers WILL click on those links and when they see they lead to these junk sites, they are going to stop reading you.  And that is why the websites that use contextual links the most are the ones that never seem to grow. </p>
<p>Moreover, for too many, it seems to be that press trips are the pinnacle of blogging, as if the more press trips you take, the better your blog. But when you become a large blog, you will get more trip offers than you’ll know what to do with. </p>
<p>But let me say something – your readers don’t care about what you do. Sure, they are invested in you because they can see themselves in you, but no one wants to read about your awesome trip that they can never take or see photos of the seven-course, 10-star meal some tourism board gave you while they are stuck in a cubicle. What they want to read is a story that allows them to envision themselves following in your footsteps. Even if they never plan on doing it, they want to at least pretend. </p>
<p>And so posting videos and photos of seven-course meals you received simply because you were being wined and dined isn’t going to fly with your readers – it won’t grow your audience. After all, most of us started as travelers and people read us because they wanted to follow in our footsteps and for at least a blog post, they pictured that they can. </p>
<p>Too often this criticism is taken as a personal insult. It’s not. I’m just saying that we should strive to be better as an industry, that we should try to play long ball, not short ball. I hear a lot of complaints about the lack of money in travel blogging, but when asked what people are doing to grow their income, they don’t have an answer. They don&#8217;t have a plan.  </p>
<p>You need products. You need to have something on your menu.  The sites that do create long term sustainable income. </p>
<p>Chris Guillebeau wrote <a href="http://chrisguillebeau.com/3x5/the-audience-is-listening/">this great article where he said</a>:</p>
<p>“I used to run several little businesses that produced a good income, but they were completely dependent on external factors such as Google rankings or the lack of competition in my space. It was fun while it lasted, but when efficiency entered the marketplace, I had to move on.</p>
<p>Looking back, I can now see that I didn’t really have a business; I was merely taking advantage of an opportunity.”</p>
<p>He’s right. If you are not selling anything, you are simply taking advantage of a Google loophole and when that loophole closes, you are going to be left with nothing. This year I’ve completely left text links behind. I used to have some on sites I ran besides my main site but I’ve sold them to some friends. In doing so, I lost about $30,000 USD in potential revenue. That’s a lot of money &#8212; but it forced me to monetize my site in different ways and think of products and things I could offer that can be of value to my readers as well as make money.  And now, I am poised to recoup that income &#8212; and more &#8212; while freeing up tons of time to focus on stuff that actually matters.</p>
<h3>The Fix, part 3: Why are you so ugly? </h3>
<p>I want to make two final points.  </p>
<p>First, if you look at big blogs in any field, they all look outward. They are all multi-media publishing houses. They are more than their blog and they network with bloggers of all sorts in all fields.  If you want to be a success, you need to think about what will grow your business by leaps and bounds. </p>
<p>Travel overlaps with so many other niches. Why don’t the solo female travelers of the world guest blog on women’s websites? You have an empowering story… pitch it! Why aren’t the older travelers writing for boomer websites and magazines? Those who volunteer around the world could work with student and other organizations! If video is your thing, link up with other video bloggers! </p>
<p>The best growth will come from outside travel blogging.  And once you do that, everything snowballs. When people walk by a busy restaurant, they stop and peek in. They think to themselves, “This place must be good if it is full.” People will think about your blog the same way. </p>
<p>Secondly, back to our restaurant analogy, there is not enough focus on design. No one wants to eat in an ugly-looking restaurant. Design is costly, but you have seven seconds to appeal to someone before they move on to the next website. If people don’t like how you look, they aren’t even going to give your content a chance. Invest in your design, otherwise you are just another blog. </p>
<p>Travel bloggers have been great to me, and I count many of them as friends. I love watching people grow and become better and helping them when and where I can. They do the same for me. But over the last few months, I’ve watched people tread water and too many new bloggers become disenchanted about blogging when they shouldn’t be. </p>
<p>My blog is not perfect. I have a lot to learn, and I am constantly getting feedback from friends, readers, and experts. A few years ago, I had drinks with Ramit Sethi, author of <a href="http://www.iwillteachyoutoberich.com/home/">I Will Teach You to Be Rich</a>. He’s one of the best bloggers I know with an audience of 160,000 subscribers. He’s a genius. We were having drinks and, since at the time his website was still focused on saving money, I asked if he wanted to help promote an e-book I was working on. He peppered me with questions to which I had no answers. Then he spent a good 45 minutes ripping me and everything I did apart. (And he’s not very tactful when he does this, either). But I took that advice and made my site better. I never took it personally. He was trying to help.  I took his advice, the advice of others, and I copied their best practices &#8212; and I used it all to grow my site. Now when we talk, I take great joy when he says &#8220;I like that idea, Matt!&#8221;</p>
<p>We all start from zero. We all have to work for it. In the beginning, we all start from the same line. There is plenty of room for us all, but if you don’t think strategically, long-term, and about the bigger picture, you will always be treading water and complaining about how hard blogging is.</p>
<p>Make this year the year you stop treading water and become an Olympic swimmer. Let&#8217;s make this the year we all do.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/143/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/143/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=143&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://mattkepnes.wordpress.com/2013/03/03/the-real-business-of-travel-blogging/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>40</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/0883b968af7d8301b235987d16654839?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F0.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">nomadicmatt</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Peace : Militarization</title>
		<link>http://gukira.wordpress.com/2013/03/04/peacemilitarization/</link>
		<comments>http://gukira.wordpress.com/2013/03/04/peacemilitarization/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2013 14:58:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>keguro</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Feeling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kenya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://gukira.wordpress.com/?p=2435</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[If one browses #kenyadecides on twitter, one soon comes across photographs of military personnel driving fancy looking vehicles across Kenya, or at least Nairobi, accompanied by approving comments from the twitterati. Television coverage has emphasized, repeatedly, that over 90,000 military people have been “deployed” across the country to guarantee “peace.” Were we living in a [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2435&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If one browses #kenyadecides on twitter, one soon comes across photographs of military personnel driving fancy looking vehicles across Kenya, or at least Nairobi, accompanied by approving comments from the twitterati. Television coverage has emphasized, repeatedly, that over 90,000 military people have been “deployed” across the country to guarantee “peace.” Were we living in a different time, a less militarized time, a time when militarization was not considered part of everyday life, these images of military personnel deployed across the country might traffic under a different name: military coup, state repression, dictatorship.</p>
<p>Now, we call it “peace,” “security,” “necessary.”</p>
<p>Jomo Kenyatta’s short story, “Gentlemen of the Jungle,” ends with a man trapping repressive animals inside a hut, setting the hut on fire, watching them die, and then uttering, “Peace is costly, but it’s worth the expense.” Now, I can’t read this story without thinking of the men, women, and children set ablaze in a church in Kiambaa in 2008 during the post-election violence. I have to think about this killing act and to ask about the cost of “peace.”</p>
<p>Kenyans have been praised for their “order” and “restraint” and control during this election, but how could it be otherwise with such a heavy military presence? How could it be otherwise when the much-proclaimed “peace” is enabled by militarization? The militarization of everyday life tells us, should tell us, that this is not a peaceful election. This is an election conducted under conditions of ongoing war. That we cannot recognize this, that we dare not recognize this, should surely give us pause.</p>
<p>How have we so normalized militarization that we consider it essential to everyday life?</p>
<p>Here is what I wrote in 2011, when I was in Nairobi:</p>
<blockquote><p>I remain interested in how the fact of being at war lodges itself in the quotidian: in the forms of freedom and practices of bodily integrity we have given up so readily and in the forms of surveillance that we now practice on each other.</p>
<p>Indeed, for all our declarations of “never again” after the PEV, we continue to inhabit its logic and practices of violence.</p></blockquote>
<p>I asked,</p>
<blockquote><p>What might it mean to share the banality of war as the basis for sociality?</p></blockquote>
<p>And I noted,</p>
<blockquote><p>I blunder into cobweb filaments, the sticky demands of then folded into emerging cavities of now. Time looms. Other intimacies suffuse once-familiar spaces.</p></blockquote>
<p>Now, NTV is screening footage of a slightly rowdy voting crowd, understandable given long lines. I hear guns going off to “maintain order.” The guns going off elicit no comment. Because they are to maintain order.</p>
<p>How is the militarization of everyday life not a form of quotidian violence?</p>
<p>Can we distinguish between the militarization “required” to maintain peace during elections and that required to “maintain peace” in non-election years?</p>
<p>In 2011, I noticed the militarization of everyday life because of the war with Somalia—presumably, the war against Al-Shabaab. Because of my time  in the U.S., because I had witnessed militarization become banal under ongoing war regimes, I worried that the same thing would happen in Kenya. I worried that militarization would be considered necessary. Now, it has been named as the condition of peace. Indeed, it has been named as “peace.”</p>
<p>There is NO commentary on any Kenyan site I have seen that discusses the militarization of this election. I have been corrected on twitter that Kenya has deployed “security,” not “military,” personnel. I’m honestly not smart enough to tell the difference. I heard gunshots on an NTV report. I have seen men in uniform controlling voters. I have seen a nation or at least a national media celebrate the militarization of the election. It would be a mistake to believe that the militarization of peace can be restricted to this election period. And the consequences of that understanding for Kenya should give us pause.</p>
<p>They frighten me.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2435/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2435/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2435&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://gukira.wordpress.com/2013/03/04/peacemilitarization/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f0a9bc9e6660a8a5cadfee32eb5792fa?s=96&#38;d=wavatar&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">keguro</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Personal Myth</title>
		<link>http://peopletriggers.wordpress.com/2013/01/31/the-personal-myth/</link>
		<comments>http://peopletriggers.wordpress.com/2013/01/31/the-personal-myth/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 21:05:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>peopletriggers</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Social Psychology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[behavior]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Benedict Carey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[linkedin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mark Twain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal myth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[psychology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sam Keen]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://peopletriggers.wordpress.com/?p=1084</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;It ain’t so much the things we don’t know that get us into trouble, it’s the things we do know that just ain’t so.&#8221; &#8211;Mark Twain Some (very reputable) psychologists are absolutely convinced that DNA is destiny. Other (very reputable) psychologists are convinced that your personality is shaped by what happens to you as an [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1084&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://peopletriggers.wordpress.com/2013/01/31/the-personal-myth/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>28</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/0e9c620c65633be680b25fc160bc8786?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">peopletriggers</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://www.addictinginfo.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/myths.gif" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Myths</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://www.starsandseas.com/SAS_Mythology/yellowdragon.JPG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Myths</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://unpredictableblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/memories.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Sabbatical from the Twitters</title>
		<link>http://scatteredsmotheredandcovered.wordpress.com/2013/03/01/a-sabbatical-from-the-twitters/</link>
		<comments>http://scatteredsmotheredandcovered.wordpress.com/2013/03/01/a-sabbatical-from-the-twitters/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 21:12:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>The Mom</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shorts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook drools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mute button]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media abstinence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social-media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech Talk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter rules]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[twitter sabbatical]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[twitter timeout]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitters]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://scatteredsmotheredandcovered.wordpress.com/?p=3166</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;m on a Twitter sabbatical. It&#8217;s not my first. But it&#8217;s the first one I haven&#8217;t blogged through. Usually I&#8217;m over at TechFanatix  complaining about it the entire time. Crying. Languishing. Not this time though. I&#8217;m not taking a Twitter time-out because I have nothing to say. I always have something to say. Whether you want [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3166&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://scatteredsmotheredandcovered.wordpress.com/2013/03/01/a-sabbatical-from-the-twitters/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>28</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://scatteredsmotheredandcovered.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/pic12.png?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://scatteredsmotheredandcovered.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/pic12.png?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">pic1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/424dc8e90c207d3aaf64012f88f5590a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">amandalfultz</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://scatteredsmotheredandcovered.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/pic11.png?w=461" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">pic1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://scatteredsmotheredandcovered.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/pic12.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">pic1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://scatteredsmotheredandcovered.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/pic1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">pic1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://scatteredsmotheredandcovered.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/pic11.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">pic1</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is Prayer Surrender?</title>
		<link>http://christianthought.hbu.edu/2013/02/28/is-prayer-surrender/</link>
		<comments>http://christianthought.hbu.edu/2013/02/28/is-prayer-surrender/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 03:06:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Charles Halton</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Theology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Benedict]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prayer]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://christianthought.hbu.edu/?p=906</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Paolo Flores d’Arcais wrote a breathtaking blog post for the New York Review of Books. It’s one of the most trenchant attempts to interpret Benedict XVI’s resignation that I’ve read. He explores the theological implications of a Spirit-inspired Vicar of Christ on Earth saying that he is too old to continue in his divinely appointed [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=906&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://hbuchristianthought.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/filepapa_benedetto.jpeg"><img class="size-full wp-image-915 alignleft" alt="Benedict XVI" src="http://hbuchristianthought.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/filepapa_benedetto.jpeg?w=200&#038;h=300" width="200" height="300" /></a>Paolo Flores d’Arcais wrote a breathtaking <a href="http://www.nybooks.com/blogs/nyrblog/2013/feb/28/papal-surrender/">blog post</a> for the <i>New York Review of Books</i>. It’s one of the most trenchant attempts to interpret Benedict XVI’s resignation that I’ve read. He explores the theological implications of a Spirit-inspired Vicar of Christ on Earth saying that he is too old to continue in his divinely appointed task. Is the Holy Spirit not able to strengthen him and the church during a time of mortal weakness?</p>
<p>This is a weighty question, to be sure. But what intrigued me even more is d’Arcais’s speculation that in the face of raging power struggles that are bringing the Church to her knees, Benedict decided to surrender. To scamper off to Castel Gandolfo and after that to a former convent. Too old and feeble to fight, the now Pope Emeritus chose to pray.</p>
<p>But should we equate prayer with surrender? The author of Ephesians writes:</p>
<blockquote><p>We’re not waging war against enemies of flesh and blood alone. No, this fight is against tyrants, against authorities, against <i>supernatural</i> powers <i>and demon princes that slither</i> in the darkness of this world, and against wicked <i>spiritual armies</i> that lurk about in heavenly places (6:12, The Voice).</p></blockquote>
<p>Possibly, Benedict had this passage in mind when he received the report he commissioned in the wake of the “<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vatileaks_scandal">Vatileaks scandal</a>.” Scheming priests, money laundering bankers, and blackmailing bishops – they are just bit players in a much bigger game. Their sins would take some doing to unravel but the real challenge would be addressing the evil that propels them. That’s something that no pope, no matter how physically fit, is able to do on his own.</p>
<p>At this point – emotionally dead, physically frail, and spiritually tired – perhaps Benedict thought of Christ at Gethsemane. After his closest friends failed him and a trusted advisor betrayed him, Jesus faced his own death. The Pope may have seen similarities between his circumstances and those of his Lord. Intriguingly, Christ responded to all this by retreating in prayer.</p>
<p>If we keep reading we find that after this night of passionate petition Jesus went to his death and, as the Gospels confess, death was defeated in resurrection. Jesus didn’t surrender to pray, he prayed to continue the fight. But it was a fight that was won through self-sacrifice and persistent – defiant, even – prayer.</p>
<p>To many, Benedict’s decision seems like a foolhardy act of cowardice at best and a negligent abdication of his religious duty at worst. He gave up at a time when the church needed him the most. Yet, it might be that, in Benedict’s mind, he was taking the fight to a whole other level.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/906/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/906/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=906&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://christianthought.hbu.edu/2013/02/28/is-prayer-surrender/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>35</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/d0208e9e3576afaa9b5f1f4b740d3426?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F1.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">akismet-d0208e9e3576afaa9b5f1f4b740d3426</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hbuchristianthought.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/filepapa_benedetto.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Benedict XVI</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
