<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2013 20:02:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>The Godfather: Retro Reviews</title>
		<link>http://imthemadman.wordpress.com/2013/01/30/the-godfather-retro-reviews/</link>
		<comments>http://imthemadman.wordpress.com/2013/01/30/the-godfather-retro-reviews/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2013 16:55:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>imthemadman</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Film Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[On a More Serious Note]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews and Critiques]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Serious Film Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Funny]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Serious]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[al pacino]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[francis ford coppola]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gangsters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mario puzo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marlon brando]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the godfather]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://imthemadman.wordpress.com/?p=542</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I truly can’t do The Godfather justice in a mere thousand words.  And, unfortunately, many have already written volumes analyzing and exploring this divine document.  But as someone extremely fussy and picky about film quality, and someone attempting to better educate themselves about the history of cinema, I feel I’m doing an injustice not to [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=542&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://imthemadman.wordpress.com/2013/01/30/the-godfather-retro-reviews/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/489b7a68344224e744966e8d9baaae85?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=X" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">imthemadman</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://g-ecx.images-amazon.com/images/G/01/DVD/Paramount/detailpages/TheGodfather/GdfthrColl_Still_H2_L.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">the godfather al pacino crime sitting in chair </media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://i2.listal.com/image/3508184/600full-the-godfather-screenshot.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">the godfather marlon brando al pacino old retired micheal don corleone</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mayor Ed Koch</title>
		<link>http://anafternoonwith.com/2013/02/01/mayor-ed-koch/</link>
		<comments>http://anafternoonwith.com/2013/02/01/mayor-ed-koch/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 17:42:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>AnAfternoonWith...</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[ALL FEATURES]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BRONX]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BROOKLYN]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ICONS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[INTERIOR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MANHATTAN]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[apartment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[deceased mayors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ed koch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ed koch home]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ed koch phone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[edward koch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[headphones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interior]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[koch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leather seating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Manhattan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mayor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mayor ed koch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mayor's homes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mayor's life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nyc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nyc apartments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nyc homes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nyc mayor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photograph]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pictures of ed koch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[portrait]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[story]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://anafternoonwith.com/?p=3848</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Growing up in New York City, the honorable Mayor Edward Irving Koch was a big part of my life. This is an afternoon I spent with him for House &#38; Garden back in the 90&#8242;s. I was just with him three weeks ago, and he was as funny and clever as ever. I&#8217;m sorry to [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3848&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://anafternoonwith.com/2013/02/01/mayor-ed-koch/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/8d548cd0990b438b3599fb7789a3a487?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F2.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">michaelmundy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://michaelmundy.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/mayor-ed-koch_p1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mayor Ed Koch photographed in his home in Manhattan, New York. Copyright Michael Mundy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://michaelmundy.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/mayor-ed-koch_p2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mayor Ed Koch&#039;s Living Room. Copyright Michael Mundy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://michaelmundy.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/mayor-ed-koch_p3.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mayor Ed Koch&#039;s Apartment. Copyright Michael Mundy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://michaelmundy.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/mayor-ed-koch_p5.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mayor Ed Koch&#039;s Dining Room. Copyright Michael Mundy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://michaelmundy.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/mayor-ed-koch_p4.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mayor Ed Koch&#039;s Bedroom. Copyright Michael Mundy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://michaelmundy.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/mayor-ed-koch_p6.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mayor Ed Koch Grilling Outside NYC. Copyright Michael Mundy</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Evidence from Evolution and Biology</title>
		<link>http://quantumveil.wordpress.com/2013/01/31/the-evidence-from-evolution-and-biology-part-1/</link>
		<comments>http://quantumveil.wordpress.com/2013/01/31/the-evidence-from-evolution-and-biology-part-1/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 14:03:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dennis Rice</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Biology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Metaphysics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Physics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quantum Physics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://quantumveil.wordpress.com/?p=87</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[My previous posts have focused on the evidence for a rational agent inherent in the laws of physics.  There has been an implicit assumption that the laws of physics are rigorously deterministic.  But clearly life is not deterministic, so it was necessary for me to point to some possible feature of the laws of physics [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=87&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>My previous posts have focused on the evidence for a rational agent inherent in the laws of physics.  There has been an implicit assumption that the laws of physics are rigorously deterministic.  But clearly life is not deterministic, so it was necessary for me to point to some possible feature of the laws of physics that allowed for the wild variation and unpredictability of life.  I will summarize my thought process as follows:</p>
<ol>
<li>The universe is ordered by deterministic laws and forces such as the force of gravity and electromagnetism.  There are also non-deterministic laws such as quantum theory.  One of the laws that combine both features is the law of increasing entropy.  Entropy always increases throughout the universe, but it is allowed to decrease locally.  Since quantum theory ultimately controls all interactions in the universe, all forces are non-deterministic at the quantum level.  (The only possible exception is gravitation which has not yet been unified with quantum theory.)</li>
<li>The deterministic laws (electromagnetism, etc.), by themselves, cannot account for life and consciousness.  There must be another factor in the fundamental laws of physics that allows living organism to lower entropy.  The process of lowering entropy is essential to life because it concentrates energy for future use and organizes the genome for transmission to future generations.</li>
<li>That factor in the laws of physics is the collapse of the wave function in quantum physics, also called decoherence.  Decoherence is absolutely necessary for any measurable energy transfer.  In decoherence, the universe actually chooses an outcome for every transfer of energy.  This choosing, or decisionality, on the part of the universe is what I have called rational agency and it is responsible for the forward direction of time.</li>
<li>This decisionality on the part of the universe is always mixed up with randomness because we are prohibited from knowing precisely all the states of matter, particularly the states of entanglement between particles.  This is a consequence of a kind of cosmic censorship hypothesis.  The Heisenberg uncertainty principle is one such limitation on our knowledge.</li>
<li>There can be no ordering principle or lowering of entropy based on true randomness.  True randomness, by definition, is maximum entropy.  In all of physics the only candidate for non-random yet non-deterministic action is decoherence.</li>
<li>Therefore, this choice by the universe is directed choice.  It is a rational choosing based on the laws of physics and contains within it the possibility of lowering entropy.  It is the physical undergirding of all life and consciousness.  It is the physical action responsible for the forward direction of time.</li>
</ol>
<p>Essentially, I think that the laws of physics favor life or are conducive to life.  In general, nature prefers to disperse energy; therefore there must be physical explanations for how energy gets concentrated.  Just as there is an explanation for how nature concentrates energy for lightning, there must also be an explanation for how living organisms concentrate energy and lower entropy.   These six steps summarize my explanation.  In this series on evolution and biology, I will lay out the case for the laws of physics favoring life as opposed to the case for life adapting to the laws of physics.  Both dynamics occur, but only laws conducive to life can create life from inanimate matter.</p>
<p>I don’t consider this logic highly dependent on particular experimental results.  Scientific theories are always provisional; they can be superseded by better theories or more accurate results.  My reasoning is broadly based on the general properties of physical laws.  A portion of the laws are rigorously deterministic and use mathematics to make predictions about future events.  A portion of the laws of physics deals with the presence of uncertainty in the universe.  I fully expect the laws of physics to be revised and improved, but I don’t expect that these general characteristics will be much altered.  If string theory is proved true, that would not change my basic logic, but my perspective might need to accommodate rational agency operating in a multiverse scenario.   String Theory, for all its promise, does not yet make any testable predictions.</p>
<p>Along with the laws of physics, I view the theory of evolution as a valid scientific theory.  It is a theory based on the idea that all living organisms adapt to their specific environment and pass along adaptive traits through procreation.  Darwin’s concept of “natural selection” was devised in contradistinction to “artificial selection,” whereby human breeders selected the best mates in order to raise generations of specifically adapted animals.</p>
<p>Biology is a complex science.  For someone like me, who has spent a major part of his life focused on math and the physical sciences, the main shock of encountering biology is the sheer astronomical diversity of life.  Last year, I took one of the online courses offered from UC Berkeley.  It was the basic undergraduate course for biology majors and it was something I needed because my previous biology class must have been in high school.  It was just as well that I didn’t have very much previous instruction because so much has changed between then and now.  The sheer volume of information is astounding.  I found myself wondering how on earth does anyone organize this much data.  In fact, it took three teachers to cover the material.  One instructor had a background in molecular biology; one was a specialist in genetics and one was from a medical background.  I had the distinct feeling that complete mastery was beyond the capability of any one individual.  But, I am still learning and I do have some observations based on my perspective from the physical sciences.</p>
<p>One observation concerns the principle of emergence.  Emergence is the concept that complex living organisms are able to exhibit new properties and traits by virtue of their complexity and organization.  The example from the textbook for the UC Berkeley class is one that interests me:  “For example, although photosynthesis occurs in an intact chloroplast, it will not take place in a disorganized test-tube mixture of chlorophyll and other chloroplast molecules.  Photosynthesis requires a specific organization of these molecules in the chloroplast.”  The text is saying that photosynthesis is an emergent phenomenon.  That is fine.  That helps organize knowledge, but for someone who wants to know how things work, there is a further question:  How is it that the particular organization contributes to function?  What are the properties of the constituent parts that enable the composite function to emerge?  Too often, emergence is used simply as label for a new function that can’t be explained any further.  When that happens, it becomes a kind of false knowledge: a category without explanatory power.</p>
<p>To take another example, water is composed of two room-temperature gases: hydrogen and oxygen.  I suppose you could say the emergent property of water is its liquidity.  But, with water, one can trace its properties to the molecular properties of hydrogen and oxygen and the strong bond between them as well as the weak bond between water molecules.  These particular molecular properties can also be used to explain surface tension, freezing and boiling.  My expectation is that biology will someday be explained in terms of molecular dynamics.  That day is a long way into the future.</p>
<p>Biological scientists are answering these kinds of questions and it is painstaking work.  It is slow and tedious work to demonstrate how biological molecules work, but I suppose, that is the part of biology that mainly interests me.  I have two main areas of interest in the biological sciences.  One is photosynthesis because of its use of quantum coherence for efficient transmission of sunlight energy to the “reaction center” where chemical food production begins.  The other is the biological molecule tubulin.</p>
<p>Tubulin is a protein molecule that assembles into microtubules.  Microtubules are long, narrow, hollow tubes that play an amazing variety of roles in living cells.  There is a natural tendency for microtubules to assemble themselves because of the positive and negative polarity on the tubulin molecule.  Once assembled, microtubules play key roles in biological cell functions.  They play an essential role during mitosis, cell division, by grabbing hold of the chromosomes and causing the genome to precisely separate toward opposite ends of the cell.  Microtubules are part of the cell’s cytoskeleton; they give shape and form to the cell.  In plants, microtubules guide the alignment of cellulose and direct plant growth at the cellular level.</p>
<p>Microtubules form the infrastructure that transports molecules from outside the cell to the inside and <i>vice versa</i>.  Motor proteins “walk” vesicles containing molecules back and forth along microtubules to their destination.  For example, pancreas cells that make insulin transport the insulin from inside the cell to the outside by this method.   In addition, microtubules are used for cell interaction with its environment.  They form some types of flagella and cilia for locomotion of the cell or movement of particles in the cell’s environment.  For example, the human sperm cell is propelled by action of a flagella made up of microtubules.</p>
<p>In short, microtubules are a very versatile cellular component.  Furthermore, they are an essential part of nerve cells.  Tubulin, the protein that forms microtubules, has a very high density in brain tissue.  That has led some researchers to project a key role in brain activity and consciousness for microtubules.  Microtubules are long, hollow, round tubes that might be ideal for quantum coherence.  There has been some research along these lines.</p>
<p>Tubulin is the protein building block of microtubules and it or similar proteins are probably very ancient, perhaps going back to the beginning of life.  One source specified that all cells had such proteins, except blue-green algae also known as cyanobacteria.  However, cyanobacteria have a tubulin-like molecule (a homologue) called “Ftsz.”  An interesting connection between my two main interests is that the cyanobacteria use photosynthesis for energy harvesting from sunlight.  It is the light harvesting complex from cyanobacteria that are used in the experiments testing quantum coherence.</p>
<p>Cyanobacteria are among the oldest life forms on Earth, perhaps as old as 3.5 billion years.  It would be a very interesting development if microtubules or microtubule-like structures go back to the beginning of life and if it can be demonstrated that quantum coherence played a key role in efficient energy transmission in these structures.  Those are two very big “ifs” and most researchers are very cautious about any evidence pointing towards quantum coherence in biological molecules.  But I remember some fairly incautious statements about the beginning of life from many years ago.</p>
<p>I think it was probably in high school chemistry class that the teacher, one day, covered the Miller-Urey experiment.  This experiment was conducted in 1952 and involved sending a spark of electricity (to simulate lightning) through a mix of chemicals assumed to represent Earth’s primitive atmosphere.  The result was a mixture of amino acids and sugars, both essential building block of life.  Stanley Miller and Harold Urey had demonstrated that organic compounds necessary for life could be easily formed from reasonable atmospheric compounds, such as water, methane, ammonia and hydrogen.  Not only that, but the teacher thought that we would soon be able to synthesize life in the test tube.  Well, that was over 50 years ago and the synthesis of life seems as elusive as ever.  Science doesn’t yet know what makes biochemicals spring to life.</p>
<p>The mystery of the beginning of life notwithstanding, the theory evolution brought incredible organizing power to the huge diversity of biology.  Darwin’s “natural selection” brought explanatory power to the huge diversity of species on Earth.  In the mid-twentieth century, the discovery of DNA and the genetic code brought into the evolutionary system a mechanism for adaptation.  This has led to what has been called the “central dogma” of molecular biology:  DNA makes RNA which makes proteins.  DNA contains coded information that is used to create a coded sequence of RNA which is used to create a sequence of amino acids which make up proteins.   The next step, which isn’t explicitly stated and is poorly understood, is that proteins must fold into a specific three dimensional form in order to be useful.   What is startling to me, coming from a computer programming background, is that the coded sequence of DNA contains just four characters representing four small molecules: A (adenine), C (cytosine), G (guanine) and T (thymine).</p>
<p>These four codes are interpreted in groups of three which gives 64 possible “words” for amino acids in the genetic code (4 X 4 X 4).  Of the 64 possible combinations of DNA code only 20 are actually needed, because there are only 20 amino acids that are needed to make all the known proteins.  Most of the 64 DNA sequences specify the same amino acid as another sequence, so there is built-in redundancy.  Only Tryptophan and Methionine rely on a single coded sequence; all the others have at least two sets of DNA codes and some (Serine, Leucine and Arginine) have six.  It seems possible to me that different evolutionary branches developed a reliance on different DNA sequences for the amino acids.  For someone with a data processing background, the DNA codes are reminiscent of a computer system that has been copied and modified to meet different objectives – even to the extent that duplicate codes are mainly sequential (e.g., Leucine: TTA, TTG, CTT, CTC, CTA, CTG).  From a “systems design” perspective it would seem that at one time there was provision for expansion with 64 codes for all 20 amino acids, but after evolutionary modifications all 64 codes are now in use.  I suppose that if there developed a need for a 21st amino acid, one of the existing redundant codes would be used.  The whole process is very complex, but the same basic DNA, RNA and amino acids are found in all life forms on Earth.  This amazing discovery of the genetic code is universal to life as we know it.  (There are some exceptions.  The <i>Paramecium</i> uses the “stop” codons, UAG and UAA, to code for Glutamate.)</p>
<p>“Natural selection” coupled with the genetic code has given enormous explanatory power to evolutionary biology.  But like all theories, it is a conceptual model of the physical processes that occur.  There remain many questions such as how did life begin.  And then there’s the question asked by Stephen Hawking, “What is it that breathes fire into the equations and makes a universe for them to govern?”  What is it that actually makes the world act in a way that is consistent with the conceptual model?  Readers of my previous posts will suspect that my answer is similar to what I’ve written before: there is a decisional power at work in the universe that breathes life into biological molecules.  It is this decisionality that insures that time flows forward and therefore gives evolution direction.</p>
<p>Some of the evidence for my answer resides in the evidence for directionality in evolution.  But, first of all, the evolutionary model is a rational model.  Even more amazing is that the implementation of the genetic code is an abstract, rational system!  Who would have thought that nature would have arrived at the very rational system of using a three character code to specify a sequence based on 20 amino acids that comprise the proteins for all life?   Let me be direct: The genetic code <i>is</i> information.  The central dogma of molecular biology <i>is</i> an information processing system.  The end results are proteins and decisional governance of the cell. This is exactly the type of system one might expect from a rational agent acting through nature.</p>
<p>As to directionality, the immediate form of the evidence is in the form of the adaptability of evolutionary change.  Evolutionary change produces living organisms that get better at adapting to their environment.  Not only are more advanced organisms better adapted, but they are better at adapting!  For higher life forms like mammals and particularly humans, this implies a higher consciousness.  Therefore, the longer range implication of evolution is higher consciousness.  I think this trend is evident from the archeological and historical record.  For almost 4 billion years, life has survived under the constant threat of a cosmic catastrophe such as the one that brought an end to the dinosaurs.  Today, we are beginning to track the asteroids and comets that have the potential to cause another life-ending cataclysm.  That would not be possible without some sort of advanced consciousness.  In a strange sort of self-reflection, adaptation has become adaptability for which is needed a higher consciousness.  This implies a robust moral development as well, but that is beyond what I can cover in these posts on science and reason.</p>
<p>But a rational agent is not the only explanation.  The alternative view is that evolution is the byproduct of random mutation.  First of all, I don’t think randomness is a good scientific answer.  Science succeeds when it finds and explains rational patterns.  To say that a process is random is to admit defeat from a scientific point of view.  The second thing I would say is that when someone refers to random mutation, it is unclear what type of randomness they are referring to: lack of knowledge randomness or the genuine non-determinism of quantum physics.  The common view of evolution is that it requires generations of offspring in order for nature to select the best attributes and pass those on to future generations.  Is evolution inherently random because some individuals show up at the wrong place at the wrong time or, alternatively, at the right place at the right time?  Is it random because a cosmic ray has altered the genome?  Is it random because we can’t predict how our children will turn out?  The most likely reason mutation might be random is because of a transcription or copying error.  But modern cells have evolved elaborate safeguards against such copying errors.</p>
<p>It turns out that when evolutionists speak of “random mutation,” they mean something specific.  My biology textbook (on Kindle!) only uses the phrase once in over 1000 pages of small font text, and that one occurrence refers to copies of genes that have lost functionality (i.e. the gene has been degraded) over time.  The textbook does not refer to new functionality as “random mutation,” but does use the phrase, “accidents during meiosis” (cell division in reproductive cells).  This phrase, too, has a specific meaning that might not be expected by normal English interpretation.  In general, the textbook prefers to state evidence positively, in terms of what we know rather than in terms of what we don’t know.  As to genetic mutation, it refers to various mechanisms for altering the genome, such as transposition of small portions of the DNA from one location to another.</p>
<p>One internet site was particularly helpful in tracking down the origin of the phrase “random mutation.”  This site was associated with UC Museum of Paleontology (at Berkeley).  The website is a teaching guide for evolution named “Evolution 101.”  This source was very explicit:</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><b>“</b><strong>Mutations are random.</strong><br />
Mutations can be beneficial, neutral, or harmful for the organism, but mutations do not “try” to supply what the organism “needs.” In this respect, mutations are random—whether a particular mutation happens or not is unrelated to how useful that mutation would be.”</p>
<p>Behind this brief description is a debate that began with Darwin.  Prior to Darwin, there was a French biologist named Jean-Baptiste Lamarck who held the view that (1) Individuals acquire traits that they need and lose traits that they don’t need and (2) Individuals inherit the traits of their ancestors.  He gave as examples the Giraffe whose neck was assumed to have stretched in order to reach higher leaves in trees and blacksmiths whose strong arms appeared to have been inherited by their sons.  But these ideas have been debunked.</p>
<p>When Darwin published Origin of Species in 1859, he gave some credibility to Lamarck’s view, but later evolutionists elevated Lamarck’s idea to a major theme of evolution.  By the mid-twentieth century, biologists had become adept at doing experiments with bacteria.  In 1943, two biologists, Max Delbrück and Salvador Luria, wanted to test Lamarck’s hypothesis for bacteria, which were thought to be the more likely organism to use Lamarckian adaptation.  The Luria-Delbrück experiment tested whether bacteria exposed to a lethal virus would develop any adaptive mutation and whether that mutation would be acquired prior to exposure or not.  Their experiment showed conclusively that some bacteria had acquired an adaptive mutation prior to exposure, as did subsequent experiments by others, including Esther and Joshua Lederberg who are referenced on the “Evolution 101” website.</p>
<p>So, based on experiments, what evolutionists mean when they say that mutations are random is that some adaptive mutations occur before any exposure to infectious agents in a test.  The mutations do not occur because of exposure.  Now this is a somewhat contentious finding because it defies the rather commonsense view that mutations happen for a reason, most likely that reason is related to some inoculation or exposure to an agent.  In other words, either the finding appears to violate causality or the explanation is an admission of ignorance about the cause of adaptation.</p>
<p>I take the view that the finding is an admission of ignorance.  We really don’t know what might have caused an adaptive mutation to occur before exposure.  The real scientific question is what causes the mutation and biologists prefer to focus on what we can discover.  One such biologist is James A. Shapiro, professor of microbiology at the University of Chicago.  He characterizes the association of “random mutation” with the Luria-Delbruck experiment as follows:</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">One has to be careful with the word &#8220;proof&#8221; in science. I always said that conventional evolutionists were hanging a very heavy coat on a very thin peg in the way they cited Luria and Delbrück. The peg broke in the first decade of this century.</p>
<p>Professor Shapiro goes on to write about mechanisms that bacteria have for “remembering” previous exposure to infectious agents.  Those mechanisms include modification of the bacteria DNA.  He states that Delbrück and Luria would have discovered this if they had not used a virus that was invariably lethal and if they had the tools for DNA analysis.  The announcement of the DNA structure would take place in 1953, ten years after the Luria-Delbrück experiment, and the tools for analysis are still being developed.  It should not be too big a surprise that bacteria have elaborate mechanisms for DNA sharing and modification. The human immune response to invasive agents also includes the recording of information in the DNA of certain white blood cells (lymphocytes).   You can read Shapiro’s entire article here: <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/james-a-shapiro/epigenetics-ii-cellular-m_b_1668820.html">http://www.huffingtonpost.com/james-a-shapiro/epigenetics-ii-cellular-m_b_1668820.html</a>.</p>
<p>It is no longer fashionable to speak of Lamarckian inheritance, but the field of epigenetics is devoted to adaptation by means other than DNA modification.  My own view is that the amount of debate and discussion on the issue of “soft” inheritance points to a conclusion that this is unsettled science.  Microbiologists today have many more tools and techniques for answering questions about causes for adaptive inheritance then they did sixty years ago and I suspect that they would prefer to look at changes to the DNA and other molecules rather than make statistical inferences as Luria and Delbrück did.  Current research of the type that James Shapiro is doing is demonstrating specific causes for adaptation.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/87/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/87/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=87&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://quantumveil.wordpress.com/2013/01/31/the-evidence-from-evolution-and-biology-part-1/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/36d172fb014922b16b7c097e00fcdf44?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">djrfree</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>It\&#8217;s Okay, You Aren\&#8217;t Broken.\&#8221;</title>
		<link>http://shaunanagins.com/2013/01/30/sex-lies-and-story-time-its-okay-you-arent-broken/</link>
		<comments>http://shaunanagins.com/2013/01/30/sex-lies-and-story-time-its-okay-you-arent-broken/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2013 18:22:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>shaunanagins</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Lifestyle & Brainwaves]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants & Raves]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[feminism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[liberation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sex]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sexuality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thoughts]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://shaunanagins.com/?p=1202</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I have wanted to write about this for a long time.  I have so much to say about it. The problem is that I don’t have any stories about it&#8211; not that I am willing to share, at least. The world belongs to people who have the best stories.  Sexual liberation belongs to women who [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1202&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span id="internal-source-marker_0.14823800511658192">I have wanted to write about this for a long time.  I have so much to say about it. The problem is that I don’t have any stories about it&#8211; not that I am willing to share, at least. The world belongs to people who have the best stories.  Sexual liberation belongs to women who are willing to stand up and say “I have sex! I have <em>this much</em> sex with <em>this many</em> people, and it’s okay!” or  “I dress <em>like this</em>, so take that society!” Purity, modesty, and all that is pro-Virgin power comes from personal testimonies and Conservatively told bible stories.</span></p>
<p>And then there’s me.</p>
<p>Of course, I admire people who do tell their stories. They have changed my life, and the world really does belong to them.  Stories have a neat way of improving social consciousness, evolving into full-blown movements. [Insert Pokemon evolution joke here?].</p>
<p>Me, I really don’t have a story that will change your life.  I could probably make you laugh, but ultimately I’m not willing to share whether I’ve said Yes or No&#8211;certainly, I’m not telling the internet, nor my parents, nor most people I know. That doesn’t make me ashamed, by the way. I am fully comfortable with my sexuality. And I’m fully comfortable with keeping it to myself.</p>
<p>But since stories run the show, I will tell you the stories that I know.</p>
<p>I know stories about women saying Yes, and it being a big problem. I know stories about women saying No, and it being a big problem. I know stories about misogyny disguised as miscommunication.  I also know stories of miscommunication disguised as misogyny&#8211;God bless the little boys who receive mixed messages and lowered bars from society every day.</p>
<p>I know stories about people ashamed of what they <em>have</em> done, because that big bully “Society&#8221; told them they ought to be.  Then there the people ashamed of what they <em>haven’t</em> done. There’s also shame in the couldn’t do, wouldn’t do&#8211;or, God forbid, <em>like</em> to do.</p>
<p>Oh, and there’s shame in what people <em>don’t like</em> to do, too. Sometimes, the don’t likes meet the likes and they confuse and shame <em>each other</em>.  Fun, right?</p>
<p>I know stories about women who proudly wear the title “sexually liberated” because, well, they have a lot of sex and they want to own it and <em>good for them</em>.  I know stories about women are “sexually liberated,” or “sex positive,” but don’t have a lot of sex at all.  I have heard tall tales from people who pretend they have <em>more</em> sex than they actually do, because they want to be part of the conversation. And then, of course, there are heartbreaking stories from folks who pretend they have <em>less</em> sex than they actually do, because that’s what is acceptable.</p>
<p>To make matters more confusing, these stories can all belong to the same person.  Whether you’re in a Eucharist line or a picket line, chances are your sexual history is more definitive of who you are as a person than it should be.</p>
<p>Yes, I know stories.  And so many of these stories make want to run up and give their keepers a big hug and say “It’s okay! You’re okay! <strong>You aren’t broken</strong>.”</p>
<p>Everyone is just trying to figure their s**t out. If sexuality was sensible, reasonable, formulated, and mundane, then it wouldn’t be so friggin’ funny. And it is funny. It’s ridiculous. It’s romantic. It’s silly.</p>
<p>Welcome to human relationships, friends&#8211;they’re <em>weird</em>.  When people take their clothes off, they get even <em>weirder</em>. So no, they don’t need your judgement.  They need your love, and they need God’s love.  Please leave the close-mindedness at the door.</p>
<p>Oh, yes, there are serious things involved in sexuality: Health. Pregnancy. HIV. Disease. Emotional well-being. Rape. Consent.  And we’re awfully good at confusing people about the serious parts by making up stupid rules about the ridiculous parts.  These things need to be discussed honestly, but we keep loading them down with arbitrary social standards.  Why? Do we really need to make sex <em>more</em> emotionally loaded and confusing?</p>
<p>Here’s what we need to do:  Care about the stories. Let them speak. Respect the storytellers.  Share your own stories, if you want to.  And whatever your story is, however different it is than someone elses, whatever you choose to do with it: <em><strong>You aren’t broken.</strong></em></p>
<p>You’re just another person with a story and a body, and no matter what, those two things belong to you and you alone.</p>
<div id="attachment_1212" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 647px"><a href="http://shaunanaginsdotcom.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/shaunanaginstumbnail2.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-1212  " alt="ShaunanaginsTumbnail2" src="http://shaunanaginsdotcom.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/shaunanaginstumbnail2.jpg?w=637&#038;h=421" width="637" height="421" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Photo by Samantha Polzin for shaunanagins.com, January 2013</p></div>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1202/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1202/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1202&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://shaunanagins.com/2013/01/30/sex-lies-and-story-time-its-okay-you-arent-broken/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>31</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/50de525dd174548194718ce1d17a0beb?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">shaunanagins</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://shaunanaginsdotcom.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/shaunanaginstumbnail2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ShaunanaginsTumbnail2</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Saying Goodbye</title>
		<link>http://culturallife.wordpress.com/2013/01/31/weekly-writing-challenge-saying-goodbye/</link>
		<comments>http://culturallife.wordpress.com/2013/01/31/weekly-writing-challenge-saying-goodbye/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 13:41:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Grace @ Cultural Life</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing challenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPchallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hospitals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[illness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[surgery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing challenge]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://culturallife.wordpress.com/?p=925</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[When I saw this week’s writing challenge from The Daily Post, I planned to write a fun story about the characters we see in the photo. But then I thought about the wider theme I interpreted in this picture: saying farewell. The people in the photo could be greeting each other, I suppose, but to [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=925&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://culturallife.wordpress.com/2013/01/31/weekly-writing-challenge-saying-goodbye/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>42</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/fdc11863ca43ee6576b35316bc7fed0f?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">culturallife</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://culturallife.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/couple-embrace.jpg?w=241" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>1,000 Words, Take Two</title>
		<link>http://littlemisswordy.wordpress.com/2013/01/30/weekly-writing-challenge-1000-words-take-two/</link>
		<comments>http://littlemisswordy.wordpress.com/2013/01/30/weekly-writing-challenge-1000-words-take-two/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2013 14:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>littlemisswordy</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Challenges]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Inspiration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Storytelling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thoughts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[death]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DP Challenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hug]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inspiration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mental-health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[siblings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[storytelling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weekly writing challenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://littlemisswordy.wordpress.com/?p=1542</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I cling to him, feeling the slippery slope of time catching up to me as the ticks on my watch drum in my ears like a tribal rain dance circling round my brain. If only I could freeze time and force it to turn around and head back in the opposite direction, even if it [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1542&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://littlemisswordy.wordpress.com/2013/01/30/weekly-writing-challenge-1000-words-take-two/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>63</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/70f0e4f24da2a226a165a3455da6dce9?s=96&#38;d=wavatar&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">littlemisswordy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://littlemisswordy.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/couple-embrace.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">couple-embrace</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Four-Letter Words</title>
		<link>http://frommywriteside.wordpress.com/2013/01/29/four-letter-words/</link>
		<comments>http://frommywriteside.wordpress.com/2013/01/29/four-letter-words/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2013 04:30:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>SAM</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flash fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prompts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[psychosis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scriptic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tales from the dark side]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thriller]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cable car]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[couple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPChallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[four letter words]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mental-health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photo prompt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[picture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transportation]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://frommywriteside.wordpress.com/?p=2737</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[She said she loved the train. In the next breath, she said she loved me. Odd that we were on the wrong side of the train to catch it. If she really loved the train, she would have made sure we were on the right side, but we weren&#8217;t. Look. I&#8217;m getting repetitious already. She [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2737&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://frommywriteside.wordpress.com/2013/01/29/four-letter-words/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>51</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/ae648c024b0b344b8b8100f5ef13cdf8?s=96&#38;d=monsterid&#38;r=X" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">stephaniemayers</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dailypost.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/couple-embrace.jpg?w=620" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://gallery.mailchimp.com/62aeb18b1810c88501e4196cf/images/scriptic_raven_logo.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="https://ff.duckduckgo.com/favicon.ico" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="https://www.google.com/favicon.ico" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Through the Blue Door and Out</title>
		<link>http://nikprose.wordpress.com/2013/01/29/through-the-blue-door-and-out/</link>
		<comments>http://nikprose.wordpress.com/2013/01/29/through-the-blue-door-and-out/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 05:14:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>nikprose</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nikolarogan15.wordpress.com/?p=2</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I took the picture. Hell, I took several- he just wouldn&#8217;t let go. My stomach was churning. I took note of an aluminum streetcar and pointed my Nikon in its direction and snapped away. It reminded me of a futuristic homage to better days. A rounded man in a striped shirt struggled up the stiff and shiny [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://nikprose.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/couple-embrace1.jpg"><img class="wp-image-45 alignright" alt="couple-embrace" src="http://nikprose.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/couple-embrace1.jpg?w=189&#038;h=234" width="189" height="234" /></a>I took the picture. Hell, I took several- he just wouldn&#8217;t let go. My stomach was churning. I took note of an aluminum streetcar and pointed my Nikon in its direction and snapped away. It reminded me of a futuristic homage to better days.</p>
<p>A rounded man in a striped shirt struggled up the stiff and shiny cobbled steps. He reached out with his left arm and latched on to his wife’s, who seemed to have a little more vigor in her step. They were most likely going home for an afternoon siesta. Siesta: that’s all it seemed people did around here.</p>
<p>We were walking down a narrow sloped hill with beautifully crumbling buildings on each side, separated only by those challenging staccato cobbled stone steps, and by tram lines going up the middle of the ‘street.’ I took a moment to soak it all in- I finally felt like I was in South America.</p>
<p>“Did you get it? Did you get the shot?” It was Michael. They had finally stopped hugging.</p>
<p>“Yeah, I got it.”</p>
<p>“How did it turn out?” he asked.</p>
<p>“Just fine,” I replied. I looked at Anna who gave me a half-hearted  glance and looked away. She was wearing her red floral sundress. The one that always lifted ever so slightly with the breeze and made me wonder whether her little frame would one day blow away altogether.</p>
<p>“Good,” said Michael with a big grin. &#8220;It’s just down the steps and to the left. You guys are going to love it.”</p>
<p>I stopped holding my camera and let it hang around my neck and adjusted the straps of my little backpack. Michael was already three steps down while Anna still hadn&#8217;t moved.</p>
<p>“Come on, what are you guys waiting for?” I could see her looking at me from the corner of her eye. She continued down the steps and so did I behind her. When she reached Michael he took her hand.</p>
<p>“You tired, Tony?” he asked.</p>
<p>“Nope.”</p>
<p>“You look a little tired or something. Doesn&#8217;t he look tired, Anne?”  She looked up at me, still holding his hand.</p>
<p>“No, I don’t think so,” she said, producing the faintest of smiles.</p>
<p>“Are you jet lagged? You can’t still be jet lagged?”</p>
<p>“No, I’m not jet lagged Mike. I’m fine.”</p>
<p>“Alright, alright! Sorry, man. I’m just excited. I want everyone to have a good time. The tequila will help! Come on.” He pulled Anna down with him and like always I followed behind.</p>
<p>He was living here. Walking the cobbled steps and riding trams up city streets built on burning rolling hills. Michael moved here from Ohio for med school. He couldn&#8217;t get in anywhere stateside and heard about the school from one of his father’s colleagues. This was the first time we were seeing him in three months. Anna and I flew in together the night before.</p>
<p>Descending the steps and out of the shade into the testing sun, a fuller woman stood in black pants, white sleeveless collar, with her arms crossed, seemingly bored and completely unbothered by the scorching heat; presumably waiting for patrons to arrive.</p>
<p>“Ola,” said Michael, with his American accent. The woman rolled her eyes and responded with an, Ola senior.</p>
<p>We walked through a tight blue door and I gave the broad woman a nervous smile that resulted in more eye rolling.</p>
<p>The bar was a dimly lit hole in the wall. There was lively ethnic music on in the background and a soccer match played in the corner above a wooden bar and dusty bottles on an ancient TV.</p>
<p>“Didn’t I tell you,” said Michael. “Didn’t I tell you it was authentic? We come here at least once a week to get away from studying. There’s a guy Ernesto here who’s the-” and before he could finish his sentence a white swinging door opened revealing, “Ernesto!” shouted Michael, and he and the man embraced. I smiled and looked over at Anna who smiled too.</p>
<p>“Ernesto, they’re here! They made it. This is my best friend Anthony,” said Michael, grabbing me by the shoulders. Ernesto and I shook hands. “And this Ernesto- this is my beautiful girlfriend, the love of my life, Anna.” My stomach churned. Ernesto took a moment and looked her up and down and then pulled her in for a hug and kissed her twice on both cheeks.</p>
<p>We sat at the wooden bar and pounded back tequila and rum and cokes. Ernesto laughed at the sun burn developing on my nose and forehead, and complemented Anna’s already beautifully sun kissed skin.</p>
<p>“To the three amigos,” cheersed Michael. We drank.</p>
<p>“To my best friend Tony boy coming all this way to see me,” cheersed Michael. We drank.</p>
<p>“To my beautiful and loyal girlfriend Anne, who I miss so much. Salud!” We drank.</p>
<p>“Excuse me,” said Anna and stepped outside through the blue door, a burst of light sobering through.</p>
<p>“I should go check on her,” I said. As I stood, Michael pulled me back down.</p>
<p>“You been taking care of her like I asked?”</p>
<p>There was a long pause.</p>
<p>“I have.”</p>
<p>“Good boy,” he said. “I have to piss.” And he left for the bathroom.</p>
<p>Outside and a little bit further down the slope I found Anna crossed armed, her one leg bent behind her, leaning against a stores façade. There were trails on her soft cheeks fading away. I nearly stumbled past her down those damn steps and she caught me with a hug.</p>
<p>“Are you ok?” I asked.</p>
<p>“I don’t know how I’m going to do this,” she replied.</p>
<p>“It’ll be alright.”</p>
<p>“He’s good, he really is. But he’s absolutely clueless.”</p>
<p>“We bought the tickets before any of this even happened.” I hiccuped and she laughed.</p>
<p>“I’m drunk,” I said.</p>
<p>“I know. Me too, a little.”</p>
<p>“I like your dress.”</p>
<p>“Thank you.” She nestled her head against my chest and I kissed her sandy hair.</p>
<p>“We still have five more days to tell him.”</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://nikprose.wordpress.com/2013/01/29/through-the-blue-door-and-out/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/604f1813243465eaa067ea4bac222ce5?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">nikprose</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nikprose.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/couple-embrace1.jpg?w=241" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">couple-embrace</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Scouting Tolerance</title>
		<link>http://tokendissonance.wordpress.com/2013/01/29/scouting-tolerance/</link>
		<comments>http://tokendissonance.wordpress.com/2013/01/29/scouting-tolerance/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2013 01:58:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Rek</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Boy Scouts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Campus Pride]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chick-fil-A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dan Cathy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shane Windmeyer]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tokendissonance.wordpress.com/?p=820</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Update: This post was adapted by The Huffington Post. You can find that article here. “We all live with the objective of being happy, our lives are all different and yet the same.” –Anne Frank As a child, I was taught that you catch more flies with honey than vinegar. Dad’s particular corollary—pick your battles, as it’s [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=820&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em><strong>Update</strong></em>: This post was adapted by <em>The Huffington Post</em>. You can find that article <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/rek-lecounte/boy-scouts-gay-ban_b_2581766.html?utm_hp_ref=gay-voices">here</a>.</p>
<p>“We all live with the objective of being happy, our lives are all different and yet the same.” –Anne Frank</p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 551px"><a href="http://www.timepass.info/post/Where-two-oceans-meet-but-do-not-mix.aspx"><img class="  " alt="Amazing natural phenomenon where the Baltic and North Seas meet but don't mix because of the differing density" src="http://i.imgur.com/lCPDX.jpg" width="541" height="360" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">&#8220;Two nations between whom there is no intercourse and no sympathy; who are as ignorant of each other&#8217;s habits, thoughts, and feelings, as if they were dwellers in different zones, or inhabitants of different planets.&#8221; –Benjamin Disraeli</p></div>
<p>As a child, I was taught that you catch more flies with honey than vinegar. Dad’s particular corollary—pick your battles, as it’s not always worth it to be “right”—has served him well in the Army, so I’ve long aspired to apply its wisdom to my life. For this reason, it always made a sort of intuitive sense to seek mutual understanding and deescalate conflict rather than appeal to the choir in a scorched-earth crusade for feel-good “authenticity”. There is little value in a crown of bitterness, however righteous.</p>
<p>This philosophy of living, it turns out, is wonderfully conducive to maintaining close, mutually edifying relationships with many people whose political and ideological priorities would, I strongly suspect, be the <a href="http://tokendissonance.wordpress.com/2012/09/01/the-pride-of-yale/">ruin of America</a> (and Western civilization) if ever realized. I have well-meaning friends who oppose <a href="http://dailycaller.com/2012/12/20/the-court-of-marriage/">gay marriage</a>, distrust the military, hate <a href="http://dailycaller.com/2013/01/17/empire-state-of-guns/">guns</a>, disdain football, loathe the South, think highly of France, want ever <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/rek-lecounte/fear-and-consequence_b_2235135.html">higher taxes</a>, and blaspheme the <a href="http://tokendissonance.wordpress.com/2013/01/07/guns-taxes-and-the-devil/">Southeastern Conference</a>. I don’t need my loved ones to <a href="http://dailycaller.com/2012/11/05/why-im-voting-for-mitt-romney/">agree with me</a> on all that’s right and true, and I have defended those <a href="http://tokendissonance.wordpress.com/2012/07/26/i-disagree-with/">whose positions I reject</a>. I just need the people I care about to be willing to hear me and understand where I’m coming from. Where consideration is given, it is returned.</p>
<p>Accordingly, I’m not terribly surprised by the development of what might seem an unlikely friendship between LGBT activist Shane Windmeyer of <a href="http://www.campuspride.org/3890/campus-pride-suspends-chick-fil-a-5-simple-facts-about-chick-fil-a-national-college-campaign-2/">Campus Pride</a> and noted evangelical Dan Cathy of <a href="http://rachelheldevans.com/blog/chick-fil-a">Chick-fil-A</a>. If there is any virtue in “tolerance” and “diversity”, you can <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/shane-l-windmeyer/dan-cathy-chick-fil-a_b_2564379.html">find it in this</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>“Dan, in his heart, is driven by his desire to minister to others and had to choose to continue our relationship throughout this controversy. <em>He had to both hold to his beliefs and welcome me into them</em>. He had to face the issue of respecting my viewpoints and life even while not being able to reconcile them with his belief system. He defined this to me as &#8220;the blessing of growth.&#8221; <strong>He expanded his world without abandoning it. I did, as well.</strong> [My emphasis]”</p></blockquote>
<p>And thus a chasm <a href="http://www.campuspride.org/3890/campus-pride-suspends-chick-fil-a-5-simple-facts-about-chick-fil-a-national-college-campaign-2/">was bridged</a>.</p>
<p>Just last summer, as another bitter presidential campaign launched into orbit, the Boy Scouts closed a two-year study by reaffirming their ban on gay scouts and leaders. By then, there was something resembling growing public consensus in favor of including gays, and <a href="http://usnews.nbcnews.com/_news/2012/08/08/13185136-obama-opposes-boy-scouts-policy-banning-gays?lite">both presidential candidates</a> were on record supporting that consensus. Still, the Boy Scouts were primarily backed by <a href="http://www.the-daily-record.com/ap%20lifestyle/2012/08/03/as-eagle-scouts-return-medals-gay-ban-still-firm">religious organizations</a> that preferred the status quo, and so it held. Now, however, it seems that policy <a href="http://abcnews.go.com/US/wireStory/scouts-retreat-gays-policy-18337361">might change</a>, after all, much to the <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/01/29/boy-scouts-gay-policy-change-conservative-pundits-_n_2573828.html">chagrin of some</a>—though certainly not all—of the faithful.</p>
<p>If the Boy Scouts decide to shed their national requirement to exclude gays, there will not necessarily be a sudden, massive change-of-heart within the ranks any more than Dan Cathy is now a gay rights activist because of his friendship with Shane Windmeyer. While those troops that have long been gay-friendly will be able to come out of <a href="http://usnews.nbcnews.com/_news/2013/01/28/16738860-cub-scout-pack-were-dropping-gay-friendly-policy-in-face-of-boy-scouts-pressure?lite">glass closets</a>, others will be allowed to maintain their locally decided ban on gays. In short, a new world won’t be built overnight. What will matter is that <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/08/06/as-eagle-scouts-return-me_0_n_1747067.html">fewer members</a> will be <a href="http://www.cnn.com/2010/US/06/21/pennsylvania.gay.scout/">rejected</a> for being <a href="http://www.cnn.com/2013/01/08/us/california-gay-eagle-scout/index.html">who they are</a>, and religious conservatives will not be compelled to contravene their values. In an ideal world, people from various perspectives will find new occasions and opportunities to understand one another, to everyone’s benefit. Even if not all minds ever fully change, there is hope in the possibility of harmony emerging from where once there thrived grievance and resentment.</p>
<p>Wherever you fall on this or any issue, there is often a world of difference between being wrong and being evil. We don’t have to all agree on the content or path to a better world of enduring fulfillment and mutual respect, but we can at least acknowledge that we each strive for one. If nothing else, may we always have at least that much in common.</p>
<p>We can agree to disagree.</p>
<br /> Tagged: <a href='http://tokendissonance.wordpress.com/tag/boy-scouts/'>Boy Scouts</a>, <a href='http://tokendissonance.wordpress.com/tag/campus-pride/'>Campus Pride</a>, <a href='http://tokendissonance.wordpress.com/tag/chick-fil-a/'>Chick-fil-A</a>, <a href='http://tokendissonance.wordpress.com/tag/dan-cathy/'>Dan Cathy</a>, <a href='http://tokendissonance.wordpress.com/tag/gay-rights/'>gay rights</a>, <a href='http://tokendissonance.wordpress.com/tag/shane-windmeyer/'>Shane Windmeyer</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/820/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/820/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/820/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/820/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/820/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/820/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/820/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/820/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/820/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/820/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/820/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/820/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/820/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/820/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=820&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tokendissonance.wordpress.com/2013/01/29/scouting-tolerance/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>20</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f82764fac4eb0728895c17d3098efbe9?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">reklecounte</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://i.imgur.com/lCPDX.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Amazing natural phenomenon where the Baltic and North Seas meet but don&#039;t mix because of the differing density</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fear Of Being Exposed</title>
		<link>http://laurenjbarnhart.wordpress.com/2013/01/31/fear-of-being-exposed/</link>
		<comments>http://laurenjbarnhart.wordpress.com/2013/01/31/fear-of-being-exposed/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2013 00:14:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>laurenjbarnhart</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Publishing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Art & Fear - Observations On The Perils (and Rewards) of Artmaking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Book Release]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David Bayles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lauren j. barnhart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Memoir]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[publishing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ted Orland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://laurenjbarnhart.wordpress.com/?p=303</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I am in the final stages before releasing my memoir, and for a few weeks there, I dealt with a paralyzing fear.  All I could think about are the attacks people will make on my character (though I’ve been attacked by readers before, on numerous occasions).   Or the ways in which certain people in the [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=303&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I am in the final stages before releasing my memoir, and for a few weeks there, I dealt with a paralyzing fear.  All I could think about are the attacks people will make on my character (though I’ve been attacked by readers before, on numerous occasions).   Or the ways in which certain people in the book will feel misrepresented or insulted (though I did my best to tell my story as it actually happened).</p>
<p>I listened to my dad telling stories about my sister and I over family dinner, and realized how unique each of our stories and perceptions really are.  He had no recollection of what we were really going through at different stages of our lives.  A bitter drink turned sweet with distance.  In fact, <i>everyone</i> from my youth has little idea of the double life I lived, now captured in my book.</p>
<p>“The risk is fearsome: in making your real work you hand the audience the power to deny the understanding you seek; you hand them the power to say, “you’re not like us; you’re weird; you’re crazy (Bayles, Orland, 39).”</p>
<p>In all truth, I prefer people that I don’t know at all to read my work, rather than people who know me.  It’s okay for a stranger to not like it, or not get it, but when it’s your friend, it means that they don’t really get <i>you</i> at all.</p>
<p>In the midst of my publishing fear phase, a friend leant me the book “Art &amp; Fear – Observations On The Perils (and Rewards) of Artmaking”.  As soon as I began reading it, my fear subsided.  I was able to fully focus again on the process of making art, rather than fearing the result of my art.  And I remembered how amazing it is to be where I am at, and see that the creation of this book all happened through mad stubborn persistence, diligence, pain, tears, upheaval, countless rewrites, and that fleeting feeling of triumph.</p>
<p>“Basically, those who continue to make art are those who have learned how to continue – or more precisely, have learned how to not quit (Bayles, Orland, 9).”</p>
<p>In the beginning, I imagined I would write a novel.  My boyfriend at the time so fascinated me that I had to capture him with words.  I thought it would just be a story of him, but it grew and grew into a whole community.  How I got there, what I was searching for, and how it all ended up.  In the end, it was not really about him or them at all.  It was about me.</p>
<p>I thought it would be finished in 1-2 years.  It would be published by a major with a huge book advance, become a best seller, and I would receive a movie deal within the year (how wonderful it is to be naïve and clueless).  As I slugged away at horrible jobs that paid practically nothing, this image of the victorious author got me through the worst.</p>
<p>Then there was the issue, that in my twenties I partied so hard and lived so much to the fullest (which makes for much of my subject matter), that it was hard to find time and a morning without a hangover to write.  But no matter.  I still lugged my computer to the coffee shop when I could, on my one day off from work a week.  Eventually, even in the early morning hours.</p>
<p>“To the artist, art is a verb (Bayles, Orland, 90).”</p>
<p>Bit by bit the pieces grew organically, and came to fit together.  The book started as a third person novel, then a novel in the 1<sup>st</sup> person, then with voices of two other characters thrown in.  Finally, three years ago, I was able to find the courage to admit that it is a memoir.  But I would not have had the guts to say what I did, if it hadn’t started out as fiction.  I also wouldn’t have come to know the other characters so well without that extra exploration.  Did I mention that I began writing this book in 2002?</p>
<p>“The artists life is frustrating not because the passage is slow, but because he imagines it to be fast (Bayle, Orland, 17).”</p>
<p>It still amazes me that I have not given up.  But on the other hand, it doesn’t amaze me at all, because I had no other choice.  I couldn’t release it from my brain until it was all written down.  And when it was finally done, it lifted like magic, and I was free of it.</p>
<p>I am at an age now, where the idealism begins to fade away.  I’ve watched plenty of friends give up their craft for stability.  Life is hard.  Most artists don’t survive as artists once they leave the supportive community of school.  After that, it’s just you and your art, and good luck getting people to care about what you do.  Your friends are not necessarily your fans.</p>
<p>Facing the fact that my book will be available to the public, I wonder how my life will change.  I will do everything I can to see that it’s successful, but there is the fear that it won’t sell.  I won’t know until I take that risk.  And whatever happens, it will still be a foundation that I can build from.</p>
<p>Years ago, a friend of mine read several chapters.  Paul was a young techie nerd, who was bored with life, and struggling to find social skills.  He kept talking to me about one of the main characters: a binging, partying, player who puts on a debonair act.  He became obsessed with this guy.  It didn’t take long before he was turning into him.</p>
<p>Suddenly, Paul was out every single night, getting wasted, and hounding women wherever he went.  In a bizarre turn of events, he married an older woman within three months of meeting her.  But he continued to go out every night, and slurred to me that he wasn’t sure how he’d gotten sucked into the institution.</p>
<p>At one point, he had been my best friend.  But soon, it was too embarrassing to go anywhere with him.  He was rude to bartenders who were my friends.  He was loud and obnoxious, trying to see how many curse words he could fit into one sentence.  He went from being madly intelligent and witty, to talking in circles without making any sense.  It was like watching Truman Capote’s downfall.</p>
<p>Was it the book?  Or was it because he also had feelings for me?  Or maybe, I was not responsible at all, and he was just on that course looking for an avenue to go down.  I don’t know.  But it was a disturbing realization that the book might be a little dangerous for the slightly unstable.</p>
<p>“Artmaking grants access to worlds that may be dangerous, sacred, forbidden, seductive, or all of the above.  It grants access to worlds you may otherwise never fully engage (Bayle, Orland, 108).”</p>
<p>I hope that my memoir shows that the world is never exactly as we are told it is, and it is up to each of us to find out for ourselves.  Every person has the right to be an adventurer, an explorer of life.  To Think for themselves.</p>
<p>Of course, it is dangerous to really live.  To take chances, and be open to people who are different from ourselves.  But it’s the only way to find out who we really are.  If we live in fear, we’ll remain in a bubble where nothing really happens, and nothing can really grow.</p>
<p>“Insist that the world must always remain <i>x</i>, and <i>x</i> is indeed exactly what you’ll get (Bayles, Orland, 111-112).”</p>
<p>I am excited, that soon, with the book release, my life will open up to new possibilities.  It will be out there, speaking for me, doing the work that I put into it for a decade of my life.  I will keep you all updated when it is released.</p>
<p>Do any of you have book release experiences to share?  Was it uplifting?  Did it feel like a let down?  Did it open your life up to new things?  Please share.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/303/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/303/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=303&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://laurenjbarnhart.wordpress.com/2013/01/31/fear-of-being-exposed/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>49</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/065432e9cfd4ef8d6ead61599f2fea28?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">laurenjbarnhart</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
