<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2013 21:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Kelly</title>
		<link>http://maesday.wordpress.com/2013/01/12/kelly/</link>
		<comments>http://maesday.wordpress.com/2013/01/12/kelly/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2013 05:31:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>maesprose</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cancer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Grief]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mastectomy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Memories]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://maesday.wordpress.com/?p=725</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I lost a friend this week. My friend lost her life. I knew from the beginning our friendship would end this way.  Yet, I didn’t know how wonderful our friendship would be or how much I would grow from it.  I always knew how much I would miss her. Kelly was my yoga teacher.  I [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=725&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://maesday.wordpress.com/2013/01/12/kelly/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/3f6c6b1b817c7b4db7654dc530653ea2?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">maesprose</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://maesday.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/violin.jpeg?w=252" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Violin</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Learning from Competition</title>
		<link>http://blog.learningbyshipping.com/2013/01/14/learning-from-competition/</link>
		<comments>http://blog.learningbyshipping.com/2013/01/14/learning-from-competition/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2013 22:30:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Steven Sinofsky</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[competition]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://learningbyshipping.wordpress.com/?p=201</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Gotcha. Traitor. Snicker. Those were some of the reactions when people discovered that I was using an iPhone. I stand before you accused of using a competitor’s [sic] product and I plead guilty. Moving beyond the gotcha blogs, there’s an actual reason for using technology products and services other than the ones you make (or [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=201&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><i>Gotcha. Traitor. Snicker.</i> Those were some of the reactions when people <i>discovered</i> that I was using an iPhone. I stand before you accused of using a competitor’s [sic] product and I plead guilty.</p>
<p>Moving beyond the gotcha blogs, there’s an actual reason for using technology products and services other than the ones you make (or happen to be made by the company where you work/ed). I think everyone knows that, even a thousand tweets later.  The approach in many industries to downplay or even become hostile to the competition are well-documented and studied, and generally conclude that experiencing the competition is a good thing.</p>
<p>Learning from the competition is not just required of all product development folks, but can also be somewhat of a skill worth honing. Let’s look at the ins and outs of using a competitive product.</p>
<h2>Why?</h2>
<p>Obviously you should use a competitive product. You should know what you’re up against when a consumer (or business) ultimately faces a buying decision. They will weigh a wide array of factors and you should be aware of those not only for the purposes of sales and marketing but when you are designing your products.</p>
<p>It is easy to fall into the trap of checklists or cloning competitive products and so that might be why you follow the competition. That’s a weak way to compete. Part of planning your product/service is establishing your unique value proposition—is it features, pricing, implementation or execution for example?</p>
<p>Simply being the same as your competitor that might be more established is not good enough and so knowing the competition for the sake of skimming their value proposition won’t work. Generally speaking, just adding the cool thing from a competitor at the last minute to your product’s plan is not going to work well for customers and will be readily transparent. That’s checklist product development.</p>
<p>Product development is a complex endeavor. There is no magic. Worse than that, most people making products in a “category” are pulling insights, ideas, and technologies from the same sources. What separates wildly successful products from distant number two products can often be just a few of thousands of choices.</p>
<p>Studying your competitor, well, gives you a chance to evaluate your choices in an entirely different context. When you make a product choice you are making it in the context of your company, strategy, business model, and people/talents. What if you change some of those? That is what knowing the competition allows you to do, and basically for free (no consultants or top secret research).</p>
<p>What does it mean to study the competition well? What are some common mistakes made when studying the competition?</p>
<h2>Common Mistakes</h2>
<p>Even when you study the competition, there are some techniques that are often employed, and with the best of intentions. There are ways of executing on a competitive analysis that leave some information on the table.</p>
<p>Worse, it is possible to execute on a competitive analysis from a dismissive or <i>get this over with</i> posture that takes away what is perhaps the most valuable source of information in forward looking product design.</p>
<p>While there are many potential challenges, here are a couple of examples of patterns I’ve seen.</p>
<ul>
<li><b>Using the product in a lightweight manner.</b> All too often analyzing the competition itself becomes a checklist work item. Go to the store and play with it for a few minutes. Maybe ask a friend or neighbor what they think. The usage of a competitive product needs to be in depth and over time. You need to use the product like it is your primary product and not switch or fall back to your old way of working. Often this is weeks or more of usage. Even as a reviewer this applies. Walt Mossberg famously took an iPad on a <a href="http://allthingsd.com/20100922/an-american-in-paris-says-au-revoir-to-his-laptop/">10 day trip to France</a>—no laptop at all. That’s how to use a product.</li>
<li><b>Thinking like yourself, not the competition.</b> When using a competitive product you need to use it like it was intended to be used by the designers. Don’t get the product and use the customization tools to morph it into the familiar. Even if a product has a mode to make it work like the familiar (as a competitive bridge they offer) don’t use it. Use native file formats. Use defaults in the UI and functionality. Follow the designed workflow. They key is to let loose of your muscle memory and develop new memory.</li>
<li><b>Betting competitors act similarly (or even rationally).</b> If you think like a competitor you have to make future decisions like they might. Of course you can’t really do that or really know and this is where product intuition comes to mind (and also why blogs predicting product directions are often off the mark). You have to really wrap yourself around the culture, constraints, resources, and more of a competitor. The reality is that your competitor is not going “fix” their product to turn it into your product. So then the question is what would a competitors do in their context, not what would you do if you were designing the follow-on product in your context. This might actually feel irrational to you. One of the most classic examples of this is whether or not the Mac OS should have been licensed to other PC makers or not. Arguments could be made either way, both then and now. But what is right or assumed in one context simply doesn’t make sense in another. That context can also include a time dimension where the answer actually changes.</li>
<li><b>Assume the world is static.</b> Even after you’ve reviewed a competitor through usage you might feel confident because they are missing some features or might have done some things poorly. That’s a static view of the world. Keep in mind analyzing the competition is a two-way street. If you noticed a weakness there’s a really good chance the competitor knew about it. When everyone pointed out that a phone was missing copy/paste, don’t make a mistake thinking that was news to the development team and would remain a competitive advantage.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Approaches</h2>
<p>There’s a reason Patton often made reference to Thucydides treatise on the <i>History of the Peloponnesian War</i>. It is a thorough and thoughtful analysis that goes beyond who won which battles but gets inside the minds of the men, the culture, and the thought processes. Competing in business is not war and should not be treated as such, either literally or as a metaphor (the stakes are relatively insignificant and business is an <i>endless</i> series of skirmishes and battles rather than aiming for an ‘end’, at the very least). However, the idea of being thoughtful and understanding tactics, decision making, resource allocation, and more are important.</p>
<p>There are a few techniques that are often used in conjunction with using the product. The most important thing is of course to use the product and to adopt it as your primary tool for all the uses it was intended in the manner in which it was intended. With that raw data, there are number of potential tools for sharing that learning:</p>
<ul>
<li><b>Feature comparisons.</b> The most obvious tool is to make a long list of features and compare products. This works well for some folks and especially when handed to customers. It is also the least useful in product design. A feature checklist is only as good as the features you put on it. We all know how easy it is to make a product look feature rich or feature poor simply by picking the right set of features to check off. You can even pick weird measures for whether a feature is in or not—you could have a “WiFi” check item or you could make it “WiFi a/b/g/n” and change who won or lost. You can also lead to a false conclusion if you try to score or just count features—it is doubling the error rate of your check list because you’re doubly-assuming your context.</li>
<li><b><i>SWOT.</i></b> A common “single slide” approach to competitors is to distill down competition into something like <i>strengths, weaknesses, opportunities, threats</i>. These are very hard to do well, again because of the context, but by including all of these you force yourself to confront your own product shortcoming and missteps. Personally, I don’t like the use of “threats” because it starts to conjure up war and sports metaphors but you can think of them as risks that customers won’t choose your product/service. SWOT is often used by the marketing team because you can intermix near term tactics in the marketplace (opportunities).</li>
<li><b>Scenario comparisons.</b> A nice way to take a more end-to-end approach to competitive analysis is to consider more complete scenarios. If you’re testing for battery life then don’t just play a movie, but play a movie with the radios on and an active mailbox, as an example. As with everything, it is important to pick scenarios that are truly representative of what a product was designed to do and how it was designed to do it, not how your product/service does. Measuring a scenario comparison could involve clicks/gestures, clock time, resource consumption, and more.</li>
<li><b>Competitive review or blog.</b> My favorite test of really getting in the mind of the competitor is to challenge yourself to review your own product as though you were the competitor. Alternatively, you could write a press release or blog for a competitive product—the product that competes with you. I remember once writing a whole “press kit” for what became Visual C++ as though I were the Borland C++ team. It was great fun. Rather than focus on Windows (3.0!) development, I focused on compiler speed, code size, array of command line options, and more. Those were the things that Borland would focus on. I then ripped into Visual C++ as a Borland person, highlighting what options were missing, the slowness of the tools, and so on. Even though VC++ 1.0 had a Windows dev environment, resource editor, class library and more—all assets relative to Borland.</li>
</ul>
<p>Of course not matter what your approach, be sure to write down your work and analysis (writing is thinking!) and share it with the team (learning by sharing).</p>
<h2>Be Obsessed</h2>
<p>Those are a few common pitfalls and approaches to competitive analysis.  There are many more.  Feel free to share your favorite approaches in the comments.</p>
<p>Finally, studying the competition is the job of everyone on a team. Importantly, the people doing the work need to study the competition. It is not a job for a staff function or those outside product development. Management studies the competition not just receives reports on the competition. Experts in domains that are parts of a product should drill into the details of the competition (hardware, software, subsystems, peripherals, APIs, etc.)</p>
<p>Be obsessed with the competition. Always. This has never been truer than the fast paced and dynamic world of products where the flow of information is instant and the scale and complexity are greater than ever before.</p>
<p>&#8211;Steven</p>
<p>PS: My plan was not to publish so frequently/rapidly, but even in my old MS blog if something came up that was so timely relative to the ongoing dialog, I&#8217;d do a quick post.  I&#8217;m still going to pace myself :-)</p>
<p align="center">###</p>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=201&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://blog.learningbyshipping.com/2013/01/14/learning-from-competition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>25</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/968256575c4ec55a6f6bb09d411e38f6?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sinofsky</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Men</title>
		<link>http://thetriviapursuit.wordpress.com/2013/01/14/men/</link>
		<comments>http://thetriviapursuit.wordpress.com/2013/01/14/men/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 01:57:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>hummeljt</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[People]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[men]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pursuit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trivia]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thetriviapursuit.wordpress.com/?p=867</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;A whole gender? That doesn&#8217;t seem trivial at all!&#8221; Hey, arbitrary person. First of all, thanks for reading this. Really means a lot. Second of all, prepare to be amazed. I&#8217;ve been thinking about this for a long time and I think I&#8217;m ready to try to dehumanize half of the world&#8217;s population. If you [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=867&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;A whole gender? That doesn&#8217;t seem trivial at all!&#8221; Hey, arbitrary person. First of all, thanks for reading this. Really means a lot. Second of all, prepare to be amazed. I&#8217;ve been thinking about this for a long time and I think I&#8217;m ready to try to dehumanize half of the world&#8217;s population. If you feel like an insentient styrofoam peanut after reading this, good because I will too. Let&#8217;s be friends.</p>
<p>DISCLAIMER: Many male trivialities are also applicable to non-males. Be fair.</p>
<p>ANOTHER DISCLAIMER: This post contains partially hurtful gender stereotypes. Be fair, still.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s say I live 80 years, from 1989 to 2069 (hehe). There were about 3 billion men on the planet when I was born, and about 65 million born each year until the year I die, for a grand total of 8.25 billion bros that will exist during my lifetime. You meet 100,000 people during the course of your life (sounds high, but it works out to around 3 people per day). I will never meet 99.999% of the men that will walk this Earth while I&#8217;m alive, I won&#8217;t understand how they will impact me, and I&#8217;ll rarely give them any thought. Extend that further and think about the possibility of life on other planets, or in other universes. I&#8217;m a 20-something social media fan, so I&#8217;m about 1000% saturated with ignorance, self-righteousness, and delusion, but even *I* can&#8217;t fathom how unimportant everything I do will ever be in the midst of all that vastness. Sorry, guys named Braden, it doesn&#8217;t matter if you leave the sticker on your #swag hat.</p>
<p>Okay, okay, maybe that&#8217;s unfair. After all, I can&#8217;t use &#8220;Well, the universe is huge&#8221; as an excuse for not wearing a tie to an interview. The importance of what we do is relative to the size of the context (that #swag hat might get you laid in high school, but in no way affects the outcome of our planet, etc.). But still, think about it. Think about how important you are, how important you want to be, how important you think you are to others, and how important your life has been so far. THEN THINK ABOUT HOW YOU ARE ACTUALLY A SPECK OF DUST.</p>
<p>But why that? Doesn&#8217;t the feeling of being microscopic apply to female humans, too? Sure, ya jackwagon, but which gender values power and reputation more? Every great general led specks of dust into battle against different specks of dust. Every great scientist discovered something that made life as a common speck of dust a little easier. Every great architect designed a speck of dust slightly bigger than himself. Every great musician gave specks of dust something to talk about while they sipped on specks of dust at the Speck of Dust Cafe. Every great painter made a speck of dust out of different colored specks of dust. Every great prophet was charismatic enough to make other specks of dust follow him. Every great humanitarian made sure that each speck of dust was treated the same. To us, those are real people accomplishing extraordinary things, but when you combine ALL of that, over the course of our ENTIRE human history, you get a large speck of dust.</p>
<p>TL;DR version: We&#8217;re important to those we know, we&#8217;re barely important on earth, and earth is barely important. <a title="Check this out" href="http://htwins.net/scale2/" target="_blank">http://htwins.net/scale2/</a></p>
<p>But wait! It&#8217;s certainly possible to find some triviality here on earth. After all, I&#8217;m not writing this from Alpha Centauri. Naturally, many men will live their lives without doing much aside from using one life&#8217;s worth of resources. Some will accomplish wonderful things. But whatever they do, it&#8217;s almost entirely driven by social stigma. Even today, where equality is stressed (and sometimes forced to uncomfortable levels), we still have gender roles, as we always have. To some extent, men have assumed the role of provider (hunter) as women assume the role of caretaker (gatherer).</p>
<p>Somewhere along the line, the hunters were attached an insensitive label, and the gatherers a sensitive label. Probably because you need to be stone-hearted to kill and provide, and kind-hearted to care for a family. What gets lost (much like the point of this post, probably), is that HUMANS need to be BOTH stone/kind-hearted to manage a successful life. But the stigma suppresses much of the kind-hearted instincts and deeper sentiments of men. And as soon as they break the stigma, they get corrected (getting called a faggot in middle school is a good way to keep feelings from surfacing again). Emotional suppression and failure to live up to another&#8217;s standards are a recipe for depression, and that&#8217;s made evident by the fact that men are 3 times more likely to end their own life. It doesn&#8217;t happen when men go crazy, it happens when men feel trivial.</p>
<p>So how do we keep that from happening? Like I said before, we&#8217;re mired in a culture of forced equality, and that idea exists outside of gender equality, too. Our educational system and labor forces are all regimented like the military. Everyone would work, learn, and play differently if we let them, but we don&#8217;t. Ironically, having a higher governing power dictate your progression through life is a great way to feel lost. If we could individualize more aspects of education and work, and do our best to remove gender stigmas at a young age, it might take some of the triviality out of living the lives we&#8217;re told to live.</p>
<p>Thus, the pursuit of trivia continues.</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://thetriviapursuit.wordpress.com/category/people/'>People</a> Tagged: <a href='http://thetriviapursuit.wordpress.com/tag/men/'>men</a>, <a href='http://thetriviapursuit.wordpress.com/tag/pursuit/'>pursuit</a>, <a href='http://thetriviapursuit.wordpress.com/tag/trivia/'>trivia</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/867/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/867/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=867&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thetriviapursuit.wordpress.com/2013/01/14/men/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>46</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/da6f89b67c30647d47d1e7837a3f2790?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">hummeljt</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Don\&#8217;t Go In the Water, Because You Might Attract Sharks</title>
		<link>http://letstalkabouttext.wordpress.com/2013/01/14/dont-go-in-the-water-because-you-might-attract-sharks/</link>
		<comments>http://letstalkabouttext.wordpress.com/2013/01/14/dont-go-in-the-water-because-you-might-attract-sharks/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2013 07:29:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Let's Talk About Text</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crying]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Judy Blume]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lady time]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[My Super Sweet Sixteen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Period]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[playground]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snickers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[work]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://letstalkabouttext.wordpress.com/?p=273</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Every month I have an &#8220;Are You There God? It&#8217;s Me, Margaret moment&#8221;, in which I&#8217;m able to discern that I haven&#8217;t gone completely batty, but was solely on the verge of starting my period. I verbally refer to it as &#8220;lady time&#8221;, because it seems a little less female gym coach like. You would assume that by my age I&#8217;d [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=273&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img alt="" src="http://howmanyarethere.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/PMS-resized-300x181.jpg" /></p>
<p>Every month I have an &#8220;Are You There God? It&#8217;s Me, Margaret moment&#8221;, in which I&#8217;m able to discern that I haven&#8217;t gone completely batty, but was solely on the verge of starting my period. I verbally refer to it as &#8220;lady time&#8221;, because it seems a little less female gym coach like. You would assume that by my age I&#8217;d be able  to figure out the pattern, but I inevitably end up having a meltdown that looks like something from the show &#8220;My Super Sweet Sixteen&#8221; and contemplate abandoning this humor writing thing I do to write bad poetry about my feelings and listen to Ani DiFranco,  while cutting my own hair.</p>
<p>On my commute to work this morning I started crying, at first because I was anxious and Monday mornings in general are lacking in charisma, but it evolved into blubbering, because I didn&#8217;t even know why I was really weeping in the first place. There&#8217;s nothing sadder than not knowing why you&#8217;re sad, because you actually have no reason to be sad. Actually&#8230;there are <em>much</em> sadder things, but it&#8217;s <em>still</em> sad, yes?</p>
<p>Within a 20 minute drive my hormones put my docile logic through some kind of sick hazing in order to become a part of the sorority house that exists in my psyche. I sat in the parking lot of my place of employment convinced that everything in my world had fallen apart, while eating a granola bar and sipping a Diet Coke, because that&#8217;s what you do when a <em>real  </em>&#8220;tragedy&#8221; strikes, make sure you get your fiber intake and foster the development of your aspartame addiction.</p>
<p>I wanted to be back in bed, under a blanket, preferably eating a Snickers bar and watching reruns of Gilmore Girls. I couldn&#8217;t fathom how I was going to enter the building, let alone make it through an entire day of work, but then things kick in like responsibility and reality and the fact that I was sitting in a new car that needed a monthly payment and there was a classroom full of children actually depending on my arrival.</p>
<p>I stood on the playground feeling bloated and frumpy, passing for an old librarian or the &#8220;before&#8221; on pretty much any makeover show. Despite one of my co-workers complimenting my weight loss and another group of women shouting out compliments about my &#8220;new&#8221; haircut I&#8217;ve had for nearly a month, I still wanted that blanket and chocolate and quick witted banter exchanged between a mother and daughter with flawless skin.</p>
<p>My self esteem workbook talks about the difference between your ordinary mind and wisdom mind. Your ordinary mind basically states all the mean things you think about yourself and paints a pretty ugly picture of what it believes to be reality and the wisdom mind is what&#8217;s<em> actually</em> occurring. I tried to figure out which one I was using and before I knew it they&#8217;d mated and created a new mind that just wanted to shame eat Wendy&#8217;s in the car.</p>
<p>Around 3 o&#8217;clock I wanted to rip out my ovaries and a throw them at someone&#8217;s face, but kind of in a <em>celebratory</em> way&#8230;like <em>confetti</em>? I got my period, God! I was elated. I wasn&#8217;t on the verge of a nervous breakdown. I wasn&#8217;t slowly sinking into clinical depression. My sanity was there all along, it was just smothered by an estrogen monsoon.</p>
<p>It never hurts to remind myself that happiness is <em>always</em> possible, sometimes I just need to work a little harder to get it. And when my other options run out, Snickers bars are <em>really</em> high in protein.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/273/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/273/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=273&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://letstalkabouttext.wordpress.com/2013/01/14/dont-go-in-the-water-because-you-might-attract-sharks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>31</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/faf9eadb76044c2e0e6f32659fdc1463?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">adulttranslations</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://howmanyarethere.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/PMS-resized-300x181.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Silence of the Gays</title>
		<link>http://lgbticons.com/2013/01/15/silence-of-the-gays/</link>
		<comments>http://lgbticons.com/2013/01/15/silence-of-the-gays/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 12:40:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>lgbticons</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Celebrities]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Coming out]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lesbian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LGBT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Role Models]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DADT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Don't Ask Don't Tell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Golden Globe Awards]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hollywood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jodie Foster]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Paul Rudd]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://lgbticons.com/?p=684</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;I&#8217;m not sure I would go as far as to say that gay celebrities have a social or moral duty to be open about their sexuality. But I am prepared to argue that by refusing to acknowledge that they are gay &#8211; or that once, not that long ago, they were scared to admit it [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=684&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong><em>&#8220;I&#8217;m not sure I would go as far as to say that gay celebrities have a social or moral duty to be open about their sexuality. But I am prepared to argue that by refusing to acknowledge that they are gay &#8211; or that once, not that long ago, they were scared to admit it in public &#8211; they&#8217;re perpetuating an inhibiting and heteronormative status quo.&#8221;</em></strong></p>
<p style="text-align:right;">Josef Church-Woods</p>
<div id="attachment_686" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 460px"><a href="http://lgbticons.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/jodie_foster_28-1024.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-686   " alt="Jodie Foster" src="http://lgbticons.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/jodie_foster_28-1024.jpg?w=450&#038;h=337" width="450" height="337" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Jodie Foster</p></div>
<p>In case you somehow managed to miss it, Jodie Foster used her acceptance speech at the Golden Globe Awards on Sunday night, to plant her feet firmly outside of her admittedly already rather flimsy glass closet.</p>
<p>It was an emotional speech, in which she talked about a whole life lived in the public eye and the value of privacy, as well as her love for her female ex-partner, their joint children and her mother, among many others.</p>
<p>It wasn&#8217;t exactly a coming out speech, nor was it the first time she&#8217;s acknowledged her relationship with the co-parent of her children, but it was nonetheless a bit of a big deal, set in the unusual context of a major, Hollywood A-list event. So, good for you Jodie, and good for everybody else who believes in equality &#8211; we need all the positive, gay role models we can get, flying the flag for &#8216;modern families&#8217; and the notion that love is love, regardless of sexuality.</p>
<p>However, watching the clip of Jodie on stage (see link below), I couldn&#8217;t help wondering why exactly, in the 21st century, such a successful, intelligent, supported and loved person would feel that talking freely about being a lesbian amounts to an invasion of her privacy.</p>
<p>I find it frustrating that so many people seem to confuse sexual orientation with their private selves. It&#8217;s perfectly possible to be open about your sexuality, without talking excessively to media outlets about your personal relationships, or sharing every aspect of your life with the world. Lots of people who are in the spotlight have mastered this balance. Even intensely private, straight celebrities do not hide or refuse to acknowledge the fact that they are sexually attracted to people of the opposite sex. Why would they? The fact that Paul Rudd likes women says virtually nothing about him as a person, how he lives his life or what kind of a family he has.</p>
<p>Obviously, coming out as gay is not quite the same thing as being openly straight. It&#8217;s not my intention to trivialise the struggle that many LGBT people face by likening a queer person&#8217;s experience of dealing with their sexuality to that of a straight person, who is automatically welcomed into the majority fold. Heterosexuality is the norm &#8211; the default setting &#8211; and homophobia is still a very real and tangible threat for most of us. For many it has devastating consequences, even in western countries with political leaders who candidly endorse LGBT equality.</p>
<p>And this is exactly why I think it&#8217;s so important that people who are considered role models speak out. It&#8217;s why it rubs me up the wrong way when someone like Jodie Foster stands in front of the whole world and half comes out, then swiftly makes it clear that the reason she still refuses to let the word &#8216;gay&#8217; pass her lips, is because it&#8217;s a personal matter and sharing this side of her being with the public amounts to a violation of her privacy. There&#8217;s no need for a press conference or a reality TV show &#8211; but unless you think there is something wrong with being gay, why would you refuse to confirm something which is just as generic as the colour of your skin?</p>
<p>No offense Jodie; I know that you came out to your family and friends many years ago and I don&#8217;t mean to call into question your honesty or integrity. It&#8217;s just that I believe your long and somewhat ambiguous journey to that Golden Globe acceptance speech is symptomatic of an oppressive catch 22.</p>
<p>The reason famous, gay people keep their public persona in the closet is because they are worried about the reaction that their coming out might provoke, and the potential impact on their careers and families &#8211; not because they are &#8216;private people&#8217;. This is something I feel needs to be expressed, because when it&#8217;s brushed over, it sends a very clear &#8216;Don&#8217;t Ask, Don&#8217;t Tell&#8217; message. And even the US army has conceded that <i>that</i> particular approach to diversity is both unjust and harmful.</p>
<p>I do understand that there is a lot of extra pressure to handle when your every move is observed, recorded and generally regarded as public property. Fear of judgment, damage to career trajectory and potential loss of earnings are all valid enough reason to feel nervous about stepping out in public with your same-sex partner.</p>
<p>As such, I&#8217;m not sure I would go as far as to say that gay celebrities have a social or moral duty to be open about their sexuality. But I am prepared to argue that by refusing to acknowledge that they are gay &#8211; or that once, not that long ago, they were scared to admit it in public &#8211; they&#8217;re perpetuating an inhibiting and heteronormative status quo.</p>
<p>I hope, as we move forward, more famous men and women feel able to be open, not just about their sexuality, but also about the reasons why perhaps they hesitated within the familiar comfort of their closet walls.</p>
<p><em>Josef Church-Woods (<a title="Joe on Twitter" href="http://www.twitter.com/josefcw" target="_blank">@JosefCW</a>)</em></p>
<span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='640' height='390' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/5bZofatrNAQ?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/684/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/684/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=684&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://lgbticons.com/2013/01/15/silence-of-the-gays/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>23</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/5629ccdcffbd0b3dc7d2e313ef7a06d5?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lgbticons</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lgbticons.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/jodie_foster_28-1024.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Jodie Foster</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Homemade Target Cookies</title>
		<link>http://peasandcougars.com/2013/01/08/homemade-target-cookies/</link>
		<comments>http://peasandcougars.com/2013/01/08/homemade-target-cookies/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2013 10:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Rae</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cats and Cats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holidays]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cartoon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cookies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[homemade]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[target]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://peasandcougars.com/?p=2716</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Sometimes there&#8217;s a little bit of truth in every lie.<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2716&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://peasandcougars.com/2013/01/08/homemade-target-cookies/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>28</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/466d873b4d81dced14552228b994ff62?s=96&#38;d=wavatar&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Plastic Daffodils</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peasandcougars.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/cookies-1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cookies 1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peasandcougars.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/cookies-23.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cookies 2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peasandcougars.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/cookies-3.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cookies 3</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peasandcougars.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/cookies-4.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cookies 4</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peasandcougars.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/cookies-5.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cookies 5</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peasandcougars.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/cookies-6.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cookies 6</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peasandcougars.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/cookies-7.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cookies 7</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://peasandcougars.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/cookies-8.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cookies 8</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Online Dating Advice for the Lovelorn</title>
		<link>http://1pointperspective.wordpress.com/2013/01/06/online-dating-advice-for-the-lovelorn/</link>
		<comments>http://1pointperspective.wordpress.com/2013/01/06/online-dating-advice-for-the-lovelorn/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2013 15:23:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>1pointperspective</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electronic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manslaughter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[romance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vermont]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://1pointperspective.wordpress.com/?p=4697</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A Vermont woman named Christine Billis recently pled guilty to manslaughter after she intentionally drove her car into a tree, causing her husband&#8217;s death.  Ms. Billis would have gotten away with it, but shortly after the accident, she joined the online dating website okcupid.com, then confessed the deed to a prospective beau.  The guy decided to go to the authorities instead of pursuing a relationship with her.  [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4697&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_4752" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 435px"><a href="http://1pointperspective.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/datelessndallas-dot-com.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-4752" alt="Step One: Rearrange the buttons on your keyboard to write cute things.  Step Two: Take a piocture of it! (Image from datelessndallas.com)" src="http://1pointperspective.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/datelessndallas-dot-com.jpg?w=720"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text"><em><strong>I checked my keyboard &#8211; this is not the actual orientation of keys on my laptop.  (Image from datelessndallas.com)</strong></em></p></div>
<p>A <a href="http://autos.aol.com/article/Christine-Billis-Vermont-husband-accident-manslaughter/">Vermont woman</a> named Christine Billis recently pled guilty to manslaughter after she intentionally drove her car into a tree, causing her husband&#8217;s death.  Ms. Billis would have gotten away with it, but shortly after the accident, she joined the online dating website okcupid.com, then confessed the deed to a prospective beau.  The guy decided to go to the authorities instead of pursuing a relationship with her.  It seems wearing a wire and becoming an undercover informant is preferable to finding love for some people.</p>
<p>No one will dispute that it&#8217;s wrong to hasten the demise of your spouse by driving into a tree, no matter how much he snores over there in the passenger seat.  The old &#8220;thou shalt not kill&#8221; credo is pretty standard.  In her defense, Ms. Billis later claimed her husband was controlling and abusive.  Mental note: If you&#8217;re controlling and abusive, you should do the driving.</p>
<p>What&#8217;s glaringly apparent to me is that Christine, and possibly others, need some guidance in the dos and don&#8217;ts in the world of online dating.  Being an old guy who&#8217;s been married since Moses was a pup, I&#8217;m clearly not the most knowledgable about dating in these modern times, much less the new-fangled internet variety.  Despite my lack of expertise, I don&#8217;t see anyone else volunteering much advice for you folks, so here goes.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><strong><em>D</em><em>o -</em></strong> be honest about yourself, particularly in the &#8220;Likes and Dislikes&#8221; portion of the initial questionaire.  If a potential love-interest doesn&#8217;t enjoy scrap-booking, it&#8217;s better to find out right away.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><em><strong>Don&#8217;t -</strong></em> admit to killing your husband by driving his side of the Ford Fiesta into a sugar maple.  Save that story for when the guy doesn&#8217;t want to see you anymore.  He&#8217;ll think twice about breaking things off &#8211; especially if you&#8217;ve gotten the Fiesta repaired and on the road again.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;padding-left:30px;">. _ . _ .</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><strong><em>Do &#8211; </em></strong>bend the truth a little bit when describing your best features.  A little creativity can&#8217;t hurt.  Who hasn&#8217;t accidentally dropped five years off their sentence or twenty-five pounds off their derriere for the sake of embellishment?</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><strong><em>Don&#8217;t -</em></strong> go nuts on the fabrications.  Describing yourself as looking like a young Meryl Streep when you look more like an old Merle Haggard will make for an awkward first date.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;padding-left:30px;">. _ . _ .</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><em><strong>Do &#8211; </strong></em>realize that there&#8217;s going to be a bit of fabrication on both sides of the ball.  If the guy describes himself as &#8220;an outdoorsman&#8221;, there&#8217;s a chance he lives in his car.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><em><strong>Do</strong><strong>n&#8217;t &#8211; </strong></em>rush to judgement.  Living in a car has its upside, especially if you haven&#8217;t gotten the Fiesta fixed yet because the twits at the insurance company are fussing about that pesky manslaughter charge.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;padding-left:30px;">. _ . _ .</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><em><strong>D</strong><strong><em>o -</em></strong></em> post a picture of yourself if the website requires it.  Try to find a shot which highlights your best features while minimizing the negatives.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><em><strong>Don&#8217;t -</strong> </em> use video-stills from your trial.  Also, very few people have complexions which are complimented by orange prison jumpsuits, so consider a black and white shot.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;padding-left:30px;">. _ . _ .</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><em><strong>Do &#8211; </strong></em>agree to meet in a public place for your first date.  It takes the pressure off and keeps expectations in line.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><em><strong>Don&#8217;t &#8211; </strong></em>worry about the presence of onlookers, or as some people call them, witnesses.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;padding-left:30px;">. _ . _ .</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><strong><em>Do -</em></strong> come up with a cute, catchy screen name for yourself, which reflects your interests and personality, like &#8220;<em>CatsMeow21</em>&#8221; or &#8220;<em>iLuvSunsetz365</em>&#8220;</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><em><strong>Don&#8217;t -</strong></em> choose a name which might have a negative connotation, like &#8221;<em>DeptOfCorrexuns3167239</em>&#8221; or &#8221;<em>iMakeLicPlates4u</em>&#8220;</p>
<p style="text-align:center;padding-left:30px;">. _ . _ .</p>
<p>Those are just a few of the thoughts I came up with so far.  I hope people find them helpful.  Hopefully by the time Christine gets back out on the dating scene, I&#8217;ll have a more comprehensive list of tips ready for her.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4697/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4697/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4697&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://1pointperspective.wordpress.com/2013/01/06/online-dating-advice-for-the-lovelorn/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>85</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/46d497df747b91d5354a4030f1f355a3?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">1pointperspective</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1pointperspective.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/datelessndallas-dot-com.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Step One: Rearrange the buttons on your keyboard to write cute things.  Step Two: Take a piocture of it! (Image from datelessndallas.com)</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8216;Ship-Creators of Mighty Bangladesh&#8217;</title>
		<link>http://gmbakash.wordpress.com/2013/01/13/ship-creators-of-mighty-bangladesh/</link>
		<comments>http://gmbakash.wordpress.com/2013/01/13/ship-creators-of-mighty-bangladesh/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2013 15:49:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Gmb Akash</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Survivors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bangladesh economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[climate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GMB Akash works on shipyard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photo stories on shipyard.]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography of asian shipyard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ship building in Bangladesh]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ship building stories of south asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shipyard labourer of asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shipyard of south asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shipyard workers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transportation]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://gmbakash.wordpress.com/?p=1063</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[“Steeping into the muddy shiphub my eyes stumble on barefooted children playing ‘Akka Dokka’. By following their queries giggles I smiled to the little-girl next to me asking ‘What to your father do’?  With a wide smile showing her recently missing baby teeth’s, she whispered ‘My father builds big big ships’. The place is familiar [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1063&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="center">
<p align="center"><b><i>“Steeping into the muddy shiphub my eyes stumble on barefooted children playing ‘Akka Dokka’. By following their queries giggles I smiled to the little-girl next to me asking ‘What to your father do’?  With a wide smile showing her recently missing baby teeth’s, she whispered ‘My father builds big big ships’. The place is familiar to me so as these children but I rejoice these moments every day when I jump from my boat and my day start with ‘big big ships’.  I walk towards to Ship Creators, to the people that the world knows little about. Step to them, who are building ships on a daily basis with their expertise, power, energy and who dream to make something big, bigger than their life, bigger than their identity, bigger than their credits without much expectation. ” </i></b></p>
<p align="center"><b><i>– GMB AKASH</i></b></p>
<p align="center">
<p align="center"><a href="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-18.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1064" alt="New final ship (18)" src="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-18.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p align="center"><a href="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-3.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1065" alt="New final ship (3)" src="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-3.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p align="center"><a href="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-8.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1066" alt="New final ship (8)" src="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-8.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><i>© GMB Akash</i></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>In the shipyard every worker is full of activity, no one have any time to talk. Constant work with flame, sound and dust may seem intolerable. Especially the constant ‘Dhang-Dhang-Dhang’ sounds of steel and hammer will auto upgrade any ones heart beat. But to the workers it’s their daily doze.  These Ship-craft-masters never get tired often handle everything in spite of getting any structural design keep building ships on their own effort with their basic genetic talent without any break. Frequently without goggles, risking serious injury or blindness, they all climb tall rope ladders to the ships&#8217; highest points to retrieve items, risking death if they slip but yet happily they keep working in the pleasure of building the ship</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-11.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1067" alt="New final ship (11)" src="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-11.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-17.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1068" alt="New final ship (17)" src="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-17.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1069" alt="New final ship (1)" src="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-1.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><i>© GMB Akash</i></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>Bangladesh is set to emerge as a new export leader for building small ships after cutting deals worth over $ 250 million last year alone. More than 250,000 skilled and semi-skilled workers are employed in the shipbuilding industry Bangladesh. All inland and coastal ships are constructed and repaired locally in these Bangladeshi shipyards. Bangladesh has all the ingredients to turn itself into a hub of export oriented shipbuilding for small and medium-sized vessels. The full utilization of the opportunities that are now present in the global shipbuilding market can turn this sector into a billion dollar industry within a decade. In recent times, a dozen shipyards are expanding their capacity for building ocean-going ships to enter the international market.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-10.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1070" alt="New final ship (10)" src="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-10.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-14.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1071" alt="New final ship (14)" src="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-14.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-19.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1072" alt="New final ship (19)" src="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-19.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><i>© GMB Akash</i></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><i>** (There are more than one hundred shipyards and workshops in Bangladesh, most of them are privately owned shipyards. Out of these shipyards, approximately 70 per cent are located in and around Dhaka and Narayanganj along the side of the river bank of Buriganga, Shitalakha and Meghna. About 20 per cent shipyards of Chittagong division are located along the side of the Karnapuli river and six per cent are located along the bank of the Poshur River in Khulna division while the remaining for per cent are located in Barisal division)</i></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1073" alt="New final ship (2)" src="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-2.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-6.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1074" alt="New final ship (6)" src="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-6.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-15.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1075" alt="New final ship (15)" src="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-15.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><i>© GMB Akash</i><b></b></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>Availability of cheap human input is the main strength of the country and this is one of the main determinants in allowing this labour intensive industry to flourish. Also, easily trainable workers can provide this country with a decisive edge over other prospective countries. Bangladesh is in very much an advantageous position in this respect as labour cost is the cheapest among other shipbuilding countries around the world. But it alleys not that only for livelihood these ship-creators give their labour to this industry. Their dream, their hope ties with it and it’s in their gene to build ships.  But the work is sporadic, and after paying the rent on the family&#8217;s tiny bamboo shack, workers has barely forty cents left to feed each of the family members. With no other options, workers usually sat their eldest son down in the work. An armature’s job would add $2.20 to the family&#8217;s daily budget. Still they build their hopes, build their ships with or without expectation.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-20.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1076" alt="New final ship (20)" src="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-20.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-21.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1083" alt="New final ship (21)" src="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-21.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-4.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1078" alt="New final ship (4)" src="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-4.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><i>© GMB Akash</i></p>
<p align="center"><b><i>Mishir Mia and his 25 member’s team seat silently beside the shipyard. After working two long years their team builds a world class ship. It will sail within short time. No one was answering my repeated questions. After a long break Mishir Mia said “Let me bring my son sir. I will show him the ship. He will become a marine engineer one day; then he will bravely share with friends that without any degree his father once built big big ships. Let me go Sir. I will answer you later.”  Team of 25 labours is sign of victory. It’s our victory. It’s Tribute to their bravery, their silent involvement in the economy. Aren’t we seeing a mighty Bangladesh? </i></b></p>
<p align="center"><b><i>– GMB Akash</i></b></p>
<p align="center">
<p align="center"><a href="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-13.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1079" alt="New final ship (13)" src="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-13.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p align="center"><a href="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-7.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1080" alt="New final ship (7)" src="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-7.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p align="center"><a href="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-12.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1082" alt="New final ship (12)" src="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-12.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p align="center"><i>© GMB Akash</i></p>
<p align="center">
<br /> Tagged: <a href='http://gmbakash.wordpress.com/tag/bangladesh-economy/'>Bangladesh economy</a>, <a href='http://gmbakash.wordpress.com/tag/climate/'>climate</a>, <a href='http://gmbakash.wordpress.com/tag/gmb-akash-works-on-shipyard/'>GMB Akash works on shipyard</a>, <a href='http://gmbakash.wordpress.com/tag/photo-stories-on-shipyard/'>Photo stories on shipyard.</a>, <a href='http://gmbakash.wordpress.com/tag/photography-of-asian-shipyard/'>photography of asian shipyard</a>, <a href='http://gmbakash.wordpress.com/tag/ship/'>ship</a>, <a href='http://gmbakash.wordpress.com/tag/ship-building-in-bangladesh/'>ship building in Bangladesh</a>, <a href='http://gmbakash.wordpress.com/tag/ship-building-stories-of-south-asia/'>ship building stories of south asia</a>, <a href='http://gmbakash.wordpress.com/tag/shipyard-labourer-of-asia/'>shipyard labourer of asia</a>, <a href='http://gmbakash.wordpress.com/tag/shipyard-of-south-asia/'>shipyard of south asia</a>, <a href='http://gmbakash.wordpress.com/tag/shipyard-workers/'>shipyard workers</a>, <a href='http://gmbakash.wordpress.com/tag/transportation/'>transportation</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1063/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1063/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1063/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1063/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1063/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1063/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1063/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1063/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1063/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1063/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1063/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1063/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1063/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1063/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1063&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://gmbakash.wordpress.com/2013/01/13/ship-creators-of-mighty-bangladesh/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>32</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/bd304d37acabe39b48231f64a398ac74?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">G.M.B.Akash</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-18.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">New final ship (18)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-3.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">New final ship (3)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-8.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">New final ship (8)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-11.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">New final ship (11)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-17.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">New final ship (17)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">New final ship (1)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-10.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">New final ship (10)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-14.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">New final ship (14)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-19.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">New final ship (19)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">New final ship (2)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-6.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">New final ship (6)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-15.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">New final ship (15)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-20.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">New final ship (20)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-21.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">New final ship (21)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-4.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">New final ship (4)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-13.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">New final ship (13)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-7.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">New final ship (7)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gmbakash.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/new-final-ship-12.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">New final ship (12)</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Faint Glimmer of Hope</title>
		<link>http://conceivingsolo.com/2013/01/13/a-faint-glimmer-of-hope/</link>
		<comments>http://conceivingsolo.com/2013/01/13/a-faint-glimmer-of-hope/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2013 10:51:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>lucinainhope</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Artificial insemination]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Autobiography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Donor conception]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IVF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lifestyle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Memoir]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Baby]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Choosing single motherhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Early pregnancy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Female empowerment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finding out you are pregnant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pregnancy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Solo mother by choice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trying to conceive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Women's rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writer]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://conceivingsolo.com/?p=317</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I am holding my future in my hands. Trembling fingers can barely rip open the plastic casing containing the thin strip that will show me whether I’m pregnant, or have just thrown away a chunk of life savings and my soul on failed IVF. My mouth goes dry and my heart starts into erratic bat-wing [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=317&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://conceivingsolo.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/heaven.jpg"><img src="http://conceivingsolo.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/heaven.jpg?w=300&#038;h=200" alt="Heaven" width="300" height="200" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-330" /></a></p>
<p>I am holding my future in my hands. </p>
<p>Trembling fingers can barely rip open the plastic casing containing the thin strip that will show me whether I’m pregnant, or have just thrown away a chunk of life savings and my soul on failed IVF.  </p>
<p>My mouth goes dry and my heart starts into erratic bat-wing thumps. I need to do this quickly before I start thinking too much, while I’m still groggy with sleep and this hazy dreamlike state is providing a buffer against reality. </p>
<p>I&#8217;m testing early, perhaps too early. Tomorrow (Monday, 14 days after embryo transfer) is the official testing date recommended by my fertility clinic but I know that I couldn’t face the second week of a new teaching job on the back of devastating news. Testing today will at least give me a few hours to try to come to terms with the result.</p>
<p>I’ve been hyper-sensitive to any bodily symptoms over the last two weeks. Most signs that herald early pregnancy can also be caused by the progesterone supplements taken after IVF, making it impossible to read too much into them. But yesterday my abdomen seemed alive with tweaks, spasms and pulls, which lasted all day. I began to wonder if my embryos were attaching to the womb lining or practising circus skills! Period-type pains, veiny breasts, ravenous hunger, heightened sense of smell and sore nipples also added to the series of promising signs. I couldn’t shake the belief I was pregnant. </p>
<p>The moment of truth… I dip the strip in urine and place it on my dressing table. I lie on my bed and let tears and prayers soak up the longest three minutes of my life.    </p>
<p>From a distance I see only the bold control line. Bitter bile rises to my throat, but when I bring the test closer and into focus I see a second line – faint but unquestionably there. <em>Positive!</em></p>
<p>The sobs flow freely. My legs buckle and I sink back down onto the bed. <em>Thank you, God. </em>I feel a wave of relief but fight the urge to get my hopes up just yet. I have a doctor’s appointment booked on Tuesday and will wait for the blood test results. I can’t relax until I’m sure this isn’t a false reading, or a chemical or ectopic pregnancy. And if I am pregnant, has only one embryo attached, or both? My mind is a tornado of questions and emotions, but the greatest of them all is hope. </p>
<p>It may be foolishly premature, but I order a &#8216;Baby on Board&#8217; badge from London Transport.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/317/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/317/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=317&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://conceivingsolo.com/2013/01/13/a-faint-glimmer-of-hope/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>55</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/e7854b2c2beaa4eb9b21ee5d577c9e53?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lucinainhope</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://conceivingsolo.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/heaven.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Heaven</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mi-chemin; at the Intersection of Tradition and Modernity</title>
		<link>http://lizguerra.wordpress.com/2012/12/14/mi-chemin-at-the-intersection-of-tradition-and-modernity/</link>
		<comments>http://lizguerra.wordpress.com/2012/12/14/mi-chemin-at-the-intersection-of-tradition-and-modernity/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2012 16:42:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>lizguerra</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Morocco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Middle East]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://lizguerra.wordpress.com/?p=863</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;Morocco is&#8230;,&#8221; is a  statement I try to avoid making, because it is cumbersome, stereotypical, and leaves no room for the brilliance of our imagination and the diversity of reality. Frankly, I don&#8217;t know what  Morocco is  at all. There are so many different Morocco&#8217;s, as each person lives and experiences this country in a different [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=863&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;Morocco is&#8230;,&#8221; is a  statement I try to avoid making, because it is cumbersome, stereotypical, and leaves no room for the brilliance of our imagination and the diversity of reality. Frankly, I don&#8217;t know what  Morocco <em>is </em> at all. There are so many different Morocco&#8217;s, as each person lives and experiences this country in a different manner.</p>
<p>I live my life on what the French call &#8220;mi-chemin,&#8221; which literally translates to &#8220;mid path.&#8221; I love the idea of always being mi-chemin &#8212; on a journey &#8212; somewhere in the in between. But I also think that this word can translate  to an intersection or the crossing of two paths. In this case, I&#8217;m also living at an intersection; one of culture and identity, and more specifically, one of tradition and modernity.</p>
<p>Recently, I&#8217;ve begun observing a fascinating juxtaposition between tradition and modernity. The more I think about it, the more aware I am of how these two worlds weave their way through the lives of those who call Morocco home. Tradition <em>versus</em> modernity? Not neccesarily. It&#8217;s not completely a versus &#8212; not black and white. Rather, it&#8217;s more of a mi-chemin. An intersection.</p>
<p>At this point I find myself with the necessity of defining modernity and tradition. This is a feat in itself, and one I do not wish to over simplify. Therefore, instead of defining it, I will give you examples of how I have experienced these these criss-crossing worlds.</p>
<p><a href="http://lizguerra.wordpress.com/2012/12/14/mi-chemin-at-the-intersection-of-tradition-and-modernity/rabat01/" rel="attachment wp-att-870"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-870" alt="rabat01" src="http://lizguerra.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/rabat01.jpeg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>1. A donkey on the tram</p>
<p>A friend recently told me he saw a man trying to bring his donkey onto the tram. The tram, which runs two lines across Rabat, is the very essence of modernity for this city. Not only does it look like a silvery gray spaceship, but for a minimal price you can conveniently commute across town. When he told me about what he saw, I laughed because it was simultaneously ridiculous and exactly the kind of thing that would happen here. The donkey, of course, is a symbol of tradition; it&#8217;s the very antithesis of rapid, convenient technology. And yet, these two worlds collided mi-chemin as this brilliant man attempted to coax his ass onto the tram. I don&#8217;t blame him for trying.</p>
<p>2. Micky D&#8217;s and conterfeits</p>
<p>Commercial colonization has penetrated itself into Morocco. That&#8217;s to say, those who can afford Western name brands, which include both fast food chains and clothing stores, are gung-ho. McDonald&#8217;s, for example, is one of the most adored restaurants in this city. It&#8217;s posh and American and oh-so-fantastically modern. It&#8217;s always chock-full of customers dressed to the nines. Right down Avenue Mohammed V, where McDonald&#8217;s and big stores flamboyantly boast their presence, there&#8217;s the medina &#8212; the old city. Where a westerner such as myself feels like they&#8217;ve stepped backwards in time. It&#8217;s bustling and chaotic and noisy and the informal economy reigns supreme. Vendors sell their goods from stalls or in the streets and anything is possible if your patient and willing to haggle. The informal aspect of the economy  is what I consider to be the keeper of tradition in the medina and throughout Morocco. Though McDonald&#8217;s hasn&#8217;t stamped its name in the Medina (yet), many other name brands can be informally purchased there. So friends, place your orders for the newest software and technology, because copyrights do not exist in Morocco. You can purchase the most expensive up-to-date products for a fraction of the cost in the Medina. A true (and amazing) intersection of tradition and modernity.</p>
<p>3. A Moroccan wedding</p>
<p>Last weekend I attended a &#8220;traditional&#8221; Moroccan wedding. I was a guest of the brother of the groom, and he advised that I wear the traditional costume, a takcheta. All the women would be wearing one, and I would stand out  if I wasn&#8217;t properly garbed. It was fun, and I felt a bit like my 7 year old self, as I dressed up in my princess gown for the ball. Upon arrival, it was clear that I had made the right decision to wear the takcheta. All the women were decked out. But as I looked around the room, there was one lone man wearing the traditional white jalaba. Every other man was wearing his nicest suit and tie. Again, an intermingling of old and new.  The fashion here in Morocco, is very much a melange of these two narratives. You see both men and women wearing traditional Moroccan clothes, as well as those who wear western name brands. They are not mutually exclusive, however, and many people mix it up depending on the day. I, myself, have been on the hunt for a jalaba and I just purchased my very first pair of babouche slippers. I have a feeling they will soon become a staple in my wardrobe.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://lizguerra.wordpress.com/2012/12/14/mi-chemin-at-the-intersection-of-tradition-and-modernity/297583_3916979293870_1136540551_n/" rel="attachment wp-att-869"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-869" alt="297583_3916979293870_1136540551_n" src="http://lizguerra.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/297583_3916979293870_1136540551_n.jpeg?w=420&#038;h=560" width="420" height="560" /></a></p>
<p>It doesn&#8217;t feel abnormal to me. In fact, I actually think that it&#8217;s really cool that Moroccans have found  so many ways to retain their heritage while simultaneously transitioning between the stark and contrasting worlds of tradition and modernity.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/863/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/863/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=863&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://lizguerra.wordpress.com/2012/12/14/mi-chemin-at-the-intersection-of-tradition-and-modernity/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/e9bb3bb69f689086c302e0e02318cd45?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lizguerra</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lizguerra.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/rabat01.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">rabat01</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lizguerra.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/297583_3916979293870_1136540551_n.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">297583_3916979293870_1136540551_n</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
