<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2013 21:02:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>A Poem to All My Fellow Insomniatic Writers.</title>
		<link>http://tismond.wordpress.com/2013/01/09/a-poem-to-all-my-fellow-insomniatic-writers/</link>
		<comments>http://tismond.wordpress.com/2013/01/09/a-poem-to-all-my-fellow-insomniatic-writers/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2013 01:40:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tismond</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Poetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Creative writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[insomnia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[late night]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[night]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sleep]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tismond.wordpress.com/?p=333</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[If you&#8217;ve ever found yourself writing your best work during what the normal folk call &#8220;ungodly hours&#8221; then I think you&#8217;ll agree with me on this one: The Unobserved Hour The clock strikes three                                           [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=333&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you&#8217;ve ever found yourself writing your best work during what the normal folk call &#8220;ungodly hours&#8221; then I think you&#8217;ll agree with me on this one:</p>
<p>The Unobserved Hour</p>
<p>The clock strikes three                                                                                                                      A time where logic loses its edge                                                                                                     And the conscious mind free falls                                                                                                  Off the edge of sanity,</p>
<p>Where the burdened brain shatters                                                                                           And impossibilities merge with reality                                                                                       Into a kaleidoscope so obscene                                                                                                           That only cold dreamers can perceive:</p>
<p>They watch our long caged desires                                                                                                    Transcend the laws of religion                                                                                                    Tear through the holes of science                                                                                                   And past the prison of society</p>
<p>To a place where none shall judge you                                                                                          No inferno to sway your conscience                                                                                                All boundaries removed and banished                                                                                            So creativity shall reign supreme</p>
<p>This is the hour of lovers                                                                                                                All poets and artists to be                                                                                                                 Once bound by the chains of reason                                                                                                 Now freed from their slavery.</p>
<p>A.C.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/333/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/333/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=333&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tismond.wordpress.com/2013/01/09/a-poem-to-all-my-fellow-insomniatic-writers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>17</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tismond.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/coastatnight72.jpeg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tismond.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/coastatnight72.jpeg?w=150" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/fdbee1b98a5247cc0812eb046755fd5b?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tismond</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Good Writing Matters</title>
		<link>http://neurotaylor.com/2013/01/09/why-good-writing-matters/</link>
		<comments>http://neurotaylor.com/2013/01/09/why-good-writing-matters/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2013 09:56:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>neurotaylor</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[language]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[neuroscience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[skills]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://neurotaylor.com/?p=894</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Years ago now, I recall a senior scientist who&#8217;d read a piece of my work saying doubtfully, &#8216;It&#8217;s very well-written. Very literary.&#8217; The implication was clear: &#8216;But is it good science?&#8217; With hindsight, I can agree: that particular effort wasn&#8217;t ace. I can&#8217;t even remember its title, and the obscurity&#8217;s well-deserved. What did stick was [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=894&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://neurotaylor.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/writing-hand.jpg"><img class="size-thumbnail wp-image-917 " alt="A hand about to write" src="http://neurotaylor.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/writing-hand.jpg?w=150&#038;h=112" width="150" height="112" /></a></p>
<p>Years ago now, I recall a senior scientist who&#8217;d read a piece of my work saying doubtfully, &#8216;It&#8217;s very well-written. Very <em>literary</em>.&#8217; The implication was clear: &#8216;But is it good science?&#8217;</p>
<p>With hindsight, I can agree: that particular effort wasn&#8217;t ace. I can&#8217;t even remember its title, and the obscurity&#8217;s well-deserved. What did stick was my surprise that my colleague (undoubtedly a good scientist) saw good science and good writing as not just independent, but even perhaps opposed, since science is all about precision and language is irretrievably vague.</p>
<p>Years later, I still have a problem with this.<span id="more-894"></span></p>
<p>The problem for science is that the vast majority of scientific communication, even within the fraternity, uses language, not mathematics.  The better they write, the clearer their message. The more equations, the fewer people read them and cite them, <a title="Equations impede communication paper" href="http://www.pnas.org/content/109/29/11735.abstract" target="_blank">at least in my research field, biology</a>. Science, as we keep being told, needs good communication.</p>
<p>If you think language is vague, you may (incorrectly) infer that how scientists write their abstracts and articles doesn&#8217;t matter. It does. A poorly-written abstract can be ambiguous, confusing and at times incomprehensible. Yet in science training, writing skills can be downplayed, or even seen as suspicious. Media dons have good writing skills, you know.</p>
<p>Hmm. Sure, language isn&#8217;t mathematics. Thank goodness, it&#8217;s much richer and more flexible. But even though individual word meanings aren&#8217;t rigidly defined, they can be combined with surprising subtlety. A simple example: Microsoft Word assures me that &#8216;pleasant&#8217; and &#8216;pleasurable&#8217; are synonyms &#8212; i.e. they mean the same thing &#8212; but they don&#8217;t. Saying to your lover &#8216;Sex with you&#8217;s so pleasant&#8217; is less complimentary than &#8216;Sex with you&#8217;s so pleasurable&#8217;. For another example, think about the difference between &#8216;Microsoft Word assures me&#8217; and my first choice, &#8216;Microsoft Word tells me&#8217;, when it comes to deciding how much faith to place in MS Word.</p>
<p><strong>A science example</strong></p>
<p>Here&#8217;s an instance from the research literature: an abstract of a <a title="Dannlowski et al article" href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0006322311010213" target="_blank">2012 article</a> by Dannlowski <em>et al.</em> in <em><a class="zem_slink" title="Biological Psychiatry" href="http://www.sobp.org/journal" target="_blank" rel="homepage">Biological Psychiatry</a></em>. It&#8217;s not a bad abstract; I&#8217;ve come across far worse. It does however show how language can affect understanding.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><span style="color:#0000ff;">Childhood maltreatment represents a strong risk factor for the development of depression and posttraumatic stress disorder (PTSD) in later life. In the present study, we investigated the neurobiological underpinnings of this association.</span></p>
<p>Nice clear opening statement. But &#8230; which association? Between maltreatment and depression, maltreatment and PTSD, or both? I&#8217;m already unclear what&#8217;s being argued here; depression ≠ PTSD.</p>
<p>Hmm. So I&#8217;ll guess it means both.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><span style="color:#0000ff;">Since both depression and PTSD have been associated with increased amygdala responsiveness to negative stimuli as well as reduced hippocampal gray matter volume, we speculated that childhood maltreatment results in similar functional and structural alterations in previously maltreated but healthy adults.</span></p>
<p>So depression and PTSD are associated with a) more amygdala responsiveness (a functional difference) and b) less hippocampal gray matter (a structural difference), but it&#8217;s ambiguous as to whether a) and b) are themselves associated.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><span style="color:#0000ff;">One hundred forty-eight healthy subjects were enrolled via public notices and newspaper announcements and were carefully screened for psychiatric disorders.</span></p>
<p>The word &#8216;carefully&#8217; here has the unintended effect of making me wonder why the authors felt they needed to put it there. Who writes, &#8216;Our screening was pretty crap, we just ticked a few boxes&#8217;? I&#8217;m now a smidgen less inclined to trust this research.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><span style="color:#0000ff;">Amygdala responsiveness was measured by means of functional magnetic resonance imaging and an emotional face-matching paradigm particularly designed to activate the amygdala in response to threat-related faces. Voxel-based morphometry was used to study morphological alterations.</span></p>
<p>What sort of threat? Anger, disgust, a knife gripped between the teeth? And &#8212; morphological alterations? Why not say &#8216;gray matter changes&#8217; if that&#8217;s what you mean? Or &#8216;structural changes&#8217;, to make the link with earlier sentences transparent. It&#8217;s also easier to read. I like the idea of an emotional paradigm, though, stuck in the corner sulkily matching faces.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><span style="color:#0000ff;">Childhood maltreatment was assessed by the 25-item Childhood Trauma Questionnaire (CTQ). We observed a strong association of CTQ scores with amygdala responsiveness to threat-related facial expressions.</span></p>
<p>Right. This tells me the functional result, and now I want to find out more about the control conditions, and I&#8217;m curious as to whether the CTQ&#8217;s any good, so I&#8217;m more likely to read the article. Now for the structural result:</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><span style="color:#0000ff;">The morphometric analysis yielded reduced gray matter volumes in the hippocampus, insula, orbitofrontal cortex, anterior cingulate gyrus, and caudate in subjects with high CTQ scores. Both of these associations were not influenced by trait anxiety, depression level, age, intelligence, education, or more recent stressful life events.</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">Both of what? Guys, you lost me. I&#8217;m reading about associations between high CTQ scores and <strong>five</strong> brain regions. So &#8212; retracking here &#8212; maybe &#8216;both&#8217; means &#8216;both the functional and structural associations&#8217;? </span><span style="color:#000000;">And what does &#8216;depression level&#8217; mean &#8212; now, over the past year, or what? Too much neurotransmitter got used decoding these sentences.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><span style="color:#0000ff;">Childhood maltreatment is associated with remarkable functional and structural changes even decades later in adulthood. These changes strongly resemble findings described in depression and PTSD. Therefore, the present results might suggest that limbic hyperresponsiveness and reduced hippocampal volumes could be mediators between the experiences of adversities during childhood and the development of emotional disorders.</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">I thought participants were screened to be free of such disorders? Or are they just not reaching the required clinical thresholds? And, eek, that stretch from &#8216;amygdala&#8217; to &#8216;limbic&#8217;! </span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">All in all, I&#8217;m confused, and that makes me feel stupid, and as if I&#8217;ve already wasted too much time on this abstract. There&#8217;s an <a title="Reconsolidation article" href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0006322311010419" target="_blank">interesting-looking piece on reconsolidation</a> in the same table of contents. I think I&#8217;ll read that instead &#8230;</span></p>
<p><strong>Clarity matters</strong></p>
<p>In the fierce competition for readers&#8217; attention, clarity is crucial &#8212; and clarity comes from using language well. Ease of reading is also important, because I (and I suspect most readers) are less inclined to struggle through an abstract, let alone a whole paper, if the authors make it hard work. I like to read in a smooth, fast flow, sucking up meaning without having to stop and think about how to interpret every sentence; if I wanted that kind of intellectual workout I&#8217;d read French. Translating from science into English can be quite hard enough even if the writing&#8217;s limpidly transparent, given the jargon and surfeit of acronyms.</p>
<p>Of course, language can also be used to create deliberate ambiguity, as in the apocryphal job reference, &#8216;You would indeed be lucky to get this person to work for you&#8217;.</p>
<p>Words can also be used to trigger particular ideas without saying so explicitly, as in &#8216;that particular effort wasn&#8217;t ace&#8217; (implying that all the others were). These and other skills come with good writing, and allow the writer to be remarkably adept at putting across ideas. Indeed, one problem with mathematics is that it can convey a false sense of clarity and hence security, as all those failed economic models should have taught us.</p>
<p>Even foggy language, as in government or scientific jargon, can be skilfully and carefully unclear if the aim is to obfuscate &#8212; as when a politician claims to have <strong>refuted</strong> an argument (destroyed its force) when all they&#8217;ve done is <strong>rebutted</strong> it (argued against it, unsuccessfully in the case I&#8217;m remembering).</p>
<p>Then again, it may just be that the person is inept, or isn&#8217;t quite sure what exactly they&#8217;re trying to say. Writing is a great way to sort out thoughts. And a skilful writer has more armour against the linguistic trickery of others, another reason for learning to write well.</p>
<p><strong>Accuracy matters</strong></p>
<p>On a different level from the slightly prickly abstract above is simple abuse. Language-lovers get extremely frustrated by common linguistic slopperies, like the following horror from the BBC, who should know better:</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">(of a dead soldier) &#8216;if he&#8217;d had the equipment, he may have survived&#8217;</p>
<p>NO! &#8216;may&#8217; ≠ &#8216;might&#8217;! The whole point is he DIDN&#8217;T survive! I hope the grieving family didn&#8217;t hear that insensitive report.</p>
<p>Language-lovers understand that putting words in order can be a counterproductive mess, a workaday chore, or a useful and beautiful craft. Like athletes, they aim to use their skills as best they can because, basically, why settle for mediocre when you can do better? That athletes are more admired is unfortunate for writers trying to make a career of it, but like science, writing&#8217;s more a compulsion than a career choice. Seeing the gift of language wasted makes skilled wordsmiths wince, just as a pianist might wince on seeing a Steinway grand being bashed about. Why have such a powerful language-enabled brain if you&#8217;re going to use its powers so poorly, just to get by, leaving yourself open to manipulation and blind to the fabulous riches of your linguistic heritage? Besides, as hobbies go wordplay&#8217;s a good choice for these fearful and thrifty times: safer than swordplay, easier than foreplay, and cheaper than gameplay.</p>
<p>Setting feelings aside, however, clear and fluent language is hugely important to communication. For that reason alone it&#8217;s worth trying to do it better. In science, as elsewhere, good writing matters.</p>
<div id="nuan_ria_plugin"></div>
<div id="nuan_ria_plugin"></div>
<div id="nuan_ria_plugin"></div>
<div id="nuan_ria_plugin"></div>
<div id="nuan_ria_plugin"></div>
<div id="nuan_ria_plugin"></div>
<div id="nuan_ria_plugin"></div>
<div id="nuan_ria_plugin"></div>
<div id="nuan_ria_plugin"></div>
<div id="nuan_ria_plugin"></div>
<div id="nuan_ria_plugin"></div>
<div id="nuan_ria_plugin"></div>
<div id="nuan_ria_plugin"></div>
<div id="nuan_ria_plugin"></div>
<div id="nuan_ria_plugin"></div>
<div id="nuan_ria_plugin"></div>
<div id="nuan_ria_plugin"></div>
<div id="nuan_ria_plugin"></div>
<div id="nuan_ria_plugin"></div>
<div id="nuan_ria_plugin"></div>
<div id="nuan_ria_plugin"></div>
<div id="nuan_ria_plugin"></div>
<div id="nuan_ria_plugin"></div>
<div id="nuan_ria_plugin"></div>
<div id="nuan_ria_plugin"></div>
<div id="nuan_ria_plugin"></div>
<div id="nuan_ria_plugin"></div>
<div id="nuan_ria_plugin"></div>
<div id="nuan_ria_plugin"></div>
<div id="nuan_ria_plugin"></div>
<div id="nuan_ria_plugin"></div>
<div id="nuan_ria_plugin"></div>
<div id="nuan_ria_plugin"></div>
<div id="nuan_ria_plugin"></div>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=894&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://neurotaylor.com/2013/01/09/why-good-writing-matters/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/48618d13694c557c2424d87fa6a32373?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">neurotaylor</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://neurotaylor.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/writing-hand.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">A hand about to write</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8221; The Thread That Connects Us All &#8220;</title>
		<link>http://mikepillowsphoto.wordpress.com/2013/01/04/the-thread-that-connects-us-all/</link>
		<comments>http://mikepillowsphoto.wordpress.com/2013/01/04/the-thread-that-connects-us-all/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2013 05:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>MikeP</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[SJ MeetUp Group]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Workshop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Factory]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[HDR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[history]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Klotz Throwing Co.]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lonaconing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MD]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photo essay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Silk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[silk factory]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Textile]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mikepillowsphoto.wordpress.com/?p=1092</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I was treated to an early gift this season&#8230; it was a dusty, old, dark, and very magical treat to this photographer’s eyes. The present I am referring to, was my visit to the last intact silk mill left in the US. Built in  1907, and known as Klotz Throwing Company, it is located in [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1092&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_1093" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 496px"><a href="http://mikepillowsphoto.wordpress.com/2013/01/04/the-thread-that-connects-us-all/slikmill-blog-6/" rel="attachment wp-att-1093"><img class=" wp-image-1093    " style="border:7px solid white;" alt="&quot;To Walk a Mile in...&quot;" src="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/slikmill-blog-6.jpg?w=486&#038;h=324" width="486" height="324" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">&#8220;To Walk a Mile in&#8230;&#8221;</p></div>
<p>I was treated to an early gift this season&#8230; it was a dusty, old, dark, and very magical treat to this photographer’s eyes. The present I am referring to, was my visit to the last intact silk mill left in the US. Built in  1907, and known as <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;v=AQxLEC6VAIc#!">Klotz Throwing Company</a>, it is located in <a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?q=Lonaconing,+MD&amp;hl=en&amp;sll=40.07304,-74.724323&amp;sspn=7.085694,10.480957&amp;oq=Loanaconing,MD&amp;hnear=Lonaconing,+Allegany,+Maryland&amp;t=m&amp;z=15">Lonaconing, MD</a> which is about a five and a half hour drive from where I live.</p>
<p>On rare occasions, you can feel a presence of history in a place. I felt it instantly, when I set foot inside this mill. What also set the mood was the ambient light I had to work in.  The smell and feel of a past life lets your thoughts drift back to when it was a booming factory. Seeing the thousands of spools, and their links to the machinery, led you to actually imagine the sounds and visualize the people who had worked on the factory floor.</p>
<p>Throwing, as used in the name of the mill, constituted pulling and twisting the raw material into a thread that was used in the making of garments and later parachutes. By the 1920’s, the mill employed 359 workers. Just imagining that many people in the factory, made you realize how it must have been an incredibly busy place. The town alone, with its tiny twisting streets, seemed to be developed and tied to a company mindset where everything and everyone relied on the factory. A railroad passed through the center of town which helps to better understand its location since, WV coal mines were not very far down the road. Klotz Throwing Co.,  just like the Nation, went from feast to famine during the depression which was closely followed by WW II.</p>
<p>The mill went through a number of growing spurts that saw sanctions on raw silk from Japan, which almost closed the facility, to the start of a synthetic silk called rayon. By the 1950’s, silk demand was dwindling and the workers’ pay had also declined. In 1957, due to the poverty level of wages, they decided to strike and without warning, the owners closed the factory. The mill was shut down so quickly that to this day when you arrive on the second floor, you can still find a room with bins of shoes and other personal belongings. This sudden abandonment lends to the atmosphere of human trauma and decay that you can still feel permeates the building.</p>
<p>We see it throughout our nation&#8230; factories and businesses, both large and small are closing. Like a spider’s web, each thread spun is interconnected and leads to the center. The heart of our society is also woven one thread at a time. That thread of life is not just a single factory in Lonaconing but also one that connects us to each of the families that worked there. This emotion is as prevalent today as it was on that factory floor, where each incomplete severed piece of silk thread represents a family&#8217;s hopelessness&#8230;. or rebirth.</p>

<a href='http://mikepillowsphoto.wordpress.com/2013/01/04/the-thread-that-connects-us-all/slikmill-blog-sml/' title='slikmill blog sml'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="1138" data-orig-file="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml.jpg" data-orig-size="600,400" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;16&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;Canon EOS 5D Mark II&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1355054442&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;28&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;200&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="slikmill blog sml" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml.jpg?w=590" width="150" height="100" src="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml.jpg?w=150&#038;h=100" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="&quot;Ghosts of Silks Past&quot;" /></a>
<a href='http://mikepillowsphoto.wordpress.com/2013/01/04/the-thread-that-connects-us-all/slikmill-blog-sml-8/' title='slikmill blog sml-8'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="1133" data-orig-file="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-8.jpg" data-orig-size="391,600" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;16&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;Canon EOS 5D Mark II&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1355065650&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;16&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;800&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="slikmill blog sml-8" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-8.jpg?w=195" data-large-file="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-8.jpg?w=384" width="97" height="150" src="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-8.jpg?w=97&#038;h=150" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="slikmill blog sml-8" /></a>
<a href='http://mikepillowsphoto.wordpress.com/2013/01/04/the-thread-that-connects-us-all/slikmill-blog-sml-3/' title='slikmill blog sml-3'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="1128" data-orig-file="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-3.jpg" data-orig-size="600,400" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;16&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;Canon EOS 5D Mark II&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1355057990&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;35&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;200&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="slikmill blog sml-3" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-3.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-3.jpg?w=590" width="150" height="100" src="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-3.jpg?w=150&#038;h=100" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="&quot;A Bygone Time&quot;" /></a>
<a href='http://mikepillowsphoto.wordpress.com/2013/01/04/the-thread-that-connects-us-all/slikmill-blog-sml-2/' title='slikmill blog sml-2'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="1127" data-orig-file="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-2.jpg" data-orig-size="600,383" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;16&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;Canon EOS 5D Mark II&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1355057260&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;35&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;200&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="slikmill blog sml-2" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-2.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-2.jpg?w=590" width="150" height="95" src="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-2.jpg?w=150&#038;h=95" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="slikmill blog sml-2" /></a>
<a href='http://mikepillowsphoto.wordpress.com/2013/01/04/the-thread-that-connects-us-all/slikmill-blog-sml-4/' title='slikmill blog sml-4'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="1129" data-orig-file="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-4.jpg" data-orig-size="600,471" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;2.8&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;Canon EOS 5D Mark II&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1355060406&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;35&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;200&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0.3&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="slikmill blog sml-4" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-4.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-4.jpg?w=590" width="150" height="117" src="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-4.jpg?w=150&#038;h=117" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="slikmill blog sml-4" /></a>
<a href='http://mikepillowsphoto.wordpress.com/2013/01/04/the-thread-that-connects-us-all/slikmill-blog-sml-5/' title='slikmill blog sml-5'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="1130" data-orig-file="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-5.jpg" data-orig-size="600,400" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;16&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;Canon EOS 5D Mark II&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1355062682&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;18&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;800&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;8&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="slikmill blog sml-5" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-5.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-5.jpg?w=590" width="150" height="100" src="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-5.jpg?w=150&#038;h=100" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="slikmill blog sml-5" /></a>
<a href='http://mikepillowsphoto.wordpress.com/2013/01/04/the-thread-that-connects-us-all/slikmill-blog-sml-6/' title='slikmill blog sml-6'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="1131" data-orig-file="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-6.jpg" data-orig-size="600,400" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;16&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;Canon EOS 5D Mark II&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1355064751&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;35&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;200&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;15&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="slikmill blog sml-6" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-6.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-6.jpg?w=590" width="150" height="100" src="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-6.jpg?w=150&#038;h=100" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="slikmill blog sml-6" /></a>
<a href='http://mikepillowsphoto.wordpress.com/2013/01/04/the-thread-that-connects-us-all/slikmill-blog-sml-7/' title='slikmill blog sml-7'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="1132" data-orig-file="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-7.jpg" data-orig-size="600,401" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;16&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;Canon EOS 5D Mark II&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1355065479&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;16&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;800&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="slikmill blog sml-7" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-7.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-7.jpg?w=590" width="150" height="100" src="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-7.jpg?w=150&#038;h=100" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="slikmill blog sml-7" /></a>
<a href='http://mikepillowsphoto.wordpress.com/2013/01/04/the-thread-that-connects-us-all/slikmill-blog-sml-9/' title='slikmill blog sml-9'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="1134" data-orig-file="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-9.jpg" data-orig-size="418,600" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;16&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;Canon EOS 5D Mark II&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1355067094&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;35&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;800&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;15&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="slikmill blog sml-9" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-9.jpg?w=209" data-large-file="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-9.jpg?w=411" width="104" height="150" src="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-9.jpg?w=104&#038;h=150" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="slikmill blog sml-9" /></a>
<a href='http://mikepillowsphoto.wordpress.com/2013/01/04/the-thread-that-connects-us-all/slikmill-blog-sml-10/' title='slikmill blog sml-10'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="1135" data-orig-file="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-10.jpg" data-orig-size="400,600" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;16&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;Canon EOS 5D Mark II&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1355067264&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;31&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;800&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="slikmill blog sml-10" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-10.jpg?w=200" data-large-file="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-10.jpg?w=393" width="100" height="150" src="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-10.jpg?w=100&#038;h=150" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="slikmill blog sml-10" /></a>
<a href='http://mikepillowsphoto.wordpress.com/2013/01/04/the-thread-that-connects-us-all/slikmill-blog-sml-11/' title='slikmill blog sml-11'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="1136" data-orig-file="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-11.jpg" data-orig-size="600,400" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;16&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;Canon EOS 5D Mark II&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1355067899&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;35&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;800&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="slikmill blog sml-11" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-11.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-11.jpg?w=590" width="150" height="100" src="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-11.jpg?w=150&#038;h=100" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="slikmill blog sml-11" /></a>
<a href='http://mikepillowsphoto.wordpress.com/2013/01/04/the-thread-that-connects-us-all/slikmill-blog-sml-12/' title='slikmill blog sml-12'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="1137" data-orig-file="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-12.jpg" data-orig-size="600,354" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;16&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;Canon EOS 5D Mark II&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1355068005&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;35&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;800&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;30&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="slikmill blog sml-12" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-12.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-12.jpg?w=590" width="150" height="88" src="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-12.jpg?w=150&#038;h=88" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="slikmill blog sml-12" /></a>

<br />Filed under: <a href='http://mikepillowsphoto.wordpress.com/category/sj-meetup-group/'>SJ MeetUp Group</a>, <a href='http://mikepillowsphoto.wordpress.com/category/travel/'>Travel</a>, <a href='http://mikepillowsphoto.wordpress.com/category/workshop/'>Workshop</a> Tagged: <a href='http://mikepillowsphoto.wordpress.com/tag/factory/'>Factory</a>, <a href='http://mikepillowsphoto.wordpress.com/tag/hdr/'>HDR</a>, <a href='http://mikepillowsphoto.wordpress.com/tag/history/'>history</a>, <a href='http://mikepillowsphoto.wordpress.com/tag/klotz-throwing-co/'>Klotz Throwing Co.</a>, <a href='http://mikepillowsphoto.wordpress.com/tag/lonaconing/'>Lonaconing</a>, <a href='http://mikepillowsphoto.wordpress.com/tag/md/'>MD</a>, <a href='http://mikepillowsphoto.wordpress.com/tag/photo-essay/'>photo essay</a>, <a href='http://mikepillowsphoto.wordpress.com/tag/photography/'>Photography</a>, <a href='http://mikepillowsphoto.wordpress.com/tag/silk/'>Silk</a>, <a href='http://mikepillowsphoto.wordpress.com/tag/silk-factory/'>silk factory</a>, <a href='http://mikepillowsphoto.wordpress.com/tag/textile/'>Textile</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1092/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1092/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1092&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://mikepillowsphoto.wordpress.com/2013/01/04/the-thread-that-connects-us-all/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>48</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/05ee9ae66b9077dbd71f20fab27fe09d?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F0.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">photomike209</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/slikmill-blog-6.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">&#34;To Walk a Mile in...&#34;</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">&#34;Ghosts of Silks Past&#34;</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-8.jpg?w=97" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">slikmill blog sml-8</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-3.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">&#34;A Bygone Time&#34;</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-2.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">slikmill blog sml-2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-4.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">slikmill blog sml-4</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-5.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">slikmill blog sml-5</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-6.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">slikmill blog sml-6</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-7.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">slikmill blog sml-7</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-9.jpg?w=104" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">slikmill blog sml-9</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-10.jpg?w=100" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">slikmill blog sml-10</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-11.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">slikmill blog sml-11</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mikepillowsphoto.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/slikmill-blog-sml-12.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">slikmill blog sml-12</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Wake and Wander’s ‘Holy S**t Moments’ of 2012</title>
		<link>http://wakeandwander.com/2013/01/02/wake-and-wanders-holy-shit-moments-of-2012/</link>
		<comments>http://wakeandwander.com/2013/01/02/wake-and-wanders-holy-shit-moments-of-2012/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2013 19:45:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Will McGough</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adventure travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alaska]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Arizona]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aspen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bahamas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[camping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Colorado]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Conundrum Hot Springs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy vortexes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Exuma Islands]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hiking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ice canoe racing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lake Ohrid]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Macedonia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Maho Bay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ohrid]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quebec City]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Royal Caribbean]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sedona]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[St. Maarten]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[swimming with pigs]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://wakeandwander.com/?p=3418</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I made a comment yesterday at a New Year&#8217;s Day party in Philadelphia (during the Mummer&#8217;s Parade) that incited laughter and resulted in being labeled as an &#8220;old man,&#8221; but I&#8217;ll say it again here because it&#8217;s one of the truest things I know: Life goes faster and faster every year, and there&#8217;s not a [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3418&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I made a comment yesterday at a New Year&#8217;s Day party in Philadelphia (during the Mummer&#8217;s Parade) that incited laughter and resulted in being labeled as an &#8220;old man,&#8221; but I&#8217;ll say it again here because it&#8217;s one of the truest things I know: Life goes faster and faster every year, and there&#8217;s not a damn thing we can do but enjoy the hell out of every inch of it.</p>
<p>When I first announced that I would write this piece and <a href="http://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=467445186634854&amp;set=a.257964074249634.60658.190957710950271&amp;type=1&amp;theater" target="_blank">asked others for their &#8220;holy shit moments&#8221; of the year</a>, everybody started spouting off about negative or scary experiences. Those are well and good and definitely memorable, but a holy shit moment doesn&#8217;t have to be terrifying &#8212; they can, as you&#8217;ll see from mine, be quite beautiful.</p>
<p>I thank everyone who has been a part of this year, friends and family and colleagues and all those I&#8217;ve been fortunate enough to meet along the way. I&#8217;ve told you before I have a knack for using the holidays as a life reference point of comparison and the new year certainly has a lot to live up to given how great 2012 turned out to be. Writing this piece and going through all the photos and stories was a perfect reminder of how much fun I had and all the things I was able to experience. Cheers to that.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve linked to stories and videos throughout this article in case you&#8217;d like to dig a bit deeper and read more about one of the moments that made the list. Here they are, my Holy Shit Moments of 2012, in no specific order:</p>
<p><b>Swimming with Pigs on the Exuma Islands in the Bahamas:</b></p>
<p><a href="http://wakeandwander.com/2013/01/02/wake-and-wanders-holy-shit-moments-of-2012/img_82712/" rel="attachment wp-att-14055"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-14055" alt="IMG_82712" src="http://willmcgough.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_82712.jpg?w=640&#038;h=426" width="640" height="426" /></a></p>
<p>Okay, I’m cheating – it was just before the year turned last November &#8212; but I didn’t do one of these recaps last year (I did countdown <a href="http://wakeandwander.com/travel/top-happy-hour-spots-of-2011/" target="_blank">my top happy hour spots of 2011</a>, though). We’ll start fresh with those rules next year. This was too excellent of a moment to leave off the inaugural list. It’s actually the experience I’ve written the most about in my career, and one of the rarest things I’ve done to date.</p>
<p>You will soon be able to check out a narrative of the experience in my adventure travel column this month on <a href="http://www.farewelltravels.com" target="_blank">Farewell Travels</a>, and look for an article about it coming up on Travel and Escape in a few weeks (I&#8217;ll pass them both on). <a href="http://www.tripfilms.com/Travel_Video-v80254-Exuma-Swimming_with_Pigs_in_the_Bahamas-Video.html#" target="_blank">See the short video</a> that was shot during my visit by Mike Corey from Kick the Grind – he was so kind as to let me make a cameo. <a href="http://www.facebook.com/willmcgough/posts/186685448140449?notif_t=like" target="_blank">Here is another perspective</a> from a video by Jess Parker. Gotta love those piggies. <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-je51Q6upPg&amp;list=UUqwvALW3XnHiNXJx7qUhj4Q&amp;index=29" target="_blank">We also fed french fries to an endangered species on this trip</a>.</p>
<p><b>Hiking in Galachica National Park above Lake Ohrid in Ohrid, Macedonia:</b></p>
<p><a href="http://wakeandwander.com/2013/01/02/wake-and-wanders-holy-shit-moments-of-2012/img_8742-jpg-2/" rel="attachment wp-att-14057"><img alt="IMG_8742.jpg" src="http://willmcgough.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_8742.jpg?w=640&#038;h=330" width="640" height="330" /></a></p>
<p>When I was in Macedonia in November, I came up with the concept of this column after witnessing a sunset over Lake Ohrid from the hills of Galachica National Park. It had been cloudy for most of the hike, but during our descent the sun broke through. I cut through a field and upped my pace – running at times – to reach the north face of the hill. I crested, and it was just spectacular, the coast line curving and glowing and golden.</p>
<p>During the sunset, I sat down on a rock and recorded a video, speaking into it for about four minutes. I suppose I was somewhat leaving a message to my future self. Watching it now, the man in the video tells me that he’s experiencing one of the greatest moments of his life, that he’s enjoying complete bliss and saturation of beauty. He told me to do whatever I had to do to keep it going, to keep pushing my limits and seeking to experience all the planet has to offer. The reward was well worth it, I certainly remember that, and it’s no surprise Lake Ohrid is the most popular vacation spot in Macedonia.</p>
<p>You can <a href="http://wakeandwander.com/2012/12/11/macedonia-food-booze-and-culture-top-list-of-memories/" target="_blank">read about the food and booze of Macedonia</a>, <a href="http://wakeandwander.com/2012/11/19/eastern-europe-long-days-bright-nights-in-macedonia/" target="_blank">see the beauty of Lake Ohrid</a>, and hear about <a href="http://wakeandwander.com/2012/11/26/macedonia-paragliding-pleases-matka-canyon-teases/" target="_blank">my first-ever paragliding experience over Skopje</a>. I’ll have a photo essay on Lake Ohrid running in Travel and Escape shortly that I’ll pass on. I also talked about my trip in <a href="http://www.blogtalkradio.com/midliferoadtrip/2012/12/20/guest-will-mcgough-travel-writer" target="_blank">a recent radio appearance</a>.</p>
<p><b>Ice Hotel and Ice-Canoe Racing in Quebec City</b></p>
<p><a href="http://wakeandwander.com/2013/01/02/wake-and-wanders-holy-shit-moments-of-2012/3_twitter/" rel="attachment wp-att-14049"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-14049" alt="3_twitter" src="http://willmcgough.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/3_twitter.jpg?w=640&#038;h=393" width="640" height="393" /></a></p>
<p>Who knew freezing your face off could be so much fun?</p>
<p>One of the reasons I like to travel is to see the way in which other people choose to live their lives. Before visiting Quebec City, the only appreciation I had for a culture that embraced winter came from spending time in ski towns. Quebec City has skiing nearby, but it&#8217;s certainly no one-trick pony. The photo above captures the yearly ice-canoe races, which is without a doubt one of the most insane sporting events I&#8217;ve had the pleasure of attending. Teams navigate large chunks of ice floating in the St. Lawrence, and when there&#8217;s nowhere else to go, they climb right over them (seriously, see video below). <a href="http://wakeandwander.com/travel/canada/quebec-city-quebec/ice-canoe-races-cap-off-quebec-city-winter-carnival/" target="_blank">You can read the story here</a>.</p>
<p>The fact that <a href="http://wakeandwander.com/travel/canada/quebec-city-quebec/plains-of-abraham-cross-country-skiing-in-the-city/" target="_blank">the locals cross-country ski in the heart of their city</a> is also pretty wild, and if you want more seclusion, you can be <a href="http://wakeandwander.com/travel/canada/quebec-city-quebec/back-to-winter-snowshoeing-in-parc-de-la-jacques-cartier/" target="_blank">snowshoeing in Parc de la Jacques Cartier</a> in under an hour. <a href="http://wakeandwander.com/travel/canada/quebec-city-quebec/hair-dryer-comes-in-handy-at-quebec-city-ice-hotel/" target="_blank">I stayed a night at the ice hotel</a> and never appreciated a hair dryer more. I walked <a href="http://wakeandwander.com/travel/canada/quebec-city-quebec/european-history-feel-walk-old-quebecs-winter-streets/" target="_blank">the European-influenced streets</a> during the day and later defrosted at <a href="http://wakeandwander.com/travel/canada/quebec-city-quebec/caribou-in-a-cane-igloo-heats-up-with-snow-rave/" target="_blank">a rave inside of an igloo</a>.</p>
<p><span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='640' height='360' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/NtzaARFSy3w?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span><br />
&nbsp;<br />
<strong>Conundrum Hot Springs in Aspen, Colorado</strong></p>
<p><a href="http://wakeandwander.com/2013/01/02/wake-and-wanders-holy-shit-moments-of-2012/1-jpg-23/" rel="attachment wp-att-14048"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-14048" alt="1.jpg" src="http://willmcgough.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/1.jpg?w=640&#038;h=480" width="640" height="480" /></a></p>
<p>That&#8217;s right &#8212; Aspen in the summer beats out Aspen in the winter, however it&#8217;s not fair to compare the two experiences. It takes a lot snow for a ski trip to become a &#8220;Holy Shit Moment,&#8221; but an 18-mile backpacking trip to the highest elevated natural hot springs in North America requires none (it sits at 11,200 feet). <a href="http://www.outsideonline.com/blog/conundrum-at-conundrum-hot-springs.html" target="_blank">I wrote an article about the adventure for Outside Online</a> discussing some of the environmental issues associated with the remote location, and also <a href="http://wakeandwander.com/2012/08/29/nature-calls-campers-to-cut-loose-at-conundrum-hot-springs-2/" target="_blank">posted a bunch of photos and wrote a narrative of the experience here on Wake and Wander</a>.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not everyday that you walk nine miles into the wilderness and come across 50 people partying in a natural hot tub. Clothing, for sure, was optional.</p>
<p><strong>Exploring the Alaskan Fjords with Royal Caribbean</strong></p>
<p><a href="http://wakeandwander.com/2013/01/02/wake-and-wanders-holy-shit-moments-of-2012/img_4223/" rel="attachment wp-att-14067"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-14067" alt="IMG_4223" src="http://willmcgough.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_4223.jpg?w=640&#038;h=480" width="640" height="480" /></a></p>
<p>When we were standing in line to check our bags before boarding the ship, we started up a conversation with the people behind us. They told us they had been planning this trip their entire lives, that they had worked all that time to save up the money. I smiled at my friend, both of us in the latter half of our twenties and boarding the same boat.</p>
<p>The biggest difference between an Alaskan and Caribbean cruise is the type and frequency of the scenery (<a href="http://wakeandwander.com/travel/united-states/alaska/alaskan-cruise-how-the-journey-differs-from-others/" target="_blank">read my thoughts here</a>). When you&#8217;re cruising the Caribbean and between islands, all you see for the most part is water. That&#8217;s beautiful and romantic in its own right, but the arms and fjords that make up the Inside Passage in Alaska provide a constantly changing landscape, including mountains, waterfalls, and glaciers (Dawes Glacier is shown in the photo above).</p>
<p>I&#8217;ll never forget the waiter pouring the table an after-dinner glass of champagne at around ten, and when I looked out the window I could still see the snow on the tops of the mountains at 10:44 p.m. The sun rose between four and five and didn&#8217;t set until well after ten &#8212; pretty awesome given the amount of scenery to take in. You can read about <a href="http://wakeandwander.com/travel/united-states/alaska/alaska-gold-rush-train-ride-ends-with-lesson-in-prostitution/" target="_blank">my lessons in prostitution</a>, <a href="http://wakeandwander.com/travel/united-states/alaska/glaciers-in-juneau-no-roads-lead-to-alaskas-capital/" target="_blank">my salmon feast on Tako Glacier</a>, <a href="http://wakeandwander.com/travel/united-states/alaska/skagway-alaska-where-all-journalists-go-to-liarsville/" target="_blank">how journalists ruined the lives of many during the Gold Rush</a>, and <a href="http://wakeandwander.com/travel/united-states/alaska/farewell-alaska-photos-from-the-finale-aboard-rhapsody/" target="_blank">see some shots from the ship</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Experiencing the Energy Surrounding the City of Sedona, Arizona</strong></p>
<p><a href="http://wakeandwander.com/2013/01/02/wake-and-wanders-holy-shit-moments-of-2012/img_9817-jpg/" rel="attachment wp-att-14080"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-14080" alt="IMG_9817.jpg" src="http://willmcgough.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_9817.jpg?w=640&#038;h=320" width="640" height="320" /></a></p>
<p>Given that there are more than 100 hiking trails in the area, you won’t have to sit on the sidelines &#8212; something I always like about a destination. The town is known for being a New Age eclectic mix thanks to the reputation of the area as being an energy vortex. It’s certainly a crossroads sort of place, with each person’s path bringing them to Sedona for a different reason. My final night in town I had beers with a hitchhiker, a retired Air Force veteran, a traveling bartender and three wanderers having the time of their lives working in a restaurant by night and soaking in the scenery by day. Now that&#8217;s diversity.</p>
<p>I had an article run today on Travel and Escape about <a href="http://www.travelandescape.ca/2013/01/the-mystical-vortexes-of-sedona/" target="_blank">exploring the energy vortexes in Sedona</a>. I&#8217;ll be posting a few more stories and photos on the area in the coming week here on Wake and Wander. I had my first psychic reading over the phone with a Sedonian woman shortly after leaving town, which I will tell you about soon.</p>
<p><strong>Taking on an Airbus 340 in Maho Bay, St. Maarten<br />
</strong></p>
<p><a href="http://wakeandwander.com/2013/01/02/wake-and-wanders-holy-shit-moments-of-2012/attachment/1/" rel="attachment wp-att-14105"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-14105" alt="1" src="http://willmcgough.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/11.jpg?w=640&#038;h=320" width="640" height="320" /></a></p>
<p>St. Maarten is a half Dutch, half French Caribbean island located close to St. Barths and Anguilla. Last year during my visit <a href="http://wakeandwander.com/travel/caribbean/st-maarten/hills-thieves-of-pic-paradis-no-sweat-for-wake-and-wander/" target="_blank">I hiked to the highest peak</a>, <a href="http://wakeandwander.com/travel/caribbean/st-maarten/maho-bay-happy-hour-big-birds-high-in-the-sky/" target="_blank">got drunk watching the planes land during happy hour</a>, <a href="http://wakeandwander.com/travel/caribbean/st-maarten/island-tour-beer-for-breakfast-serenity-at-sunset/" target="_blank">drove a Jeep around the entire island</a>, <a href="http://wakeandwander.com/travel/caribbean/st-maarten/island-traffic-enhances-day-at-sonesta-great-bay/" target="_blank">got stuck in the best traffic jam of my life</a>, and broke my sunglasses just before <a href="http://wakeandwander.com/travel/caribbean/st-maarten/broken-sunglasses-nude-senior-citizens-an-interesting-mix/" target="_blank">visiting a nude beach</a>. I did <a href="http://wakeandwander.com/travel/caribbean/st-maarten/" target="_blank">some other stuff</a>, too.</p>
<p>As for messing around on Maho Beach by the infamous Princess Juliana Airport, I&#8217;ll let the videos speak for themselves. If you&#8217;ve never heard of the airport, it won&#8217;t take you long to see why it&#8217;s a tourist attraction. The first video is of when a plane lands on my head, the second is when I stand behind it during takeoff and a million grains of sand introduce themselves to my face.</p>
<span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='640' height='360' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/zcyTs9j2kLU?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span>
<p>I say in this second video that it&#8217;s a 747 I&#8217;m standing behind, but it turned out to be an A340 coming down the runway. Whoops!</p>
<span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='640' height='360' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/UL1_p7ms_eE?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3418/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3418/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3418&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://wakeandwander.com/2013/01/02/wake-and-wanders-holy-shit-moments-of-2012/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/5136a76a46e0c4937a75ea8ea4241a8f?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">willmcgough</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://willmcgough.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_82712.jpg?w=640" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_82712</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://willmcgough.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_8742.jpg?w=640" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_8742.jpg</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://willmcgough.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/3_twitter.jpg?w=640" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">3_twitter</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://willmcgough.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/1.jpg?w=640" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">1.jpg</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://willmcgough.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_4223.jpg?w=640" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_4223</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://willmcgough.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_9817.jpg?w=640" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_9817.jpg</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://willmcgough.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/11.jpg?w=640" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">1</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Listen to the Music: Keep on Keepin’ On</title>
		<link>http://absurdbeats.net/2013/01/08/listen-to-the-music-keep-on-keepin-on/</link>
		<comments>http://absurdbeats.net/2013/01/08/listen-to-the-music-keep-on-keepin-on/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2013 03:49:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>absurdbeats</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Musing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[change]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[duty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[groove]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Listen to the music]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://absurdbeats.net/?p=2876</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I lost my groove. I mentioned in a previous post that I am no longer a completist, that is, I no longer need to own every cd by every singer or band that I like. Five U2 cds? Enough. Six REM? Plenty. It&#8217;s not that I won&#8217;t buy any more cds of those for whom [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2876&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I lost my groove.</p>
<p>I mentioned in a previous post that I am no longer a completist, that is, I no longer need to own every cd by every singer or band that I like. Five U2 cds? Enough. Six REM? Plenty. It&#8217;s not that I won&#8217;t buy any more cds of those for whom I already own multiple discs, but, y&#8217;know, the urgency has faded.</p>
<p>Given my former completist sensibilities, however, I do own many cds by one band/singer which, frankly, has been a problem on my quest to listen to every cd I own: I burn out on a group.</p>
<p>My current (cheapo) stereo allows me to load 3 discs at a time, which is just right: Enough for a solid listening section, without me wanting to cut it short. But when you&#8217;re working through your collection alphabetically, that means the Beatles are followed by the Beatles followed by the Beatles.</p>
<p>I like the Beatles. But, unlike in the past where I would overdose on a single group, I no longer have the patience to listen to three or six hours of the Beatles or Beck or, really, anyone. Hell, the 72-minute long Mary J. Blige cd was too long for me.</p>
<p>Like I said, the groove was gone.</p>
<p>Once it became apparent that I was avoiding listening to my cds because I didn&#8217;t want multiple all-Beck nights, I decided to switch things up. I considered just plucking cds out randomly, but I figured that the pick wouldn&#8217;t really be random and that I&#8217;d just pick cds I often listen to. No, better to continue with the alpha-step, but tweak it.</p>
<p>Now, when I have more than one cd by the same performer(s), I choose the first one, then pick a cd from the following groups. So I chose Beck&#8217;s <em>Mellow Gold</em>, then Daniel Belanger, then Belle and Sebastien&#8217;s <em>&#8220;Tigermilk&#8221;</em>. The next night, Beck&#8217;s <em>Sea Change</em>, Belle &amp; Sebastien&#8217;s <em>Storytelling</em>, and Belly&#8217;s s<em>tar</em>.</p>
<p>Works like a charm.</p>
<p>A few other things. One, I really do like Belly. I like Tanya Donelly&#8217;s wordplay (<em>On every track/I fractured every back/Thinking the point was step on every crack</em>), and how her voice cracks on &#8220;Super-Connected&#8221;&#8212;one of the things that distinguishes pop singing from, say, operatic singing is that the flaws are an integral part of the force of the song. (Think of Merry Clayton&#8217;s break in the Stones&#8217;s &#8220;Gimme Shelter&#8221;: she&#8217;s been hauling Jagger through that wail, and when she finally breaks near the end, you know what she&#8217;s been through and what she&#8217;s put you through.)</p>
<p>Two, I am a puddle in the face of a good leftist rallying song. Goddamn if I didn&#8217;t tear up listening to Black 47&#8242;s &#8220;James Connelly&#8221; (<em>Oh Lily, I don&#8217;t want to die, we&#8217;ve got so much to live for/And I know we&#8217;re all goin&#8217; out to get slaughtered, but I just can&#8217;t take any more).</em> I am a pinko all the way through my bitter little heart.</p>
<p>Three, I think this whole quest is starting to take shape. Early on I was treating this as a kind of duty; even as I claimed I wanted to see if I could recapture my connection to the music, it felt more like a test&#8212;and who likes taking tests? But I&#8217;ve gotten off my ass enough times to shimmy around the wood floor, or paused just to take in the words and the sounds that now, now it feels more like a chance.</p>
<p>And that&#8217;s all right.</p>
<p>~~~<br />
28. Be Good Tanyas, <em>Chinatown</em><br />
29. Be Good Tanyas, <em>hello love</em><br />
30. Beach Boys, <em>Endless Summer</em><br />
31. Beatles, <em>Revolver</em><br />
32. Beatles, <em>Abbey Road</em><br />
33. Beatles, <em>Please Please Me</em><br />
34. Beatles, <em>White Album</em><br />
35. Beatles, <em>Sgt. Pepper&#8217;s Lonely Hearts Club Band</em><br />
36. Beck, <em>Odelay</em><br />
37. Beck, <em>Midnight Vultures</em><br />
38. Beck, <em>Mutations</em><br />
39. Beck, <em>Mellow Gold</em><br />
40. Daniel Belange, <em>Rever Mieux</em><br />
41. Belle and Sebastien, <em>&#8220;Tigermilk&#8221;</em><br />
42. Beck, <em>Sea Change</em><br />
43. Belle and Sebastien, <em>Storytelling</em><br />
44. Beck, <em>Guero</em><br />
45. Belly, <em>star</em><br />
46. Belly, <em>King</em><br />
47. Benedictine Monks of Santo Domingo de Silos, <em>Chant</em><br />
48. Beta Band, <em>Hot Shots II</em><br />
49. Bettie Serveet, <em>lamprey</em><br />
50. Jordy Birch, <em>Funmachine</em><br />
51. Bjork, <em>Post</em><br />
52. Black 47 [eponymous ep-cd]<br />
53. Mary J. Blige, <em>No More Dramas</em></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2876/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2876/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2876&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://absurdbeats.net/2013/01/08/listen-to-the-music-keep-on-keepin-on/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/551e675e54e27ccdd969b3162be45412?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F2.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">absurdbeats</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Unexpected Voice</title>
		<link>http://outsideofparnassus.wordpress.com/2013/01/08/the-unexpected-voice/</link>
		<comments>http://outsideofparnassus.wordpress.com/2013/01/08/the-unexpected-voice/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2013 05:41:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jennifer Lynn Krohn</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Creative Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Poets and Poetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Voice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://outsideofparnassus.wordpress.com/?p=545</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I just finished reading John Dies at the End by David Wong. The book is creepy, surreal, psychedelic, manic, absurd, sarcastic and crassly funny—all in all a good read if you don’t mind an occasional (or frequent) dick joke or a major plot point revolving around dog poop. John Dies at the End reminded me [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=545&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I just finished reading <a title="John Dies at the End " href="http://johndiesattheend.com/" target="_blank"><i>John Dies at the End</i></a> by <a title="David Wong" href="http://www.cracked.com/members/David+Wong/" target="_blank">David Wong</a>. The book is creepy, surreal, psychedelic, manic, absurd, sarcastic and crassly funny—all in all a good read if you don’t mind an occasional (or frequent) dick joke or a major plot point revolving around dog poop.</p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 490px"><img title="John Dies at the End" alt="" src="http://www.geeksofdoom.com/GoD/img/2012/10/2012-10-30-john_dies_at_the_end-e1351580358909-533x384.jpeg" width="480" height="346" /><p class="wp-caption-text">The cover to both my copy of the book and the film adaptation.</p></div>
<p><i>John Dies at the End</i> reminded me of several books I especially loved during my late teens and early twenties: <a title="The Invisibles" href="http://www.vertigocomics.com/graphic-novels/the-invisibles-vol-1-say-you-want-a-revolution" target="_blank"><i>The Invisibles</i></a> (a graphic novel series about a group of guerrilla fighters battling an evil government conspiracy involving magical/ inter-dimensional beings), <a title="Tank Girl" href="http://www.amazon.com/Tank-Girl-Apocalypse-Remastered-Unnumbered/dp/1845767659" target="_blank"><i>Tank Girl </i></a>(a graphic novel series about a girl with a tank who drinks too much, kills things, and shags kangaroos), <a title="Transmetropolitan" href="http://www.vertigocomics.com/graphic-novels/transmetropolitan-vol-1-back-on-the-street" target="_blank"><i>Transmetropolitan</i></a> (a graphic novel series about a drug fueled, violently insane, manic reporter and his two filthy assistants who topples a ruthless and corrupt president in the distant future), <a title="Johnny the Homicidal Maniac" href="http://www.amazon.com/Johnny-Homicidal-Maniac-Directors-Cut/dp/1593621655" target="_blank"><i>Johnny the Homicidal Maniac </i></a>(a graphic novel about a homicidal maniac), and <a title="Fear and Loathing in Las Vegas" href="http://www.indiebound.org/book/9780679785897" target="_blank"><i>Fear and Loathing in Las Vegas </i></a>(not a graphic novel…and I shouldn&#8217;t have explain it to you). My taste ran to self-destructive manic characters who either saw that the conventions of polite society were B.S. or saw that those conventions masked evil parasites (both metaphorical and literal in their respective universes). My taste made a certain amount of sense for an angst ridden and depressed young adult.</p>
<p>During that time I tried to write countless stories with similarly insane weird protagonists: a fraudulent medium who reads fortunes from the crumbs of potato chip bags and is always right, or a girl who after being turned into a hungry monster is pissed off that she been turned back into a human and is still hungry. Fun ideas maybe, but I never could get the stories to work. All I knew was I wanted to write in a mind-bending and profanity laden voice similar to those authors I loved. But with each attempt that I made, I only ended up writing bad copy laden with cliché. Maybe it was because I didn&#8217;t have the attention span required of those longer works, or maybe I didn&#8217;t do enough drugs.</p>
<p>But because I had a short attention span, I was writing poems the whole time. As I struggled with a story, I would get an idea for a poem and in an hour I could have the first draft down, and return to that frustrating story.  At the time I treated the poems like I treated journal entries—an expression of current emotion—that I was slightly more likely to share with my friends. I never thought it would develop into anything—though to be fair at that time in my life I assumed I’d be dead in the gutter by age of 30 and only went to college out of spite. I took a fiction class and wrote horrible stories involving sarcastic vampires then I took a poetry class and wrote horrible poems with some good lines. By the time I graduated with a Bachelor’s in Creative Writing, I’d given myself over completely to poetry. After all my poetry improved by leaps and bounds, while my fiction was still a sad weak little thing. It was only in the last year of graduate school that I dared to start submitting my fiction, which by then had radically changed.</p>
<p>I think my focus on poetry is what changed my voice. Oh, I could still be creepy, sarcastic, surreal and even a little mad at times, but the focus shifted. I became interested in motivation, in images, in sound. I even wrote poems that were quiet and took their time. I still have a lot of anger in my work, but it is calmer, more focused, more self-aware, not the self-destructive manic energy I once so admired. And of course, this voice that emerged in my poems infected my fiction.</p>
<p>As I read <i>John Dies at the End</i> I couldn&#8217;t help but think, this is the type of book I once wanted to write. The moment almost tasted like failure—a goal I did not reach—but I’m still writing.  I&#8217;ve published work, and I and currently submitting my manuscript to publishers (fingers crossed). I simply did not meet my goals in the way I thought I would when I was 19 and 20 years old. So my writing now owes more to <a title="Angela Carter" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Angela_Carter" target="_blank">Angela Carter</a>, <a title="Italo Calvino " href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Italo_Calvino" target="_blank">Italo Calvino</a>, and <a title="Ai" href="http://www.poetryfoundation.org/bio/ai" target="_blank">Ai</a> than it does to <a title="Warren Ellis" href="http://www.warrenellis.com/" target="_blank">Warren Ellis</a>, <a title="Grant Morrison " href="http://www.grant-morrison.com/" target="_blank">Grant Morrison</a>, and <a title="Jhonen Vasquez" href="http://www.questionsleep.com/" target="_blank">Jhonen Vasquez</a>, that does not mean failure.</p>
<p>In the end it just turns out that I had different things to say, but isn&#8217;t that the nature of writing. You sit down with a blank page and head full of ideas, and by the time you finish covering the page with words you have something completely different from what was in your head. I may not write in the voice that I’d once wanted to, there are already writers doing that far better than I could, but I write in voice that is my own.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/545/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/545/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=545&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://outsideofparnassus.wordpress.com/2013/01/08/the-unexpected-voice/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/01b8403573d4d1673b42c287ec035bb6?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Jennifer Krohn</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://www.geeksofdoom.com/GoD/img/2012/10/2012-10-30-john_dies_at_the_end-e1351580358909-533x384.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">John Dies at the End</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Challenge is On! How Long Can We Spin This Out For?</title>
		<link>http://ltclifeonhigh.wordpress.com/2013/01/04/the-challenge-is-on-how-long-can-we-spin-this-out-for/</link>
		<comments>http://ltclifeonhigh.wordpress.com/2013/01/04/the-challenge-is-on-how-long-can-we-spin-this-out-for/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2013 12:27:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>lillianccc</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog Fun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bloggers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inspiration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ltclifeonhigh.wordpress.com/?p=1678</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s a new year and a new month&#8230;.. which means, time for a new blogging game! Yay! Uh, you guys WERE looking forward to this, weren&#8217;t you? So maybe some of you have noticed by now, but last month I failed to do a blogging game due to time constraints, stress, lack of inspiration, and [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1678&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s a new year and a new month&#8230;.. which means, time for a new blogging game! Yay! Uh, you guys WERE looking forward to this, weren&#8217;t you?</p>
<div class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 156px"><a href="http://ltclifeonhigh.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/eyes-on-you.jpg"><img class="  " title="eyes on you" alt="" src="http://ltclifeonhigh.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/eyes-on-you.jpg?w=146&#038;h=102" width="146" height="102" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">My blog game mascot is NOT amused.</p></div>
<p>So maybe some of you have noticed by now, but last month I failed to do a blogging game due to time constraints, stress, lack of inspiration, and just plain laziness. I&#8217;d originally intended to post one after I came back from vacation and then when that didn&#8217;t work out, after Christmas, but by then I figured no one really cared and if we all survived the end of the world, a new month would be here in no time.</p>
<p>And now here we are.</p>
<p>So.</p>
<p>I thought long and hard about what would be interesting and fitting for this time of year, when we&#8217;re all still starry-eyed and full of ambition. And then I came upon the idea of a never-ending story. (<em>A never-ending story, baby just say yes~~</em> oops, wrong lyrics&#8230;. sorry, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Love_Story_%28Taylor_Swift_song%29">Taylor!</a>) Don&#8217;t ask me how that correlates with being starry-eyed and full of ambition, it just does. <del><br />
</del></p>
<p>What&#8217;s going to happen is I&#8217;ll start off the story and then it&#8217;ll be up to YOU to keep it going. Don&#8217;t worry too much about story logic or plot structure. Yes, those things are important if you&#8217;re writing a book but we&#8217;re not, so don&#8217;t be afraid to indulge in your inner fantasies! (Wait. That didn&#8217;t sound quite right&#8230;.) I&#8217;m more interested in how this all plays out so feel free to add in random twists, turns, and cliffhangers for the next person to play off of. Or not. It&#8217;s all up to you.</p>
<p>When it looks like everyone&#8217;s imagination has been exhausted, I&#8217;ll wrap the story up and post it in a separate blog in all it&#8217;s glory for everyone to see. No, there won&#8217;t be a definitive ending (at least I don&#8217;t anticipate there will be one) but it&#8217;ll be good fun to see how everything comes together. Like an elementary school science project. Get ready to pour, mix, and blow things up, everyone.</p>
<p>There is no minimum or maximum word count so feel free to be as succinct or rambly as you want. You can also come back and add to the plot as many times as you&#8217;d like (if you start spamming or hogging the space though, I will have to ask you to step away with your typing hands raised). Most importantly, use your imagination and get creative! No one is going to judge you (you there, stop judging!) so please don&#8217;t be shy. Just go with it and see where your brain takes you. This is going to be the best story EVER.</p>
<p>Here we go! I&#8217;m not a fiction writer so if you&#8217;re cringing at the awful beginning, well, too bad. I never said I was good at fiction.</p>
<p><strong>&#8212;-The Story&#8212;-</strong></p>
<p>It wasn&#8217;t like she didn&#8217;t know where she was going. She did. Things just had a way of turning into obstacles or else distracting her so much that by the time she realized she was off track, she forgot what her original intention or destination was.<br />
Like two days ago. She was running late as usual, but stopped by the post office anyways to mail an important package. As she dashed across the street, she caught a glimpse of a very odd sight and unconsciously slowed down for a better look.</p>
<p><em>What did she see? Did her package get mailed off? Do we even care about that? What&#8217;s her name, anyway? Please continue this story!<br />
</em></p>
<br /> Tagged: <a href='http://ltclifeonhigh.wordpress.com/tag/bloggers/'>bloggers</a>, <a href='http://ltclifeonhigh.wordpress.com/tag/blogging/'>blogging</a>, <a href='http://ltclifeonhigh.wordpress.com/tag/games/'>games</a>, <a href='http://ltclifeonhigh.wordpress.com/tag/humor/'>humor</a>, <a href='http://ltclifeonhigh.wordpress.com/tag/inspiration/'>inspiration</a>, <a href='http://ltclifeonhigh.wordpress.com/tag/story/'>story</a>, <a href='http://ltclifeonhigh.wordpress.com/tag/writing/'>writing</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1678/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1678/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1678&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://ltclifeonhigh.wordpress.com/2013/01/04/the-challenge-is-on-how-long-can-we-spin-this-out-for/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>28</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/13a45e0d14e97d035e3edb5b06753072?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lillianccc</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ltclifeonhigh.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/eyes-on-you.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">eyes on you</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Random Thoughts On Living Authentically In Artificial Times</title>
		<link>http://kalliopeamorphous.wordpress.com/2013/01/08/random-thoughts-on-living-authentically-in-artificial-times/</link>
		<comments>http://kalliopeamorphous.wordpress.com/2013/01/08/random-thoughts-on-living-authentically-in-artificial-times/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2013 19:24:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Kalliope Amorphous</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anais nin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[authenticity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fine art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[freedom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[literature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[living]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[passion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[twitter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[visual art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://kalliopeamorphous.wordpress.com/?p=1426</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[“To hell, to hell with balance! I break glasses; I want to burn, even if I break myself. I want to live only for ecstasy. Nothing else affects me. Small doses, moderate loves, all half-shades, leave me cold. I like extravagance, heat. Letters which give the postman a stiff back to carry, books which overflow [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1426&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://kalliopeamorphous.wordpress.com/2013/01/08/random-thoughts-on-living-authentically-in-artificial-times/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>77</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://kalliopeamorphous.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/tumblr_mdxguycein1qh020fo1_500.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://kalliopeamorphous.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/tumblr_mdxguycein1qh020fo1_500.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tumblr_mdxguycEiN1qh020fo1_500</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/eeaa857379edc2325f3b1b8a21cf9aa6?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">kalliopeamorphous</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://kalliopeamorphous.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/tumblr_mdxguycein1qh020fo1_500.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tumblr_mdxguycEiN1qh020fo1_500</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://kalliopeamorphous.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/tumblr_m90r4l7mre1qb6xzno1_500.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tumblr_m90r4l7MRE1qb6xzno1_500</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Online Writing as a Tool for Decolonization</title>
		<link>http://decolonization.wordpress.com/2013/01/08/online-writing-as-a-tool-for-decolonization/</link>
		<comments>http://decolonization.wordpress.com/2013/01/08/online-writing-as-a-tool-for-decolonization/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2013 21:31:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Editors</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[academia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://decolonization.wordpress.com/?p=101</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I write this piece for those of us who are academics. We trumpet our forward thinking research, yet so often fail to be forward thinking on how we engage with our communities, how we spread our thoughts, and what it means to live out and generate a decolonizing praxis. How do you envision your role [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=101&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://decolonization.wordpress.com/2013/01/08/online-writing-as-a-tool-for-decolonization/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>38</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/e56f4be965b6fc5def1079e9f64a5f7a?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F2.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">decolonization</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://decolonization.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/tumblr_mesgusqete1r4i23fo1_1280.jpg?w=194" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image by Dwayne Bird, www.birdwiremedia.com</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Meet the Men of Match.com: Really, Guys, Are You Serious?</title>
		<link>http://scholarsandrogues.com/2013/01/08/meet-the-men-of-match-com-really-guys-are-you-serious/</link>
		<comments>http://scholarsandrogues.com/2013/01/08/meet-the-men-of-match-com-really-guys-are-you-serious/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2013 23:21:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Guest Scrogue</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[American Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funny]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet, Telecom & Social Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal Narrative]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adventure travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[horror stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Match.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[match.com reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[men match.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online dating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online dating stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[slider]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://scholarsandrogues.com/?p=79116</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[by Lisa Barnard I&#8217;m turning 30 in a few months, and I recently realized I&#8217;m now at the age I made a lot of promises about in the past. One of those promises was that if I was still single at 30, I&#8217;d try online dating. I&#8217;ve had an onslaught of terrible dating experiences in [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=79116&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://scholarsandrogues.com/2013/01/08/meet-the-men-of-match-com-really-guys-are-you-serious/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>159</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://scholarsandrogues.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/online-dating.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://scholarsandrogues.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/online-dating.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">CATEGORY: Online-Dating</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/1f2295622ca32dcfee705fef1e0b7fd6?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Guest Poster</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://scholarsandrogues.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/online-dating.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">CATEGORY: Online-Dating</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
