<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2012 20:02:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Is There Really Any Need?</title>
		<link>http://lordwilliamsofwoodcroft.wordpress.com/2012/10/17/71/</link>
		<comments>http://lordwilliamsofwoodcroft.wordpress.com/2012/10/17/71/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2012 12:19:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Mark Williams</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Lifestyle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Religion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[debate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[religion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://lordwilliamsofwoodcroft.wordpress.com/?p=71</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This picture was posted on Twitter and subsequently retweeted by thousands of people, including the usual suspects, chief among them, renowned atheist Richard Dawkins. Yes, I do follow Dawkins on Twitter. I also follow Ricky Gervais and a couple of other famous and outspoken atheists. I&#8217;m not really one for ignoring people who disagree with [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=71&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://lordwilliamsofwoodcroft.wordpress.com/2012/10/17/71/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/99dc57f0b96fed2323f45bd892314e57?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">wilbo39</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lordwilliamsofwoodcroft.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/picture-2.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Dear Religion</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Art of the Foul Ball &#8211; Brandon Belt</title>
		<link>http://brandon.mlblogs.com/2012/10/16/the-art-of-the-foul-ball-brandon-belt/</link>
		<comments>http://brandon.mlblogs.com/2012/10/16/the-art-of-the-foul-ball-brandon-belt/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2012 16:30:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>mlblogssfgiants1</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Belt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brandon Belt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Giants]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brandon.mlblogs.com/?p=121</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[We’re getting ready to go to the ballpark where we’ll take buses to the airport. I love that our wives can go with us. We don’t have to make separate travel arrangements and worry about all the logistics. And it saves us money, too – which still matters to the younger guys. Haylee and I [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=121&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We’re getting ready to go to the ballpark where we’ll take buses to the airport. I love that our wives can go with us. We don’t have to make separate travel arrangements and worry about all the logistics. And it saves us money, too – which still matters to the younger guys.</p>
<p>Haylee and I moved out of our rental in Walnut Creek and now are staying in a hotel in San Francisco. I walked to the park for the first two games and it was like there was a carnival in town. It felt a little like going to a college football game. Everybody’s in orange-and-black. There’s an excitement in the air. I’m kind of recognizable because I’m pretty tall, but I walked with my hood up and tried to blend in so I could just enjoy the atmosphere. (The only disappointment was no fly-over before the game. I love the fly-overs.)</p>
<p>Last night’s win was great all-around. Vogey was the Vogey we’ve seen all year. He pitched his butt off. The bats came alive, the defense was strong as usual. I haven’t heard anything about Marco yet this morning. I’m sure we’ll learn more when we get to the park. He’s a huge part of the team, but if he can’t play, we have Theriot. So we’ll be in good shape. I didn’t see the slide because I was looking to catch Marco’s throw.</p>
<p>There’s a lot to talk about from the game, but I thought I’d give you a little insight about something a little more obscure – catching foul balls. I made a catch in the third inning that was far up the right-field line where there’s an indent past a VIP box. Those kinds of plays illustrate how important it is to know the quirks and characteristics of a park. I learned that from Will Clark and J.T. Snow. You learn about a park in different ways. You roll a ball down the line to see how it breaks. You watch the way the wind pushes fly balls. You take note of the configuration so you’re aware of how much room you have in foul territory.</p>
<p>With high foul balls, the first thing is to get some sense of where the ball’s going as soon as it comes off the bat. Then you head there as fast as you can. And then the biggest thing: Find the rail.</p>
<p>Last night I knew I had more foul territory to play with because of that indent. I’m told a fan had his glove outstretched while I was trying to catch it. I didn’t see him. But if he did interfere, I don’t think I’d be mad because if I was a fan I’d do the same thing. It would be awesome to catch a playoff ball.</p>
<p>A few innings later, I caught a ball that really was probably the second-baseman’s ball. But I had a bead on it and, more important, I have a bigger glove than any of the other infielders. It’s a glove made for catching, so theoretically I have a greater chance of catching. That’s why you see first-basemen catch so many infield flies.</p>
<p>One of my favorite moments of last night’s game was watching Aubrey Huff score from second base on Theriot’s single in the sixth. He looked like he was running with a trailer hitched to his back. We all give him a hard time about his speed. When he got to the dugout and everybody was high-fiving him, I took the opportunity to give him a turkey tap, which he didn’t like too much. (I’m not describing what a turkey tap is but you can google it.)</p>
<p>Ok, that’s it for now. This should be a pretty happy flight today. A little different from when we headed to Cincinnati in the NLDS.</p>
<p>Thanks for reading!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>-Brandon B.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/121/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/121/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=121&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://brandon.mlblogs.com/2012/10/16/the-art-of-the-foul-ball-brandon-belt/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>29</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/6d079979551c51e1aa54b20244bc3c6a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mlblogssfgiants1</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What Makes a Post Freshly Press-able: There Is a Light That Never Goes Out</title>
		<link>http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2012/10/17/what-makes-a-post-freshly-press-able-there-is-a-light-that-never-goes-out/</link>
		<comments>http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2012/10/17/what-makes-a-post-freshly-press-able-there-is-a-light-that-never-goes-out/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2012 15:57:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>michelle w.</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Freshly Pressed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Inspiration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inspiration]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dailypost.wordpress.com/?p=10735</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Every day, a handful of WordPress.com bloggers are featured in Freshly Pressed. And every day, many more wonder, “What do I have to do to get Freshly Pressed?” Well, it’s time to reveal what the folks who push the launch button are thinking. Each week, we’ll take a close look at one post and why [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=10735&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Every day, a handful of WordPress.com bloggers are featured in </em>Freshly Pressed<em>. And every day, many more wonder, “What do I have to do to get Freshly Pressed?”</em></p>
<p><em>Well, it’s time to reveal what the folks who push the launch button are thinking. Each week, we’ll take a close look at one post and why we thought it was Press-worthy. We hope we can provide insight into the process and give you tips and tools to make your blog the best it can be.<br />
____________________________________________</em></p>
<p>Many Freshly Pressed picks make us laugh, introduce us to new ideas, or provoke conversations. After all, one reason for having Freshly Pressed at all is to inspire everyone to blog more, so we&#8217;re drawn to posts that will stimulate discussion.</p>
<p>Sometimes, though, a post slices through the din of the blogosphere on the strength of raw emotion. When we run across those posts, we share them for three reasons:</p>
<p><span id="more-10735"></span></p>
<ol>
<li>There is power in the words used to so bluntly describe a painful experience.</li>
<li>We know that the WordPress.com community will respond with support.</li>
<li>Sharing the post might help some else facing a similar situation feel less alone.</li>
</ol>
<p>That&#8217;s why we recently featured <a title="There Is a Light That Never Goes Out" href="https://charliesotherangel.wordpress.com/2012/10/09/there-is-a-light-that-never-goes-out/">There Is a Light That Never Goes Out</a>, from new blog <em><a title="Charlie's Other Angel" href="https://charliesotherangel.wordpress.com/">Charlie&#8217;s Other Angel</a></em>. Two things about this post forced us to stop in our tracks:</p>
<h2>The opening line made us sit up and take notice.</h2>
<p>It&#8217;s not often that you click over to a blog and are confronted with:</p>
<blockquote><p><em>My ex-husband died tonight.</em></p></blockquote>
<p>There was no cute story gently introducing the topic, no collage of family photos, no loving words about the deceased; just four simple words landing on our screens with a thud. &#8220;My ex-husband died tonight.&#8221;</p>
<p>Those words tell us what the post will be about in more ways than one. Yes, it will be a post about a serious loss. <em>And</em> it will be straightforward and unforgiving. There will be no scrim softening the line between the experience and the post—his blogger is going to lay things bare. This will not be an easy post to read, and if this topic is a trigger for you, now might be a good time to leave.</p>
<h2>She pulled no punches.</h2>
<p>True to her opening line, she was honest about her ex-husband, their relationship, and herself.</p>
<blockquote><p>Because, over the 22 years I’ve known my ex, it hasn’t been easy.  It was often fun.  I laughed and cried and laughed some more.  I got cancer.  I attended a lot of Al-anon meetings.  I wished his death on at least one major occasion, and luckily God knew me better than that weakness of character and said No&#8230;</p>
<p>I am so sad.  And not just for our boys — though most especially for our boys.  Sad at what might have been for this sweet man.  Sad that he hadn’t been able to kick the demons.  Sad that it took his final month to bring us all back together, so close.</p></blockquote>
<p>This is not a storybook memorial to a prince charming. It&#8217;s a real-life look at the flexibility and resilience of the ties that bind family members, even those from whom we think we&#8217;re unfettered. Ultimately, it&#8217;s the story of a woman who was able to knot off one of those ties in a way that brought her peace, and the redemption of a man ultimately bested by his addiction.</p>
<p>Blogging can be a scary activity when we&#8217;re publishing something lighthearted; there are always elements of fear and uncertainty when we release our words into the wild. To write so openly and eloquently about such a deeply personal experience takes another level of bravery, one that we&#8217;re moved to acknowledge.</p>
<p><em><a title="Charlie's Other Angel" href="https://charliesotherangel.wordpress.com/">Charlie&#8217;s Other Angel</a></em> is off to an incredible start with this post—will you stick around to read more?</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/10735/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/10735/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=10735&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2012/10/17/what-makes-a-post-freshly-press-able-there-is-a-light-that-never-goes-out/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>30</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/2367004060918e221dcb9799584e9279?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Michelle, Communications</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Buddy Holly Curse</title>
		<link>http://grafiklit.wordpress.com/2012/10/14/the-buddy-holly-curse/</link>
		<comments>http://grafiklit.wordpress.com/2012/10/14/the-buddy-holly-curse/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2012 19:28:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>kat</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Halloween]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Buddy Holly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[curses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[horror]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lubbock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plane crashes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ritchie Valens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Texas]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://grafiklit.wordpress.com/?p=1088</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I don&#8217;t think you could definitely say that there is a curse associated with 1950s rock-n-roller Buddy Holly; you could probably safely karaoke &#8220;Peggy Sue&#8221; or &#8220;That&#8217;ll Be the Day&#8221; and not wind up dead the next day. (Note the  definitely and probably. Those adverbs clear me of any liability if you sing any of his songs and [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1088&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://grafiklit.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/buddyholly.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-1089" title="Buddy+Holly" alt="" src="http://grafiklit.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/buddyholly.jpg?w=256&#038;h=300" height="300" width="256" /></a></p>
<p>I don&#8217;t think you could definitely say that there is a curse associated with 1950s rock-n-roller Buddy Holly; you could probably safely karaoke &#8220;Peggy Sue&#8221; or &#8220;That&#8217;ll Be the Day&#8221; and not wind up dead the next day. (Note the  <em>definitely</em> and <em>probably</em>. Those adverbs clear me of any liability if you sing any of his songs and get stabbed by a crazed karaoke hater.) However, there have been a number of unfortunate incidents associated with Holly, so let&#8217;s sprinkle a ring of salt around us and get started, shall we?</p>
<p>I suppose some background is in order. Buddy Holly was born Charles Holley, on September 7, 1936, in Lubbock, Texas. I spent almost two years in Lubbock. It&#8217;s dusty, windy, and full of dirt. There&#8217;s a Buddy Holly statue in a park, and you can see his grave in, uh, a graveyard. Buddy was his longtime nickname; Decca Records, who first signed him, misspelled his last name, and it stuck.</p>
<p>Holly and his band, the Crickets, started actively recording in 1957. Despite the busy schedule, Holly found time to marry Maria Santiago in June 1958. (He saved time by proposing on their first date.) He was also offered a spot in the Winter Dance Party, a 3-week tour across the midwestern United States that opened on January 23, 1959. (I have been to the Midwest, and as I experienced, it is extremely friggin&#8217; cold that time of year.)</p>
<p>Shortly into the tour, Holly&#8217;s drummer, Carl Bunch, had to leave the Party, because he suffered frostbite on his feet. Add to that the Big Bopper (J.P. Richardson, &#8220;Chantilly Lace&#8221;) and Ritchie Valens (&#8220;La Bamba&#8221;, Lou Diamond Phillips) coming down with colds, the tour bus constantly breaking down, and it was a pretty miserable experience. You can&#8217;t blame Buddy for thinking &#8220;Fuck this&#8221; and chartering a plane to take him from the Surf Ballroom in Clear Lake, Iowa, to their next stop.</p>
<p>Richardson and Valens, though, weren&#8217;t supposed to be on the plane. Waylon Jennings (the guy who sang the <em>Dukes of Hazzard</em> theme) gave his seat to Richardson, and Valens won his through a coin flip with Tommy Allsup, a member of Holly&#8217;s backing band.</p>
<p>On February 3, 1959, the plane went up, and then came back down shortly after take-off, about 5 miles from the airport. There was a snowstorm, and the pilot wasn&#8217;t qualified to fly by instruments only, something he neglected to tell his passengers.</p>
<p>And here&#8217;s where the curse, or maybe just the unfortunate happenings associated with Buddy Holly, begins.</p>
<p>Singer Eddie Cochran (&#8220;Summertime Blues&#8221;) was supposed to be with the Winter Dance Party, but he dropped out shortly before it started. On April 17, 1960, Cochran was in a car wreck while driving to London&#8217;s Heathrow Airport. His two passengers lived, but Cochran was thrown from the car and died the next day of massive head injuries. The last single released by Cochran before his death? &#8220;Three Steps to Heaven&#8221;, a song backed by Holly&#8217;s old band the Crickets.</p>
<p>Singer Ronnie Smith stepped in to replace Holly for the rest of the Dance Party. On October 25, 1962, he hanged himself in a hospital bathroom; he&#8217;d been committed to a state hospital in Texas for drug abuse.</p>
<p>The original Crickets decided to draft a new singer; 17 year-old David Box sang with them for a few years, recording the song &#8220;Peggy Sue Got Married&#8221; (thus the title of the Kathleen Turner/Nicolas Cage &#8217;80s movie) before moving on to a solo career. On October 23, 1964, the Cessna plane he was riding in crashed, killing him and the pilot. He was 22, the same age as Holly when his crash occurred.</p>
<p>Bobby Fuller idolized Buddy Holly; he sent a demo record to Holly&#8217;s parents, who forwarded it to their son&#8217;s former producer. Fuller and his band, the Bobby Fuller Four, were signed and recorded some songs, including &#8220;I Fought the Law&#8221;, which was written by one of the Crickets.  On July 18, 1966, Fuller was found dead in his car, which was parked in front of his house. He&#8217;d been severely beaten and drenched in gasoline. Fuller reportedly had been in trouble with local mobsters, due to his dalliances with a mob dame. The police ruled his death a suicide. (Because, you know, if you want to do yourself in, punching yourself in the face and then pouring gasoline over yourself&#8211;and you gotta make sure to swallow some of it&#8211;is the best way to go.) Fuller&#8217;s connection with the Holly curse, beyond the Cricket-penned song? He recorded &#8220;Love&#8217;s Made a Fool of You&#8221; right before his death, a song that had been written by Holly.</p>
<p>All right, so, a few unfortunate occurrences, but this is rock-n-roll, baby. You pick up a guitar or a set of drum sticks with the knowledge that you may die young. Plane crashes, car crashes, drugs, drinking, suiciding. Blame it on Robert Johnson and his deal with the devil at the crossroads.</p>
<p>But now we come to Hollywood. The movies, I meant. But still, check that out. Hollywood. Buddy Holly.</p>
<p>In 1978, Gary Busey was not the addled, could-be-your-weird-uncle-who-does-PCP-and-makes-his-own-moonshine-in-his-toilet guy we know today. Back then, he was a singer turned actor, with an okay resemblance to Holly. Thus, he was cast in <em>The Buddy Holly Story</em>, a biopic covering the singer&#8217;s life from Lubbock to that plane in Iowa.</p>
<p><a href="http://grafiklit.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/rs274-rs.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-1091" title="RS274-RS" alt="" src="http://grafiklit.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/rs274-rs.jpg?w=244&#038;h=300" height="300" width="244" /></a></p>
<p>He garnered an Academy Award nomination for his role, and did all the singing in the movie. But somehow, his career just never took off. And in 1988, he got in a near-fatal motorcycle wreck and fractured his skull, because helmets are for pussies. And now we have quotes like:</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://www.buseyworld.com/index.htm" target="_blank">&#8220;Imagine the peace symbol.  The peace symbol has three pieces in it.  One piece </a><br />
<a href="http://www.buseyworld.com/index.htm" target="_blank">is emotion, that&#8217;s your body.  Another piece has spirit in it, that&#8217;s your </a><br />
<a href="http://www.buseyworld.com/index.htm" target="_blank">fuel.  Another piece has intellect in it and that&#8217;s your steering wheel.  You </a><br />
<a href="http://www.buseyworld.com/index.htm" target="_blank">can never overdo the fuel that goes into the body, which is the emotions and the </a><br />
<a href="http://www.buseyworld.com/index.htm" target="_blank">steering wheel to drive it.&#8221;</a></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">All right, but so what? An actor rides a bike without a helmet, and does it 10 years after that movie, and maybe he never became a big star, that might have something to do with cocaine, but there has to be more to it than that, right?</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Excellent point. Want to guess what happened to Robert Gittler, <em>The Buddy Holly Story</em>&#8216;s screenwriter?</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">He killed himself right before the film was released.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">As I mentioned earlier, not conclusive stuff. Nothing happened to Don McLean (&#8220;American Pie&#8221;, come on, you&#8217;ve heard it) or Madonna, when she made that demon miscarriage of a remake.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Still, though, don&#8217;t think I&#8217;ll be singing &#8220;That&#8217;ll Be the Day&#8221; aloud anytime soon.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><strong>Terrific Trivia Time! </strong>Holly&#8217;s song &#8221;That&#8217;ll Be the Day&#8221; was inspired by John Wayne, who said the line several times in <em>The Searchers (1956). </em></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">And if I wanted to blow y&#8217;all&#8217;s minds, I could add that Natalie Wood played the abducted girl, the object of John Wayne&#8217;s character&#8217;s obsessed hunt, in <em>The Searchers</em>. And we all know what happened to Natalie Wood. Either she was the victim of the Holly curse, or the <a href="http://theselvedgeyard.wordpress.com/2009/02/10/the-rebel-without-a-cause-cast-of-characters/" target="_blank"><em>Rebel Without a Cause</em> curse</a> . . .</p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><a href="http://grafiklit.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/buddy-holly-plane-crash.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-1092" title="buddy-holly-plane-crash" alt="" src="http://grafiklit.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/buddy-holly-plane-crash.jpg?w=300&#038;h=210" height="210" width="300" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1088/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1088/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1088&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://grafiklit.wordpress.com/2012/10/14/the-buddy-holly-curse/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>27</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://grafiklit.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/buddyholly.jpg?w=128" />
		<media:content url="http://grafiklit.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/buddyholly.jpg?w=128" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Buddy+Holly</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/20ec0e31ca48d669f26d61225bb2845d?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">grafiklit</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://grafiklit.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/buddyholly.jpg?w=256" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Buddy+Holly</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://grafiklit.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/rs274-rs.jpg?w=244" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">RS274-RS</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://grafiklit.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/buddy-holly-plane-crash.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">buddy-holly-plane-crash</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Wardrobe Malfunction</title>
		<link>http://abreakfastserial.com/2012/10/16/the-wardrobe-malfunction/</link>
		<comments>http://abreakfastserial.com/2012/10/16/the-wardrobe-malfunction/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2012 11:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>abreakfastserial</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[embarrassing moments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[school]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[teaching]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://abreakfastserial.com/?p=949</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#60; by Brennan &#62; Showing off your undergarments is a personal, intensely private experience. When was the last time you tried on underwear and walked out of the dressing room to ask for an opinion? Dreamt you got to school in your skivvies just as the bell rang? Teaching a classroom of 28 second graders [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=949&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&lt; by <a href="http://abreakfastserial.com/authors/" target="_blank">Brennan</a> &gt;</p>
<p>Showing off your undergarments is a personal, intensely private experience. When was the last time you tried on underwear and walked out of the dressing room to ask for an opinion? Dreamt you got to school in your skivvies just as the bell rang?</p>
<p>Teaching a classroom of 28 second graders can lead to some rather hectic moments. Each child is like their own individual roller coaster, twists and turns coming when you least expect them, never quite sure what is coming next. It gives yield to some amazing moments of emotion and sympathy, anger, and frustration. And that&#8217;s just from the teacher.</p>
<p>Caught up in a particularly passionate moment of explaining long division — you would be surprised how energized the sensation of remembering basic math can make you feel — I lost control of my eraser; it clattered to the floor. Bending down to pick it up, I realized my shirt had come untucked in the back and my pants were a little loose a moment too late. The damage was done.</p>
<p>Embarrassment comes in many forms, but redemption is universally sweet. As my kids left for the day, one of my students pulled me down and whispered: &#8220;It&#8217;s ok, Mr. Lowery. I like SpongeBob too.&#8221;</p>
<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/rlevans/428076367/"><img src="http://farm1.staticflickr.com/163/428076367_713f349454_n.jpg" alt="DSC00098.JPG" width="320" height="240" /></a></p>
<p><em>Photo by RLEVANS</em><strong id="yui_3_5_1_3_1350476494721_1077"></strong></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/949/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/949/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=949&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://abreakfastserial.com/2012/10/16/the-wardrobe-malfunction/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>29</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f648e7be5876853ddaee87a1f7190ab7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">abreakfastserial</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Well, Isn&#8217;t That Pinteresting?</title>
		<link>http://yourmonthlyperiodical.com/2012/09/14/well-isnt-that-pinteresting/</link>
		<comments>http://yourmonthlyperiodical.com/2012/09/14/well-isnt-that-pinteresting/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2012 19:13:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bitchyeditor</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Issue 6]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consumerism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crafting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[garbage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[guilt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[housewives]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ladies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[materialism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pinterest]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://yourmonthlyperiodical.com/?p=1055</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Written By: Kat Today I logged into Pinterest for the first time in a few weeks. As I scrolled through, page after page loading, I was quickly reminded of how terrible and plebeian everything in my life is. My bedroom doesn&#8217;t look anything like an airy beachside bungalow, my wall-hangings have zero rustic character, and [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1055&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1156" title="P1070926" src="http://yourmonthlyperiodical.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/p1070926.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="479" /></p>
<p style="text-align:right;"><em>Written By: Kat</em></p>
<p>Today I logged into Pinterest for the first time in a few weeks. As I scrolled through, page after page loading, I was quickly reminded of how terrible and plebeian everything in my life is. My bedroom doesn&#8217;t look anything like an airy beachside bungalow, my wall-hangings have zero rustic character, and there is nary a stitch of stainless steel in my kitchen. Thanks, Internet, I&#8217;ll be in my shitty little shanty if you need me.</p>
<p><a href="http://yourmonthlyperiodical.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/167548048607107328_jlgtez7f_f.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-1092" title="167548048607107328_jLGTEZ7F_f" src="http://yourmonthlyperiodical.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/167548048607107328_jlgtez7f_f.jpg?w=200&#038;h=300" alt="" width="200" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>As far as I can tell, Pinterest is the reason your wife drinks heavily. It&#8217;s a place ladies go to be reminded they are not nearly adequate, due to the fact that they have not yet mastered &#8220;the perfect ganache,&#8221; or hand-sewn that elaborate princess costume for their daughters.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a place where middle-class women fantasize about $4k Burberry trench coats, obsess over creative shelving, and lust after $100 a roll wallpapers. It is rife with photos of young New York City fashionistas, pinned and repinned by stay-at-home moms in the flyover states, peering through the Pinterest peephole at an alternate reality.</p>
<p><strong>Suddenly, it dawned on me. Pinterest is the digital embodiment of everything I hate. </strong></p>
<p>I am the kind of person who loves to throw things out. Not perfectly good, functioning items; but the defunct remnants of Made in China ANYTHING are trash to me. Not because I am wealthy and can afford to buy new things, but because I long ago accepted that IM NOT GOING TO FUCKING FIX THAT.</p>
<p>So I throw it out instead of leaving it sitting around, making me feel guilty. Goodbye $15 window fan from 6 years ago, I&#8217;m sure the replacement part to fix you is only $2, and it would be real easy to pull out your workings and get you right back in order. But IM NOT GOING TO FUCKING DO THAT. Goodbye, stinky old sectional sofa from my ex boyfriends mother. I bet a steam-cleaning and a trendy slip cover would make you good as new. BUT IM NOT GOING TO FUCKING DO THAT. We can discuss how simple re-purposing all our shoddily-crafted overseas items would be all day long, but guess what? I already know. IM NOT GOING TO.</p>
<p>And I am not going to be guilted into thinking there is something wrong with me by a big pile of broken shit, just sitting around, waiting for me to breathe new life into it. I am not crafty. I don&#8217;t look at a broken pampasan chair and think &#8220;oh that would make an excellent light fixture!&#8221; Because I know, by the time I get home from work, run errands, take care of my pets, and eat a meal, there&#8217;s no chance in hell I am spray painting, double-sided-taping, or glitter-gluing anything. It&#8217;s a good day if I actually mend that little hole in my sweater I&#8217;ve been meaning to fix for months.</p>
<p><a href="http://yourmonthlyperiodical.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/80009330850233988_tkie7vqp_f.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-1093" title="80009330850233988_TkIE7VqP_f" src="http://yourmonthlyperiodical.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/80009330850233988_tkie7vqp_f.jpg?w=225&#038;h=300" alt="" width="225" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>My simple math tells me this is ok! In my rationale, my time and energy has it&#8217;s own value. If any project will take me longer than 2 hours, it needs to be something worth more than $30&#8211; and that doesn&#8217;t include supply costs, and inevitable crafting rage. So if it&#8217;s going to cost me $20 in paint, then take 2 hours of my time, plus cause me anxiety, the value of my broken item better go up at least $50. Which a broken lawn chair reupholstered by belts, or a mail-holder made from an old window shutter, is absolutely not worth to me.</p>
<p>Yes, it would be just splendid to live in a world where we never throw anything out and everyone is so goddamn Pinteresting they can&#8217;t even fit all their creative awesomeness in a mason jar. And maybe some ambitious, crafty women out there are eternally grateful for all the inspiration on their Pinterest boards&#8211; elegantly fishtail braiding their toddler&#8217;s hair while she consumes nutritious home-made baby food from a repurposed bowling ball. But for the rest of us rat-racing females, who cant even stand the word appliqué, Pinterest is Internet version of those shoes you&#8217;ve been meaning to have repaired, that wonderful torte recipe your mother-in-law gave you 4 years ago, and the blanket you began crocheting that still looks like a scarf.</p>
<div id="attachment_1158" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://yourmonthlyperiodical.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/p1070937.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1158" title="P1070937" src="http://yourmonthlyperiodical.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/p1070937.jpg?w=300&#038;h=226" alt="" width="300" height="226" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">CRAFTING RAGE</p></div>
<p>If it makes you feel guilty, toss it. This includes stacks of unfinished projects and boards full of complicated recipes. Let it all go and see how much better you feel. While you oggle some affluent family&#8217;s bathtub, filling up boards with things that, in the big picture, don&#8217;t even matter, you are doing nothing for human progress. Life is too short to waste planning an imaginary future on the Internet. Don&#8217;t let Pinterest make you believe otherwise.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1055/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1055/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1055&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://yourmonthlyperiodical.com/2012/09/14/well-isnt-that-pinteresting/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>38</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://yourmonthlyperiodical.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/p1070926.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://yourmonthlyperiodical.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/p1070926.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">P1070926</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/ab9cbc6202a6afcee603cc458806db94?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bitchyeditor</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://yourmonthlyperiodical.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/p1070926.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">P1070926</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://yourmonthlyperiodical.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/167548048607107328_jlgtez7f_f.jpg?w=200" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">167548048607107328_jLGTEZ7F_f</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://yourmonthlyperiodical.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/80009330850233988_tkie7vqp_f.jpg?w=225" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">80009330850233988_TkIE7VqP_f</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://yourmonthlyperiodical.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/p1070937.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">P1070937</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Weird Science: Testing Brains in Vats</title>
		<link>http://laughtersounds.wordpress.com/2012/10/16/weird-science-testing-brains-in-vats/</link>
		<comments>http://laughtersounds.wordpress.com/2012/10/16/weird-science-testing-brains-in-vats/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2012 00:12:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lucas Schleicher</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brain in a vat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[philosophy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quantum chromodynamics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quantum mechanics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rene Descartes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[simulated reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[skepticism]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://laughtersounds.wordpress.com/?p=122</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I don&#8217;t know how seriously other scientists will take this, but according to this article at Phys.org, physicists at the University of Bonn believe they can develop a test that will accurately measure whether or not we are a bunch of brains in a vat. Or just one one brain in a vat. The test would [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=122&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://laughtersounds.wordpress.com/2012/10/16/weird-science-testing-brains-in-vats/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://laughtersounds.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/rene_descartes.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://laughtersounds.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/rene_descartes.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">rene_descartes</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/44a888884ed6c69563ee0200c976f861?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F1.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Luke</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Struggling Artists and Pain</title>
		<link>http://cristianmihai.net/2012/10/14/struggling-artists-and-pain/</link>
		<comments>http://cristianmihai.net/2012/10/14/struggling-artists-and-pain/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2012 15:49:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Cristian Mihai</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[About Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Essays]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[literature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cristianmihai.net/?p=1818</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There are a lot of people out there who think that you have to suffer in order to create real art. For a long time I thought so myself. I think there&#8217;s something about the definition of the artist&#8230; a misunderstood individual with a reckless behavior, prone to addictions and depression, all that stuff. And [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1818&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://cristianmihaid.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/artists.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1824" title="artists" alt="" src="http://cristianmihaid.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/artists.jpg" height="260" width="423" /></a>There are a lot of people out there who think that you have to suffer in order to create real art. For a long time I thought so myself. I think there&#8217;s something about the definition of the artist&#8230; a misunderstood individual with a reckless behavior, prone to addictions and depression, all that stuff. And there are numerous examples of writers, painters, singers, whose lives were terrible.<span id="more-1818"></span></p>
<p>In a way, it&#8217;s somehow true. You know, you can&#8217;t fully understand love unless you get your heart broken, you can&#8217;t write about all that&#8217;s terrible and sad and greedy and painful in human nature until you experience it. Or at least observe it. But is there a certain amount of pain required before one becomes a &#8220;true&#8221; artist? Can pain be measured? Not physical pain (that one can be measured), but that pain that you can&#8217;t locate anywhere on your body.</p>
<p>I think it all comes down to how much life changes us, how we react and learn from our mistakes and experiences. I also believe that pain or suffering aren&#8217;t required to become a writer. You don&#8217;t have to be starving in order to write the next Great American Novel. You need the right message to transmit and the right tools to make people understand it.</p>
<p>Like I said, for a long time I used to think that art never comes out of happiness. I used to write in my darkest moments, when there was nothing else to do. Every time you pass a point of no return, there&#8217;s only one thing left to do. You can write about it. I used to think that you have to hit rock bottom because that way art will be the only thing you have left. You know, when you write to live, not the other way around.</p>
<p>But I changed my mind about all this. Well, Max Blecher changed my mind. He was a Romanian writer. He&#8217;s not even famous in our country, even though I consider him to be the most talented writer ever to be born in this country. At the age of 19 he was diagnosed with Pott&#8217;s disease, a terrible disease that confined him to bed. He spent the next 10 years of his life moving from one sanatorium to another. He corresponded with a lot of great writers, including Andre Breton, Andre Gide, and Martin Heidegger.</p>
<p>During his brief existence he published 2 novels. And he never got a chance to finish a third one. All of them are autobiographical and revolve around him fighting his disease. Of course, you can feel his pain, his suffering, all that. But in one of his novels he said that people think that you need to suffer in order to become an artist. But he thought that there were a lot of great writers who lived long, happy lives.</p>
<p>I find that ironic. I think we&#8217;re going to struggle to find someone who suffered more than this guy, yet he believed art to be more than the product of struggling people.</p>
<p>Art is a means of escaping oppression or fighting against it. But you don&#8217;t have to experience oppression in order to write about it, in order to make a stand. In the end, it all comes down to our own capability to understand and analyze life.</p>
<p>Pain doesn&#8217;t inspire anything in us. Pain just hardens our souls, makes us immune to tragedy.</p>
<p>Isn&#8217;t it true that we write about the things we had and lost not because of the pain we feel, but because we wish to recapture the moments of joy, to keep the flame alive long after our memories have turned to dust?</p>
<h6 class="zemanta-related-title">Related articles</h6>
<ul class="zemanta-article-ul zemanta-article-ul-image" style="margin:0;padding:0;overflow:hidden;">
<li class="zemanta-article-ul-li-image zemanta-article-ul-li" style="padding:0;background:none;list-style:none;display:block;float:left;vertical-align:top;text-align:left;width:84px;font-size:11px;margin:2px 10px 10px 2px;"><a style="box-shadow:0 0 4px #999;padding:2px;display:block;border-radius:2px;text-decoration:none;" href="http://cristianmihai.net/2012/09/03/being-a-writer/" target="_blank"><img style="padding:0;margin:0;border:0;display:block;width:80px;max-width:100%;" alt="" src="http://i.zemanta.com/110120671_80_80.jpg" /></a><a style="display:block;overflow:hidden;text-decoration:none;line-height:12pt;height:80px;padding:5px 2px 0;" href="http://cristianmihai.net/2012/09/03/being-a-writer/" target="_blank">Being a Writer</a></li>
<li class="zemanta-article-ul-li-image zemanta-article-ul-li" style="padding:0;background:none;list-style:none;display:block;float:left;vertical-align:top;text-align:left;width:84px;font-size:11px;margin:2px 10px 10px 2px;"><a style="box-shadow:0 0 4px #999;padding:2px;display:block;border-radius:2px;text-decoration:none;" href="http://cristianmihai.net/2012/08/27/write-about-what-you-know/" target="_blank"><img style="padding:0;margin:0;border:0;display:block;width:80px;max-width:100%;" alt="" src="http://i.zemanta.com/108921445_80_80.jpg" /></a><a style="display:block;overflow:hidden;text-decoration:none;line-height:12pt;height:80px;padding:5px 2px 0;" href="http://cristianmihai.net/2012/08/27/write-about-what-you-know/" target="_blank">Write About What You Know</a></li>
<li class="zemanta-article-ul-li-image zemanta-article-ul-li" style="padding:0;background:none;list-style:none;display:block;float:left;vertical-align:top;text-align:left;width:84px;font-size:11px;margin:2px 10px 10px 2px;"><a style="box-shadow:0 0 4px #999;padding:2px;display:block;border-radius:2px;text-decoration:none;" href="http://cristianmihai.net/2012/09/20/being-an-observer/" target="_blank"><img style="padding:0;margin:0;border:0;display:block;width:80px;max-width:100%;" alt="" src="http://i.zemanta.com/113405489_80_80.jpg" /></a><a style="display:block;overflow:hidden;text-decoration:none;line-height:12pt;height:80px;padding:5px 2px 0;" href="http://cristianmihai.net/2012/09/20/being-an-observer/" target="_blank">Being an Observer</a></li>
<li class="zemanta-article-ul-li-image zemanta-article-ul-li" style="padding:0;background:none;list-style:none;display:block;float:left;vertical-align:top;text-align:left;width:84px;font-size:11px;margin:2px 10px 10px 2px;"><a style="box-shadow:0 0 4px #999;padding:2px;display:block;border-radius:2px;text-decoration:none;" href="http://cristianmihai.net/2012/10/08/what-makes-you-unique/" target="_blank"><img style="padding:0;margin:0;border:0;display:block;width:80px;max-width:100%;" alt="" src="http://i.zemanta.com/117169475_80_80.jpg" /></a><a style="display:block;overflow:hidden;text-decoration:none;line-height:12pt;height:80px;padding:5px 2px 0;" href="http://cristianmihai.net/2012/10/08/what-makes-you-unique/" target="_blank">What Makes You Unique</a></li>
<li class="zemanta-article-ul-li-image zemanta-article-ul-li" style="padding:0;background:none;list-style:none;display:block;float:left;vertical-align:top;text-align:left;width:84px;font-size:11px;margin:2px 10px 10px 2px;"><a style="box-shadow:0 0 4px #999;padding:2px;display:block;border-radius:2px;text-decoration:none;" href="http://cristianmihai.net/2012/09/23/salman-rushdie-on-writing/" target="_blank"><img style="padding:0;margin:0;border:0;display:block;width:80px;max-width:100%;" alt="" src="http://i.zemanta.com/113950514_80_80.jpg" /></a><a style="display:block;overflow:hidden;text-decoration:none;line-height:12pt;height:80px;padding:5px 2px 0;" href="http://cristianmihai.net/2012/09/23/salman-rushdie-on-writing/" target="_blank">Salman Rushdie on Writing</a></li>
</ul>
<div class="zemanta-pixie" style="margin-top:10px;height:15px;"><img class="zemanta-pixie-img" style="border:none;float:right;" alt="" src="http://img.zemanta.com/pixy.gif?x-id=5868ce38-29f1-4e3d-b1e0-ebaef2ecd672" /></div>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://cristianmihai.net/category/blog/about-writing/'>About Writing</a>, <a href='http://cristianmihai.net/category/blog/essays/'>Essays</a> Tagged: <a href='http://cristianmihai.net/tag/art/'>Art</a>, <a href='http://cristianmihai.net/tag/culture/'>culture</a>, <a href='http://cristianmihai.net/tag/fiction/'>fiction</a>, <a href='http://cristianmihai.net/tag/literature/'>literature</a>, <a href='http://cristianmihai.net/tag/pain/'>Pain</a>, <a href='http://cristianmihai.net/tag/writer/'>Writer</a>, <a href='http://cristianmihai.net/tag/writing/'>writing</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1818/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1818/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1818&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://cristianmihai.net/2012/10/14/struggling-artists-and-pain/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>142</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c87b0e5b32e3383df7109d0c4a544dce?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mihaicristiandaniel</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cristianmihaid.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/artists.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">artists</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://i.zemanta.com/110120671_80_80.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://i.zemanta.com/108921445_80_80.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://i.zemanta.com/113405489_80_80.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://i.zemanta.com/117169475_80_80.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://i.zemanta.com/113950514_80_80.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://img.zemanta.com/pixy.gif?x-id=5868ce38-29f1-4e3d-b1e0-ebaef2ecd672" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tonight\&#8217;s Town Hall Debate: What Would Your One Question Be?</title>
		<link>http://blog.prodigalpaul.com/2012/10/16/town-hall-debate-what-would-your-one-question-be/</link>
		<comments>http://blog.prodigalpaul.com/2012/10/16/town-hall-debate-what-would-your-one-question-be/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2012 16:22:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Paul Burkhart</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Just for Fun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2012]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Barack Obama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[debate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mit romney]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[presidential election]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.prodigalpaul.com/?p=7569</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Update: I&#8217;ve written some specific reflections on the debate last night. Tuesday was the second Presidential Debate of the 2012 election. We&#8217;ve had one Presidential and one Vice-Presidential Debate so far, both of which were traditional debate formats. This debate, though, was a &#8220;Town Hall&#8220;-style debate in which the candidates walked freely and spoke to [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=7569&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://paulburkhart.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/ap528118692098.jpeg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7570" title="town-hall-debate-ap" alt="" src="http://paulburkhart.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/ap528118692098.jpeg" height="400" width="584" /></a></p>
<p><strong>Update:</strong> I&#8217;ve written <a title="A Presidential Debate Debrief {#3}" href="http://blog.prodigalpaul.com/2012/10/17/a-presidential-debate-debrief-3/"><strong>some specific reflections</strong></a> on the debate last night.</p>
<p>Tuesday was the second Presidential Debate of the 2012 election. We&#8217;ve had <a title="Some post-Presidential Debate thoughts… {#1}" href="http://blog.prodigalpaul.com/2012/10/04/some-post-presidential-debate-thoughts/">one Presidential</a> and <a title="Some post-Vice-Presidential Debate thoughts… {#2}" href="http://blog.prodigalpaul.com/2012/10/12/some-post-vice-presidential-debate-thoughts-2/">one Vice-Presidential</a> Debate so far, both of which were traditional debate formats. This debate, though, was a &#8220;<a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2012/10/16/us/politics/strict-rules-behind-debates-looser-town-hall-format.html">Town Hall</a>&#8220;-style debate in which the candidates walked freely and spoke to a small studio audience that encircled them as they took their questions directly from audience members. They did not know the questions beforehand, but as the years have gone on, <a href="http://thepage.time.com/2012/10/14/moderator-role-under-scrutiny-before-the-debate/">the Debate Commission has limited</a> both the ability to have back-and-forth exchanges with the audience members as well as the follow-up role of the moderator, giving them far more space to dance around the question with no accountability (these changes were put in place after Clinton devastated Bush <a href="http://youtu.be/7ffbFvKlWqE">in this exchange</a> in 1992).</p>
<p>This got me thinking: what if I was there, and I got <em>one shot</em> to ask them <em>one</em> question. I&#8217;ve had my <a title="I’m a one issue voter: specific abuses of Executive power {pt.3}" href="http://blog.prodigalpaul.com/2012/02/29/im-a-one-issue-voter-specific-abuses-of-executive-power-pt-3/">fair share of complaints</a> about <a title="I almost voted for Romney, but then I remembered…" href="http://blog.prodigalpaul.com/2012/09/13/i-almost-voted-for-romney-but-then-i-remembered/">both</a> <a title="I almost voted for Obama, but then I remembered…" href="http://blog.prodigalpaul.com/2012/09/17/i-almost-voted-for-obama-but-then-i-remembered/">candidates</a> (<a title="Catholics Aren’t Crazy: Paul Ryan &amp; the 2013 House Budget" href="http://blog.prodigalpaul.com/2012/03/21/catholics-arent-crazy-paul-ryan-the-2013-house-budget/">and their running mates</a>), so boiling all of this down to one question that would both be difficult for them politicize <em>and</em> address the most issues I&#8217;m concerned about was difficult, but this is what I came up with:</p>
<blockquote><p>Mr. President and Governor: as a social worker, I&#8217;m taught that the goals I make with my clients should be S.M.A.R.T. goals: <strong>S</strong>imple, <strong>M</strong>easurable, <strong>A</strong>ttainable, <strong>R</strong>ealistic, and <strong>T</strong>imely. Using this criteria, could each of you, in terms that are not cliched, rhetorical, or abstract, tell me what the goals of the War on Terror are, and what would represent the end and accomplishment of that War? Thank you.</p></blockquote>
<p><strong>What do you think would be their answers to this question? What would be your question?</strong> (And how do you think they&#8217;d answer?) Sound off in the comments below, and tune in at 9pm tonight for the debate.</p>
<p>[<em>image credit: AP photo, from <a href="http://prospect.org/article/five-fool-proof-tips-winning-town-hall-debate">an article</a> at The American Prospect</em>]</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://blog.prodigalpaul.com/category/just-for-fun/'>Just for Fun</a>, <a href='http://blog.prodigalpaul.com/category/news/'>News</a>, <a href='http://blog.prodigalpaul.com/category/personal/'>Personal</a>, <a href='http://blog.prodigalpaul.com/category/politics/'>Politics</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/7569/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/7569/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=7569&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://blog.prodigalpaul.com/2012/10/16/town-hall-debate-what-would-your-one-question-be/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>59</slash:comments>
		<georss:point>39.952335 -75.163789</georss:point>
		<geo:lat>39.952335</geo:lat>
		<geo:long>-75.163789</geo:long>
		<media:thumbnail url="http://paulburkhart.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/american-flag-wood-header.jpeg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://paulburkhart.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/american-flag-wood-header.jpeg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">american-flag-wood-header</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/8f750fdc13756bf5250296dd0e1d1beb?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=X" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">burkhartpm</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://paulburkhart.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/ap528118692098.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">town-hall-debate-ap</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bloggomunications</title>
		<link>http://somethingfathappened.wordpress.com/2012/10/15/bloggomunications/</link>
		<comments>http://somethingfathappened.wordpress.com/2012/10/15/bloggomunications/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2012 19:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Maggie O'C</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[back handed compliments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blog community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[that was a stupid thing to write]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://somethingfathappened.wordpress.com/?p=2507</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I am surprised at how much I have learned from blogging. Obviously writing more and writing regularly has honed my technical skills. I am far more conscientious about word choice and sentence formation, hopefully grammar but I ain&#8217;t fer sure on that. I have learned about  food and customs and people from around the world, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2507&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I am surprised at how much I have learned from blogging. Obviously writing more and writing regularly has honed my technical skills. I am far more conscientious about word choice and sentence formation, hopefully grammar but I ain&#8217;t fer sure on that.</p>
<p>I have learned about  food and customs and people from around the world, religions, governments, joys, sorrows and illnesses. I have made friends. I have laughed and cried and ground my teeth in anger over injustices visited upon my friends.  Just as people do when making friends in &#8220;real life&#8221;, in the blogosphere you get used to people&#8217;s idiosyncrasies and styles of communication. When are they joking? When are they serious? Who is sensitive? Who has a tough hide?  My friend Brigitte wrote a Freshly Pressed piece on <a href="http://brigittebanter.com/2012/04/06/a-gracious-guide-to-benevolent-blogging-five-tips/">Blogging Etiquette</a>, which is a good read for new bloggers as well as those that have been around a while.</p>
<p>I am a fairly blunt communicator. On WordPress I have learned to hold my tongue, don&#8217;t respond in anger (or at least don&#8217;t hit send in anger), don&#8217;t tease someone if you don&#8217;t know how they will take it, be sincere, be positive, be kind. I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;m particularly diplomatic and I call &#8216;em like I see &#8216;em. I think I&#8217;m fairly in tune to the blogs I follow regularly and I can tell when there is action going on between the lines.</p>
<p>I guess where I&#8217;m slowly going with this is that while we form friendships here on WordPress, we are still typing. We aren&#8217;t Skyping so we can see facial expressions. We aren&#8217;t on the phone so we can hear voice inflections. We are typing words on a screen. And as with email or texting, sometimes what you  type isn&#8217;t what you meant or you didn&#8217;t mean it like that! So what if you do hurt someone&#8217;s feelings by accident? What if someone calls you out for something you wrote to them in the Comments section that they didn&#8217;t care for?</p>
<p>Instead of getting defensive, dramatic, self-righteous, etc&#8230; pause for a minute and reread what you wrote. Ask yourself, &#8220;is there a chance that my comment didn&#8217;t come across the way I meant it to?&#8221; Just take a breath and think, &#8220;how would I react if someone wrote this to me?&#8221;</p>
<p>WordPress is such a gift. It is generally such a positive place and if people need to rant, they need to rant, it&#8217;s not about you, it&#8217;s about the writer and what they need to express. That doesn&#8217;t mean that our words don&#8217;t have consequences and sometimes people don&#8217;t want to read our rants and that is fair. My main point is, in the Comments section, if necessary think hard before you hit Reply.</p>
<div id="attachment_2513" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://somethingfathappened.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/saying-make-hideous-drag-gay-pride-parade-ecard-someecards.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-2513" title="saying-make-hideous-drag-gay-pride-parade-ecard-someecards" alt="" src="http://somethingfathappened.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/saying-make-hideous-drag-gay-pride-parade-ecard-someecards.jpg?w=300&#038;h=167" height="167" width="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">You never know when you might deliver a back-handed compliment.</p></div>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2507/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2507/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2507&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://somethingfathappened.wordpress.com/2012/10/15/bloggomunications/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>171</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/0e9c3ecee26e0de3bf7268d6b038a472?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jetmag26</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://somethingfathappened.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/saying-make-hideous-drag-gay-pride-parade-ecard-someecards.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">saying-make-hideous-drag-gay-pride-parade-ecard-someecards</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>