<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2013 20:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>The Grass Is Greener Where You Water It</title>
		<link>http://bekahoutsidethebox.com/2012/12/31/the-grass-is-greener-where-you-water-it/</link>
		<comments>http://bekahoutsidethebox.com/2012/12/31/the-grass-is-greener-where-you-water-it/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 01:30:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bekahoutsidethebox</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[About]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Self Care]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yoga]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[experiment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mindfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Neil Barringham]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[satya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stories]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://bekahoutsidethebox.com/?p=322</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Someone close to me once said that I have a &#8220;catastrophic imagination&#8221; because I have a strong tendency to imagine the worst. A friend doesn&#8217;t return a phone call &#8211; obviously they hate me. In a dark alley &#8211; obviously I&#8217;m about to get raped, mugged, and murdered. Start to get sick &#8211; obviously I&#8217;m [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=322&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_323" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 280px"><a href="http://randomactsofkindnezz.wordpress.com/tag/neil-barringham/"><img class=" wp-image-323 " alt="" src="http://bekahoutsidethebox.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/pinned-image.jpeg?w=270&#038;h=384" width="270" height="384" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">{Photo Credit :: Random Acts of Kindness}</p></div>
<p>Someone close to me once said that I have a &#8220;catastrophic imagination&#8221; because I have a strong tendency to imagine the worst. A friend doesn&#8217;t return a phone call &#8211; <em>obviously</em> they hate me. In a dark alley &#8211; <em>obviously</em> I&#8217;m about to get raped, mugged, and murdered. Start to get sick &#8211; <em>obviously</em> I&#8217;m about to die. Can&#8217;t do a particular yoga pose &#8211; <em>obviously</em> I&#8217;m a terrible yogi. You get the picture &#8230;</p>
<p>And (of course) it&#8217;s not just that I imagine these things once and move on, oh no. All of these stories tend to swirl around in my head over and over and over again. Thinking this way has become so habitual that I barely even register when I&#8217;m doing it anymore, and once you <em>think</em> something often enough, it <em>almost</em> seems to become true. Maybe you can relate?</p>
<p>But I heard this clever twist on a familiar saying the other day: <strong>the grass is greener where you water it</strong>. And it occurred to me that investing my mental and emotional energy in these sort of repetitive negative thoughts was essentially like &#8220;watering&#8221; them &#8230; and so long as I continue to water them, they will continue to flourish. Plus, our stores of mental and emotional energy are limited, and if we&#8217;re expending large quantities on thinking about what we <em>don&#8217;t</em> want to happen, that leaves little energy left over for the good stuff!</p>
<p><strong>A different approach? </strong></p>
<p>Over the past few days I have been thinking a lot about what a different approach might entail and I certainly do not have all of the answers. (Sorry to disappoint! ;)) But I do know how I would like to go about getting started with exploring (and maybe even breaking) this habit, and if you can relate to the above, maybe you&#8217;d like to start here too:</p>
<ul>
<li><span style="line-height:13px;"><strong>Noticing.</strong> (Really, this is always the first step, right?) Becoming aware of the thoughts and the simple fact that they&#8217;re happening. Noticing what feelings arise before, during, and after engaging in the habitual behavior. </span></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Getting curious. </strong>Asking questions about what is <em>really</em> going on here. Examining where these thoughts are originating from and paying attention to what triggers these negative patterns of thinking.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Returning to the facts. </strong>Imaginary catastrophes are just that &#8211; imaginary, made up, not real. They are often rooted in our fears about what might happen in the future or our reactions to things that happened in the past. But, returning to the facts brings us back to the present and back to the Truth.</li>
</ul>
<p>Will this work? Will noticing, getting curious, and returning to the facts help me (and you) learn how to &#8220;water&#8221; the areas of our lives that we want to thrive? Stay tuned, let&#8217;s find out together &#8230;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/322/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/322/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=322&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://bekahoutsidethebox.com/2012/12/31/the-grass-is-greener-where-you-water-it/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://bekahoutsidethebox.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/pinned-image.jpeg?w=105" />
		<media:content url="http://bekahoutsidethebox.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/pinned-image.jpeg?w=105" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Pinned Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/af2b0226921b9a6a0cf0e3c4dd5d5acc?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bekahoutsidethebox</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://bekahoutsidethebox.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/pinned-image.jpeg?w=450" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rooftops</title>
		<link>http://thebluehourmagazine.com/2012/12/31/rooftops-heather-minette/</link>
		<comments>http://thebluehourmagazine.com/2012/12/31/rooftops-heather-minette/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 08:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bluehourmagazine</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Poetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Heather Minette]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Journey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Poets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reckoning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wisdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Womanhood]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thebluehourmagazine.com/?p=1353</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I looked for her on the rooftops of Brooklyn, the makeshift balconies of Manhattan, and the subway in between. On the mountaintops of Spain, the dirty pubs of Dublin, and every European train. On southern country roads, and the foothills of Tennessee, and a lake house preserving childhood dreams. In the classrooms of philosophers and [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1353&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I looked for her on the rooftops of Brooklyn,<br />
the makeshift balconies of Manhattan,<br />
and the subway in between.</p>
<p>On the mountaintops of Spain,<br />
the dirty pubs of Dublin,<br />
and every European train.</p>
<p>On southern country roads,<br />
and the foothills of Tennessee,<br />
and a lake house preserving childhood dreams.</p>
<p>In the classrooms of philosophers and mystics,<br />
the offices of scholars,<br />
and the garden of a Buddhist.</p>
<p>In a home painted yellow,<br />
behind an ill-fitting apron,<br />
and white picket fence.</p>
<p>In the cramped apartments of men who wrote,<br />
and drank,<br />
and beneath the sheets of those who understood.</p>
<p>On the folded pages of library books,<br />
the texture of painted canvas,<br />
and the sound of piano keys.</p>
<p>I looked for her through my bedroom window,<br />
barefoot and hardly clothed,<br />
not lonely, but alone.</p>
<p>I looked for her,<br />
and did not find her,<br />
but instead, created her.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1353/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1353/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1353&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thebluehourmagazine.com/2012/12/31/rooftops-heather-minette/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/5abfe9208968b9e6f64ae7b114fb9511?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bluehourmagazine</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>And They Lived Fearlessly Ever After . . .</title>
		<link>http://oliotalk.wordpress.com/2012/12/31/and-they-lived-fearlessly-ever-after/</link>
		<comments>http://oliotalk.wordpress.com/2012/12/31/and-they-lived-fearlessly-ever-after/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 14:28:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>skaushiva</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[People]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Places]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Abuse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amanat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Candlelight vigil]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Damini]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Delhi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jantar Mantar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life of Pi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Memories of Fear]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nirbhaya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rape]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Women's freedom]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://oliotalk.wordpress.com/?p=280</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[ &#160; So then, what is it about this 23 year-old girl who raised the conscience of India on December 16, 2012? Was it the barbaric way in which she met her end? Was she the last straw that broke the back of an overladen camel? Was it her young age, her thwarted ambitions and aspirations, or her [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=280&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size:11px;line-height:17px;"> </span>&nbsp;</p>
<div id="attachment_292" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://oliotalk.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/fearless.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-292 " title="Cry against violence on women" alt="After Amanat - the fight continues" src="http://oliotalk.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/fearless.jpg?w=300&#038;h=224" width="300" height="224" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Pink Rising in India?</p></div>
<p>So then, what is it about this 23 year-old girl who raised the conscience of India on December 16, 2012?</p>
<p>Was it the barbaric way in which she met her end?</p>
<p>Was she the last straw that broke the back of an overladen camel?</p>
<p>Was it her young age, her thwarted ambitions and aspirations, or her<br />
parents’ unfulfilled hopes, dreams and expectations?</p>
<p>Was it her last wish, to be able to survive and make it out of her nightmarish ordeal?</p>
<p>All the above perhaps, and maybe just something more.</p>
<div></div>
<p>She did not step out with her friend that night on a mission to alter the conscience of her country. She had no intentions to lift the blinders off the eyes of a male-dominated society either. She was clearly not out to get the media to christen her with a fancy new name. And it perhaps did not matter one bit to her or her family if she were labeled a brave-heart or not, while she struggled to survive at the hospitals.</p>
<p>Look again, look beneath all those glossy labels that were bestowed upon her and you will find just another young girl, with her whole life ahead of her. Someone who was out at the cinemas one weekend and stepped into the wrong bus on her way back home, for which she paid with her life. And yes, it happened in the ugliest possible way right around dinnertime in the capital of our country.</p>
<p>Over a decade ago, my college curriculum included a documentary titled <i>‘Memories of Fear’</i>, a film by Madhushree Dutta. I still remember how sensitively and accurately it captured the fears a girl grows up with in her journey to womanhood and beyond.</p>
<p>What was called fear in my mother’s days became awareness for the world at large with the passage of time. The truth is that the vacuum that builds up in a girl’s stomach as she quickens her pace through a desolate road, looking back every other minute to ensure there is no other shadow lurking behind her, is nothing but fear.</p>
<p>Fear is the single common heirloom, that as girls in India, we all inherit from our mothers, grandmothers, aunts, sisters and friends. Fear for self-preservation, and of men who can do things to hurt and shame us. We learn to weave this fear seamlessly into our lives and never even realize when it becomes second nature. This perpetual fear eats into a woman’s carefree spirit and keeps her on guard at all times.</p>
<p>A friendly pat from an uncle on the bottom, or a male colleague’s claims of great working chemistry are both met with suspicion, followed by the cold shoulder. While we can turn a deaf ear to despicable remarks about certain parts of our body from a group of rogue teens, it takes longer to deal with the trauma of being groped on a crowded bus.</p>
<p>We figure ways of avoiding a run-in with the neighbourhood lech, and develop at least three different tactics of accepting coins from shopkeepers without having our palms unnecessarily felt. Even on a student budget, we willingly pay a premium for balcony seats at the cinema to avoid the flashers in the front stalls. As a general rule, we prefer the safety of aisle seats both in air and on ground. We have heard about hidden recording devices and two-way mirrors in changing rooms, and are alert even before we take off our stoles. We prefer to avoid places, situations and people who make us uncomfortable or give us the creeps. Many friendships do get affected, and sometimes, even years of trust come under scrutiny too. Personal freedom and professional progress are rarely unfettered for a woman.</p>
<p>Between growing up to be a lady and becoming independent in a society that is full of frustrated and perverted men on the prowl, it should not come as a surprise that girls grow up faster. Do we even have a choice?</p>
<p>As protests continue across the nation for this young girl who has lost her life most tragically, everybody seems to have their own views on what needs to be changed, who needs to be blamed or how the offenders should be dealt with. I do pray and wish that these protests and vigils bring about some meaningful change for all of us. But I also think it is time to dig a little deeper.</p>
<p>Decades past our independence, on the brink of a day when a jolly ride into space is no longer just a dream, it is a shame that in the world’s largest democracy, a woman cannot be guaranteed a life free from the fear of being manhandled, attacked, abused, shamed, ridiculed or victimized in any form simply because she is physically weaker. Long before we encourage our sons to be MBA’s, consultants, doctors, engineers or scientists, we need to teach them to first be humane.</p>
<p>They say that she was out to watch Life of Pi that fateful night.</p>
<p>Ironically, a movie that is a story of survival against all odds by relying on faith. She did not make it after a fortnight, but perhaps in her fight for survival lies a cue for all of us, to have the faith that we can indeed bring about change if we continue to make ourselves heard.</p>
<p>I am not giving up hope yet.</p>
<p>Someday, I hope little girls in my country will be living in a time when they can relate to fairytales again.</p>
<p>PS: For those interested,  I had written an article on this subject way back in 2009 as well.</p>
<p><a href="http://oliotalk.wordpress.com/2009/03/08/flagging-fear/" rel="nofollow">http://oliotalk.wordpress.com/2009/03/08/flagging-fear/</a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/280/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/280/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=280&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://oliotalk.wordpress.com/2012/12/31/and-they-lived-fearlessly-ever-after/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>36</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c83413071d2517087b54973a42a514b7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">skaushiva</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://oliotalk.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/fearless.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Cry against violence on women</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>2012 On My Mobile Phone</title>
		<link>http://echwaluphotography.wordpress.com/2012/12/07/2012-on-my-mobile-phone/</link>
		<comments>http://echwaluphotography.wordpress.com/2012/12/07/2012-on-my-mobile-phone/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2012 14:45:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>echwaluphotography</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Potrait]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Poverty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Random]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2012 on Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[African Landscape]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[African Market]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[African on Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[African Photographer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Belfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Landscape Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile Phones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Night Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Northern Ireland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photographing Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Portraits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Road side market]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uganda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ugandan Photographer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ugandan photography]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://echwaluphotography.wordpress.com/?p=2720</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The United States economy is nine times the size of Africa&#8217;s, but Africa has twice as many mobile phones according to Harvard Business Review (HBR). Visually, Africa’s story is silently being told through these little gadgets. Unfortunately, many will remain as such. Silent. I am a perfect example on how good stories are photographed and [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2720&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States economy is nine times the size of Africa&#8217;s, but Africa <a href="http://blogs.hbr.org/cs/2012/07/africas_true_mobile_revolution.html">has twice as many mobile phones</a> according to Harvard Business Review (HBR).</p>
<p>Visually, Africa’s story is silently being told through these little gadgets. Unfortunately, many will remain as such. Silent.<a href="http://echwaluphotography.wordpress.com/2012/12/07/2012-on-my-mobile-phone/01-7/" rel="attachment wp-att-2721"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-2721" alt="01" src="http://echwaluphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/011.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>I am a perfect example on how good stories are photographed and stashed because they were taken on a mobile phone.</p>
<p>No wonder the only other thing more personal in my possession except my mind is a mobile phone. And that in itself underlines how important this tool is, not just in my personal life but professional one as well.<a href="http://echwaluphotography.wordpress.com/2012/12/07/2012-on-my-mobile-phone/02-10/" rel="attachment wp-att-2722"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-2722" alt="02" src="http://echwaluphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/021.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>Not until 15 months ago, a mobile phone to me was about making calls, texting and storing relevant phone contacts. And yes, playing some games too. That role however has drastically changed as i professionally grew as a photographer.<a href="http://echwaluphotography.wordpress.com/2012/12/07/2012-on-my-mobile-phone/03-14/" rel="attachment wp-att-2723"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-2723" alt="03" src="http://echwaluphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/031.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>Today I see a mobile phone as a very important documentary tool. Perhaps one of the most important tools. I know many of you might not necessarily believe me but here are my reasons.</p>
<p><b><i>Professional Camera</i></b></p>
<p>Just what is a professional camera? Honestly, I don’t have an answer to this question. This year alone, I have got over a dozen “professional camera advice” request from some of my followers. In return, I have always given a fair recommendation.<a href="http://echwaluphotography.wordpress.com/2012/12/07/2012-on-my-mobile-phone/04-10/" rel="attachment wp-att-2724"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-2724" alt="04" src="http://echwaluphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/041.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>I believe there are no professional cameras but people are. A perfect example is an <a href="http://lightbox.time.com/2012/08/16/an-iphone-in-congo-photos-by-michael-christopher-brown/#1">“iPhone in DR Congo”</a> , a photo project done by Michael Christopher Brown about the effects of minerals on every life of a Congolese.</p>
<p><b><i>Personal Moments</i></b></p>
<p>The most personal, naughty, moments in life are mostly taken using a mobile phone. These are the pictures that in our memories the longest. They are usually poorly composed with suicidal lighting but rich in terms of reality, originality and honesty. They speak volumes about who we really are. Maybe that’s why many people hold their phones close to their chests because there is a lot we protect beyond the naughty text messages in our <em>inboxes</em>.<a href="http://echwaluphotography.wordpress.com/2012/12/07/2012-on-my-mobile-phone/05-9/" rel="attachment wp-att-2725"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-2725" alt="05" src="http://echwaluphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/051.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p><b><i>Invisibility</i></b></p>
<p>A mobile camera is perhaps the most open, yet secretive camera anyone can have. There is this casualness associated with people taking pictures using a phone. I have many times dropped by heavy camera gear for my Nokia Lumia 800 to record everyday life in Kampala unnoticed. And on every occasion, I haven’t infuriated anyone.<a href="http://echwaluphotography.wordpress.com/2012/12/07/2012-on-my-mobile-phone/010-8/" rel="attachment wp-att-2726"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-2726" alt="010" src="http://echwaluphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/010.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>I remember for example n October this year when I took a picture of the peace sculpture at the Kololo Independence grounds. At the time, there was ongoing preparation at the ground for the celebration of Uganda’s 50<sup>th</sup> anniversary. The presidents security personal were all over the place. Cameras were not allowed within the vicinity that day, BUT mobile phones were allowed.</p>
<p><strong><i>Light Weight</i></strong></p>
<p>On a normal day my backpack usually has, two heavy cameras, two lenses (Wide angle and a zoom), a laptop, an extension, phone chargers, iPod charger, laptop charger, lens cleaners, head phones, face towel, water, etc. Whenever I drop that for a phone, it feels like carrying one piece of a crisp. Very light. Fatigue does not come in as fast as it would have.<a href="http://echwaluphotography.wordpress.com/2012/12/07/2012-on-my-mobile-phone/06-8/" rel="attachment wp-att-2727"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-2727" alt="06" src="http://echwaluphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/061.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p><strong><i>Price Value</i></strong></p>
<p>I recently met a guy who looked to be genuinely interested in photography. He was telling me how the prices of what he called professional cameras are prohibitive. In the very conversation, he was over the moon, bragging about the eminent arrival of his iPhone 5. I broke it down for him this way.<a href="http://echwaluphotography.wordpress.com/2012/12/07/2012-on-my-mobile-phone/07-7/" rel="attachment wp-att-2728"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-2728" alt="07" src="http://echwaluphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/07.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>One of my favourite cameras is<a href="http://www.bhphotovideo.com/c/product/753766-REG/Canon_5757B002_EOS_Rebel_T3_Digital.html"> a Canon EOS Rebel T3 on Amazon</a>. It costs a paltry $550. (12.2MP APS-C CMOS Sensor, 18-55 EF-S Lens, 100-6400 ISO, 720p HD Movie Mode, 3 fps Continuous Shooting……). <a href="http://www.amazon.com/s/ref=nb_sb_noss_1?url=search-alias%3Delectronics&amp;field-keywords=iphone+5&amp;rh=n%3A172282%2Ck%3Aiphone+5&amp;ajr=2">An iPhone 5</a> on the hand costs $784. So which is cheaper?<a href="http://echwaluphotography.wordpress.com/2012/12/07/2012-on-my-mobile-phone/08-7/" rel="attachment wp-att-2729"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-2729" alt="08" src="http://echwaluphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/08.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>A lot of people walk around with “professional cameras”-read Mobile Phones and do not even realize it.</p>
<p>A camera does not have to weigh 5kg to qualify as a professional one. It does not have to make the 20 mega pixel mark to join the professional rank.<a href="http://echwaluphotography.wordpress.com/2012/12/07/2012-on-my-mobile-phone/09-6/" rel="attachment wp-att-2730"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-2730" alt="09" src="http://echwaluphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/09.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>Food for thought; what if <a href="http://www.novinite.com/view_news.php?id=133119">this picture of Gaddafi</a> was captured on a fake phone-We call them: Chinese Phones in Uganda. Imagine what your iPhone, Nokia, Samsung or Alcatel could have done!<a href="http://echwaluphotography.wordpress.com/2012/12/07/2012-on-my-mobile-phone/011-jpeg/" rel="attachment wp-att-2731"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-2731" alt="011.jpeg" src="http://echwaluphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/011-jpeg.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2720/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2720/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2720&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://echwaluphotography.wordpress.com/2012/12/07/2012-on-my-mobile-phone/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/b7d6ea3e7a567224697103002f8db850?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">echwaluphotography</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://echwaluphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/011.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">01</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://echwaluphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/021.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">02</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://echwaluphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/031.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">03</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://echwaluphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/041.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">04</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://echwaluphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/051.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">05</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://echwaluphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/010.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">010</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://echwaluphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/061.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">06</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://echwaluphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/07.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">07</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://echwaluphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/08.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">08</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://echwaluphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/09.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">09</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://echwaluphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/011-jpeg.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">011.jpeg</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Monomyth, Joseph Campbell, and Me</title>
		<link>http://deliberatedonkey.wordpress.com/2012/12/26/the-monomyth-joseph-campbell-and-me/</link>
		<comments>http://deliberatedonkey.wordpress.com/2012/12/26/the-monomyth-joseph-campbell-and-me/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2012 01:35:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Melanie</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[A Day in a Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[domestic violence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[heros journey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[intimate partner violence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[joseph campbell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[men hit women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the hero with a thousand faces]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[violence against women]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deliberatedonkey.wordpress.com/?p=3436</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Damn I hate it when this happens. I didn&#8217;t pick up this book to learn something about myself. It&#8217;s not me I was trying to impress. The quick synopsis that won&#8217;t get you even a &#8220;D&#8221; on any pop-quiz is this: The Hero With a Thousand Faces is Joseph Campbell&#8217;s influential study of world mythology. He set out to explain [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3436&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://deliberatedonkey.wordpress.com/2012/12/26/the-monomyth-joseph-campbell-and-me/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>58</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/2d4854fad14d7af9c5cd0d9d8c26972f?s=96&#38;d=wavatar&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tendingweeds</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://deliberatedonkey.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/heros-journey.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">&#34;We have not even to risk the adventure alone; for the heroes of all time have gone before us, the labyrinth is fully known; we have only to follow the thread of the hero-path.&#34;</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How To See Your New Year\&#8217;s Resolution Through</title>
		<link>http://daveknickerbocker.wordpress.com/2012/12/27/how-to-see-your-new-years-resolution-through/</link>
		<comments>http://daveknickerbocker.wordpress.com/2012/12/27/how-to-see-your-new-years-resolution-through/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2012 14:43:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dave Knickerbocker</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Random Thoughts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adventure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christianity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jesus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Motivation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New Year]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pruis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Religion and Spirituality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Resolution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snow Storm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Toyota]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://daveknickerbocker.wordpress.com/?p=2576</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This morning I noticed a Toyota Prius trying to get up a small hill that is very gradual.  It&#8217;s a small car that does wonders with gas mileage . . . normally. Northeast Ohio, where I live, was hit by a load of snow yesterday (Yes, the day after Christmas. Bummer.).  We used to live [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2576&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://commons.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Toyota_Prius_III_20090710_front.JPG" target="_blank"><img class="zemanta-img-inserted zemanta-img-configured" title="Toyota Prius III" alt="Toyota Prius III" src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/e/ed/Toyota_Prius_III_20090710_front.JPG/300px-Toyota_Prius_III_20090710_front.JPG" width="300" height="201" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Toyota Prius III (Photo credit: Wikipedia)</p></div>
<p>This morning I noticed a Toyota Prius trying to get up a small hill that is very gradual.  It&#8217;s a small car that does wonders with gas mileage . . . normally.</p>
<p>Northeast Ohio, where I live, was hit by a load of snow yesterday (Yes, the day <em>after</em> Christmas. Bummer.).  We used to live in Rochester, NY, where there was an abundance of snow removal equipment. That was because there was quite a bit of snow up there on a regular basis. In fact, our first winter there it was the snowiest city in the United States (except for Alaska).  After the first major snow storm that year I was amazed to see a small snow plow being driven by an employee of our town. It was just the right size for the sidewalk! Pretty cool.</p>
<p><span id="more-2576"></span>We don&#8217;t get that much snow where we live now.  When it does snow a ton the plows don&#8217;t get around as quickly because we aren&#8217;t equipped to remove so much at one shot.</p>
<p>The New Year is right around the corner.  It&#8217;s the time when we take a look at ourselves with constructive criticism. <em>What is it that I need to change about myself? Boy, I really let myself go last year!</em>  I like to think that the Holy Spirit capitalizes on this time of year. We could help him out by listening to his prodding about how he&#8217;d like to transform us a little more. Maybe a lot more. Sometimes that voice you hear isn&#8217;t you trying to improve yourself. Often times it&#8217;s God.</p>
<p>Identifying the goal is the first step. Then you must agree to try to accomplish it. After agreeing to accomplish it, we need to use the right tools to make it happen. We fail at our New Year&#8217;s Resolutions at this final step more often than the rest. Zechariah 4:6 says &#8220;‘Not by might nor by power, but by my Spirit,’ says the Lord Almighty. (NIV)&#8221;</p>
<p>And so the little Prius struggled in the depths, spinning and whirring to get the job done. He&#8217;d back up ten feet and charge forward to plow his way through, but to no avail.  I wonder what kind of mileage that guy got today.  From the looks of it, he had about six feet to the gallon in the minute that I watched. Eventually, he gave up. He had struggled valiantly, but he just wasn&#8217;t equipped for the task.</p>
<p>What hill is it that God wants you to conquer this year? Don&#8217;t take a Prius to an SUV party. God has the power you&#8217;ll need.  Stop depending on your own, because you&#8217;re just spinning your wheels.</p>
<p>Happy New Year!</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2576/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2576/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2576&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://daveknickerbocker.wordpress.com/2012/12/27/how-to-see-your-new-years-resolution-through/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>29</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/3d5145cd2bf0f0fb18b72ea421b65b7c?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jezknick</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/e/ed/Toyota_Prius_III_20090710_front.JPG/300px-Toyota_Prius_III_20090710_front.JPG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Toyota Prius III</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Good Riddance, Facebook</title>
		<link>http://thisawesomelife0918.wordpress.com/2012/12/27/good-riddance-facebook/</link>
		<comments>http://thisawesomelife0918.wordpress.com/2012/12/27/good-riddance-facebook/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2012 07:59:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>thisawesomelife0918</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Musings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[farewell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[goodbye]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thisawesomelife0918.wordpress.com/?p=1181</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Dear Facebook, It&#8217;s not you, it&#8217;s me. I need to figure things out. Like how you are sucking all my time and how you&#8217;re making me into someone I am not. Like how you make me hate myself as I skim through posts and pictures of my so-called &#8220;friends&#8221;. God, their lives are so perfect! [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1181&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dear Facebook,</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not you, it&#8217;s me. I need to figure things out. Like how you are sucking all my time and how you&#8217;re making me into someone I am not. Like how you make me hate myself as I skim through posts and pictures of my so-called &#8220;friends&#8221;. God, their lives are so perfect! Why is my life not as perfect as theirs? Am I the only one who have to deal with occasional bouts of jealousy and self-doubt every time I read about a &#8220;friend&#8221; who bought his own private jet, and another &#8220;close friend&#8221; who spent his holidays on the moon? I feel so pathetic.</p>
<p>Oh please, don&#8217;t stare at me with those wide pitiful eyes. That won&#8217;t work anymore. I know, things were going so great between us, and it&#8217;s such a shocker that I&#8217;m telling you this. But this has been on the back of my mind for months, and I&#8217;m sorry it has taken me quite a long time to finally gather enough courage to confess that you and I just aren&#8217;t good for each other. Remember that time I was at the top of the Eiffel tower in Paris? For a fleeting moment, while taking in the breathtaking panorama of the City of Lights, I really felt like I was the King of the World, that everything was truly possible, and yes, that with a panoramic view of Paris at night, who needs drugs to get high? But that feeling of being invincible quickly evaporated and was immediately replaced by a seemingly innocuous thought along the lines of: &#8220;I need to share this on Facebook! Paris, you&#8217;ll now be Instagrammed!&#8221;</p>
<p>Oh by the way, I don&#8217;t have an Instagram account, so I might have slightly altered the line above. But then, altering wall posts and minor adjustments in statuses have become a staple part of our complicated relationship dynamics, right? You&#8217;ve always made me feel like I needed to make my posts and stories more interesting than they really are, so there you go, I made some minor adjustments in them. It&#8217;s not that the minor adjustments are lies you know, they are after all, just minor. I just want my &#8220;friends&#8221; to like my posts, isn&#8217;t it a noble motivation to alter, and in doing so fake a post? Everyone&#8217;s doing it, so nothing&#8217;s possibly wrong with it, right?</p>
<p>Listen, you&#8217;re really great. You are. And you&#8217;re way too generous, to the point that I&#8217;m really having a hard time receiving all the stuff you so generously shower upon me. How come you know that I need to get informed on what my &#8220;friends&#8221; had for dinner, or about how a &#8220;friend&#8217;s&#8221; baby just had the first poop of the baby&#8217;s life, complete with DSLR-quality pictures of the poop? And isn&#8217;t it too much information when a &#8220;friend&#8221; posted about her weird bodily functions, about another&#8217;s drunken ramblings, and beat this &#8211; about someone&#8217;s sex life?</p>
<p>Our relationship was founded on complete trust. We even made a pact to be totally honest to each other. You promised me that you will reveal to me all your secrets, that all the things you know I will know. You have given me the power to really <del>stalk</del> know someone &#8211; what someone is up to, what type of movies she likes, where she spent her weekend, what sort of jokes she finds funny, how she looks like in a swimsuit, and even when she has a period &#8211; all in the comfort of my room and with a mindless click of a button! You even told me about a friend of a friend&#8217;s family background and life history, even though that friend of a friend is someone I&#8217;ve only known through you, and wouldn&#8217;t even talk to in real life. I sometimes feel queasy about this kind of set-up. Don&#8217;t you think it&#8217;s a little unhealthy knowing too much about a person without even spending time talking with that person?</p>
<p>This is not easy for me, believe me. We had so much promise, we shared so many memories. But as time passes by, I feel like our relationship has become a little more than a superficial facade, a carefully altered representation of myself. It has been totally unexpected that with the ease you provide in communicating with &#8220;friends&#8221;, my relationships with my &#8220;friends&#8221; are increasingly becoming shallower. What went wrong? Is it because with your existence, I have been more concerned about what others think of me through my online persona? That instead of meeting and talking with friends and family, I have resigned myself to simply liking and commenting on their posts?</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not you, it&#8217;s me. You deserve someone better. I deserve a better life too &#8211; a life of genuine relationships, a life that couldn&#8217;t care less about what people think as long as I know it&#8217;s what I want, a life lived every moment without thinking of posting it online&#8230; which is why, I&#8217;m setting both of us free.</p>
<p>Farewell,</p>
<p>Gary</p>
<div id="attachment_1188" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 480px"><a href="http://thisawesomelife0918.wordpress.com/2012/12/27/good-riddance-facebook/goodbye_by_dark_scythe/#main" rel="attachment wp-att-1188"><img class="size-full wp-image-1188" alt="From http://fav.me/dgfspn" src="http://thisawesomelife0918.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/goodbye_by_dark_scythe.jpg?w=590"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">From <a href="http://fav.me/dgfspn" rel="nofollow">http://fav.me/dgfspn</a></p></div>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://thisawesomelife0918.wordpress.com/category/musings/'>Musings</a> Tagged: <a href='http://thisawesomelife0918.wordpress.com/tag/facebook/'>facebook</a>, <a href='http://thisawesomelife0918.wordpress.com/tag/farewell/'>farewell</a>, <a href='http://thisawesomelife0918.wordpress.com/tag/goodbye/'>goodbye</a>, <a href='http://thisawesomelife0918.wordpress.com/tag/love/'>love</a>, <a href='http://thisawesomelife0918.wordpress.com/tag/social-media/'>social media</a>, <a href='http://thisawesomelife0918.wordpress.com/tag/writing/'>writing</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1181/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1181/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1181&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thisawesomelife0918.wordpress.com/2012/12/27/good-riddance-facebook/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>253</slash:comments>
		<georss:point>11.014155 124.601595</georss:point>
		<geo:lat>11.014155</geo:lat>
		<geo:long>124.601595</geo:long>
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/3b139717a4b0e8afad86d439beda30c9?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">thisawesomelife0918</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thisawesomelife0918.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/goodbye_by_dark_scythe.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">From http://fav.me/dgfspn</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Hobbit: An Unexpected Journey, the Extended Edition</title>
		<link>http://thecortex.com.au/2012/12/27/the-hobbit-an-unexpected-journey-the-extended-edition/</link>
		<comments>http://thecortex.com.au/2012/12/27/the-hobbit-an-unexpected-journey-the-extended-edition/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2012 06:43:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>thecortexteam</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thecortex.com.au/?p=491</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[UPDATE: I saw The Hobbit: An Unexpected Journey in 48 frames-per-second 3D. I felt that this format deserved its own article. Check it out here. BENJAMIN ZAUGG: Right at the beginning of The Hobbit: An Unexpected Journey, there is a wonderful scene depicting Thrór, the Dwarf King of Erebor, surrounded by mountains of gold, going completely mad with [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=491&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>UPDATE: I saw The Hobbit: An Unexpected Journey in 48 frames-per-second 3D. I felt that this format deserved its own article. Check it out <a title="The Hobbit: framing the issue of high frame rates" href="http://thecortex.com.au/2013/01/04/the-hobbit-framing-the-issue-of-high-frame-rates/">here</a>.</em></p>
<p><a title="Authors" href="http://thecortex.com.au/authors/">BENJAMIN ZAUGG</a>: Right at the beginning of <i>The Hobbit: An Unexpected Journey</i>, there is a wonderful scene depicting Thrór, the Dwarf King of Erebor, surrounded by mountains of gold, going completely mad with greed and power. As I watched the rest of the film I would frequently find myself recalling that scene and substituting that Dwarf King with Peter Jackson.</p>
<p>At a little over 300 pages long, the original paperback of <i>The Hobbit</i> is a rather and short straightforward tale. Originally, Peter Jackson was going to tackle it in two films, adding some backstory/sidestory elements to fill out two separate features. This was a bit of a surprise, but given Jackson&#8217;s relatively strong track record I was cautiously optimistic. When I heard that he was splitting the 300-page tale into <i>three</i> films I began to worry.</p>
<div id="attachment_492" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 310px"><img class="size-medium wp-image-492" alt="Peter Jackson's The Hobbit is far too long at 170-minutes. " src="http://cortexnews.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bilbo_1280x1024.jpg?w=300&#038;h=240" width="300" height="240" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Peter Jackson&#8217;s The Hobbit is far too long at 170-minutes.</p></div>
<p>Going in with these grave concerns I came out at the end neither disappointed nor overly pleased with what I saw. There is no doubt that the movie was a combination of two dark forces: Warner Brother Studios milking three films out of what could easily have been one or two, and Peter Jackson given unlimited power to explore every nook and cranny of his cherished middle-earth. What makes Jackson different to say, George Lucas, is that he is actually an extremely good filmmaker. So while this first installment is overloaded with tacked-on story elements it holds together far better than it has any right to.</p>
<p>If you go into this expecting a faithful film adaptation of the first third of <i>The Hobbit</i> you will probably be disappointed. However, if you want to experience a richly detailed backstory to <i>Lord of The Rings</i> where part of <i>The Hobbit</i> is the main plot line, then this may be your cup of tea. Perhaps because I went in knowing it would be more of the latter I enjoyed myself most of the time.</p>
<p>The problem with expanding the story beyond the original book seems to be that much of its spirit seems to have been lost in the process. Part of what made the book so charming was its very linear Bilbo-centric storyline and Tolkien&#8217;s excellent pacing &#8211; which was so different from LOTR. With all the backstory and &#8216;side-quests&#8217; stuffed into this installment there is an added weight that slows down the narrative and it also feels like the story is more about the fellowship than about Bilbo Baggins. This is a particular shame because I felt that Martin Freeman&#8217;s Bilbo was the best thing about the film and I would have enjoyed a film more focused on that character’s journey.</p>
<p>It is only the <i>extra</i> story elements that slow things down, not the key ones. The arrival of the dwarves and the unveiling of their plan at the hobbit hole, while a scene or two too long, was very well done. The meeting of Gollum and Bilbo is above and beyond what I ever expected, and the appearance of the Goblin King (Barry Humphries) was excellent.</p>
<p>Whole swathes of story could be cut from around the main plot points and the film would only have benefited. Instead, Jackson seemed to be pulling out every bell and whistle to keep the add-ons interesting. I lost count of how many scenes occurred on or just near an overhanging cliff (there&#8217;s a new drinking game), and by the end of the film I&#8217;d almost forgotten what normal daylight looked like, because every scene seemed to take place at either sunrise or sunset. The editing seemed to be working overtime to keep things dynamic. Just when I thought they exhausted every camera angle a new one would appear.</p>
<p>Despite being a Frankenstein&#8217;s monster of plot and despite being something other than the original tale of <i>The Hobbit</i>, the stunning visuals and extraordinary cast made this film an enjoyable watch. I have no doubt that once all three films are finally released on Blu-ray, someone somewhere will rip and edit them all into a single three-hour epic with no extraneous plot. <i>That</i> film will be incredible. In the meantime, I&#8217;m going to treat each of these installments like the extended extended edition releases that they seem to be.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='640' height='390' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/b1SJ7yaa7cI?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/491/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/491/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=491&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thecortex.com.au/2012/12/27/the-hobbit-an-unexpected-journey-the-extended-edition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>67</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://cortexnews.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bilbo_1280x1024.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://cortexnews.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bilbo_1280x1024.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bilbo_1280x1024</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/785ded3abd871e25e638a22ca097c786?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">thecortexteam</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cortexnews.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bilbo_1280x1024.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Peter Jackson&#039;s The Hobbit is far too long at 170-minutes. </media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Acosta’s ‘Crayons’ Mural Recalls Sandy Hook</title>
		<link>http://piedtype.com/2012/12/27/acostas-crayons-mural-recalls-sandy-hook/</link>
		<comments>http://piedtype.com/2012/12/27/acostas-crayons-mural-recalls-sandy-hook/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2012 07:30:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>PiedType</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[guns]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://piedtype.com/?p=28803</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This 6&#8242; × 24&#8242; graffiti mural is the work of Gamma Acosta, Longmont, Colo. &#8220;Crayons&#8221; is his statement about the Sandy Hook school massacre, done a day later. It&#8217;s gone now, boards and all, to an anonymous art collector who wanted it preserved. Normally Acosta, who paints on his uncle&#8217;s vacant building, would have painted over it [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=28803&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://piedtype.com/2012/12/27/acostas-crayons-mural-recalls-sandy-hook/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>126</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://piedtype.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/acosta_crayons_x450.jpg?w=120" />
		<media:content url="http://piedtype.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/acosta_crayons_x450.jpg?w=120" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Gamma Acosta&#039;s mural &#039;Crayons&#039; recalls the Sandy Hook school shooting (Photo: Gamma Gallery)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/13ef446214b9dc7ef5be19c26647eddc?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Pied Type</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://piedtype.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/a-friend-of-mine-created-this-sandy-hook-tribute-mural-heartbreaking-and-beautiful-at-the-same-time-imgur.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Gamma Acosta&#039;s mural &#039;Crayons&#039; recalls the Sandy Hook school shooting (Photo: Gamma Gallery)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://piedtype.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/gammaacosta.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Gamma Acosta and his mural &#34;Crayons&#34; (Photo: Greg Lindstrom/Times-Call)</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>9 Ways To Make Your Own Funeral Fun</title>
		<link>http://armyofawesomepeople.com/2012/12/27/9-ways-to-make-your-own-funeral-fun/</link>
		<comments>http://armyofawesomepeople.com/2012/12/27/9-ways-to-make-your-own-funeral-fun/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2012 05:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>List of X</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Satire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comedy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[death]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funeral]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://armyofawesomepeople.com/?p=3585</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Funerals are generally thought of as glum and solemn affairs, but it doesn&#8217;t always have to be that way. Here are some things you can try to make your own funeral fun with a little planning. (Disclaimer: DO NOT attempt to make someone else’s funeral fun without prior consent, as some people’s ghosts have no [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3585&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://armyofawesomepeople.com/2012/12/27/9-ways-to-make-your-own-funeral-fun/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>246</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://armyofawesomepeople.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/rental-1.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://armyofawesomepeople.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/rental-1.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Rental-1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c9b538799505057a3201a9210955d016?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">listofx</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://armyofawesomepeople.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/rental-1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Rental-1</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
