<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2011 20:26:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>What&#8217;s My Dad Doing on Facebook?</title>
		<link>http://francopolis.wordpress.com/2011/03/10/whats-my-dad-doing-on-facebook/</link>
		<comments>http://francopolis.wordpress.com/2011/03/10/whats-my-dad-doing-on-facebook/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2011 06:58:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Michael Franco</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://francopolis.wordpress.com/?p=290</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[When I received a friend request from my dad, I was, frankly, weirded out.  But the inherent distance of online communication somehow allowed us to express affection in ways that are too awkward in person. My dad and I are Facebook friends.  That sounds like a completely ridiculous thing to say.  I mean, we’re friends [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=290&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://francopolis.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/beav20.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-291 alignleft" title="Beav20" src="http://francopolis.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/beav20.jpg?w=145&#038;h=125" alt="" width="145" height="125" /></a></p>
<p><em><a href="http://francopolis.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/facebook_accept_reject_v1.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-292 alignleft" title="facebook_accept_reject_v1" src="http://francopolis.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/facebook_accept_reject_v1.jpg?w=254&#038;h=250" alt="" width="254" height="250" /></a>When I received a friend request from my dad, I was, frankly, weirded out.  But the inherent distance of online communication somehow allowed us to express affection in ways that are too awkward in person.</em></p>
<p>My dad and I are Facebook friends.  That sounds like a completely ridiculous thing to say.  I mean, we’re friends in the real world, so why wouldn’t we be Facebook friends?  But that’s not the reason it sounds ridiculous.  No, it sounds ridiculous because I see my dad practically every single day of my life, but I’m closer to the virtual him than the actual him.  Strange, right?  How is that even possible?</p>
<p>My father, you see, comes from a generation of men &#8212; perhaps the last &#8212; for whom expressing affection towards their children can be awkward, particularly children of the same sex.  This, I&#8217;m sure, has something to do with evolving gender roles and what it means to &#8220;be a man&#8221;.  For my dad&#8217;s generation &#8212; the early baby boomers &#8212; being a man meant providing a family with essentials, not emoting all over the place.  Men were to be sturdy and stoic, not soft and sensitive.</p>
<p>I also get the impression that my dad wasn’t too close with his parents.  His mother seemed distant; his father eccentric – neither the personification of affection.  When I think back to my father’s interactions with his parents before they passed, words like “cordial” and “businesslike” come to mind.  He was kind to them because he’s a kind person, but I never got the impression that he was maintaining fulfilling relationships.  In light of that, I’m surprised he even knew how to express affection to my brother and me.</p>
<p>This doesn’t mean my dad never showed his love for us when we were growing up.  I can recall countless acts he performed to express his affection.  When he would take a day off from work, for example, he would spend it ironing our clothes and cooking dinner.  My brother and I didn&#8217;t even care if our clothes were ironed, but I knew that was my dad&#8217;s way of saying that he loved us.  Who, after all, takes off from work to iron Nike t-shirts and prepare roast chicken in garlic gravy?</p>
<p>But I could probably count the number of times my father has told me he loves me on my twenty digits, and that&#8217;s simply no big deal to me.  I&#8217;ve never once thought that he doesn&#8217;t; I&#8217;ve just always known that some things are easy to feel but harder to say.  There have been many times, in fact, when I have wanted to tell my dad I love him but have felt that it would be too awkward to do so.  Guys can be funny that way.</p>
<p>So when I received a Facebook friend request from my dad, I was, frankly, weirded out.  I&#8217;ve been accustomed to keeping my dad close, but not too close.  Sunday night dinner?  Sure.  Friday night pub crawl?  No thanks.  In accepting his request, I would give my dad insight into my entire life: my interactions with friends, my comings and goings, my random thoughts, my likes, my dislikes, what I &#8220;like&#8221; and &#8220;unlike&#8221;, the random compliments I give my girlfriend (who, ironically, doesn&#8217;t even have a Facebook account)&#8230; This simple request felt more like an invasion.</p>
<p>And yet, I knew I had no option but to “friend” my dad.  What conceivable excuse could I have to not?  Before I clicked on “Accept”, though, I took the time to review my past posts and photos to “clean up” my profile.  I even thought about starting a whole new profile for friends and keeping the one I had for people like my dad and my boss – people for whom I reserve the persona that, otherwise, only gets used when I attend Mass every few years.</p>
<p>In the end, though, I decided to let my dad simply be like any other Facebook friend because, well, he’s my dad.  At first, however, I wasn’t sure how to virtually interact with him.  I was even scared to look at his profile.  Would he post creepy photos of him and my mom drinking martinis and standing too close to one another at creepy parties for creepy people of their age?  Would he have bizarre, unacceptable interests, like scrapbooking or watching <em>American Idol? </em>Would he be socially awkward, posting head-scratching comments on others’ posts?</p>
<p>All the worrying was for naught.  My dad, turns out, is completely normal.  What’s more, accepting his friend request allowed the two of us to communicate more than we ever have before.  While I have always talked to my mother on a daily basis, neither my dad nor myself have ever felt comfortable just picking up the phone and diving into conversation.  Again, the generational divides.</p>
<p>But on my Facebook page, my dad was suddenly showing interest in my life: complimenting me on accomplishments, posting comments on my posts, taking notice of the things that are my life.  Somehow, the inherent distance of online communication allowed him to express affection in ways that are too awkward in person, and that has given us things to talk about in our face-to-face interactions.</p>
<p>One day, for example, he commented about my blog, not realizing that I spend many evenings in front of the computer.  “I like your blog,” he said.  “I didn’t know you blogged.  Is there a way for me to add it to my favorites?  I really like your articles.”  And just yesterday he complimented me about a piece I wrote for an online magazine, telling me I did a good job.  No matter how old you are, hearing your father express interest in your interests is flattering, nice.  And if he weren’t my “friend”, he might never know of my writing pursuits.</p>
<p>I’ve also learned a lot about my dad because of our newfound “friendship”.  Through his Facebook page, for example, he has revealed an astute humor I never knew he possessed.  One night, my girlfriend and I couldn&#8217;t keep from cracking up at his profile picture: a shot of him sitting on a toilet in the middle of a driveway, scarf wrapped around his neck and stocking cap on his head, posed like Rodin&#8217;s &#8220;The Thinker&#8221;.  Why was a toilet in the middle of a driveway?  What was my dad doing sitting on it on an obviously cold day?  Most of all, why would my dad make this his profile picture, his way of greeting the online world?  It was genius, that&#8217;s why, and it turns out my dad has a genius wit.</p>
<p>The best part of having my dad as a Facebook friend, though, is that it keeps the family in constant contact with one another.  If I post a picture of my son that’s particularly funny or charming, my parents will comment on it or call to get the full story.  If I comment about an exciting happening during my day, my parents will ask me about it when I talk to them later in the day.  These moments – relatively small but meaningful nonetheless – would go by without being shared if not for Facebook.</p>
<p>No, I don&#8217;t necessarily buy into the notion that the Internet has made the world smaller in every single circumstance, bringing everyone closer together in every conceivable way.  In many ways, it has done just the opposite, giving people the means to seclude themselves in their virtual lives rather than participating in their actual lives &#8212; as well as draw rigid ideological lines that purposely exclude large portions of the world.</p>
<p>But for all the ridiculous, overblown assertions that the Internet can erase divisions and bring people together, sometimes it actually does.  Some people, for instance, join couch surfing groups and travel around the world, staying with complete strangers with a shared love of travel.  Others join online communities and talk to people from foreign countries, learning about cultures that, without the Internet, they’d never have the chance to experience.</p>
<p>And then there’s me: I accepted my dad’s friend request and found out that in addition to being a great dad, he’s also pretty damn cool.  Maybe that Friday night pub crawl is in our future yet.  Perhaps a virtual beer first&#8230;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/290/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/290/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/290/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/290/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/290/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/290/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/290/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/290/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/290/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/290/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/290/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/290/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/290/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/290/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=290&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://francopolis.wordpress.com/2011/03/10/whats-my-dad-doing-on-facebook/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>71</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/a06c22c0a94b7fb10f086a67b3e29544?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">francopolis</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://francopolis.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/beav20.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Beav20</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://francopolis.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/facebook_accept_reject_v1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">facebook_accept_reject_v1</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>We&#8217;re Being Shaken and Stirred in Japan</title>
		<link>http://amblerangel.wordpress.com/2011/03/11/were-being-shaken-and-stirred-in-japan/</link>
		<comments>http://amblerangel.wordpress.com/2011/03/11/were-being-shaken-and-stirred-in-japan/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2011 11:28:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>amblerangel</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Moving to Japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Earthquake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Emily Cannell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Moving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Offspring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tokyo]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://amblerangel.wordpress.com/?p=2721</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[First- thanks to all of you for checking in to see how the Clampitts are faring in the face of this Earthquake. I&#8217;m certainly not CNN, however, here&#8217;s the situation from Shibuya-ku. Spouse is in Osaka- he&#8217;s usually gone for major snowstorms, earthquakes, pet emergencies, etc. The kids experienced this first earthquake at school and [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=2721&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>First- thanks to all of you for checking in to see how the Clampitts are faring in the face of this Earthquake. I&#8217;m certainly not CNN, however, here&#8217;s the situation from Shibuya-ku. Spouse is in Osaka- he&#8217;s usually gone for major snowstorms, earthquakes, pet emergencies, etc. The kids experienced this first earthquake at school and are currently en route home- a journey that has been underway for the last 4.5 hours as the highways are currently jammed.</p>
<p>For us, it started about 2:30 in the afternoon. I was at the grocery store perusing the narrow aisles, gazing absent-mindedly at syrup,&#8221; Breakfast for dinner?&#8221; when the boxes started to fall on me as if that was a such a good idea they just jumped on down of their own accord. I hurdled the next three Japanese women in my race to be the first out of the store. I heard the wine crashing to the ground on my way out. I stopped in the middle of the street as all the other people flooded out of the buildings. A man and I looked each other in the eyes as he stood holding on to a swaying telephone pole. Where were my kids? The pole covered a distance of 5 to 6 feet, back and forth. I looked up to see if it would hit me when it fell. The street was narrow- where was I safest? Under one of the building overhangs or lying buried in its rubble? I decided to run for the intersection where there was more space. The Japanese, used to earthquakes, were now starting to panic as the intensity of the earthquake grew. They began to hold each other. Some were starting to cry. The ground was swaying enough to when I moved I lost my footing. Or was it because I was still holding a death grip on my shopping cart? Good thing I brought that along- could I crawl under it? Where were my kids? It lasted forever. Plants started to fall off balconies, cars started moving, bikes fell, the vending machines were toppling over. People were frozen. All was silent except for the sounds of the buildings shaking. Creaking. Squeaking. We all stood rooted to our spot, unmoving, except for our eyes, darting quickly to each building, wondering which one was going to fall on us, all the time evaluating if we would see it in time to run. Was this our time? Where in the HELL was my family?</p>
<p>It stopped. The collection looked at each other.  We were alive and the buildings around us were standing. I walked back to the grocery store. The young grocery clerk was crying. I put my arm around her. I talked to her in English. A Japanese woman came over and took her from me. I wished she were my daughter. Broken bottles lay smashed all over the floor. A woman scrubbed tomato sauce with her hands.</p>
<p>My phone didn&#8217;t work. I tried to text. That didn&#8217;t work. It was quiet. No one was talking. Hundreds of people were lining a tiny street but no one said a word. The subways were closing. People poured out of the hole where the subway belonged.</p>
<p>An aftershock. People grabbed each other. I walked home. I didn&#8217;t know what was happening. I couldn&#8217;t understand the announcements- but- the buildings were standing. No fires. No panic. No blood. In the Ouiser hierarchy of panic situations, I chalked this all up as positive.</p>
<p>Upon entering my building, I noticed the water feature now had waves. Another aftershock.</p>
<p><a href="http://amblerangel.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_2891.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2726" title="IMG_2891" src="http://amblerangel.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_2891.jpg?w=768&#038;h=1024" alt="" width="768" height="1024" /></a></p>
<p>I came in our door. The first signs of damage.</p>
<p><a href="http://amblerangel.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/20110311-074708.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2724" title="20110311-074708.jpg" src="http://amblerangel.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/20110311-074708.jpg?w=480&#038;h=643" alt="" width="480" height="643" /></a></p>
<p>I filled the bath tub with water in case we needed it later.</p>
<p>I opened the windows so they wouldn&#8217;t get jammed shut.</p>
<p>The kids texted me that they were on the bus. I started to feel better. Spouse checked in.</p>
<p>Now my emergency preparedness classes finally kicked in:</p>
<p>Fill the bathtub, get out the backpack with the flares, the first aid, the compass, the map, the money, the blankets, the stitch kit, the food, the gun, (just kidding, there&#8217;s no gun), cut off the gas and the electricity, make sure there&#8217;s enough food for a week, keep passports on us at all times, good thing I registered with the State Department. I actually got the email entitled, &#8220;Earthquake and Tsunami Warning from US Embassy.&#8221;</p>
<p>The computer worked. I Skyped the Nose- 2:00 AM her time- &#8220;When you wake up- you&#8217;ll see we&#8217;ve had a 8.9 earthquake- we&#8217;re all ok. Don&#8217;t worry&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Ok- thanks for calling- good night&#8221;</p>
<p>A few minutes later- the news sunk in, I got an email from her thanking me for saving her from the morning panic she would have endured trying to track us down.</p>
<p>Currently public transportation is shut down. For some reason, unless there is an alien invasion, the airports remain open. Sensei is sitting in my living room because she can&#8217;t get home. Hopefully I can talk her into spending the night because the alternative is a 4 hour walk home. She&#8217;s so polite I might have to lock her in order to make her stay.</p>
<p>Tsunamis now are wreaking havoc. The after shocks continue one after the other. Tonight I&#8217;ll feel better when the kids walk through the door. I&#8217;ll pray for those not as lucky. And give thanks for those who cared to do the same for us.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2721/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2721/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2721/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2721/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2721/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2721/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2721/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2721/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2721/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2721/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2721/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2721/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2721/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2721/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=2721&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://amblerangel.wordpress.com/2011/03/11/were-being-shaken-and-stirred-in-japan/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>50</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/b60bfe36ce364c646c7717e5c8d6a5ca?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=R" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">amblerangel</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://amblerangel.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_2891.jpg?w=768" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_2891</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://amblerangel.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/20110311-074708.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">20110311-074708.jpg</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Achill Island</title>
		<link>http://goodbyemenlo.wordpress.com/2011/03/08/achill-island/</link>
		<comments>http://goodbyemenlo.wordpress.com/2011/03/08/achill-island/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2011 11:10:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>lucremii</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ireland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://goodbyemenlo.wordpress.com/?p=208</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Two weekends ago I took a trip north to county Mayo, specifically Mulranny and Achill Island. I didn&#8217;t get up to Mulranny where I was staying until late that night, so Friday I slept in a little bit and ended up having a huge fry breakfast in the morning after seeing the sights around Mulranny. [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=208&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://goodbyemenlo.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_1352.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-209" title="IMG_1352" src="http://goodbyemenlo.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_1352.jpg?w=640&#038;h=426" alt="" width="640" height="426" /></a></p>
<p>Two weekends ago I took a trip north to county Mayo, specifically Mulranny and Achill Island. I didn&#8217;t get up to Mulranny where I was staying until late that night, so Friday I slept in a little bit and ended up having a huge fry breakfast in the morning after seeing the sights around Mulranny. The weather was gorgeous on Saturday so luckily we took the opportunity to have a little road trip all around Achill Island, which happens to be the largest island off the coast of Ireland. I would immensely recommend a tour around here if you&#8217;re ever in Ireland, because the drive itself is gorgeous. The picture above here is located in Doogort, which has a nice beach and a lovely little hotel right on the water. There was actually a wedding there when we were driving through.</p>
<p><a href="http://goodbyemenlo.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_1306.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-213" title="IMG_1306" src="http://goodbyemenlo.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_1306.jpg?w=640&#038;h=426" alt="" width="640" height="426" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://goodbyemenlo.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/picture-4.png"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-214" title="Picture 4" src="http://goodbyemenlo.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/picture-4.png?w=640&#038;h=208" alt="" width="640" height="208" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://goodbyemenlo.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_1297.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-215" title="IMG_1297" src="http://goodbyemenlo.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_1297.jpg?w=640&#038;h=426" alt="" width="640" height="426" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://goodbyemenlo.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_1314.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-216" title="IMG_1314" src="http://goodbyemenlo.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_1314.jpg?w=640&#038;h=426" alt="" width="640" height="426" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://goodbyemenlo.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_1376.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-217" title="IMG_1376" src="http://goodbyemenlo.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_1376.jpg?w=640&#038;h=960" alt="" width="640" height="960" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://goodbyemenlo.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/picture-1.png"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-218" title="Picture 1" src="http://goodbyemenlo.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/picture-1.png?w=551&#038;h=412" alt="" width="551" height="412" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://goodbyemenlo.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_1331.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-219" title="IMG_1331" src="http://goodbyemenlo.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_1331.jpg?w=640&#038;h=426" alt="" width="640" height="426" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://goodbyemenlo.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_1385.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-220" title="IMG_1385" src="http://goodbyemenlo.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_1385.jpg?w=640&#038;h=426" alt="" width="640" height="426" /></a></p>
<p>The scenery included several gorgeous beaches, including the one directly above here, lots of sheep, and copious amounts of green. The island was relatively quiet as I don&#8217;t think tourist season has really kicked in at all, so it was kind of nice to have a very calm day driving around. Along our drive there was an old IRA pub that I would have loved to go have a pint in, but unfortunately it was closed. During the spring/summer there&#8217;s a lot of room to go camping and spend time outside though so hopefully I can make it back over to Achill Island at some point soon!</p>
<p><a href="http://goodbyemenlo.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/picture-10.png"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-222" title="Picture 10" src="http://goodbyemenlo.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/picture-10.png?w=466&#038;h=631" alt="" width="466" height="631" /></a></p>
<p>On the way back we stopped by a country little pub pretty much on the side of the road, called Compass where I was literally the only lady in the whole pub besides the bartender, which I thought was pretty fun. Then instead of going out to dinner a three-course feast was prepared, including bruschetta, thick rib-eye steaks, potatoes, grilled onions, Bulmer&#8217;s, and ice cream with smarties on top. Needless to say this was delicious and might have been one of my favorite parts of the weekend. The next morning however the weather took a bit of a down turn, so I slept in for quite a while, then we heading back towards Galway, stopping through some towns on the way home.</p>
<p><a href="http://goodbyemenlo.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_1408.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-224" title="IMG_1408" src="http://goodbyemenlo.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_1408.jpg?w=640&#038;h=426" alt="" width="640" height="426" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://goodbyemenlo.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/picture-2.png"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-223" title="Picture 2" src="http://goodbyemenlo.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/picture-2.png?w=546&#038;h=413" alt="" width="546" height="413" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://goodbyemenlo.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/picture-3.png"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-225" title="Picture 3" src="http://goodbyemenlo.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/picture-3.png?w=640&#038;h=225" alt="" width="640" height="225" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://goodbyemenlo.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_1461.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-226" title="IMG_1461" src="http://goodbyemenlo.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_1461.jpg?w=640&#038;h=426" alt="" width="640" height="426" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://goodbyemenlo.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_1468.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-227" title="IMG_1468" src="http://goodbyemenlo.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_1468.jpg?w=640&#038;h=960" alt="" width="640" height="960" /></a></p>
<p>On the way home, we stopped off first at the County Mayo Sailing Club, which was really interesting to see. There I saw where an old British Coast Guard station was, and was able to climb to the top of the place and get a wonderful view of all the islands around county Mayo. I also fed a couple of donkeys and saw some amazing sailboats that are specific to each part of Ireland. After that we stopped by Croagh Patrick which I definitely hope to climb some day soon. The scenery there was gorgeous and it was nice to be able to get out and walk around at the base of the mountain. Across the road from the mountain base is also the potato famine memorial, as seen in the pictures of the skeleton ship, which was remarkable. As soon as I walked on site there you can just feel the history and realize it&#8217;s impossible to understand what the people of Ireland went through during this time, and how it still affects them today. Even though it brought down the light heartedness of trip for a little bit, I&#8217;m still very happy that I went and saw it. Our last stop off before heading back home was to Westport, which I definitely NEED to go back to. The place was seriously gorgeous and I&#8217;ve heard that the nightlife there is really fun. The last two pictures in the bunch are from there and luckily when my dad comes he&#8217;s showed some interest in going there as well.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/208/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/208/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/208/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/208/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/208/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/208/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/208/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/208/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/208/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/208/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/208/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/208/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/208/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/208/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=208&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://goodbyemenlo.wordpress.com/2011/03/08/achill-island/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/ebc39ee32b488a466be8baddb10ab18f?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lucremii</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://goodbyemenlo.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_1352.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_1352</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://goodbyemenlo.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_1306.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_1306</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://goodbyemenlo.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/picture-4.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Picture 4</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://goodbyemenlo.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_1297.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_1297</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://goodbyemenlo.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_1314.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_1314</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://goodbyemenlo.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_1376.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_1376</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://goodbyemenlo.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/picture-1.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Picture 1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://goodbyemenlo.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_1331.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_1331</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://goodbyemenlo.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_1385.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_1385</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://goodbyemenlo.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/picture-10.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Picture 10</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://goodbyemenlo.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_1408.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_1408</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://goodbyemenlo.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/picture-2.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Picture 2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://goodbyemenlo.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/picture-3.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Picture 3</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://goodbyemenlo.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_1461.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_1461</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://goodbyemenlo.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_1468.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_1468</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Reverse Graffiti</title>
		<link>http://inspirationalgeek.wordpress.com/2011/03/07/reverse-graffiti/</link>
		<comments>http://inspirationalgeek.wordpress.com/2011/03/07/reverse-graffiti/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2011 21:32:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>inspirationalgeek</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Environment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Videos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[graffiti]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reverse graffiti]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alexandre Orion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[São Paulo]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://inspirationalgeek.wordpress.com/?p=1821</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[For as long as there have been dirty vehicles, people have writing &#8220;clean me&#8221; on them, but visual artist Alexandre Orion has taken this concept to a new level with his much more creative (and time consuming!) take on &#8216;reverse graffiti&#8217;.  It&#8217;s like traditional graffiti, but with an eco twist. Detergents, wire brushes and good [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=1821&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://inspirationalgeek.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/clean-me.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1824" title="clean me" src="http://inspirationalgeek.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/clean-me.jpg?w=450&#038;h=300" alt="" width="450" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>For as long as there have been dirty vehicles, people have writing &#8220;clean me&#8221; on them, but visual artist <a href="http://www.alexandreorion.com/ossario/texts.html" target="_blank">Alexandre Orion</a> has taken this concept to a new level with his much more creative (and time consuming!) take on &#8216;reverse graffiti&#8217;.  It&#8217;s like traditional graffiti, but with an eco twist.</p>
<p>Detergents, wire brushes and good ol&#8217; fashion elbow grease replace the spray cans and stencils that we&#8217;re used to seeing from graffiti artists, cleaning away layers of dirt and pollution to reveal the city&#8217;s natural facade and material colouring.  Driven overseas where authorities are more relaxed on this issue, though still not entirely supportive of the acts, a tunnel in São Paulo has become the latest canvas to spring reverse graffiti into the fame spotlight.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://inspirationalgeek.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/im_orion9.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1834" title="im_orion9" src="http://inspirationalgeek.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/im_orion9.jpg?w=450&#038;h=300" alt="" width="450" height="300" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://inspirationalgeek.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/im_orion8.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1833" title="im_orion8" src="http://inspirationalgeek.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/im_orion8.jpg?w=450&#038;h=300" alt="" width="450" height="300" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://inspirationalgeek.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/im_orion4.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1835" title="im_orion4" src="http://inspirationalgeek.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/im_orion4.jpg?w=450&#038;h=300" alt="" width="450" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>The process itself is intriguing and fascinating, so if you can spare three minutes this video is well worth a watch.</p>
<span style="text-align:center; display: block;"><a href="http://inspirationalgeek.wordpress.com/2011/03/07/reverse-graffiti/"><img src="http://img.youtube.com/vi/JwsBBIIXT0E/2.jpg" alt="" /></a></span>
<p>&#8220;He is not vandalising the urban environment as he uses no paint and merely strips away layers of grime and pollution&#8221; and besides, there are claims that &#8220;no one owns the dirt&#8221;, which is actually a rather good point.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://inspirationalgeek.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/im_limpa1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1828" title="im_limpa1" src="http://inspirationalgeek.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/im_limpa1.jpg?w=450&#038;h=300" alt="" width="450" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>Even though he is actually making the city a cleaner place, authorities do seem to frown upon his acts and spend a lot of time and effort chasing down the reverse graffiti antics just to wash them away.</p>
<p>It is a shame that this remarkably creative work is being scrubbed away by the the authorities, but the silver lining, I guess, is that they are actually making the city a cleaner place, which can&#8217;t be a bad thing.</p>
<p><em>More images well worth checking out over <a href="http://www.alexandreorion.com/ossario/images.html" target="_blank">here</a>.</em></p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://inspirationalgeek.wordpress.com/category/environment/'>Environment</a>, <a href='http://inspirationalgeek.wordpress.com/category/videos/'>Videos</a> Tagged: <a href='http://inspirationalgeek.wordpress.com/tag/alexandre-orion/'>Alexandre Orion</a>, <a href='http://inspirationalgeek.wordpress.com/tag/graffiti/'>graffiti</a>, <a href='http://inspirationalgeek.wordpress.com/tag/reverse-graffiti/'>reverse graffiti</a>, <a href='http://inspirationalgeek.wordpress.com/tag/sao-paulo/'>São Paulo</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1821/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1821/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1821/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1821/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1821/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1821/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1821/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1821/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1821/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1821/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1821/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1821/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1821/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1821/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=1821&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://inspirationalgeek.wordpress.com/2011/03/07/reverse-graffiti/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/5c8679ee98b315c802ffaa168a66190d?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">inspirationalgeek</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://inspirationalgeek.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/clean-me.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">clean me</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://inspirationalgeek.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/im_orion9.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">im_orion9</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://inspirationalgeek.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/im_orion8.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">im_orion8</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://inspirationalgeek.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/im_orion4.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">im_orion4</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://inspirationalgeek.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/im_limpa1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">im_limpa1</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is There Anything You Couldn&#8217;t Do?</title>
		<link>http://twentyfifthyear.wordpress.com/2011/03/10/is-there-anything-you-couldnt-do/</link>
		<comments>http://twentyfifthyear.wordpress.com/2011/03/10/is-there-anything-you-couldnt-do/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2011 20:22:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lauren</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[25]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[postaday2011]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jobs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[growing up]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://twentyfifthyear.wordpress.com/?p=541</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Growing up, my parents (the world&#8217;s best) made it clear that there is nothing you can&#8217;t do. Something may be difficult, inconvenient or exhausting, but that doesn&#8217;t mean you can&#8217;t do it. Mom often reminds me of how hard she worked at multiple jobs to get through college, while maintaining great grades. Dad had to [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=541&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Growing up, my parents (the world&#8217;s best) made it clear that there is <em>nothing </em>you <strong>can&#8217;t</strong> do. Something may be difficult, inconvenient or exhausting, but that doesn&#8217;t mean you can&#8217;t do it. Mom often reminds me of how hard she worked at multiple jobs to get through college, while maintaining great grades. Dad had to walk uphill both ways (with no feet!) to get to school, but he did it. Well, that may be an exaggeration.</p>
<p>But the point is that, when I&#8217;m thinking about being <a href="http://twentyfifthyear.wordpress.com/2011/03/09/a-post-per-day-every-day/">grateful for my job</a>, I often feel grateful to have a job that I <em>can </em>do. There are a million jobs out there that I <em>could </em>do (because I <em>could </em>do anything) but it would be a struggle. For example:</p>
<p><strong>Dental Hygenist, Shampoo Assistant, or Nurse</strong></p>
<p>Being in other people&#8217;s personal space for a living would take some toughening up. While I used to think it would be awesome to be a dentist &#8212; inspired by my own mandibular ups and downs &#8212; I&#8217;ve come to realize that I may just not have the stomach for digging around in strangers&#8217; mouths. The idea that my parents used to deal with Dylan and me wiggling, pulling and yanking out our teeth makes my skin crawl. I admire nurses who are fine with finding veins and poking them with needles, but my skin crawls again. A shampoo assistant is probably the most feasible in this list for me, but I&#8217;d still rather not scratch scalps other than my own.</p>
<p><strong>Veterinarian</strong></p>
<p>Having my own pet that I love, I can&#8217;t understand how people are able to do things to animals like take their temperature, hold them forcefully to clip their nails or &#8212; I hate to even say this &#8212; put them down. I think my heart would be broken every day.</p>
<p><strong>CPA</strong></p>
<p>Excel spreadsheets? Numbers? Formulas? Rules and regulations? 90-hour work weeks? I&#8217;m sure I could learn the very basics necessary to be an accountant, but the four-part CPA exam would probably take me years and many, many attempts to pass. I admire those of you who have framed CPA licenses hanging on your walls. I admire you and I do not envy you. And I thank you for being so financially intelligent.</p>
<p><strong>Truck Driver</strong></p>
<p>I love driving, and I even love driving large vehicles. But I don&#8217;t think I would last months on the road. Well, maybe with a good passenger? And maybe if my truck was full of grilled cheeses and chocolate?</p>
<p><strong>Lawyer</strong></p>
<p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-564" title="File-Legally_blonde" src="http://twentyfifthyear.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/file-legally_blonde.jpg?w=220&#038;h=331" alt="" width="220" height="331" /></p>
<p>While I respect what Elle Woods did for blondes everywhere, and I happen to be a Reese Witherspoon fan, <em>and </em>I can enjoy a good argument here and there, I couldn&#8217;t see myself arguing when someone&#8217;s livelihood is at stake. And defense attorneys? No way I&#8217;d be able to defend someone I knew was guilty &#8212; even if all they did was flick someone on the forehead.</p>
<p>Picturing myself in jobs that I would not enjoy has helped my Lenten commitment to stop complaining. (Yes I realize it&#8217;s only day 2). I can imagine how much complaining I&#8217;d want to do if I flossed 56 dirty sets of teeth every day and it&#8217;s not a pretty thought. It also brings much needed perspective to this formative era of twentysomethinghood in which career development is a constant hot topic and often an open-ended question.</p>
<p><strong>What are some jobs you couldn&#8217;t or wouldn&#8217;t want to do? </strong></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/541/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/541/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/541/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/541/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/541/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/541/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/541/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/541/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/541/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/541/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/541/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/541/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/541/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/541/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=541&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://twentyfifthyear.wordpress.com/2011/03/10/is-there-anything-you-couldnt-do/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/b9777eb8f2918b3def73dffb658d6e9a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">momentaryhilarity</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://twentyfifthyear.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/file-legally_blonde.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">File-Legally_blonde</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Country Loaf</title>
		<link>http://tomatoesinlove.wordpress.com/2011/02/23/country-loaf/</link>
		<comments>http://tomatoesinlove.wordpress.com/2011/02/23/country-loaf/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2011 17:53:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lisa</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[baking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[baking bread]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bread]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[country loaf]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[white bread]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tomatoesinlove.wordpress.com/?p=1090</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The Seattle sunshine is over. Yesterday it snowed/rained/hailed. I guess that&#8217;s what you call a wintry mix? Unpleasant, no matter what you call it. I stayed in. Today looks much the same &#8211; big low grey clouds, evergreens blustering about, and a chilly looking seagull glaring at me from a neighboring rooftop. The weatherman says [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=1090&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Seattle sunshine is over. Yesterday it snowed/rained/hailed. I guess that&#8217;s what you call a wintry mix? Unpleasant, no matter what you call it.</p>
<p>I stayed in.</p>
<p>Today looks much the same &#8211; big low grey clouds, evergreens blustering about, and a chilly looking seagull glaring at me from a neighboring rooftop. The weatherman says it might snow and stick. That&#8217;s a big deal around here, as they don&#8217;t seem to have salt or snow plows or winter driving experience and they <em>do</em> have big, big hills.</p>
<p>Good days for baking!</p>
<p>I made bread.</p>
<p><a href="http://tomatoesinlove.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/img_5680.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1098" title="IMG_5680" src="http://tomatoesinlove.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/img_5680.jpg?w=600&#038;h=450" alt="" width="600" height="450" /></a></p>
<p>And then I posed my loaf next to a rose and took goofy pictures of it. Can&#8217;t blame myself. Both were on the table. Both were pretty.</p>
<p>Recipe from Betty Crocker&#8217;s cookbook (Betty is very trustworthy). You can see the recipe online <a href="http://www.bettycrocker.com/recipes/country-loaf/33f0fe1d-5d6c-48f4-a0fb-3d80c0ad010c" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<p>What you need:</p>
<ul>
<li>5 cups flour</li>
<li>1 teaspoon sugar</li>
<li>2 1/4 teaspoons yeast</li>
<li>2 cups warm water</li>
<li>2 tablespoons vegetable oil</li>
<li>2 teaspoons salt</li>
<li>A good sense of fun and a willingness to mess up your kitchen</li>
</ul>
<p>Now, Betty said to use bread flour because something something more gluten? And I had bread flour! But only 3 cups of it. I used all-purpose for the remaining 2 cups.</p>
<p>I think I used to be scared of baking, and bread baking in particular, because I thought I had to be very precise. I was wrong. Yes, you should follow the measurements. You do have to be sort of precise. But things usually work out if you make little errors, is all I&#8217;m saying.</p>
<p>This does not seem to hold true for pie crusts. Pie crusts still make me nervous.</p>
<p>Bread fear is conquered, pies are next on the list. Bring it, pie.</p>
<p>Ok, back to the recipe. Sorry.</p>
<p>Mix 2 cups of flour with yeast and sugar. Stir in the 2 cups warm water (I just used hot water from the tap). Cover with plastic wrap and let sit for 1 hour.</p>
<p><a href="http://tomatoesinlove.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/img_5660.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1091" title="IMG_5660" src="http://tomatoesinlove.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/img_5660.jpg?w=600&#038;h=450" alt="" width="600" height="450" /></a></p>
<p>It will look like this after 1 hour &#8211; big and bubbly.</p>
<p>Add oil and salt. Stir in remaining flour, 1/2 a cup at a time. Don&#8217;t worry if all the flour doesn&#8217;t quite incorporate. Mine had chunks of dough falling off. You&#8217;re about to knead the heck out of it, so  that will do the trick.</p>
<p>Flour a surface (like your counter) and knead, knead, knead!</p>
<p><a href="http://tomatoesinlove.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/img_5662.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1092" title="IMG_5662" src="http://tomatoesinlove.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/img_5662.jpg?w=600&#038;h=450" alt="" width="600" height="450" /></a></p>
<p>You seriously do knead (hahaha) to knead if for about 7-10 minutes. The dough will become smooth and pliable as you do this &#8211; amazing!</p>
<p>Then plop your stretchy and smooth dough in a greased bowl, flipping it around to grease all sides. Cover with plastic wrap, and let it sit for another hour or so.</p>
<p><a href="http://tomatoesinlove.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/img_5667.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1093" title="IMG_5667" src="http://tomatoesinlove.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/img_5667.jpg?w=600&#038;h=603" alt="" width="600" height="603" /></a></p>
<p>It will rise.</p>
<p><a href="http://tomatoesinlove.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/img_56681.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1106" title="IMG_5668" src="http://tomatoesinlove.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/img_56681.jpg?w=600&#038;h=450" alt="" width="600" height="450" /></a></p>
<p>Poof!</p>
<p>Ta-da!</p>
<p>Line a cookie sheet with parchment paper or grease the cookie sheet.</p>
<p>Now, dump your dough out of its bowl and form it into a ball. You don&#8217;t want to punch it down (I know, darn) and release all the air bubbles, but it will definitely deflate a bit as you form it into a nice smooth ball.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s ok, because we&#8217;re going to let it rise AGAIN. Told you this is a good dreary day activity.</p>
<p>Plop your dough ball on your cookie sheet and sprinkle a little cold water on it.</p>
<p><a href="http://tomatoesinlove.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/img_5672.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1095" title="IMG_5672" src="http://tomatoesinlove.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/img_5672.jpg?w=600&#038;h=450" alt="" width="600" height="450" /></a></p>
<p>Loosely cover with plastic wrap and let rise for about an hour.</p>
<p>Pre-heat your oven to 425 and fill a small 9&#215;9 dish with hot water. Put this dish on the bottommost rack of the oven as it heats, and leave it there throughout the bread baking. Having water in the oven helps make the crust crusty, I&#8217;m told. I just follow the rules.</p>
<p>When your dough is risen and your oven is hot (and Jupiter aligns with Mars), slice a few thin lines in the top of your dough ball, sprinkle with a little more cold water and a little bit of flour and then shove it in the oven.</p>
<p>Bake for 35 minutes until golden brown! It should sound hollow when you tap it.</p>
<p><a href="http://tomatoesinlove.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/img_5673.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1096" title="IMG_5673" src="http://tomatoesinlove.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/img_5673.jpg?w=600&#038;h=450" alt="" width="600" height="450" /></a></p>
<p>Oooh.</p>
<p><a href="http://tomatoesinlove.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/img_5684.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1100" title="IMG_5684" src="http://tomatoesinlove.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/img_5684.jpg?w=600&#038;h=449" alt="" width="600" height="449" /></a></p>
<p>Ahhh.</p>
<p><a href="http://tomatoesinlove.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/img_5690.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1101" title="IMG_5690" src="http://tomatoesinlove.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/img_5690.jpg?w=600&#038;h=450" alt="" width="600" height="450" /></a></p>
<p>Yummm.</p>
<p>Slap on some butter and enjoy!</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://tomatoesinlove.wordpress.com/category/food-2/'>Food</a> Tagged: <a href='http://tomatoesinlove.wordpress.com/tag/baking/'>baking</a>, <a href='http://tomatoesinlove.wordpress.com/tag/baking-bread/'>baking bread</a>, <a href='http://tomatoesinlove.wordpress.com/tag/bread/'>bread</a>, <a href='http://tomatoesinlove.wordpress.com/tag/country-loaf/'>country loaf</a>, <a href='http://tomatoesinlove.wordpress.com/tag/white-bread/'>white bread</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1090/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1090/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1090/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1090/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1090/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1090/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1090/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1090/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1090/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1090/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1090/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1090/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1090/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1090/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=1090&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tomatoesinlove.wordpress.com/2011/02/23/country-loaf/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>26</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/71b4ab8e7fdd6e0913baffb230e5fb48?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lisajwheeler</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tomatoesinlove.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/img_5680.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_5680</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tomatoesinlove.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/img_5660.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_5660</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tomatoesinlove.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/img_5662.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_5662</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tomatoesinlove.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/img_5667.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_5667</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tomatoesinlove.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/img_56681.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_5668</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tomatoesinlove.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/img_5672.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_5672</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tomatoesinlove.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/img_5673.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_5673</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tomatoesinlove.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/img_5684.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_5684</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tomatoesinlove.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/img_5690.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_5690</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Japan earthquake live blog: 6.6 quake reported in Nagano, Japan</title>
		<link>http://news.blogs.cnn.com/2011/03/11/live-blog-japan-earthquake/</link>
		<comments>http://news.blogs.cnn.com/2011/03/11/live-blog-japan-earthquake/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2011 20:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>lendonsan</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[2011 tsunami]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Earthquake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Natural Disasters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tsunami]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CNN's Brad Lendon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CNN.com]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://news.blogs.cnn.com/?p=63481</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[An 8.9-magnitude earthquake hit northern Japan today, triggering tsunamis that sent a wave filled with boats and houses toward land. Hawaii and the U.S. West Coast are under a tsunami warning. Are you in an affected area? Send an iReport. Read the full report on how the quake hit Japan and generated a Pacific-wide tsunami. [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=63481&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong></strong>An 8.9-magnitude earthquake hit northern Japan today, triggering tsunamis that sent a wave filled with boats and houses toward land. Hawaii and the U.S. West Coast are under a tsunami warning. Are you in an affected area? <a href="http://ireport.cnn.com/ir-topic-stories.jspa?topicId=569459">Send an iReport</a>. <a href="http://www.cnn.com/2011/WORLD/asiapcf/03/11/japan.quake/index.html">Read the full report</a> on how the quake hit Japan and generated a Pacific-wide tsunami.</p>
<p>[cnn-video url="http://www.cnn.com/video/#/video/world/2011/03/11/bolduan.japan.quake.am.wrap.cnn"]</p>
<p><strong>[3:00 p.m. ET, 5:00 a.m. Tokyo] </strong> Japanese authorities have informed the IAEA’s Incident and Emergency Centre that today’s earthquake and tsunami cut the supply of off-site power to the Fukushima Daiichi nuclear power plant. In addition, diesel generators intended to provide back-up electricity to the plant’s cooling system were disabled by tsunami flooding, and efforts to restore the diesel generators are continuing.</p>
<p>At Fukushima Daiichi, officials have declared a nuclear emergency situation, and at the nearby Fukushima Daini nuclear power plant, officials have declared a heightened alert condition.</p>
<p>Japanese authorities say there has so far been no release of radiation from any of the nuclear power plants affected by today’s earthquake and aftershocks.</p>
<p>The IAEA’s IEC continues to liaise with the Japanese authorities, and is in full response mode to monitor the situation closely round the clock. </p>
<p><strong>[2:40 p.m. ET, 4:40 a.m. Tokyo] </strong>Tokyo Electric Power Company says it will vent possibly radioactive air from its Fukushima nuclear power plant to avoid a breakdown of the reactor&#8217;s containment vessels, <a href="http://www3.nhk.or.jp/daily/english/12_15.html">broadcaster NHK reports on its website</a>.</p>
<p><strong>[2:21 p.m. ET, 4:21 a.m. Tokyo] </strong>An estimated 6.6-magnitude earthquake has struck Nagano and Niigata prefectures in Japan, the Kyodo News Service reported. The U.S. Geological Survey says this latest event is a 6.2-magnitude temblor.</p>
<p><strong>[1:42 p.m. ET, 3:42 a.m. Tokyo] </strong>Using Air Force planes, the U.S. government has sent over coolant for the Fukushima nuclear plant, Secretary of State Hillary Clinton said Friday. Japan&#8217;s officials say a small radiation leak could occur at the plant after Friday&#8217;s earthquake and tsunami.</p>
<p><strong><span id="more-63481"></span>[1:34 p.m. ET, 3:34 a.m. Tokyo] </strong>According to the official count by Japan&#8217;s National Police, at least 151 people have been killed, 722 have been injured and 530 are missing after the 8.9-magnitude earthquake that hit Japan on Friday. Additionally, between 200 and 300 bodies have been found in the coastal city of Sendai in Miyagi Prefecture following the subsequent tsunami that struck that area. The official death toll is likely to rise.</p>
<p><strong><!--more-->[1:24 p.m. ET, 3:24 a.m. Tokyo] </strong>Japan&#8217;s trade minister, Banri Kaieda, says a small radiation leak could occur at the Fukushima nuclear plant, Japan&#8217;s Kyodo News Agency reported Saturday. Prime Minister Naoto Kan is planning to inspect the plant, according to Chief Cabinet Secretary Yukio Edano.</p>
<p><strong>[1:12 p.m. ET, 3:12 a.m. Tokyo] </strong>Tsunami of more than 8 feet recorded in Crescent City, California.</p>
<p><strong>[1:08 p.m. ET, 3:08 a.m. Tokyo] </strong>Sailing vessels were knocked loose from their moorings at a marina in Santa Cruz, California. Several were swamped.</p>
<p><strong><!--more-->[1:05 p.m. ET, 3:05 a.m. Tokyo] </strong>President  Obama said that Japan&#8217;s prime minister told him there was no evidence so far of radiation leaks from nuclear reactors due to the earthquake and tsunami.</p>
<p>[cnn-video url="http://www.cnn.com/video/#/video/world/2011/03/11/vo.japan.ground.aftermath.NHK"]</p>
<p><strong>[12:45 p.m. ET, 2:45 a.m. Tokyo] </strong>Gerard Fryer with The Pacific Tsunami Warning Center in Hawaii says they are lifting the evacuation orders for Hawaii.</p>
<p>&#8220;The shoreline is still hazardous so we&#8217;re updating the warning to an advisory.  What that means is you no longer have to remain evacuated, but stay off the beach and don&#8217;t tend to the water,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p><strong>[12:39 p.m. ET, 2:39 a.m. Tokyo] </strong>Friday&#8217;s quake is the strongest earthquake in recorded history to hit Japan, according to U.S. Geological Survey records. The previous record was an 8.6 magnitude earthquake that struck near the Chubu region near southwestern Honshu on October 28, 1707, that may have killed 5,000 people, said CNN meteorologist Sean Morris.</p>
<p>That quake generated a 33-foot (10-meter) tsunami, and some scientists believe the quake may have triggered the eruption of Mount Fuji 49 days later, Morris said.</p>
<p>The world&#8217;s largest recorded quake took place in Chile on May 22, 1960, with a magnitude of 9.5, the USGS said.</p>
<p>[cnn-video url="http://www.cnn.com/video/#/video/world/2011/03/11/natpkg.tsunami.wrap.cnn"]</p>
<p><strong>[12:20 p.m. ET, 2:20 a.m. Tokyo] </strong>Damaging waves reported at Kailua-Kona on Hawaii&#8217;s Big Island, Hawaii County Civil Defense Agency reports on its website. Maui police have reports of a 9-foot wave hitting Lahaina Harbor, Maui County Civil Defense Agency reports.</p>
<p><strong>[12:06 p.m. ET, 2:06 a.m. Tokyo] </strong>Radiation level rising in Fukushima No. 1 nuclear plant turbine building, Kyodo News Agency reports.</p>
<p><strong>[12:02 p.m. ET, 2:02 a.m. Tokyo] </strong>The death toll from the massive earthquake in Japan will likely surpass 1,000, the Kyodo News Agency reported.</p>
<p><strong><!--more-->[11:57 a.m. ET, 1:57 a.m. Tokyo] </strong>The U.S. Navy has announced the following ship movements in reaction to the earthquake in Japan:<strong><br />
</strong></p>
<p><strong></strong>&#8211; USS Essex, with the 31<sup>st</sup> Marine Expeditionary Unit (about 2,000 Marines) aboard, is preparing to leave Malaysia for Japan.</p>
<p>&#8211; USS Blue Ridge is in Singapore loading up with humanitarian supplies and then heading to Japan.</p>
<p>&#8211; USS Tortuga is at a base in Sasebo, in the far south of Japan ready to assist where needed.</p>
<p>&#8211; USS Harpers Ferry and USS Germantown are in the region and steaming towards Japan.</p>
<p>&#8211; USS Ronald Reagan was in the region for a long-planned exercise off Korea, but now steaming towards Japan to help.</p>
<p>&#8211; USS George Washington was docked at a maintenance pier in Japan when quake struck. Unclear what help, if any, it could provide.</p>
<p>&#8211; USS Dubuque put to sea from Seal Beach, California.</p>
<p><strong><!--more-->[11:54 a.m. ET, 1:54 a.m. Tokyo] </strong>A dam has broken in Fukushima prefecture, washing away scores of homes in the area, Japan&#8217;s Kyodo news agency reported early Saturday. The Defense Ministry says 1,800 homes have been destroyed in Fukushima.</p>
<p><strong>[11:39 a.m. ET, 1:39 a.m. Tokyo] </strong>At least 133 people were killed, 722 were injured and 530 were missing after the 8.9-magnitude earthquake that hit Japan on Friday, Japan&#8217;s National Police said. Additionally, between 200 and 300 bodies have been found in the coastal city of Sendai in Miyagi Prefecture following the subsequent tsunami that struck that area. The death toll is likely to rise.</p>
<p><strong>[11:31 a.m. ET, 1:31 a.m. Tokyo] </strong>Delta canceled 29 flights into and out of Tokyo on Friday. American Airlines canceled six flights en route to Tokyo on Friday, with some of the planes diverted to Anchorage, Alaska, and others to the Sapporo and Osaka airports in Japan. American Airlines, Delta and United have issued travel waivers for passengers flying to, from or through Japan in the next several days. The waivers will allow travelers to change their plans without a fee.</p>
<p>[cnn-video url="http://www.cnn.com/video/#/video/ireports/2011/03/11/ireport.japan.bennett.cnn"]</p>
<p><strong>[11:07 a.m. ET, 1:07 a.m. Tokyo] </strong>At least 137 people were killed, 539 were injured and 351 were missing after the 8.9-magnitude earthquake that hit Japan on Friday, according to the Kyodo News Agency, citing police. Additionally, between 200 and 300 bodies have been found in the coastal city of Sendai in Miyagi Prefecture following the subsequent tsunami that struck that area. The death toll is likely to rise as there are few casualty counts yet from the worst-hit areas.</p>
<p>[cnn-video url="http://www.cnn.com/video/#/video/world/2011/03/11/nat.moment.of.quake.cnn"]</p>
<p><strong>[10:59 a.m. ET, 12:59 a.m. Tokyo] </strong>About 4 million homes had no power in Tokyo and surrounding areas.</p>
<p><strong>[10:53 a.m. ET, 12:53 a.m. Tokyo] </strong>As the first light of dawn broke Friday in Hawaii, officials reported no significant damage from a series of tsunami waves that struck the islands after Japan&#8217;s earthquake. Tsunami brought waves of nearly 7 feet to a harbor in Maui, authorities said, but other areas reported lower levels.</p>
<p><strong><!--more-->[10:42 a.m. ET, 12:42 a.m. Tokyo] </strong>A dam has broken in Fukushima prefecture, washing away scores of homes in the area, Japan&#8217;s Kyodo news agency reported early Saturday.</p>
<p><strong><!--more-->[10:39 a.m. ET, 12:39 a.m. Tokyo] </strong>Video aired by NHK showed widespread fires in Hakodate in the southern part of Hokkaido island in northern Japan. An oil refinery was burning in Chiba prefecture near Tokyo, according to NHK, and firefighters could not get close enough to fight it because of the heat. And Kyodo said fires could be seen in extensive areas of Kesennuma in Miyagi prefecture.</p>
<p><strong>[10:33 a.m. ET, 12:33 a.m. Tokyo] </strong>Forecasters say waves are expected on the Oregon coast after 7 a.m. local time (10 a.m. ET). The predicted heights of the waves are as follows: Astoria, less than a foot; Clatsop Spit, 4.7 feet; Cannon Beach, 3.9 feet; Oceanside, 3.5 feet; Neskowin, 2.8 feet; Siletz Bay, 7.5 feet; Newport, 3.6 feet; Yachats, 3.9 feet; and Siuslaw River-Florence, 3.2 feet.</p>
<p><strong>[10:15 a.m. ET, 12:15 a.m. Tokyo] </strong>Tsunami waves resulting from Japan&#8217;s earthquake rolled onto the Hawaiian Islands about every 15 minutes Friday morning, bringing waves of nearly 7 feet to a harbor in Maui, authorities said. No significant damage had been reported two hours after the first waves arrived, but officials said they will know more after sunrise.</p>
<p>[cnn-video url="http://www.cnn.com/video/#/video/bestoftv/2011/03/11/exp.Marciano._Tsunami_Warnings.cnn"]</p>
<p><strong>[10:13 a.m. ET, 12:13 a.m. Tokyo] </strong>The Japanese Defense Ministry is readying 300 aircraft and 40 ships to help with relief efforts, the Kyodo News agency reported Friday.</p>
<p>[cnn-video url="http://www.cnn.com/video/#/video/bestoftv/2011/03/11/exp.nr.quake.tokyo.supermarket.cnn"]</p>
<p><strong><!--more-->[10:11 a.m. ET, 12:11 a.m. Tokyo] </strong>Expected tsunami heights in California: Morro Bay, 3.9 feet; Port San Luis Harbor, 7.1 feet; Pismo Beach, 2.4 feet; Santa Maria, 3.3 feet; Santa Barbara, 1.6 feet; Ventura, 2.9 feet; Malibu, 1.2 feet; Santa Monica, 2.8 feet; Redondo Beach, 2.1 feet; San Pedro Harbor, 1.3 feet; Huntington Beach, 2.3 feet.</p>
<p>[cnn-video url="http://www.cnn.com/video/#/video/world/2011/03/11/vo.whirlpool.earthquake.nhk"]</p>
<p><strong>[9:53 a.m. ET, 11:53 p.m. Tokyo] </strong>Fire crews have been able to extinguish a fire at Japan&#8217;s  Onagawa nuclear plant, according to the International Atomic Energy Agency.</p>
<p>[cnn-video url="http://www.cnn.com/video/#/video/world/2011/03/11/sot.japan.tidal.wave.mud.nhk"]</p>
<p><strong>[9:40 a.m. ET, 11:40 p.m. Tokyo] </strong>The toll in the Japan 8.9 quake stands at least 93 dead, 539 injures and 351 missing, according to Japan&#8217;s National Police. Additionally, in Miyagi Prefecture, between 200 and 300 bodies have been found following the tsunami that hit that area.</p>
<p><strong>[9:38 a.m. ET, 11:38 p.m. Tokyo] </strong>Officials are reporting one train derailment and loss of contact with another train in Miyagi prefecture in northern Japan, according to the Kyodo News Agency.</p>
<p><strong>[9:37 a.m. ET, 11:37 p.m. Tokyo] </strong>60,000 to 70,000 people were being evacuated to shelters in the Sendai area of Japan, according to Kyodo.</p>
<p><strong>[9:06 a.m. ET, 11:06 p.m. Tokyo] </strong>The tsunami waves that have hit Hawaii &#8220;are not going to be a major damaging event&#8221; but will cause scattered damage, according to the Pacific Tsunami Warning Center. Waves of nearly 8 feet have been reported Friday on the island of Maui.</p>
<p>[cnn-video url="http://www.cnn.com/video/#/video/bestoftv/2011/03/11/exp.evans.hawaii.tsunami.arrival.cnn"]</p>
<p><strong>[9:02 a.m. ET, 11:02 p.m. Tokyo] </strong>Hawaii could see waves as high as 8 feet in some areas and some resulting damage, Pacific Tsunami Warning Center says.<strong><br />
</strong></p>
<p>[cnn-video url="http://www.cnn.com/video/#/video/world/2011/03/11/vo.japan.water.fields.nhk"]</p>
<p><strong>[8:48 a.m. ET, 10:48 p.m. Tokyo] </strong>Police in Miyagi prefecture say between 200 to 300 bodies have been found in the coastal city of Sendai alone, Japan&#8217;s Kyodo News Agency reported late Friday.</p>
<p><strong>[8:39 a.m. ET, 10:39 p.m. Tokyo] </strong>The National Weather Service said the waves could hit Oregon and California between 7:15 a.m. and 7:30 a.m. PT (10:15-10:30 a.m. ET).</p>
<p><strong>[8:37 a.m. ET, 10:37 p.m. Tokyo] </strong>The first tsunami waves have reached the Hawaiian Islands following a massive earthquake in Japan, local authorities say.</p>
<p><strong>[8:35 a.m. ET, 10:35 p.m. Tokyo] </strong>The toll following the major earthquake that hit Japan Friday stands at  64 dead and 57 missing, according to Japan&#8217;s National Police.</p>
<p><strong>[8:29 a.m. ET, 10:29 p.m. Tokyo] </strong>Some cooling functions at Japan&#8217;s Fukushima nuclear plant are not working and authorities are &#8220;bracing for the worst,&#8221; Japan&#8217;s Chief Cabinet Secretary Yukio Edano said Friday. There is no danger to the environment, but authorities have ordered the evacuation of a few thousand people who live closest to the plant, the Kyodo News agency reported. Others who live nearby have been urged to stay indoors, Edano said.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.cnn.com/video/flashLive/live.html?stream=stream4&amp;hpt=T1"><strong>[8:28 a.m. ET, 10:28 p.m. Tokyo] </strong>Watch a live stream from Hawaii.</a></p>
<p><strong>[8:24 a.m. ET, 10:24 p.m. Tokyo] </strong>The Japan Meteorological Agency said it cannot rule out the possibility of more tsunamis hitting coastal areas in Japan.</p>
<p><strong>[8:19 a.m. ET, 10:19 p.m. Tokyo] </strong>Indonesia&#8217;s Bureau of Meteorology, Geophysics and Climatology has lifted its tsunami warning. Only 10 centimeter waves were reported in Bitung, Manado, North Sulawesi and Halmahera, Maluku, according to the bureau.</p>
<p><strong>[8:15 a.m. ET, 10:15 p.m. Tokyo] </strong>Tsunami warning lifted for Guam; no damage reported.<strong><br />
</strong></p>
<p><strong></strong><strong>[8:10 a.m. ET, 10:10 p.m. Tokyo]</strong> Japan&#8217;s Chief Cabinet<br />
Secretary Yukio Edano ordered the evacuation of a three-kilometer area<br />
around the Fukushima nuclear reactor Friday.</p>
<p><strong>[7:56 a.m. ET, 9:56 p.m. Tokyo] </strong><a href="http://www.khon2.com/content/mediacenter/live.aspx?videoId=8928&amp;navCatId=4">Live webcam on Kauai,</a> where first wave expected at 8:07 ET<strong>. </strong>Waves could be as high as 10 feet in some areas of Hawaii.<strong><br />
</strong></p>
<p><strong>[7:51 a.m. ET, 9:51 p.m. Tokyo] </strong>First tsunami could hit Kauai, Hawaii&#8217;s westernmost main island at 8:07 ET, Coast Guard says<strong>.</strong></p>
<p><strong>[7:42 a.m. ET, 9:42 p.m. Tokyo] </strong>Japan has asked U.S. forces to help with relief efforts, the Kyodo News agency reported.</p>
<p><strong>[7:35 a.m. ET, 9:35 p.m. Tokyo] </strong>Four Japanese nuclear power plants closest to the quake were safely shut down, the U.N. nuclear watchdog agency said. About 2,000 residents near the Fukushima nuclear power plant were being told to evacuate, Kyodo news service said.</p>
<p>[cnn-video url="http://www.cnn.com/video/#/video/bestoftv/2011/03/11/exp.japan.quake.witness.cnn"]</p>
<p><strong>[7:35 a.m. ET, 9:35 p.m. Tokyo] </strong>The U.S. State Department issues a travel alert for Japan, saying U.S. citizens should avoid travel there. The alert expires on April 1.<strong><br />
</strong></p>
<p><strong>[7:28 a.m. ET, 9:28 p.m. Tokyo] </strong>The U.S. ambassador to Japan, John Roos, has moved a U.S. Embassy command center in Japan to an alternate location as a result of numerous aftershocks following a major earthquake in Japan, U.S. State Department spokesman P.J. Crowley said on Twitter.</p>
<p><strong>[7:27 a.m. ET, 9:27 p.m. Tokyo] </strong>The death toll from the earthquake in Japan has risen to 59, the Kyodo News agency reported.</p>
<p><strong>[7:23 a.m. ET, 9:23 p.m. Tokyo] </strong>The city of Honolulu says residents who are not ill are going to hospitals seeking shelter. It is asking them to go to hospitals only if they are ill as hospital do not have facilities for them. <a href="http://www.khon2.com/content/news/developingstories/story/City-asks-residents-not-to-evacuate-to-hospitals/Mym99bFYBUurF7-2HeiHEg.cspx">CNN affiliate KHON reports</a>.</p>
<p><strong>[7:15 a.m. ET, 9:15 p.m. Tokyo] </strong>From Matt Alt, a Tokyo resident, <a href="http://www.cnngo.com/tokyo/life/tokyo-earthquake-survivor-describes-live-account-380455">reporting on CNNGo</a>:<span style="font-family:Arial;font-size:x-small;"> </span>&#8220;Parts of both downtown and in the suburbs are without power. Aftershocks, smaller but still unsettling, continue to rock the area from time to time. As darkness falls over the city, only one thing is for sure. It&#8217;s going to be a long night.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>[7:12 a.m. ET, 9:12 p.m. Tokyo] </strong>Fires were burning at more than 80 locations in Japan after a massive earthquake, the country&#8217;s Kyodo News agency reported.</p>
<p><strong>[7:05 a.m. ET, 9:05 p.m. Tokyo] </strong>The death toll from an earthquake in Japan has risen to more than 50, the Kyodo News agency reported.</p>
<p><strong>[7:01 a.m. ET, 9:01 p.m. Tokyo]</strong> Sailors aboard the aircraft carrier USS George Washington docked in Yokosuka, Japan, <a href="http://www.stripes.com/news/pacific/quake-moves-u-s-aircraft-carrier-from-yokosuka-pier-1.137338">tell Stars and Stripes</a> the force of the quake moved the 60,000-ton ship away from the pier.</p>
<p>[cnn-video url="http://www.cnn.com/video/#/video/world/2011/03/11/bpr.carter.evans.hawaii.tsunami.cnn"]</p>
<p><strong>[6:51 a.m. ET, 8:51 p.m. Tokyo] </strong>Hawaii&#8217;s first tsunami impact may be felt at 3:07 a.m. local time (8:07 a.m. ET), according to Hawaii State Civil Defense, which issued a tsunami warning. Honolulu Mayor Peter Carlisle told CNN the city is planning for several contingencies, because it is not certain how large the waves could be and where they may rush inland.</p>
<p><strong>[6:45 a.m. ET, 8:45 p.m. Tokyo] </strong>Hotel fire, building collapses <a href="http://www3.nhk.or.jp/daily/english/11_35.html">reported by Japan&#8217;s NHK TV</a>.</p>
<p><strong></strong><strong>[6:41 a.m. ET, 8:41 p.m. Tokyo] </strong>CNN International, citing Reuters news service, is reporting a ship with 100 people aboard has been swept away by the tsunami off Japan.<strong><br />
</strong></p>
<p><strong></strong><strong>[6:23 a.m. ET, 8:23 p.m. Tokyo] </strong>All major commercial airports in the state of Hawaii have been closed, CNN affiliate <a href="http://www.khon2.com/news/local/story/Hawaii-airports-closed-due-to-tsunami-warning/_mxY7NUuDkKMRZXx81Rl4A.cspx">KHON reports</a>.<strong><br />
</strong></p>
<p><strong></strong><strong>[6:17 a.m. ET, 8:17 p.m. Tokyo] </strong>The U.S. Navy air facility in Atsugi, Japan, is allowing commercial flights to land there in an effort to help commercial airports in Japan, military officials said.</p>
<p><strong></strong><strong>[6:15 a.m. ET, 8:15 p.m. Tokyo] </strong>Japan government issues emergency declaration for nuclear power plant near Sendai. Plant having troubles with electrical system, CNN&#8217;s Kyung Lah reports.<strong><br />
</strong></p>
<p><strong></strong><strong>[6:11 a.m. ET, 8:11 p.m. Tokyo] </strong>President Obama sends condolences to people of Japan, says U.S. is ready to help in recovery.<strong><br />
</strong></p>
<p><strong></strong><strong>[6:09 a.m. ET, 8:09 p.m. Tokyo] </strong>Officials fear that waves from a tsunami caused by the 8.9-magnitude earthquake that struck Japan could be so high that they wash over entire islands in the Pacific, a spokesman for the International Federation of Red Cross and Red Crescent Societies said Friday.</p>
<p><strong></strong>[cnn-video url="http://www.cnn.com/video/#/video/world/2011/03/11/sot.naoto.kan.cnn"]</p>
<p><strong>[5:59 a.m. ET, 7:59 p.m. Tokyo] </strong>Gerard Fryer of the Pacific Tsunami Warning Center says a five-foot tsunami is being indicated by buoys at Midway Atoll in the Pacific Ocean. A higher tsunami is expected in Hawaii, he tells CNN.<strong><br />
</strong></p>
<p><strong></strong><strong>[5:54 a.m. ET, 7:54 p.m. Tokyo] </strong>The U.S. Navy&#8217;s Pacific Fleet says via Twitter that its ships at Pearl Harbor, Hawaii, will remain in port.</p>
<p><strong>[5:39 a.m. ET, 7:39 p.m. Tokyo]</strong> At least 32 people have been killed and numerous others injured, Japan&#8217;s Kyodo news service reported.</p>
<p>[cnn-video url="http://www.cnn.com/video/#/video/world/2011/03/11/stout.quake.map.cnn"]</p>
<p>[cnn-video url="http://www.cnn.com/video/#/video/world/2011/03/11/lah.bureau.quake.looklive.cnn"]</p>
<p>[cnn-video url="http://www.cnn.com/video/#/video/world/2011/03/11/vo.quake.cars.water.mov.avn"]</p>
<p>[cnn-video url="http://www.cnn.com/video/#/video/world/2011/03/11/von.quake.meeting.avn"]</p>
<p>[cnn-video url="http://www.cnn.com/video/#/video/world/2011/03/11/bpr.quake.witness.cnn"]</p>
<p>[cnn-video url="http://www.cnn.com/video/#/video/world/2011/03/11/vo.japan.quake.cnn.cnn"]</p>
<p>[cnn-video url="http://www.cnn.com/video/#/video/world/2011/03/11/sot.tsunami.hit.japan.cnn"]</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/63481/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/63481/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/63481/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/63481/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/63481/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/63481/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/63481/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/63481/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/63481/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/63481/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/63481/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/63481/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/63481/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/63481/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=63481&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://news.blogs.cnn.com/2011/03/11/live-blog-japan-earthquake/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>281</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/54529bb8fcdb8b546a9b9c5518b05269?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lendonsan</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cape Daisy Macro 2011</title>
		<link>http://adrianharveyphotography.wordpress.com/2011/03/06/cape-daisy-macro/</link>
		<comments>http://adrianharveyphotography.wordpress.com/2011/03/06/cape-daisy-macro/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2011 10:50:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Adrian</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Nature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flowers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Macro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canon 50D]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Closeup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wildlife]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flowers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flower photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blue]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[purple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Camera]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stamens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[60mm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cropped]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fotografia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fotograf]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://adrianharveyphotography.wordpress.com/?p=1121</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Macro of Cape Daisy &#160;<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=1121&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a rel="attachment wp-att-1122" href="http://adrianharveyphotography.wordpress.com/2011/03/06/cape-daisy-macro/cape-daisy-5/"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1122" title="Cape Daisy" src="http://adrianharveyphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/cape-daisy.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=740" alt="" width="1024" height="740" /></a></p>
<p>Macro of Cape Daisy</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">&nbsp;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1121/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1121/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1121/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1121/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1121/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1121/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1121/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1121/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1121/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1121/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1121/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1121/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1121/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1121/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=1121&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://adrianharveyphotography.wordpress.com/2011/03/06/cape-daisy-macro/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		<georss:point>38.739891 -0.012076</georss:point>
		<geo:lat>38.739891</geo:lat>
		<geo:long>-0.012076</geo:long>
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/73c8e876c55f3b9a8c9f3c93ddf31ba4?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">axalo</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://adrianharveyphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/cape-daisy.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Cape Daisy</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Time Has Come To Spring Forward</title>
		<link>http://miami.cbslocal.com/2011/03/10/the-time-has-come-to-spring-forward-this-weekend/</link>
		<comments>http://miami.cbslocal.com/2011/03/10/the-time-has-come-to-spring-forward-this-weekend/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2011 18:42:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>cbs4lisa</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Local]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daylight Saving Time]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daylight Savings Time]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spring Forward]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Standard Time]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Time Change]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://miami.cbslocal.com/?p=30259</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In a sleep deprived nation, we're all about to lose a little more as Daylight Saving Time arrives Sunday. This means the daylight will begin later in the morning and the sun will set later in the evening.<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=30259&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>MIAMI (CBS4) &#8212; In a sleep deprived nation, we&#8217;re all about to lose a little more as Daylight Saving Time arrives Sunday. This means the daylight will begin later in the morning and the sun will set later in the evening.</p>
<p>So this is your reminder: Before going to bed Saturday night, move your clocks and watches forward by one hour or risk being an hour late to Sunday church or other activities.</p>
<p>The lost hour will return Sunday, November 6th, when clocks go back to standard time.</p>
<p>The only two states that do not observe daylight-saving time are Arizona and Hawaii. Neither does American Samoa, Guam, Puerto Rico, and the U.S. Virgin Islands.</p>
<p>Daylight Saving Time begins at 2:00 a.m. on the second Sunday in March and reverts to Standard Time on the first Sunday in November.</p>
<p>Of course, whenever you set your clocks ahead one hour, you are also supposed to make another change. Change the batteries on your smoke detectors.</p>
<p>Smoke detector batteries need changing every six months and the switch to daylight-saving time is the perfect time to make the change.</p>
<p>The Florida Highway Patrol also warns drivers and pedestrians to be especially careful on the Monday morning commute to work or school. It will likely be dark and everyone needs to pay close attention to the roads.</p>
<p>Did you know? Daylight saving time was first used during World War I, as part of an effort in the United States and other warring countries to conserve fuel. In theory, using daylight more efficiently saves fuel and energy because it reduces the nation&#8217;s need for artificial light.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/30259/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/30259/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/30259/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/30259/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/30259/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/30259/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/30259/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/30259/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/30259/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/30259/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/30259/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/30259/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/30259/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/30259/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=30259&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://miami.cbslocal.com/2011/03/10/the-time-has-come-to-spring-forward-this-weekend/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/520d63b861a8142ca37aa3ec689e82fb?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F1.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cbs4lisa</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>2011, The Year of the Sequel</title>
		<link>http://themoviebros.com/2011/03/06/2011-the-year-of-the-sequel/</link>
		<comments>http://themoviebros.com/2011/03/06/2011-the-year-of-the-sequel/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2011 13:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>The Movie Brothers</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Commentary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Entertainment News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Movie Camp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Movie review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[action]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adventure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alvin And The Chipmunks: Chipwrecked]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bad movie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Big Mommas: Like Father]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Camp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cars 2]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cinema]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comedy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comic book]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comic book movie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comic books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commentary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diary Of A Wimpy Kid 2: Rodrick Rules]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entertainment news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fast Five]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Final Destination 5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ghostbusters 3]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ghostbusters III]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Happy Feet 2]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Harry Potter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Harry Potter And The Deathly Hallows Part Two]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hoodwinked Too! Hood Vs. Evil]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[horror]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Johnny English Reborn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kung Fu Panda 2]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Like Son]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Madea’s Big Happy Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mission: Impossible – Ghost Protocol]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Movie reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[murder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mystery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Paranormal Activity 3]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Piranha 3DD]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pirates Of The Caribbean: On Stranger Tides]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Puss In Boots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sci-fi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scream 4]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sherlock Holmes: A Game Of Shadows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spy Kids 4: All The Time In The World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Star Wars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[suspense]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Hangover Part II]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Movie Brothers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Muppets and Rise Of The Ape]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Twilight Saga: Breaking Dawn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thriller]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Transformers: Dark of the Moon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Winnie The Pooh]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[X-Men First Class]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://themoviebros.com/?p=3833</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Matt It&#8217;s official: Hollywood is tapped for any fresh ideas. One in five films released this year will either be a sequel, prequel, or spin-off. Not that this should come as a huge shock to anyone. According to a report by Box Office Mojo, Hollywood will rely on former glories in 2011 to a greater degree [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=3833&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3><a href="http://themoviebros.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/big-mommas-like-father-like-son-1-700671.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3836" title="big-mommas-like-father-like-son-1-700671" src="http://themoviebros.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/big-mommas-like-father-like-son-1-700671.jpg?w=500&#038;h=375" alt="" width="500" height="375" /></a>Matt</h3>
<p>It&#8217;s official: Hollywood is tapped for any fresh ideas. One in five films released this year will either be a sequel, prequel, or spin-off. Not that this should come as a huge shock to anyone.</p>
<p><a href="http://boxofficemojo.com/news/?id=3063&amp;p=s.htm" target="_blank">According to a report by Box Office Mojo</a>, Hollywood will rely on former glories in 2011 to a greater degree than ever before. Sequels, prequels, and spin-offs comprise over a fifth of the currently scheduled nationwide releases, tallying 27 &#8212; including the third installment of the Big Momma series, &#8220;Big Mommas: Like Father, Like Son.&#8221; Last year, there were 19 sequels, prequels and spin-offs, and the previous high was 24 in 2003.<a href="http://themoviebros.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/scream-4-poster_344.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-3841" title="scream-4-poster_344" src="http://themoviebros.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/scream-4-poster_344.jpg?w=202&#038;h=300" alt="" width="202" height="300" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://themoviebros.com/2010/06/08/enough-with-the-tv-remakes/" target="_blank">I&#8217;ve complained about adaptations and remakes, especially with TV.</a> In general, I&#8217;m not totally opposed to sequels.<a href="http://themoviebros.com/2010/11/21/ghostbusters-3-update/" target="_blank"> I hope they make Ghostbusters 3</a>, expect Scream 4 to be a blast, and can&#8217;t wait for the next Iron Man and Batman films. But we don&#8217;t need a third Big Mamma, a third Alvin and the Chipmunks, a fourth Mission Impossible and Pirates of the Caribbean. And we certainly don&#8217;t need a fifth installment of the Fast and the Furious franchise. I&#8217;m pretty sure we&#8217;ll all survive without it.</p>
<p>And some of the titles to these are just precious. The next<a href="http://themoviebros.com/2010/08/22/piranha-3-d/" target="_blank"> Piranha 3-D </a>film will be called&#8230;. wait for it&#8230;. Piranha 3DD. I can see the movie poster taglilne: &#8220;Piranha 3DD &#8212; The extra &#8216;D&#8217; is for Dumb.&#8221;</p>
<p>Hollywood can do better. It&#8217;s up to the consumer to show them what we&#8217;re not willing to spend our money on bad movies.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s the complete list of all the sequels set for release this year:</p>
<p><strong>Second films</strong>: Cars 2, Diary Of A Wimpy Kid 2: Rodrick Rules, The Hangover Part II, Happy Feet 2, Hoodwinked Too! Hood Vs. Evil, Johnny English Reborn, Kung Fu Panda 2, Piranha 3DD, Sherlock Holmes: A Game Of Shadows.</p>
<p><strong>Third films</strong>: Alvin And The Chipmunks: Chipwrecked, Big Mommas: Like Father, Like Son, Madea’s Big Happy Family, Paranormal Activity 3, Transformers: Dark Of The Moon.</p>
<p><strong>Fourth films</strong>: Mission: Impossible – Ghost Protocol, Pirates Of The Caribbean: On Stranger Tides, Scream 4, Spy Kids 4: All The Time In The World, The Twilight Saga: Breaking Dawn (Part One).</p>
<p><strong>Fifth films</strong>: Fast Five, Final Destination 5, Puss In Boots, X-Men: First Class, Winnie The Pooh.</p>
<p><strong>Seventh films</strong>: The Muppets and Rise Of The Apes.</p>
<p><strong>Eighth film</strong>: Harry Potter And The Deathly Hallows Part Two.</p>
<span style="text-align:center; display: block;"><a href="http://themoviebros.com/2011/03/06/2011-the-year-of-the-sequel/"><img src="http://img.youtube.com/vi/a_a7oHYtNA4/2.jpg" alt="" /></a></span>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3833/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3833/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3833/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3833/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3833/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3833/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3833/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3833/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3833/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3833/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3833/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3833/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3833/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3833/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=3833&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://themoviebros.com/2011/03/06/2011-the-year-of-the-sequel/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>99</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/1af0c1d77c37b245eea0380e70289f24?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mattvolke</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://themoviebros.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/big-mommas-like-father-like-son-1-700671.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">big-mommas-like-father-like-son-1-700671</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://themoviebros.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/scream-4-poster_344.jpg?w=202" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">scream-4-poster_344</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>