<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2013 21:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>A Lesson With My Daughter on Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr.</title>
		<link>http://egoinflux.wordpress.com/2013/01/15/stand-up-a-lesson-with-my-daughter-on-dr-martin-luther-king-jr/</link>
		<comments>http://egoinflux.wordpress.com/2013/01/15/stand-up-a-lesson-with-my-daughter-on-dr-martin-luther-king-jr/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2013 03:28:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jason Leslie Rogers</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Memoirs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Philosophy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[activism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[civil rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[justice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[king]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Martin Luther King]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MLK]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MLK Day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nobel Prize]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[racism]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://egoinflux.wordpress.com/?p=248</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;What would you do,&#8221; I asked my daughter, &#8220;if you walked into a restaurant full of little boys and little girls with green and brown and hazel eyes, and you sat down and asked for something to eat, but the restaurant owner told you that you couldn&#8217;t eat in his restaurant because your eyes were [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=248&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://egoinflux.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/mlk_fanart2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-249" alt="Martin Luther King Jr." src="http://egoinflux.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/mlk_fanart2.jpg?w=1000&#038;h=562" width="1000" height="562" /></a></p>
<p>&#8220;What would you do,&#8221; I asked my daughter, &#8220;if you walked into a restaurant full of little boys and little girls with green and brown and hazel eyes, and you sat down and asked for something to eat, but the restaurant owner told you that you couldn&#8217;t eat in his restaurant because your eyes were blue? How would that make you feel?&#8221;<span id="more-248"></span></p>
<p>Let&#8217;s back up a minute. In all fairness, my eight-year-old daughter is the one who started this conversation. I&#8217;m not sure I have the foresight in my daily activities to plan a historical and cultural lesson that just happens to coincide with the anniversary of the birth of one of the greatest men in the last century.</p>
<p>&#8220;Have you ever heard of Martin Luther King?&#8221; she asked me earlier tonight.</p>
<p>&#8220;I sure have, sweetheart,&#8221; I said.</p>
<p>(ignoring me) &#8220;Well, dad,&#8221; she continued, &#8220;Martin Luther King was a very important man. He won the Nobel Peace Prize because he got the blacks and the whites to stop living separately and to stop being so mean to each other.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Okay,&#8221; I replied. &#8220;I guess that&#8217;s one way of putting it.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Dad, what&#8217;s a Nobel Peace Prize?&#8221; she asked, so I reminded her about Norman Borlaug and how he developed dwarf wheat, a plant that saved 1 billion lives (she had read about Borlaug and talked about him in class the week before). Then we talked about Gandhi and Mandela and Dr. Martin Luther King Jr. and the work those three men did, how they all just wanted people to be treated the same, even if they were different. I told her that the Nobel Peace Prize was something that was given only to men and women, and sometimes even groups of people, that do wonderful and extraordinary things to make the world a better and safer place to live.</p>
<p>(after a thoughtful pause) &#8220;Dad, am I white?&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Well, yeah, sweetheart. I suppose that, if you were to ask people back when Dr. King was still alive, they would have called you &#8220;white.&#8221;</p>
<p>A look of slight relief came across her face. &#8220;So I wouldn&#8217;t have to drink from a different water fountain that said, &#8216;Colored only&#8217; or go to a different school than my friends?&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;No, you wouldn&#8217;t have to do any of those things, but all of your friends at school who have darker skin would have to leave your school and go to a different school where everyone there had dark skin like them.&#8221; I could tell by the lack of response to this statement that this wasn&#8217;t really sinking in.</p>
<p>So I asked my daughter, &#8220;What would you do if you walked into a restaurant full of little boys and little girls with green and brown and hazel eyes, and you sat down and asked for something to eat, but the restaurant owner told you that you couldn&#8217;t eat in his restaurant because your eyes were blue? How would that make you feel?&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;That wouldn&#8217;t make me feel very nice,&#8221; she replied. &#8220;I think that would make me very sad.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Well, sweetie,&#8221; I said,&#8221; that&#8217;s the way it felt for people with dark skin who lived in the United States of America when Martin Luther King was alive. There were separate schools and buses and restaurants and water fountains and even separate churches. And this was all because some of the people in our country had darker skin than the rest.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;But Martin Luther King stood up to them, didn&#8217;t he, daddy?&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Mmm-hmm,&#8221; I agreed, as I pulled her onto the recliner with me and set her on my lap.</p>
<p>&#8220;But then a man shot him,&#8221; she said, looking troubled and with her voice starting to break. &#8220;Why did they shoot him just like they did Abraham Lincoln? They shot President Abraham Lincoln before he could finish! And then Martin Luther King had to finish it for him! And then they shot Martin Luther King!&#8221; she said, sinking her head into the spot where my arm and chest meet. &#8220;Why did that man shoot Martin Luther King?&#8221;</p>
<p>I thought for a moment about how to explain something like this to an eight-year-old. &#8220;Dr. King said some things that made a lot of people angry. Some of them got so angry that they wanted to hurt him, and one man did,&#8221; I said to my daughter as she stared toward the floor. &#8220;But you know what? It was too late. The man that shot Martin Luther King Jr. may have killed him, but he couldn&#8217;t do anything to stop all the good work that Dr. King did.&#8221;</p>
<p>An idea suddenly struck me. &#8220;Would you like to see a video of Dr. Martin Luther King Jr. giving a very important speech?&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Is it the &#8216;I Have a Dream Speech?&#8217;&#8221; she asked, her eyes lighting up. I nodded yes. &#8220;Yeah!&#8221; She said, clapping her hands together. &#8220;We read about that in class!&#8221;</p>
<p>I quickly turned the Blu-ray player to the YouTube channel and found a slightly shorter version of  the speech (it was already past her bedtime). We cuddled together and listened to the speech. She didn&#8217;t squirm, she didn&#8217;t ask questions, and she didn&#8217;t take her eyes off the video. At the end, she asked me if that was really Dr. Martin Luther King Jr. on the video, if that was really his voice. I told her it was, and then I asked her how she felt and what she thought while she was watching the video.</p>
<p>&#8220;It made me feel like freedom should ring for every person in the whole world,&#8221; she said, &#8220;even the animals so they won&#8217;t get eaten.&#8221; (I&#8217;ll have to remind her of this the next time she&#8217;s eating a plate full of bacon at breakfast.)</p>
<p>A few minutes later, after I tucked her into bed and sang her two favorite bedtime songs (&#8220;You Are My Sunshine&#8221; and &#8220;Twinkle, Twinkle&#8221;), she asked me, &#8220;Daddy, if I win the Nobel Peace Prize does that mean somebody will shoot me? Because I&#8217;d like to be a scientist and invent things that make people&#8217;s lives a lot better. And I want to make sure we always have the laws that say you can&#8217;t separate black people and white people from each other.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;No, sweetheart,&#8221; I said, running my fingers through the hair on the top of her head. &#8220;Just because you win the Nobel Peace Prize, it doesn&#8217;t mean that someone will want to shoot you. But you don&#8217;t have to win a prize to be able to do good things for people. Gandhi and Mandela and Borlaug and Martin Luther King, they weren&#8217;t trying to win a prize or an award. They were just trying to do what was right.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Okay, daddy,&#8221; she said with a long sigh. &#8220;That&#8217;s good, because I wanna stand up.&#8221;</p>
<p>And with that, I kissed her and left her to her dreams.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/248/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/248/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=248&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://egoinflux.wordpress.com/2013/01/15/stand-up-a-lesson-with-my-daughter-on-dr-martin-luther-king-jr/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>15</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/b6c8c04c3d9f9a1ad0438367e1f03388?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Indigo Embrace</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://egoinflux.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/mlk_fanart2.jpg?w=1000" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Martin Luther King Jr.</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tabula Rasa</title>
		<link>http://epsilon4.wordpress.com/2013/01/15/tabula-rasa/</link>
		<comments>http://epsilon4.wordpress.com/2013/01/15/tabula-rasa/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 22:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jon Ball</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Musings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[childhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[discovery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[philosophy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[slate]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://epsilon4.wordpress.com/?p=247</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I am firm in the belief that our environment is responsible for a lot of what makes us who we are. Part of who we are comes from genetics, but I believe the majority of it comes from the environment. And whatever genetic predispositions our minds have can still be greatly altered by the people around us [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=247&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I am firm in the belief that our environment is responsible for a lot of what makes us who we are. Part of who we are comes from genetics, but I believe the majority of it comes from the environment. And whatever genetic predispositions our minds have can still be greatly altered by the people around us and whatever situations in which we find ourselves during the developmental part of our lives. You are the product of your childhood. Your parents are mostly responsible for how you turned out. You totally have the right to blame them for all your problems, or if not them, then someone who played a major role in your early years. Even as an adult, every life that comes in contact with yours has the potential to shape and mold your self in new ways. You have just as much potential to shape and mold other people&#8217;s lives as well. As the saying goes, no man is an island. We are all interconnected and we all pull our nature from each other.</p>
<p>We all start out life as a blank slate. Throughout the time we spend on this planet, things are constantly being added to the parchment of our personality. Each new thing builds onto every other thing that came before it. Habits are formed, routines are established, opinions and ideals are isolated and solidified. Each addition to the page makes it more difficult to add something else because there is only so much space that can be utilized. It&#8217;s like you are trying to write out everything that defines yourself on a single sheet of paper.</p>
<p>During childhood the page is completely blank, so you make very large pen strokes. Then, during adolescence, you realize there is not quite as much free space anymore, so you make smaller markings. There is still plenty of space to write what you have to say though. As you enter adulthood, your letters become very small and scrunched together at the bottom of the page as you try to wrap things up. Hopefully you don&#8217;t have much more to add because you have pretty much run out of room. Throughout your later years you occasionally add a few things in the margins (you only have room to edit your initial draft with the most important changes). There is always room for additions, but it becomes more and more difficult to throw them in, and your initial large pen strokes will always dominate the page.</p>
<p>Life is written in pen. We cannot go back and erase our mistakes. We can, however, cross things out. We can acknowledge that our lives began to take a certain path, but now we choose to take a different path. We are forced to keep the scars of our past, but the depth of those scars depends on how thoroughly those previous markings are scratched out. Sometimes we can even get our hands on some whiteout and cover up old parts of ourselves in order to write in something new and fresh. It&#8217;s a way to somewhat recover that initial blank slate state, although there are still imperfections.</p>
<p>I feel like recently I was able to whiteout my life. Not all of it, but a large part of it that had been really dragging me down. A major part of me that was holding me back. And now that it is covered up, I can go back and rewrite it. I can explore options that I could have explored before but never did. At first I was relieved to be rid of such a burden, but now I am excited, because what was once a burden is now a huge opportunity to discover myself again. I can look at familiar ideas under a new light, and it is spectacular. Seeing things from a different perspective makes a huge difference in the way life itself is experienced.</p>
<p>Until next time, may you write legibly on your metaphysical parchment.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://desireemahr.wordpress.com/2012/01/25/4-ways-pen-paper-can-kick-start-your-writing-process/"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-251" alt="Notebook on Wood" src="http://epsilon4.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/notebook-on-wood.jpg?w=464&#038;h=298" width="464" height="298" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/247/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/247/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=247&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://epsilon4.wordpress.com/2013/01/15/tabula-rasa/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/cd4c19778ec0ae86943bbd814d5a1e9e?s=96&#38;d=retro&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">epsilon4</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://epsilon4.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/notebook-on-wood.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Notebook on Wood</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Questioning Reason</title>
		<link>http://mmews.wordpress.com/2013/01/15/questioning-reason/</link>
		<comments>http://mmews.wordpress.com/2013/01/15/questioning-reason/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2013 03:30:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>mmews</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Philosophy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Revolution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Simplicity]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://mmews.wordpress.com/?p=1311</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[One of my favorite Ohio vineyards is for sale. I&#8217;ve been trying to dismiss the dream as unreasonable since I heard about it this weekend. Rationalization about the loan, my ability to garden, my love of the city, work, kids, dogs, anything to talk myself out of it. Tonight, I find myself alone with the [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1311&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One of my favorite Ohio vineyards is for sale.  </p>
<p>I&#8217;ve been trying to dismiss the dream as unreasonable since I heard about it this weekend.  Rationalization about the loan, my ability to garden, my love of the city, work, kids, dogs, anything to talk myself out of it.  Tonight, I find myself alone with the vineyard listing with a full hour of quiet stretching in front of me.</p>
<p>Normally, that&#8217;s heaven.  Except, that vineyard is calling me&#8230;&#8221;Oh, Monica&#8217;s gut&#8230;come, let&#8217;s rule the vineyard together&#8230;&#8221; like a siren beckoning.</p>
<p>No, I should be productive and DO something.  I tune into my overdue History lesson.  I&#8217;m a few weeks behind, but intuition, sick children and work responsibilities have kept me from catching up.  Until tonight.  I need a distraction from all this thinking about owning a vineyard on the Ohio River.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s the 1900s and my History teacher is comparing modernity with the Enlightenment&#8230;or should I say he&#8217;s contrasting them.  There&#8217;s not much in common.  Where Enlightenment taught that men could think and create and be independent, modernity of the 1900s&#8212;especially the growing trend towards materialism&#8212;showed that men were irrational, slaves to societal thinking and dependent.</p>
<p>Men, that is, except for Gandhi.  Gandhi believed in self sufficiency.  &#8220;He believed in learning to do as much for yourself as possible,&#8221; my teacher says leading me right back to a vineyard and winery&#8230;</p>
<p>I could certainly suffice for myself on 128 acres of fertile field.  In addition to growing and making wine to share, I would have fruit trees, a vegetable garden, wild turkeys, deer, space for my dogs to run free, fresh clean air, a house with a kitchen in which to bake bread and cook meals, a sunroom in which to write, a yard to stretch out all my laundry on the line.  </p>
<p>And a barn in which to sing and dance and host song and dance.</p>
<p>Would I need anything?  Well, for certain I&#8217;d need loved ones and friends to celebrate with me, to sing with me, to dance with me.  I&#8217;d need neighbors with whom to chat over a fence and remark upon the weather.  There is the matter of a million dollar loan.  But also I&#8217;d need a fire in my fireplace.  And a bottle of wine at the ready.</p>
<p>Perhaps I&#8217;d also need to learn to sew a bit better than just a rudimentary skirt.  And maybe some handyman skills&#8230;or a handyman.  My accountant would have to stay with me too, because she is as much a trusted advisor on living well as an outstanding and wise mathematician and friend.  </p>
<p>Yes, that&#8217;s right about when I began questioning my reason again and demand from myself a focus on history.  </p>
<p>We can learn so much from history.  I already have!  Especially with this course.</p>
<p>Max Weber, the age of psychology, Sigmund Freud.  What&#8217;s with all this concern about sexuality, I wonder as my teacher again begins to contrast Enlightenment with this.  We went from beauty in human art and a focus on nature to base desires, animalistic drives and urges, women as moralistically vulnerable&#8230;</p>
<p>I must be hallucinating as I listen.  </p>
<p>&#8220;So the rise of civilization was not the triumph of reason,&#8221; he states matter of factly, almost sadly, &#8220;but the ability to contain ourselves, to repress ourselves.&#8221;  </p>
<p>I should definitely buy that vineyard.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1311/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1311/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1311&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://mmews.wordpress.com/2013/01/15/questioning-reason/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/400c95108361ca3e4077b5e6b88cf736?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mmews</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Finding My Guts</title>
		<link>http://annieharm.wordpress.com/2013/01/16/finding-my-guts/</link>
		<comments>http://annieharm.wordpress.com/2013/01/16/finding-my-guts/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2013 02:27:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Annie Haarmann</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[on a serious note]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[colleagues]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[employee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[employer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gig]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[guts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leadership]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life lesson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[office]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[raise rejected]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[work]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://annieharm.wordpress.com/?p=1044</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[ I was told it was nothing personal, just business. The rejection stung like a paintball gun to the kidney. Cognitively, I understood that it was &#8220;just business&#8221; but that didn&#8217;t make it any less heartbreaking. It may have been business to them, but it was personal to me&#8230; This week, I will graduate from a [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1044&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p><em> I was told it was nothing personal, just business. The rejection stung like a paintball gun to the kidney. Cognitively, I understood that it was &#8220;just business&#8221; but that didn&#8217;t make it any less heartbreaking. It may have been business to them, but it was personal to me&#8230; </em></p></blockquote>
<p>This week, I will graduate from a four-month leadership program through FOCUS St. Louis and Coro Women in Leadership. I&#8217;m really glad I participated in the program, and I gained some invaluable lessons and insights. For example, I learned about:</p>
<p>1. Risks. I am an ambitious risk-taker. A Coro classmate described me as &#8220;taking a swan dive into every new situation.&#8221; I like the sound of that.</p>
<p>2. Mistakes. Recognizing my mistakes is not the same as hating myself for them. It&#8217;s more important for me to be willing to learn from screw-ups than to be perfect all the time.</p>
<p>3. Guts. My gut is smarter than I give it credit for. I should trust it more often.</p>
<div id="attachment_918" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 404px"><a href="http://annieharm.files.wordpress.com/2012/03/floatation.jpg"><img class="wp-image-918 " alt="I wore floaties until I reached high school." src="http://annieharm.files.wordpress.com/2012/03/floatation.jpg?w=394&#038;h=526" width="394" height="526" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Here I am prepared to take a &#8220;swan dive&#8221; into any new situation.</p></div>
<p><strong>Acceptance</strong><br />
I was accepted to the leadership program in August. My supervisors had enthusiastically written letters of recommendation for me, and my boss allowed me the time to attend the program.</p>
<p>Most attendees in the program had their tuition paid for by their employers. Without this kind of support, the program was a significant financial investment for my husband and me to make. We had to weigh the benefits of the program against the likelihood we could only afford to eat saltines and generic Kraft cheese slices for the next few months. But I saw the value in professional development, and I needed a challenge.</p>
<p>Actually, scratch that. What I really needed was to change my career.</p>
<p>Let me step back.</p>
<p><strong>Finding My Tribe</strong><br />
My employer had been a positive part of my life for two and a half years. My position was exactly what I needed after having worked for a sociopath during the 10 months prior to being hired there. My new boss quickly became a mentor, teacher and friend. Under his tutelage, I improved as a writer and as a professional.</p>
<p>My coworkers laughed at my jokes, granting me permission to be myself in the department. I quickly found my place in the pack. I belonged.</p>
<p>I don&#8217;t always express admiration or care toward others in the warmest way. My modus operandi is to deflect personal emotions with sarcasm and humor. But I feel things very strongly. I internalize everything.</p>
<p>Over the years, I grew to care very deeply for my colleagues, and I was passionate about my work. Plus, I was good at my job &#8211; really good.</p>
<p><strong>A Tough Blow</strong><br />
At my annual performance review in April, I received perfect marks and glowing feedback &#8211; as I had in each previous review. Unfortunately, it wasn&#8217;t enough to garner the raise I requested. I was told it was nothing personal, just business.</p>
<p>The rejection stung like a paintball gun to the kidney.</p>
<p>Cognitively, I understood that it was &#8220;just business&#8221; but that didn&#8217;t make it any less heartbreaking. It may have been business to them, but it was personal to me. My self-esteem has always been reflective of my professional achievements.</p>
<p>Until then, I had imagined myself working my way up the ranks to a VP someday. I had even brushed off a couple of recruiters throughout the years. But now everything had changed.</p>
<p>I hadn&#8217;t positioned myself as a good enough investment. From the company&#8217;s perspective, they had me for a bargain. I had already developed a comprehensive strategy and was leading several projects and initiatives. Upon making it into the boardroom, I noticed I was the lowest level employee in there. I certainly appreciated the seat at the table, but if they already had the milk for cheap, why should they give the cow more money? That would have been udderly ridiculous.</p>
<p><strong>A Second Opinion</strong><br />
Friends responded to my plight in one of two ways. Some said I was right to ask for what I deserved. Others said I asked for too much and should be grateful I had a job at all.</p>
<p>Was I deluding myself?</p>
<p>My gut told me I was worth it. But the only power I had was the freedom to leave. And at the time, I didn&#8217;t fully realize just how powerful that freedom was. I had no idea I wielded the only power I needed.</p>
<p><strong>L is for Loser</strong><br />
I started feeling like a schmuck for putting myself in this situation. I was bummed. Then I was sad. I became depressed. Fortunately, I learned that the company&#8217;s Employee Assistance Program covered counseling.</p>
<p>Perfect! My company was kind enough to provide someone to help me address the depression I felt because of my company.</p>
<p>To call this period a really dark time would be the biggest understatement ever written on this blog. I don&#8217;t want to get into specifics, but let&#8217;s just say even I couldn&#8217;t muster enough sarcasm to combat the deep melancholy of those months. I was in the shit.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s amazing how differently my year ended than it began.</p>
<p>It took me some time to accept that I wouldn&#8217;t be advancing at the company. But walking away is a risk.</p>
<p>I took my time. I sent a handful of applications, went on a few &#8220;interesting&#8221; interviews &#8211; some of which are blog posts for another day. But in August, right around the same time I started my leadership program, I was called in to an interview.</p>
<p>Then, I was called in to an interview somewhere else. Fast forward a few weeks, and I had two job offers in front of me.</p>
<p>My gut was cheering me on! And simultaneously telling me to puke. I had never been so optimistic nor so terrified.</p>
<p><strong>Moving On</strong><br />
When I put in my notice, my boss wasn&#8217;t surprised. No one was surprised. I&#8217;ve never had a very good poker face, but I never wanted to give the impression I was unhappy. Unsatisfied, certainly. But I loved my work and enjoyed every day collaborating with the talented people around me.</p>
<p>The departure was rough. Having deflected emotion via sarcasm for the past two and a half years, I found tears welling upon informing colleagues.</p>
<p>Despite everything, I left the company in the best way possible. I know they made a business decision. I understand that it wasn&#8217;t personal, even though it hurt. I wish everyone could find joy and passion in their job the way I did at this one. I will always be grateful to the company for my experience, and I can honestly say I found something to get pumped up about on every single day I came to work. I laughed on every single day of work. How many people can say that?</p>
<p><strong>Guts and Glory</strong><br />
My gut has been shouting, &#8220;I told you so!&#8221; ever since I began my new gig. And since starting, I&#8217;ve been challenged in ways I never anticipated. I&#8217;ve learned several valuable lessons from this past year&#8217;s experience:</p>
<p>1. My self worth is not determined by the value an employer may put on me.</p>
<p>2. I&#8217;m very, VERY good at what I do.</p>
<p>3. I&#8217;ve got good guts.</p>
<p>I will never again let my self worth be defined by my net worth &#8211; a lesson I want to record here lest I need a future reminder.</p>
<p>My gut tells me I&#8217;m not the only one who needs a reminder.</p>
<p><strong><em>For less about my own personal triumph and more about my own personal humiliation, check out some of my other posts:</em></strong></p>
<ul>
<li><em><a title="The 4 Jerks You Meet at The Airport" href="http://annieharm.wordpress.com/2012/08/02/the-4-jerks-you-meet-at-the-airport/">The 4 Jerks You Meet at The Airport</a></em></li>
<li><em><a href="http://annieharm.wordpress.com/2011/12/20/3-awful-holiday-traditions/">3 Awful Holiday Traditions</a></em></li>
<li><em><a href="http://annieharm.wordpress.com/2011/02/23/4-good-reasons-to-hate-babies/">4 Perfectly Acceptable Reasons to Hate Babies</a></em></li>
<li><em><a title="Tales of Humiliation: Hell on Wheels" href="http://annieharm.wordpress.com/2012/03/21/tales-of-humiliation-hell-on-wheels/">Tales of Humiliation: Hell on Wheels</a></em></li>
<li><em><a title="The Worst Thing I Ever Saw" href="http://annieharm.wordpress.com/2010/10/04/the-worst-thing-i-ever-saw/">The Worst Thing I Ever Saw</a></em></li>
</ul>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1044/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1044/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1044&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://annieharm.wordpress.com/2013/01/16/finding-my-guts/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>22</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/542f6ce0109b0af5f97a9565759df79c?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">anniehaarmann</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://annieharm.files.wordpress.com/2012/03/floatation.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">I wore floaties until I reached high school.</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Traveling Carnival</title>
		<link>http://thetruthache.com/2013/01/15/traveling-carnival/</link>
		<comments>http://thetruthache.com/2013/01/15/traveling-carnival/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2013 14:35:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>mygirlfriday</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[The Disease]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bi-polar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bipolar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[disease]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dreams]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[madness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medicine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pills]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[truth]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thetruthache.com/?p=678</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I am having a bad day.  And strangely it has nothing to do with the disease.  I am having a normal bad day; bank account looking scary, child forgot book bag, boss on my ass.  Such normal sucky things, that I find for the most kind of reassuring.  It means that my act, my desire [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=678&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://atruthache.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/carnavil.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-679" alt="carnavil" src="http://atruthache.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/carnavil.jpg?w=720"   /></a>I am having a bad day.  And strangely it has nothing to do with the disease.  I am having a normal bad day; bank account looking scary, child forgot book bag, boss on my ass.  Such normal sucky things, that I find for the most kind of reassuring.  It means that my act, my desire to appear normal may be working.</p>
<p>I know intellectually that people with bi-polar disease have bad days; and the days that are disappointing or stressful don&#8217;t have to do with how much medicine I am taking or where on the rainbow scale my feelings are.  They are just the products of life.  The effects of the causes.</p>
<p>But there is a sort of harmony in what I imagine is the normal.  I am not normal; but to have a day that I can share with a sister without worrying about the consequences is unique in my world.  The tough day I am having is so normal that it actually doesn&#8217;t upset me.  There are times I crave normal, I crave a life without medicine and darkness; I crave the very thing that would make others sweat.</p>
<p>Normal isn&#8217;t a word I get to use very often.  In fact, I have gotten so use to the question asked of me, &#8220;What is normal?&#8221; that I resent it as some sort of trap.  I will never be a soccer mom or a Girl Scout Troop leader (mostly because I have no desire to be those things).  I will never not need medication, or hate the fact that I have to live with it.  I will never know if tomorrow I am going to be high or low, although there is no doubt that I will be one or the other, since I can&#8217;t be that normal.</p>
<p>When I was young(er) all I wanted was normal.  And all I got was that stupid question.  But these days I think of normal as this: waking up with the alarm, going about my day with a little anger, a little happiness, some joy; then going home to my child, cooking dinner, taking care of the myriad chores that always pile up.  These are the things I crave.  Instead my day either starts out with me popping out of bed, or hitting the snooze five times; I am either happy to be at work or wish I didn&#8217;t actually have to speak and could pretend to have laryngitis, getting home and either falling so deep in a book to escape my abnormal life, or just heading to bed.</p>
<p>There is no consistency in my life, which is frustrating.  There is no magic in my life, which is disappointing.  There is no freedom in my life, which is simply wrong.  My life and all my actions are dictated to an extent that one can point to the exact cause for any of my effects.  Was it the medicine, was it the lack of space, was it the forced interaction of people?</p>
<p>I spoke in my last post about not wanting to take my meds.  I confess, even when I take them I don&#8217;t want to.  Or when I look at that full bottle I wonder if I should just take them all.  There is a desire to go from one extreme to the other, and that desire is felt together.  Sink or swim, soar or fall, live or die.  That is my normal.</p>
<p>I have this fantasy in my head about what my normal could be.  If I simply stopped taking those cursed drugs, I have an exact picture of what it could be.  It could be my normal; periods of true darkness, followed by those amazing rays of light.  Sadness followed by depression, followed by a strange floating feeling, followed by ecstasy; or vice versa.  It could be seeing a beautiful sunset and being able to pick out the colors, it could be feeling the wind in my hair and knowing it is more than just my imagination.  It could be soaring within the stories I have buried in my heart, and the evil that I know as intimately as I know my child.</p>
<p>It could be so much real, than the reality I am forced to love. It could be my own slice of that traveling carnival.</p>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=678&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thetruthache.com/2013/01/15/traveling-carnival/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/268161042f84e6d15464b59996db35c7?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F2.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">goodgrieffriday</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://atruthache.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/carnavil.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">carnavil</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>FYI: Bach Is Not Affecting My Sex Life</title>
		<link>http://nathanvjohnson.wordpress.com/2013/01/12/fyi-bach-is-not-affecting-my-sex-life/</link>
		<comments>http://nathanvjohnson.wordpress.com/2013/01/12/fyi-bach-is-not-affecting-my-sex-life/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2013 17:56:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>nathanjohnson</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brier Jirka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bright Eyes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daft Punk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Love Songs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Magnetic Fields]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mood Setters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prince]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Slowdive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Suede]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Teenage Fanclub]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Cure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tom Tom Club]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weeknd]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nathanvjohnson.wordpress.com/?p=2370</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;Is Bach affecting your sex life?&#8221; Well, what a question to ask. It was this inquiry that I encountered while perusing the Omaha World-Herald&#8216;s site this week. Intrigued, I had to read more. It turned out that it was a column about sex and music written by Brier Jirka, a sex therapist with the Methodist [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2370&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;Is Bach affecting your sex life?&#8221;</p>
<p>Well, what a question to ask.</p>
<p>It was this inquiry that I encountered while perusing the <em>Omaha World-Herald</em>&#8216;s site this week. Intrigued, I had to read more.</p>
<p>It turned out that it was a column about sex and music written by Brier Jirka, a sex therapist with the Methodist Physicians Clinic Women&#8217;s Center.</p>
<p>She <a href="http://www.omaha.com/article/20130108/LIVEWELL16/130109624/1685#is-bach-affe%20cting-your-sex-life" target="_blank">writes</a>:</p>
<div>
<blockquote><p>You know it as soon as you hear it.</p>
<p>THE song that brings back memories of a special moment between you and your partner. That moment when fireworks exploded and you knew love was in the air.</p>
<p>The fact that music has such a prominent place in our relationships should not be surprising. We all listen to music on a daily basis, and a person&#8217;s taste can vary from classical or rock to country, pop or R&amp;B.</p>
<p>For some, that special song is anything by the band Boston or ever popular REO Speedwagon. For others it could be by Marvin Gaye or one of today&#8217;s superstars – Usher, Carrie Underwood, or dare I say Justin Bieber!</p>
<p>But have you ever thought about how much music actually influences your sexual behavior?</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a common question I hear in sex therapy: What music should I play to set the mood?</p>
<p>“Let&#8217;s Get It On” or “Sexual Healing” usually come to mind right away. However, an article on the subject published in <a href="http://news.softpedia.com/news/How-Does-Music-Influence-Sex-and-Human-Behavior-73779.shtml">Softpedia</a> noted research which showed those that enjoy jazz music have 34 percent more sex than those who like pop music.</p>
<p>The least sexually active group – those who prefer classical, like Bach or Beethoven.</p>
<p>So what gives? Blame brain functions. The left hemisphere is linked to language and the right to our feelings. Music often triggers both at the same time, resulting in stronger outward behavior, AKA movement. Simply put, music encourages touching.</p>
<p>Both men and women rate tactile (touching) stimuli as most important in sexual arousal. However, when it comes to musical stimuli, men are often less responsive than women.</p>
<p>For men, the type of music doesn&#8217;t really matter. But for females, “her song&#8221; will likely result in positive thoughts and feelings.</p>
<p>Next time you want to set the mood for love, consider what your partner&#8217;s ears prefer.</p>
<p>And in case nothing comes to mind, here is a list of songs that may help set the mood, followed by those which will ruin your chances for intimacy.</p>
<p>This list was generated from a combination of online polls and my professional suggestions.</p>
<p><b>Top 5 Mood Setters</b></p>
<p>• I&#8217;ll Make Love to You (Boyz II Men)<br />
• Come A Little Closer (Dierks Bentley)<br />
• Shook Me All Night Long (AC/DC)<br />
• Too Afraid to Love You (The Black Keys)<br />
• Feel Like Making Love (Bad Company)<br />
• I&#8217;ve Got You Under My Skin (Frank Sinatra)</p>
<p><b>Top 5 Mood Spoilers</b></p>
<p>• How You Remind Me (Nickelback)<br />
• Boyfriend (Justin Bieber)<br />
• I Wanna Sex You Up (Color Me Badd)<br />
• I&#8217;ll Do Anything for Love (Meatloaf)<br />
• Anything Disney – seriously it&#8217;s wrong to mix sexual intimacy and Disney music</p></blockquote>
<p>OK, I know Jirka says that men are less responsive than women to music, but I can say that if any lady out there tries to seduce me with the mood setters listed above (aside from The Black Keys) I&#8217;m likely to either burst out laughing or run away in horror. (&#8220;Feel Like Making Love&#8221; actually makes people want to make love? Are you kidding me???)</p>
<p>However, I&#8217;m glad to see people are turned off by Nickelback, Bieber and Meatloaf.</p>
<p>&#8220;I Wanna Sex You Up&#8221; though? I could handle that if we were in the right mood — as in, not a serious mood. It&#8217;s certainly better than AC/DC. Seriously.</p>
<p>Now, you know what comes next. This is where I have to list 10 songs that I think are great mood setters (because I will go 200 percent for those I love — and because I don&#8217;t have the discipline to pick only five). I&#8217;m not going to disappoint you.</p>
<p>Turn down the lights. Spread the rose petals. Don&#8217;t those candles smell great?</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s get started.</p>
<p>&#8220;This wine tastes great. Hey, are you familiar with this song that Robert Smith wrote for his fiance as a wedding present. Whenever I hear it, I can&#8217;t help but think of you.&#8221;</p>
<iframe src="https://embed.spotify.com/?uri=spotify%3Atrack%3A0QbKDAp6iEC9XtQbkjRxMm" style="display:block; margin:0 auto; width:300px; height:380px;" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true"></iframe>
<p>&#8220;Would you like to hear some poetry? &#8216;If you stay, I&#8217;ll chase the rain-blown fields away. We&#8217;ll shine like the morning and sin in the sun. Oh, if you stay, we&#8217;ll be the wild ones running with the dogs today.&#8217;&#8221;</p>
<iframe src="https://embed.spotify.com/?uri=spotify%3Atrack%3A3hLDdmkhisfvi7QNVPv2L4" style="display:block; margin:0 auto; width:300px; height:380px;" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true"></iframe>
<p>&#8220;I really don&#8217;t have the words.&#8221;</p>
<iframe src="https://embed.spotify.com/?uri=spotify%3Atrack%3A6DOJgDuUVDaJ98GQxwyLTh" style="display:block; margin:0 auto; width:300px; height:380px;" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true"></iframe>
<p>&#8220;I&#8217;ve got a genius idea. Let&#8217;s have some fun. Natural fun. (Please don&#8217;t slap me.)&#8221;</p>
<iframe src="https://embed.spotify.com/?uri=spotify%3Atrack%3A6UBQONiLH8kNmmB8UrV2Ef" style="display:block; margin:0 auto; width:300px; height:380px;" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true"></iframe>
<p>I don&#8217;t gotta say a word &#8230;</p>
<iframe src="https://embed.spotify.com/?uri=spotify%3Atrack%3A28S2K2KIvnZ9H6AyhRtenm" style="display:block; margin:0 auto; width:300px; height:380px;" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true"></iframe>
<p>&#8220;&#8216;It may not be the right time. I might not be the right one. But there&#8217;s something about us I want to say.&#8221;</p>
<iframe src="https://embed.spotify.com/?uri=spotify%3Atrack%3A1NeLwFETswx8Fzxl2AFl91" style="display:block; margin:0 auto; width:300px; height:380px;" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true"></iframe>
<p>&#8220;I thought you&#8217;d want to hear about this really incredible book.&#8221;</p>
<iframe src="https://embed.spotify.com/?uri=spotify%3Atrack%3A6UGpcXcENaUqQKPc6oqOe4" style="display:block; margin:0 auto; width:300px; height:380px;" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true"></iframe>
<p>&#8220;Girl, why mess with the rest when you got the best? I&#8217;m what you need.&#8221;</p>
</div>
<div><iframe src="https://embed.spotify.com/?uri=spotify%3Atrack%3A7IpDQcksaT8SxS7vOX4SRm" style="display:block; margin:0 auto; width:300px; height:380px;" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true"></iframe></div>
<div>&#8220;This is one of the most beautiful songs I&#8217;ve ever heard in my life. I can&#8217;t believe I&#8217;m with the most beautiful woman I&#8217;ve ever met in my life right now. What a coincidence.&#8221;</div>
<div><iframe src="https://embed.spotify.com/?uri=spotify%3Atrack%3A55CenVQ4alvDJ1PS8aYB0m" style="display:block; margin:0 auto; width:300px; height:380px;" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true"></iframe></div>
<div>
<p>&#8220;Can we just cuddle already?&#8221;</p>
<iframe src="https://embed.spotify.com/?uri=spotify%3Atrack%3A5OiaAaIMYlCZONyDBxqk4G" style="display:block; margin:0 auto; width:300px; height:380px;" frameborder="0" allowtransparency="true"></iframe>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>So, uh, how was it? Was that Bach or Boys II Men?</p>
<p>(By the way, if you&#8217;re visiting this post via &#8220;Freshly Pressed,&#8221; WELCOME! Thanks for checking out &#8220;An Inland Voyage.&#8221; Please look around and share any thoughts. Find out more about me and &#8220;An Inland Voyage&#8221; <a href="http://nathanvjohnson.wordpress.com/about/" target="_blank">here</a>. &#8212; Nathan)</p>
</div>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2370/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2370/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2370&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://nathanvjohnson.wordpress.com/2013/01/12/fyi-bach-is-not-affecting-my-sex-life/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>15</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/cd055059a6f504a8a1a2ece39ca62065?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">nathanvjohnson</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Omo Tribes: Ethiopia’s Natural Beauties.</title>
		<link>http://franceleclerc.com/2013/01/12/the-omo-tribes-ethiopias-natural-beauties-2/</link>
		<comments>http://franceleclerc.com/2013/01/12/the-omo-tribes-ethiopias-natural-beauties-2/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2013 00:47:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>franceleclerc</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ethiopia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cattle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lip Plates]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Omo Child]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Omo River]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Omo Tribes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Omo Valley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Suri]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Surma]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://franceleclerc.com/?p=1483</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Last fall I had the chance to fulfill my one of my long-held dreams to visit the Omo valley and spend time with its remaining tribes.  The Omo valley is in the Southern part of Ethiopia and the lack of roads and infrastructure in the area makes it very difficult to reach and to explore.  [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1483&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last fall I had the chance to fulfill my one of my long-held dreams to visit the Omo valley and spend time with its remaining tribes.  The Omo valley is in the Southern part of Ethiopia and the lack of roads and infrastructure in the area makes it very difficult to reach and to explore.  Staying at two different camps over two weeks, seven of us were able to meet with four of the sixteen or so different tribal groups found in the region.  We spent time with members of the Surma (also called Suri) tribe, the Kara (Karo) tribe and their archenemies the Nyagathom and finally we had a brief but colorful encounter with the Hamar, one of the largest tribal groups in the area.  Two weeks was obviously not enough time to understand the richness of these vanishing cultures, but I got a few insights and a few photos that I thought were worth sharing.</p>
<p>Having been isolated from the outside world, the Omo tribes have adopted a number of unique rituals and practices.  But before I get to that, one of the most jarring things I faced when I arrived is the fact that, as some of you may know, Omo tribesmen have adopted the practice of demanding money for “each” picture taken (which can obviously be tricky with a digital camera).  This is obviously not a practice appreciated by travel photographers and not one that I had participated in before, at least not explicitly.</p>
<p>When I heard about this initially I envisioned a situation similar to what I have seen in many other less developed countries namely, a few “model-wannabes” asking for money who can easily (well sometimes not so easily) be avoided and then access to the real locals who would not mind me taking pictures of their daily activities.  In fact, this is the way it was in other areas of Ethiopia that I visited.  But for some reasons that are still unclear to me, the Omo people take this money/photo exchange very seriously (even the remote tribes do, including some of the ones we met who see very few travelers.)  There is a set price: 5 birr –about 30 cents- for an adult, 2 birr for a child.   Thank goodness babies are free otherwise I would be broke. There is also an elaborate exchange procedure, including the fact that everyone wants to be paid in birr notes even if birr coins are now available.  So for two weeks, we were walking around feeling rich with large wads of birr.</p>
<p>Everyone is in on the deal and if you take a photo of someone’s back without them noticing you can be sure that he or she will be told that you did so and that a payment will be claimed.  And since most tribesmen walk around with an AK-47 on their shoulders, I decided it would be unwise to object to this policy.</p>
<p>As expected, children were showing their interest in having us taking their pictures, but surprisingly adults were not.  If we wanted to take a picture of someone we had to “ask permission” and then pay.  When we were invited to events such as dances, our guide would pay to compensate for each of us being there. So for the sake of full disclosure, I guess it is fair to say that most of these tribe people were “paid” for allowing me to photograph them.</p>
<p>Has this practice impacted my photography?  I am sure it has.  But I realized that what was the most problematic was not the money per se, as it was very little money for us, and I was more than happy to make some small contribution to their economic welfare.  And strangely, it sometimes felt that the money transaction was just a way for them to get an acknowledgement that we value their pictures.  The worry, of course, is that this commercial exchange might change the behavior of the locals; that they would end up posing or acting as they thought I wanted them to act instead of just being themselves. Upon reflection and looking at my photos, I felt that this may have been the case with body painting where some youngsters were clearly trying to outdo one another.  But overall, I had the impression that for the most part, the Omo tribe people just did not know how to be anything else other than themselves.  Of course, I cannot know for sure, I wish I had been there longer to be able to confirm that impression. And I am not saying that this is a practice that I favor, far from that. But I felt that after I had overcome my discomfort with the process, I was able to capture some real moments.  Well, I hope I did.</p>
<p>Some of the rituals and practices adopted by the various tribes are quite intriguing to the modern world like the cattle-jumping initiation rite in which young men run along the backs of cattle to prove they are ready to marry.  Others are shocking to us such as women asking to be whipped until they bleed as a sign of commitment to a relative.  And there are some practices that challenge all we believe in.  For example, the Kara and Hamar tribes have a tradition of practicing what they called “mingi”.  This requires the tribe members to kill a child who is born out of wedlock or with a birth defect as a way to control the bad luck (mingi) associated with such a birth.   Luckily, mingi and other “harmful traditional practices” are now banned by the Ethiopian government, though as is often the case, such bans are not easy to implement.  Luckily also, a wonderful organization, The Omo Child (www.omochild.org), is trying to rescue and take care of these children before the worst happens.</p>
<p>I thought the best way to illustrate the similarities and differences among the four tribes we visited was to present them one at a time.  I will discuss each one of them one in the order in which I visited them.  In this post, I’ll talk about my experience with the Surma while subsequent posts will cover the remaining tribes (so stay tuned if you are interested).  I hope these comments provide some useful background to help you understand what you are seeing in the images that follow.</p>
<p>If you meet the Surma, few things will stay with you (well they sure stayed with me).  Married Surma women wear lip-plates, at least they are expected to wear them when strangers are around.   These plates are thought of being a symbol of beauty, and according to some, the size of the lip plate may also be a function of the price (in cattle) the husband paid for his bride. The lip plate is considered another of the “harmful ritual practices” the government has banned.  Surma women also stretch their ears using clay plates similar to those used to stretch the lip.  They also often use what looks like giant wood plugs that they paint or decorate (and sometimes anything else that is available such as a small plastic cups.)</p>
<p>As we know from the beautiful work of Hans Silvester among others, the Surma enjoy decorating themselves. They use colors from nature (chalk, charcoal, ochre and red clay) and paint their face or body in quite intricate ways.  They also started using flowers, fruits, leaves and whatever else they think will improve their appearance or catch attention.  Surma people also beautify themselves, in their eyes, by practicing scarification.  To do so, they use a razor blade to cut the skin and an acacia thorn to create bumpy scars to form simple or elaborate designs.</p>
<p>The lives of the Surma tribesmen revolve around cattle.  Cows (and goats) are some of the most prized possessions, and men spent a lot of time with them.  Most young boys will spend extended time away from the village caring for the cattle so that they develop the necessary skills and knowledge to tend them.  The cows are very rarely killed but young cattlemen drink cow’s blood to get stronger. As a couple of the photos show, an arrow is used to pierce a vein, and the blood is drank quickly before it coagulates, either directly from the cow or from a calabash.</p>
<p>Finally, the Surma have their own dance rituals. The one we witnessed involved a large group of people dancing in a large circle.  From time to time, two men or a man and a woman would venture to dance in the middle of the circle. Surprisingly, guns were shot repeatedly during this dance, perhaps because the dance was in honor of someone who had recently died.</p>
<p>Meet the Surma.</p>
<p>France</p>
<p><a href="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia02.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1484" alt="Ethopia02" src="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia02.jpg?w=720"   /></a> <a href="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia03.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1485" alt="Ethopia03" src="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia03.jpg?w=720"   /></a> <a href="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia04.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1486" alt="Ethopia04" src="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia04.jpg?w=720"   /></a> <a href="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia05.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1487" alt="Ethopia05" src="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia05.jpg?w=720"   /></a> <a href="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia06.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1488" alt="Ethopia06" src="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia06.jpg?w=720"   /></a> <a href="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia07.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1489" alt="Ethopia07" src="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia07.jpg?w=720"   /></a> <a href="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia08.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1490" alt="Ethopia08" src="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia08.jpg?w=720"   /></a> <a href="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia09.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1491" alt="Ethopia09" src="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia09.jpg?w=720"   /></a> <a href="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia10.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1492" alt="Ethopia10" src="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia10.jpg?w=720"   /></a> <a href="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia11.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1493" alt="Ethopia11" src="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia11.jpg?w=720"   /></a> <a href="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia12.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1494" alt="Ethopia12" src="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia12.jpg?w=720"   /></a> <a href="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia13.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1495" alt="Ethopia13" src="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia13.jpg?w=720"   /></a> <a href="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia14.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1496" alt="Ethopia14" src="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia14.jpg?w=720"   /></a> <a href="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia15.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1497" alt="Ethopia15" src="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia15.jpg?w=720"   /></a> <a href="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia33.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1514" alt="Ethopia33" src="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia33.jpg?w=720"   /></a><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1498" alt="Ethopia16" src="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia16.jpg?w=720"   /> <a href="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia17.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1499" alt="Ethopia17" src="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia17.jpg?w=720"   /></a> <a href="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia18.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1500" alt="Ethopia18" src="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia18.jpg?w=720"   /></a> <a href="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia19.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1501" alt="Ethopia19" src="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia19.jpg?w=720"   /></a> <a href="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia20.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1502" alt="Ethopia20" src="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia20.jpg?w=720"   /></a> <a href="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia21.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1503" alt="Ethopia21" src="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia21.jpg?w=720"   /></a> <a href="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia22.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1504" alt="Ethopia22" src="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia22.jpg?w=720"   /></a> <a href="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia23.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1505" alt="Ethopia23" src="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia23.jpg?w=720"   /></a> <a href="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia24.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1506" alt="Ethopia24" src="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia24.jpg?w=720"   /></a> <a href="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia25.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1507" alt="Ethopia25" src="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia25.jpg?w=720"   /></a> <a href="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia26.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1508" alt="Ethopia26" src="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia26.jpg?w=720"   /></a> <a href="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia27.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1509" alt="Ethopia27" src="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia27.jpg?w=720"   /></a> <a href="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia28.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1510" alt="Ethopia28" src="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia28.jpg?w=720"   /></a> <a href="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia29.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1511" alt="Ethopia29" src="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia29.jpg?w=720"   /></a> <a href="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia30.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1512" alt="Ethopia30" src="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia30.jpg?w=720"   /></a> <a href="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia31.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1513" alt="Ethopia31" src="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia31.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://franceleclerc.com/category/ethiopia/'>Ethiopia</a>, <a href='http://franceleclerc.com/category/photography/'>Photography</a>, <a href='http://franceleclerc.com/category/travel/'>Travel</a> Tagged: <a href='http://franceleclerc.com/tag/africa/'>Africa</a>, <a href='http://franceleclerc.com/tag/cattle/'>Cattle</a>, <a href='http://franceleclerc.com/tag/ethiopia/'>Ethiopia</a>, <a href='http://franceleclerc.com/tag/lip-plates/'>Lip Plates</a>, <a href='http://franceleclerc.com/tag/omo-child/'>Omo Child</a>, <a href='http://franceleclerc.com/tag/omo-river/'>Omo River</a>, <a href='http://franceleclerc.com/tag/omo-tribes/'>Omo Tribes</a>, <a href='http://franceleclerc.com/tag/omo-valley/'>Omo Valley</a>, <a href='http://franceleclerc.com/tag/photography/'>Photography</a>, <a href='http://franceleclerc.com/tag/suri/'>Suri</a>, <a href='http://franceleclerc.com/tag/surma/'>Surma</a>, <a href='http://franceleclerc.com/tag/travel/'>Travel</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1483/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1483/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1483/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1483/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1483/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1483/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1483/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1483/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1483/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1483/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1483/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1483/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1483/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1483/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1483&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://franceleclerc.com/2013/01/12/the-omo-tribes-ethiopias-natural-beauties-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>36</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/e4a62f26891937163476380ce4cf0cca?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">franceleclerc</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia02.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ethopia02</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia03.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ethopia03</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia04.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ethopia04</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia05.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ethopia05</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia06.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ethopia06</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia07.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ethopia07</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia08.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ethopia08</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia09.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ethopia09</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia10.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ethopia10</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia11.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ethopia11</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia12.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ethopia12</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia13.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ethopia13</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia14.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ethopia14</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia15.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ethopia15</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia33.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ethopia33</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia16.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ethopia16</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia17.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ethopia17</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia18.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ethopia18</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia19.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ethopia19</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia20.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ethopia20</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia21.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ethopia21</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia22.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ethopia22</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia23.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ethopia23</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia24.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ethopia24</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia25.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ethopia25</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia26.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ethopia26</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia27.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ethopia27</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia28.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ethopia28</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia29.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ethopia29</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia30.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ethopia30</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://franceleclerc.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ethopia31.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ethopia31</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Girl Who Took Care Into Her Own Hands</title>
		<link>http://inspiredscribble.com/2013/01/12/the-girl-who-took-care-into-her-own-hands/</link>
		<comments>http://inspiredscribble.com/2013/01/12/the-girl-who-took-care-into-her-own-hands/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2013 04:48:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>kristen25</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Creative Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nonfiction]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://inspiredscribble.com/?p=5036</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I buy books the way I buy groceries. Every two weeks or so, I drop $60 and call it a night. Either way, it&#8217;s food. And it&#8217;s meant to sustain me for periods of time. Time that I spend learning how I live, work and play in a given environment. It&#8217;s a fascinating and never-ending [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=5036&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I buy books the way I buy groceries. Every two weeks or so, I drop $60 and call it a night. Either way, it&#8217;s food. And it&#8217;s meant to sustain me for periods of time. Time that I spend learning how I live, work and play in a given environment. It&#8217;s a fascinating and never-ending pursuit.</p>
<p>Yesterday I bought a book called <em>Archetypes</em> by Caroline Myss, the same author who wrote <em>Anatomy of the Spirit</em>. And I liked that book. Might as well open the cover of this one too. I spent a few minutes reading the preface and introductions, though was hesitant about the content inside. Could this just be a book about labels? I wasn&#8217;t interested. I wasn&#8217;t interested in defining myself by a list of categories that I may or may not fit in to. It was like shrinking my soul into a size 2. And everybody knows we are so much more than skin and bones.</p>
<p>I was, however, interested in the organization of the human character, however this woman had perceived them to be. I was sure that I&#8217;d disagree defiantly, based on my lingering objection to the act of pinning everything down; as if it&#8217;s all figured out, settled then, case closed.</p>
<p>I still had a life to live. I sure wasn&#8217;t going to put myself in a box. A good book, however, that I&#8217;ll do. It always set you free.</p>
<p>Though I have yet to begin reading the first chapter, I did visit archetypeme.com; a website companion to the hardcover I had in my hands. Wouldn&#8217;t you know? You can take a 10-question test to determine your authentic self. So began the war of the worlds. While this tool has potential and may even prove helpful by the time I&#8217;m done reading this book, it has also set off a number of alarms and red flags. I don&#8217;t want a website to tell me who I am. I&#8217;d rather just pay attention to my daily habits, thoughts and routines to determine my psychological and behavioral thought patterns. That&#8217;s why I write and pray and exercise. What frightens me is that there are plenty of people who aren&#8217;t willing to put in the heart and soul into their own lives. They&#8217;d rather let a simple test decide their persona and perhaps even the path forward. It&#8217;s the Google effect: are we smarter because we have access to more knowledge? Or are we lazier because we don&#8217;t know how to sift through it?</p>
<p>Our personal decision-marking process is at risk. Do we want fact or fiction or convenience? Truth, however, is not like the cream that rises. It&#8217;s dirty work that requires lots of digging. Infinite searching. It&#8217;s how the best stories are made.</p>
<p>But I thought, what the heck? Let me find out what this little test says about me. I was curious to see if there were any surprises. Turns out, I&#8217;m 26% Athlete, 26% Spiritual, 28% Caregiver and 20% Other (mix of several other archetypes). What got me to raise an eyebrow was the Caregiver part. It&#8217;s not necessarily how I see myself. I&#8217;m not responsible for anybody at this particular moment: no husband, no children. Just me. Plus, I&#8217;m the baby of my immediate family so I&#8217;ve always been the one taken care of <img src='http://s1.wp.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif' alt=';)' class='wp-smiley' /> </p>
<p>This begs the question: to whom am I giving my care too?</p>
<p>If there&#8217;s anything this test proves, it&#8217;s the blindness we can have to ourselves. Sure, I&#8217;ve been a spiritual athlete for as long as I can remember. But a caregiver? Not an adjective I&#8217;ve used to describe myself. I&#8217;m not saying that the test is wrong, though I&#8217;ve already stated my distrust for it. But I am curious to explore this part of myself and give it a definition worthy in its own right. I&#8217;ll have to do some digging, but it just might help in some of the decisions I make.</p>
<p><a href="http://inspiredscribble.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/chart-771431228.png"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5096 aligncenter" alt="My Archetypes" src="http://inspiredscribble.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/chart-771431228.png?w=300&#038;h=250" width="300" height="250" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5036/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5036/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=5036&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://inspiredscribble.com/2013/01/12/the-girl-who-took-care-into-her-own-hands/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>21</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://inspiredscribble.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/chart-771431228.png?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://inspiredscribble.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/chart-771431228.png?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">My Archetypes</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/72c681cbbcbafeb7cfeb1fa50cd510fc?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F1.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">kristen25</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://inspiredscribble.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/chart-771431228.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">My Archetypes</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Kelly</title>
		<link>http://maesday.wordpress.com/2013/01/12/kelly/</link>
		<comments>http://maesday.wordpress.com/2013/01/12/kelly/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2013 05:31:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>maesprose</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cancer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Grief]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mastectomy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Memories]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://maesday.wordpress.com/?p=725</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I lost a friend this week. My friend lost her life. I knew from the beginning our friendship would end this way.  Yet, I didn’t know how wonderful our friendship would be or how much I would grow from it.  I always knew how much I would miss her. Kelly was my yoga teacher.  I [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=725&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://maesday.wordpress.com/2013/01/12/kelly/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>65</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/3f6c6b1b817c7b4db7654dc530653ea2?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">maesprose</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://maesday.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/violin.jpeg?w=252" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Violin</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Learning from Competition</title>
		<link>http://blog.learningbyshipping.com/2013/01/14/learning-from-competition/</link>
		<comments>http://blog.learningbyshipping.com/2013/01/14/learning-from-competition/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2013 22:30:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Steven Sinofsky</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[competition]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://learningbyshipping.wordpress.com/?p=201</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Gotcha. Traitor. Snicker. Those were some of the reactions when people discovered that I was using an iPhone. I stand before you accused of using a competitor’s [sic] product and I plead guilty. Moving beyond the gotcha blogs, there’s an actual reason for using technology products and services other than the ones you make (or [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=201&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><i>Gotcha. Traitor. Snicker.</i> Those were some of the reactions when people <i>discovered</i> that I was using an iPhone. I stand before you accused of using a competitor’s [sic] product and I plead guilty.</p>
<p>Moving beyond the gotcha blogs, there’s an actual reason for using technology products and services other than the ones you make (or happen to be made by the company where you work/ed). I think everyone knows that, even a thousand tweets later.  The approach in many industries to downplay or even become hostile to the competition are well-documented and studied, and generally conclude that experiencing the competition is a good thing.</p>
<p>Learning from the competition is not just required of all product development folks, but can also be somewhat of a skill worth honing. Let’s look at the ins and outs of using a competitive product.</p>
<h2>Why?</h2>
<p>Obviously you should use a competitive product. You should know what you’re up against when a consumer (or business) ultimately faces a buying decision. They will weigh a wide array of factors and you should be aware of those not only for the purposes of sales and marketing but when you are designing your products.</p>
<p>It is easy to fall into the trap of checklists or cloning competitive products and so that might be why you follow the competition. That’s a weak way to compete. Part of planning your product/service is establishing your unique value proposition—is it features, pricing, implementation or execution for example?</p>
<p>Simply being the same as your competitor that might be more established is not good enough and so knowing the competition for the sake of skimming their value proposition won’t work. Generally speaking, just adding the cool thing from a competitor at the last minute to your product’s plan is not going to work well for customers and will be readily transparent. That’s checklist product development.</p>
<p>Product development is a complex endeavor. There is no magic. Worse than that, most people making products in a “category” are pulling insights, ideas, and technologies from the same sources. What separates wildly successful products from distant number two products can often be just a few of thousands of choices.</p>
<p>Studying your competitor, well, gives you a chance to evaluate your choices in an entirely different context. When you make a product choice you are making it in the context of your company, strategy, business model, and people/talents. What if you change some of those? That is what knowing the competition allows you to do, and basically for free (no consultants or top secret research).</p>
<p>What does it mean to study the competition well? What are some common mistakes made when studying the competition?</p>
<h2>Common Mistakes</h2>
<p>Even when you study the competition, there are some techniques that are often employed, and with the best of intentions. There are ways of executing on a competitive analysis that leave some information on the table.</p>
<p>Worse, it is possible to execute on a competitive analysis from a dismissive or <i>get this over with</i> posture that takes away what is perhaps the most valuable source of information in forward looking product design.</p>
<p>While there are many potential challenges, here are a couple of examples of patterns I’ve seen.</p>
<ul>
<li><b>Using the product in a lightweight manner.</b> All too often analyzing the competition itself becomes a checklist work item. Go to the store and play with it for a few minutes. Maybe ask a friend or neighbor what they think. The usage of a competitive product needs to be in depth and over time. You need to use the product like it is your primary product and not switch or fall back to your old way of working. Often this is weeks or more of usage. Even as a reviewer this applies. Walt Mossberg famously took an iPad on a <a href="http://allthingsd.com/20100922/an-american-in-paris-says-au-revoir-to-his-laptop/">10 day trip to France</a>—no laptop at all. That’s how to use a product.</li>
<li><b>Thinking like yourself, not the competition.</b> When using a competitive product you need to use it like it was intended to be used by the designers. Don’t get the product and use the customization tools to morph it into the familiar. Even if a product has a mode to make it work like the familiar (as a competitive bridge they offer) don’t use it. Use native file formats. Use defaults in the UI and functionality. Follow the designed workflow. They key is to let loose of your muscle memory and develop new memory.</li>
<li><b>Betting competitors act similarly (or even rationally).</b> If you think like a competitor you have to make future decisions like they might. Of course you can’t really do that or really know and this is where product intuition comes to mind (and also why blogs predicting product directions are often off the mark). You have to really wrap yourself around the culture, constraints, resources, and more of a competitor. The reality is that your competitor is not going “fix” their product to turn it into your product. So then the question is what would a competitors do in their context, not what would you do if you were designing the follow-on product in your context. This might actually feel irrational to you. One of the most classic examples of this is whether or not the Mac OS should have been licensed to other PC makers or not. Arguments could be made either way, both then and now. But what is right or assumed in one context simply doesn’t make sense in another. That context can also include a time dimension where the answer actually changes.</li>
<li><b>Assume the world is static.</b> Even after you’ve reviewed a competitor through usage you might feel confident because they are missing some features or might have done some things poorly. That’s a static view of the world. Keep in mind analyzing the competition is a two-way street. If you noticed a weakness there’s a really good chance the competitor knew about it. When everyone pointed out that a phone was missing copy/paste, don’t make a mistake thinking that was news to the development team and would remain a competitive advantage.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Approaches</h2>
<p>There’s a reason Patton often made reference to Thucydides treatise on the <i>History of the Peloponnesian War</i>. It is a thorough and thoughtful analysis that goes beyond who won which battles but gets inside the minds of the men, the culture, and the thought processes. Competing in business is not war and should not be treated as such, either literally or as a metaphor (the stakes are relatively insignificant and business is an <i>endless</i> series of skirmishes and battles rather than aiming for an ‘end’, at the very least). However, the idea of being thoughtful and understanding tactics, decision making, resource allocation, and more are important.</p>
<p>There are a few techniques that are often used in conjunction with using the product. The most important thing is of course to use the product and to adopt it as your primary tool for all the uses it was intended in the manner in which it was intended. With that raw data, there are number of potential tools for sharing that learning:</p>
<ul>
<li><b>Feature comparisons.</b> The most obvious tool is to make a long list of features and compare products. This works well for some folks and especially when handed to customers. It is also the least useful in product design. A feature checklist is only as good as the features you put on it. We all know how easy it is to make a product look feature rich or feature poor simply by picking the right set of features to check off. You can even pick weird measures for whether a feature is in or not—you could have a “WiFi” check item or you could make it “WiFi a/b/g/n” and change who won or lost. You can also lead to a false conclusion if you try to score or just count features—it is doubling the error rate of your check list because you’re doubly-assuming your context.</li>
<li><b><i>SWOT.</i></b> A common “single slide” approach to competitors is to distill down competition into something like <i>strengths, weaknesses, opportunities, threats</i>. These are very hard to do well, again because of the context, but by including all of these you force yourself to confront your own product shortcoming and missteps. Personally, I don’t like the use of “threats” because it starts to conjure up war and sports metaphors but you can think of them as risks that customers won’t choose your product/service. SWOT is often used by the marketing team because you can intermix near term tactics in the marketplace (opportunities).</li>
<li><b>Scenario comparisons.</b> A nice way to take a more end-to-end approach to competitive analysis is to consider more complete scenarios. If you’re testing for battery life then don’t just play a movie, but play a movie with the radios on and an active mailbox, as an example. As with everything, it is important to pick scenarios that are truly representative of what a product was designed to do and how it was designed to do it, not how your product/service does. Measuring a scenario comparison could involve clicks/gestures, clock time, resource consumption, and more.</li>
<li><b>Competitive review or blog.</b> My favorite test of really getting in the mind of the competitor is to challenge yourself to review your own product as though you were the competitor. Alternatively, you could write a press release or blog for a competitive product—the product that competes with you. I remember once writing a whole “press kit” for what became Visual C++ as though I were the Borland C++ team. It was great fun. Rather than focus on Windows (3.0!) development, I focused on compiler speed, code size, array of command line options, and more. Those were the things that Borland would focus on. I then ripped into Visual C++ as a Borland person, highlighting what options were missing, the slowness of the tools, and so on. Even though VC++ 1.0 had a Windows dev environment, resource editor, class library and more—all assets relative to Borland.</li>
</ul>
<p>Of course not matter what your approach, be sure to write down your work and analysis (writing is thinking!) and share it with the team (learning by sharing).</p>
<h2>Be Obsessed</h2>
<p>Those are a few common pitfalls and approaches to competitive analysis.  There are many more.  Feel free to share your favorite approaches in the comments.</p>
<p>Finally, studying the competition is the job of everyone on a team. Importantly, the people doing the work need to study the competition. It is not a job for a staff function or those outside product development. Management studies the competition not just receives reports on the competition. Experts in domains that are parts of a product should drill into the details of the competition (hardware, software, subsystems, peripherals, APIs, etc.)</p>
<p>Be obsessed with the competition. Always. This has never been truer than the fast paced and dynamic world of products where the flow of information is instant and the scale and complexity are greater than ever before.</p>
<p>&#8211;Steven</p>
<p>PS: My plan was not to publish so frequently/rapidly, but even in my old MS blog if something came up that was so timely relative to the ongoing dialog, I&#8217;d do a quick post.  I&#8217;m still going to pace myself :-)</p>
<p align="center">###</p>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=201&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://blog.learningbyshipping.com/2013/01/14/learning-from-competition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>36</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/968256575c4ec55a6f6bb09d411e38f6?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sinofsky</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
