<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2012 23:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>There He Goes &#8230;</title>
		<link>http://keithparker.net/2012/11/12/there-he-goes/</link>
		<comments>http://keithparker.net/2012/11/12/there-he-goes/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2012 22:23:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Keith Parker</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Creative Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fantasy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science Fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fantasy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[time travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://keithparker.net/2012/11/12/there-he-goes/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[“Any real body must have extension in four directions: it must have Length, Breadth, Thickness, and – Duration.” ~ H.G. Wells, The Time Machine, 1895 The grandfather paradox is such a morbid thought question. And even as a scientist I’ll be the first to admit scientists and science fiction writers can conjure some pretty dark [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=634&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em><strong>“Any real body must have extension in four directions: it must have Length, Breadth, Thickness, and – Duration.” ~ H.G. Wells, The Time Machine, 1895</strong></em></p>
<p>The grandfather paradox is such a morbid thought question.  And even as a scientist I’ll be the first to admit scientists and science fiction writers can conjure some pretty dark humor from time to time (see: Cat, Schrödinger&#8217;s).  But have you ever really <i>thought</i> about the <em>meaning</em> of the grandfather paradox?  It means you go back in time and <i>murder your own</i> grandfather before he has a chance to bring your parent into the world.  Is that messed up, or what?</p>
<p>The paradox itself is pretty simple: If you dispose of one of your forefathers before you’ve been conceived, then how can you even <i>exist</i> in order to go back in time and commit the crime in the first place? After all, one of your parents was never born, so how could <em>you</em> have been?  The paradox has other names, of course, and there are various ways “around” the problem that have been explored to death, as it were, but think about the human part of this for a second. I think that that’s something lost in a lot of science fiction literature.</p>
<p>My own grandfather wasn’t killed, thankfully.  He passed away in 1975 while working on a storm door on the back porch.  He was sitting there on the decking, cross-legged, screwdriver in hand, trying to fasten a hinge. He simply fell over sideways and … died.   There are worse ways to go.</p>
<p><a href="http://keithparkerdotnet.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/there-he-goes.jpg"><img id="i-633" class=" wp-image" style="width:101px;" alt="Image" src="http://keithparkerdotnet.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/there-he-goes.jpg?w=155&#038;h=123" height="123" width="155" /></a></p>
<p>Granddaddy was a good-humored man.  Thin, balding, long-faced and mellow, he was the epitome of the easy-going Southern working man, a true shade-tree mechanic who actually <i>did </i>work on cars under the shade of &#8230; a tree &#8230; an oak, to be exact.  But as that shade started to get long, and the wet Alabama heat started to fritter away, he’d retire to his front porch, a sweaty glass of sweetened iced tea in hand.  As a youngster, I’d sit next to him, watching cars and pedestrians pass on the street out front.</p>
<p>One time a man sporting blue jeans and a white T-shirt moseyed by on the sidewalk.</p>
<p>My grandfather nodded, said, “There he goes.”</p>
<p>I tilted my head. “Who?”</p>
<p>Granddaddy pointed.  “Him.”</p>
<p>“You know him?” I said.</p>
<p>He never answered.  He just cracked a wry smile and sipped his tea.  Later in life I learned the expression “there he goes” is slang from my grandparents’ generation, a form of martini dry humor from folks born around 1900.</p>
<p>Now, fast forward to 2012. Suppose I rewired the DeLorean or phone booth in my backyard.  If I turn its knobs and dials so it’s ready for a flight to 1969, Earth, North America, United States, Alabama (I’m sure there&#8217;s an app for that) I just might find myself strolling along that same roadway, prompting my own grandfather to nod at the older me, so he could then tell the younger me, “There he goes.” And he’d be right.</p>
<p>My point here is to offer advice: <em>All</em> of the time travel paradoxes are well-known, and if you try to explain those logical twists and contortions in your fiction, you&#8217;re going to bore your reader.  If you want to write time travel fiction (and I urge you to do so) you need to embrace the element that binds <em>all</em> good fiction: character. Without it, why would we write in the first place?</p>
<p>I’ve got my blue jeans on.  Now, where’d I put that white T-shirt?</p>
<p>Copyright © 2012 Alan Keith Parker.  The content of this blog is copyrighted across all time and space.</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://keithparker.net/category/creative-writing/'>Creative Writing</a>, <a href='http://keithparker.net/category/fantasy/'>Fantasy</a>, <a href='http://keithparker.net/category/creative-writing/fiction/'>Fiction</a>, <a href='http://keithparker.net/category/science-fiction/'>Science Fiction</a> Tagged: <a href='http://keithparker.net/tag/fantasy-2/'>fantasy</a>, <a href='http://keithparker.net/tag/fiction/'>Fiction</a>, <a href='http://keithparker.net/tag/science-fiction-2/'>science fiction</a>, <a href='http://keithparker.net/tag/time-travel/'>time travel</a>, <a href='http://keithparker.net/tag/writing/'>writing</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/634/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/634/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=634&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://keithparker.net/2012/11/12/there-he-goes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a4cb16752b4ba1fae4a2d497cd767392?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">keith0363</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://keithparkerdotnet.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/there-he-goes.jpg?w=390" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Shed Light</title>
		<link>http://hiranadhia.com/2012/11/13/shed-light/</link>
		<comments>http://hiranadhia.com/2012/11/13/shed-light/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2012 20:58:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>hiran1</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General Stuff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diwali]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[light]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[illumination]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meaning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aesop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moral]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://hiranadhia.com/?p=187</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This is not going to be a typical Diwali post. It may not be a Diwali post at all. I have been quite measured in my approach today in looking regularly at all of my social media accounts as well as my phone for the best message or most inspiring text. It seems to be [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=187&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter" alt="" src="http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3075/3144029753_137c5765ae_z.jpg" /></p>
<p>This is not going to be a typical Diwali post. It may not be a Diwali post at all. I have been quite measured in my approach today in looking regularly at all of my social media accounts as well as my phone for the best message or most inspiring text. It seems to be some sort of unofficial competition. Who can get the most interesting, yet relevant image, matched with a caption from a distant great thinker that is unique yet recognizable? It is even more prevalent on Twitter with people showing pictures of them buying and eating mithai (Indian heart-blockers/stoppers) while they go out and enjoy themselves. I do not begrudge any of them, but I can’t help feel like the most important piece of the puzzle is missing. The moral.</p>
<p>Aesop’s fables without the familiar lessons at the end are strange and sometimes ludicrous situations, normally involving some sort of animal. They are meaningless without a moral though. Why am I talking about Aesop? Well relate this to Diwali, or any other festival in any religion – if we just hear the stories and perform the rituals, but do not see to understanding the meanings behind them, then they are just bedtime stories. We must think about what these things represent. Don’t worry, I am not about to give you a lecture on the symbols in Hinduism and what they represent (if you really want to know then we can have a separate discussion). But asking a question for the sake of it is folly…actively striving to find the answer is what is required.</p>
<p>I am sick of people saying that religions and especially Hinduism is superstitious and ritualistic. What they fail to see is that these rituals have a meaning and an understanding behind them, but if we choose to be ignorant then who are we to criticize? It is not easy to discover these meanings, but that does not mean that it is not worthwhile. Our parents and grandparents may not have asked these questions, but unless we take this opportunity to find out, how can we expect our children to adopt our culture and our values when we never bothered to find out ourselves? Think about it.</p>
<p>It will not be easy and we will make mistakes. We will get the wrong end of the stick and we will not look deep enough. But every year, we hope to learn something new, to make a new discovery, to come one step closer to understanding. And that is what we hope to celebrate! Because that is what Diwali is about: illumination. So it is great to buy fireworks, to visit family that we don’t visit enough and to smell the homemade sweets as they drift through the house, but that isn’t enough. Today, tomorrow, this year make a resolution – that you will try to find out one more thing that you didn’t understand, one more thing that you can shed light on. Because this is the <i>festival</i> of light. So make the most of it.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/187/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/187/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=187&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://hiranadhia.com/2012/11/13/shed-light/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/8f745f1083137b035c78e3d1af6d3a83?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">hiran1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3075/3144029753_137c5765ae_z.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dating In the Dark</title>
		<link>http://ruthrutherford.wordpress.com/2012/11/13/dating-in-the-dark/</link>
		<comments>http://ruthrutherford.wordpress.com/2012/11/13/dating-in-the-dark/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2012 04:35:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ruth Rutherford</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Dating Fun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dating Standards]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chemistry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dark]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dating advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dating tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electricity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[first date]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Garden State]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gasoline]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grandparents]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hurricane Sandy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New Jersey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parents]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[power outage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shared interests]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[simplicity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sparks]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ruthrutherford.wordpress.com/?p=2603</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Just got back from visiting my ol&#8217; stomping grounds in New Jersey where I spent the weekend with my parents and grandparents, just talking, eating and enjoying good company. And all this was done in the dark. Yep, that&#8217;s right. Even nearly two weeks after Hurricane Sandy unleashed her fury, the Garden State is still [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2603&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Just got back from visiting my ol&#8217; stomping grounds in New Jersey where I spent the weekend with my parents and grandparents, just talking, eating and enjoying good company. And all this was done in the dark. Yep, that&#8217;s right. Even nearly two weeks after Hurricane Sandy unleashed her fury, the Garden State is still struggling to recover. <strong>And let me tell you: Living without power for that long will quickly make you appreciate the little things.</strong></p>
<p>Like walking into a dark room and then transforming it with just the flip of a switch. Or turning on a faucet and seeing water actually pour out. Or pulling into a gas station on any day you choose, not just the days you&#8217;re allowed to based on the numbers on your license plate. <strong>Or just using the bathroom without strategically planning your &#8220;number twos&#8221; based on how much water is in the tank. </strong>Or not having to wake up at two o&#8217;clock in the morning to wander outside in your pajamas to fill the generator with gas. (Okay, fine. My dad did that part. But still&#8230;)</p>
<p>When you&#8217;re without electricity for a while, your mind tends to do a lot of thinking. There are no reality shows to turn your brain into mush, no hair dryers to block out the noise of everyday life, and no steaming hot baths to drown your worries in. Basically, it&#8217;s you, alone, with a candle, a flashlight and your thoughts. So I spent the time brain blogging.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><em><strong>Brain blogging [noun]</strong><strong> \ˈbrān bläg-ing</strong><strong>\ The act of composing web logs in one&#8217;s memory, usually practiced during periods of intermittent Internet access</strong></em></p>
<p>The topic of said brain blog? Well, duh: <em>dating</em>. But it took me a while to get there. I started thinking about the little things that I appreciated so much only when I lost them due to the power outage &#8212; the electricity, the running water, the reliable gas station service. I thought about all the other things that used to cloud my view &#8212; television, tech gadgets, iPhone apps. The hustle and bustle of 2012 can really muddy the waters of life, making it easy to forget how good we have it.</p>
<p><a href="http://ruthrutherford.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/photo-1.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-2610" title="Lamp" alt="" src="http://ruthrutherford.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/photo-1.jpg?w=300&#038;h=300" height="300" width="300" /></a>And sitting there with my grandparents put things into perspective really quick.<strong> One night, under the glow of one generator-juiced light bulb in the kitchen, we chatted about the &#8220;olden days.&#8221;</strong> The days when my Slavic baba and dido (grandma and grandpa) lived in China and shared one outhouse (a hole in the ground) between ten families. When they heated their small house with a wood burning stove, only to wake up every day to burnt embers and a bitter cold house. When they trekked to the town well or the river to get buckets of water for cooking and washing. <em>When there was no such thing as a power outage.</em></p>
<p><strong>I think we&#8217;ve made dating way too complicated, particularly in the Christian dating scene.</strong> We&#8217;ve taken a simple thing and added unnecessary rules, pressures and expectations &#8212; making it something impossible to satisfy. And I think what we need is a massive power outage to bring us back to the basics.</p>
<p>I know too many people that enter dating with a mindset altogether too serious. They expect to gauge so much during the first date, ultimately hoping to know if the person sitting across from them is indeed their future spouse. They expect to hear from God, through a burning bush or a burning restaurant menu, that this person is or is not &#8220;the one.&#8221; And all this in a couple hours over an oriental chicken salad and a glass of white wine? Let&#8217;s get real!</p>
<p>Why does dating have to be so serious? When did it lose the fun factor?</p>
<p><strong>Here&#8217;s a thought: What if we knocked out the power for a while and started to simplify the process of dating?</strong> (Note: I&#8217;m not suggesting dating in the dark, people. That was a terrible and short-lived reality show premise that really lowered the standards of humanity.) What I&#8217;m suggesting is filtering past all the things we&#8217;ve built up in our minds as to what dating actually is, and landing on something a bit easier.</p>
<p><strong>Dating is <em>not</em> a magic litmus test to find a husband or wife.</strong></p>
<p>Dating is <em>not</em> a feeler to gauge how many children your date wants in the future.</p>
<p>Dating is<em> not</em> a way to tell if he or she will make a good father or mother.</p>
<p>Dating is <em>not</em> a way to find out if someone is good in bed.</p>
<p>Dating is <em>not</em> a seminary course exam to test the theological prowess of your date.</p>
<p>Dating is <em>not</em> when you&#8217;ll find out if your date will be the spiritual leader of the family.</p>
<p>Phew! No wonder dating has become so complicated. We&#8217;re setting the expectation level right below &#8220;completely unrealistic&#8221; and right above &#8220;yeah right.&#8221; <strong>It&#8217;s a typical problem that I notice with Christian dating &#8212; going too deep too soon, and viewing &#8220;dating&#8221; the same as &#8220;relationships.&#8221; </strong>Because there is a huge difference between those two things, and not realizing that can unfortunately stop both of them from ever working for you.</p>
<p><a href="http://ruthrutherford.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/shallow-end.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-2611" title="shallow-end" alt="" src="http://ruthrutherford.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/shallow-end.jpg?w=273&#038;h=300" height="300" width="273" /></a>So if all the topics listed above are off limits for at least the first date, if not the first five, then what&#8217;s left to explore?</p>
<p><em>The really shallow stuff.</em></p>
<p>Yep, I&#8217;m telling you to be shallow.</p>
<p><strong>Forget the deep end, folks. Jump, cannonball style, into the shallow end and let the fun begin!</strong></p>
<p>Shared interests. Favorite movies. Local hot spots. Interesting hobbies. Recent vacations. Current music playlists. Boring work stories. Embarrassing childhood memories. Stupid jokes. Mutual attraction. Sparks. <em>Chemistry.</em></p>
<p><strong>Because if you can&#8217;t relate on these basic levels, then who the heck cares if you both want two boys, one girl and a yellow Labrador named Minnie?</strong></p>
<p>Start small. Start simple. Grab a lantern and meet during a power outage. It&#8217;s amazing what you&#8217;ll find out about your date in the dark. (With your clothes <em>on</em>, people! Get your minds out of the gutter.)</p>
<p>~Ruth</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2603/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2603/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2603&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://ruthrutherford.wordpress.com/2012/11/13/dating-in-the-dark/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>28</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/1ad89b0b5348f47ff887ddc6f5cd77e5?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ruthrutherford</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ruthrutherford.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/photo-1.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Lamp</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ruthrutherford.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/shallow-end.jpg?w=273" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">shallow-end</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Journal Notes, November, Oxford</title>
		<link>http://piratesandfireflies.wordpress.com/2012/11/04/oxford/</link>
		<comments>http://piratesandfireflies.wordpress.com/2012/11/04/oxford/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2012 00:34:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Alexandra Lister</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Journal]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://piratesandfireflies.wordpress.com/?p=4310</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The leafiness. When you wonder why you live in Oxford as opposed to (well, only London, really, at the moment), this is what you come up with. The parks. The walled gardens. The canal. The gardens along the canal. Port Meadow. All the leafy enclaves of North Oxford. The school playing fields stretching down to [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4310&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://piratesandfireflies.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/dsc01163.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-4311" title="" alt="" src="http://piratesandfireflies.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/dsc01163.jpg?w=768&#038;h=1024" height="1024" width="768" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">The leafiness. When you wonder why you live in Oxford as opposed to (well, only London, really, at the moment), this is what you come up with. The parks. The walled gardens. The canal. The gardens along the canal. Port Meadow. All the leafy enclaves of North Oxford. The school playing fields stretching down to the river. And the proximity of the countryside, of a pub lunch in Cuddesdon, a long afternoon walk under browning leaves on Watlington Hill.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">Morning and evening are getting frostier every day, the peaty smell of burning firewood, the orange glow of streetlamps, table lamps through windows after dark. On Sunday, we walk the perimeter of Port Meadow, at Wolvercote turning back to cross over into the nature reserve and then drink Bloody Marys by the fire at the Old Parsonage. I love that about this time of year &#8211; the rosy glow you have after being outside, peeling off your layers as you come into the warmth.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">The onslaught of winter, the narrowing of daylight to a few misty hours, the persistent drizzle, has been made bearable this year by my brief sojourn to Paris and coming back, keeping warm in my new Parisian wardrobe, glad that I acted on the spontaneous desire to stockpile knitwear. For the past week I have lived in a navy wool Guernsey and boucle jacket from Isabel Marant and glossy black suede brogues &#8211; which will need to go to the cobblers soon unless I take them off. I cycle home against an uncomfortably chill evening wind, the prickle of rain on my face, over fat, bright leaves on the pavement. I wear suede ankle boots the colour of claret and lipstick called Mexican Rose and a cashmere coat in camel and feel that I am indistinguishable from the colour palette of autumn. The sky is daubed with wisps of gold and a thundery, bruised grey. Paris had almost been bleached colourless with cold, as though it had been dusted with talcum powder. The streets and the sky were white. But Oxford is green, brown, grey.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"> There are lights up on the High Street, the odd wreath appearing here and there. Pubs are serving mulled wine already – the florists, mistletoe and berries. We discuss where to spend New Year’s Eve. Seven weeks until Christmas, I realize with a shock, looking at my diary. In the run-up to the New Year there are dinner parties and Christmas parties, carols and school plays, shopping in London, a weekend in Cornwall, a few days deep in the Sussex Downs doing not very much at all. By contrast, the pages of January look blank, save a Northumberland wedding. On a whim I book flights to Italy for early in the New Year and start researching train services in Tuscany. At least then there&#8217;s something to look forward to when the festivities of Christmas have passed and there is only the long, dark stretch ahead until spring. I am pleased with my impulsiveness. The afternoon passes in a daydream of Prosciutto di Parma and snow on cypress trees.</p>
<p><a href="http://piratesandfireflies.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/dsc01154.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-4312" title="" alt="" src="http://piratesandfireflies.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/dsc01154.jpg?w=768&#038;h=1024" height="1024" width="768" /></a><a href="http://piratesandfireflies.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/dsc01174.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-4313" title="" alt="" src="http://piratesandfireflies.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/dsc01174.jpg?w=768&#038;h=1024" height="1024" width="768" /></a><a href="http://piratesandfireflies.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/dsc01167.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-4314" title="" alt="" src="http://piratesandfireflies.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/dsc01167.jpg?w=768&#038;h=1024" height="1024" width="768" /></a><a href="http://piratesandfireflies.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/dsc01178.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-4315" title="" alt="" src="http://piratesandfireflies.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/dsc01178.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=788" height="788" width="1024" /></a><a href="http://piratesandfireflies.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/dsc00317.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-4316" title="" alt="" src="http://piratesandfireflies.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/dsc00317.jpg?w=768&#038;h=1024" height="1024" width="768" /></a><a href="http://piratesandfireflies.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/dsc01309.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-4317" title="" alt="" src="http://piratesandfireflies.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/dsc01309.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=768" height="768" width="1024" /></a><a href="http://piratesandfireflies.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/dsc00493.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-4318" title="" alt="" src="http://piratesandfireflies.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/dsc00493.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=768" height="768" width="1024" /></a><a href="http://piratesandfireflies.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/dsc01181.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-4319" title="" alt="" src="http://piratesandfireflies.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/dsc01181.jpg?w=768&#038;h=1024" height="1024" width="768" /></a><a href="http://piratesandfireflies.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/dsc00459.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-4320" title="" alt="" src="http://piratesandfireflies.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/dsc00459.jpg?w=768&#038;h=1024" height="1024" width="768" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4310/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4310/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4310&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://piratesandfireflies.wordpress.com/2012/11/04/oxford/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/6caf23f38c000313e5ad4d4e404f1197?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">coral84</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://piratesandfireflies.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/dsc01163.jpg?w=768" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://piratesandfireflies.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/dsc01154.jpg?w=768" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://piratesandfireflies.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/dsc01174.jpg?w=768" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://piratesandfireflies.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/dsc01167.jpg?w=768" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://piratesandfireflies.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/dsc01178.jpg?w=1024" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://piratesandfireflies.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/dsc00317.jpg?w=768" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://piratesandfireflies.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/dsc01309.jpg?w=1024" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://piratesandfireflies.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/dsc00493.jpg?w=1024" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://piratesandfireflies.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/dsc01181.jpg?w=768" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://piratesandfireflies.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/dsc00459.jpg?w=768" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Burma Is the New Focus of International Relations</title>
		<link>http://alittleviewoftheworld.wordpress.com/2012/11/13/why-burma-is-the-new-focus-of-international-relations/</link>
		<comments>http://alittleviewoftheworld.wordpress.com/2012/11/13/why-burma-is-the-new-focus-of-international-relations/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2012 19:52:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>alittleviewoftheworld</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Asian Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Business & Economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Society & People]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Burma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[International Relations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reform]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[South East Asia]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://alittleviewoftheworld.wordpress.com/?p=891</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In the last week, in which Obama was re-elected to the Presidency, the American leader announced his intention to travel to Burma on an official visit, the first of its kind made by a serving US President. This landmark visit has been hailed as a sign of Burma&#8217;s new found importance in international relations  Add to [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=891&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the last week, in which Obama was re-elected to the Presidency, the American leader announced his intention to travel to Burma on an official visit, the first of its kind made by a serving US President. This landmark visit has been hailed as a sign of Burma&#8217;s new found importance in international relations  Add to this historic visits made by Hilary Clinton, US State Secretary, in November 2011 and David Cameron, British Prime Minister, in April 2012, and it is clear that the international status of Burma is ever-growing.</p>
<p>But why has Burma gone from being a byword for repression and poverty in Asia to the country every global power wants a piece of?</p>
<p>This resurgent interest in Burma has largely been the result of mass reforms that where instigated during March 2011 when the military junta, which had been in control of the country for many decades, were replaced by a quasi-civilian government that instituted changes within all levels of Burmese politics and life.</p>
<p>President Thein Sein was chosen as the leader of the new and reformed Burma and instituted many changes, that included the release of Aung San Suu Kyi, the leader of the opposition, who had been under house arrest for many years. This dramatic political change, that later allowed Suu Kyi to take a place in Parliament, has been the impetus for this renewed interest in Burma and it has largely been Suu Kyi, herself, who stimulated this interest, through traveling the world promoting Burmese issues. For Western politicians these reforms symbolised a new era in Burmese politics and economics, where Western nations can take advantage of a previously closed and hidden nation.</p>
<p>The country has a great wealth of natural resources and low-cost labour which is untapped following its long-term political isolation. Burma, due to its drive towards economic development, could also potentially be a new market for consumer goods from Western businesses looking to expand into this nation.</p>
<p>Politicians have also seen Burma as a root into China due to its strategic position and its political connections to the country, which it became close to during its isolation. As China was the only world power that would negotiate with Burma, whilst the West imposed sanctions, Western politicians see closer ties with Burma as a way to both improve regional relations with China and to balance Chinese influence in Burma, so that it doesn&#8217;t become an economic puppet of its Northern neighbour.</p>
<p>However for many critics, including human rights activists, the attention that Burma is receiving ignores the very real problems that still exist in the country. Although figures, such as David Cameron, have called for a furthering of the steps towards to democracy that Burma has already made, many have failed to address the fundamental social issues that exist in the country.</p>
<p>The issues that plague contemporary Burmese society are largely those regarding ethnicity and religion. Since democratic reforms have been implemented Burma has experienced a <a title="Renewed Threats to Democracy in Burma" href="http://alittleviewoftheworld.wordpress.com/2012/06/11/renewed-threats-to-democracy-in-burma/">wave of ethnic violence</a> targeted at the Katchin and Rohingya people. This violence is focused on the fact that the Rohingya people are Muslim, whereas the general population of Burma is Buddhist, and this religious divide has caused a worsening human rights and sectarian crisis.</p>
<p>For critics, whilst these issues still plague Burmese society foreign politicians should not be courting Burma as the new economic market of Asia. Instead they should be using the platform of increasing relations and a more open politics to call for the end to such conflict and encourage a move forward to real reform in Burma. This real reform would secure a complete break from the military junta (who have an important presence behind the scenes) and attempts made to resolve Burma&#8217;s historic problems.</p>
<p>However with China prepared to support Burma no matter what the political circumstances, it is even more important that Western nations do work with the new Burmese government so that progress can occur in a way that Western nations support. By leaving Burma to chart its own path through democracy without Western support, it is <a title="Suu Kyi: Burmese Progress Not Irreversible" href="http://alittleviewoftheworld.wordpress.com/2012/06/01/suu-kyi-burmese-progress-not-irreversible/">possible that Burma cannot achieve the mass reforms</a> that it is looking to implement or reach the full political and economic integration with the world system that it seeks.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/891/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/891/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=891&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://alittleviewoftheworld.wordpress.com/2012/11/13/why-burma-is-the-new-focus-of-international-relations/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://alittleviewoftheworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/hilary-clinton-aung-san-suu-kyi.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://alittleviewoftheworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/hilary-clinton-aung-san-suu-kyi.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Hilary Clinton &#38; Aung San Suu Kyi</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/b68915e25790ce02c3d45208456034de?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">alittleviewoftheworld</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Being Darkly Wise, and Rudely Great</title>
		<link>http://gonzarro.wordpress.com/2012/11/13/a-being-darkly-wise-and-rudely-great/</link>
		<comments>http://gonzarro.wordpress.com/2012/11/13/a-being-darkly-wise-and-rudely-great/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2012 21:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>gonz</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[dribblings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thinking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fight Club]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Victory]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://gonzarro.wordpress.com/?p=1441</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The past week or so has led me to some serious contemplation. Chief among them are thoughts like: Who am I? And what is this I? Am I amazing or inferior? Am I unique or pedestrian? Is that a pimple or a tumor? These are thoughts that a lot of us have. We want to [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1441&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The past week or so has led me to some serious contemplation. Chief among them are thoughts like:</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">Who am <strong>I</strong>? And what is this <strong>I</strong>?</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">Am I <strong>amazing</strong> or <strong>inferior</strong>?</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">Am I <strong>unique</strong> or <strong>pedestrian</strong>?</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">Is that a <strong>pimple</strong> or a <strong>tumor</strong>?</p>
<p>These are thoughts that a lot of us have. We want to feel as if we mean something, that whatever time we have in our brief lives isn&#8217;t fodder for despair and misery. We crave compassion, but don&#8217;t give it. We yearn for beauty and happiness as we stumble through the playground.</p>
<p>At times, it seems like coincidence mars any progress I try to make. Oftentimes, I&#8217;ll sit and, after a spate of deep pity and self-hatred, summarize my resolve not to wallow. &#8220;Fuck it,&#8221; I&#8217;ll say. &#8220;I&#8217;m going to be happy. I&#8217;m going to love and live and know that the universe gives not one whit whether I&#8217;m alive or dead.&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align:right;">Honestly, it works!</p>
<p>But, like I said, there&#8217;s an eerie synchronicity that pops up when I do that. &#8220;I will be happy,&#8221; I declare to friends and family. Then, poompf!, an obstacle arises: a dead car, an unforeseen expense, something bad. Coincidence or serendipity, whatever you call it, I say only that it&#8217;s debilitating. And discouraging. It makes me retreat back again to that sad Eeyore state-of-mind. <em>Why bother? It&#8217;s all going to end badly, if you like it that way.</em></p>
<p>But that&#8217;s defeatist and not really helpful in pulling me out of where I am mentally and physically. It&#8217;s a white flag to consistently think that no matter what I&#8217;ll do will be abject defeat. We suffer, it is no secret. We are all in this horrible reality together and not given any real instructions to transcend. We have theories, philosophies, and religions, but these are salves and advice. None of it really helps unless we allow it to help.</p>
<p>We have two options when hit obstacles, rocks, walls, and moats. One is to simply resign yourself to futility. This one I&#8217;ve orated quite a lot in my past performances. It&#8217;s belittling and consuming, a real downer:</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><em>I don&#8217;t deserve happiness. I&#8217;m tainted and a sinner, some would say loathsome. I should know better than to think otherwise. I give up.</em></p>
<p>The other, though, is to present toils and troubles with a middle-finger mindset:</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><em>I deserve happiness. I am a good chap. Some would say awesome. But whenever troubles arise, I think, reality must be pretty fucking jealous of me.</em></p>
<p>This, folks, is my new jam. Self-love still stronger.</p>
<p>So I do a lot of thinking, a lot of self-examination designed to fix those pings and grits in my machinery. I am a dented shell, but I don&#8217;t want to give in. It&#8217;s hard, yes. It&#8217;s hard for all of us. I&#8217;m not the only one who is suffering. I&#8217;m fortunate in that I have a roof over my head and food in my cupboard even if the number of dollars I have are outnumbered by the membership of Adolf Hitler Appreciation Society, Westerplatte Chapter 1939.</p>
<p>Ha, which reminds me&#8230;</p>
<h6>I am not how much money I have in my bank account.</h6>
<h6 style="padding-left:240px;text-align:left;">I am Gonz&#8217;s smirking revenge.</h6>
<h6 style="padding-left:330px;text-align:left;"><span style="text-align:right;">We are all a part of the same compost heap.</span></h6>
<h6 style="padding-left:420px;text-align:right;"><span style="text-align:right;">It&#8217;s only after we&#8217;ve lost <em>everythin</em>g that we&#8217;re free to do <strong>anything</strong>.</span></h6>
<p style="text-align:left;">I haven&#8217;t lost everything, but there are times when it feels close to it. I still have the love of my daughters. I have my friends, my humor, my kooky sense of perspective. I&#8217;m a student of the universe, listening to any and all wise teachers. I am the recipient of great warmth and generosity. A Beatles song can still make me nostalgic. A goodly and beautiful woman can still stir passion. I still can laugh.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;padding-left:30px;">A man gets a job at the sawmill. One morning, as his boss is walking by, he says, &#8220;Boss, I&#8217;ve just lost my finger!&#8221; The boss asks, &#8220;How did it happen?&#8221; The man replies, &#8220;I just touched this big spinning thing like thi&#8230; Damn, there goes another one!&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">The lesson is to not keep going to the same thing that damages you. Resigning myself to misery and not trying does that. Thinking I&#8217;m horrible because I&#8217;m in a situation I don&#8217;t want, that others might be thankful to be in considering their current state, isn&#8217;t going to move me.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">I am amazing.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">I am, in fact, pretty fucking awesome.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Jam on.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1441/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1441/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1441&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://gonzarro.wordpress.com/2012/11/13/a-being-darkly-wise-and-rudely-great/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>17</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/b859e74023aa9df3c4505ddefcfd0d44?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Gonz</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is Ronald Reagan Actually a Hero of The Tea Party?</title>
		<link>http://lowdownblog.com/2012/11/13/is-ronald-reagan-actually-a-hero-of-the-tea-party/</link>
		<comments>http://lowdownblog.com/2012/11/13/is-ronald-reagan-actually-a-hero-of-the-tea-party/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2012 17:00:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Steve Murray</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Columns]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Barack Obama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GOP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Republicans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ronald Reagan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tea Party]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://lowdownblog.com/?p=27657</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[If you talk to Republicans, one of their greatest heroes is actor-turned-politician Ronald Reagan. The 40th President of the United States is an icon for Conservatives. However, is it possible that Reagan&#8217;s policies of the 1980s would be politically left of those who claim him as a sort of demigod, the Tea Party? Could it [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=27657&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://lowdownblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/ronald-reagan-inauguration.jpg"><img class="alignleft  wp-image-27785" title="ronald-reagan-inauguration" alt="" src="http://lowdownblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/ronald-reagan-inauguration.jpg?w=270&#038;h=209" height="209" width="270" /></a>If you talk to Republicans, one of their greatest heroes is actor-turned-politician Ronald Reagan. The 40th President of the United States is an icon for Conservatives. However, is it possible that Reagan&#8217;s policies of the 1980s would be politically left of those who claim him as a sort of demigod, the Tea Party? Could it be that the Tea Party is so out of touch with the policies that led to American prosperity under Reagan that he couldn&#8217;t win the Republican Presidential nomination if he ran in 2012?<span id="more-27657"></span></p>
<p>Today&#8217;s Republican Party, led by a faction of neoconservatives referred to as The Tea Party, are an uncompromising group who believes in smaller government, cutting spending (except in defence where the policy is peace through strength) and lowering taxes. They see President Obama as the antithesis of their core values while President Reagan embodies all that they fight for.</p>
<p>Socially, while Reagan was firmly in favour of imposing his and his party&#8217;s beliefs on America, he was willing to admit that there was room for compromise. In his 1980 platform, Reagan and the GOP admitted that abortion was a complex issue and there were many different views. Still, he wanted a constitutional amendment banning abortion. The Tea Party refers to abortion as a war on religion. They also lump the Democrats&#8217; policies on health care and same-sex marriage as part of the war on religion.</p>
<p>Of course, the First Amendment of the US Constitution makes reference to government not doing anything for or against religious beliefs but Republican views on abortion are almost always based solely on religious views. It&#8217;s contradictory that the Republicans would hold up the Constitution as the be all and end all of political documents but champion policies on same-sex marriage and abortion that spit in the face of the First Amendment and the words of founding father Thomas Jefferson who believed in a &#8220;wall of separation between Church &amp; State.&#8221;</p>
<p><a href="http://lowdownblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/2012-republican-national-convention.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-27786" title="2012-republican-national-convention" alt="" src="http://lowdownblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/2012-republican-national-convention.jpg?w=300&#038;h=200" height="200" width="300" /></a>The immigration policies of the 1980 Republican Party and the 2012 GOP sound like they are from two different parties with two different philosophies. The Reagan-era policy includes the line &#8220;Republicans are proud that our people have opened their arms and hearts to strangers from abroad and we favor an immigration and refugee policy which is consistent with this tradition.&#8221; That&#8217;s an almost inclusionary sounding policy from the Republicans. Today&#8217;s GOP talks more about curbing illegal immigration and preventing illegal entrants into America from seeing any prosperity rather than encouraging people to come to America.</p>
<p>Even beyond Reagan&#8217;s two terms, there were Republican presidents whose initiatives wouldn&#8217;t be supported by the Tea Party. The Environmental Protection Agency was created under the watch of Richard Nixon. Today, Republicans don&#8217;t believe that global warming is a scientific fact. George H.W. Bush was a supporter for the Americans with Disabilities Act while today&#8217;s GOP is targeting social security for spending cuts. George W. Bush added a prescription drug benefit to Medicare while the GOP are looking to reinvent Medicare as something derogatorily referred to as VoucherCare.</p>
<p>Economically, the two talk the same game but Reagan&#8217;s actions during his first team are very different from what he promised in the 1980 Republican Platform. Reagan&#8217;s first platform made repeated references to cutting taxes for families and decreasing the burden that taxation places on them. However, his two tax increases of 1982 and 1983 actually increased the tax burden on middle-class families by 0.7%. Noted economist Paul Krugman wrote in 2004 that &#8220;no peacetime president has raised taxes so much on so many people.&#8221; If you look at the tax changes legislated in under Reagan, while taxes decreased overall, the Reagan administration dialled back half of his original 1981 tax cut.</p>
<p><a href="http://lowdownblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/occupy-wall-street-protest.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-27787" title="occupy-wall-street-protest" alt="" src="http://lowdownblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/occupy-wall-street-protest.jpg?w=300&#038;h=168" height="168" width="300" /></a>Today&#8217;s Tea Party dominated Republican Party is opposed to any tax increases despite the fact that economic prosperity was better when Clinton raised taxes than under Reagan&#8217;s yo-yo-ing tax policies. American saw a faster increase in middle-class income and job creation. Despite evidence to the contrary, the Republicans believe that the best course of action is cutting income tax 20% across the board, extending the George W. Bush tax cuts and eliminating investment taxes on the middle and lower classes. Somehow, they&#8217;ll cut enough spending to balance the budget. All these ideas are effectively a modernization of Reaganomics. In the end, Reagan went back on his tax cuts and never came close to balancing the budget.</p>
<p>One of the recurring themes of the Republican campaign for the White House was that President Obama&#8217;s spending is out of control as evidenced by the national debt reaching its highest level ever. Prominent Republicans like House speaker John Boehner referred to the debt as a &#8220;drain on [the] economy and a crushing burden on our kids and grandkids.&#8221; Republican National Committee chair Reince Priebus suggested that the rising debt showed that Obama couldn&#8217;t control spending.</p>
<p><a href="http://lowdownblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/barack-obama-state-of-the-union-2012.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-27788" title="barack-obama-state-of-the-union-2012" alt="" src="http://lowdownblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/barack-obama-state-of-the-union-2012.jpg?w=300&#038;h=202" height="202" width="300" /></a>However, while Reagan may have cut government spending during his time in office, he wasn&#8217;t opposed to running deficits which increased the national debt. The national debt as a percentage of GDP in 1980, immediately prior to Reagan to taking office, was 26.1%. At the end of Reagan&#8217;s two terms in office was 41.0% after running deficits in each of his eight years in office. In terms of dollars, the debt nearly tripled from $712 billion to $2.05 trillion or an increase of 188%. By comparison, the debt under President Obama increased by 176% with debt at the end of 2008 being $5.8 trillion and most recently being reported at $16 trillion. Republican pundits like to say that debt has never grown faster than under Obama but Reagan actually has him beat.</p>
<p>While today&#8217;s GOP says they look to Reagan for inspiration on how to best govern America, it&#8217;s apparent that the Tea Party has charted its own course for governing. In the grand scheme of the political spectrum, the Tea Party&#8217;s social policies are more conservative than Reagan. While the economic policies are based around the same principles of lower taxes and spending, Reagan was willing to raise taxes subsequent to his 1981 tax cut.</p>
<p>So we come back to the question of if Ronald Reagan, hero of the Tea Party, would be too moderate to earn the Republican Presidential nomination. Governor Mitt Romney of Massachusetts should have been too moderate thanks to his assault rifle ban and introducing health care reform used as the basis for President Obama&#8217;s Affordable Care Act. Chameleon Mitt Romney at times seems more moderate than Reagan and more conservative depending on the audience he is talking to. Reagan was always Reagan. Agree with his politics or not, in researching his politics and Presidency, I&#8217;ve never once read that he flip-flopped constantly or completely changed his message to appeal to all voters.</p>
<p>Reagan probably would have been able to win the Presidential nomination for 2012 considering the weak field that the Republicans put up. If he had to combat with people who were charismatic or had bipartisan appeal like the prospective 2016 nominees such as Chris Christie, Marco Rubio and Bobby Jindal, I wouldn&#8217;t like Reagan&#8217;s chances. His policies just don&#8217;t fit with the Tea Party&#8217;s values well enough to get their support.</p>
<p><a href="http://lowdownblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/ronald-reagan-oval-office-white-house.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-27789" title="ronald-reagan-oval-office-white-house" alt="" src="http://lowdownblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/ronald-reagan-oval-office-white-house.jpg?w=300&#038;h=200" height="200" width="300" /></a>If Reagan was elected President in 2012, I think it would have been a far different Presidency than his of the 1980s. The tax cuts, spending cuts and increase in defense funding would have all still been there. So would the perpetual deficit and increase in national debt. From the last four years, we&#8217;ve already seen that the Republicans aren&#8217;t willing to compromise on their ideals. It&#8217;s unlikely that the rest of the GOP would let Reagan raise taxes during his second year in office. Without that tax increase, who knows how bad the debt would get. From this campaign, it&#8217;s apparent that prayer is the only means the Tea Party has at its disposal to balance the budget.</p>
<p><strong>Sources:</strong><br />
The American Presidency Project &#8211; <a href="http://www.presidency.ucsb.edu/ws/index.php?pid=25844">Republican Party Platform of 1980</a><br />
Bloomberg &#8211; <a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2012-08-28/hero-reagan-s-compromise-would-collide-with-tea-party-certitude.html">Hero Reagan’s Compromise Would Collide With Tea Party Certitude</a><br />
Capital Gains and Games &#8211; <a href="http://capitalgainsandgames.com/blog/bruce-bartlett/1632/reagans-tax-increases">Reagan&#8217;s Tax Increases</a><br />
CBS News &#8211; <a href="http://www.cbsnews.com/8301-503544_162-57505995-503544/as-national-debt-passes-16-trillion-gop-blasts-obamas-policies-/">As national debt passes $16 trillion, GOP blasts Obama&#8217;s policies</a><br />
Congressional Budget Office &#8211; <a href="http://www.cbo.gov/publication/21999">Budget and Economic Outlook: Fiscal Years 2011 to 2021</a><br />
GOP &#8211; <a href="http://www.gop.com/2012-republican-platform_home/">2012 Republican Platform</a><br />
Library of Congress &#8211; <a href="http://www.loc.gov/loc/lcib/9806/danpre.html">Jefferson&#8217;s Letter to the Danbury Baptists</a><br />
The Lowdown Blog &#8211; <a href="http://lowdownblog.com/2012/09/27/greed-isnt-good-why-supply-side-economics-doesnt-work/">Greed isn’t Good: Why Supply-Side Economics Doesn’t Work</a><br />
New York Times &#8211; <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2012/08/29/us/politics/republican-platform-takes-turn-to-right.html?_r=1">Platform’s Sharp Turn to Right Has Conservatives Cheering</a><br />
New York Times &#8211; <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2004/06/08/opinion/the-great-taxer.html">The Great Taxer</a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://www.facebook.com/LowdownBlog"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-24672" title="The Lowdown Blog on Facebook" alt="" src="http://lowdownblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/facebook-64px.png?w=590"   /></a><a href="http://twitter.com/LowdownBlog"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-26302" title="The Lowdown Blog on Twitter (@LowdownBlog)" alt="" src="http://lowdownblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/twitter-new-64px.png?w=590"   /></a><a href="https://plus.google.com/u/0/100851849231467065414/"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-24674" title="The Lowdown Blog on Google Plus" alt="" src="http://lowdownblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/google-plus-64px.png?w=590"   /></a><a href="http://lowdownblog.tumblr.com/"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-24675" title="The Lowdown Blog Tumblr" alt="" src="http://lowdownblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/tumblr-64px.png?w=590"   /></a><a href="http://lowdownblog.com/feed/"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-24676" title="The Lowdown Blog RSS Feed" alt="" src="http://lowdownblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/rss-64px.png?w=590"   /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/27657/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/27657/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=27657&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://lowdownblog.com/2012/11/13/is-ronald-reagan-actually-a-hero-of-the-tea-party/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://lowdownblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/ronald-reagan-oval-office-white-house.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://lowdownblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/ronald-reagan-oval-office-white-house.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ronald-reagan-oval-office-white-house</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/aa9fd8aee2330223d4ab2060ce9d8c07?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F1.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Steve</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lowdownblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/ronald-reagan-inauguration.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ronald-reagan-inauguration</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lowdownblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/2012-republican-national-convention.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2012-republican-national-convention</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lowdownblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/occupy-wall-street-protest.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">occupy-wall-street-protest</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lowdownblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/barack-obama-state-of-the-union-2012.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">barack-obama-state-of-the-union-2012</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lowdownblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/ronald-reagan-oval-office-white-house.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ronald-reagan-oval-office-white-house</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lowdownblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/facebook-64px.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The Lowdown Blog on Facebook</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lowdownblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/twitter-new-64px.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The Lowdown Blog on Twitter (@LowdownBlog)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lowdownblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/google-plus-64px.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The Lowdown Blog on Google Plus</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lowdownblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/tumblr-64px.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The Lowdown Blog Tumblr</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lowdownblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/rss-64px.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The Lowdown Blog RSS Feed</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Psychology of the Oreo Cookie</title>
		<link>http://mysticcircle.wordpress.com/2012/11/13/psychology-of-the-oreo-cookie/</link>
		<comments>http://mysticcircle.wordpress.com/2012/11/13/psychology-of-the-oreo-cookie/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2012 23:07:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>fairydancer221</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Concepts to Think About]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oreo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Psychology]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mysticcircle.wordpress.com/?p=785</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Apparently, there is some psychology behind the way you eat an Oreo cookie. To learn what the method you use to eat an Oreo, choose one from this list: The whole thing at once. One bite at a time. Slow and methodical nibbles examining the results of each bite afterwards. In little feverous nibbles. Dunked [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=785&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://mysticcircle.wordpress.com/2012/11/13/psychology-of-the-oreo-cookie/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/7104321d63a9fdc20b45baa1943b54f4?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">fairydancer221</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Auctioning Off My Gaming Childhood</title>
		<link>http://gamedelver.wordpress.com/2012/11/12/auctioning-off-my-gaming-childhood/</link>
		<comments>http://gamedelver.wordpress.com/2012/11/12/auctioning-off-my-gaming-childhood/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2012 02:13:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Game Delver</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dreamcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nostalgia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Playstation 1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pokemon TCG]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://gamedelver.wordpress.com/?p=538</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Since college, I&#8217;ve gotten used to being poor and broke most of the time, but when I was a lot younger I was very spoiled.  I had one chore every day of every week &#8211; feeding our chickens and collecting eggs &#8211; and my father paid me the tidy sum of twenty dollars a week [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=538&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Since college, I&#8217;ve gotten used to being poor and broke most of the time, but when I was a lot younger I was very spoiled.  I had one chore every day of every week &#8211; feeding our chickens and collecting eggs &#8211; and my father paid me the tidy sum of twenty dollars a week to do it. Needless to say, most of my money went directly into videogames and videogame-related hobbies. Recently though, I&#8217;ve taken to ebaying off various things from my past to afford various things of my future, which has had me reconsidering my younger days with sadness, nostalgia, and reserved glee.</p>
<p>I had the foresight as a kid to buy almost any JRPG I could get my hands on.  Even if they were bad, I had enough cash burning a hole in my pocket that I&#8217;d take a leap without necessarily doing the research to see if it is any good.  I ended up with a lot of duds on my Playstation and Dreamcast that I barely played, but I loved owning so many.  But considering I sold off my Playstation long ago to buy a Playstation 2 and my Playstation 2 has long since been dead ever since it plummeted to its demise on a hardwood floor in the middle of a heated game of NFL Blitz, the games I still had left for Sony systems have long been inaccessible to me. It was a pleasant surprise when my near mint copy of Vagrant Story sold for more than I would&#8217;ve expected.</p>
<p>Unlike my history with Playstations, my Dreamcast remains an immaculate and very beloved system in my repertoire that has moved with me into every new chapter of my life. Well immaculate save for the fact that I was a stupid kid who thought a console decal would be a great idea.  I had to scratch and claw to get it off, so my Dreamcast looks like a survivor of an actual cat fight: but it runs beautifully.  I actually began a project a couple of years ago of reacquiring the right games and accessories to make the console a staple device for parties as well.  I bought VMUs, extra controllers, controller extension cords, and looked into buying all the classics.</p>
<p>Of course, buying the classics for a system with such rare games proved to be a far too expensive undertaking, so I settled for piracy (sorry Dreamcast developers, I loved you when it counted).  With piracy, came the nerve to just sell off the games I did still have that were worth anything.  Exit Skies of Arcadia, my favorite Dreamcast game of all time (with the exception of Sonic Adventure, Marvel vs Capcom 2, Toy Commander, and Power Stone 2 in select contexts). And whether I play them or not, it helps me sleep at night that my Dreamcast is never <em>THAT</em> far away.</p>
<p>However, today marks the true final step in ridding myself of my childhood&#8217;s most prized possessions.  After much debate, <a href="http://www.ebay.com/itm/65-Rare-Pokemon-Cards-Basic-Jungle-Japanese-Fossil-Japanese-Rocket-Promo-/271101869501?pt=LH_DefaultDomain_0&amp;hash=item3f1eee3dbd">I&#8217;ve decided to ebay my Pokemon cards.</a></p>
<p>I remember the addiction I felt toward these stupid things.  All of my money and my attention went toward acquiring more and more of them.  I even managed to anger my father because on one particular family vacation to Florida, I wanted to spend all our time looking for card shops that sold Japanese Pokemon cards.  You see, I come from Alabama where nothing cool exists (unless you love <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/National_Peanut_Festival">peanuts</a>), especially not something as cool as this:</p>
<p><a href="http://gamedelver.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/t2ec16hce9s4pvnelbqohfsvbcq60_12.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-539" title="$T2eC16h,!)cE9s4PvnELBQoHFSVBcQ~~60_12" alt="" src="http://gamedelver.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/t2ec16hce9s4pvnelbqohfsvbcq60_12.jpg?w=198&#038;h=300" height="300" width="198" /></a></p>
<p>Yes, this is a Japanese Fossil Dragonite. Being a predictable child beast, I loved dragonite as a kid and I probably would&#8217;ve killed for this card if its original owner were someone other than my best friend at the time.  I had the sheer luck of pulling more than one Charizard from the Basic set, so the Fates hadn&#8217;t abandoned me entirely.  But when I saw this card, when I held it in my hand, I traded a hell of a lot to own it including my precious Charizards among many others.  I still have no clue what the card says, but I&#8217;ll be damned if I am not proud to own it.</p>
<p>Alas, it is in the lot too, along with so many other cards that I once loved and adored and prided myself on owning. I already sold the one Charizard I did manage to keep a few months ago, so it shouldn&#8217;t of taken this long to move the rest of the rares I had left. After all, I haven&#8217;t played the TCG since middle school and the last Pokemon game I owned was Pokemon Silver. These things don&#8217;t hold the sway that they once did.</p>
<p>Except they do, at least to some extent, and I am saddened to see them go.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/538/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/538/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=538&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://gamedelver.wordpress.com/2012/11/12/auctioning-off-my-gaming-childhood/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>36</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/12572da9fca6f322e0caefea297bbdfe?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ctmurphy46</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gamedelver.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/t2ec16hce9s4pvnelbqohfsvbcq60_12.jpg?w=198" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">$T2eC16h,!)cE9s4PvnELBQoHFSVBcQ~~60_12</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Conversation Between a Libertarian and a Statist</title>
		<link>http://manchesterliberal.wordpress.com/2012/11/12/a-conversation-between-a-libertarian-and-a-statist/</link>
		<comments>http://manchesterliberal.wordpress.com/2012/11/12/a-conversation-between-a-libertarian-and-a-statist/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2012 11:13:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>manchesterliberal</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Philosophy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Political theory]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://manchesterliberal.wordpress.com/?p=1260</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In the interest of greater interaction between ideologically opposed people below is a conversation I had recently with a statist acquaintance of mine along with some interjections by an open-minded observer. As Bob Hoskins said in those BT ads, its good to talk. Statist &#8211; Tax is the subscription you pay for living in a [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1260&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_ITCRyA9-aUU/TIeJtwO4s5I/AAAAAAAAAKs/FAGFggOjiSI/s1600/good+to+talk.jpg"><img class="aligncenter" style="width:531px;height:441px;" alt="" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_ITCRyA9-aUU/TIeJtwO4s5I/AAAAAAAAAKs/FAGFggOjiSI/s320/good+to+talk.jpg" height="399" width="481" /></a></p>
<p><em>In the interest of greater interaction between ideologically opposed people below is a conversation I had recently with a statist acquaintance of mine along with some interjections by an open-minded observer. As Bob Hoskins said in those BT ads, its good to talk.</em></p>
<p>Statist &#8211; Tax is the subscription you pay for living in a complex society like ours.</p>
<p><strong>Libertarian &#8211; Can I unsubscribe?</strong></p>
<p>Statist &#8211; If you go and live somewhere else, yes.</p>
<p><strong>Libertarian &#8211; No, I want to stay here, it&#8217;s where I&#8217;m from after all.</strong></p>
<p>Statist &#8211; Well then you&#8217;re choosing to belong to this particular club and thus have to pay he subscription decided by the majority of the club.</p>
<p><strong>Libertarian &#8211; That&#8217;s what I was looking for, the majoritarianism, our way or the highway. It&#8217;s not a subscription, it&#8217;s a forced levy. </strong></p>
<p><strong>Tell you what, why don&#8217;t you slash my taxes and I&#8217;ll sort my own pension and healthcare out and educate my own kids?</strong></p>
<p>Statist &#8211; As I said, you can always leave the club if you don&#8217;t like the way its organised and go and live somewhere that suits you better.</p>
<p><strong>Libertarian &#8211; I don&#8217;t see why I should, I was born in this country just like you and your mates in the majority. It&#8217;s as much mine as yours. In fact, what gives you the right to issue an ultimatum like that? </strong></p>
<p><strong>As I say, why don&#8217;t you slash my taxes and I&#8217;ll sort my own pension and healthcare out and educate my own kids? I&#8217;ll go and do my own thing and you and the majority can do your thing, set up an NHS, a comprehensive system and all the rest, whatever you like.</strong></p>
<p>Statist &#8211; Eh?</p>
<p>You apparently want to be part of a community called the UK, yet apparently you don&#8217;t want to abide by the rules that the majority of that community decides upon.  That makes about as much sense as me joining a tennis club, voting for the subscription to be £80 and when the majority vote for it to be £100 complaining that they have no right to issue to me an ultimatum that I should pay £100 to be in the club.</p>
<p>I think we are different planets when we are on this issue and I am afraid I really do not get this moral indignation at having to abide by decisions that the majority make that I might not agree with.  I mean I don&#8217;t like having to contribute to Trident for example, but I don&#8217;t think subscriptions to the nuclear defence system should be voluntary, even though I am quite happy to go without the alleged benefits of Trident.</p>
<p><strong>Libertarian &#8211; No, I want to live in the place I was born in (hence your tennis club analogy is a total dud). You want to make my living there conditional on handing my money over to you and your mates in the majority so that you can spend it as you wish which may not accord with how I wish it to be spent. </strong></p>
<p><strong>So you havent answered my question.</strong></p>
<p>Statist &#8211; You are making a fetish of being born on a particular piece of ground.  That, to me, is irrelevant.</p>
<p>You want to live in a particular political community.  That community has rules.  You can choose to obey those rules or go and live somewhere else.  If you choose to  live in that political community you can also try to persuade others to change the rules to your way of thinking.</p>
<p>I am struggling to see what is objectionable about that unless you are arguing that any government spending is of necessity illegitimate (police? courts? military? &#8211; they are all funded by money taken from you and I to spend in ways we might not agree with).</p>
<p>Your argument ultimately leads you to some kind of anarchism &#8211; after all if you should not have to pay for pensions, education etc, a pacifist should not have to pay for police, military or the rest the state&#8217;s coercive arms.  You then get a situation where people only pay for government functions they agree with which, of course, makes government impossible.</p>
<p><strong>Libertarian &#8211; It&#8217;s not irrelevant to me, I was born here. I&#8217;ve just as much right to be here as you or any of your majority. And, for that matter, I have just as much right to tell you all to clear off.</strong></p>
<p><strong>There&#8217;s a fundamental point here. My philosophy would leave you alone. If you and everyone else in the country wanted to set up an NHS or paint your heads green you could do that. I wouldn&#8217;t stop you.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Your philosophy, by complete contrast, demands that I be involved on pain of expulsion or imprisonment. It requires that what 51% want is swallowed by the other 49% on pain of punishment.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Not too appealing.</strong></p>
<p>Statist &#8211; You would agree then that I should not have to pay towards Trident and a pacifist should get a full rebate on all taxes that go towards the military?  After all anyone else who wants to pay for Trident or the military can continue doing so.  Me and the pacifist wouldn&#8217;t stop them.</p>
<p><strong>Libertarian &#8211; Fine. I&#8217;d join you, Trident is a waste of money.</strong></p>
<p>Statist &#8211; The point is &#8211; as you are well aware &#8211; that you do, in fact agree that the state should be able to coerce people to fund some things &#8211; the military and the justice system for example.  What we are therefore arguing about is not a point of principle about state coercion but about for what particular purposes the state should be able to coerce people.</p>
<p>Some people think that the state should be able to coerce people to fund the military.  Other people disagree with that.  Ditto with healthcare. How do we resolve those disagreements?  I can&#8217;t think of a better way than a majority vote.</p>
<p><strong>Libertarian &#8211; Well, I have my doubts about the justice system. I deal with county courts day in day out and they are a shambles. I saw a woman at Bow County Court treated appallingly by the staff last week. I was going to tell her to go to the competing court but, of course, there isn&#8217;t one. That&#8217;s what you and your majority have given us for our forced levy.</strong></p>
<p><strong>The question is how do people spend their money. I can&#8217;t think of a better way than to let them spend it themselves.</strong></p>
<p>Statist &#8211; So you don&#8217;t believe there should be any state at all?    No military?  No police?  Every person for themselves?</p>
<p><strong>Libertarian &#8211; I don&#8217;t see why you assume that just because I don&#8217;t want the State to do something you assume that I don&#8217;t want that thing done at all.</strong></p>
<p>Statist &#8211; Because your argument was that it was illegitimate for the majority to impose its will on the minority in any circumstances.  If you think that, as a matter of principle, the majority of the population should not be able to force you to contribute towards the NHS it must follow that, as a matter of principle, the majority of the population should not be able to force the pacifist to contribute towards the military.  It then follows that contributions to all government services become voluntary, with the resulting collapse of the state.</p>
<p><strong>Libertarian &#8211; It means the State stops doing certain things but it isn&#8217;t very good at doing them anyway and, as I say, that&#8217;s not to say that those things wouldn&#8217;t be done at all.</strong></p>
<p>Statist &#8211; So you have no objection on principle to the state coercing people to pay for things they don&#8217;t want to pay for, it&#8217;s just a question of deciding what those things should be?</p>
<p><strong>Libertarian &#8211; I&#8217;m not clear on how you&#8217;ve deduced that. I think a system which gives most people what they want is better than one which gives 51% of people what they want.</strong></p>
<p>Swing voter - I&#8217;m pretty sure most people are in favour of the NHS.</p>
<p><strong>Libertarian &#8211; I&#8217;m sure they are.</strong></p>
<p>Swing voter &#8211; So given that you want a system that gives most people what they want, do you want to be outside that system sorting out your own healthcare?</p>
<p><strong>Libertarian &#8211; Wouldnt the option be nice? I mean, how chuffed would you be if you went into a restaurant and ordered steak only to be told &#8220;Well, 51% of the diners wanted Lentil Soup so you&#8217;ll have to have that&#8221;?</strong></p>
<p>Swing voter &#8211; I think I&#8217;d prefer that option than the other option which is &#8220;51% of the diners have had the lentil soup, so supply is quite limited at the moment. If you want the lentil soup, you&#8217;ll have to pay through the nose for it&#8221;</p>
<p>I don&#8217;t think we should be continuing the Restaurant/healthcare comparisons&#8230;</p>
<p><strong>Libertarian &#8211; You might be right but if this restaurant is charging you loads for lentil soup and you&#8217;re gagging for it would pay another restaurant to flog lentil soup cheaper. Of course, that presupposes A) the availability of another restaurant and B) the ability to pick up your wallet and go there with it.</strong></p>
<p>Statist &#8211; Your original point appeared to be that it was somehow illegitimate for the majority to force the minority to contribute towards something they don&#8217;t want to contribute towards. You were waxing all indignant about that. I pointed out that, taking that principle to its logical conclusion would make any form of state impossible as all contributions to the state would become purely voluntary.</p>
<p>You seemed to accept that in that you drew a distinction between the things that you considered the state wasn&#8217;t very good at with the things that you considered it was good at (I know you don&#8217;t say that explicitly but you certainly implied it earlier) and, I assume, accepted that people should be coerced into paying for the latter. You therefore accept that it is not illegitimate, <i>in some circumstances, </i>for the state to coerce people to do things they don&#8217;t want to do</p>
<p>That then, of course, raises the question as to how we decide which things the state should do (and which people should be coerced to pay for) and what it shouldn&#8217;t do. I can&#8217;t think of any better way of deciding this then a majority vote.</p>
<p>The thing is you are between a rock and a hard place here. The only two logically coherent positions are:</p>
<p>1. It is never legitimate for the majority to coerce the minority into paying for things they don&#8217;t want to pay for. As such, no form of state and no state functions are legitimate.</p>
<p>2. In some circumstances it is legitimate for the majority to coerce the minority to pay for things they don&#8217;t want to pay for. Thus some form of state and some state functions are legitimate and what is to be decided is what those functions are.</p>
<p>It, of course, does not necessarily follow from proposition 2 that how you decide what those functions should be should be via majority vote. There are competing theories &#8211; you can refer to your Holy Book or you can have some concept of rights and I actually think what you are groping towards is some notion of the latter. You want to hold that some things inalieanbly appertain to the individual and should not be invaded by the collective. The problem you then, of course, have is on what basis can you say that these rights to appertain to the individual when the majority of your society disagree with you.</p>
<p>Take the notion of the right to property. Since the rise of socialism in the 19th century, this has been hugely contested. Those with property generally argued that things like progressive income tax, inheritance tax, nationalisation etc invaded the individual&#8217;s inalienable right to property and was illegitimate no matter than the majority might vote for them. The socialists argued equally vehemently that there was no such right (or that the right was limited by the needs of society as a whole). How can one decide a dispute like that? It&#8217;s either by voting or by war isn&#8217;t it?</p>
<p><strong>Libertarian &#8211; It does not follow that because &#8220;all contributions to the state would become purely voluntary&#8221; &#8220;any form of state (becomes) impossible&#8221; There are all sorts of voluntary associations which have lasted longer than most states.  </strong></p>
<p><strong>&#8220;You seemed to accept that in that you drew a distinction between the things that you considered the state wasn&#8217;t very good at with the things that you considered it was good at (I know you don&#8217;t say that explicitly but it is certainly implied in post 98 )..&#8221; I didn&#8217;t intent to make that implication (I can&#8217;t actually see that I did) so the rest doesn&#8217;t follow.</strong></p>
<p><strong>&#8220;The problem you then, of course, have is on what basis can you say that these rights to appertain to the individual when the majority of your society disagree with you.&#8221; Indeed, it was the same problem slaves had in the United States. It&#8217;s the same thing gays have when US voters decide not to let them marry. If you believe that no right is inalienable and that we only have the rights we have because the majority consents to letting us have them, then if that majority votes for slavery or discrimination you would have to accept that as perfectly legitimate.</strong></p>
<p>Swing voter &#8211; And if the majority votes for a compulsory healthcare system you have to do the same.</p>
<p><strong>Libertarian &#8211; Indeed, exactly the same principle which brought you Obamacare brought you California&#8217;s ban on gay marriage.</strong></p>
<p>Statist &#8211; So do you agree or disagree that a state, as opposed to voluntary associations, should exist?</p>
<p>On your latter point, I agree, it&#8217;s a difficult issue.  I didn&#8217;t say that I didn&#8217;t believe they were inalienable rights, what I said was that the nature of such rights is heavily contested.  If people can&#8217;t agree what those rights are, you then have to decide how one decides what amounts to an inalienable right and what doesn&#8217;t.</p>
<p>A burglar might argue that, as a staunch social Darwinist, he believes in the survival of the fittest and that he has an inalienable right to pit his strength against that of an individual householder and see who comes out best.  It follows that it is an infringement of this right for society to lock him up if he commits a burglary.</p>
<p>If we can&#8217;t say the burglar is wrong because virtually everyone disagrees with him, how can we say he is wrong?</p>
<p><strong>Libertarian &#8211; Well if we both agree that there are inalienable rights then it becomes a slightly more technical question of what those inalienable rights are. Id argue there is an inalienable right to life, that&#8217;s why I oppose the death penalty. I think we&#8217;d agree. Id also argue you have an inalienable right to do what you like with your own body. That might be more contentious?</strong></p>
<p>Exactly, which then begs the question as to how we decide what are and what are not inalienable rights.  Which then, it seems to me, leaves us with the alternatives of either majority vote or war.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not an easy issue.  On something like the right to property I would say that this is a matter of majority vote.  If society votes to tax those earning over £150,000 at 50%, then those who have to pay such a tax have a duty to pay it and not resist it by force as an illegitimate invasion of their right to property.</p>
<p>On the other hand if Hitler had held a (fair) referendum on the extermination of the Jews and, say 70%, voted for extermination, I would say that the 30% had a right to resist that majority decision by force as an illegitimate invasion of the Jews&#8217; right to life.</p>
<p>So sometimes, it seems to me, it is reasonable to allow a majority to define an inalienable right and sometimes it isn&#8217;t.  Unfortunately, the circumstances of when allowing the majority to define an inalienable right is reasonable is also contested and we go into an infinite regression&#8230;</p>
<p><strong>Libertarian &#8211; Possibly all correct, but first Id ask again about that individuals right to do what he or she wants with her body. I would consider that inalienable, would you?</strong></p>
<p>Statist &#8211; To an extent.  Does an individual have a right to pay a doctor to amputate his leg when there is no medical need for such an operation?  I would say not, given that the subsequent disability will impose burdens on society.</p>
<p><strong>Libertarian &#8211; That&#8217;s only a problem if &#8216;society&#8217; accepts those burdens. If the guy knows in advance that it wont he might think twice before doing it.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Besides, Aids is, I understand, disproportionately a disease which afflicts homosexuals. We could reduce rates of HIV infection and avoid these supposed societal costs by voting to ban gay sex.</strong></p>
<p><strong>I wouldn&#8217;t support that.</strong></p>
<p>Statist &#8211; I think the nature of humanity is such that if people see a one-legged man, they will not stop to enquire how he came by his disability, they will try to help him , so it&#8217;s pretty impossible not to get a situation where having only one leg does not impose a burden on other people.</p>
<p>In fact, I think a society where people are not allowed to pay doctors to chop their legs off on a whim (incidentally the doctor commits the offence not the amputee) but where the disabled are helped without deep enquiry as to how they came by their disability is much preferable to a society where such voluntary maiming is allowed but where disabled people are only helped if enquiry establishes that they are deserving of help.</p>
<p>Your final para again illustrates the difficulty of balancing the rights of the individual with the rights of society and how this is deeply contested (and historically contingent given that, until 40ish years ago gay sex was illegal virtually everywhere).</p>
<p><strong>Libertarian &#8211; If individuals willingly want to help the one-legged man that&#8217;s up to them.</strong></p>
<p><strong>In both cases we have a negative externality which could, we are assuming, be mollified by legislation, either to stop the man having his leg chopped off or to stop men having sex with each other. How can one be accepted and the other not? Especially when the externalities of Aids are much greater than the externalities of people having their legs chopped off to solicit sympathy and money.</strong></p>
<p>Statist &#8211; Actually people tend to get their legs chopped off for reasons of sexual gratification..</p>
<p>Virtually everything anyone does involves a &#8220;negative externality&#8221;.  If I choose to go to work by train rather than bus that involves a &#8220;negative externality&#8221; to the bus company and its employees as it deprives the former of revenue and makes it slightly more likely that the latter will lose their jobs.  Politics is all about making subjective judgments as to which forms of individual behaviour involve such an unnaceptable amount of &#8220;negative externality&#8221; that they should be forbidden.</p>
<p>There is no deep principle that says an individual should be able to do whatever he likes and that &#8220;negative externalities&#8221; don&#8217;t matter.  Going back to our friend the social Darwinist burglar, he is, after all, just acting in accordance with his individual desires and his individual conscience, yet I think you would agree that, in his case, the &#8220;negative externalities&#8221; of his behaviour are such that we should forcibly prevent him from committing burglary.</p>
<p><strong>Libertarian &#8211; Well, you see, if I believe in an inalienable right to property then the burglar hasn&#8217;t got a leg to stand on. Just like your amputee.</strong></p>
<p><em>The conversation sort of petered out there. </em></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1260/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1260/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1260&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://manchesterliberal.wordpress.com/2012/11/12/a-conversation-between-a-libertarian-and-a-statist/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>24</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a3bf03c701c6d82ae56c57327a062a09?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">manchesterliberal</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_ITCRyA9-aUU/TIeJtwO4s5I/AAAAAAAAAKs/FAGFggOjiSI/s320/good+to+talk.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>