<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2012 01:02:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>The Psychological Power of Storytelling</title>
		<link>http://dranilj1.wordpress.com/2012/07/29/the-psychological-power-of-storytelling/</link>
		<comments>http://dranilj1.wordpress.com/2012/07/29/the-psychological-power-of-storytelling/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2012 15:06:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>nishanil</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Animal Farm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[climate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[literature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lord of the Rings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Napoleon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Old Major]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Soviet Union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Storytelling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vacation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[World War II]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dranilj1.wordpress.com/?p=5046</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The Psychology of Storytelling Stories are a very vital piece of being convincing. You’d feel that, as a guy who cares for inquiries and data, I’d be indisposed to storytelling in one piece. As a vendor though, I can’t be: those in sales and marketing have recognized for a long time that stories win against [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=5046&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_5048" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 1034px"><a href="http://dranilj1.wordpress.com/2012/07/29/the-psychological-power-of-storytelling/aphorodite011_2012-07-28_184558/" rel="attachment wp-att-5048"><img class="size-full wp-image-5048" title="The Psychological Power of Storytelling" src="http://dranilj1.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/aphorodite011_2012-07-28_184558.png" alt="The Psychological Power of Storytelling" width="1024" height="765" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The Psychological Power of <a class="zem_slink" title="Storytelling" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Storytelling" rel="wikipedia" target="_blank">Storytelling</a></p></div>
<p><span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
The Psychology of Storytelling<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
Stories are a very vital piece of being convincing.<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
You’d feel that, as a guy who cares for inquiries and data, I’d be indisposed to storytelling in one piece.<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
As a vendor though, I can’t be: those in sales and marketing have recognized for a long time that stories win against data when it comes to influencing for the reason that stories are easier to appreciate and tie in to.<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
Are you slotting in stories into your copy? Are you using them on your blog?<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
If you’re fretful to appreciate and tap into the influence of storytelling, get prepared to jot down some notes!<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
Why You Need to add in Storytelling<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
Storytelling works.<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
But why should you have to add in this flowery technique into your writing?<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
A bunch of folks are reluctant to telling stories because they think that “the specifics” are the most influential pieces of substance they can bring.<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
It’s not, and here’s a revelation that assists to clarify why:<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
Am I telling you that it’s better to say nothing in a brilliant style?<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
No, of course not In its place, the point that I’d pretty make is that how you say something is just as essential as what you are saying.<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
If you reject to recognize this, you menace having your excellent information become lost in an ocean of less precious substance.<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
Here’s the thing,: While we are all frequently opposed to the idea of being told what to do, we are very vulnerable to approving with the “moral of the story” due to how it is accessed to us.<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
How Stories have an effect on the Mind<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
It would be polite to be able to justly sway people into fitting more flattering about your contribution, right?<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
Of course!<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
The question then is this…<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
Do stories really hold that much sway?<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
According to research by psychologists Green &amp; Brock, they do.<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
In fact, it’s probable that you greatly underrate how much stories influence you!<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
The cause that stories click so well on us is that we are vulnerable to getting “swept up” in both their significance and in the way of their telling.<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
Quite literally, stories are able to transport our mind to another place, and in this place we may hug things we’d likely ridicule at in the “cruel, genuine world”.<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
Think about this example: You’ll often see politicians create a “story” for their campaign, and focus much of their efforts speaking with the public in crafting and footing by these stories.<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
Creating the story of “tough guy who is cruel on crime and supports states rights” is easier to appreciate than discussing the intricacy of how the administration plans to actually tackle the crime rate.<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
You see this being utilized every day on platforms as big as TED talks to speeches by world leaders.<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
Instead of only discussing the “information”, they begin talks with phrases like, “Imagine if you will…”, and as we’ve seen, it’s with very good reason: stories help sell arguments of all types, from, “I believe that these liberal/conservative points of view are correct,” to, “I believe this product is suited for my goals.”<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
This information is useless, however, unless we address how to write better stories.<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
How to Create Better Stories<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
The #1 trait of a persuasive story is how “engaging” the story is.<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
There are a million writing blogs that will go on and on about how to craft amazing stories, but is any of that (potentially good) advice backed up by research?<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
In fact, there is an additional study conducted by Green &amp; Brock that addresses just what makes a story engaging.<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
Here’s what they found:<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
1.) Suspense works just as well as you’d expect<br />
The “cliffhanger” just may be the oldest trick in the writing book, especially writing for television, but there is a reason why it’s used so often…<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
It works!<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
Despite our numerous exposure to this method, our brain just can’t “get over” suspenseful moments: it’s a relationship that just won’t die, we will always want to know what happens next!<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
In fact, suspense works so well that the hotly debated <a class="zem_slink" title="Suspense" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Suspense" rel="wikipedia" target="_blank">Zeigarnik Effect</a> would have you believe that it’s the best way to kill procrastination.<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
Research in that area seems to point to humans being much more inclined to finish something that has already been started (researchers interrupted people doing “brain buster” tasks before they could complete them… nearly 90% of people went on to finish the task anyway, despite being told they could stop).<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
Suspense in stories really allows you to create addictive content, as long as the suspense appears early enough in the post to activate the Zeigarnik Effect.<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
2) Creating detailed imagery helps craft the setting YOU want.<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
Want to get people swept up in your stories?<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
Tell them what they are receiving swept up in to, and they will respond.<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
Could any of us relate to the heroic deeds in tales like those of the <a class="zem_slink" title="The Lord of the Rings" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Lord_of_the_Rings" rel="wikipedia" target="_blank">Lord of the Rings</a> without <a class="zem_slink" title="J.R.R. Tolkien" href="http://www.last.fm/music/J.R.R.%2BTolkien" rel="lastfm" target="_blank">Tolkien</a>’s elegantly comprehensive imagery of the dangers of Mordor or the perils faced by Frodo and Sam?<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
The imagery paints the picture of any good story, we could say that [Spoilers if you haven't read/seen Lord of the Rings] “Frodo and Sam fight a massive spider,” but Tolkien spends an entire chapter on the ordeal, taking the time to help the reader picture, the fierce character of the enemy and the bravery of our heroes who persevere despite their many weaknesses (doubt, fear, dismay, etc.)<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
Implementing the “real” into a fantastic setting often helps create a better connection with the reader.<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
I don’t know the feeling of encounter a spider the size of a house, but I do know what terror feels like, and I also know how hard it can be to persevere in the face of immense doubt of your abilities.<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
These “all-too-real” elements of a fantastical story make it easier to relate to.<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
3.) Literary techniques (like metaphors or irony) are essential pieces of memorable stories<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
As with most high school kids in the <a class="zem_slink" title="United States" href="http://maps.google.com/maps?ll=38.8833333333,-77.0166666667&amp;spn=10.0,10.0&amp;q=38.8833333333,-77.0166666667 (United%20States)&amp;t=h" rel="geolocation" target="_blank">United States</a>, I was required to read a lot of the “staples” of high ch1ld literature.<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
By far my favorite work was <a class="zem_slink" title="Animal Farm: Centennial Edition" href="http://www.amazon.com/Animal-Farm-Centennial-George-Orwell/dp/0452284244%3FSubscriptionId%3D0G81C5DAZ03ZR9WH9X82%26tag%3Dzemanta-20%26linkCode%3Dxm2%26camp%3D2025%26creative%3D165953%26creativeASIN%3D0452284244" rel="amazon" target="_blank">Animal Farm</a>, a story that serves as a great example of the power of the many literary techniques at your disposal.<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
In the beginning, the story in Animal Farm seems quirky at best: When the de-facto leader of the animals, <a class="zem_slink" title="Old Major" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Old_Major" rel="wikipedia" target="_blank">Old Major</a>, dies, two pigs called Snowball and <a class="zem_slink" title="Napoleon" href="http://www.biography.com/people/napoleon-9420291" rel="biographycom" target="_blank">Napoleon</a> take over and see out his “vision”, which they interpret to be the driving out of Mr. Jones, the farm owner.<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
Snowball is eventually chased away by Napoleon, and Napoleon begins to enact new rules for the Animal Farm, which begin to become warped as Napoleon and the pigs become more like their previous masters, culminating with the memorable phrase revealing what the rules have truly become:<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
All animals are equal, but some animals are more equal than others.<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
Needless to say, there is a lot at work under the surface of this story, as it is a metaphorical tale that relates the events of the rise of Stalin and the <a class="zem_slink" title="Soviet Union" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Soviet_Union" rel="wikipedia" target="_blank">Soviet Union</a> before the second <a class="zem_slink" title="World War II" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/World_War_II" rel="wikipedia" target="_blank">World War II</a>.<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
Suddenly, a book about pigs taking over a farm begins to serve as a cautionary tale on how political dogma can be turned into malleable propaganda.<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
There are many literary techniques and a countless amount of examples, I’m simply serving up this particular one to show you a singular instance of a writer using them to turn a seemingly simplistic story into a extraordinarily memorable and highly controversial work of art.<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
4.) Modeling works because change is easier with an example<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
If you want someone to change a conduct (or become more inclined to taking a desired action), then you can “model” it with a story.<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
The character in said story should go through the transformation that you would like the reader to go through.<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
The transportation effect is really evident here: people place themselves in the situation being told, reimagining themselves as the main character.<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
Oftentimes, they are made to see why the choices made were the right choices.<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
Strangely enough (or maybe it’s not so strange…), I often see web hosting providers showcase stories of customers past “cheap web-hosting nightmares” in which the customer describes a situation where they were freaking out from their site being down after receiving massive exposure, eventually “learning their lesson” and vowing to never again use anything but ______ [insert whoever is selling.<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
Positive stories are also used quite often, stories where individuals solve a huge menace in their life or get to where most people would like to be serve as transportation vehicles to recruiting new people to the cause.<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
If you run a fitness based business (as an example), highlighting a tale of triumph over the generalized disadvantages of being out-of-shape to accomplish what previously seemed like “impossible” fitness results is a great way to get people fired up up to become more interested in fitness.<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
6 ) Characteristics of Highly Influential Stories<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
Now, a post on Sparring Mind wouldn’t be complete without an additional study to compare things to (reliable information is the result of approving research).<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
I really enjoyed a recent investigation (and the actual research) discussed in a piece by Roger Dooley, author of Brainfluence (great book, that’s my aff link).<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
Dooley discusses what a difficult time lawyers have in influenced the jury during a tough case and the comparison he makes to your typical “car salesman” is spot on:<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
One of the difficulties of persuasion tasks is convincing a jury in a courtroom.<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
Car salespeople have it easy by comparison – they control the environment and have the complete concentration of the customer.<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
Envisage, if you were in a Lexus showroom listening to why you should buy one of their vehicles, and at your elbow was a BMW salesperson, once in a while objecting to the Lexus pitch and then delivering her own.<br />
<span style="color:#0b8fd0;font-family:'Bookman Old Style';font-size:medium;"><br />
That’s the condition of affairs in a courtroom–arguments presented by one side will be directly (and mercilessly) attacked by the other side.</span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></span></p>
<h6 class="zemanta-related-title" style="font-size:1em;">Related articles</h6>
<ul class="zemanta-article-ul">
<li class="zemanta-article-ul-li"><a href="http://lisagobrien.com/2012/07/12/story-telling/" target="_blank">Story Telling</a> (lisagobrien.com)</li>
<li class="zemanta-article-ul-li"><a href="http://blog.800ceoread.com/2012/07/24/become-a-storyteller-be-a-better-leader/" target="_blank">Become a Storyteller: Be a Better Leader</a> (800ceoread.com)</li>
<li class="zemanta-article-ul-li"><a href="http://gracewolbrink.wordpress.com/2012/07/26/improving-your-storytelling-beyond-the-basics-for-all-who-tell-stories-in-work-and-play/" target="_blank">Improving Your Storytelling Beyond the Basics for All Who Tell Stories in Work and Play</a> (gracewolbrink.wordpress.com)</li>
<li class="zemanta-article-ul-li"><a href="http://mythginger.com/2012/06/26/the-storytelling-animal/" target="_blank">The Storytelling Animal</a> (mythginger.com)</li>
<li class="zemanta-article-ul-li"><a href="http://billives.typepad.com/portals_and_km/2012/05/the-power-of-business-storytelling-firing-up-the-imagination.html" target="_blank">The Power Of Business Storytelling &#8211; Firing up the Imagination</a> (billives.typepad.com)</li>
<li class="zemanta-article-ul-li"><a href="http://johnheenan.typepad.com/adblogging/2012/06/the-worlds-foremost-authorities-on-marketing-how-to-use-storytelling-techniques-to-advance-a-marketi.html" target="_blank">The World&#8217;s Foremost Authorities On Marketing: How to Use Storytelling Techniques to Advance a Marketing Campaign</a> (johnheenan.typepad.com)</li>
<li class="zemanta-article-ul-li"><a href="http://erronis.nl/2012/07/23/storytelling-cheat-sheet/" target="_blank">Storytelling Cheat Sheet</a> (erronis.nl)</li>
<li class="zemanta-article-ul-li"><a href="http://elakkiya.com/2012/06/05/storytelling-part-i/" target="_blank">Storytelling &#8211; Part I</a> (elakkiya.com)</li>
<li class="zemanta-article-ul-li"><a href="http://catherinekaputa.typepad.com/art-of-branding/2012/07/the-persuasive-power-of-story.html" target="_blank">The Persuasive Power of Story</a> (catherinekaputa.typepad.com)</li>
<li class="zemanta-article-ul-li"><a href="http://addictivestory.wordpress.com/2012/07/18/guest-post-writing-vs-storytelling-whats-the-difference/" target="_blank">Guest Post: Writing vs. Storytelling &#8211; What&#8217;s the Difference?</a> (addictivestory.wordpress.com)</li>
<li class="zemanta-article-ul-li"><a href="http://c4ss.org/content/11108" target="_blank">Four Legs Good, Two Legs Bad</a> (c4ss.org)</li>
<li class="zemanta-article-ul-li"><a href="http://mombloggersforsocialgood.com/2012/07/16/using-your-storytelling-powers-for-good-session-at-evo/" target="_blank">Using Your Storytelling Powers for Good Session at EVO</a> (mombloggersforsocialgood.com)</li>
<li class="zemanta-article-ul-li"><a href="http://www.ishmaelscorner.com/2012/05/29/words-can-shred-one-storyteller-to-another/" target="_blank">Words Can Shred: One Storyteller To Another</a> (ishmaelscorner.com)</li>
</ul>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://dranilj1.wordpress.com/category/art/'>Art</a> Tagged: <a href='http://dranilj1.wordpress.com/tag/animal-farm/'>Animal Farm</a>, <a href='http://dranilj1.wordpress.com/tag/climate/'>climate</a>, <a href='http://dranilj1.wordpress.com/tag/gaming/'>gaming</a>, <a href='http://dranilj1.wordpress.com/tag/literature/'>literature</a>, <a href='http://dranilj1.wordpress.com/tag/lord-of-the-rings/'>Lord of the Rings</a>, <a href='http://dranilj1.wordpress.com/tag/napoleon/'>Napoleon</a>, <a href='http://dranilj1.wordpress.com/tag/old-major/'>Old Major</a>, <a href='http://dranilj1.wordpress.com/tag/science/'>science</a>, <a href='http://dranilj1.wordpress.com/tag/soviet-union/'>Soviet Union</a>, <a href='http://dranilj1.wordpress.com/tag/storytelling/'>Storytelling</a>, <a href='http://dranilj1.wordpress.com/tag/travel/'>Travel</a>, <a href='http://dranilj1.wordpress.com/tag/united-states/'>United States</a>, <a href='http://dranilj1.wordpress.com/tag/vacation/'>vacation</a>, <a href='http://dranilj1.wordpress.com/tag/world-war-ii/'>World War II</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5046/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5046/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5046/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5046/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5046/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5046/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5046/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5046/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5046/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5046/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5046/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5046/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5046/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5046/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=5046&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://dranilj1.wordpress.com/2012/07/29/the-psychological-power-of-storytelling/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/3a4493bd18e3e70b20f7af135b8c6a5b?s=96&#38;d=&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">nishanil</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dranilj1.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/aphorodite011_2012-07-28_184558.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The Psychological Power of Storytelling</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Drugs in Gaming</title>
		<link>http://ninetyninepercentgaming.wordpress.com/2012/07/29/drugs-in-gaming/</link>
		<comments>http://ninetyninepercentgaming.wordpress.com/2012/07/29/drugs-in-gaming/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2012 13:20:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>ninetyninepercentgaming</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Opinions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[3]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bioshock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drugs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fallout]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opinion]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ninetyninepercentgaming.wordpress.com/?p=210</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A look into the treatment drug-like substances are given in video games. Drugs in games don&#8217;t work like their real-life counterparts. Often all they do is augment the player character, giving special powers or increased abilities. Often these substances are marketed as &#8220;power-ups&#8221;, however there is one mainstream series that doesn&#8217;t mask it&#8217;s intentions when [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=210&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter" src="http://www.slashgamer.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/10/bioshock2doll.jpg" alt="" width="516" height="304" /></p>
<p><strong>A look into the treatment drug-like substances are given in video games.</strong></p>
<p><strong><span id="more-210"></span></strong></p>
<p>Drugs in games don&#8217;t work like their real-life counterparts. Often all they do is augment the player character, giving special powers or increased abilities. Often these substances are marketed as &#8220;power-ups&#8221;, however there is one mainstream series that doesn&#8217;t mask it&#8217;s intentions when it comes to using drugs.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>Bioshock: ADAM</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><img class="alignleft" src="http://images.wikia.com/bioshock/es/images/0/09/EVE_hypo.jpg" alt="" width="361" height="262" /></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">  The series Bioshock are revolutionary games, treating the player to unique and amazing locales, as well as a gripping mythos. The series never shied away from delicate issues, reveling in violence and bloodthirsty children, but it is the series portrayal of the drug ADAM that is perhaps the most controversial.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">The wonder drug utilizes blank D.N.A to mold and create super powers and enhancements to the users body. Scattered throughout the sunken city of Rapture, ADAM is found in hypodermic syringes. These Hypo&#8217;s are graphically injected into the veins of your character&#8217;s forearm. This blunt, horrifically realistic portrayal of drug use is mysteriously offset by it&#8217;s lack of impact. Sure, your character gains the use of lightning, or can throw a fireball, but there is no indication of any sort of addiction as a result of these self injections.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">This anomaly is made even more mysterious by the twisted inhabitants of Rapture known as Splicers. These residents were twisted and mutated by their extensive abuse of the drug. It&#8217;s overuse contributed to the downfall of the City, and yet your character seems completely immune to it&#8217;s addictive nature. All this does is tell the gamer while the drug will destroy other people&#8217;s lives, they needn&#8217;t worry about it themselves. This is a poor treatment regarding the addictive aspect of drugs in games. There is another game that deals with this subject in a more realistic manner. And that Game is Fallout 3.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>Fallout 3: Chems</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><img src="http://fallout3.nexusmods.com/mods/images/15960-1-1301611678.jpg" alt="" width="561" height="421" /></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Drugs are a large part of the post apocalyptic wasteland. (For a review of Fallout 3, click <a href="http://ninetyninepercentgaming.wordpress.com/2012/07/26/review-fallout-3/#more-3" target="_blank"><span style="color:#0000ff;">here</span></a>). In such a grim and hopeless setting, the inhabitants of the Capital Wasteland often turn to chems, meds, stimulants and drugs to escape. Your character is no different, and can utilize a variety of IV-like fluids as well as syringes and pills to augment both mind and body, as well as to flush his body of unwanted radiation and poisons.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Substances like the inhaler Jet and the pill Mentat are addictive, and repeated use over a short period of time will cause the player character to become hooked on the drug. Without then using the drug, the player will experience periods of disorientation and dizziness. Their overall ability will suffer and all their stats will drop. It is an effective way of portraying the negative aspect of substances. Alas, one drug is not treated the same way as the others. It also happens to be the most crucial one.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://www.fallout3.net/obrazki/f3_ekwipunek/stimpak.jpg" alt="" width="496" height="372" /></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">A stimpak is effectively post-apocalypse morphine. A hypodermic syringe which restores health to the player, This drug can be used infinitely with no negative effects. This is in complete contrast to the other substances in the game. While fixed in Fallout New Vegas, the decision to omit Stimpaks from the addictive substance list highlights the worlds regard of painkilling drugs against recreational drugs.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>Conclusion</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><img src="http://ninetyninepercentgaming.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/mariomushroom.jpg?w=510&h=329" alt="" width="510" height="329" /></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">drugs have an unquestionable presence in video games. They come in a variety of shapes, forms and potency. They&#8217;re often mistreated and misused, but recent games have started treating them with the respect and fear they warrant. Every year, the video game industry improves and furthers itself to maturely deal with controversial topics such as these, and this fellow gamers, is a good thing.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">                                                                                                                                                                                                                           -Michael</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/210/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/210/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=210&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://ninetyninepercentgaming.wordpress.com/2012/07/29/drugs-in-gaming/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/9e5f29fafeeb3c0a3dc201c7b0a404c9?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ninetyninepercentgaming</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://www.slashgamer.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/10/bioshock2doll.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://images.wikia.com/bioshock/es/images/0/09/EVE_hypo.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://fallout3.nexusmods.com/mods/images/15960-1-1301611678.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://www.fallout3.net/obrazki/f3_ekwipunek/stimpak.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://ninetyninepercentgaming.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/mariomushroom.jpg?w=300" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Greatest Moment in Film History: 2000-2012 or Subtlety is a Dying Art</title>
		<link>http://bertbranson.wordpress.com/2012/07/29/greatest-moment-in-film-history-2000-2012-or-subtlety-is-a-dying-art/</link>
		<comments>http://bertbranson.wordpress.com/2012/07/29/greatest-moment-in-film-history-2000-2012-or-subtlety-is-a-dying-art/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2012 06:43:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bert Branson</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[action]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bane]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Batman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christopher nolan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cinema]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[death]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[great moments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[subtlety]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the dark knight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the dark knight rises]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://bertbranson.wordpress.com/?p=159</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Today, I have renewed faith in cinema&#8230;    A great moment can pass you by if you&#8217;re not paying attention. If you&#8217;re so busy waiting for something epic or magnificent to happen, you may miss something far more moving and ten-fold more important. This morning, I&#8217;m going to talk about something that was in a [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=159&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Today, I have renewed faith in cinema&#8230;</strong></p>
<p>   A great moment can pass you by if you&#8217;re not paying attention. If you&#8217;re so busy waiting for something epic or magnificent to happen, you may miss something far more moving and ten-fold more important. This morning, I&#8217;m going to talk about something that was in a recent film and is <u><strong>THE</strong></u> most important and vital moment in film history for the last twelve years.</p>
<p>   It&#8217;s got to be from a foreign film right? Wrong. It&#8217;s from an established American director responsible for two, soon to be three, of the highest grossing films in history. Well, it had to be Spielberg or Scorsese or Coppola right. Wrong again. It&#8217;s Christopher Nolan&#8211;famous for the Batman re-crafting and &#8220;<strong>Memento</strong>&#8220;. What, pray tell, is this magical moment? What movie is it from? Tell us Bert! Please tell us!</p>
<p>   Here is the most important and powerful moment in film history since the start of the new millennium and most folks missed it:</p>
<p>   <strong>In &#8220;Batman: Rise of the Dark Knight&#8221;, Daggett is berating Bane for not fulfilling his end of the deal. Bane then does something that chills my blood&#8230;</strong></p>
<p><strong><em>He softly places the knife edge of his left hand quietly on Daggett&#8217;s shoulder.</em></strong></p>
<p>   Bane said nothing yet his action spoke volumes. A lesser director might have had the villain rip his heart out or something clumsy and cliched like that. Nolan chose something far more frightening and sinister.  Something that is unmistakably powerful and brutal, yet subtle and delicate&#8211;icy and cruel. You knew instantly Daggett had stepped over an invisible line and the Devil himself was waiting past that threshold.</p>
<p>   </p>
<p><img title="tumblr_m7up9mWtPx1qadcdio1_1280.png" class="alignnone" alt="image" src="http://bertbranson.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/wpid-tumblr_m7up9mwtpx1qadcdio1_1280.png" /></p>
<p>   I feel this moment ranks up there with that horrible, empty stare Hannibal Lecter gives agent Starling at their first meeting. It&#8217;s the end of &#8220;<strong>The Usual Suspects</strong>&#8221; or Samuel L. Jackson&#8217;s speech in the diner from &#8220;<strong>Pulp Fiction</strong>&#8220;. It&#8217;s an amazing moment in cinema history, and Bert said it first.</p>
<p><span class="post_sig">Posted from somewhere deep within my anger pit&#8230;</span></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/159/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/159/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=159&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://bertbranson.wordpress.com/2012/07/29/greatest-moment-in-film-history-2000-2012-or-subtlety-is-a-dying-art/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f2a7ad28f000d5148ad880372b9553f0?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bertbranson</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://bertbranson.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/wpid-tumblr_m7up9mwtpx1qadcdio1_1280.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tumblr_m7up9mWtPx1qadcdio1_1280.png</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Don&#8217;t Write That!!!!!</title>
		<link>http://nightmirrors.wordpress.com/2012/07/27/dont-write-that/</link>
		<comments>http://nightmirrors.wordpress.com/2012/07/27/dont-write-that/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2012 18:21:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Raymond</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Great Horror & Suspense Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Night Watch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[horror]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[literature]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nightmirrors.wordpress.com/?p=310</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Horror fans, be it books or films, are some of the most difficult people to please. Most “non-horror” folks rely on misconceived perceptions of the genre to shelve it under, “I don’t like all that blood and guts stuff.” Which is what horror is and which, of course, is what horror is not. The challenge [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=310&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://nightmirrors.wordpress.com/2012/07/27/dont-write-that/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/6cc2cfd0a787953657b35eda16d46fd0?s=96&#38;d=monsterid&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">raymondesposito</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nightmirrors.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/pumpkin-light-radiant-horror.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">pumpkin-light-radiant-horror</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>My Blog Audience</title>
		<link>http://bottledworder.wordpress.com/2012/07/25/my-blog-audience/</link>
		<comments>http://bottledworder.wordpress.com/2012/07/25/my-blog-audience/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2012 01:44:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bottledworder</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[audience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[genre]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[globalization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[literature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing process]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://bottledworder.wordpress.com/?p=1761</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Perhaps it&#8217;s because I&#8217;m still new to blogging that I haven&#8217;t lost the sense of wonder yet. It&#8217;s summer here and things are kind of nice late at night. I was sitting at my computer in a room with a big glass window. The city skyline was spread out in front of me glittering like [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1761&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Perhaps it&#8217;s because I&#8217;m still new to blogging that I haven&#8217;t lost the sense of wonder yet. It&#8217;s summer here and things are kind of nice late at night.</p>
<p>I was sitting at my computer in a room with a big glass window. The city skyline was spread out in front of me glittering like a long necklace across the empty river.<br />
<span id="more-1761"></span></p>
<p>I was reading a blog on a topic similar to one I&#8217;d written the previous week&#8211;<span style="color:#0000ff;"><a title="Cafes and the city" href="http://bottledworder.wordpress.com/2012/07/17/cafes-and-the-city/"><span style="color:#0000ff;">Cafes and the city</span></a></span>. I suggested to a fellow blogger (who had said he couldn&#8217;t work in cafes because he found them noisy) that he could sit in the park and write if he felt disturbed working in cafes so much.</p>
<p>Summer. Empty benches. Park. It all came so naturally to me.</p>
<p>Then his reply came. He would if he could. He was in the middle of the &#8220;deep darkness of winter&#8221;.</p>
<p>I had a sudden change of perspective. A snowy park. No leaves on trees. Bitter cold. Moonlight shining blue on the snow at this very moment I had my finger on the typewriter. Some winter wonderland at night.</p>
<p>Then he wrote again. He said he was in the library.</p>
<p>Shift in perspective. Library? What kind of library?</p>
<p>Perhaps a library in a very cold place with small windows and wooden panels and very old, ancient books and an even older librarian in monocles. People shaking the snow off their boots as they entered.</p>
<p>No. I didn&#8217;t seriously think <em>that</em> but imagination did wander. And when imagination wanders, it tends to think of the person at the other end as the opposite of everything you are. With the small adjustment of a modern computer and keyboard hidden somewhere in that scenario so it won&#8217;t jar with the image.</p>
<p>Yesterday, another blogger asked if I was Canadian. I can&#8217;t think why but I did go over the details I&#8217;d mentioned in my blog to check what could make him think that. His imagination also must have wandered. He&#8217;s either Canadian himself and felt some camaraderie with me or the opposite of Canadian (whatever that is) and thought I was for some reason.</p>
<p>Blogging. It makes the world unfold in strange ways and makes different worlds intersect.</p>
<p>There are others I&#8217;ve interacted with. I read a blog last week by a mommy who was writing as her kids were dangerously balancing themselves on the window sill playing a game. A commenter same day liked my blog. I found her profile said she was a reverend. A chef at a restaurant wanted some feedback on his writing in the comments section. Someone somewhere had found my blog searching for &#8220;business suits for dogs&#8221; (can&#8217;t think why anyone would look for that&#8211;they were the Google search terms on my stats page). He&#8217;d come up with my <a title="It’s a dog’s life" href="http://bottledworder.wordpress.com/2012/05/25/its-a-dogs-life/">It&#8217;s a Dog&#8217;s Life</a>.</p>
<p>People I would never have exchanged writing and reading with in my regular life.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s been a strange experience seeing the views of the blog by country unfold one by one. For me, at first it&#8217;s usually the US. Then it slowly shows the UK, then Canada and then a lot of other countries unfold. I know that all of that is not necessarily accurate since there could be many countries that use proxy servers in other locations. My technical knowledge is not strong enough to understand how but that only deepens the romance.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s many countries I&#8217;ve seen and many I haven&#8217;t. As I sit at my desk here, I imagine someone in a three wheeler auto rickshaw in Kolkata half sitting, half hanging out of the front seat next to the driver, deftly manoeuvring his knees and hands through the rush hour traffic so neighbouring cars don&#8217;t hit him, taking a glance at my blog on his smart phone screen. I see a high-level executive on the back seat of his car in Mumbai interrupted while reading the blog as he yells at the driver to overtake the car in front. I see a bored student in Lexington, Kentucky, looking up from his Calculus worksheet during his late night dinner at Chipotle  looking over the pictures on my blog as he waits for his study group to arrive. I see people in London, in Toronto, in innumerable other places.</p>
<p>Then there&#8217;s many places I&#8217;ve never seen. They are fixed in my mind like still paintings before I have to shake myself off from my reverie. A rice farmer in a paddy field in Indonesia. Folks in pointy hats next to unloading ships in Singapore (this must be from some British Victorian sketches I&#8217;d seen somewhere), a woman in traditional dress at a tea ceremony in Japan (that&#8217;s probably from the package of an expensive brand of tea I bought from an upscale grocery store), a man with a big animal standing next to a tree in Botswana. . .</p>
<p>Of course, rationally, I know these are not the people reading my blog. Many don&#8217;t exist at all outside my stereotypical imagination. These are only personifications of my ignorance thrust upon those statistical numbers.</p>
<p>But somehow I was writing for them. I was writing for the guy standing next to the loading docks in Singapore telling him what the dogs were like in New York. I was telling the guy in the auto rickshaw what cafes looked like in New York in case he liked to have a look and ever wanted to come. I knew those people who were in university libraries in the US (or the UK, or Canada) would know immediately what I was talking about when I mentioned libraries that had ceilings three stories high, escalators  and walls of glass. What study groups were. But there would be many who wouldn&#8217;t know.</p>
<p>I was wrong. Perhaps the guy  in Singapore has libraries with better escalators and newer glass than the ones I saw here. Perhaps the guy in Kolkata was going to his study group meeting that day. He had seen more places in the world than I ever did. Perhaps you, who are reading this now, have ridden innumerable auto rickshaws and didn&#8217;t need that scene painted so vividly and thought it was a redundant detail.</p>
<p>Who am I writing for? Do I even know my audience?</p>
<p>One day I had a comment from a woman in New York. She was fascinated by my blog on cafes. She worked in direct marketing, lived in New York, but had never been to a cafe. She was very happy with me for having painted a picture for her about life in a cafe, so to speak.</p>
<p>I was surprised. I never realized that people who were so near could also be far. There were many who had never dropped in ever into the realm of my experience and needed the details.</p>
<p>Then again, being on the internet makes one think one has the world in one&#8217;s hand. A blue ball that fits in nicely into the palm of your hand that you can speak to. That it&#8217;s patiently listening.</p>
<p>There are so many spots on the map on the stats page always dark for me. In my case, it&#8217;s most of Africa and South America and a big part of Asia.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve been thinking of the blog as a great genre for conversation. But as far as those parts are concerned, I&#8217;ve been talking to myself while they, certainly, have been talking to themselves. In a language that&#8217;s not English. In a medium that doesn&#8217;t involve a keyboard and a screen. In a voice that does not require writing.</p>
<p>Or perhaps my concerns are far away from anything they are concerned about. Or ever were. Or ever should be. Or perhaps they just think I&#8217;m boring.</p>
<p>Even the people from the parts that are highlighted are probably mostly people like me, who can and like putting ideas in sentence, sentences into paragraphs, paragraphs into grammatically consistent wholes, putting ideas out there by being able and willing to click a box and compose a blog.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s a very small percentage of the world, I&#8217;m sure.</p>
<p>I wonder who my audience is and who isn&#8217;t. Guess I&#8217;ll never know.</p>
<p><a class="aligncenter zemanta-img" href="http://commons.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:SennMicrophone.jpg" target="_blank"><img class="zemanta-img-inserted zemanta-img-configured aligncenter" title="English: A Sennheiser Microphone" src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/9/91/SennMicrophone.jpg/300px-SennMicrophone.jpg" alt="English: A Sennheiser Microphone" width="300" height="201" /></a></p>
<p>[For those who are waiting for The Writer (Part 3) after <span style="color:#0000ff;"><a title="The Writer (Part 1)" href="http://bottledworder.wordpress.com/2012/07/22/the-writer-part-1/"><span style="color:#0000ff;">The Writer (Part 1)</span></a></span> and <span style="color:#0000ff;"><a title="The Writer (Part 2)" href="http://bottledworder.wordpress.com/2012/07/23/the-writer-part-2/"><span style="color:#0000ff;">The Writer (Part 2)</span></a></span>: It's coming. Have to get back into the funny mood before I return to that.]</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1761/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1761/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1761&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://bottledworder.wordpress.com/2012/07/25/my-blog-audience/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>70</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/93a27b5a03ea73d11e2eb796bca379a6?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bottledworder</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/9/91/SennMicrophone.jpg/300px-SennMicrophone.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">English: A Sennheiser Microphone</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Olympics are Fabulous (Sometimes)</title>
		<link>http://juliahass.wordpress.com/2012/07/28/the-olympics-are-fabulous-sometimes/</link>
		<comments>http://juliahass.wordpress.com/2012/07/28/the-olympics-are-fabulous-sometimes/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2012 03:52:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Julia</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Fashion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[london olympics 2012]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[olympics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[olympics 2012]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[olympics fashion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parade of nations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parade of nations 2012]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://juliahass.wordpress.com/?p=1009</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In case my excessive tweeting hadn&#8217;t tipped anyone off, I fucking love the Olympics. Love them. I spent the entire afternoon enraptured by fencing. (And looking up lessons, because nothing says &#8220;good idea&#8221; like me and sharp objects, am I right?) I also love making bitchy, sarcastic commentary on things I probably have no business [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1009&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In case my <a href="https://twitter.com/JuliaHass">excessive tweeting</a> hadn&#8217;t tipped anyone off, I fucking <em>love</em> the Olympics. Love them. I spent the entire afternoon enraptured by fencing. (And looking up lessons, because nothing says &#8220;good idea&#8221; like me and sharp objects, am I right?) I also love making bitchy, sarcastic commentary on things I probably have no business critiquing, and because I was bored today, I decided what better to do than semi-belatedly (and only on the internet can &#8220;24 hours after&#8221; be considered &#8220;belated&#8221;) critique the fashion from the Parade of Nations? That&#8217;s right. Nothing could be better. After all, coming together as a world to mock countries that aren&#8217;t ours is what the Olympics are really about.</p>
<p><span id="more-1009"></span></p>
<p><a href="http://juliahass.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/parade001.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1010" title="parade001" src="http://juliahass.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/parade001.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="357" /></a></p>
<p>I think Belgium might have been my favorite out of the entire parade. It peaked super early. But they illustrate an excellent point &#8211; always go preppy. Not airline-preppy, prep-school preppy. Gosh, you look adorable, Belgium. Snaps.</p>
<p><a href="http://juliahass.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/parade002.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1011" title="parade002" src="http://juliahass.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/parade002.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="358" /></a>How quickly you sour, Olympic fashion. A lot of people thought this was a tribute to the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gumbys">Monty Python Gumbys sketch,</a> like this excuses bright blue rain boots and spandex that makes the baby Jesus weep. First of all, if they <em>were</em> doing a tribute, they needed to go whole-hog and have those weird tied kerchiefs on their head. And furthermore, while I understand wanting to pay tribute to your host nation, this is what you chose, Czech Republic? Really? The United Kingdom has a rich cultural history, not to mention fashion history, and you were not inspired by any of that, but a sketch about a group of morons whose catchphrase is &#8220;my brain hurts&#8221;, that&#8217;s where you found your muse!</p>
<p>Look at your life, Czech Republic. Look at your choices.</p>
<p><a href="http://juliahass.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/parade003.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1013" title="parade003" src="http://juliahass.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/parade003.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="336" /></a>You know those Hot and Cold thermal bags that look like they&#8217;re made of crinkly tinfoil? Apparently, Estonia does, because it looks like their jackets were part of a Project Runway challenge where they had to re-purpose things they found in a Target. Though I do give them props for their clear commitment to recycling.</p>
<p><a href="http://juliahass.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/parade004.jpg"><img title="2012 Olympic Games - Opening Ceremony" src="http://juliahass.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/parade004.jpg?w=500&h=333" alt="" width="500" height="333" /></a>One of my best friends, Teija, (who, incidentally, is from Finland) is getting married. One day we were discussing how the sudden influx of wedding-related e-mails meant that the sidebar ads were taking a turn for the strange. The ad we spent the most time boggling over was one for this service called <a href="http://www.loveisartkit.com/">Love Is Art</a>, which supplies body paint that you and your partner cover yourself in, then you lay out a canvas, and then you, well. You know. Get down to business.</p>
<p>Because of Teija, I always pay special attention to how Finland does in the Olympics. And literally the first thing I thought was &#8220;oh my god, the pattern is from the Love Is Art people! Teija is going to die!&#8221; But no, no, it&#8217;s apparently some sort of Finnish landscape. The motto of these uniforms seems to be &#8220;Finland, where everything is so bleak our landscape gets confused for paint splatters&#8221;.</p>
<p><a href="http://juliahass.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/parade005.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1014" title="parade005" src="http://juliahass.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/parade005.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="429" /></a>This is by far the outfit that upset my mother the most. Not just because she&#8217;s always hated the pink is for girls, blue is for boys thing, either. &#8220;Those aren&#8217;t Germany&#8217;s colors,&#8221; she kept repeating. &#8220;THOSE AREN&#8217;T GERMANY&#8217;S COLORS.&#8221; And then I had to hold back a really terrible pun about &#8220;would you say this is <em>Anarchy in the UK</em>?!&#8221; Mostly because I knew she wouldn&#8217;t get the reference.</p>
<p>Though we both agreed the scarves were nice.</p>
<p><a href="http://juliahass.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/parade007.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1015" title="parade007" src="http://juliahass.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/parade007.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="362" /></a>India&#8217;s such a jerk. They have the prettiest native costume and they know it. &#8220;I hope your serape comforts you while you <em>suck it</em>, Mexico,&#8221; they cackle. They&#8217;re the worst. By which I mean they&#8217;re the best. They&#8217;re like the Chinese gymnastic team in Olympics of ethnic costumes. And they know they&#8217;ve got looking the fliest on lockdown until the Japanese get the balls to come out in full-on kimonos.</p>
<p>Goddammit, India.</p>
<p><a href="http://juliahass.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/parade009.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1016" title="South Korea's flagbearer Yoon Kyung Shin" src="http://juliahass.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/parade009.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="332" /></a>A lot of countries tried to pull off the hats, and a <em>lot</em> of countries failed. And if you&#8217;d polled me about which countries could totally pull off fedoras and white pleated pants, I&#8217;m not gonna lie, South Korea would not be on my list. But dudes, they look baller. I like to imagine that they dressed so well because the Olympic opening ceremonies are like going to a wedding when you know your crazy ex is going to be there. &#8220;Why yes, North Korea,&#8221; these outfits say, &#8220;I&#8217;m leading a satisfying and fulfilled life <em>without</em> your totalitarian dictatorship. Also, lately I&#8217;ve been trying a diet rich in antioxidants, and I feel like it&#8217;s really working for me.&#8221;</p>
<p><a href="http://juliahass.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/parade010.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1017" title="parade010" src="http://juliahass.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/parade010.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="292" /></a>My mom actually clocked out somewhere in the J&#8217;s or K&#8217;s to check her e-mail and go to bed. She was literally on the first step and going upstairs with her fudgicle when Mexico came on and I screamed for her to come see and mock with me. Look, I can stand by crazy color, and I realize that Mexico is far more liberal with the neons than my staunchly New Englander soul is comfortable with. But for the love of God, at least all wear coordinating color, and <em>do not edge your ponchos with faux fur</em><em> in neon green or orange</em>. I mean I&#8217;m against faux fur in general, but if you&#8217;re going to do it, do it for the winter games, and do it in a natural color. Right now it just looks like the entire Mexico contingent raped and pillaged Sesame Street on the way to the ceremony.</p>
<p><a href="http://juliahass.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/parade011.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1018" title="Members of Nigeria's contingent wave as they take part in the athletes parade during the opening ceremony of the London 2012 Olympic Games at the Olympic Stadium" src="http://juliahass.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/parade011.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="376" /></a>Overall, Africa just destroyed everyone in this parade, though. It&#8217;s like they had a continent-wide conference where they were like &#8220;Guys, I know we lose in literacy rates, infant mortality, and we&#8217;re kind of going through some issues with brutal dictatorships and genocides, but dammit, we&#8217;re really pretty!&#8221; and then decided to run with that as their theme. And man, they served up some gorgeous, fierce women. Look at these delegates from Nigeria, working it like these Olympics owe them rent money.</p>
<p><a href="http://juliahass.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/parade011_oman.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1019" title="parade011_oman" src="http://juliahass.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/parade011_oman.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="773" /></a>This look from Oman (fine, technically in Asia) makes me want to be RuPaul so I can comment on in appropriately with phrases like &#8220;SERVING UP 1000 ARABIAN NIGHTS OF FIERCENESS&#8221; and &#8220;GENIE, RUB MY LAMP&#8221; and some pun about queens that I&#8217;m sure I could make if only I did drag. See? I need help from experts on this. Also, if I&#8217;m heterosexual, white, and biologically female can I get away with snapping in Z formation and saying &#8220;girl, you betta werk&#8221;? If the answer is yes, that&#8217;s what I&#8217;m doing. If the answer is no, I was asking for a hypothetical friend.</p>
<p><a href="http://juliahass.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/parade011_saudiarabia.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1020" title="parade011_saudiarabia" src="http://juliahass.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/parade011_saudiarabia.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="353" /></a>This is not a picture about fashion, by the way, this is taking  break to cheer for the first female athletes repping Saudi Arabia. They could be wearing potato sacks, for all I care. Feminism five! Go get &#8216;em, ladies.</p>
<p><a href="http://juliahass.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/parade011_serbia.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1021" title="parade011_serbia" src="http://juliahass.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/parade011_serbia.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="386" /></a>USA, see what Serbia&#8217;s doing? See how <em>awesome</em> Serbia looks? This is how you do preppy right. This is how we should have looked. We should not have looked like a French flight attendant who in their spare time maintains a yacht. (Also whoever thought up the double-breasted blazer, I hope you&#8217;re burning in hell. Double-breasted looks terrible on everyone.) We should have been all about this level of fine, fresh, and fierce. America, you can make it up to me by getting me an outfit exactly like this in my size.</p>
<p><a href="http://juliahass.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/parade012.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1022" title="parade012" src="http://juliahass.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/parade012.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="368" /></a>The entire contingent from Spain seemed extremely drunk. If I had to wear this hot mess, I&#8217;d have gotten wasted too. Team Spain could have come out all in $5 matador Halloween costumes like you see at Walmart and it would have looked more chic than this.</p>
<p><a href="http://juliahass.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/parade014.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1023" title="parade014" src="http://juliahass.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/parade014.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="350" /></a>I feel like everyone hated Team Sweden&#8217;s look but me. But I love these colors! I love rugby shirts! I think it&#8217;s cute! Suck it, world, you&#8217;re just jealous because the entire nation of Sweden is made up of improbably attractive people. And that&#8217;s not even my opinion, it&#8217;s just a scientific fact.</p>
<p><a href="http://juliahass.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/parade015.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1024" title="parade015" src="http://juliahass.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/parade015.png" alt="" width="500" height="308" /></a>I feel like the thought process behind Ukraine&#8217;s outfit was the result of locking a bunch of designers in a room with drapes from Crate &amp; Barrel and telling them that they weren&#8217;t allowed out until they designed the most stereotypically Ukranian outfit they could possibly design.</p>
<p>Also, I have never been to Ukraine, but I feel like even there it&#8217;s not cold enough to warrant wearing fur fezzes in the summer. Actually, I take that back &#8211; there is no weather that excuses a fur fez. There less objectionable ways to lose your ears to frostbite, and if it&#8217;s either that or wear the fez, frostbite is the more noble option.</p>
<p><a href="http://juliahass.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/parade015.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1025" title="parade015" src="http://juliahass.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/parade015.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="403" /></a>&#8220;I am so jealous of Great Britain and what a great nation they are, because they have made possible the only thing I have ever wanted in my entire life &#8211; for my armpits to be made of gold!&#8221; &#8211; No one</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1009/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1009/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1009&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://juliahass.wordpress.com/2012/07/28/the-olympics-are-fabulous-sometimes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>19</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/4bc838c235108a8d0508cd3ed15f6bc5?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">juliahass</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://juliahass.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/parade001.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">parade001</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://juliahass.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/parade002.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">parade002</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://juliahass.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/parade003.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">parade003</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://juliahass.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/parade004.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2012 Olympic Games - Opening Ceremony</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://juliahass.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/parade005.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">parade005</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://juliahass.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/parade007.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">parade007</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://juliahass.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/parade009.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">South Korea&#039;s flagbearer Yoon Kyung Shin</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://juliahass.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/parade010.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">parade010</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://juliahass.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/parade011.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Members of Nigeria&#039;s contingent wave as they take part in the athletes parade during the opening ceremony of the London 2012 Olympic Games at the Olympic Stadium</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://juliahass.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/parade011_oman.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">parade011_oman</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://juliahass.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/parade011_saudiarabia.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">parade011_saudiarabia</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://juliahass.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/parade011_serbia.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">parade011_serbia</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://juliahass.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/parade012.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">parade012</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://juliahass.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/parade014.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">parade014</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://juliahass.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/parade015.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">parade015</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://juliahass.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/parade015.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">parade015</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Over Our Dead Bodies&#8230;</title>
		<link>http://satelliteshow.wordpress.com/2012/07/28/over-our-dead-bodies/</link>
		<comments>http://satelliteshow.wordpress.com/2012/07/28/over-our-dead-bodies/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2012 19:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Clint</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Home of the Bizarre Rant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Projected Pixels and Emulsion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dramas that should be comedies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[looming horror]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[squick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[twilight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Warm Bodies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zombies]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://satelliteshow.wordpress.com/?p=8241</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It was the last refuge. Where vampires, werewolves, and innumerable other creatures that went bump in the night had succumbed to the Twilight phenomenon, I could at least take comfort that the zombie would remain uncompromised at the hands of the YAF romance crowd. There is just nothing sexy about a rotting corpse, no matter how [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=8241&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It was the last refuge. Where vampires, werewolves, and innumerable other creatures that went bump in the night had succumbed to the <em>Twilight</em> phenomenon, I could at least take comfort that the <a href="http://www.zombieranchcomic.com/2010/08/18/horror-and-hotness/" target="_blank">zombie would remain uncompromised</a> at the hands of the YAF romance crowd. There is just nothing sexy about a rotting corpse, no matter how many Zombie Pin-Up girl calendars I&#8217;ve seen at conventions. I have always chosen to believe that the people making those and buying them are doing so ironically, because any other interpretation is madness.</p>
<p>No, the modern, post-Romero zombie is a wonderful thing, a force of nature, a blank slate of hunger onto which we project our own very human flaws. Like the xenomorphs of <em>Aliens</em>, you don&#8217;t see them fucking each other over for a percentage. Or fucking, for that matter. And definitely, definitively not <em>angsting about fucking</em>. When people (like luminary hobbit enthusiast <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0103873/" target="_blank">Peter Jackson</a>) portray zombie romance or zombie sex, they do it for laughs, or at least are cognizant that this is not the stuff of dreamy sighs and heart doodles in notebooks. You can&#8217;t play it straight. You can&#8217;t <em>Twilightize</em> zombies. It&#8217;s just not possible in any sort of sane world&#8230;</p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 370px"><img title="FFFFFFFFFFFFFFFFFFFFFUUUUUUUUUUUU--" src="http://www.zombieranchcomic.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/nicholas-hoult-teresa-palmer-warm-bodies-promo-image.jpg" alt="" width="360" height="509" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Oh, fuck.</p></div>
<p>That&#8217;s the promo image from the upcoming feature film <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1588173/" target="_blank">Warm Bodies</a>. Here&#8217;s the IMDB summary:</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><em>&#8220;After a zombie becomes involved with the girlfriend of one of his victims, their romance sets in motion a sequence of events that might transform the entire lifeless world.&#8221;</em></p>
<p>Here&#8217;s the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Warm_Bodies" target="_blank">Wikipedia entry</a>, so far combining the movie and the book it was based on. The book plot:</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><em>&#8220;R is a zombie. After a zombie apocalypse, he shambles across an America filled with collapsed buildings, rusted cars, shattered windows, and abandoned high-rises. He can only grunt or moan and craves human brains to get high on their memories. After eating the brains of a suicidal teen, R is overcome with love for the teen&#8217;s companion, Julie Grigio. R rescues Julie from his zombie pack and takes her back to his lair. She eventually leaves, and R follows her back to Citi Stadium, the largest remaining human refuge&#8230;&#8221;</em></p>
<p>Now, I have not read this book. It is entirely possible that the book is a fully aware, tongue-in-cheek riff on the concept, otherwise known in societal circles as &#8220;getting the joke&#8221;. There&#8217;s no mention here, after all, of Julie returning the groaning, grunting love of her rotting would-be paramour. Also, hey, a story like <em>King Kong</em> proves that with enough skill involved this sort of set-up can even be a bit tragic and touching. <em>Warm Bodies</em> apparently goes with the Romeo &amp; Juliet allusions instead, which doesn&#8217;t seem as good a fit, and the book cover has a Stephenie Meyer endorsement right at the top&#8230; but the concept alone doesn&#8217;t instantly, viscerally lurch up into my craw the way that the film promo image does.</p>
<p>There have been misleading ad campaigns before; I can in particular remember when <em>Heathers</em> first came out in 1988 with marketing featuring little more than <a href="http://twscritic.com/2012/05/13/lamb-movie-of-the-month-review-heathers-1988/" target="_blank">Winona Ryder and Christian Slater cuddling up </a>and imaginative taglines like &#8220;The COOLEST kids! The HOTTEST movie!&#8221;. That happened&#8211; but <em>Heathers</em> turned out to be far above and beyond a formulaic, vapid teen romance film; I&#8217;d go so far as to say it smartly savaged nearly everything about the genre, including daring to put forth a moral lesson that sometimes falling in love with the bad boy has bad consequences.</p>
<p>Should I extend the same consideration to <em>Warm Bodies</em>? Well, again from the wiki&#8230;</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><em>&#8220;The studio behind The Twilight Saga, Summit Entertainment, is backing the film&#8230;&#8221;</em></p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><em>&#8220;The zombies don’t really talk in the film, so extensive voice-over will be used to express their thoughts. Director [Jonathan] Levine sought to expand the zombie mythology by making the zombies better looking than in other films&#8230;&#8221;</em></p>
<p>Uh, so&#8230; this isn&#8217;t even going to be a perspective from the protagonist? We&#8217;re going to be treated to the voice-over thoughts of <em>more than one </em>zombie, here? More than one &#8220;better looking&#8221; zombie? That sounds thoroughly awful. So awful I may end up longing for the unintelligibility of the <em>Star Wars Holiday Special</em> wookiee family.</p>
<p>Did I mention that on IMDB this movie is tagged as Drama, not Comedy? Because there is no way this is not a Comedy. The more it tries to Not Be A Comedy, the more Comedic it will become.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m with the <a href="http://forum.rifftrax.com/index.php?topic=23460.0" target="_blank">Rifftrax forums</a> on this one: <em>&#8220;Holy crap, this thing is real. Let me reiterate: holy crap, this thing is really really real.&#8221;</em></p>
<p>IMDB does also have the movie categorized as &#8216;Horror&#8217;.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ll admit, I&#8217;m feeling that.</p>
<p>(<em>For fiction about walking, rotting corpses that doesn&#8217;t involve trying to make them sexy to tweens, why not check out Justin&#8217;s article about his new novel, <a href="http://satelliteshow.wordpress.com/2012/07/27/liner-notes-undead-on-arrival/" target="_blank">Undead on Arrival</a>? Or you can get really out there and have a look at my ongoing webcomic, <a href="http://www.zombieranchcomic.com" target="_blank">Zombie Ranch</a>.</em>)</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://satelliteshow.wordpress.com/category/home-of-the-bizarre-rant/'>Home of the Bizarre Rant</a>, <a href='http://satelliteshow.wordpress.com/category/projected-pixels-and-emulsion/'>Projected Pixels and Emulsion</a> Tagged: <a href='http://satelliteshow.wordpress.com/tag/dramas-that-should-be-comedies/'>dramas that should be comedies</a>, <a href='http://satelliteshow.wordpress.com/tag/looming-horror/'>looming horror</a>, <a href='http://satelliteshow.wordpress.com/tag/squick/'>squick</a>, <a href='http://satelliteshow.wordpress.com/tag/twilight/'>twilight</a>, <a href='http://satelliteshow.wordpress.com/tag/warm-bodies/'>Warm Bodies</a>, <a href='http://satelliteshow.wordpress.com/tag/zombies/'>zombies</a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=8241&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://satelliteshow.wordpress.com/2012/07/28/over-our-dead-bodies/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/aae26a208d277b228e2a6b7de1df0bf0?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">doctorfeh</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://www.zombieranchcomic.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/nicholas-hoult-teresa-palmer-warm-bodies-promo-image.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">FFFFFFFFFFFFFFFFFFFFFUUUUUUUUUUUU--</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Wild Denali</title>
		<link>http://girlmeetsbulgaria.com/2012/07/28/wild-denali/</link>
		<comments>http://girlmeetsbulgaria.com/2012/07/28/wild-denali/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2012 06:02:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>whitneybg</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Alaska]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Animals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flora and fauna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[caribou]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dall Sheep]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Denali National Park]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Denali National Park and Preserve]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grizzly bear]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kantishna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mount McKinley]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://girlmeetsbulgaria.com/?p=3249</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[On my recent trip into Denali National Park, I saw some incredible wildlife. And of course I had to share it here! My trip began with a flight over the park, around Mt. McKinley, to Kantishna. From there it was a 5 hour bus ride back to the park entrance. Along the way we were [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3249&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;">On my <a title="Soaring Over Denali National Park" href="http://girlmeetsbulgaria.com/2012/07/25/soaring-over-denali-national-park/">recent trip into Denali National Park</a>, I saw some incredible wildlife.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">And of course I had to share it here!</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">My trip began with a flight over the park, around Mt. McKinley, to Kantishna. From there it was a 5 hour bus ride back to the park entrance.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">Along the way we were were lucky enough to spot some of the parks most famous inhabitants.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">
<div id="attachment_3250" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://girlmeetsbulgaria.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dsc_2622_e.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-3250" title="DSC_2622_e" src="http://girlmeetsbulgaria.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dsc_2622_e.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="398" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">A mother Grizzly with two cubs, waaaay far away.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_3251" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://girlmeetsbulgaria.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dsc_2651_e.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-3251" title="DSC_2651_e" src="http://girlmeetsbulgaria.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dsc_2651_e.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="398" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">I spy a Dall sheep</p></div>
<p><a href="http://girlmeetsbulgaria.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dsc_2659_b.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3252" title="DSC_2659_b" src="http://girlmeetsbulgaria.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dsc_2659_b.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="398" /></a></p>
<div id="attachment_3253" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://girlmeetsbulgaria.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dsc_2824_e.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-3253" title="DSC_2824_e" src="http://girlmeetsbulgaria.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dsc_2824_e.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="398" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">wandering caribou</p></div>
<p style="text-align:center;"><span id="more-3249"></span></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">In all, we saw about 12 grizzly bears (including 4 cubs), a handful of caribou, many birds, and about 20 Dall sheep.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">Most amazingly, the bus actually came up on an entire group of male Dall sheep in the middle of the road. Usually the sheep are nothing more than tiny snow-white dots on the highest cliffs. However, our driver told us there are times when they come down in groups to the lower elevations.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">The group stood, and a few even laid down, in the road in front of the bus for a good 10 minutes. Eventually, they meandered past the bus and down the road. It was truly one of the most amazing experiences I have ever had in the park.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://girlmeetsbulgaria.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dsc_2683_b.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3262" title="DSC_2683_b" src="http://girlmeetsbulgaria.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dsc_2683_b.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="398" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://girlmeetsbulgaria.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dsc_2696_b.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-3263" title="DSC_2696_b" src="http://girlmeetsbulgaria.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dsc_2696_b.jpg?w=420&h=632" alt="" width="420" height="632" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://girlmeetsbulgaria.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dsc_2692_b.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3265" title="DSC_2692_b" src="http://girlmeetsbulgaria.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dsc_2692_b.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="398" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://girlmeetsbulgaria.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dsc_2709_b.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3257" title="DSC_2709_b" src="http://girlmeetsbulgaria.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dsc_2709_b.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="398" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://girlmeetsbulgaria.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dsc_2720_b.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3264" title="DSC_2720_b" src="http://girlmeetsbulgaria.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dsc_2720_b.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="398" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">It was an incredible day that I will remember always.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">Here&#8217;s to many more ahead.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">W.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">***</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">To follow my adventures in Alaska, please subscribe, connect with my on <a href="https://twitter.com/whitneypiper" target="_blank">Twitter</a>, or chat with me on <a href="http://www.facebook.com/pages/Girl-Meets-Bulgaria/236771603066798?ref=ts" target="_blank">Facebook</a>.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3249/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3249/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3249&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://girlmeetsbulgaria.com/2012/07/28/wild-denali/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/bce61213fc11d4e9c333110b13f67dd5?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">whitneybg</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://girlmeetsbulgaria.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dsc_2622_e.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_2622_e</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://girlmeetsbulgaria.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dsc_2651_e.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_2651_e</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://girlmeetsbulgaria.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dsc_2659_b.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_2659_b</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://girlmeetsbulgaria.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dsc_2824_e.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_2824_e</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://girlmeetsbulgaria.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dsc_2683_b.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_2683_b</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://girlmeetsbulgaria.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dsc_2696_b.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_2696_b</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://girlmeetsbulgaria.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dsc_2692_b.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_2692_b</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://girlmeetsbulgaria.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dsc_2709_b.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_2709_b</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://girlmeetsbulgaria.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dsc_2720_b.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_2720_b</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>how to make a load of washing highly socio-technical.</title>
		<link>http://daniellewolhuter.wordpress.com/2012/07/29/how-to-make-a-load-of-washing-highly-socio-technical/</link>
		<comments>http://daniellewolhuter.wordpress.com/2012/07/29/how-to-make-a-load-of-washing-highly-socio-technical/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2012 03:20:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>daniellewolhuter</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Accident Forensics entries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[machine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Moodle Activity 1A]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[procrastination]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[socio-technical]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[system]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://daniellewolhuter.wordpress.com/?p=123</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[One awkward fact of uni life is that you start reading whatever you&#8217;re studying into real life. When I studied Psych, I had fun with using classical conditioning to train my puppy dog. I started studying Anatomy and Physiology, and skin was no longer skin- it was stratified squamous epithelia. Similarly, I just went to [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=123&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One awkward fact of uni life is that you start reading whatever you&#8217;re studying into real life. When I studied Psych, I had fun with using classical conditioning to train my puppy dog. I started studying Anatomy and Physiology, and skin was no longer skin- it was stratified squamous epithelia. Similarly, I just went to put on a load of washing, and the chore of washing clothes had suddenly transformed into a Human-Machine System, or more accurately a mechanical human-machine system.</p>
<div id="attachment_124" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 300px"><a href="http://daniellewolhuter.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/washing-machine.png"><img class="size-medium wp-image-124" title="washing machine" src="http://daniellewolhuter.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/washing-machine.png?w=290&h=300" alt="Hitachi of some variety" width="290" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">is it a box? is it a machine? it&#8217;s a human-machine system!</p></div>
<p>The parts in this system consist of:</p>
<ul>
<li>the washing machine</li>
<li>the connection to electricity and water which therefore provide the power to clean my jeans</li>
<li>the detergent which the human administers</li>
<li>and me! The human who manipulates control devices to make the complex machine do what I want.</li>
</ul>
<p>The system goal would be to make my uniforms (and other clothes) not dirty anymore&#8230; self-explanatory, right? Additionally, it sings a little tune when it&#8217;s done. I&#8217;m not sure what relevance that has socio-technically, but I like it. Reward for the user, maybe?<br />
There are PLENTY of Human Factors issues that potentially exist with a washing machine. Just ask any teenage boy- they all seem to have had their socks washed pink at some point.</p>
<ul>
<li>putting the wrong colours or new clothes in together (think pink!)</li>
<li>forgetting to put the lid down on the top (in which case it goes so far and no further)</li>
<li>forgetting to put powder or detergent in (clothes now wet and smelly..)</li>
<li>using the wrong settings for the clothes (damage, shrink, run&#8230; it&#8217;s all possible.)</li>
<li>I&#8217;ve often confused the on/off button with the start/stop button, in which case you have to do all the custom settings again.</li>
<li>the list goes on.</li>
</ul>
<p>I can also think of a few notable potential relationship mismatches. For instance, the controls are all in English with no other indication (pictorial, shape, colour) as to what they might do. We often have Asian homestays in the house, so they struggle to use it and often just resort to hand washing. Since it&#8217;s a top-loading machine, particularly small people have problems with getting things out, even if they can put them in.</p>
<p>They&#8217;ve done fairly well with most other design features, though. For example, the little tune that plays at the end is about 20 seconds long, and it goes through a range of little beeping notes in a cheerful song that cuts through most ambient noise or hearing loss. It&#8217;s almost a pity- no more excuses for not hearing that the washing was done.</p>
<p>Now if you&#8217;ll excuse me&#8230; I have a load of washing to hang up.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/123/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/123/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=123&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://daniellewolhuter.wordpress.com/2012/07/29/how-to-make-a-load-of-washing-highly-socio-technical/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/ac08decd35b9b32d19e8e030aa1eb943?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">daniellewolhuter</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://daniellewolhuter.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/washing-machine.png?w=290" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">washing machine</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dissing the Disinformation</title>
		<link>http://hashandeggs.wordpress.com/2012/07/28/dissing-the-disinformation/</link>
		<comments>http://hashandeggs.wordpress.com/2012/07/28/dissing-the-disinformation/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2012 02:32:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>John S</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[World]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://hashandeggs.wordpress.com/?p=1184</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[At some point in the earliest days of e-mail, the internet began to take away our power of critical thought. It moved in slowly, taking hold like a cancer and then spreading. It preyed on our trust. It made us think it wanted to protect us from things or tell us about interesting things of [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1184&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://hashandeggs.wordpress.com/2012/07/28/dissing-the-disinformation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>63</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/0636301cd4d836c7d653dc6116686f1f?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">playwrightguy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hashandeggs.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/bull.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bull</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hashandeggs.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/statues1-e1343155157729.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://hashandeggs.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/final-e1343163204929.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">final</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>