<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 21:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>The Conversation</title>
		<link>http://elroyjones.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/the-conversation/</link>
		<comments>http://elroyjones.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/the-conversation/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 14:45:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>elroyjones</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Autonomy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[INDEPENDENCE]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://elroyjones.wordpress.com/?p=3180</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[She hadn&#8217;t forgotten the relief scrawled all over James&#8217;s face when she picked him up in Myrtle Beach. He held her so tight she thought she&#8217;d break. She could feel him shudder as he choked back sobs. When she pulled away, his eyes welled up and tears ran down his face.  She watched him lean [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3180&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>She hadn&#8217;t forgotten the relief scrawled all over James&#8217;s face when she picked him up in Myrtle Beach. He held her so tight she thought she&#8217;d break. She could feel him shudder as he choked back sobs. When she pulled away, his eyes welled up and tears ran down his face.  She watched him lean over to get his bag, saw the nape of his neck that was replicated in her kids, felt a treacherous tug on her heart. His eyes had filled anew as he turned toward her. &#8220;James, what&#8217;s wrong?&#8221; He stopped. He looked down at her, his brows knit in consternation, &#8220;I was afraid I&#8217;d never see you again.&#8221; She reached for him and held him close.</p>
<p>They started a conversation.<br />
She asked &#8220;Why?&#8221; Why was he mad at her all the time? Why didn&#8217;t he trust her?<br />
He wasn&#8217;t mad. He didn&#8217;t know what to do. He&#8217;d always known who she was. When he came back from Vietnam, she was still there, the same as she was when he&#8217;d left. She was committed to her religion, when he was only going through the motions of habit, avoiding the conflict of examining where god went when you were so scared you shit yourself, when families were being blown to bits for reasons nobody knew. She hadn&#8217;t pestered him about it, she didn&#8217;t ask any questions. He felt that she understood who he was inside.<br />
&#8220;I wanted to know. I wanted to know what happened. I didn&#8217;t ask you because it wasn&#8217;t my business. I thought the church was your reason for living. Then why did you get so mad when I cut my hair?&#8221;<br />
&#8220;It was beautiful and soft and it smelled good. I liked to touch it before I went to sleep because it meant you were right there, with me. Every day, as soon as I got done work, I went home to get the kids to come see you at the market because I couldn&#8217;t wait for you to come home. When you cut it, I thought that was the beginning of the end. You were changing. I thought you didn&#8217;t love me.&#8221;</p>
<p>He said a lot more; private things she hadn&#8217;t expected, things he thought she just knew. They&#8217;d stayed through the weekend before they drove back home. They&#8217;d made it through the intervening years, trudging through some and sailing through others. They had ugly words and sweet words, more words than she&#8217;d imagined. In the end, whether she&#8217;d chosen her destiny, or they had created it, didn&#8217;t matter at all.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3180/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3180/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3180&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://elroyjones.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/the-conversation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>17</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/21e9dfba7851063d7a62404210420278?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">elroyjones</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Paranoia, Meet Theism.</title>
		<link>http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.wordpress.com/2013/03/10/paranoia-meet-theism-theism-this-is-paranoia-youre-biological-father-6/</link>
		<comments>http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.wordpress.com/2013/03/10/paranoia-meet-theism-theism-this-is-paranoia-youre-biological-father-6/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2013 11:14:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>john zande</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Sketches on Atheism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ancestor cults]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[and the oldest of them all]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[animism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[atheism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[False Associations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[god]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Neurosis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new atheism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[origin of religion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[paganism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pantheism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Paranoia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[religion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[root of belief]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[superstition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Theism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Totemism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Unnatural]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.wordpress.com/?p=1440</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Just so there’s no doubt: Anthropomorphic theism is about as natural as tennis rackets, ice cream cones and bikini’s. It is neither automatic nor inevitable. No religion has emerged twice anywhere on the planet, no single deity has been envisaged by two populations separated by time and geography, and not a solitary person in history [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1440&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/hancock-joseph-man-with-umbrella-under-a-regional-rain.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-1443" alt="hancock-joseph-man-with-umbrella-under-a-regional-rain" src="http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/hancock-joseph-man-with-umbrella-under-a-regional-rain.jpg?w=338&#038;h=450" width="338" height="450" /></a>Just so there’s no doubt: Anthropomorphic theism is about as natural as tennis rackets, ice cream cones and bikini’s. It is neither automatic nor inevitable. No religion has emerged twice anywhere on the planet, no single deity has been envisaged by two populations separated by time and geography, and not a solitary person in history has arrived independently at Mithraism, Christianity, Islam, Zoroastrianism, Hinduism, Scientology or Judaism without it first being taught to them. That is an inalienable, unarguable truth. Theism (the progeny of far older generations of pantheism, Totemism, paganism, animism and the oldest of them all, ancestor cults) is nothing but the latest imaginative appendage to have grown out from (culturally-centric) superstition; itself nothing but the elaborately dressed-up residue cast off from blunders in causation and correlation. That’s all superstition is; irrational mistakes in cognition where we observe one event (B) happening after another event (A) and assume A is responsible for B. Upon sensing a storm approaching my wife’s deeply superstitious great grandmother would, I’m told, crawl beneath the kitchen sink and furiously beat pots and pans together until the lightning and thunder had passed. Not so surprisingly this method of chasing storm demons away worked every time. The storm would pass. The reasons why, of course, differed according to whom you asked.</p>
<blockquote><p><b>“The General root of superstition is that men observe when things hit, and not when they miss, and commit to memory the one, and pass over the other.” (Francis Bacon)</b></p></blockquote>
<p>Like theism, superstition is however also not natural. It will not rise instinctively like hunger, and no two populations will arrive at the same irrational fears. A monstrous, head-exploding, palm tree bending sneeze on the Banks Islands of Polynesia is cause for serious concern as someone is certainly talking badly of you, but for the Maoris in nearby New Zealand the same roof-lifting nose orgasm is reason to celebrate because someone fun is surely about to visit. <a href="http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/pf-paranoia.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-1386" alt="PF-paranoia" src="http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/pf-paranoia.jpg?w=241&#038;h=300" width="241" height="300" /></a>The tripwire for superstition is cultural, it’s anthropological, but this is not however to say there <i>isn’t</i> a physiological trigger buried deep inside the gnome that kicks the door open to culturally-centric superstition and through that paves the way for its uglier but more organised cousin, religion. There is, and it’s spelt  P  A  R  A  N  O  I  A.</p>
<p>Granted, on first inspection most will say paranoia, like superstition, is simply an unwelcomed cognitive clusterfuck, the information processing equivalent of a shipwreck, and in many ways it is just that. It is however an unavoidable, preordained shipwreck hardwired into each and every one of us… and for very good reason: the madness served us extremely well at a time not that very long ago when even the strongest of us were counted as snack items. A breeze bending blades of grass could easily be attributed (albeit in this instance incorrectly) to a stalking lioness and all the dangers that it implied. Danger is bad, and to get ahead of it we, as a species, played it safe and erred on the side of caution. We learnt to jump before (possible) peril arrived. The causal associations made between the unpredictable movement of grasses and the presence of danger (to use this example) was a good thing, a promotable skill, a biologically useful adaption that was slowly but surely etched into our gnome. To put it simply, our evolutionary path rewarded the lesser of two evils whereby the cost of paranoia was deemed lower than the cost of scepticism which, if wrong, extracts a painfully high price: namely death. The sceptical hominid might see the bending grass but take a moment to then survey surrounding trees and see if they too were bending. If they were then the probability of wind causing the movement of the grass increased but did not necessarily rule out the presence of a hungry lioness. Wrongly attributing the bending grass to an approaching lioness ninety-nine times out of a hundred was, it appears, far less costly than being wrong once. The paranoid lived on to practice (or fend off) increasingly bad pick-up lines whereas the brazen sceptic tired of jumping at the slightest rustle met a less than pleasant demise.</p>
<p>In a sentence, nature beatified the neurotic.</p>
<p>A tendency to make quick albeit mostly false associations was deemed more evolutionarily beneficial than more reliable but equally more time-consuming rational scepticism. There was a price to pay for this inbuilt paranoia, anxiety and suspicion, but the price was evidently considered tolerable in the face of the more costly alternatives. We are, as such, biologically predisposed to this neurosis. Paranoia is, at a genetic level, our default setting: the natural state of a human being at rest. Bending blades of grass are observed, synaptic nerve endings fire and the observation is linked to past events where the pattern of bending grass is followed by a blinding flash of sandy blonde fur and hazardously huge feline paws. What happens next is entirely involuntary. Up top there is a not-so mild biochemical explosion and norepinephrine floods the brain; the neurological equivalent of someone yelling “FIRE!” in a crowded theatre. Adrenal glands go off like solid rocket fuel motors and adrenalin saturates the sympathetic nervous system. Neurons in the visual cortex spark off at triple normal speed and time appears to slow. Faster than thought the liver dumps its store of glucose into the blood. The heart and lungs snap into overdrive flooding muscles with oxygen, and with that the body is near-instantly prepared for Flight or Fight: a survival mechanism that has changed little, if at all, through the last 830,000 generations.</p>
<p>That’s just the way it is and I can no sooner change that than I can change my eye colour. Today as I walk my dogs an abrupt rustle in the tall grass will make me jump. The likelihood of a lioness leaping out might be remote, a mouse is more probable, but my natural, pre-programmed bias to making the quicker and cheaper false association is there, ingrained. My speedy (life-preserving) reaction, which I’m not shy to admit might include yelping like a little girl, I can thank some deep time relative – perhaps Australopithecus afarensis – for. However, simply because some 830,000 generations ago this neurosis was deemed less expensive than careful scepticism does not mean there hasn’t been a hidden cost slowly accruing in the background; an expense steadily but surely building up like silt behind a once useful dam wall. The truth is there has been, and that cumulative cost is our stubborn attachment to superstition: the nucleus of theism and all its unnatural nonsense.</p>
<br /> Tagged: <a href='http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.wordpress.com/tag/ancestor-cults/'>ancestor cults</a>, <a href='http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.wordpress.com/tag/and-the-oldest-of-them-all/'>and the oldest of them all</a>, <a href='http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.wordpress.com/tag/animism/'>animism</a>, <a href='http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.wordpress.com/tag/atheism/'>atheism</a>, <a href='http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.wordpress.com/tag/false-associations/'>False Associations</a>, <a href='http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.wordpress.com/tag/god/'>god</a>, <a href='http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.wordpress.com/tag/gods/'>gods</a>, <a href='http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.wordpress.com/tag/neurosis/'>Neurosis</a>, <a href='http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.wordpress.com/tag/new-atheism/'>new atheism</a>, <a href='http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.wordpress.com/tag/origin-of-religion/'>origin of religion</a>, <a href='http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.wordpress.com/tag/paganism/'>paganism</a>, <a href='http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.wordpress.com/tag/pantheism/'>pantheism</a>, <a href='http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.wordpress.com/tag/paranoia/'>Paranoia</a>, <a href='http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.wordpress.com/tag/religion/'>religion</a>, <a href='http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.wordpress.com/tag/root-of-belief/'>root of belief</a>, <a href='http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.wordpress.com/tag/superstition/'>superstition</a>, <a href='http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.wordpress.com/tag/theism/'>Theism</a>, <a href='http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.wordpress.com/tag/totemism/'>Totemism</a>, <a href='http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.wordpress.com/tag/unnatural/'>Unnatural</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1440/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1440/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1440/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1440/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1440/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1440/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1440/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1440/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1440/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1440/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1440/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1440/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1440/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1440/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1440&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.wordpress.com/2013/03/10/paranoia-meet-theism-theism-this-is-paranoia-youre-biological-father-6/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>72</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c0a3dbb25b899dda42934295ee0d3a25?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">johnzande</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/hancock-joseph-man-with-umbrella-under-a-regional-rain.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">hancock-joseph-man-with-umbrella-under-a-regional-rain</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/pf-paranoia.jpg?w=241" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">PF-paranoia</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lunchtime</title>
		<link>http://mikehardisty.wordpress.com/2013/03/17/weekly-photo-challenge-lunchtime/</link>
		<comments>http://mikehardisty.wordpress.com/2013/03/17/weekly-photo-challenge-lunchtime/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2013 14:27:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Mike Hardisty</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[High Dynamic Range]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Interesting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mike Hardisty Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Postaday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PostaWeek 2013]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weekly Photo Challenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asaph]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Denbighshire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diesel locomotives]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flint]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Llangollen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Llangollen Railway]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prestatyn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ruabon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wales]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://mikehardisty.wordpress.com/?p=5009</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[When I’m out for the day on a photography trip lunchtime is one of those points in the day that I always aim to take. As a lot of my photography is landscapes I can just sit and enjoy the beautiful scenery whilst eating my lunch. However this trip was different. Two weeks ago I [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=5009&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://mikehardisty.wordpress.com/2013/03/17/weekly-photo-challenge-lunchtime/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>47</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://mikehardisty.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/off-the-rails.jpg?w=200" />
		<media:content url="http://mikehardisty.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/off-the-rails.jpg?w=200" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Off the Rails</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/4e2d094f79240dc276f8e5de16daaae0?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">arkitekt878</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://static.flickr.com/8239/8565250478_0d56ae0e40_b.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Off the Rails</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://static.flickr.com/8376/8565250144_c82f381af9_b.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Platform 1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://static.flickr.com/8085/8565250684_3bf618d4a2_b.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Berwyn Railway Station</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://static.flickr.com/8511/8564148937_5b80082bc6_b.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Over the Bridge</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://static.flickr.com/8367/8565250370_bca873b245_b.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">On the Bridge</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://static.flickr.com/8524/8565250584_528e565345_b.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Inside The Cafe</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ten Entirely Invented Motivational Quotations for Writers</title>
		<link>http://jamesgillingham.wordpress.com/2013/03/17/10-entirely-invented-motivational-quotations-for-writers/</link>
		<comments>http://jamesgillingham.wordpress.com/2013/03/17/10-entirely-invented-motivational-quotations-for-writers/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2013 22:44:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>jamesgillingham</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[long arm films]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[motivation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quotations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[screenwriting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing tips]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://jamesgillingham.wordpress.com/?p=1321</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I try very hard not to be a moaner. I mean we all love a good moan now and then: about the government, the football, the shockingly poor selection of cheese available from the corner shop but no one actually LIKES a moaner do they? No one wants to be sitting on the bus, or [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1321&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I try very hard not to be a moaner. I mean we all love a good moan now and then: about the government, the football, the shockingly poor selection of cheese available from the corner shop but no one actually LIKES a moaner do they? No one wants to be sitting on the bus, or in the tea room or astride a ski-lift next to someone who is letting rip about the veins in their legs or the price of lawnmowers these days or the shocking state of post-structuralist teaching in some of our second-tier universities. We all moan about moaners. And with good reason. So I do try to avoid the overly-negative in these &#8220;blog&#8217; posts; I try to look towards the light and not the dark, celebrate rather than denigrate, be silly rather than cynical. Sometimes I succeed (<em>I bought some new boots this weekend; they are brilliant!</em> &#8211; see, just like that), but at other times I fail (<em>Peanut butter is disgusting and anyone who says otherwise is on the devil&#8217;s payroll</em> - yep, like that) and I am sad to say that this is one of those times.</p>
<p>So here goes. Existence: feel my wrath!</p>
<p>You know what really annoys me? Quotes. And not just the fact that the noun is &#8220;quotation&#8221; which EVERYBODY GETS WRONG ALL OF THE BLOODY TIME (although this does make me cross and repulsively self-righteous, so much so that at times I do want to punch myself in the face) but also the fact that they get plastered up everywhere as if somehow such gobbets of wisdom could be of actual use to ANYBODY when in reality they&#8217;re just further examples of the reductive and under-baked nonsense that passes for thought in this so-called &#8220;Twenty First&#8221; century of ours. (Gosh, I am grumpy this evening).</p>
<p>Bruce Robinson, author of &#8220;Withnail and I&#8221; reportedly had a sign on his typewriter which read &#8220;Write damn you; it&#8217;s the only thing you&#8217;re good for&#8221;. I like that. That one can stay, that one is allowed but all other quotATIONS that are plastered around the walls of student flats and schools and pubs (those ones particularly grate &#8211; I don&#8217;t need Samuel Johnson&#8217;s reassurance that drinking a pint of ale is like kissing a princess or something &#8211; I KNOW IT IS) should be made illegal from tomorrow. No, earlier than that. They should be made illegal from this very moment. From now. That&#8217;s it. I&#8217;ve passed the law. They are now illegal and the punishment for displaying even the most likeable aphorism in a public space will be punitive and entirely unfair. And if you post one on Facebook then the keys on your keyboard will secrete superglue before becoming electrified. And that is for your first offence.</p>
<p>I am sounding entirely unlikeable aren&#8217;t I? I do try not to be wherever possible. Perhaps I should be a little less misanthropic; after all, if a well-chosen quotation gets you through your day then what the hell does it matter what I think? It doesn&#8217;t matter a jot, of course it doesn&#8217;t. But do a quick google search for &#8220;inspirational quotations&#8221; and be prepared to vomit all over your pyjamas &#8211; even if you have to cross the sitting room, go up the stairs, past the bathroom and into your bedroom where you open the second drawer on your chest just to find your pyjamas in order to vomit over them. Listen up world, you don&#8217;t need the blessing of someone most likely dead (and certainly as flawed and farty as you are) to kickstart your chosen career. Writers seem particularly needy in this respect and whilst I know only too well the challenges involved in sitting down and ACTUALLY WRITING SOMETHING I don&#8217;t see how a phrase ripped entirely from its context and then rendered in a twee typeface gets you closer to finishing your masterpiece. Did James Joyce have a little sign blue-tacked up in his garret as he wrote Ulysses which said &#8220;<em>Words are like rain. Just put out a jar beneath a piece of guttering and assuming that it is a rainy night then after a bit you&#8217;ll have lots of them</em>&#8220;? Well if he did, it would certainly weaken my point so let&#8217;s just agree that he didn&#8217;t.</p>
<p>If you are the type of a writer who needs an aphoristic jump-start to get you going in the morning then at least let me help you; let me save you the searching and the sifting through thousands of trite and largely useless scrapings from the barrel of human thought by providing you a list of handy phrases to set you on your way. For this there shall be NO CHARGE. Yes, the following is absolutely free. It will cost you neither pound nor dollar, neither Yen nor Euro, as I present:</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>LONG ARM FILMS&#8217;</strong><br />
<strong>TEN ENTIRELY INVENTED MOTIVATIONAL QUOTATIONS<br />
FOR ASPIRING SCREENWRITERS</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://jamesgillingham.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screen-shot-2013-03-17-at-21-19-48.png"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-1322" alt="Bill Murray quotation" src="http://jamesgillingham.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screen-shot-2013-03-17-at-21-19-48.png?w=525&#038;h=230" width="525" height="230" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">1. &#8220;Even Bill Murray has days when he is not Bill Murray&#8221;. - <em>C14th Estonian Proverb</em></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">2. &#8220;Good writing is like good jam: sweet, fruity and sealed with a floral lid&#8221;<br />
- <em>Sarah Basterds &#8211; &#8220;The Impish Sentiment&#8221; (1932)</em></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">3. &#8220;Film is the distance between onanism and quantum theory&#8221; -<br />
<em>Prof F.J. Ruislip &#8211; &#8220;Once upon a time in the Western Avenue&#8221; (1998)</em></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">4. &#8220;The perfect screenplay is like the footprints of a deer across a Scottish hillside. I don&#8217;t need to sodding explain why.&#8221;<br />
<em>Alice Childress &#8211; usherette at the Alexandra Cinema, Newton Abbot, 1985</em></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">5. &#8220;Working hard is almost always relatively useful&#8221;.<br />
<em>Edgar Sirmadam, (19th philanthropist and sausage pioneer</em></p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><a href="http://jamesgillingham.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screen-shot-2013-03-17-at-21-23-31.png"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-1324" alt="working hard quotation" src="http://jamesgillingham.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screen-shot-2013-03-17-at-21-23-31.png?w=525&#038;h=234" width="525" height="234" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">6. &#8220;Love yourself. Frequently&#8221;.<br />
<em>Sir Francis Walsingham</em></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">7. &#8220;Take doubt out to dinner. Give good chat to doubt. Let doubt linger over dessert and coffee then stab doubt repeatedly in the taxi on the way home&#8221;.<br />
<em>Mary Quite, &#8220;Fish and Chaps&#8221; &#8211; The birth of seaside homo-eroiticism: (1974) </em></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">8. &#8220;Choosing the right words is less important than order them the putting in right&#8221;<br />
<em>Geoffrey Chaucer -&#8221;The Screenwriter&#8217;s Tale&#8221; (1378)</em></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">9. &#8220;Belief is the fart that warms the duvet of talent&#8221;.<br />
<em>King Christian VII of Norway addressing the Oslo branch of the WI (1802).</em></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">10.  &#8221;When people ask me why I write, I tell them it is to nourish my soul. When people ask me <em>how</em> I write I tell them that I use my fingers on a computer keyboard and press letters in a pre-determined sequence, that I began to learn around four years old and really haven&#8217;t stopped working on since, which in turn creates words that are understood by speakers of the English language and then I repeat this process until I have created something that is maybe just a shopping list or maybe the libretto for an opera it just depends on how sexy I&#8217;m feeling&#8221;<br />
<em>Hadrian Patel &#8211; Winner of the Branston Prize in 2005 for his novel &#8220;Balls&#8221;</em></p>
<p><a href="http://jamesgillingham.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screen-shot-2013-03-17-at-22-37-13.png"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-1325" alt="belief quote" src="http://jamesgillingham.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screen-shot-2013-03-17-at-22-37-13.png?w=525&#038;h=234" width="525" height="234" /></a>Feel free to pin any of these up by your desk and reap the creative and inspirational benefits.</p>
<p>You are welcome. I do it because I care.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1321/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1321/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1321&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://jamesgillingham.wordpress.com/2013/03/17/10-entirely-invented-motivational-quotations-for-writers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>19</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/056a4c1e75bdf2e6208ececc52ffa943?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jamesgillingham</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jamesgillingham.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screen-shot-2013-03-17-at-21-19-48.png?w=525" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Bill Murray quotation</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jamesgillingham.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screen-shot-2013-03-17-at-21-23-31.png?w=525" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">working hard quotation</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jamesgillingham.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/screen-shot-2013-03-17-at-22-37-13.png?w=525" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">belief quote</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Hidden Art of Silent Films</title>
		<link>http://swingstatevoter.me/2013/03/01/the-hidden-art-of-silent-films/</link>
		<comments>http://swingstatevoter.me/2013/03/01/the-hidden-art-of-silent-films/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 17:23:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>swingstatevoter</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Movies]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://swingstatevoter.wordpress.com/2013/03/01/the-hidden-art-of-silent-films/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Silent films are a lost art.  Hollywood really has gone overboard on special effects and underwhelming plot lines (that is, when they do something other than just remaking an 80&#8242;s film or re-vamping Superman for the zillionth time). I took a trip back to my alma mater Ohio Wesleyan University last weekend.  As I meandered [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=588&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Silent films are a lost art.  Hollywood really has gone overboard on special effects and underwhelming plot lines (that is, when they do something other than just remaking an 80&#8242;s film or re-vamping Superman for the zillionth time).</p>
<p>I took a trip back to my alma mater Ohio Wesleyan University last weekend.  As I meandered down memory lane, I was saddened to see my favorite professor, Helmut Kremling, was no longer teaching.  Not only was he a great mentor for me while proffing the courses of my major (German Studies), he also taught an Introduction to Film class that completely opened up a whole new world to me.  I had always been a lover of movies, but never before had I experienced so much fascination with a dying art form.  Much like the old celluloid films of the late 19th Century, the structural integrity of true trend-setting and cutting-edge films is in question.</p>
<p>Considering how many of us gripe about cell phones and computers causing social ineptitude (one can&#8217;t walk down the street without seeing earbuds as a social barrier &#8211; of which I am 100% guilty) it is miraculous to watch silent films, when facial expression and posturing was the only way an actor could connect with a viewer to channel the emotion in a particular scene.</p>
<p>Do you have any idea how difficult it is to show 100% of your emotion in your face, and not through your words?  Often times when I find myself angry or hurt, and have to express that to another person, I really don&#8217;t feel like I can express myself fully unless I talk it out.  I can&#8217;t quite emphasize the level of screwed I&#8217;d be if I could never portray my emotions in words. I suppose that&#8217;s why I&#8217;m a better writer than actor.</p>
<p>The first silent film I watched in its entirety was &#8220;Broken Blossoms&#8221; starring Lillian Gish and Richard Barthelmess.  Gish stars as a battered child of &#8220;Battling Burrows&#8221;, an alcoholic boxer.  After being beaten severely by her dad, she is taken in by a very kind opium-smoking Chinese fella.  By modern standards, this film is incredibly insensitive in portraying old stereotypes of the Chinese culture.  However, it does show a kindhearted man who wants to fix a broken girl &#8211; the broken blossom &#8211; by nursing her back to health and hoping she will reciprocate his love for her.  Of course, the jerk of a father doesn&#8217;t like hearing his daughter is hanging with a &#8220;yellow man&#8221; as they called him (grrr), and he sought to beat the crap out of Barthelmess&#8217;s character as well.</p>
<p><a href="http://swingstatevoter.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/gish.jpg"><img src="http://swingstatevoter.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/gish.jpg?w=257&#038;h=196" alt="Gish" width="257" height="196" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-718" /></a></p>
<p>Let&#8217;s just say Romeo &amp; Juliet + Dirty Harry = sob story that makes &#8220;Steel Magnolias&#8221; look like a kindergarten play.</p>
<p>Gish and Barthelmess were the Tom Hanks/Meg Ryan pairing of the early 20th century, going on to star in several popular films together before talkies dug significant divots into their careers.  It is no wonder to me why director D.W. Griffith was so enamored of Lillian Gish (he truly was in love with the girl!), seeing the depth of character in her tiny body and the abyss of emotion in her captivating eyes.  That film changed my life, and my ability to see film as an art form rather than just entertainment.</p>
<p>Perhaps it was the &#8220;damsel in distress&#8221; nature of the Gish/Barthelmess pairing, or it could have been the fact that both actors were unquestionably refined in their charming good looks. </p>
<p> <a href="http://swingstatevoter.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/broken-blossoms.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-594" alt="Broken Blossoms" src="http://swingstatevoter.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/broken-blossoms.jpg?w=200&#038;h=150" width="200" height="150" /></a></p>
<p>Regardless, I felt like I lost myself in the film&#8217;s plot, and felt every single emotion Gish showed on her face.  What struck me most was that I couldn&#8217;t think of a single modern film that carried that much emotion.  Mel Gibson&#8217;s &#8220;FREEEEEEEEDOMMMMMM!!!!&#8221; or (more lightheardedly) Tom Cruise&#8217;s &#8220;SHOW ME THE MONEY!!!!&#8221; come close, but still have nowhere near the unbelievable pain or desperation the characters Gish portrayed as having in &#8220;Broken Blossoms&#8221; and (another Gish/Barthelmess match-up) &#8220;Way Down East.&#8221;</p>
<p>So what&#8217;s a girl to do when she wants to get a good cry going on up in here?  That&#8217;s right, I watch Lillian Gish.  I could choose to watch &#8220;Fried Green Tomatoes&#8221; for the umpteenth time, with a side dish of &#8220;When Harry Met Sally&#8221;, but I sometimes find myself losing the sappiness every time they tell a good joke.  The dialogue seems to get in the way.  You know that feeling when you&#8217;re so mad you could scream/cry/something-in-between/maybe-both, and then someone tells a joke that makes you laugh and you think &#8220;DAMN! I almost got a good cry in!&#8221;  With silent dramas, the cheesy dialogue only hinders the emotion, insomuch as one is willing to read the words on the screen.  If it&#8217;s too cheesy, my eyes are closed for that 7-8 seconds.  The pairing of the music with the acting gives the greatest connection with the plot I&#8217;ve ever found.  Go ahead, girls, cry it out!</p>
<p>But if you need a good laugh, nothing is finer than a Buster Keaton flick.  One of the most underrated comedians of the silent era, Keaton was a genius at slapstick and telling a joke with his body.  You almost felt sorry for the poor guy, with the incessant &#8220;Awwww, I just sat in dog shit&#8221; facial expression he mastered. </p>
<p><a href="http://swingstatevoter.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/keaton.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-580" alt="Keaton" src="http://swingstatevoter.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/keaton.jpg?w=220&#038;h=273" width="220" height="273" /></a></p>
<p>Charlie Chaplin must have had a better manager to have surpassed Buster Keaton in the minds of our generation as *the* comedian in the silent era.  Chaplin, as talented as he was, could not hold a candle to Keaton.</p>
<p>My personal favorite of his, &#8220;Sherlock, Jr.&#8221;, is brilliant comedy mixed with aesthetically groundbreaking cinematography. Keaton portrays a poor movie theater projectionist who has high hopes for winning the favor of a beautiful girl.  Keaton&#8217;s character is studying to be a detective, so he dreams (literally) about how to solve the mystery of a stolen pocket watch to win her heart, since he has no money with which to impress her. Unbeknownst to Keaton, he has been framed for the theft by some douchebag of a baller also trying to win the girl over.  Douchebag gets the girl temporarily with his flashy money, but Keaton&#8217;s character is more savvy with the street smarts.</p>
<p>The dream sequence is a masterful mesh of Keaton conforming real-time acting to the scenery around him on screen as it constantly changes &#8211; creating the illusion that he had joined the movie being played in the theater in which he is snoozing.  Keaton was so dedicated to his physical comedy that he severely fractured his neck in one scene while falling from a water tower (which became the cut used in the final version of the film).  He doesn&#8217;t miss a beat in continuing the scene.  As much as I know that fall was painful, it is still so damn funny I can&#8217;t help but laugh when I see it.  Keaton gave his all in a comedic performance, and his acting makes most modern-day comedians seem like amateurs.</p>
<p>Be it comedy or drama, silent films have what modern films don&#8217;t &#8211; simplicity in design, but superiority in output. I will forever be grateful to Dr. Kremling for introducing me to film as an art form, and I hope this will inspire at least one person to embrace a dying art&#8230;so perhaps it won&#8217;t die after all.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/588/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/588/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=588&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://swingstatevoter.me/2013/03/01/the-hidden-art-of-silent-films/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>25</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/1b118ee3646412af78505d1bf820a346?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">swingstatevoter</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://swingstatevoter.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/gish.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Gish</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://swingstatevoter.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/broken-blossoms.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Broken Blossoms</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://swingstatevoter.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/keaton.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Keaton</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hello, Six</title>
		<link>http://joylovelyjoy.wordpress.com/2013/03/13/hello-6/</link>
		<comments>http://joylovelyjoy.wordpress.com/2013/03/13/hello-6/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2013 14:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lara</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[letters to my daughter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[6]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[a letter to my daughter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Anne Lamott]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[birthday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[go and wake up your luck]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lucky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[turning six]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://joylovelyjoy.wordpress.com/?p=527</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;Go and wake up your luck&#8221; -Persian Proverb Dear Mia, As of 10:32 this morning, you are 6. This is how it happens, I know, the days of the year circling back to this one when I first held my heart outside my body. I watched you squirm and scream, red-faced and mad, until you [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=527&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;"><em><strong>&#8220;Go and wake up your luck&#8221;</strong> </em></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><em></em>-Persian Proverb</p>
<p>Dear Mia,</p>
<p>As of 10:32 this morning, you are 6.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://joylovelyjoy.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/picmonkey-collage.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-599" alt="Mia portrait collage" src="http://joylovelyjoy.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/picmonkey-collage.jpg?w=529&#038;h=176" width="529" height="176" /></a></p>
<p>This is how it happens, I know, the days of the year circling back to this one when I first held my heart outside my body. I watched you squirm and scream, red-faced and mad, until you were in my arms. Suddenly, you stopped and settled and I thought,</p>
<p><em>Lucky me,</em></p>
<p><em>          Lucky me,</em></p>
<p><em>                    Lucky me.</em></p>
<p>I could go on like this, waxing nostalgic about beating hearts and secret languages and umbilical chords that are never truly cut, but today you are 6 and yesterday was not such a good day.</p>
<p><em>&#8220;I don&#8217;t have a switch you can turn on to make me nice.&#8221;</em></p>
<p>Arms crossed, back hunched, tears pooling at the rims of blue eyes.</p>
<p><em>Hello, 6.</em></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://joylovelyjoy.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/mia133-11-13.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-620" alt="Mia, 6" src="http://joylovelyjoy.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/mia133-11-13.jpg?w=230&#038;h=423" width="230" height="423" /></a></p>
<p>The thing about mothering is this: I thought I would have all the answers by now. I thought I would be a seasoned pro by the time 6 rolled around. I thought I would be an authority, a veteran. Turns out, I&#8217;m still winging it because the moment you were born so too was I. The mother in me turns 6 today too.</p>
<p>For the past few weeks I have felt this day fast approaching, leaving me untethered and wandering, watching you race ahead to 6 while I say my final goodbyes to 5. The very same 5 with which I had<a title="5" href="http://joylovelyjoy.wordpress.com/2012/09/14/5/"> just recently made amends</a>.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://joylovelyjoy.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/mia63-11-13.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-601" alt="Mia, 6" src="http://joylovelyjoy.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/mia63-11-13.jpg?w=238&#038;h=423" width="238" height="423" /></a></p>
<p>I think 5 might be my favorite age, full of intellectual growth and independence &#8211; an ability to converse and interact in a way that you couldn&#8217;t before. Last week you wrote personal notes to all the girls in your class that said things like, <em>“I love your eyes that are brown,”</em> and <em>“You been a good friend to me,”</em> and <em>&#8220;I just love your hare.&#8221;</em> I find rainbow colored hearts tucked into your backpack, all labeled<em> Mommy.</em> You bring paperwork home with stories and scribbles doodled on the back. Rather than playing with toys, you invest yourself in writing picture books and illustrating fashion books.</p>
<blockquote><p>You are <strong>lucky</strong> to be one of those people who wishes to build sand castles with words, who is willing to create a place where your imagination can wander&#8230;I think this is a wonderful kind of person to be.&#8221;   ~Anne Lamott</p></blockquote>
<p>Sometimes when you need a break from the noise and raucous of your brothers I find you curled on your bed reading (reading!) a chapter book (by yourself!). As awe-inspiring as it is to bear witness to this growth, it comes with a bittersweet realization: You will never be 5 again.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://joylovelyjoy.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/mia113-11-13.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-603" alt="Mia, 6" src="http://joylovelyjoy.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/mia113-11-13.jpg?w=250&#038;h=423" width="250" height="423" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">It used to be that I had to lay in bed with you until you fell asleep. Now I choose to stay. It&#8217;s in the dark of your room &#8212; tucked under the covers, breath and stillness between us &#8212; that you tell me scraps and snippets of your day, things you don&#8217;t say in the light.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><em>&#8220;I like morning better than night.&#8221;</em></p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><em>&#8220;Why?&#8221;</em></p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><em>&#8220;Because I&#8217;m afraid of the dark sky.&#8221;</em></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">You ask me if vampires are real and how do I know and what are vampires anyway. You ask us if we believe in God and how do we know. You ask if I will die and leave you and how do I know.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><a href="http://joylovelyjoy.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/mia123-11-13.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-614" alt="Mia, 6" src="http://joylovelyjoy.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/mia123-11-13.jpg?w=283&#038;h=423" width="283" height="423" /></a><em>&#8220;Go and wake up your luck.&#8221;</em></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">I don&#8217;t remember the first time I heard this quote, but these are the words that find me when I climb the stairs to wake you up every morning before school. And now as I&#8217;m finishing up this post, I look at the clock and realize it&#8217;s almost time to wake you up. Once again, these quiet morning hours have flown by and I still have a million items to check off my to-do list. I swat at thoughts and worries that swarm about my head and brush away the general feeling of being overwhelmed. As I climb the stairs to wake you with kisses on your 6th birthday I&#8217;m only thinking,</p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><em>Lucky me,</em></p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><em>          Lucky me,</em></p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><em>                    Lucky me.</em></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">I love you to the moon and back.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">xo,</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Mommy</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">This post is part of <a title="Collectively Creative" href="http://cobwebscupcakesandcrayons.com/2012/10/19/collectively-creative/" target="_blank">Collectively Creative</a>, hosted by Kelly of <a title="Cobwebs, Cupcakes &amp; Crayons" href="http://cobwebscupcakesandcrayons.com/" target="_blank">Cobwebs, Cupcakes &amp; Crayons</a>. To read more on this month&#8217;s theme, &#8220;Lucky&#8221;, check out these links:</p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><a title="Cobwebs, Cupcakes &amp; Crayons Lucky Post" href="http://wp.me/p1Jcjh-1ej" target="_blank">Jell-O Shamrocks: A Kid’s Lucky Snack</a> - (Cobwebs, Cupcakes &amp; Crayons)</p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><a title="Pillows A La Mode" href="http://wp.me/p1SvbW-2lO" target="_blank">A Lucky Save!</a> - (Pillows A-La-Mode)</p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><a title="Time With Thea Lucky Post" href="http://wp.me/p26t5y-Pc" target="_blank">DIY Craft: ‘Stained Glass’ Shamrock</a> - (Time With Thea)</p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><a title="The Thing About Joan Lucky Post" href="http://wp.me/p2du4c-v8" target="_blank">The many meanings of “lucky”</a> - (The Thing About Joan)</p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><a title="Green Door Hospitality Lucky Post" href="http://wp.me/p22JCi-HN" target="_blank">This Party Calls For A Theme:  It’s All Rainbows and Unicorns</a> - (Green Door Hospitality)</p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><a title="A Ponytail Kind Of Day Lucky Post" href="http://wp.me/p2A17p-bD" target="_blank">Keep Calm and Pinch On</a> - (A Ponytail Kind Of Day)</p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><a title="My Healthy 'Ohana Lucky Post" href="http://wp.me/p1GSiF-zw" target="_blank">Honorary Irish and my favorite Irish Soda Bread</a> - (My Healthy ‘Ohana)</p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><a title="Minerva's Hand Lucky Edition Post" href="http://wp.me/p1fAgS-3d" target="_blank">Luck o’the Irish for Easter!</a>  - (Minerva’s Hand)</p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><a title="Now At Home Mom Lucky Edition" href="http://wp.me/p2PK2e-oQ" target="_blank">Lucky Gold Elephant</a> – (Now at Home Mom)</p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><a title="Gentle Stitches Lucky Post" href="http://wp.me/p2FLQT-ny" target="_blank">Make your own luck (using a crochet hook)</a> - (Gentle Stitches)</p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><a title="Asian Cucumber Salad" href="http://wp.me/p2EYpb-nU" target="_blank">Asian Cucumber Salad</a> – (Inspire and Indulge)</p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><a href="http://joylovelyjoy.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/the-lucky-edition-logo-march-2013.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-624" alt="The Lucky Edition Logo March 2013" src="http://joylovelyjoy.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/the-lucky-edition-logo-march-2013.jpg?w=249&#038;h=300" width="249" height="300" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=527&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://joylovelyjoy.wordpress.com/2013/03/13/hello-6/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>45</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/e3f177b89278e92b00a1d4f63df9906a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">laralovelyjoy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://joylovelyjoy.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/picmonkey-collage.jpg?w=529" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mia portrait collage</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://joylovelyjoy.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/mia133-11-13.jpg?w=287" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mia, 6</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://joylovelyjoy.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/mia63-11-13.jpg?w=297" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mia, 6</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://joylovelyjoy.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/mia113-11-13.jpg?w=313" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mia, 6</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://joylovelyjoy.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/mia123-11-13.jpg?w=354" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mia, 6</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://joylovelyjoy.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/the-lucky-edition-logo-march-2013.jpg?w=249" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The Lucky Edition Logo March 2013</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>I Am Jane Doe</title>
		<link>http://makemeasammich.org/2013/03/17/i-am-jane-doe/</link>
		<comments>http://makemeasammich.org/2013/03/17/i-am-jane-doe/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2013 16:07:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Rosie</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Dark Places]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Men]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jane Doe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ma'lik Richmond]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rape]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rape culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sexual assault]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[society]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Steubenville]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Steubenville Ohio]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trent Mays]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[victim blaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Victims]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://makemeasammich.org/?p=2369</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[[Warning: This post is about rape.] I was fourteen years old the night my friend G took me to my first kegger. We told my mom we were going to “a little get together.” I remember almost nothing about the evening—flashes, mostly. I remember absolutely nothing about being raped that night. I might never have [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2369&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://makemeasammich.org/2013/03/17/i-am-jane-doe/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>59</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/08d32088b4cbea4649532b22b4e3cef2?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">makemeasammichrosie</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://girlempowered.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/womanreclining.jpeg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Untitled by Ernst Ewerbeck</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://girlempowered.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/dontbethatguy.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">dontbethatguy</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Five Best Scotch Whiskies</title>
		<link>http://theholbornmag.com/2013/03/15/5-best-scotch-whiskies/</link>
		<comments>http://theholbornmag.com/2013/03/15/5-best-scotch-whiskies/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 12:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>theholborn1</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[The Bar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cocktails]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Drinks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pubs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[restaurants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scotch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scotch whisky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[whiskey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Whisky]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://theholbornmag.com/?p=5639</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#160; Scotch is a drink that is the remnant of an older, wilder world. At some point   before the Eighteenth century cravat wearers in mahogany rooms chuckled to themselves about toppling financial competitors, scotch whisky &#8211; yes, spelled without an “e&#8221; was essential to life. As you may know, the Gaelic phrase for whisky is [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=5639&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://theholbornmag.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/title-whiskey.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-6760" alt="title whiskey" src="http://theholbornmag.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/title-whiskey.png?w=251&#038;h=246" width="251" height="246" /><br />
</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Scotch is a drink that is the remnant of an older, wilder world. At some point   before the Eighteenth century cravat wearers in mahogany rooms chuckled to themselves about toppling financial competitors, scotch whisky &#8211; yes, spelled without an “e&#8221; was essential to <em>life</em>. As you may know, the Gaelic phrase for whisky is “<em>uisge beatha</em>,” and translates literally to “water of life.” For men traveling through the hebridian wilderness on horseback, it provided warmth during long rides and worked as a tasty disinfectant for various cuts and bruises.</p>
<p>After countless hours of imbibing and years of wincing,  I’ve come to realise scotch is a beautiful towering monument to craft and deliciousness. But, don’t take my word for it; take Noah S. Sweat’s famous “whiskey speech” as the definitive testament. Delivered in 1952 in opposition to a proposed whisky ban, the then 24-year-old congressman said:</p>
<p>“But, if when you say whiskey you mean the oil of conversation, the philosophic wine, the ale that is consumed when good fellows get together, that puts a song in their hearts and laughter on their lips, and the warm glow of contentment in their eyes; if you mean Christmas cheer; if you mean the stimulating drink that puts the spring in the old gentleman’s step on a frosty, crispy morning; if you mean the drink which enables a man to magnify his joy, and his happiness, and to forget, if only for a little while, life’s great tragedies, and heartaches, and sorrows; if you mean that drink, the sale of which pours into our treasuries untold amounts, which are used to provide tender care for our little crippled children, our blind, our deaf, our dumb, our pitiful aged and infirm; to build highways and hospitals and schools, then certainly I am for it.</p>
<p>This is my stand. I will not retreat from it. I will not compromise.”</p>
<p>With that in mind, The Holborn contacted some of the best Bartenders around, and Tom Gavin, American ex-pact and former London clubman came back to us with a lip-smacking collection that would make a Jehovah&#8217;s Witness hit the hard stuf.  Many of these whiskies are single-barrel releases hand-selected by retired Bartender and Whisky champion Richard Maynard, whose held positions and some of the world&#8217;s most respected drinking institutions &#8211; a chap who, to put it simply knows more about Scotch than you or I could ever dream of. They have been selected on the basis of quality, accessibility and o course, the taste.</p>
<p>We stand with Mr. Sweat; don’t compromise.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">I)<em><a href="http://www.thewhiskyexchange.com/P-15859.aspx"> Gordon and MacPhail Caol Ila 12 year</a>, </em>£42.95 &#8211; The Whisky Exchange<br />
&#8221;Beautiful, barbecued fruit can be smelled across the room. Seriously. One tiny glass generates a profound amount of smoky rose with peppermint wafting in the background. On the palate the whisky starts with a salty toffee sweetness, followed by smoked malt and a bit of lemon. The slightly oily body coasts along and the finish goes for miles.&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://www.thewhiskyexchange.com/P-15859.aspx"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-6755" alt="Whisky1" src="http://theholbornmag.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/whisky1.jpg?w=360&#038;h=466" width="360" height="466" /></a></p>
<p>II)<em><a href="http://www.masterofmalt.com/whiskies/scapa-2000-gordon-and-macphail-whisky/?srh=1"> Gordon and MacPhail Scapa 11 year</a>, </em>£39.95 &#8211; Master of Malt<br />
&#8221;Orange cream. White pepper. Sea spray. Soft and delicate body. A perfect balance of spice and fruit that coyly moves across the tongue at a snail’s pace, evolving and changing every second. This is a perfect before-dinner scotch. Or breakfast scotch, depending on the company you keep…&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="//www.masterofmalt.com/whiskies/scapa-2000-gordon-and-macphail-whisky/?srh=1"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-6756" alt="Whisky 2" src="http://theholbornmag.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/whisky-2.jpg?w=360&#038;h=466" width="360" height="466" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><em><br />
</em>III)<em><a href="http://www.masterofmalt.com/whiskies/benromach-10-year-old-whisky/"> Bendromach 10 Year</a>, </em>£27.67 &#8211; Master Of Malt<br />
&#8221;Melted caramel drizzled over a pile of brown sugar atop a brownie. Seriously. The aroma is intoxicating. It could be the Lana Del Ray currently blasting out of the studio speakers, but there is something romantic about this whiskey. It’s aggressive, yet graceful. And rough around the edges to start, then mellowing into a honey coated malty cloud that floats around your brain.&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://www.masterofmalt.com/whiskies/benromach-10-year-old-whisky/"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-6757" alt="Bendromach" src="http://theholbornmag.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/bendromach.jpg?w=360&#038;h=466" width="360" height="466" /><br />
</a></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">IV) <em><a href="http://www.ocado.com/webshop/product/Springbank-10-Year-Old-Single-Malt/46775011?sku=46775011&amp;dnr=y">Springbank 10 year</a>, </em>£32. 29 &#8211; Watroise/Ocado<br />
&#8221;This is the last distillery to carry out every production process on site. This old-school dram is lush and phenomenal, with a slick, oily body and a sweet front-end blast. Then, the spices invades like the Romans and gives you no chance for escape. It slays for all the right reasons with soft sherry, vanilla and tangerine. Look out.&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://theholbornmag.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/springbank.jphttp://www.ocado.com/webshop/product/Springbank-10-Year-Old-Single-Malt/46775011?sku=46775011&amp;dnr=y"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-6758" alt="Springbank" src="http://theholbornmag.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/springbank.jpg?w=360&#038;h=466" width="360" height="466" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">V)<em><a href="http://www.thedrinkshop.com/products/nlpdetail.php?prodid=2998"> Gordon and MacPhail Glenturret Distillery 10 Year</a> </em>£36.35 &#8211; The Drink Shop<br />
&#8221;This guy doesn’t mess around. It’s like the scotch equivalent of a missile; super intense, very loud, kind of scary, but awesome. Like a missile, it’s focused and precise. With ample spice and hazelnut blasting away, somehow ripe mango makes an appearance, soothing the palate and making you think that sometimes, you have to enter with a bang.&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://www.thedrinkshop.com/products/nlpdetail.php?prodid=2998"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-6759" alt="whisky 3" src="http://theholbornmag.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/whisky-3.jpg?w=360&#038;h=466" width="360" height="466" /></a></p>
<p><em>Richard Maynard &amp; JMN</em></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5639/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5639/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=5639&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://theholbornmag.com/2013/03/15/5-best-scotch-whiskies/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>18</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/e2de0d4a541ba404e7d21226cd563c46?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">theholborn1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theholbornmag.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/title-whiskey.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">title whiskey</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theholbornmag.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/whisky1.jpg?w=450" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Whisky1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theholbornmag.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/whisky-2.jpg?w=450" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Whisky 2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theholbornmag.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/bendromach.jpg?w=450" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Bendromach</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theholbornmag.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/springbank.jpg?w=450" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Springbank</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theholbornmag.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/whisky-3.jpg?w=450" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">whisky 3</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tiredness</title>
		<link>http://ecclekticgh.wordpress.com/2013/03/18/tiredeness/</link>
		<comments>http://ecclekticgh.wordpress.com/2013/03/18/tiredeness/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 18:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>I, Ghanaian</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Thinking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thoughts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ECG]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ghana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ghana Electricity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ghana Government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ghana petrol]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ghana problems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ghana Water]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://ecclekticgh.wordpress.com/?p=331</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;m tired. I&#8217;ve been oscillating between apathy and the kind of anger that makes my chest feel tight, that makes my voice tremble when I shout. Sometimes I&#8217;m despondent; the silver lining on Ghanaian clouds is the first flash of a lightning bolt, watch out for that, it&#8217;ll get ya. Sometimes I&#8217;m hopeful; it&#8217;s still [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=331&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://ecclekticgh.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/wpid-20130318_141840_01.jpg"><img title="20130318_141840_0.jpg" class="alignnone size-full" alt="image" src="http://ecclekticgh.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/wpid-20130318_141840_01.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>I&#8217;m tired. I&#8217;ve been oscillating between apathy and the kind of anger that makes my chest feel tight, that makes my voice tremble when I shout. Sometimes I&#8217;m despondent; the silver lining on Ghanaian clouds is the first flash of a lightning bolt, watch out for that, it&#8217;ll get ya. Sometimes I&#8217;m hopeful; it&#8217;s still better here (for me) than elsewhere (and I don&#8217;t mean the places with war and strife, I mean the UK and the US). Sometimes I pray. I&#8217;m Christian but I never understood why people prayed for their country till now. God gave us free will and a country runs on the amalgamation of that free will. So sure, I&#8217;d pray that <em>I</em> wouldn&#8217;t do something stupid with <em>my own</em> free will but praying for the country sounded like an infringement. If people chose to drive like maniacs, vote like lemmings and lead like pirates then far be it from God to stop them, right? That was then. This is now and what the fuck else am I supposed to do? I am so tired. I&#8217;m tired of thinking and analyzing, problem solving and solution hunting. I&#8217;m tired of talking, writing and typing onto screens that people can&#8217;t read or afford to read, whispering in front of my elders and screaming at the top of my lungs to anyone else who will listen. My God, I&#8217;m tired of talking. I&#8217;m tired of risking my life every single time I sit in a car, whether it&#8217;s moving or not. I&#8217;m tired of telling policemen I don&#8217;t have any money to give them (the state pays them to do a job that they&#8217;re not doing in the first place.)  I&#8217;m tired for the people on the street whose government couldn&#8217;t care less and who can&#8217;t get a couple of coins from passing cars because the police got to the car first. I&#8217;m tired of not having lights, water, internet or phone reception and I&#8217;m tired of listening to people complain about lights, water, and internet as if these problems just started when 90% of our country hasn&#8217;t had any of these things at all for the last twenty years.</p>
<p>Do you really think that a ten percent tithe and a couple of cedis to a handicapped person at a traffic light constitutes a social security net? Do you really think that spending three extra hours at your nine to five and then spending a fraction of your paycheck at a local market is enough to pick the country up? Do I think that if I write a book or a blog that only half the country can read and only a fraction of that half can understand I&#8217;m somehow helping?  Do we honestly believe that if we run this country just like those places where we got our fancy degrees everything&#8217;s gonna turn out alright? As if our only issue is an inability to emulate our &#8220;gods&#8221;. I ain&#8217;t mad atcha, though. A man could go insane in a country like this if he didn&#8217;t believe in fantasies like that.</p>
<p>They are fantasies, though. Lies too. Whether the liars knew it or not. &#8220;If you all just work for yourselves everybody will be better off&#8221;. No. They won&#8217;t. That&#8217;s not true here. Maybe they&#8217;re lying to themselves too. Maybe this recent slew of recessions is proof of that. Maybe it isn&#8217;t. But here, in this place, I know for a fact that that &#8220;selfish motivations for the greater good&#8221; line is just well researched manure. Out here that shit is just not gonna cut it. We are not them. We are so very different from them. This much I know: If everyone in this country woke up at dawn tomorrow and worked as hard as possible for eight hours a day, everyday for the next ten years and made all their economic decisions based on their own selfish needs we still wouldn&#8217;t have lights or water consistently or good roads or proper rule of law. Economics as we know it is based on behaviour and we do not behave the same way as them. So I&#8217;ll say it again. That shit. Is not. The way. </p>
<p>If you don&#8217;t believe that we&#8217;re so different that we need to follow a fundamentally different economic model then believe this: Our government is so broken that all the basic assumptions of that economics are moot here. Not just this incarnation of the government, either. I&#8217;m talking about our government as an institution, as a concept. That government will fail us at every turn. That government has embraced every-man-for-himself at a level that would shame Bernie Madoff. Don&#8217;t get it twisted, people. If you want this country to be better tomorrow that it was today then nine times out of ten you&#8217;ll be fighting, begging, clawing and dragging our government kicking and screaming into that brighter future.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m tired of talking about the government. Selflessness as economic activity. That&#8217;s my bottom line. Acknowledging the part of us that isn&#8217;t inherently selfish. Even if at the beginning it&#8217;s only because you don&#8217;t want those &#8220;other people&#8221; banging on your gate and demanding your selflessness. Make no mistake this is still Africa and we don&#8217;t deal with inequality by going on camping trips in the big city.</p>
<p>One more thing. A lot of people think that we&#8217;re not that bad. &#8220;Some other country has power problems worse than ours&#8221; or &#8220;we&#8217;ve five free and fair elections in a row&#8221; so we&#8217;re good. But you know what? The day before Sierra Leone had their first civil war people were getting ready for a nationwide celebration. The day before Côte d&#8217;Ivoire had their first civil war people in Ghana were using Côte d&#8217;Ivoire as an example of where Ghana should be. Why, when I see the problems we face, would I pretend that it&#8217;s ok for now or focus on the fact that it could be worse? It&#8217;s not ok, and it could be so much better! To the people who are highlighting the good things about Ghana to a world that doesn&#8217;t  know how much we contribute, please keep keeping on. You keep doing that and I&#8217;ll do this. I&#8217;ve got nothing to prove to anybody. I see the dirt behind the shine out there. I know them and I know us and I choose to live here because this is where I see the potential. In spurts and fits and in slivers between the dross but I do see it. I&#8217;m still tired. Sometimes I just stop. I&#8217;m also hopeful, though. I guess that means that sometimes I get back up and keep going.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/331/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/331/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=331&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://ecclekticgh.wordpress.com/2013/03/18/tiredeness/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>18</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/3f2adad07e7bf09ef605fa83ab1fdda1?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ecclekticgh</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ecclekticgh.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/wpid-20130318_141840_01.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">20130318_141840_0.jpg</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sorry, But You Really Look Terrible in That Shirt</title>
		<link>http://icescreammama.com/2013/03/18/sorry-but-you-really-look-terrible-in-that-shirt-oh-and-fix-your-hair-youre-welcome/</link>
		<comments>http://icescreammama.com/2013/03/18/sorry-but-you-really-look-terrible-in-that-shirt-oh-and-fix-your-hair-youre-welcome/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 11:26:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>icescreammama</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[being judgmental]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exercise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grandmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[running]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stress release]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thinking]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://icescreammama.com/?p=2164</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Yesterday, with the sun warming my face and last night’s ice cream still cool in my belly, I decided to take my running sneakers out of hibernation and hit the streets for my first run of the new year. Although I exercise regularly, I only run outside in fair weather. With the temperature nearing 50 [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2164&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-size:13px;line-height:19px;">Yesterday, with the sun warming my face and last night’s ice cream still cool in my belly, I decided to take my running sneakers out of hibernation and hit the streets for my first run of the new year. Although I exercise regularly, I only run outside in fair weather. With the temperature nearing 50 degrees, my brain was itching for the fresh air instead of the stale gym odors that I had been inhaling all winter.</span></p>
<p>So I layered up and set out; one foot in front of the other, trip trapping down my street. It had been while, but it felt good. I missed going on autopilot through my neighborhood, while losing myself in my head. What would I think about today? I wondered and considered my options.</p>
<p>Should I wallow over my father’s declining state? That could get me through miles.</p>
<p>Or, should I think of snappy comebacks to the friend who recently said, “Wow, it’s so great that you can just go out without doing anything to yourself. I could never do that.”</p>
<p>Oh, I got it! How bout….  “You’re right. You totally look better <em>with</em> makeup.”</p>
<p>Wait! No! Better… “Thanks. It’s true. You really need self-confidence to pull it off.”</p>
<p>Hmm.. I’ll get back to that.</p>
<p>There’s always the to-do list. First shower, then supermarket, dry cleaners, stop for Dunkin Donut’s coffee, pick up kid…</p>
<p>Wow, figuring out what I’m going to think about has gotten me through over a mile. Yay. I should probably think about what to wear to tomorrow night’s School Social. Certainly not pants like the lady who just walked past me. Really? Flesh colored leggings? I don’t know anyone who can pull that off. I almost want to follow her and let her know that unless she’s auditioning for ‘What Not To Wear’, they should never be worn again.</p>
<p>In my college sweatshirt, skull cap, striped gloves and yoga pants that make my thighs look too heavy, I have no business criticizing anyone, yet I have to fight the urge to share my feelings.</p>
<p>Maybe it’s genetic. It would be something my grandma would have done. I can still remember her walking over to poor, unsuspecting strangers and saying things like, “Honey, no one’s going to tell you, but that lipstick color looks horrible on you.”</p>
<p>I always died a little, totally mortified, but now, decades later, it doesn’t seem like the worst idea. I mean, yeah, it can be seen as judgmental, but maybe it’s just being helpful. Maybe, sometimes we all need someone like that; a ‘truth teller’ in the form of a well-meaning stranger.</p>
<p>I mean who else would tell you these things? Certainly not your friends. No way will your friends tell you how fat you look in your jeans, or that –</p>
<p>Wow! The lady I just passed must be bathing in perfume.</p>
<p>What was I thinking? I might have blacked out there a moment. Oh, right, friends. They love you and don’t want to hurt your feelings. They can’t be completely honest.</p>
<p>I don’t know if the sweat has seeped into my brain, but I think this is a kick ass idea. I can open a school and train people on proper approach, having good ‘street-side’ manner, and of course, how to diffuse an offended person’s wrath. My people will be like secret agents. Employers will hire us to do an office walk-thru. Friends will hire us to say things they can’t say. It’s a public service. It’s genius!</p>
<p>I can’t believe it. I’m almost home. That was fantastic.</p>
<p>Wait, I just came up with the best comeback to my friend’s comment. Ready?</p>
<p>“You’re right. But you know, saying things like that is the reason a lot of people don’t like you.”</p>
<p>Boom!</p>
<p>Brutal Honesty. My grandma would have loved it. But would people actually appreciate the truth whispered to them by an unknown judge?</p>
<p>I don’t know, but i&#8217;ll have to think about it next time. I’ve just run out of steam.</p>
<div id="attachment_2166" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 194px"><a href="http://icescreammama.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/brittney-bad-bra.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-2166" alt="Brittney, Let's talk about that bra. I'm here to help. " src="http://icescreammama.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/brittney-bad-bra.jpg?w=184&#038;h=274" width="184" height="274" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Brittney, let&#8217;s talk about that bra. I&#8217;m here to help.</p></div>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2164/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2164/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2164&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://icescreammama.com/2013/03/18/sorry-but-you-really-look-terrible-in-that-shirt-oh-and-fix-your-hair-youre-welcome/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>88</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/4ffeafd3190f4a32945a842981489aa6?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">icescreammama</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://icescreammama.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/brittney-bad-bra.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Brittney, Let&#039;s talk about that bra. I&#039;m here to help. </media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
