<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 21:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Introvert Fairy Tales: The Princess and the Pea</title>
		<link>http://introvertfairytales.com/2013/01/31/introvert-fairy-tales-the-princess-and-the-pea/</link>
		<comments>http://introvertfairytales.com/2013/01/31/introvert-fairy-tales-the-princess-and-the-pea/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2013 23:15:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sophie</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fairy tales]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[introvert]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[princess]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://introvertfairytales.com/?p=104</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It wasn&#8217;t that the chairs were uncomfortable. After shelling out for what had been billed as a &#8220;Premium Cinema Experience&#8221; they were practically four poster beds. The red velvet was new and plush, the back and headrest were at the ideal angle for viewing the screen and the armrests were sturdy enough to keep distance [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=104&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It wasn&#8217;t that the chairs were uncomfortable. After shelling out for what had been billed as a &#8220;Premium Cinema Experience&#8221; they were practically four poster beds. The red velvet was new and plush, the back and headrest were at the ideal angle for viewing the screen and the armrests were sturdy enough to keep distance enough between strangers (and movable enough to close that distance for other purposes if and as required). Even the film itself was living up to expectations.</p>
<p>No, the problem wasn&#8217;t the upholstery. The problem was the people. The people who brought in food in crinkly wrappers. The people who couldn&#8217;t go more than three scenes without illuminating their phones, creating for the people behind them the galaxy&#8217;s most transient and irritating constellations. The people who slurped. The people who rustled. The people who TALKED.</p>
<p>Some time thereafter a small, experimental screening series started at the cinema. They never played on the larger screens and maybe they never would be in the theatres with the hydraulic seats, but the &#8220;Silent Movies&#8221; sessions became a modest success. The rules were simple: you could laugh at something funny, gasp at something shocking or discretely cry at something sad, but otherwise you were silent. The premium ticket price went to paying the ushers who ejected those who preferred, shall we say, a more interactive cinematic experience.</p>
<p>Not everyone understood the appeal, but those who did went all the time.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/104/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/104/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=104&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://introvertfairytales.com/2013/01/31/introvert-fairy-tales-the-princess-and-the-pea/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/4d582374a5335c5ed9df397623bab01b?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">postcardsandpaperbacks</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Personal Appeal to Britain\&#8217;s Politicians: Fuel Poverty is Killing People</title>
		<link>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/24/a-personal-appeal-to-britains-politicians-wake-up-from-your-warm-dreams-fuel-poverty-is-killing-people/</link>
		<comments>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/24/a-personal-appeal-to-britains-politicians-wake-up-from-your-warm-dreams-fuel-poverty-is-killing-people/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2013 12:53:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tallbloke</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[atmosphere]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Carbon cycle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[climate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Clouds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gravity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Incompetence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Natural Variation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ocean dynamics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Philosophy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robber Barons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shale gas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Solar physics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[solar system dynamics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tides]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/?p=11842</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[“The most revolutionary thing one can do always is to proclaim loudly what is happening.” Rosa Luxemburg There are times when I find it hard to speak politely. I left school at sixteen and worked on the shop-floor of a large engineering works for ten years, gaining a higher national qualification in mechanical and production [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=11842&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;"><em>“The most revolutionary thing one can do always is to proclaim loudly what is happening.”</em><br />
<em>Rosa Luxemburg</em><br />
<a href="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/tod_kaiser.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-11843" alt="tod_kaiser" src="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/tod_kaiser.jpg?w=266&#038;h=255" width="266" height="255" /></a></p>
<p>There are times when I find it hard to speak politely. I left school at sixteen and worked on the shop-floor of a large engineering works for ten years, gaining a higher national qualification in mechanical and production engineering along the way before getting the chance to study for a degree in the History and Philosophy of Science. While I worked in heavy industry, I learned some choice ways of expressing myself which are basic, direct, and hurt the sensibilities of those who have spent their lives in polite company, although they got the job done effectively. So I sometimes struggle to find the right tone at those times when a message needs communicating forcefully to people in a position to influence policy, but without having them recoil and ignore things they don&#8217;t want to contemplate.</p>
<p>But the time for niceties has passed. Britain&#8217;s people face a looming disaster of epic proportion. Britain&#8217;s political class needs to act swiftly to minimise the damage which cannot be wholly averted at this late stage. Successive governments have set the stage for the impending denouement, so this is not a partisan rant, but a cross-party appeal to common sense. People are <a href="http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/15/government-protect-wintering-birds-but-not-pensioners/">dying by the thousand</a> as a direct result of <a href="http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/23/christopher-booker-its-payback-time-for-britains-insane-energy-policy/">botched energy policy</a> and we must act to save lives. Now.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s clear some of the undergrowth so we can see the shape of the problem. Firstly, we&#8217;ll deal with the climate scare.</p>
<p><span id="more-11842"></span><strong>The Climate Question</strong></p>
<p>There is no &#8216;enhanced greenhouse effect&#8217; from rising levels of co2 in the atmosphere. Carbon dioxide is an essential trace gas with little radiative effect compared with the enormous quantity of water vapour in the air. The hydrological cycle has massive redundant capacity to provide a negative feedback to any increase in radiative forcing from additional airborne co2. In any case it is <a href="http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2012/09/12/is-the-airborne-co2-fraction-temperature-dependent/">by no means certain</a> that the majority of the increase in airborne co2 is <a href="http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2012/04/18/uncertainty-the-origin-of-the-increase-in-atmospheric-co2/">of human origin</a>.</p>
<p>The real drivers of climatic change; the cyclically varying make-up of radiation from the Sun, the tidal effects on ocean circulation caused by the Moon&#8217;s declination cycle, and the Earth&#8217;s tectonic and seismic responses to the changing disposition of the rest of the solar system masses, induce near repeating <a href="http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2011/06/30/further-terrestrial-evidence-of-planetary-cycles-affecting-climate/">cyclic patterns</a> in Earth&#8217;s ever-changing climatic history. Through the decomposition of the complex signal into <a href="http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2011/02/21/tallbloke-and-tim-channon-a-cycles-analysis-approach-to-predicting-solar-activity/">simpler sinusoidal components</a>, we are able to better determine their origin, and predict future changes.</p>
<p>The indications are that the Sun is going into a phase of low activity levels. This is likely to increase cloudiness and reduce sunshine hours. That will induce surface cooling for several decades to come.</p>
<p><strong>The Energy Issue</strong></p>
<p>Supplying society&#8217;s need for high quality securely distributed energy is paramount to our well being. Clean water supply, food, health, education, and all of modern society&#8217;s benefits stem from our production of energy. Cleaner air is a desirable aspiration, but it cannot take priority over basic requirements on which peoples lives depend. The emissions from coal burning power stations are not particularly toxic at the levels they are ingested, and some of the by-products, such as sulphur are of direct benefit to agriculture. Acid rain destroying Scandinavian forest is a long debunked myth. Sulphur dioxide doesn&#8217;t make us ill. Hypothermia kills people, especially old people who have paid their dues to society and have the right to a warm home in retirement.</p>
<p><strong>The Engineer&#8217;s Solution</strong></p>
<p>Take a leaf out of Germany&#8217;s book and Commence building modern replacements for Britain&#8217;s aging coal fired generation capacity NOW, with whatever heavy industrial capacity we have left. Frack for gas NOW. Get the Americans in to do it if necessary, but don&#8217;t offer our tax money, we pay enough for gas as it is. Just cut the red tape and they will come to work willingly, without subsidy. Re-open any viable coal mines we still have, and start building some new ones.</p>
<p><strong>The Political Situation</strong></p>
<p>It&#8217;s time to encourage the British Government to grow some bollocks and tell the unelected incompetents in Brussels to FUCK OFF.  Then it won&#8217;t be able to use the excuse that the European Large Plant Directive prevents us from solving our URGENT energy crisis in the most time efficient and self reliant way. Repeal the <a href="http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/24/major-uk-newspaper-calls-for-repeal-of-climate-change-act/">Climate Change Act</a> immediately, if not sooner. Use the money the European Union has been embezzling from us without providing audited accounts for the last two decades. Stop giving our tax money to thieves, NOW. If the British establishment doesn&#8217;t heed the warning, it will be brought down by cold, angry people voting for a populist party with no administrative experience. While it would be fun, it&#8217;s unlikely to solve the energy crisis which is upon us. The<a href="http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/22/gerard-wynn-uk-carbon-tax-to-be-levied-from-april-fools-day-get-ready-for-more-fuel-bill-hikes/"> new Carbon Tax</a> is an obvious ploy to steal more money from a cold population and will not be tolerated.</p>
<p><strong>Summary for Policy Makers</strong></p>
<p>Stop dicking around, the eyes of the people are upon you. If you don&#8217;t move fast to fix the mess you&#8217;ve created, their collective boot will be up your collective arse, and since the Labour and Conservative parties are the two cheeks of the same arse, pointing the finger at each other in parliament won&#8217;t appease the taxpayer.  You are our paid servants, not our masters, so shape up, or ship out.</p>
<p>I knew I wouldn&#8217;t be able to keep up the polite language once I started &#8216;the political bit&#8217;, oh well&#8230;</p>
<div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 610px"><img alt="" src="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/BGIIN8_CUAENRFb.jpg" width="600" height="399" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Queensbury West Yorkshire this morning. &#8220;Our children aren&#8217;t going to know what snow is&#8221; &#8211; Dr David Viner, Govt climate advisor 2002</p></div>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/11842/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/11842/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=11842&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tallbloke.wordpress.com/2013/03/24/a-personal-appeal-to-britains-politicians-wake-up-from-your-warm-dreams-fuel-poverty-is-killing-people/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>81</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/588acaa8d65126df21f9f213074b937a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tallbloke</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tallbloke.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/tod_kaiser.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tod_kaiser</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/BGIIN8_CUAENRFb.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>We Are Fandom, Hear us Roar</title>
		<link>http://3chicgeeks.com/2013/03/13/we-are-fandom-hear-us-roar/</link>
		<comments>http://3chicgeeks.com/2013/03/13/we-are-fandom-hear-us-roar/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2013 08:10:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Critique Geek</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[BBC Sherlock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Nerdiness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[baker street babes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[baker street irregulars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bbc sherlock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[doctor who]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fan culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fanboy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fandom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fangirl]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grapes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[martin freeman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Merlin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Moriarty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[participatory culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sherlock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[supernatural]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tumblr]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[twitter]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://3chicgeeks.com/?p=1193</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It’s a running joke that Tumblr is fueled by two things: hipsters and fandoms.  But mostly fandoms. Seriously, I dare you to find a hipster photography post that doesn&#8217;t get hijacked by the Supernatural, Doctor Who, Sherlock, or Merlin fandom at some point. I dare you. The beautiful thing about social media like Tumblr is that [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1193&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://3chicgeeks.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/we-are-fandom.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-1204" alt="we are fandom, hear us roar - a discourse on how a fandom can make or break anything on the internet." src="http://3chicgeeks.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/we-are-fandom.jpg?w=550&#038;h=218" width="550" height="218" /></a></p>
<p>It’s a running joke that Tumblr is fueled by two things: hipsters and fandoms.  But mostly fandoms. Seriously, I dare you to find a hipster photography post that doesn&#8217;t get hijacked by the <em>Supernatural</em>, <em>Doctor Who</em>, <em>Sherlock,</em> or<em> Merlin </em>fandom at some point. I dare you.</p>
<p>The beautiful thing about social media like Tumblr is that it has generated even more participatory culture amongst fangirls and fanboys everywhere. It&#8217;s easier than ever to paint your favorite character, remix a song, or make a fan video and share it with millions on a variety of platforms where fellow enthusiasts can offer criticism, praise, and even their own responses. Let&#8217;s not even get started on the gifs. Some shows, such as <em>BBC Sherlock</em>, have been gif&#8217;d so much that you can probably watch the entirety of the series in gifs.</p>
<p><span id="more-1193"></span>The instantaneous nature of the internet also means that fandom news travels fast. In fact, news travels so quickly that this photo of Benedict Cumberbatch and Martin Freeman turned into a fandom phenomenon in just a few hours&#8217; time on Monday, March 11th.</p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 478px"><img class=" " alt="" src="http://static.entertainmentwise.com/photos/Image/bbc%201.jpg" width="468" height="350" /><p class="wp-caption-text">It&#8217;s grape to see you too, buddy!</p></div>
<p>Yes, a simple silly picture taken between cast mates led to fan art, gifs, copycat pictures, and my personal favorite, the <a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=%23replacesherlockquoteswithgrape&amp;src=typd" target="_blank">#ReplaceSherlockQuotesWithGrape</a> tag on Twitter.</p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 410px"><img class=" " alt="" src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/712e6a73d2ae0761df1cd5ddb7c4c08a/tumblr_mjjypapKxx1s48lc7o1_500.jpg" width="400" height="294" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Okay, this one was pretty grape as well. <a href="http://25.media.tumblr.com/712e6a73d2ae0761df1cd5ddb7c4c08a/tumblr_mjjypapKxx1s48lc7o1_500.jpg" target="_blank">(Source)</a></p></div>
<p>Instead of relying on traditional news media, which can take days or even weeks to spread the word on a beloved show, we can all flock to our computer screens and have the latest news in a matter of minutes. And then we can all flail together.</p>
<p>You may be thinking: &#8220;Okay, so fans have all this access to other fan-generated content now. So what?&#8221;</p>
<p>The point is simple. Technology has changed the way in which we interact with each other as fans and has created a giant network of fans all across the world. We are not limited to sharing our love of a particular book or television show with only those in our immediate vicinity; the only limit to fandom groups now is internet access. However, this accessibility has lead to some criticism of the new generation of fandom.</p>
<p>Recently, the new wave of internet fandom has come under scrutiny, particularly in the Sherlock Holmes community. Some of the more traditional fan-based groups that pride themselves on their scholarly approach to their passion showed disdain for the new generation of Sherlockians. It is no secret that some prominent members of the Baker Street Irregulars (we&#8217;re looking at you, Shreffler) expressed their disapproval of popular podcasters, <a href="http://bakerstreetbabes.com/">The Baker Street Babes</a>. The situation even warranted a mention in a <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/03/07/books/suit-says-sherlock-belongs-to-the-ages.html?_r=0" target="_blank"><em>New York Times</em> article</a>. The fact that anyone&#8217;s &#8220;fan cred&#8221; can be questioned is ridiculous. The fact that female fans were targeted specifically YET AGAIN is outrageous. Didn&#8217;t we just fight this &#8220;fake geek girl&#8221; battle? Clearly the war is still ongoing.</p>
<p>The BSI and BSB situation raised an interesting dialogue on what it means to be a fan, one which we believe the majority of the BSI <a href="http://bakerstreetbabes.tumblr.com/post/43615655994/sherlockians-read-this-read-thiiiiiiiiiis" target="_blank">responded to beautifully</a>. The fact of the matter is, anyone can be a fan of something. It doesn&#8217;t truly matter how long you&#8217;ve been a fan of Sherlock Holmes or the Avengers. It doesn&#8217;t matter if you haven&#8217;t read every single canon story and if you don&#8217;t write academic essays on the homoerotic subtext of Batman comics. It doesn&#8217;t matter if you don&#8217;t regularly discuss the deeper symbolism of <em>Doctor Who</em> episodes at dinner parties. If you love something you are free to express that love and connect with others in any way you see fit. This is a truth that should go without saying.</p>
<p>Why then, does fan snobbery exist? The answer is quite simple. We, the online fandom generation, are a threat. In fact, we&#8217;re completely taking over. Not only do we interact with each other in new ways, but we also interact with the writers, actors, directors, artists, etc. in ways that traditional fan avenues could never hope to achieve. Sure, you can meet an actor at a convention, but do you really think that thirty second interaction is going to have as much impact on say, Martin Freeman, as does the existence of Tumblr? I don&#8217;t think so.</p>
<p>We, the online fandom, have everyone&#8217;s attention. We&#8217;re the ones helping to shape the shows we love. We&#8217;re the ones taking over social media as we know it. <em>And people are taking notice.</em></p>
<p>We are fandom, hear us ROAR.</p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 410px"><img class=" " alt="" src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/265eba91f92306429dd0fbade921b74e/tumblr_mgg44wlBbS1ric3reo1_500.gif" width="400" height="300" /><p class="wp-caption-text">ROOOOOOOOOAR <a href="http://25.media.tumblr.com/265eba91f92306429dd0fbade921b74e/tumblr_mgg44wlBbS1ric3reo1_500.gif" target="_blank">(Source)</a></p></div>
<p><em>P.S. We know you&#8217;re out there, Mr. Freeman, trolling us with your red pants and your grapes. We&#8217;re watching you watching us watch you. </em></p>
<h3>You May Also Like:</h3>
<h4><strong><em></em></strong><br />
<strong><em><a href="http://3chicgeeks.com/2013/02/04/fictional-boys-we-want-to-date-who-would-make-awful-boyfriends/">Fictional Boys We Want To Date (who would make awful boyfriends)<br />
</a></em></strong><strong><em></em></strong><strong><em></em></strong><strong><em><a title="Permalink to The Reichenbach Feels Playlist" href="http://3chicgeeks.com/2013/02/28/the-reichenbach-feels-playlist/" rel="bookmark">The Reichenbach Feels Playlist<br />
</a></em></strong><strong><em><a title="Permalink to Geek Girls Are Taking Over The World" href="http://3chicgeeks.com/2012/12/10/geek-girls-are-taking-over-the-world/" rel="bookmark">Geek Girls Are Taking Over The World</a></em></strong><strong><em><a title="Doctor Who Is Real: Reasons why I’m just going to sit here and wait for the TARDIS." href="http://3chicgeeks.com/2013/01/23/doctor-who-is-real-reasons-why-im-just-going-to-sit-here-and-wait-for-the-tardis/"><br />
</a></em></strong><strong><em><a title="Permalink to Ways to Distract Yourself Until the New Season of Sherlock Arrives" href="http://3chicgeeks.com/2012/11/12/ways-to-distract-yourself-until-the-new-season-of-sherlock-arrives/" rel="bookmark">Ways to Distract Yourself Until the New Season of Sherlock Arrives</a></em></strong></h4>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1193/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1193/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1193&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://3chicgeeks.com/2013/03/13/we-are-fandom-hear-us-roar/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>19</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/d4b57615b46e60660310839b7ac1267a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">chicgeeky</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://3chicgeeks.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/we-are-fandom.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">we are fandom, hear us roar - a discourse on how a fandom can make or break anything on the internet.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://static.entertainmentwise.com/photos/Image/bbc%201.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://25.media.tumblr.com/712e6a73d2ae0761df1cd5ddb7c4c08a/tumblr_mjjypapKxx1s48lc7o1_500.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://25.media.tumblr.com/265eba91f92306429dd0fbade921b74e/tumblr_mgg44wlBbS1ric3reo1_500.gif" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why You Shouldn&#8217;t Adopt a Dog</title>
		<link>http://paws4udogs.wordpress.com/2013/03/25/why-you-shouldnt-adopt-a-dog/</link>
		<comments>http://paws4udogs.wordpress.com/2013/03/25/why-you-shouldnt-adopt-a-dog/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 11:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Paws Abilities Dog Training</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Preventing Behavior Problems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rescue]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://paws4udogs.wordpress.com/?p=1890</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The ad is well-intentioned, as are my friends who share it on Facebook. “Adopt a less adoptable pet!” the ad urges, with examples of “less adoptable” traits such as old, blind, Pit Bull (really?&#8230;), or just different. “Don’t hate me because I’m less adoptable,” the ad pleads, “adopt me because I need you.” Now, my [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1890&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="http://paws4udogs.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/lessadoptable.jpg">ad</a> is well-intentioned, as are my friends who share it on Facebook. “Adopt a less adoptable pet!” the ad urges, with examples of “less adoptable” traits such as old, blind, Pit Bull (really?&#8230;), or just different. “Don’t hate me because I’m less adoptable,” the ad pleads, “adopt me because I need you.”</p>
<p>Now, my friends could tell you stories about my love for dogs who fit into some of these categories. I adore senior dogs, and when I put the word out that I was looking for a dog before I adopted Dobby, a friend joked that she would keep her eyes open for a three-legged, fearful, crotchety senior Pit Bull for me. I agreed that such a dog sounded lovely before I realized that she was pulling my leg.</p>
<div id="attachment_1891" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://paws4udogs.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/erick-pleitez.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1891" alt="Photo by Erick Pleitez" src="http://paws4udogs.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/erick-pleitez.jpg?w=500&#038;h=333" width="500" height="333" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Photo by Erick Pleitez</p></div>
<p>I adore many of the “less adoptable” dogs, but I think this ad campaign is abhorrent. In fact, <b>I would urge you never to adopt a dog because he needs you</b>. Don’t adopt a dog because you feel sorry for him. Don’t adopt a dog because of his appearance. Don’t adopt a dog because his story made you cry. Don’t adopt a dog because he looks sad or acts like he was abused. Don’t even adopt a dog because he’ll die otherwise. <b>Adopt a dog because he’s a good match and because you’ll make one another happy. </b>Anything less is unfair to <i>both</i> of you.</p>
<p>I understand the pull to help animals. My first day working at a local pet shop as a fifteen-year-old, I brought home a three-legged, mite-infested guinea pig that was being kept in back to be sold for snake food. My first paycheck didn’t even cover the cost of her vet bills, cage, food, and other essentials. Lucky the guinea pig later became a beloved nursery school pet, and I never regretted my decision to buy her.</p>
<p>However, every week I work with clients whose rescue stories don’t end so happily. <b>Love alone is not enough for every dog.</b> While it may feel good to save the life of that terrified, shivering dog who has pressed herself into the back corner of her kennel, bringing her home to a busy household with lots of visitors isn’t doing her any favors. In some cases, it’s merely prolonging the torture. Remember, dogs live in the moment, and every moment that your new dog spends plastered behind the sofa or barking frantically in the back room because yet another friend has stopped by to visit is painful to her. Emotional pain is every bit as cruel as physical pain. Not causing it doesn’t mean it’s okay for you to neglect to address it. And quite honestly, that bouncy, social dog in the kennel next to her (the one who would be a really great fit for your social lifestyle) needs you every bit as much.</p>
<p>Understand that I’m not saying that you shouldn’t adopt a dog who needs a little extra. Maybe you’re really good with shy dogs, and you don’t ever have any visitors, and you are a naturally patient person. In your case, that terrified dog could be a wonderful fit for your household. You’ll enjoy helping that dog blossom, and that dog will have a safe and caring environment in which to become the wonderful pet she wants to be. <b>The important consideration here isn’t whether your potential dog is perfect, but whether you and she are perfect for one another</b>.</p>
<p><b> There are thousands of wonderful dogs who would thrive in a home just like yours, and your job as an adopter is to find them.</b> Working with a <a href="http://paws4udogs.wordpress.com/2012/03/19/responsible-rescues/">responsible rescue </a>will help, but even before you get to that point, you need to take a moment to think about what you need. What traits does your ideal dog possess? Is he active or sedentary? Goofy or serious? Does he need to get along with children, visitors, cats, other dogs, livestock? Are you open to housetraining and teaching him basic obedience, or would you rather he already understand such things? Be honest about what will make you happy. Your ideal dog is someone else’s nightmare, so go find that dog and save <i>his</i> life, even if his situation may not have appeared as desperate as another dog’s.</p>
<p>If you work in a shelter or rescue, stop with the sob <a href="http://paws4udogs.wordpress.com/2011/11/25/train-the-dog-not-the-story/">stories</a> and emotional blackmail. If the only way you can save that dog is through suckering some soft-hearted person into taking them on, then I have some serious concerns. I’m not saying that you shouldn’t make your adopters feel like heroes. They are! However, you and I both know that most homeless dogs aren’t broken, merely unlucky. Let’s focus on their good traits, those things that will make them wonderful pets. Let’s focus on that ideal home and talk about why that home will be so incredibly lucky to have this great dog. Let’s do everything we can to make sure that the next home this dog winds up in is his last. Let’s make such solid, perfect matches that our adopters would do anything to keep that dog for the rest of his days, such solid matches that those people come back to you ten or fifteen years down the line when they are ready for another dog.</p>
<p><strong>Don’t adopt a dog because he needs you.</strong> Adopt a dog because <i>you</i> need <i>him</i>. <strong>Adopt a dog because you will make one another happy</strong>. Adopt a dog because you can’t imagine your life without him. There is no better feeling in the world, and no more heroic thing you can do.</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://paws4udogs.wordpress.com/category/behavior-modification/preventing-behavior-problems/'>Preventing Behavior Problems</a>, <a href='http://paws4udogs.wordpress.com/category/rescue/'>Rescue</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1890/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1890/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1890&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://paws4udogs.wordpress.com/2013/03/25/why-you-shouldnt-adopt-a-dog/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>37</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/fb61cd0b1292f9d14d1cd56ff90e3692?s=96&#38;d=wavatar&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">paws4udogs</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://paws4udogs.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/erick-pleitez.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Photo by Erick Pleitez</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Beatles’ Scariest Songs</title>
		<link>http://sticksasplaythings.wordpress.com/2013/03/25/your-guitar-weeps-because-it-is-terrified-the-beatles-scariest-songs/</link>
		<comments>http://sticksasplaythings.wordpress.com/2013/03/25/your-guitar-weeps-because-it-is-terrified-the-beatles-scariest-songs/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 17:37:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sticks As Playthings</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Drums]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[express]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fear]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[society]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Beatles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://sticksasplaythings.wordpress.com/?p=333</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The Beatles get a lot of credit.  They are generally considered to be the greatest musical entity of the 20th Century.  This makes sense, because they were.  Much has been written by individuals more qualified than myself about how The Fab Four revolutionized not just an entire music industry, but an entire generation of youth.  [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=333&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Beatles get a lot of credit.  They are generally considered to be the greatest musical entity of the 20th Century.  This makes sense, because they were.  Much has been written by individuals more qualified than myself about how The Fab Four revolutionized not just an entire music industry, but an entire generation of youth.  This makes sense, because they did.</p>
<p>Within the hallowed realm of Rock and Roll, The Beatles were progenitors, spokespeople, influencers, or inventors of a wide swath of musical stylings, from straight-ahead 50&#8242;s-style rock n&#8217; roll (&#8220;Twist and Shout&#8221;) to psychedelic (&#8220;I Am the Walrus&#8221;) to punk (the feedback opening to &#8220;I Feel Fine&#8221;, the entire post-1967 attitude of John Lennon) to heavy metal (&#8220;Helter Skelter&#8221;) to acoustic folk (&#8220;Norwegian Wood&#8221;) to protest rock (&#8220;Revolution&#8221;) to alt-freak free associative statement art (&#8220;Revoltuion 9&#8243;) to, of course, pop music (everything they ever wrote).  Their music was the stated foundation for acts as diverse as The Beach Boys and The Beastie Boys; Kurt Cobain and Katy Perry; Coldplay and The Clash.  Whatever music you are listening to right now- The Beatles influenced that sound.  Unless you are listening to Chuck Berry, JS Bach, or Gregorian chanting.  I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;m exaggerating.</p>
<p>The Beatles get a lot of credit.</p>
<p>But here&#8217;s a place where they are perhaps not as well-recognized as they could be: Liverpool&#8217;s finest could write some spine-tingling, dread-stirring, dark, twisted and disturbing material.  They were weird, they were imaginative, they had an occassionally morbid sense of humour, and they were way into hallucinogenic drugs: all of this translated into random spurts of darkness from the group most famous for wanting to hold our hand and only needing love.  To wit: this sunny little album cover of the boys in butcher gear, covered in raw meat.  Holding baby doll parts.</p>
<p><a href="http://sticksasplaythings.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/beatles-doll-parts.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-501 aligncenter" alt="Beatles Doll Parts" src="http://sticksasplaythings.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/beatles-doll-parts.jpg?w=300&#038;h=297" width="300" height="297" /></a></p>
<p>Therefore, for no apparent reason at all, I present to you&#8230;</p>
<p><strong>&#8220;The Ten Most Frightening Beatles Songs (according to my definition of fear, dread, and/or strong sense of discomfort) Of All Time&#8221;</strong></p>
<p><strong>10.</strong> <em></em><strong><em>“Eleanor Rigby”</em></strong>, Revolver (1966)<br />
Sometimes, the greatest fears are existential ones.  Is my life meaningful?  Do my actions have any significance?  Am I missing out on genuine human connection?  Is my ministry actively saving those around me from eternal damnation?  Is this mason jar large enough to contain my face?  All these questions are pondered by our two lonely protagonists, Eleanor Rigby and Father MacKenzie.  And for the most part, it seems their greatest existential fears have indeed been realized.  (At least her face fits in the jar by the door, though.)</p>
<p><b>9.</b><strong> <em>“She&#8217;s Leaving Home”</em></strong>, Sgt. Pepper&#8217;s LHCB (1967)<br />
This is a song about a young person&#8217;s desire to escape the rigidity of the life laid out for them by their parents expectations.  It was a defining song for a defining time: in 1967, young people were moving beyond the moral, societal and spiritual fences established by prior generations.  It is meant to be a song of liberation, freedom, and progress.  Now that I&#8217;m of parenting age, however, I can&#8217;t help but empathize with the horror the parents feel  at the realization that they have pushed their daughter into lonely flight.  As the string section swells, I feel a pang of fear that, in only a few short years, it could be myself asking, &#8220;What did we do that was wrong&#8221;?  Then I remember that this is just a pop song, and I get over it.</p>
<p><b>8.</b> <strong><em>“Happiness is a Warm Gun”</em></strong>, The White Album (1968)<br />
Perhaps it&#8217;s the connection to &#8220;Bowling for Columbine&#8221;, as Michael Moore soundtracked the tail end of this song to video footage of military assassinations, school shootings, and other random acts of gun terror.  But whenever I hear the almost cartoonish harmonies of &#8220;bang bang, shoot shoot!&#8221; in this chilling White Album mashup song, the irony is lost for just a moment.  Or maybe it&#8217;s simply the fact that a line like, &#8220;when I hold you in my arms/and feel my finger on your trigger&#8221; is intentionally uncomfortable.  And to think, the song title was inspired by a line from a Charlie Brown comic strip.  Maybe someone should do a Top Ten Scariest Charlie Brown Moments.  (I bet Schroeder would feature prominently in that list, with his callous, icy gaze&#8230;.)</p>
<p><b>7.</b> <strong><em>“Lucy in the Sky With Diamonds”</em></strong>, Sgt. Pepper&#8217;s LHCB (1967)<br />
The background story of the song is touching: John Lennon&#8217;s son, Julian, showed his daddy a picture he had drawn of Lucy, his classmate with kaleidoscopes for eyes, floating in a diamond-studded sky.  Adorable.  Until the psychedelic imagery gets fleshed out further, and suddenly you are floating down a river of terror, surrounded by towering technicolor flowers, &#8220;rocking horse people&#8221; (?), plasticine porters, and a girl with KALEIDOSCOPES FOR EYES.  Killer harmonies though.</p>
<p><b>6.</b> <strong><em>“Helter Skelter”</em></strong>, The White Album (1968)<br />
Even if a notorious cultic murdermonger (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Charles_Manson">Charles Manson</a>) hadn&#8217;t ordered his lackies to murder several wealthy socialites and then paint the words &#8216;Helter Skelter&#8217;, among other phrases, on the walls and refrigerator of their home <em>with the blood of their victims</em>; even if Charles Manson hadn&#8217;t believed his own twisted version of the lyrics to this song, wherein an apocalyptic war between the races would be ushered in by his sinister guidance; even if a book about these infamous murders hadn&#8217;t been written under the title &#8220;Helter Skelter&#8221;; even if none of that had ever happened, Helter Skelter would still be kind of scary.  You know, because it&#8217;s aggressively loud and stuff.  Maybe blisters on your fingers are the least of your worries.</p>
<p><b>5.</b> <strong><em>“Maxwell&#8217;s Silver Hammer”</em></strong>, Abbey Road (1969)<br />
Apparently, this song was Paul&#8217;s expression for how things can suddenly go wrong in life.  Well, things certainly go wrong for Maxwell Edison&#8217;s teacher, girlfriend, and even the judge at his trial, as they get their heads smashed in one-by-one with Maxwell&#8217;s expensive piece of custom hardware.  Upping the song&#8217;s creep factor are <em>(a)</em> the cheery, perky rhythm and upbeat tune (a homicide ballad you can whistle along to!), and <em>(b)</em> the ominous tones of the Moog synthesizer stabbing out from the background shadows in moments of murderous release.  The fact that this tune is sandwiched between two of Abbey Road&#8217;s sincerest love songs (&#8220;Something&#8221; and &#8220;Oh! Darling&#8221;) means that Paul intended this to feel like a bludgeoning to the shocked audience.</p>
<p><b>4.</b> <strong><em>“Run For Your Life”</em></strong>, Rubber Soul (1965)<br />
&#8220;Well I&#8217;d rather see you dead little girl than to be with another man/you better keep your head little girl, or you won&#8217;t know where I am&#8221;.  No, this isn&#8217;t Metallica, or Sex Pistols, or Insane Clown Posse, or Wu Tang Clan, or any of the other hundreds of artist who use dark imagery to make a point or shock an audience.  It&#8217;s John Lennon, who later called this his &#8220;least favourite Beatles song&#8221; and &#8220;the song he most regretted writing&#8221;.  Why, John?  Is it because you menacingly promised to hunt down an innocent woman for leaving you?  And, follow-up question, John&#8230; just why do you think she may have left you in the first place?  Perhaps your murderous rage?  Somehow, I get the impression that a song like that wouldn&#8217;t have gone over too terribly well with good ol&#8217; Yoko.</p>
<p><b>3.</b> <strong><em>“Tomorrow Never Knows”</em></strong>, Revolver (1965)<br />
The fear in this song is not derived by the lyrical content- a mash of Tibetan spirituality, stoned placidity, and generic platitudes about love.  No, the unsettling nature of this song is found entirely in the musicianship and studio wizardry.  Those bombastic drums (in my opinion, some of the best-recorded percussion in human history)!  Those backwards looping guitar shrieks!  That snaking line of sitar, or taboula, or synthesizer, or whatever!  This song is perfect, but if you turn off your lights and relax to it, you might float downstream into some dark and harrowing mental experiences.</p>
<p><b>2.</b> <strong><em>“Strawberry Fields Forever”</em></strong>, Magical Mystery Tour (1967)<br />
This has to be one of the loveliest songs The Beatles ever wrote.  So how did it make #2 on this list of fearsome Fab Four tunes?  I feel like any explanation I attempt with fail to capture the sense of dread I feel in the pit of my gut every time the chorus stomps through.  Combining the &#8220;let me take you down, &#8217;cause I&#8217;m going to&#8230;&#8221; lyric with the deep sweeping rush of cello and the jarring, restless Ringo drum fill creates a real sensation of dropping into an abyss.  A beautiful abyss- perhaps an oxymoronic phrase, but one that captures the original inspiration (an orphanage&#8217;s playground) perfectly.  Heightening this palpable tone of dread is the false ending, which returns with military drums, skittering flute, and alarm-bell guitars.  Beautiful and evocative, certainly; but with haunting undertones that can catch a listener unaware, like a kaleidoscopic python.</p>
<p><b>1.</b> <strong><em>“Revolution 9”</em></strong>, The White Album (1968)<br />
The first time I ever listened to this, uh, &#8220;song&#8221; was formative for my belief that there are few more terrifying works of art in modern musical history than this.  I was home alone, working in our living room, with the White Album playing on vinyl in the background.  I had seen on the album sleeve that a song titled &#8220;Revolution&#8221; was coming up, and I immediately assumed it was the eletric-guitar overload of John&#8217;s protest tune (you know, &#8220;you say you want a revo-LU-tiooooon, we-e-ell ya kno-o-o-ow&#8230;&#8221;).  Instead I got the unnerving audio equivalent to a David Lynch film.  As some lunatic repeatedly calls out for &#8220;Number 9&#8243;, slashed snippets of orchestra and crowd noise meander in and out, panning across the left and right stereo like a drunken brawler taking swings at a funhouse mirror.  When the maniacal laughing hit at 1:48, I remember realizing that, alone in my living room, I suddenly had goosebumps.  I had to turn it off before it was halfway through the 8:22 running time because it was so disturbing to me.</p>
<p>[Editor's Note: I am writing this at midnight.  Angie is in Ontario.  I am attempting to listen through it again.  The hair on my neck is sticking out.  I gave up after 2 and a half minutes.  "Revolution 9" retains its fear factor.]</p>
<p>Well, there you have it folks.  Ten Beatles songs that evoke in me a sense of fear.  I suppose you could add &#8220;Sun King&#8221; to this list, which is sung at least partly in Italian (or Spanish, or something).  Since I don&#8217;t speak the language, it&#8217;s entirely likely the Sun King is in fact some kind of soul-devouring Necromancer.  I doubt it, but as you can tell from the above list, the boys were up to some weird business in those crazy 1960&#8242;s.  What Beatles songs would be included on your list?  The claustrophobia of living in a &#8220;Yellow Submarine&#8221;?  The creepy stalker-ish pleadings of &#8220;Please Please Me&#8221;?  Perhaps you are unsettled by garden-tending octopi, or penny-grabbing Taxmen, or meter maids, or eggmen, or Mother Mary.  What Beatles tunes fill you with fear?</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/333/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/333/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=333&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://sticksasplaythings.wordpress.com/2013/03/25/your-guitar-weeps-because-it-is-terrified-the-beatles-scariest-songs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>70</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/8655158b47b12944390c967d6349b079?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sticksasplaythings</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://sticksasplaythings.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/beatles-doll-parts.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Beatles Doll Parts</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>On Being Stalked</title>
		<link>http://litlove.wordpress.com/2013/03/25/on-being-stalked/</link>
		<comments>http://litlove.wordpress.com/2013/03/25/on-being-stalked/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 17:21:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>litlove</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Literature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Give Me Everything You Have; On Being Stalked]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[James Lasdun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stalking]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://litlove.wordpress.com/?p=3155</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In the autumn of 2003, James Lasdun ran a fiction workshop at an American college where he met a talented Iranian-American student whom he calls ‘Nasreen’. He praised her work and encouraged her and they had an entirely ordinary and satisfactory working relationship. Two years later, she sent him the finished manuscript of her novel [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3155&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://litlove.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/give-me-everything.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-3156" alt="give me everything" src="http://litlove.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/give-me-everything.jpg?w=182&#038;h=276" width="182" height="276" /></a>In the autumn of 2003, James Lasdun ran a fiction workshop at an American college where he met a talented Iranian-American student whom he calls ‘Nasreen’. He praised her work and encouraged her and they had an entirely ordinary and satisfactory working relationship. Two years later, she sent him the finished manuscript of her novel in the hope he would read and comment on it. Busy at the time, Lasdun did the next best thing and offered to put her in touch with his agent. He then embarked on an email correspondence with her, for the most part benign, but including some mild flirtatious remarks, which he took to be (hoped were) ironic. When James told her that he was planning a cross-country train journey, and she replied that she wanted to smuggle herself into his cabin, ‘I began to realise that something more explicitly discouraging than a mere tactful silence was going to be required of me.’</p>
<p>At first Nasreen seemed to take it quite well. But her emails continued to multiply in his inbox and the tone became inconsistent; there would be some apologetic emails, some normal, some angry and troubling. As the volume increased to dozens a day, and the sentiment turned to outright hostility and rage, Lasdun stopped replying. Whilst this would seem like the only way to proceed, the absence of his voice seemed to catapult Nasreen into a fantasy world of her own making in which she was a victim of all sorts of malpractice. She accused him of plagiarising her work, and of stealing it to pass on to other writers (who then published before her). She insisted he’d had an affair with one of the other students in her writing class, she went on to claim that he had ‘organised’ a rape that had happened to her before the two of them met at the fiction workshop, and there were of course, reams of vicious criticism about his writing all peppered with anti-Semitic attacks. And then she spread her net wide, sending written allegations about him to all the colleges he worked at, altering his wikipedia entry, forwarding unpleasant internet material to friends and colleagues in his name, leaving atrocious reviews of his books on amazon, etc and etc, until Lasdun was nearly half out of his mind with anxiety about what she would do next, and whether he would ever work again.</p>
<blockquote><p>My total failure, after all these months, to slow down or in any way inhibit the flow of hatred had had a demoralising effect (as I write, the BP oil catastrophe is unfolding and it is impossible not to picture Nasreen’s hostility as that blackness on the spillcams, billowing unstoppably from the ocean floor, my efforts to staunch it as ineffective as BP’s with their feeble funnels and top kills). I felt flayed, utterly defenceless. Every email sent lacerating spasms through me as it struck, each with an afterburn, a half-life that was nowhere near over before the next one came in, so that I could never regroup my own forces.’</p></blockquote>
<p>What, you may ask, did he do about it? Well, pretty much everything possible to block her, including trying to involve the FBI. But as a supposedly ‘privileged’ white male claiming wrong done to him by an Iranian woman, and a student at that, he was on the wrong side of the PC divide, and in the case of a relatively new internet, outside the boundaries of the law. And it was not easy trying to put what was happening into words: ‘the harder I tried to be neutral and objective, the crazier I sounded.’ There’s a painful moment when his boss at the college turns up with a ‘very weird email’ about him, a tirade of verbal abuse in fact, which looks pretty bonkers on the face of it, but which nevertheless unsettles an always-jumpy head of an American college. Lasdun is dismayed to find that his boss expresses some concerns about the accusation of ‘daytrading fiction’, which is Nasreen’s claim that he sent her work out to other writers to use, something Lasdun had thought would appear patently absurd. It’s the same old story – some of the flung mud always sticks.</p>
<p>What raises this book above the undeniably fascinating category of car crash literature, however, is the brilliance of the writing and the depth of thought that has clearly gone into Lasdun’s account. Retreating into his inner depths to try to ascertain the extent of his own guilt, and to understand the nature of their imploded relationship, he is drawn towards literary works and writers that echo or simply speak to his situation – Gawain and the Green Knight, D. H. Lawrence, Tintin. Some of these long digressions offer incredibly potent glimpses into the sorts of darkness and pain we are manufacturing in our modern technological age, due in part to our mindless reliance on the internet:</p>
<blockquote><p>One would think that the ease of performing such manipulations and the large scale on which they immediately began occurring would have long ago discredited the Web as a source of information about anything, but…our first instinct, being creatures of the Word, is to trust it, and even on deeper consideration we tend to feel that it is basically more right than wrong, and that we can accept its approximations as the truth.’</p></blockquote>
<p>He’s right, of course. The lack of policing on the web and the opportunities it offers to upset, harm and smear others is something that hasn’t had much thought given to it yet. You’ve got to hope that the example of James Lasdun does set some sort of process in motion (not even phone calls from the police deter Nasreen, as she realises on some level that no one will really take the trouble to stop her). And yet, what ultimately intrigued me about this book was the refusal on Lasdun’s part to see Nasreen as simply mentally troubled. The emails he reproduced came across to me as quite self-evidently nutty (and vicious and rageful), but he believed that labelling her behaviour as psychotic would free her from responsibility when he felt sure her attacks were calculated. But it also ‘becomes, for literary purposes, less interesting (at least to me).’ And here we come to the quiet crux of the matter; Lasdun becomes entangled in Nasreen’s web of hatred for ‘there was also something manifestly creative in her unstoppable productivity, a vitality I couldn’t help envying.’ There is a force, albeit one of negativity, that attracts him magnetically and which prevents him from dismissing her and walking away. For me this begs the question of why it should be so much easier to do the things that are wrong, for us and for others, than it is to make the enormous effort to do things that are right. But maybe the saving grace of the whole situation, and the reason it damages him so, is that Nasreen offered him a convoluted way of suffering for art. This is an extraordinary book, but one that came at a very high price.</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://litlove.wordpress.com/category/books/'>Books</a>, <a href='http://litlove.wordpress.com/category/literature/'>Literature</a>, <a href='http://litlove.wordpress.com/category/reading/'>Reading</a>, <a href='http://litlove.wordpress.com/category/relationships/'>Relationships</a>, <a href='http://litlove.wordpress.com/category/review/'>Review</a>, <a href='http://litlove.wordpress.com/category/writers/'>Writers</a>, <a href='http://litlove.wordpress.com/category/writing/'>Writing</a> Tagged: <a href='http://litlove.wordpress.com/tag/give-me-everything-you-have-on-being-stalked/'>Give Me Everything You Have; On Being Stalked</a>, <a href='http://litlove.wordpress.com/tag/james-lasdun/'>James Lasdun</a>, <a href='http://litlove.wordpress.com/tag/stalking/'>stalking</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3155/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3155/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3155&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://litlove.wordpress.com/2013/03/25/on-being-stalked/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>51</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/1a8e67376f4afb90bb6911fd754c74fc?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F1.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">litlove</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://litlove.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/give-me-everything.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">give me everything</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How To Get What You Want Without Really Trying</title>
		<link>http://mnsho.com/2013/03/25/how-to-get-what-you-want-without-really-trying/</link>
		<comments>http://mnsho.com/2013/03/25/how-to-get-what-you-want-without-really-trying/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 14:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bob Bonsall</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Musings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[etiquette]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mnsho.com/?p=533</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The other day I was out grocery shopping, and I saw a sweet deal on my favorite soda. I go through the stuff like most people go through water, so I jumped on it. When I got to the counter it didn&#8217;t ring up correctly, and I brought it to the clerk&#8217;s attention. He said [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=533&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The other day I was out grocery shopping, and I saw a sweet deal on my favorite soda. I go through the stuff like most people go through water, so I jumped on it. When I got to the counter it didn&#8217;t ring up correctly, and I brought it to the clerk&#8217;s attention. He said it would ring properly after the sale finished, but it didn&#8217;t so I brought it to his attention again. Long story short, the soda was mislabeled. I had to go through a bit of a song and dance, but I got my money back (and the soda too!), which was pretty nice.</p>
<p>The experience reminded me that <a href="http://mnsho.com/2012/08/06/customer-service-its-not-just-for-sissies-anymore/">I&#8217;ve had plenty to say in the past about bad customer service</a>, but having been on both sides of the retail counter plenty of times, I&#8217;ve also seen plenty of bad customers. While the retail experience has been perfected from art to science (<a href="http://www.entrepreneur.com/article/78992">quite literally</a>), the retail customer doesn&#8217;t seem to have changed much from the dark days when I plied the trade. For those of you who might find yourselves in a customer service crisis, here&#8217;s some tips on how to get the most out of the situation.</p>
<p><b>Be Polite</b> &#8211; I can&#8217;t think of a single situation in my life (other than a fistfight) that hasn&#8217;t or couldn&#8217;t have been improved by being polite. I&#8217;ve seen a lot of people try to intimidate store clerks and managers, either physically or socially, and I have to tell you it almost always backfires. Being polite at the least keeps the situation in the realm of negotiation, which means you might get something, rather than demand, in which case you&#8217;re far more likely to get nothing.</p>
<p>One of my favorite misconceptions in retail is &#8220;the customer is always right&#8221;. I don&#8217;t just mean this as a factual misconception, I mean this as a misconception in the sense that anyone in retail does or should believe this. Maybe if I only had a handful of customers come in on a regular basis and my livelihood depended on them, then <i>maybe</i> I would consider this phrase, but still unlikely. In this day and age, when most retail is as anonymous as an online chat room and I have no reason to believe I will ever see you again, why should I go out of my way to put up with your crap? Because you&#8217;ll badmouth me to all your cheap friends, who are as likely to pull the same stunt as you are? Yeah, that&#8217;s a threat.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s another way to look at it: suppose I came to your office one day and told you that you were doing everything wrong. I (very loudly and obnoxiously) explain how you should be doing your job, running your business, and handling every situation, even though I clearly have no idea what I&#8217;m talking about, and chances are better than even you saw be stealing some rubber bands from the supply closet fifteen minutes ago. Then, to top it all off, I insist that I know how to run your business because I worked in a similar business for a summer in high school, thus implying that any idiot can do it.</p>
<p>Would you at all be inclined to give me anything I want under those conditions? If so, you&#8217;d be the first.</p>
<p><b>Be Patient</b> &#8211; The next biggest sin I see people committing (and I do this too, but I try not to) is that they assume there should be someone ready to help them as soon as they need it, especially if they feel like they&#8217;ve been wronged somehow. I get this, I do. You paid good money for a specific product or service, and that product or service was not produced. You want satisfaction, and the longer you have to wait, the more you feel you are being cheated, because your time is also valuable.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s the thing: They&#8217;re (usually) not making you wait on purpose. Most stores understand that having an unhappy customer standing around fuming does not make them look good to the other customers. But there are other customers to consider, and that&#8217;s assuming someone is even aware of your needs. Then there are certain procedures they need to follow, which if they don&#8217;t could mean they lose their job, which means a lot more to them than your displeasure (and trust me, they will never get fired just because you asked to speak to the manager and they were following the procedures).</p>
<p>Most of all, if there&#8217;s <i>any</i> flexibility to be had in this situation, you want it to work for you, not against you, and the fact of the matter is you are not in the position of power that you think you are. They might prefer not to lose you as a customer, but the more of an asshole you are the less they care, and there&#8217;s no law against not giving in to your unreasonable demands. Even on the (very off) chance they&#8217;re in the wrong, what are the chances you&#8217;re going to sue over a can of tomatoes or even something as big as a sweater? Slim to none, and they know that. So cool your jets.</p>
<p><b>Be Flexible</b> &#8211; This one&#8217;s a little tough to internalize, but it&#8217;s important. Most people go into a customer service situation expecting they are there to right a wrong. Not so. You are going into a negotiation, and the rules are a little fuzzy. There may be laws that apply, but do you know them? Do you really think the kid behind the counter does? And does anyone really care? There&#8217;s store policy, but that usually has some leeway to it. And then there&#8217;s custom and convention, which are pretty weak guidelines at best.</p>
<p>So understand that you are not there to right some moral wrong. You have a situation you want resolved, one were you feel you were not treated fairly, and you have a specific <i>preferred</i> resolution in mind. That&#8217;s nice. You might even get that. But be open to the possibility that there are in fact laws, policies, or even customs and conventions that are going to work against or even completely prevent you getting exactly what you want. And that&#8217;s even assuming you are completely right about the situation, which I&#8217;ve seen all too many times isn&#8217;t the case.</p>
<p>So now what? Well, you can resort to screaming and demands and see how far that gets you (usually escorted out of the store), or you can be flexible. Oftentimes unless you are completely in the wrong store managers will prefer to find a negotiated middle ground where the customer walks away feeling satisfied, and you can use that fact to your advantage. If you were expecting a full refund, maybe a partial refund, or a discount on a future purchase or exchange. Be open to alternatives.</p>
<p><b>Be Firm</b> &#8211; This goes hand in hand with being flexible. Unless you are completely in the wrong (in which case you should make as quick of a retreat as you can), stand by your guns. Don&#8217;t let the manager or anyone else try to bully or snowball you. I&#8217;ve seen plenty of times where they will pull out a circular or ad and say something like &#8220;that was last week&#8217;s sale&#8221; when they forgot to change the signage in the store, even though we both know their own store policy is to honor their posted prices.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s no need to be a dick about it, but make sure to stand your ground and be aware of your position. The best thing to do in these cases is to simply refuse to argue with them. If they pull out the circular, nod and say something like &#8220;I&#8217;m sure that&#8217;s the case, but the posted price on the shelf was different.&#8221; This way you aren&#8217;t engaging them, but you are refusing to be scared off as well. And notice: still polite. Eventually (if you are patient) they will likely offer some recompense. If you&#8217;re flexible, you should be able to get something satisfying.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/533/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/533/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=533&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://mnsho.com/2013/03/25/how-to-get-what-you-want-without-really-trying/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>79</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c2fce91830dfecf8c3af41bfcc58f49d?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=R" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bobbonsall</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>On Attending a Memoir Retreat</title>
		<link>http://mandylen.wordpress.com/2013/03/22/your-story-is-not-new-on-attending-a-memoir-retreat/</link>
		<comments>http://mandylen.wordpress.com/2013/03/22/your-story-is-not-new-on-attending-a-memoir-retreat/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2013 06:14:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Mandy Len</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[genre]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[narrative]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing about writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cheryl strayed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sleeping Lady Resort]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[telling stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Theo Pauline Nestor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wild Mountain Memoir Retreat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing memoir]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mandylen.wordpress.com/?p=941</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;The amazing thing about a memoir retreat,” I said to my friend Claire yesterday. “—is that they exist?” she finished. “No.” I laughed, then paused. “Well…maybe. I was going to say the amazing thing about a memoir retreat is that, in the course of a few minutes you get to know someone in a way [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=941&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;The amazing thing about a memoir retreat,” I said to my friend Claire yesterday.</p>
<p>“—is that they exist?” she finished.</p>
<p>“No.” I laughed, then paused. “Well…maybe. I was going to say the amazing thing about a memoir retreat is that, in the course of a few minutes you get to know someone in a way that otherwise takes months or years. You say, ‘What’s your writing project about?’ and they tell you their big story. The thing they haven’t figured out yet. They thing they can’t get over. The most difficult experience they’ve ever had. It’s instant intimacy. And everyone—I guess because they’ve already made the decision to write about themselves—is just incredibly open.”</p>
<p>Many people, I think, will be quick to dismiss the idea of a memoir retreat altogether. And while no one has said this to me yet, I can imagine what they might say: “Why on earth would it seem like a good idea to bring together a bunch of narcissists and say to them, ‘Write more about your own trivial experiences! Publish them!’ Why would we—in the era of blogs, and Facebook, and Twitter—encourage even more oversharing? And why would we dare imply that that oversharing could be literature?”</p>
<div id="attachment_953" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 536px"><a href="http://mandylen.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/photo-2.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-953 " alt="photo (2)" src="http://mandylen.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/photo-2.jpg?w=526&#038;h=394" width="526" height="394" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">the view of Icicle Creek from Sleeping Lady Resort</p></div>
<p>The amazing thing about <a href="http://wildmountainmemoir.wordpress.com/">this particular memoir retreat</a>&#8211;Wild Mountain&#8211;was that everyone I met had already asked that essential question: “So what?” And even if some folks didn’t yet have an answer, everyone understood, implicitly, that they needed one. No one seemed interested in what Susan Shapiro <a href="http://mandylen.wordpress.com/2013/02/02/january-roundup-love-and-memoir/">termed</a> “upbeat anecdotal slices of life.”</p>
<p>***</p>
<p>Lately I’ve been struggling with a minor revelation regarding my own writing: I’ve got to be more honest—to bare more, to be more vulnerable—if I want people to read it. And being more honest requires more me in the book. It means, like it or not, that what I’m writing <em>is</em> a memoir. There’s just no way around it.<span id="more-941"></span></p>
<p>Steven Church, on his blog <a href="http://myatomicangst.blogspot.ca/">My Atomic Angst</a>, explains his discomfort with the “memoir” label in a way that echoes my own:</p>
<blockquote><p>I begged, in fact, during production, that [my book] not say &#8220;memoir&#8221; in the title or subtitle. I didn’t want it to be reduced to that one word label, perhaps because for the last few years, especially at conferences like the AWP conference, the “memoir” tag has been like the herpes of genre labels; but more importantly than labels, I wanted the book to behave differently than a traditional memoir. I wanted it to be something more like a book-length braided personal essay with fictional and journalistic elements. And I didn’t want readers to look at the cover and expect something different.</p></blockquote>
<p>***</p>
<p><span style="font-style:inherit;line-height:1.625;">I am embarrassed to admit this in front of my fellow retreat-goers (and new friends) but I drove down to Leavenworth preparing myself for the possibility that I might be spending the weekend among overconfident self-promoters or&#8211;worse yet&#8211;evangelists of the upbeat anecdote and the dogma of uniqueness. Which is why I was relieved to hear organizer Theo Pauline Nester declare on the first night: “Your story is not new.”</span></p>
<p>The amazing thing about this particular retreat is that, unlike several of the reviews of Associated Writers Program conference the weekend before, every response I’ve read to Wild Mountain has been insistently, unwaveringly positive. As my friend Amy Stolls <a href="http://artworks.arts.gov/?p=16421">said about AWP</a>: “Judging by the post-conference commentary, [attendees] were either quietly inspired to write more and write better, or were crushed by the sheer numbers of writers attending and vowed never to attend an AWP conference again.” (See also Steve Almond’s lukewarm “<a href="http://www.newrepublic.com/article/112633/awp-conference-2013-writing-boom-time-declining-readers">The Writing Industry is Booming, even if the Book Industry Isn’t</a>.”)</p>
<p>For me, universal positivity always inspires a particular brand of knee-jerk cynicism: <i>Students don’t complain about an assignment? It’s not challenging enough. A book is unanimously lauded? It must be shallow.</i> <i>A lot of people like my blog post? I’m being a crowd pleaser.</i><em> </em>I do not trust it—in the same way I don’t trust people who dress appropriately for every occasion, whose hair always stays in place. Universal positivity is just spackling over some darker truth, warns a voice in my head. <i>A memoir retreat is popular? It must be pandering</i><em>. </em>But damn is it hard to be cynical toward a group of people who have generously and willingly opened themselves up to you within the first few hours of your acquaintance. Some things, I struggle to admit, are just good. Some compliments are well-earned.</p>
<p>Yes, Wild Mountain might seem like a perfect illustration of the booming writing industry Steve Almond saw at AWP: a two-day stay at a rustic-but-luxurious resort with some writing classes thrown in. But that&#8217;s a pretty narrow view of what the retreat offered to so many people: an authentication of the personal story, a reiteration of the value of human-to-human connections.</p>
<p>The atmosphere at Wild Mountain was probably inspired by keynote speaker Cheryl Strayed, who seemed to be admired at the retreat with, at times, fanatic devotion. Such admiration is easy to dismiss (see above), but I remember reading <a href="http://thesunmagazine.org/archives/2192">&#8220;The Love of my Life&#8221; </a>my first year of graduate school and finally sensing that my decision to transfer from a fiction writing program to a creative nonfiction program was not the product of my own misery, but of some larger instinct about the kind of writer I could be. Her first sentence was a revelation to me: writing could be like that. It could be bare-bones honest without being sensational.</p>
<p>So I, too, am bound to my admiration. (And perhaps it is important to remember that, though it is rare, some people succeed out of sheer deservingness. And thank God the world we live in allows for that once in awhile.) In her talk, Cheryl urged us to “write with a sense of abundance. Be happy for others’ successes.” And to “surrender to mediocrity” rather than worrying about our own talents and abilities. As far as writing advice goes, this is solid stuff, advice more interested in enabling others&#8217; success than in celebrating her own.</p>
<p>Wild Mountain could’ve pandered to writers who had sacrificed their time and money by simply telling them what they wanted to hear: that their stories were marketable, that their experiences were interesting just by virtue of having happened. Instead everyone—faculty and attendees alike—railed against the idea that your story is about you, or that anecdote equals art. But the most valuable thing about the retreat was that it always brought our attention back to the thing that matters most for a writer: the work itself.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theopaulinenestor.com/">Theo</a> describes memoir as &#8220;a genre in its adolescence.&#8221; She thinks readers are increasingly interested in memoir because we&#8217;re out of touch with the stories and storytellers of the tight-knit communities of the past. She believes we&#8217;re reading memoir to learn how to live. And I love this idea. Intuitively, it sounds right to me.</p>
<p>Steven Church, in that same blog post, (and, I think, on a panel at AWP) agrees about memoir&#8217;s potential as a genre:</p>
<blockquote><p>I want to believe that we can also think of the expectations of memoir more generously, more broadly than the confessional or traumatic. I want to believe we can think of memoir in terms of the author’s personal connection to the ideas in the book; that the form, at it’s best, can use personal experience to gather up the distinct threads of a book and bring them together into a narrative of thought that is more compelling and nuanced than a simple summary of the crazy shit that happened. Perhaps memoir can be about a place, a state, or about an entire generation and less about trafficking in humiliation or confessing some pain, loss, or sorrow. Perhaps like all literature it is aiming to capture the sublime confluence of these and other human experiences through the synchronicity of ideas and emotions.</p></blockquote>
<p>So I’ve been thinking about what this all means for me. As a memoir writer, I’ve got to stop being defensive, to stop worrying about the larger perception of what I’m doing and focus on the work. And as a writing teacher, I’ve got to start championing—both in my classes and in the world at large—the generous possibilities of memoir. Because our stories matter.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/941/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/941/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=941&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://mandylen.wordpress.com/2013/03/22/your-story-is-not-new-on-attending-a-memoir-retreat/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>51</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/5cd3892022728b1c9d265de40b87ea92?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mandylen</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mandylen.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/photo-2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">photo (2)</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Out to Sea</title>
		<link>http://anntaylorfashionstatement.wordpress.com/2013/03/22/out-to-sea/</link>
		<comments>http://anntaylorfashionstatement.wordpress.com/2013/03/22/out-to-sea/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 17:08:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>anntaylorfashionstatement</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[fashion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[memoir]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[#WPLongform]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lesbian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parris Island]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Savannah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[St. Helena]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Oaks]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://anntaylorfashionstatement.wordpress.com/?p=657</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I first met Marion Talmadge Etheridge at her annual New Year’s Day party in her tumbledown plantation house on St. Helena Island. She was in her late thirties, tall, blond curls, good figure, mother of two, married to a tire salesman. She was an artist who could draw like crazy, ambidextrous with a charcoal stick [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=657&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><div id="attachment_462" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 223px"><a href="http://anntaylorfashionstatement.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/1976-contrast.jpeg"><img src="http://anntaylorfashionstatement.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/1976-contrast.jpeg?w=213&#038;h=300" alt="Ann Taylor " width="213" height="300" class="size-medium wp-image-462" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Ann Taylor is wearing a scoop-neck nylon T shirt.</p></div>I first met Marion Talmadge Etheridge at her annual New Year’s Day party in her tumbledown plantation house on St. Helena Island. She was in her late thirties, tall, blond curls, good figure, mother of two, married to a tire salesman. She was an artist who could draw like crazy, ambidextrous with a charcoal stick in each hand sketching a portrait, a party trick she later depended on to pay her bills. </p>
<p>I drove down the long drive, still lined with trees, to The Oaks to find a crowd of beer-drinking dads in madras pants and polo shirts, an occasional baseball hat with a John Deere logo, gathered around an oyster roast in the yard. Wine-sipping moms in designer jeans filled the front porch of the Greek-revival plantation house now clad in gray asbestos shingles. Someone said that Marion was in the kitchen. I wandered through the front door. White narcissus overflowed urns, vases, pitchers, buckets in every room. My first impression was their sweet, wintry, garlicky odor. </p>
<p>I was used to people like me living in places they could never have afforded outside Savannah and coastal South Carolina. My house had nine fireplaces. Friends lived in the house on Bull Street where Lafayette stayed when he came south after the end of the war. We rattled around in our big broken-down houses without appropriate furniture, rugs, and silver. The Oaks, when Marion and her husband lived there, had plenty of heavy mahogany furniture, a long dining table with a dozen matching chairs, and a tall clock with a moon face in the front hall. Rich, old rugs lay over wide heart-pine boards, and a silver service, no longer shiny, stood on the sideboard. But the house was not quite right, too topsy-turvy, too far down the rabbit hole. </p>
<p>Every window was bare, open to marshy light, to giant oaks in the front, Chowan Creek behind the house, an old barn looking dangerously close to collapse, a country collection of rusting cars and trucks. On the mantle in the front parlor, a bevy of wigless plastic dolls had gathered. A similar crew hung out in the dining room, where Marion also kept a collection of old shoes painted silver attached with pastel ribbons to cardboard clouds. Golf clubs and a hunting rifle poked out of an umbrella stand.</p>
<p>At the back of the house, a room empty except for a pool table belonged to the husband. Marion had the kitchen, black-and-white linoleum floor tiles set on an arbitrary diagonal, cabinets painted randomly bright colors, a broken kitchen chair in one corner to which she had tied a large, white plastic flip clock with a thick rope. Marion sat with her friends around a large round table in a bay facing the tidal creek, several men and a few wives, all stoned. I slipped into an empty chair.</p>
<p>I was immediately enchanted with Marion, saw her as often as I could. Up to her elbows in cold water, washing spinach in her kitchen sink, telling me how to look at the space between the branches if I wanted to draw a tree. Coming back into my studio moments after she had left to tell me there was an alligator blocking her truck. We pounded on garbage can lids to drive him back to the river, an old guy washed out of his den by floodwaters. The Arab oil embargo made us lovers. We were in Columbus to deliver a painting. The lines long, her gas tank nearly empty, we decided to stay the night. She called one of her husband’s cousins, a professor whose wife had recently left him for a woman. He gave us dinner and a spare bedroom. I noted the irony.</p>
<p>Because I kept my hair cropped very short, I was generally assumed to be a butch. Marion’s husband shared this general assumption, accepting in his grumpy way that his wife had a lesbian lover. He said little. We spoke only when it was unavoidable. He did not enter rooms where I was and left rooms when I entered. </p>
<p>After saying all summer that we were going to take the boat out, September was slipping away with the girls back in school and we still hadn’t sailed Chowan Creek. Then one morning, Marion decided we had to sail that day and had to get under way immediately. I sat at her kitchen table gulping coffee, expecting an imminent departure, forgetting that Marion was always late, sometimes even days late. I looked at the clock tied to the kitchen chair. Marion tied the clock to the chair because the chair was sitting in her kitchen broken and unused, because the clock was heavy and fell off the wall, because she was an artist making a statement, because the clock was her marriage and she thought she was holding it together. When her daughters checked the clock to see the time, to see how late Marion was or was about to be as she puttered around her kitchen, to annoy they read aloud precisely the exact moment: oh nine three two, two two four six. </p>
<p>We eventually got out of the kitchen, packed the boat’s storage compartment with a bottle of wine and a couple of cheese sandwiches, pulled long-sleeve shirts over our bikini tops, and pushed her Sunfish to the edge of the backyard. The tide was coming in; the water was high in the creek. We pushed the boat off the bank and towed it to the dock. Marion climbed down the ladder onto the boat. I handed her the sail, rudder, and centerboard. She pushed the boat parts in place. I thought she knew what she was doing. Then I came down, took a wobbly step, and sat down hard, first time on a Sunfish in ten years. Never a sailor, always a passenger, I had spent a few high-school summer afternoons on a boyfriend’s Sunfish in Lake Michigan.</p>
<p>With the tide coming in and wind filling the sail, we moved swiftly away from the house around a bend. Marion seemed in command of her vessel. We opened the wine, looked for an inviting place to stop for lunch. Our speed slowed. Marion tried to tack, to cut a zigzag course up the creek. Each time she turned the boat to tack, I flattened myself on the deck to avoid the boom. The Vs of the zigs and zags narrowed. We sailed from one bank back to the other in a straight line, making no headway. The last time she tried to tack, Marion aimed the boat at the opposite bank, and we headed downstream with the tide. She looked more puzzled than worried. I had no idea tacking was her only sailing maneuver.</p>
<p>The boat picked up speed. We passed The Oaks before I realized where we were. The sail filled. The creek widened. No lifejackets, of course, just a quick sail because Marion had to be home when her daughters got off the school bus. “If I am going to be drowned, if I am going to be drowned, why in the name of the seven mad gods who rule the sea, was I allowed to come thus far and contemplate land and trees?” Stephen Crane’s sailor was washing toward shore, toward breakers, and we were headed out to sea, but the end result would be the same and my last words a quote memorized for English class. </p>
<p>Our feet in the boat’s well, we sat side by side and let wind and tide chart the course. Marion missed her kids’ homecoming. The time when her husband would come home from work and find the girls alone passed. The boat headed toward a narrow opening between a sandbar and the riverbank. Marion steered for the sandbar, but we kept going and spilled out into a wider river. An on-shore wind grabbed the sail, and briefly we headed up river. Then the tide regained control of the boat. It pulled us down river but also toward the far bank, where suddenly we were stuck in soft gray mud on the northeast shore of Parris Island. </p>
<p>We jumped off the boat into mud studded with broken shells and push-pulled the boat out of the water. Marion’s plan: we would drag the boat across the mud, find a road, and call for help. The seven mad gods’ plan: send in the Marines. Shaved heads, shirtless, in fatigues and big boots, the boys came whooping across the mud, their eyes bright with a fantasy come true. Two women in bikinis washed up on their shore in a little boat. </p>
<p>I feigned invisibility. Marion shook her short blond curls, told our tale, and begged for help. When the guys heard “I need to call my husband,” Marine Corps discipline was restored. They folded the sail, picked up the boat, and off we marched across the mud to a nearby boardwalk. Marion called her husband from a pay phone, and he came to get us in his pickup.</p>
<p>At the hearing, Marion’s soon-to-be ex-husband read aloud his journal entry for that day: “Wife attempted to drown herself and girl lover. Rescued the Sunfish from Parris Island.” He had hundreds of records, dates I had been at The Oaks, samples of marijuana removed from her stash box in the freezer, chronicles of missed appointments. Her mother testified against her, also her daughters. I wasn’t called, his lawyer thought I would be overkill. Marion lost everything. Even the car, the judge had said she must have, which was rear-ended in Charleston just before she left for New York. There she began again, her three rich names that conjured lost elegance and Southern grit compressed into one: Savannah.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/657/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/657/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=657&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://anntaylorfashionstatement.wordpress.com/2013/03/22/out-to-sea/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/767d3c536ce8a367f371c03c5e51d0b5?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">anntaylorfashionstatement</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://anntaylorfashionstatement.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/1976-contrast.jpeg?w=213" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ann Taylor </media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Self Portrait Turned Reptile</title>
		<link>http://micahrichardson.com/2013/03/22/arting-for-365-day-327-self-portrait-turned-reptile/</link>
		<comments>http://micahrichardson.com/2013/03/22/arting-for-365-day-327-self-portrait-turned-reptile/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 19:01:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Micah</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drawing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[art365]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dpchallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[portrait]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://micahrichardson.com/?p=5941</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Goal: to create one piece of art each day for 365 consecutive days I stood in front of a mirror, taking no more than two minutes to do a quick sketch of myself yesterday. The drawing had very little likeness to me &#8211; that was not really my aim. I just wanted to draw a [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=5941&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_5944" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 460px"><a href="http://micahsart.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/day-327-self-portrait-alien1.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-5944" alt="Day 327, 5 x 7&quot; ink on paper" src="http://micahsart.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/day-327-self-portrait-alien1.jpg?w=450&#038;h=618" width="450" height="618" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Day 327, 5 x 7&#8243; ink on paper</p></div>
<p><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Goal: to create one piece of art each day for 365 consecutive days</span></p>
<p>I stood in front of a mirror, taking no more than two minutes to do a quick sketch of myself yesterday. The drawing had very little likeness to me &#8211; that was not really my aim. I just wanted to draw a face quickly.  I walked back into my studio wondering what I was going to do with the thing. I added a few circles above the head and stared. Hmm. I began drawing circles over the face, varying sizes to build form. It was a bit creepy, yet interesting. Strangely enough, I am a fan of the piece.</p>
<p><a href="http://micahsart.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/step-1-day-3271.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5945" alt="Step 1 day 327" src="http://micahsart.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/step-1-day-3271.jpg?w=450&#038;h=627" width="450" height="627" /></a></p>
<h5>You can buy a print of this original <a href="https://www.etsy.com/listing/127295652/portrait-turned-reptile-print-from" target="_blank">here</a>!</h5>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=5941&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://micahrichardson.com/2013/03/22/arting-for-365-day-327-self-portrait-turned-reptile/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>54</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f0d74525084e6b4a393dd9bca6e676b8?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=R" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">micahdr1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://micahsart.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/day-327-self-portrait-alien1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Day 327, 5 x 7&#34; ink on paper</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://micahsart.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/step-1-day-3271.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Step 1 day 327</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
