<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2012 01:02:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Brands: Stop Being Socially Awkward</title>
		<link>http://letsoverthinkthis.com/2012/08/17/brands-stop-being-socially-awkward/</link>
		<comments>http://letsoverthinkthis.com/2012/08/17/brands-stop-being-socially-awkward/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2012 15:44:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Leslie Shaffer</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advertising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advertising]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[branding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rob delaney]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[twitter]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://letsoverthinkthis.com/?p=377</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As many pats on the back the marketing industry likes to give one another, we’re not doing very well in the “social space.” There are stacks of PowerPoint presentations containing Best Practices like stay topical and ask questions to invite conversation and be personable. These Best Practices are true. But are they really the best? [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=377&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As many pats on the back the marketing industry likes to give one another, we’re not doing very well in the “social space.” There are stacks of PowerPoint presentations containing Best Practices like stay topical and ask questions to invite conversation and be personable. These Best Practices are true. But are they really the best? I sure as hell hope not. It leads to an onslaught of brands clogging social feeds with sad little ploys for attention:</p>
<p style="padding-left:60px;">Summer is here! Don’t forget to stay cool with <em>[soda brand]</em> or <em>[ice cream brand]</em>! Tell us, what are your big plans?</p>
<p style="padding-left:60px;"><em>[Fun stylized image of the product in a silly circumstance]</em><br />
Like this post if you can relate!</p>
<p style="padding-left:60px;">Oh … Mondays. Like this if you hate them, too!</p>
<p>Brands in social media have become the equivalent of middle-school cheerleaders in a locker room or a <em>Garfield</em> comic strip without the punch line—meaningless chatter and shouting.</p>
<p>Here’s a Facebook post I made (as a person) in March:<br />
<a href="http://artleslie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/screen-shot-2012-08-14-at-7-37-59-am.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-378" title="Screen Shot 2012-08-14 at 7.37.59 AM" src="http://artleslie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/screen-shot-2012-08-14-at-7-37-59-am.png?w=529" alt=""   /></a></p>
<p>Look at me being clever. See the comment from <a href="https://twitter.com/mkw1342" target="_blank">Matt Whitaker</a>? The reason he Liked this is because he’s put together those Best Practice PowerPoints. So have I. And I’ve written endless amounts of Facebook status updates and Tweets for brands like the ones I mock above. A la <em>Seinfeld</em>, it’s funny because it’s true.</p>
<p>But… that’s enough of that.</p>
<p>We need to do something more. Or, dare I say it, something less. Do brands have to post every day? Multiple times a day? Or, consider this liberating possibility: perhaps some brands shouldn’t be in social <em>at all</em>. Throw up a Facebook and Google+ page for search reasons and call it a day. In fact, maybe post once about how you’re there but aren’t going to annoy people with empty updates. I’d bet the authenticity would go far with consumers, who let’s not forget, are people first.</p>
<p>The reason people use social media is to connect with others. To share experiences, to share what makes them who they are, to debate and laugh and be real. They can get billboards shouting at them on the highway. They don’t need it on Facebook and Twitter.</p>
<p>Our failure as brands in social media has been the belief there is a code to crack. Much like people, every brand is different. <em>There is no magic formula</em>. Once we accept that we can enjoy the freedom that is trying out new, real things and seeing what happens. Here are three steps to start:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Know who you are</strong>. Besides the product you make, what does your brand care about? What <em>don’t</em> you care about? These are your guardrails.</li>
<li><strong>Create something you can share</strong>. Not just your product. Use the guardrails above and make something new. A song. A video. A giant slip-and-slide in a park. Get creative, or hire someone else who is.</li>
<li><strong>Be real</strong>. Meaning, actual human beings.</li>
</ol>
<p>The last one is the trickiest, but most important. I was once the “voice” for a consumer-packaged good on Facebook. I remember I’d often post something and a Fan (this is back when they were Fans) would comment with frustration I could almost hear: <em>Who <strong>IS</strong> this?</em> These Fans wanted to know who was behind the curtain. Because we all know deodorant sticks and caffeinated beverages can’t type.<br />
<a href="http://artleslie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/screen-shot-2012-08-15-at-9-26-50-am.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-379" title="Screen Shot 2012-08-15 at 9.26.50 AM" src="http://artleslie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/screen-shot-2012-08-15-at-9-26-50-am.png?w=529" alt=""   /></a></p>
<p>I’m not suggesting every brand slaps the face of a brand manager or intern on their Facebook page or Twitter feed. But…maybe. Ask yourself this: If your face and identity were attached to the things your brand posts, would you be posting the crap you have been?</p>
<p>I write this whole thing out of empathy. If you’ve worked in this space, <a href="http://www.mcsweeneys.net/articles/i-am-the-intern-who-reads-all-of-your-mocking-tweets-at-the-official-taco-bell-twitter-account" target="_blank">you’ll relate to this</a>. And I pity the poor marketing soul who refreshed their social media dashboard to find this gem:<br />
<a href="http://artleslie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/screen-shot-2012-08-15-at-8-50-39-am.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-380" title="Screen Shot 2012-08-15 at 8.50.39 AM" src="http://artleslie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/screen-shot-2012-08-15-at-8-50-39-am.png?w=529" alt=""   /></a></p>
<p><a href="https://twitter.com/robdelaney" target="_blank">Rob Delaney</a> is everyone&#8217;s favorite comedian on Twitter. He shows no brand (<a href="http://www.businessweek.com/articles/2012-08-02/mitt-romneys-twitter-nemesis" target="_blank">including Mitt Romney</a>) mercy. And good for him for keeping us honest. If the idea of your face attached to whatever silly thing your brand is about to post doesn’t stop you, consider what Rob Delaney could do to it. And, if you do fall victim to Rob, remember #3 and have a sense of humor at your own expense. He respects and retweets that.<br />
<a href="http://artleslie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/screen-shot-2012-08-15-at-9-15-04-am.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-381" title="Screen Shot 2012-08-15 at 9.15.04 AM" src="http://artleslie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/screen-shot-2012-08-15-at-9-15-04-am.png?w=529" alt=""   /></a></p>
<p>I’m sorry this post doesn’t include a sophisticated flow chart or formula you can drop in a PowerPoint for your next meeting. But try the three simple things I mentioned. Even better, give yourself the freedom to fail. Remember #3: be human. What’s more human than screwing up? You’ll find people will forgive people. They won’t forgive billboards.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/377/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/377/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=377&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://letsoverthinkthis.com/2012/08/17/brands-stop-being-socially-awkward/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://artleslie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/nerd_web3.jpeg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://artleslie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/nerd_web3.jpeg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Nerd_web</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/e36fb8b2729a67fc6b00e42f00e688b0?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F2.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=R" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">artleslie</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://artleslie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/screen-shot-2012-08-14-at-7-37-59-am.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen Shot 2012-08-14 at 7.37.59 AM</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://artleslie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/screen-shot-2012-08-15-at-9-26-50-am.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen Shot 2012-08-15 at 9.26.50 AM</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://artleslie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/screen-shot-2012-08-15-at-8-50-39-am.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen Shot 2012-08-15 at 8.50.39 AM</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://artleslie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/screen-shot-2012-08-15-at-9-15-04-am.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen Shot 2012-08-15 at 9.15.04 AM</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Two Years in the Gulag for Russia&#8217;s Riot Chicks</title>
		<link>http://doorkeep.wordpress.com/2012/08/18/two-years-for-russias-riot-chicks/</link>
		<comments>http://doorkeep.wordpress.com/2012/08/18/two-years-for-russias-riot-chicks/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2012 02:43:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Pete</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Christianity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Orthodoxy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pussy Riot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russia]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://doorkeep.wordpress.com/?p=1234</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Russian punk chicks Pussy Riot got hit with two years in the clink on hooliganism charges. I had predicted a lenient sentence of possibly three years. Many were afraid the girls were going to get seven, which has been cited by some alarmists as mandatory on Russian hooliganism statutes. Bottom line is, while to an outside, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1234&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 195px"><a href="http://doorkeep.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/300px-christ_the_saviour.jpeg"><img class=" wp-image " src="http://doorkeep.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/300px-christ_the_saviour.jpeg?w=185&h=135" alt="Image" width="185" height="135" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">This was Christ the Savior Cathedral in 1905, a couple of decades before Stalin razed it to the ground and more than a century after Pussy Riot tried to desecrated with their foolish politicking that just cost them two years in the gulag.</p></div>
<p>Russian punk chicks Pussy Riot got hit with <a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2012/08/17/us-russia-pussyriot-idUSBRE87F1E520120817">two years in the clink</a> on hooliganism charges. I had predicted a lenient sentence of possibly three years. Many were afraid the girls were going to get seven, which has been cited by some alarmists as mandatory on Russian hooliganism statutes.</p>
<p>Bottom line is, while to an outside, non-Orthodox, non-Russian observer kind of severe to throw some kind of mousey looking girl-next-door types in the gulag for pulling a &#8220;hey, let&#8217;s try to shock the babushkas out of their bonnets and play a gig in church,&#8221; it&#8217;s really practically a slap on the wrist. One, they knew what they were getting themselves into. They had to. They played their protest &#8220;gig&#8221; at Christ the Savior Cathedral, practically on the doorstep of the Kremlin, where all the key religious ceremonies are held where the country&#8217;s chief heads of state, including the religious Putin and Medvedev, congregate. Sure, the girls got support outside of Russia. Stars like Sting and Madonna (not a Christian) supported them. But a small minority of Russians do. The vast majority of Russians wanted them punished. When in Russia, do as the Russians do. These chicks should have known better.</p>
<p>Apparently, they can still appeal the verdict within a matter of days from sentencing and they could be pardoned by Russia&#8217;s President, Tsar Vladimir Vladimirovich, who has said he hopes their punishment won&#8217;t be too great. The Orthodox Church has also said it won&#8217;t be too upset if the girls receive leniency, so still, at this juncture, anything could happen.</p>
<p>There are those who say that the Church and the State in this case overreacted and by judging too harshly created too much publicity for the group, but most of those voicing that opinion are outside of Russia.</p>
<p>Anyone who knows anything about Orthodoxy and has watched the video of the group&#8217;s performance inside the church knows that they knowingly offended church mores on so many fronts it&#8217;s a wonder they were not mauled to death by a mob of angry church babushkas on the spot. First, they performed what they called, a &#8220;punk moleben.&#8221; A moleben is a special prayer. It&#8217;s a sacred devotion. It should not be taken lightly nor in mockery. Strike one. Second, the girls performed in front of the holy doors. Strike number two. No girls allowed up there. Period. That rule has been in place for 2,000 years. Break it at your own peril. Number three, they did mock prostrations. I hope the guards and their prison buddies up in the gulag have them doing similar mock prostrations daily up there in Siberia. Bad taste, I know, but I couldn&#8217;t resist. The list goes on and on. These chicks knew what they were doing. They knew what they were up against and the perils of getting caught. If they had done this at a lesser Russian church somewhere further away from the Kremlin, it may have been been a little less publicity, but a little less gulag time. So, they get pay for what they get. Enjoy the vacation, devushki!</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1234/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1234/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1234&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://doorkeep.wordpress.com/2012/08/18/two-years-for-russias-riot-chicks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/831cab30260d7cb1d1b14c2cae4d81fa?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Pete</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://doorkeep.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/300px-christ_the_saviour.jpeg?w=290" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pussy Riot Sentenced: Who Cares? I Care.</title>
		<link>http://wrongside.me/2012/08/18/who-cares-pussy-riot-sentenced/</link>
		<comments>http://wrongside.me/2012/08/18/who-cares-pussy-riot-sentenced/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2012 01:07:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Fiona</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Atheist Love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Feminism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[feminism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social justice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wrongside]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fiona mccoll]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[religion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[atheism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pussy riot]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://wrongside.me/?p=2973</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#160; &#8220;This is all nonsense. I can&#8217;t believe that in the 21st century a judge in a secular court is talking about devilish movements. I can&#8217;t believe that a government official is quoting medieval church councils.&#8221; - Boris Akunin, well known Russian author I&#8217;ve been following along with and writing a bit about the Pussy [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2973&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<div id="attachment_2974" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 471px"><a href="http://wrongside1.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/pussy-riot-london.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-2974  " title="BRITAIN LONDON PUSSY RIOT PROTEST" src="http://wrongside1.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/pussy-riot-london.jpg?w=461&h=311" alt="" width="461" height="311" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Three supporters of Russian female punk band Pussy Riot deliver a petition at the Russian embassy in London<br />Picture: EPA/KERIM OKTEN</p></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&#8220;This is all nonsense. I can&#8217;t believe that in the 21st century a judge in a secular court is talking about devilish movements. I can&#8217;t believe that a government official is quoting medieval church councils.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>- Boris Akunin, well known Russian author</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve been following along with and writing a bit about the Pussy Riot arrests and trial. Although the news of the Pussy Riot sentencing came down yesterday, I was too despondent to write about it. Nadezhda Tolokonnikova, Yekaterina Samutsevich and Marina Alyokhina have been found guilty of  &#8221;hooliganism&#8221; and sentenced to two years in prison.</p>
<p>A friend just said, &#8220;Well it could be worse, they could have got seven years.&#8221; See, not feeling the &#8220;it could be worse&#8221; vibe here.</p>
<p>These young women have been incarcerated since March &#8211; that means they have already served 5 months in jail, while the circus &#8230; emm .. I mean <em>trial</em> &#8230; has been under way. They have been accused of  ludicrous motivations: &#8220;destroying 1000′s of years of orthodox church tradition&#8221;, &#8221;undertaking the work of the devil&#8221;, &#8220;abusing god&#8221;, &#8220;blasphemy&#8221;, showing &#8220;religious hatred and enmity&#8221;&#8230;</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s pause to recap what they actually <em>did</em> do.</p>
<p>They <strong>sang a song.</strong></p>
<p>Yes in a church, yes about Putin, yes <strong>questioning the division of state and religion</strong>. Peaceable, creative, protest about social justice and political accountability and fairness.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m reading the news reports about the sentencing this morning.</p>
<p>Support of celebrities and Amnesty International has been <a title="Christian Science Monitor" href="http://www.csmonitor.com/USA/Society/2012/0817/Pussy-Riot-sentenced-Is-chorus-of-support-helpful-or-just-fashionable" target="_blank">suggested </a>to be &#8220;a magnet for vapid celebs&#8230;&#8221; International protests are questioned as being merely fashionable and not helpful. [ To see some wonderful shots of the protests, have a look <a title="Telegraph Picture Gallery" href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/picturegalleries/worldnews/9482820/Masked-Pussy-Riot-supporters-stage-demonstrations-around-the-world.html?frame=2312825" target="_blank">HERE</a>]</p>
<p>A recent poll suggests that Russian support for Pussy Riot is low,</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;&#8230; only 6 percent sympathized with the women and 51 percent found nothing good about them or felt irritation or hostility. The rest could not say or were indifferent.” &#8211; Independent Levada research group</p></blockquote>
<p>Some suggest that &#8220;clueless&#8221; non-Russians are simply unable to understand that what might be seen in their countries as &#8220;provocative political protest&#8221; is seen in Russia as considerably more serious. Some people even seem to think these young women are getting their just desserts.</p>
<p>The issue is complex. It is about the inter-relationship between government and church in a country that doesn&#8217;t want to address the issue, any more than <em>our countries</em> want to address the issue.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s right. The division of church and state is not a Russian issue.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://wrongside1.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/atheism-church-and-state.png"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-2986" title="Atheism - church and state - George Carlin" src="http://wrongside1.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/atheism-church-and-state.png?w=299&h=325" alt="" width="299" height="325" /></a></p>
<p>The Pussy Riot women, could be you, or me, or anyone who believes and values separation between church and state.</p>
<p>So who cares about what has happened to Pussy Riot? I care. I care that this trial has made a mockery of secular justice and has highlighted the lack of separation between church and state. I care that all of this has happened at the expense of three young women&#8217;s lives.</p>
<p>I care.</p>
<p>Were Nadezhda, Yekaterina and Marina foolish or brave? Did they know what they were signing on for? Do they regret their actions?</p>
<p>I think no. I hope no.</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;I am not afraid of you. I am not afraid of you and I am not afraid of the thinly veneered deceit of your verdict at this &#8216;so-called&#8217; trial. My truth lives with me. I believe that honesty, free-speaking and the thirst for truth will make us all a little freer. We will see this come to pass.&#8221;</p>
<p>Marina Alyokhina (Pussy Riot)</p></blockquote>
<p>An appeal is on the way. It ain&#8217;t over til the punk girls sing.</p>
<p>Related Posts: <a title="Lest We Forget" href="http://wrongside.me/2012/07/22/lest-we-forget/" target="_blank">Lest We Forget</a>; <a title="Speaking of Stupidity" href="http://wrongside.me/2012/08/02/speaking-of-stupidity/" target="_blank">Speaking Of Stupidity.. Pussy Riot Update</a>; <a title="More On the Pussy Riot Travesty" href="http://wrongside.me/2012/08/03/more-on-the-pussy-riot-travesty-emmm-trial/" target="_blank">More On The Pussy Riot Travesty &#8230; emmm&#8230; Trial</a>; <a title="The Church Is Offended" href="http://wrongside.me/2012/08/08/the-church-is-offended-and-the-pussy-riot-trial-continues/" target="_blank">The Church Is Offended and The Pussy Riot Trial Continues</a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2973/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2973/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2973&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://wrongside.me/2012/08/18/who-cares-pussy-riot-sentenced/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/35cb712dcab5bb29713a623a9052db3e?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Fiona</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://wrongside1.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/pussy-riot-london.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">BRITAIN LONDON PUSSY RIOT PROTEST</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://wrongside1.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/atheism-church-and-state.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Atheism - church and state - George Carlin</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Video Game Deaths: Are you really a hero?</title>
		<link>http://gameoveryousuck.wordpress.com/2012/08/16/video-game-deaths-are-you-really-a-hero/</link>
		<comments>http://gameoveryousuck.wordpress.com/2012/08/16/video-game-deaths-are-you-really-a-hero/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2012 21:56:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Chris Kodoku</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Video Games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[All You Need Is Kill]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[death]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hiroshi Sakurazaka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[memento mori]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://gameoveryousuck.wordpress.com/?p=68</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hiroshi Sukarazaka wrote a light novel called, &#8220;All You Need Is Kill&#8221;. Despite the engrish sounding title, the novel is pretty great. It follows a soldier fighting in a war against aliens. After his initial death, he finds himself in a time loop. Very Groundhog Day-esque, but instead of becoming a better person, the protagonist [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=68&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hiroshi Sukarazaka wrote a light novel called, &#8220;All You Need Is Kill&#8221;. Despite the engrish sounding title, the novel is pretty great. It follows a soldier fighting in a war against aliens. After his initial death, he finds himself in a time loop. Very Groundhog Day-esque, but instead of becoming a better person, the protagonist becomes a better soldier. Each death is a learning experience for him, and each time time reverts he is a little more knowledgable of himself and his enemies. I loved it. Ate it up. The soldiers drive small mechs called &#8220;jackets&#8221; to fight the aliens. Fuck yeah. </p>
<p>But the reason I&#8217;m posting this is because the author&#8217;s afterword struck me as intresting. Sakurazaka stated that he got his inspiration for the novel from video games. Sakurazaka said he received no satisfaction from completeing games, because he died several times along the way. The king would praise the hero, saying that the kingdom was saved only because of him. Well, of course, every time the hero died he was able to retry. Naturally, the hero would save the kingdom. </p>
<p>So in video games, how special is the main character? What justifies dying and retrying? Some games do this well, like Dark/Demons Souls, Kid Icarus, immortal characters, or characters that control time. But is Mario special when he saves the princess? Are the Hunters in Monster Hunter good because they can kill a towering beast in three tries? Is Snake the legendary soldier when he can load a checkpoint? </p>
<p>Logically this can all be explained. The &#8220;retry&#8221; in video games is a do over. To revert before the crisis. As if it never happened. Cannonly, Link saves Zelda without ever dying. Same with Mario. When the character dies, time is reverted to before the princess was doomed. </p>
<p>But role playing games are the worst about this. Kefka goes God mode, destroyes the party, game over. Then, time is reverted, and the characters grind for more EXP so they can kill Kefka. In Oblivion and Morrowind, you are a nobody, that becomes somebody. But how? Because you can do what the other NPCs can&#8217;t, revive from a save. These are games designed to immerse the player. You are a part of this world while you play. So at the end of the day, do you deserve to win? </p>
<p>Granted, this is a indepth look at entertainment. Yes, I understand that games wouldn&#8217;t be fun unless you could reload a save. I see the line between fantasy and reality. These are all just thought provoking concepts after all. But ever since Sukarazaka planted these thoughts in my head with his writing, I find myself being less satisfied being a hero.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/68/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/68/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=68&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://gameoveryousuck.wordpress.com/2012/08/16/video-game-deaths-are-you-really-a-hero/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>21</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a2c9c6c83252dad22a62359699e4bcdc?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">chriskodoku</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>I Knew It! Babies are Morally Bankrupt!!</title>
		<link>http://koshersamurai.wordpress.com/2012/08/17/i-knew-it-babies-are-morally-bankrupt/</link>
		<comments>http://koshersamurai.wordpress.com/2012/08/17/i-knew-it-babies-are-morally-bankrupt/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2012 11:13:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>koshersamurai</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fashion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Musings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Psychology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Style]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thoughts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://koshersamurai.wordpress.com/?p=4270</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Hats off once again to the gang over at ScienceDaily.com for blowing the lid off of this story. Babies May Not Have a &#8216;Moral Compass&#8217; After All New research from New Zealand&#8217;s University of Otago is casting doubt on a landmark US study that suggested infants as young as six months old possess an innate [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4270&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hats off once again to the gang over at ScienceDaily.com for blowing the lid off of this story.</p>
<h3 id="headline" style="text-align:center;"><a title="Babies May Not Have a 'Moral Compass' After All" href="http://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2012/08/120815093230.htm" target="_blank">Babies May Not Have a &#8216;Moral Compass&#8217; After All</a></h3>
<p>New research from New Zealand&#8217;s University of Otago is casting doubt on a landmark US study that suggested infants as young as six months old possess an innate moral compass that allows them to evaluate individuals as &#8216;good&#8217; or &#8216;bad&#8217;.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://koshersamurai.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/baby-08.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-4271" title="baby-08" src="http://koshersamurai.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/baby-08.jpg" alt="" width="424" height="283" /></a><em>(Ethically handicapped)</em></p>
<p>The 2007 study by Yale University researchers provided the first evidence that 6- and 10-month-old infants could assess individuals based on their behaviour towards others, showing a preference for those who helped rather than hindered another individual.</p>
<p>Based on a series of experiments, researchers in the Department of Psychology at Otago have shown that the earlier findings may simply be the result of infants&#8217; preferences for interesting and attention grabbing events, rather than an ability to evaluate individuals based on their social interactions with others.</p>
<p>The Otago study was recently published in <em>PLoS One</em>, an international, peer-reviewed, open-access, online journal.</p>
<p>In the original Yale experiment, infants watched a wooden toy (i.e., the &#8220;climber&#8221;) attempt to climb a hill. They viewed two social interactions; one in which a &#8220;helper&#8221; toy nudged the climber up the hill, and another in which a &#8220;hinderer&#8221; toy nudged the climber down the hill.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://koshersamurai.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/baby-091.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-4274" title="baby-09" src="http://koshersamurai.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/baby-091.jpg?w=391&h=448" alt="" width="391" height="448" /></a><em>(Future sociopath)</em></p>
<p>After viewing these two scenarios, the infants were presented with a tray; on one side of the tray was the helper and on the other side was the hinderer. Amazingly, the majority of infants picked the helper over the hinderer. To further elucidate infants&#8217; moral reasoning abilities, a &#8220;neutral&#8221; toy (i.e., a toy that neither helped nor hindered) was pitted against the helper or hinderer. When the neutral character was paired with the helper, the infants preferred the helper; when paired with the hinderer, they preferred the neutral character.</p>
<p>The paper concluded that the experiments show that infants can evaluate individuals based on how they interact with another individual, and that their ability to do this is &#8216;universal and unlearned&#8217;.</p>
<p>Lead Otago author Dr Damian Scarf says that the Yale study caused an international sensation when it was published in the leading journal <em>Nature</em>.</p>
<p>After reviewing videos of the Yale experiments, the Otago researchers noticed that two obvious perceptual events could be driving infants&#8217; choices.</p>
<p>&#8220;On the help and hinder trials, the toys collided with one another, an event we thought infants may not like. Furthermore, only on the help trials, the climber bounced up and down at the top of hill, an event we thought infants may enjoy.&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://koshersamurai.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/baby-10.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-4275" title="baby-10" src="http://koshersamurai.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/baby-10.jpg" alt="" width="400" height="300" /></a><em>(Has no conscience)</em></p>
<p>The researchers carried out a series experiments to test these assumptions and, by manipulating the collision and bouncing events, were able to show that these perceptual events were driving infants&#8217; choices of the helper over the hinderer, Dr Scarf says.</p>
<p>In other words, the infants couldn&#8217;t care less who was helping and who was hindering. They chose the one who was bouncing around more because it amused them.</p>
<p>&#8220;For example,&#8221; continues Dr Scarf, &#8220;when we had the climber bounce at the bottom of the hill, but not at the top of the hill, infants preferred the hinderer, that is, the one that pushed the climber down the hill. If the social evaluation hypothesis was correct, we should have seen a clear preference for the helper, irrespective of the location of the bounce, because the helper always helped the climber achieve its goal of reaching the top of the hill.&#8221;</p>
<p>So there you have it, boys and girls.</p>
<p>A generation of cold, heartless infants. They will be the ones who will eventually choose the nursing homes in which we end up.</p>
<p>Better start bouncing around now, folks!</p>
<p><a href="http://koshersamurai.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/aa-kendo-kanji-red4.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-4272" title="aa-kendo-kanji-red" src="http://koshersamurai.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/aa-kendo-kanji-red4.jpg" alt="" width="40" height="40" /></a></p>
<p>____________________________________________________________</p>
<p>Be sure to check out my sister blog, <a title="Vampyre Fangs" href="http://vampyrefangs.wordpress.com/" target="_blank">Vampyre Fangs</a>!</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://koshersamurai.wordpress.com/category/children/'>Children</a>, <a href='http://koshersamurai.wordpress.com/category/family/'>Family</a>, <a href='http://koshersamurai.wordpress.com/category/fashion/'>Fashion</a>, <a href='http://koshersamurai.wordpress.com/category/musings/'>Musings</a>, <a href='http://koshersamurai.wordpress.com/category/parenting-2/'>Parenting</a>, <a href='http://koshersamurai.wordpress.com/category/photography/'>Photography</a>, <a href='http://koshersamurai.wordpress.com/category/photos/'>Photos</a>, <a href='http://koshersamurai.wordpress.com/category/psychology/'>Psychology</a>, <a href='http://koshersamurai.wordpress.com/category/research/'>Research</a>, <a href='http://koshersamurai.wordpress.com/category/science/'>Science</a>, <a href='http://koshersamurai.wordpress.com/category/style/'>Style</a>, <a href='http://koshersamurai.wordpress.com/category/thoughts/'>Thoughts</a> Tagged: <a href='http://koshersamurai.wordpress.com/tag/children/'>Children</a>, <a href='http://koshersamurai.wordpress.com/tag/family/'>Family</a>, <a href='http://koshersamurai.wordpress.com/tag/fashion/'>Fashion</a>, <a href='http://koshersamurai.wordpress.com/tag/musings/'>Musings</a>, <a href='http://koshersamurai.wordpress.com/tag/parenting/'>parenting</a>, <a href='http://koshersamurai.wordpress.com/tag/photography/'>Photography</a>, <a href='http://koshersamurai.wordpress.com/tag/photos/'>Photos</a>, <a href='http://koshersamurai.wordpress.com/tag/research/'>Research</a>, <a href='http://koshersamurai.wordpress.com/tag/science-2/'>science</a>, <a href='http://koshersamurai.wordpress.com/tag/style/'>Style</a>, <a href='http://koshersamurai.wordpress.com/tag/thoughts/'>Thoughts</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4270/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4270/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4270&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://koshersamurai.wordpress.com/2012/08/17/i-knew-it-babies-are-morally-bankrupt/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>36</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/8b48dacdf202cce0807b65b291cdfeec?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F2.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=R" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">koshersamurai</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://koshersamurai.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/baby-08.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">baby-08</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://koshersamurai.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/baby-091.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">baby-09</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://koshersamurai.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/baby-10.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">baby-10</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://koshersamurai.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/aa-kendo-kanji-red4.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">aa-kendo-kanji-red</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Future of Superhero Films</title>
		<link>http://seereadhear.com/2012/08/17/whats-next-for-superheroes/</link>
		<comments>http://seereadhear.com/2012/08/17/whats-next-for-superheroes/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2012 13:48:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>josephsaunders</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Avengers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Batman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Catwoman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marvel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nolan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[superhero]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://seereadhear.wordpress.com/?p=43</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[After the enormous success of Marvel&#8217;s Cinematic Universe films (Avengers, Iron Man etc) and Nolan&#8217;s Batman series, comic book movies have now proven themselves not only as a great source of revenue, but also being of genuine artistic worth. Now that the most well known Superheroes have been used, has the genre already peaked? Nolan [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=43&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_46" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 529px"><a href="http://seereadhear.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/superheroes.jpg"><img src="http://seereadhear.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/superheroes.jpg" alt="" title="superheroes" width="519" height="161" class="size-full wp-image-46" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">With Batman hanging up his cape for now, the future of Superheroes appears to be in Marvel&#8217;s favour</p></div>
<p>After the enormous success of Marvel&#8217;s Cinematic Universe films (Avengers, Iron Man etc) and Nolan&#8217;s Batman series, comic book movies have now proven themselves not only as a great source of revenue, but also being of genuine artistic worth. Now that the most well known Superheroes have been used, has the genre already peaked?</p>
<p>Nolan redefined the Superhero genre, showing the depth and humanity of the man in the cape and cowl. Gone was the camp crusader of the 90&#8242;s, with Batman &amp; Robin being one of, if not the worst Superhero film&#8217;s of all time, most notably in one scene where Batman brandishes a Batman-branded credit card, and the declaration that he &#8216;never leaves the Batcave without it.&#8217; The Dark Knight Rises inclusion of Catwoman eradicated Warner&#8217;s abysmal outing, replacing the Wrestlemania-ready &#8216;brought back to life by a cat&#8217; vision and instead alluded towards Bob Kane&#8217;s original creation of a mysterious burglar and jewel thief. This is where DC has truly succeeded, realising the importance of character exploration. Next Summer marks the return of Superman, with DC undoubtedly hoping that they can build a new critical and commercial reboot which can go one of two ways:<br />
1) A second attempt-Hulk like flop, similarly to the Brandon Routh failed reboot just a few years ago.<br />
2) Nolan&#8217;s successful in presenting Superman in a modern context, leading to universal critical acclaim and a sizable box office performance, paving the way for future DC films.</p>
<p>DC will be hoping that the latter is the case, with a Justice League film in the pipeline with a 2014 release date being considered, any chance of getting the green light will almost certainly be riding on the success of Superman. One big problem with such an intended release date is bringing Superman, Batman, Wonder Woman, The Flash and Green Lantern together without the stable support of individual lead in films as Marvel achieved so well with The Avengers. Zach Snyder has said that Henry Cavill&#8217;s Superman won&#8217;t be part of Justice League, which will &#8216;have it&#8217;s own Superman and Batman.&#8217; With no foundations being built prior to its potential release, it&#8217;s hard to see a Justice League film performing anywhere near as well as The Avengers.</p>
<p>With a Hulk TV series in the pipeline, could this be the next step for superheroes? Going from the big screen to the small screen allows for much more character exploration than any 2 hour film would allow. With Marvel ever-expanding its Universe, TV series could easily strengthen any future films with cameos to keep the Universe a constant.</p>
<p> The Avengers and the five films that lead into it—both Iron Man films, The Incredible Hulk, Captain America, and Thor have earned Marvel Entertainment almost $4 billion dollars, making it the fourth-highest-grossing film franchise of all time. With the announcement that Avengers 2 is due for a 2015 release date, and sequels to Thor, Iron Man and Captain America due prior to this, as well as a new entry based on Guardians of the Galaxy, it&#8217;s hard to imagine Marvel not making a ton of money from these films. The Marvel Cinematic Universe is building an insular world that can hold any number of heroes and story arcs, and the more success it&#8217;s current franchises gain, the more likely they are to transfer lesser known comic book heroes to screen. Reboots are inevitable, regardless of whether a film performs well or not, allowing for fresh vision as proven with The Amazing Spiderman. With the Superman insignia being just as recognisable as the American flag, there will always be a place for reboots whether it be on TV or the big screen, it&#8217;s just a matter of when.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/43/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/43/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=43&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://seereadhear.com/2012/08/17/whats-next-for-superheroes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>18</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a64d03211deadecfc1764bf73726cc32?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">josephsaunders</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://seereadhear.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/superheroes.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">superheroes</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why My Husband Is Always Right About Tomatoes</title>
		<link>http://dinnerbysusan.wordpress.com/2012/08/17/why-my-husband-is-always-right-about-tomatoes/</link>
		<comments>http://dinnerbysusan.wordpress.com/2012/08/17/why-my-husband-is-always-right-about-tomatoes/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2012 18:28:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>dinnerbysusan</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Restaurants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cooking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gardening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gazpacho]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lucques]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[organic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Suzanne Goin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tomatoes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vegetarian]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dinnerbysusan.wordpress.com/?p=146</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;Do we really need 10 tomato plants?&#8221; That was my question last May as my husband and I loaded up a cart at Johnson&#8217;s Florist and Garden Center (http://www.johnsonsflorists.com/). &#8220;Sure,&#8221; he said. &#8220;You can never have too many tomatoes.&#8221; &#8220;But 10? Do we need 10?&#8221; I won&#8217;t bore you with the rest of the conversation, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=146&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;Do we really need 10 tomato plants?&#8221;</p>
<p>That was my question last May as my husband and I loaded up a cart at Johnson&#8217;s Florist and Garden Center (<a href="http://www.johnsonsflorists.com/">http://www.johnsonsflorists.com/</a>).</p>
<p><a href="http://dinnerbysusan.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tomato1.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-148" title="tomato" src="http://dinnerbysusan.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tomato1.jpg?w=150&h=112" alt="" width="150" height="112" /></a>&#8220;Sure,&#8221; he said. &#8220;You can never have too many tomatoes.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;But 10? Do we need 10?&#8221;</p>
<p>I won&#8217;t bore you with the rest of the conversation, which continued along the same lines until my husband pointed out that we would only have <em>eight</em> plants if I&#8217;d agree to part with the yellow pear and black Russian varieties.</p>
<p>Sacrilege! We ended up buying 10 plants. And thanks to this summer&#8217;s searing heat, I&#8217;ve had two never-ending bowls of ripe tomatoes sitting on my kitchen counter for a good six weeks. (Yellow pear and black Russian included.)</p>
<p>Thank goodness they&#8217;re tomatoes! There comes a time every summer when I simply cannot put another cucumber in my mouth. When I stare dully at the pile of zucchini and yellow squash and wonder how I can possibly cook them again. When I clap for joy as the bush beans wilt.</p>
<p>But tomatoes? Bring them on! We&#8217;re roasting them, marinating them, slicing them onto bagels and baguettes, drizzling them with olive oil and balsamic, broiling them with fresh mozzarella. We&#8217;ve even hauled out the canning pot and put up five pints for summer tomatoes this winter.</p>
<p>But every once in awhile, we want something different. Something a little more nuanced than plain tomato slices.</p>
<p>In her wonderful cookbook/cooking memoir <em>Sunday Suppers At Lucques</em>, chef Suzanne Goin offers 32 seasonal menus from her LA restaurant, Lucques (<a href="http://www.lucques.com/">http://www.lucques.com/</a>). While beautiful, most of the recipes can be daunting. (Grilled pancetta-wrapped trout with verjus, crushed grapes and fennel gratin, anyone?) But tucked amid the clafoutis and confits is a simple soup that both whirs up for an easy weeknight dinner and dresses up for a weekend dinner party. The only &#8220;work&#8221; part is peeling the tomatoes (a must to achieve the right texture), but with boiling water the process takes very little time.</p>
<p>You can make this soup with any type of tomato. Goin&#8217;s recipe calls for yellow fruit, but I think it&#8217;s best with a combination &#8212; yellow pear and black Russian included. Best of all, it doubles and even triples with ease, using bowlfuls of garden tomatoes in the process.</p>
<p>My husband, it turns out, was right. You can never have too many tomatoes.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">***</p>
<p><strong>Tomato Gazpacho</strong> (adapted from <em>Sunday Suppers At Lucques)</em></p>
<p>Pick <strong>2 1/2 pounds ripe tomatoes</strong> and cut an X in the bottom. Blanch them in boiling water for 30 seconds. Move to a bowl of ice water, then use your fingers to slip off the skins. Remove the cores and roughly chop, saving the juice.</p>
<p>Place have the tomatoes with their juices in a blender. Add <strong>half</strong><strong> a large, peeled cucumber</strong>, <strong>half a jalepeno</strong> (seeded if you want less heat), <strong>2 sprigs of cilantro</strong>, <strong>1 clove garlic</strong>, <strong>1 tablespoon red wine vinegar,</strong> <strong>3 tablespoons olive oil</strong> and salt and pepper. Puree until completely smooth, then pour into a serving bowl.</p>
<p>Place the other half of your tomatoes with their juices in a blender. Add the rest of the peeled cucumber and jalpeno, <strong>2 more sprigs of cilantro</strong> or<strong> a handful of fresh basil </strong>(or both!),<strong> 1 garlic clove</strong>, <strong>1 tablespoon red wine vinegar</strong>,<strong> 3 tablespoons olive oil</strong> and some more salt and pepper to taste. Puree until smooth and pour into your serving bowl.</p>
<p>Taste and season more if you like. If the soup seems too thick, add some ice water to thin. Chill until very, very cold.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/146/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/146/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=146&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://dinnerbysusan.wordpress.com/2012/08/17/why-my-husband-is-always-right-about-tomatoes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>18</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c2d195f805ce32a2ac967acda85cef9e?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">dinnerbysusan</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dinnerbysusan.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/tomato1.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tomato</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Am I Spock or Not?  &#8211; Two Books in Review</title>
		<link>http://cheviceunited.wordpress.com/2012/08/17/am-i-spock-or-not-two-books-in-review/</link>
		<comments>http://cheviceunited.wordpress.com/2012/08/17/am-i-spock-or-not-two-books-in-review/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2012 17:53:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>1frontrowseat</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sci Fi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Leonard Nimoy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Star Trek]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trekkie]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cheviceunited.wordpress.com/?p=3139</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#160; &#160; I Am Not Spock is an easy read.  As I recall, I finished it in one afternoon.  I&#8217;ve followed Star Trek since I was 9 years old and really, Captain Kirk was my first man hero until my son was born.  Almost too young to be besotted by stardom, I looked up to [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3139&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><img class="aligncenter" src="https://encrypted-tbn3.google.com/images?q=tbn:ANd9GcQjYnDglzcLG6VfQdT_DInOzaoFTY7UrvMqSmKlnS-dyZsOX2i9pQ" alt="" width="259" height="194" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>I Am Not Spock</em> is an easy read.  As I recall, I finished it in one afternoon.  I&#8217;ve followed <em>Star Trek</em> since I was 9 years old and really, Captain Kirk was my first man hero until my son was born.  Almost too young to be besotted by stardom, I looked up to him for my values and my courage, like a Hollywood mentor.  One line in <em>Star Trek V</em> spoken by Kirk is still on my mind today.</p>
<p>&#8220;Damn it, Bones, you&#8217;re a doctor. You know that pain and guilt can&#8217;t be taken away with a wave of a magic wand. They&#8217;re the things we carry with us, the things that make us who we are. If we lose them, we lose ourselves. I don&#8217;t want my pain taken away! I need my pain!&#8221;</p>
<p>This is one of an infinite number of script quotes that come out of <em>Star Trek</em> and into our lives as metaphors and little wisdoms.  We have been bombarded with life meaning by Gene Roddenberry over the course of <em>Star Trek</em>&#8216;s life.  Admittedly, I am a &#8220;Trekkie.&#8221;   So I read <em>Star Trek</em>.  I write about <em>Star Trek</em> in their fanfiction.  I watch <em>Star Trek</em>.  <em>Star Trek</em> is my one vice.</p>
<p>Seeing Leonard Nimoy in person during a lecture while I was in my early college years, I grew a fondness toward him for his intellect and his perspective.  So I finally picked up his book, <em>I Am Not Spock.  </em>It is a light hearted commentary on his life with a double identity.  He wrestled with the memories he has as Nimoy and the fictional character he plays as Spock.  &#8221;Fascinated&#8221; by losing his identity to Spock, he still recalls a former life when he was himself.  Now he is known as &#8220;Spock.&#8221;  When passersby see him in a crowd they might say, &#8220;Look, it&#8217;s Spock.&#8221;  When mothers walk hand in hand with their sons and daughters, then turn to them and say, &#8220;That&#8217;s Spock,&#8221;  The children look confused and holler, &#8220;No it&#8217;s not!&#8221;  (It&#8217;s just not the same without the ears.)  Whatever happened to Leonard Nimoy?  This book reveals who the man behind Spock is.</p>
<p>As people do, they like to fantasize, and fantasize they do.  They also often criticize.  So criticize they do.  Nimoy is <em>Star Trek</em> and to claim the existence of his real self is taken by some obsessives as a denial of his appreciation for <em>Star Trek</em>.  When he wrote this first book, <em>I Am Not Spock, </em>he was criticized by his fans and labeled an &#8220;ingrate&#8221; for the character who gave him his identity.  But wait.  He is really Leonard Nimoy, after all.  And so goes the struggle he&#8217;s had with his fame.  You can read about it and the oxymoron he lives in <em>I Am Not Spock</em></p>
<p>As an intelligent person might do when he is confronted with criticism, he revamped his book, &#8220;<em>I Am Not Spock</em>&#8221; in the sequel, &#8220;I<em> Am Spock</em>.&#8221;  In an almost apologetic way, he reiterated that he is, indeed appreciative of those who identified him with Spock and he makes no bones about the fact that the character Spock has had an incredible influence on Leonard Nimoy while Nimoy has had an influence on Spock.  In various discussions throughout this book between Nimoy and Spock, he stays in character through a fanciful and yet, realistic conversation between the two over ideals, memories, and judgments.  Logic vs. Heart is a common theme.  To say the least, it is &#8220;Fascinating.&#8221;</p>
<p>As I closed the final pages of Nimoy&#8217;s work regarding his two identity which he enthusiastically embraces, I realized that Spock is only a portion of the bigger picture of Leonard, yet not such a small portion.  I had not realized how talented and versatile Nimoy is.    I was most impressed with his efforts at directing and the details he reveals throughout the book; the challenges, the pains, the pleasures of it all.  Besides directing the third and fourth Star Trek movie, he did other such delights as <em>Three Men and a Baby</em> and the tragic story <em>The Good Mother</em>. I have to admit that S<em>tar Trek IV</em> was one of my enamored favorites.  The theme came from an attempt to lighten up the voyages because Spock had already been killed, Kirk&#8217;s son, and the Enterprise had been completely destroyed.  Looking for more versatility and a more upbeat attitude to <em>Star Trek,</em> Nimoy directed <em>Star Trek IV</em>, where the search for whale song dominated the theme amid the backdrop of modern day San Francisco tangled in time travel.  The story is genius and it is pure fun.</p>
<p>Learning the details of the film was the most enjoyable part of reading about his personal experiences with directing.  The scene in San Francisco where Chekhov was looking for nuclear wessles was delightful.  In a genius attempt to smitten the audience with the mood, Nimoy chose to put the cast on the streets of San Francisco in raw foot traffic.  Those people they are asking are just passing by.  When their question was answered by a local, &#8220;Across the bay in Alameda,&#8221; the scene was prized.  They pulled this local aside and gave her a contract then paid her for her spontaneous contribution.</p>
<p>From King Leer to King Arthur, from a <em>Mission Impossible</em> agent to Spock, from actor to director, Leonard Nimoy has found his niche.  He talks about his follies, his heart break, his assertiveness to protect the image of Spock against directors who don&#8217;t know him as well as they should.  He talks about what it is like to &#8220;die&#8221; then come back to life and the mourning that his counterpart, Leonard Nimoy tackles in the process of it all.  He talks about it all.</p>
<p>You will leave these books with a feel for the bigger picture of <em>Star Trek</em> and become even more of a fan than ever.</p>
<p>Live Long and Prosper</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://i.chzbgr.com/completestore/2009/9/18/128977587349193087.jpg" alt="I am NOT Spock  Oh, wait. I am." width="360" height="450" /></p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://cheviceunited.wordpress.com/category/books/'>Books</a>, <a href='http://cheviceunited.wordpress.com/category/entertainment/'>Entertainment</a>, <a href='http://cheviceunited.wordpress.com/category/reviews/'>Reviews</a>, <a href='http://cheviceunited.wordpress.com/category/sci-fi/'>Sci Fi</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3139/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3139/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3139&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://cheviceunited.wordpress.com/2012/08/17/am-i-spock-or-not-two-books-in-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/46d780dbd8dc229fdbd9a0df2d16c22c?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">1frontrowseat</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="https://encrypted-tbn3.google.com/images?q=tbn:ANd9GcQjYnDglzcLG6VfQdT_DInOzaoFTY7UrvMqSmKlnS-dyZsOX2i9pQ" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://i.chzbgr.com/completestore/2009/9/18/128977587349193087.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">I am NOT Spock  Oh, wait. I am.</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Body Worlds. Art or Science?</title>
		<link>http://saraheverest.wordpress.com/2012/08/17/body-worlds-art-or-science-contains-possibly-distressing-image/</link>
		<comments>http://saraheverest.wordpress.com/2012/08/17/body-worlds-art-or-science-contains-possibly-distressing-image/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2012 17:26:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>saraheverest</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Art]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://saraheverest.wordpress.com/?p=531</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Gunther Von Hagens, a German anatomist, has been plastered across TV screens and the World Wide Web for a fair few years now for his controversial studies and experimentation. Von Hagens created in 1977 [and patented in 1978] Plastination, a technique in which biological tissue specimens are preserved. For the first 20 years Plastination was [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=531&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://saraheverest.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/body-worlds.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-532" title="Body-Worlds" src="http://saraheverest.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/body-worlds.jpg" alt="" width="396" height="594" /></a></p>
<p>Gunther Von Hagens, a German anatomist, has been plastered across TV screens and the World Wide Web for a fair few years now for his controversial studies and experimentation. Von Hagens created in 1977 [and patented in 1978] Plastination, a technique in which biological tissue specimens are preserved. For the first 20 years Plastination was used as a medical technique to preserve small specimens for medical study, but this has now grown and from the early 1990’s was developed to make possible the Plastination of whole body specimens, a task that takes up to 1500 person hours.</p>
<p>A few years back I became aware of Von Hagens though a brilliantly detailed and fascinating exhibition at the O2 in London named BodyWorlds. BodyWorlds showcased the forms that Von Hagens had preserved, posed in particularly moving ways, from an athlete running to a gymnast swinging, all to monitor the inside workings of these different human beings. The exhibition not only introduced human works but also animals including a horse and a Giraffe [of which preservation took 3 years to complete, 10x longer than a human being]. Since BodyWorlds, the exhibitions and subsequent BW 2,3 and 4, has taken over 26 MILLION visits across the globe.</p>
<p>The question standing is; Is this Art?</p>
<p>I was and am absolutely fascinated by the works of Von Hagens; they are without a doubt aesthetically beautiful. The art of the human body, the art of the inner body works. So educating and so scientifically involved yet so absorbing in their visuals. Ultimately the technique of Plastination was created for medical purpose, but the visuals steer the exhibition very closely to the Art world. Where does it sit? Or can both co-exist.</p>
<p>The lines can be drawn between Von Hagen and Damien Hirst. If Hirsts form of preservation is artistically classified, does that draw Von Hagen into this category, or is it wrong to view the medical preservation of the human form as Artistic?</p>
<p>I look forward to attending Von Hagens Latest works at the Natural History Museum named ‘Animal Inside Out’. Perhaps then, with a fresh look, I will make up my mind&#8230;</p>
<p>&#8212;Sarah Everest</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/531/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/531/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=531&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://saraheverest.wordpress.com/2012/08/17/body-worlds-art-or-science-contains-possibly-distressing-image/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/7e4669f0f3ffa0556c30870692271feb?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">saraheverest</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://saraheverest.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/body-worlds.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Body-Worlds</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Letter From My Future Self</title>
		<link>http://xenogirl.com/2012/07/27/a-letter-from-my-future-self/</link>
		<comments>http://xenogirl.com/2012/07/27/a-letter-from-my-future-self/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2012 23:08:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>xenogirl</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Existential Meanderings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Literati]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[career]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Courage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creativity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fear]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mid-life crisis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shakespeare & Company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Short story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[xenogirl]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://xenogirl.com/?p=482</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I am writing this letter while seated before one of my favorite locations… in front of the Shakespeare and Company Bookstore here on the Left Bank in Paris, just steps from the Seine, Notre Dame, and Île de la Cité.  This is the very spot where my husband and I scurried in from the rain to spend that afternoon browsing through shelf after shelf of books.  It is a magical and glorious… 
<a class="more-link" href="http://xenogirl.com/2012/07/27/a-letter-from-my-future-self/">Continue reading</a><img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=482&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dear Amy,</p>
<p>I am writing this letter while seated at one of my favorite locations… in front of the <a class="zem_slink" title="Shakespeare and Company (bookstore)" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shakespeare_and_Company_%28bookstore%29" rel="wikipedia" target="_blank">Shakespeare and Company</a> Bookstore here on the Left Bank in Paris, just steps from the Seine, Notre Dame, and Île de la Cité. This is the very spot where my husband and I scurried in from the rain to spend the afternoon browsing through shelf after shelf of books. It is a magical and glorious bookstore, rich in literary history… a place that reminds me why I am so in love with the written word and the ideas wrapped within them.</p>
<p><a class="alignright zemanta-img" href="http://commons.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Shakespeare_and_Company_store_in_Paris.jpg" target="_blank"><img class="zemanta-img-inserted zemanta-img-configured" title="Title: Shakespeare and Company Taken on: 2004-..." src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/4/4e/Shakespeare_and_Company_store_in_Paris.jpg/300px-Shakespeare_and_Company_store_in_Paris.jpg" alt="Title: Shakespeare and Company Taken on: 2004-..." width="300" height="225" /></a></p>
<p>As a very young child, books were truly my first love. Each week, my parents drove me and my sisters to the local public library. I would study the shelves like a young Nancy Drew, investigating each title and dust cover with excitement and curiosity. The number of books I took home was limited only by the weight I could carry. With aching arms, I would eventually haul the teetering pile up to the front desk. The rhythmic sound of the librarian’s machine punching the due date on the check-out card filled me with anticipation. As a youth growing up in small town Wisconsin, reading was my only way to explore the world; I could visit new cities, solve mysteries, meet extraordinary people, and set forth on epic journeys. Day after day was spent hidden behind the pages of my latest literary adventure. Many late nights, I attempted to surreptitiously read by the dim glow of my digital alarm clock soon after my mother had yelled for me to go to bed.</p>
<p>Remember? What about those early experiments crafting my first verses and stories? I “wrote” my first poem before I knew how to actually write words; that poem is still in my baby book, transcribed proudly in my father’s hand writing. In elementary school, I attempted my first novella: twenty-seven hand-written pages (with drawings) about a brave girl, a magical land, and a lost medallion. In high school, I wrote. A lot. My most prized possession was my electric typewriter, which my parents had gifted to me for Christmas one year. Poetry and essays and short stories cluttered my notebooks and my brain and my backpack. An English teacher even persuaded me to submit one of my stories to a state writing contest. It didn’t win, but my teacher’s vote of confidence was an award onto itself.</p>
<p><a class="zemanta-img alignleft" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/50125742@N07/4702400300" target="_blank"><img class="zemanta-img-inserted zemanta-img-configured" title="Smith Corona Electra 120" src="http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1276/4702400300_e96d622744_m.jpg" alt="Smith Corona Electra 120" width="240" height="161" /></a></p>
<p>Back then, I always assumed that when I went to college, I would major in English. Of course I would be a writer! But somewhere along the way, my dreams and priorities changed. Honestly, I cannot even recall why or when I abandoned writing of the creative sort. In college, I instead found myself challenging my intellect with political science and philosophy and research methods and career goals and adult worries. Perhaps it was a growing yet misguided sense that maturity required leaving the creativity and imagination of my youth far behind me. Like a dearly cherished but forgotten stuffed animal, my love for writing was packed away into the dusty basement of my childhood memories. Hence, my life moved forward on a very different path.</p>
<p>Years passed. But then, remember when I turned 41? The mid-life crisis. Ugh. Oh how I struggled with my identity… my calling… my purpose. It was a dark and painful time. That summer of 2012, I just quit, much like an exhausted dog on a leash digging in its heels and refusing to take one more step. I couldn’t go forward on that path any farther. Not. One. More. Step. I cried a lot. Eventually, I started to write, albeit tentatively at first. I even started my first blog. Remember… my personal blog? Hitting the “publish” button each week was exhilarating and yet so scary.  I was again writing creatively&#8230; wrestling with ideas and imagination&#8230; shaping and ordering and willing words onto the keyboard!  Writing no longer consisted of plodding through the dry, technical productions that had defined my adult life. Soon, I began to see glimpses of that girl I had abandoned so many years before. I became braver. Bold, even. I started to write, honestly and authentically. I started to dream again. Ultimately, I clearly envisioned the answer to my existential questions &#8212; I was, indeed, a writer.</p>
<p>That answer terrified me.</p>
<p><a class="alignright zemanta-img" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Shakespeare_and_Company_Poets_Corner.jpg" target="_blank"><img class="zemanta-img-inserted zemanta-img-configured" title="Poet's Corner" src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/a/a3/Shakespeare_and_Company_Poets_Corner.jpg/300px-Shakespeare_and_Company_Poets_Corner.jpg" alt="Poet's Corner" width="300" height="443" /></a></p>
<p>Looking back, I can declare that all the fear, doubt, and pain of that summer and the year ahead were worth it. I faced many late nights alone, staring at the keyboard, questioning every idea and word that wandered across my intuition. I wrote, sometimes badly, sometimes well. When I wasn’t writing, I was thinking about writing. It consumed me. At the time, my greatest fear was that I would spend the next year of my life drafting a pathetic novel that would never be published. I was afraid that my longing to write was merely a cliche, soon-to-be-regretted, mid-life delusion. Was I really a talented writer? Was I creative enough? Did I have a story within me to tell that anyone would ever want to read? Was it too late?</p>
<p>Henri Mattise once proclaimed, “Creativity takes courage.” Indeed, that summer I had to make myself painfully vulnerable before I could rediscover myself and redirect my life towards fulfillment. I became vulnerable to risk. Vulnerable to criticism. Vulnerable to failure. Every excuse imaginable ruthlessly plagued my mind. I anticipated the very worst… and yet somehow, I chose to write anyway. Idea by idea and word by word, I slowly reshaped my frightened and insecure spirit into my first novel.</p>
<p><a href="http://xenogirl.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/mp900427685.jpg"><img class="alignleft  wp-image-489" title="Stack of Library Books (photo credit: office.microsoft.com)" src="http://xenogirl.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/mp900427685.jpg?w=200&h=300" alt="" width="200" height="300" /></a>So, more years have passed since that dark, yet transformative, summer. As I relax here in Paris, I can see my fifth book displayed in the window of the bookstore. My fifth! There are copies for sale in both English and the recently translated French version. I will confess that there are few things as satisfying as holding that first printed edition in my hands. Thumbing through the pages and inhaling the scent of the freshly bound paper is a soothing gift to my troubled soul. There is a rare joy in reading the words of my heart in print, bled out in the blackest of ink onto each numbered page. Words that change lives. Words that inspire. Words that can even change the world. This I believe to be true. Even today, as an author, doubt is still a constant companion of mine. However, now I understand that such vulnerability births the very creativity, expression, and fulfillment which I endlessly seek.</p>
<p>Writing this letter to my younger, aspiring self is bittersweet because I know I will receive it in the midst of that painful summer. I will read these words in the dead of a warm, silent night, shortly before the birds begin chirping in reprimand that I must soon sleep. As I read each word from my future self, my destiny will seem unrealistic, impossible, and foolish. That night, I will carefully fold this letter and hide it away in my journal. I will cry, not for the last time that summer, but then I will steady myself. Finally, with a deep breath, I will turn back to my keyboard in determination, and I shall write.</p>
<p>Adieu,</p>
<p>Amy</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/482/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/482/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=482&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://xenogirl.com/2012/07/27/a-letter-from-my-future-self/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>122</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://xenogirl.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/mp900427685.jpg?w=100" />
		<media:content url="http://xenogirl.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/mp900427685.jpg?w=100" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Stack of Library Books</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/24bad9971143c0559c14c2faa1a8e148?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">xenogirl</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/4/4e/Shakespeare_and_Company_store_in_Paris.jpg/300px-Shakespeare_and_Company_store_in_Paris.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Title: Shakespeare and Company Taken on: 2004-...</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1276/4702400300_e96d622744_m.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Smith Corona Electra 120</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/a/a3/Shakespeare_and_Company_Poets_Corner.jpg/300px-Shakespeare_and_Company_Poets_Corner.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Poet&#039;s Corner</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://xenogirl.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/mp900427685.jpg?w=200" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Stack of Library Books (photo credit: office.microsoft.com)</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>