<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2012 22:02:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Why Romney&#8217;s &#8220;Jello&#8221; Strategy Fails</title>
		<link>http://scotterb.wordpress.com/2012/09/16/why-romneys-jello-strategy-fails/</link>
		<comments>http://scotterb.wordpress.com/2012/09/16/why-romneys-jello-strategy-fails/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2012 14:35:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Scott Erb</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[2012 Election]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Barack Obama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Democrats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fiscal Cliff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mitt Romney]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Republicans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[US Politics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://scotterb.wordpress.com/?p=7385</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[You can&#8217;t nail jello to a tree, the saying goes, and it has been the philosophy of the Romney campaign.    It&#8217;s not working, and if Romney doesn&#8217;t change course soon, he&#8217;ll enter the twilight zone inhabited by John McCain, Bob Dole and Walter Mondale as they went through the motions in a campaign whose [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=7385&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_7387" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://scotterb.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/romney-flip-flop.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-7387" title="romney flip flop" src="http://scotterb.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/romney-flip-flop.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="388" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">In politics it&#8217;s a good idea to turn a weakness into a strength; Romney tried to do so with his reputation as a flip flopper</p></div>
<p>You can&#8217;t nail jello to a tree, the saying goes, and it has been the philosophy of the Romney campaign.    It&#8217;s not working, and if Romney doesn&#8217;t change course soon, he&#8217;ll enter the twilight zone inhabited by John McCain, Bob Dole and Walter Mondale as they went through the motions in a campaign whose outcome was already known.</p>
<p>On paper, Romney&#8217;s &#8220;Jello&#8221; strategy made sense.   First, Romney has a record as a solid businessman who saved the Salt Lake City Olympic games (exaggerated credit, but hey &#8211; this is politics) and is known as a pragmatic moderate.   He&#8217;s in a race against an incumbent suffering an ongoing economic crisis, and whose legislative activism has generated strong antipathy on the right.   Still, Obama has a solid campaign team good at opposition research and not afraid to play rough.</p>
<p>The fear in Romneyworld?   Team Obama will take apart any specific plan or policy they put forth and use it against them targeting whatever demographic might be most turned off.   Worse, they could make the election about comparing plans as the campaign sinks to a morass of detail, rather than it being about replacing a failing President who got in over his head with an experienced private sector success.</p>
<p>The answer?   Stay vague.   Don&#8217;t give them any ammo, say nothing specific that can be used against Romney.   Instead, play the game on their own turf, make it about how the President&#8217;s plans have failed, put Obama on the defensive.    Be jello.   If they land a punch &#8211; squish &#8211; the jello shifts shape and remains.    Obama will be flailing but unable to connect.   Romney can pick and choose from Obama&#8217;s four year record to attack at will.</p>
<p>Won&#8217;t people demand specifics?   Nope &#8211; modern campaigns are about big themes and slogans.   Moderates will simply assume that a pragmatic moderate Republican businessman can be trusted.   Romney will veer right in rhetoric but people will assume that&#8217;s just for politics.   The right wing will have to accept the rhetoric and support him because they&#8217;re virulently anti-Obama.</p>
<p>Keys: keep it about the economy, avoid distractions, and don&#8217;t get suckered into giving details or responding to them.  Stay on track, implement the strategy and don&#8217;t let the ups and downs of the campaign tempt you to respond!   Expect the flip flop charge to work in your favor &#8211; moderates won&#8217;t believe the scare tactics coming from Obama, but the base will be satisfied that you&#8217;re the best choice.    Meanwhile massive amounts of negative advertising by outside groups will grind Obama so far down that he&#8217;ll be like Dukakis in 1988, diminished and ridiculed.   Indeed the rhetoric trotted out this summer by right wing pundits telegraphed that strategy &#8211; Obama was described as a desperate and incompetent loser, flailing about uncertainly in order to hold power.    Team Romney counted on that image to stick.</p>
<p>Trouble is, the strategy isn&#8217;t working.   President Obama has found a way to nail jello to a tree &#8211; nail the whole box!</p>
<div id="attachment_7386" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 630px"><a href="http://scotterb.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/jellotree.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-7386" title="jellotree" src="http://scotterb.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/jellotree.jpg" alt="" width="620" height="465" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Can you nail jello to a tree?</p></div>
<p>Instead of trying to trap Romney on details, the Obama team decided that if Romney didn&#8217;t want to paint a clear picture of who he is and what he&#8217;ll do, they&#8217;d oblige and paint one for them.    They&#8217;d choose how to define him, and shape the campaign narrative instead.    They nailed the entire Romney box to a tree.</p>
<p>Romney is afraid to release his tax returns.  He&#8217;s secretive.  He&#8217;s far right.  His policies are the same of those of President Bush, the same policies that brought this mess upon us.  His foreign policy is bravado and bluster, look where that got us!  Talking tough and saying America must be strong sounds like George W. Bush all over again &#8211; will Iran be the next Iraq?  And it&#8217;s working, Romney seems empty, doesn&#8217;t seem to stand for anything, and the campaign narrative is being defined by the President&#8217;s team.  Intrade odds are now 67% for an Obama victory.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve said this before, but now it&#8217;s critical.   If we are to have a real race for the Presidency Romney has to come out and make a case, take a stand and level with the American people.   Being Jello may have seemed to be a good idea on paper, but it isn&#8217;t working.   I don&#8217;t think his campaign yet understands the extent of the change that they need.  Consider the focus they&#8217;re shifting to the &#8220;fiscal cliff.&#8221;</p>
<div id="attachment_7393" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 630px"><a href="http://scotterb.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/fiscalcliff.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-7393" title="fiscalcliff" src="http://scotterb.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/fiscalcliff.jpg" alt="" width="620" height="353" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">People don&#8217;t want vague attacks, they want solutions.</p></div>
<p>The debt ceiling was raised last year in an agreement that if the Congress could agree on spending cuts/revenue enhancements by 2013 automatic spending cuts would snap in place.   These include cuts on programs the Democrats support and defense cuts that Republicans are loathe to see implemented.  The idea was that the this would force them to compromise.   It didn&#8217;t work, at least not yet.</p>
<p>Governor Romney is issuing strong denunciations of Obama&#8217;s role in this agreement, though it was essentially a bi-partisan compromise.  Even Paul Ryan voted for it.  Moreover, it&#8217;s complex &#8211; look at the chart.   Warning of a &#8220;fiscal cliff&#8221; sounds vague and strange to voters.   If he gets into the details of what that entails, it gets confusing.  I think one mistake the Romney camp has made this year is that they are too &#8220;inside politics&#8221; in their arguments.   They use terms and labels that bloggers and political junkies know, but aren&#8217;t connecting to average voters.   Politicians need to always remember that the &#8220;inside game&#8221; is oblique and mysterious to most Americans.</p>
<p>The &#8220;Jello&#8221; strategy certainly seemed compelling on paper, but it&#8217;s failed.   Romney can stubbornly stick to it, hoping that bad news and perhaps a stumble by Obama will pull him over the top.  Given the economy, that <em>might</em> work (though I doubt it).   Or he can do something that some people doubt he knows how to do:  be himself.  Say what he thinks.   Defend the principles he believes in without worrying about what demographic group he might offend, or how the Obama team might use it against him.   He can take specific stands and lay out a vision of the future that goes beyond, &#8220;hey, I&#8217;m a businessman, I know how to run a company, trust me with the country.&#8221;</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a high risk high reward shift.  If he pulls it off, he could beat Obama.   If he fails he could turn off his base and risk an even bigger defeat than what now looks likely.     Yet the American people deserve to know what the Republican challenger wants for the country.   We&#8217;re not looking for a CEO, we&#8217;re looking for a President.    And if Romney refuses to comply, then team Obama will be happy to fill in the blanks and define what Romney&#8217;s vision really is.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/7385/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/7385/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=7385&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://scotterb.wordpress.com/2012/09/16/why-romneys-jello-strategy-fails/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f69adb1eef282ff6040b276698d1ebe4?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F0.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">scotterb</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://scotterb.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/romney-flip-flop.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">romney flip flop</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://scotterb.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/jellotree.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jellotree</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://scotterb.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/fiscalcliff.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">fiscalcliff</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Wordhacking Made Easy</title>
		<link>http://makeapowerfulpoint.com/2012/09/05/wordhacking-made-easy/</link>
		<comments>http://makeapowerfulpoint.com/2012/09/05/wordhacking-made-easy/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2012 04:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Gavin</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Words]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Neoligism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Truthiness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Word of the year]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wordhacking]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://makeapowerfulpoint.com/?p=1351</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Dirty Harry speaks to a chair and overnight, Eastwooding enters the vocabulary. Eastwooding is an easy one, like Tebowing. Adding a gerund (an ing) to a noun is child&#8217;s play. More advanced wordhacks — Stephen Colbert elevating truthiness to a word of the year —  is an art form. Making up new words (that&#8217;s neologisms for the wordanistas [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1351&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://makeapowerfulpoint.com/2012/09/05/wordhacking-made-easy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://makeapowerfulpoint.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/powerfulpoint-blog-post-word-hacking-made-easy.png?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://makeapowerfulpoint.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/powerfulpoint-blog-post-word-hacking-made-easy.png?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">PowerfulPoint-Blog-Post-word-hacking-made-easy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/4770fa87e113c38e79fbe0beeebaeb7a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">makeapowerfulpoint</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://makeapowerfulpoint.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/wordhacking-part1.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">WordHacking-Part#1</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>On Child-Free Weddings</title>
		<link>http://thisruthlessworld.wordpress.com/2012/09/05/on-child-free-weddings/</link>
		<comments>http://thisruthlessworld.wordpress.com/2012/09/05/on-child-free-weddings/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2012 17:44:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Amused</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[feminism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weddings]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thisruthlessworld.wordpress.com/?p=805</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Over at Feministe, there is a discussion on whether banning children from weddings &#8212; which is becoming a trend, apparently &#8212; should be perceived as offensive to parents who are invited. Lots of virtual ink is spilled detailing children’s propensity for undecorous behavior, the poor parenting skills of people who reproduce (as oppose to the [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=805&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://thisruthlessworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/d0ba_d0b5_d0bcd0b0d0bad0bed0b2d181d0bad0b8d0b9_d0b1d0bed18fd180d181d0bad0b8d0b9_d181d0b2d0b0d0b4d0b5d0b1d0bdd18bd0b9_d0bfd0b8d180_d0b2_x.jpg"><img src="http://thisruthlessworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/d0ba_d0b5_d0bcd0b0d0bad0bed0b2d181d0bad0b8d0b9_d0b1d0bed18fd180d181d0bad0b8d0b9_d181d0b2d0b0d0b4d0b5d0b1d0bdd18bd0b9_d0bfd0b8d180_d0b2_x.jpg?w=300&h=174" alt="" title="K.E. Makovsky, &quot;A Boyar&#039;s Wedding Feast in the 17th Century&quot; (1883)" width="300" height="174" class="alignright size-medium wp-image-806" /></a><a href="http://www.feministe.us/blog/archives/2012/08/13/not-another-mummy-blogger-2/#comment-498732">Over at Feministe</a>, there is a discussion on whether banning children from weddings &#8212; which is becoming a trend, apparently &#8212; should be perceived as offensive to parents who are invited.  Lots of virtual ink is spilled detailing children’s propensity for undecorous behavior, the poor parenting skills of people who reproduce (as oppose to the child-free, who frequently emerge in these discussions as <i>the</i> experts on proper parenting), and why whole classes of adults are not excluded from such events based on unacceptable behavior of certain of their members, while excluding children is okay.<span id="more-805"></span></p>
<p>In all fairness, an invitation banning children from a wedding isn’t so controversial these days.  I once read of a couple whose wedding invitations specified that guests were expected to have mastered classic waltz by the day of the event, set forth instructions on how to twirl properly, warned that incorrect or ungraceful twirling would not be tolerated and contained a request that anyone unable or unwilling to twirl properly refrain from attending.  Even that, I am sure, isn’t the most extreme of attempts by marrying couples to achieve a “perfect” wedding.</p>
<p>Incidentally, think of what most people believe makes a wedding “perfect”.  The word conjures up images of palacial spaces, billowing pastel-colored dresses, immaculately coiffed hair, fine china and moving, heartfelt pontification.  Weddings were once rowdy affairs where children ran around, people danced with abandon, and newlyweds would sneak off right about when the merrymaking reached a fever pitch.  No longer.  A “perfect” modern American wedding more closely resembles a funeral than a family celebration &#8212; hence the growing feeling that it’s inappropriate for children.  Often, it’s not a celebration at all, but rather a <i>proceeding</i>, a stilted, highly scripted event, in which a bunch of ordinary yokels pretend to be Marie Antoinette.  </p>
<p>Few people get to do this more than three times in a lifetime, and therefore the stakes are very high.  The months and sometimes years leading up to the Big Day are full of feverish preparation and agonizing over the most minute details, arguing over tablecloth shades and sitting arrangements, insane diet-and-workout routines designed to make the bride look her most photogenic for that unforgiving (yet absolutely mandatory) strapless gown and ungodly amounts of stress, that threatens to undermine the very relationship that the wedding is intended to celebrate.  The proceedings are meticulously rehearsed &#8212; the canned, preachy speeches and the obviously choreographed “first kiss as a married couple”.  (Bleh.)  The modern wedding is a spectacle.  The emphasis is on solemnity, order and display &#8212; but above all, on creating an impressive, flawless photographic and video record.  There is very little place there for actual fun.  It is not unlike putting on a full-scale opera, except that relative to means, it represents Mars Rover landing-levels of cost, preparation, and delicacy of execution.   Is it any wonder some massively stressed-out couples don’t want kids anywhere near such an important and complicated operation?  An untimely yelp from some little fucker at any point during a wedding would be no different than a baby bawling in the middle of a performance of <i>Don Giovanni</i>.  Weddings are serious business, people.</p>
<p>Bashing weddings is not unpopular, and I hasten to separate myself from the crowd that always rushes to point out that the money spent on a wedding would be better used towards a downpayment on a home.  I actually hate it when people say things like that.  (I myself did not have a traditional wedding, but I recall a conversation by the side or a water cooler when a co-worker expressed dismay and outrage that my husband and I would spend money on a trip to Italy when we didn’t even own a home yet.)  The American obsession with home ownership for its own sake, no matter the cost or individual circumstances, is almost as ridiculous as the obsession with “perfect” weddings.  Moreover, I cringe at the underlying notion here, that it’s wrong to spend lots of money on pleasure, that young married couples should prove their grasp of responsibility by spending money only in “serious” ways, such as by buying a home when they may not want or need one.  I think that leading an enjoyable life &#8212; within reason, of course, but still &#8212; is just as important as investing money (and buying a home isn’t the only, and isn’t always the best, way to do this) and providing for any kids’ educations and one’s old age.  </p>
<p>Rather, what bothers me about “perfect” weddings is that so much emotional capital is staked on something so ephemeral, that friendships and familial ties are put in jeopardy for the sake of putting on a show.  If people applied the same energy and hard work to their marriages, the divorce rate would be close to zero.  It’s not the money that I see as the problem &#8212; though the great expenditures are certainly one manifestation of what I believe is the trouble here &#8212; it’s the over-the-top tackiness, the haughty showmanship implicit in “perfect” weddings.  The latest “no children allowed” trend is merely part of the growing obnoxiousness of that display.</p>
<p>It was said repeatedly in the thread I linked that the marrying couple have the right to decide who does or does not attend their wedding.  After all, it’s <i>their</i> day, and the guest list is their prerogative.  That is, of course, true.  However, there is often a confusion in people’s minds between having the right to do something and having the right to receive only innocuous reactions to whatever it is you do simply because you have the “right” to do it.  Of course the marrying couple may bar whomever they want to achieve their own version of a successful wedding, but expecting people never to take offense is a bit much.  The Bride and the Groom could just as well send out invitations that instruct guests not to bring significant others who are overweight, <i>because we want only conventionally attractive people at our wedding for the purpose of producing an aesthetically pleasing visual record, and it’s OUR special day, and we have the right not to allow any fat fatties, so don’t feel offended, we have the RIGHT</i>.  I’m sorry, but that’s highly unrealistic.  Point is, when you invite a relative or a friend to an event that’s meant to celebrate you starting a family, and tell them that a member of their immediate family is not welcome for reasons of elegance, you convey to that friend or relative exactly how much you value your relationship.  </p>
<p>Don’t be surprised if she gets the message.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/805/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/805/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=805&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thisruthlessworld.wordpress.com/2012/09/05/on-child-free-weddings/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>41</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/849260008d0626b824c96d8208ae7198?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">khozyajka</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thisruthlessworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/d0ba_d0b5_d0bcd0b0d0bad0bed0b2d181d0bad0b8d0b9_d0b1d0bed18fd180d181d0bad0b8d0b9_d181d0b2d0b0d0b4d0b5d0b1d0bdd18bd0b9_d0bfd0b8d180_d0b2_x.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">K.E. Makovsky, &#34;A Boyar&#039;s Wedding Feast in the 17th Century&#34; (1883)</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Lonely States of America?</title>
		<link>http://stephenedelstein.wordpress.com/2012/08/31/the-lonely-states-of-america/</link>
		<comments>http://stephenedelstein.wordpress.com/2012/08/31/the-lonely-states-of-america/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2012 14:43:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>lib1187</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Airbnb]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Atlantic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kurt Vonnegut]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mass transit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://stephenedelstein.wordpress.com/?p=598</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[“The great American disease is loneliness,” Kurt Vonnegut once said in an interview. He was right, as he was about most things, and that loneliness seems to be facilitated by technology. When Vonnegut was raising his family in postwar America, television was seen as an engine of antisocial behavior. Now, we have something much better: [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=598&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://stephenedelstein.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_0485.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-599" title="People on the T" src="http://stephenedelstein.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_0485.jpg?w=225&h=300" alt="People on the T" width="225" height="300" /></a>“The great American disease is loneliness,” Kurt Vonnegut once said in an interview. He was right, as he was about most things, and that loneliness seems to be facilitated by technology.</p>
<p>When Vonnegut was raising his family in postwar America, television was seen as an engine of antisocial behavior. Now, we have something much better: Facebook. In an article for the <em>Atlantic</em> called <a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2012/05/is-facebook-making-us-lonely/308930/">“Is Facebook Making Us Lonely?”</a> Stephen Marche argues that social media facilitate an innate desire people have to keep each other at a distance.</p>
<p>Marche correlates an increase in loneliness (measured by such things as the UCLA Loneliness Scale) and the rise of social media. However, he does not blame social media for American loneliness.</p>
<p>“Loneliness is certainly not something that Facebook or Twitter or any of the lesser forms of social media is doing to us,” Marche said. “We are doing it to ourselves.”</p>
<p>People are, after all, annoying, and Marche acknowledges this. He says Facebook and other social media apparatus could be used to bring people together, but people instead use them to sanitize all their social interactions and, ultimately, avoid all the unpleasantness of real time, face-to-face communication.</p>
<p>If Marche is right, then American society is about to get a whole lot lonelier.</p>
<p>In <a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2012/05/is-facebook-making-us-lonely/308930/">“The Cheapest Generation,”</a> a more recent article in the <em>Atlantic</em>, Derek Thompson and Jordan Weissmann argue that “Millenials” are ditching automobile and home ownership for sharing schemes like Zipcar and Airbnb. They say Millenials will push America toward a more communal economy, focused on “urban light” neighborhoods instead of traditional suburbs.</p>
<p>That sounds pretty appealing, but I don’t think the America my generation builds will be an urban hipster version of a hippie commune. It might be even lonelier than it is today.</p>
<p>Car sharing programs like Zipcar give members most of the convenience of car ownership without the soul-crushing costs and perpetual need for parking spaces. Members can pick up a car from designated stations on short notice, drive it as much as they want (they get charged by the minute or hour) and drop it off when they’re done.<a href="http://stephenedelstein.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/zipcar-004.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-600" title="Zipcar at Clark University" src="http://stephenedelstein.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/zipcar-004.jpg?w=225&h=300" alt="Zipcar at Clark University" width="225" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>It’s a great solution for people who live in urban areas, but it also reduces the driving experience to its essence: privacy. Unless a Zipcar driver is going somewhere with no mass transit, why not take the train? It would be cheaper, and give one more free time.</p>
<p>Car owners need privacy because they’re going places no one else is going; they need flexibility. But if the future really is in car sharing, would anyone take the subway if they knew they could just as easily ride alone?</p>
<p>The &#8220;Millenial&#8221; generation might easily choose the latter. We&#8217;ve grown up accustomed to texting instead of talking, and thinking that social movements can be organized solely through social media. We control the amount of our reactions with other people in a way no previous generation has.</p>
<p>Thompson and Weissmann believe personal property is a concept this generation is not accustomed to. In the same vein, spontaneous everyday interactions could be something that we avoid, and don&#8217;t want to experience just because they represent a current social norm.</p>
<p>If people are so quick to trade the uncertainty of phone calls for Facbeook statuses, and the tedium of waiting in line for self-checkout, will they be able to resist hopping in a car instead of riding with the crowd? Or will urban transportation become one more people-free aspect of our society?</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/598/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/598/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=598&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://stephenedelstein.wordpress.com/2012/08/31/the-lonely-states-of-america/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>20</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/473a4f165247f3cf60a8ae9ea38aaf47?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lib1187</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://stephenedelstein.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_0485.jpg?w=225" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">People on the T</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://stephenedelstein.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/zipcar-004.jpg?w=225" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Zipcar at Clark University</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What Choice(s) Do I Have?</title>
		<link>http://whatsmyage.wordpress.com/2012/09/09/what-choices-do-i-have/</link>
		<comments>http://whatsmyage.wordpress.com/2012/09/09/what-choices-do-i-have/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2012 00:54:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Justin Almeida</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advocacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[choice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[citizen power]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[consumerism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[environment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fair trade]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[human rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[responsible investment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[slavery]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://whatsmyage.wordpress.com/?p=102</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I am an American consumer. I have no little choice in the matter. There are extreme options for living off the grid, but I live in a big city (Seattle).  Therefore, I must do as the Seattlites do. I try to make intelligent, conscientious consumer choices: buying second hand, buying local, buying independent. However, these choices [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=102&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://whatsmyage.wordpress.com/2012/09/09/what-choices-do-i-have/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>43</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/88b8b349ad6a440dd5267bf37b637cba?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">justinwalmeida</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://whatsmyage.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/consumer_jesus_banksy1.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">consumer_jesus_banksy1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://whatsmyage.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/bloody-usb-f.jpg?w=200" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Bloody-USB-f</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://whatsmyage.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/csr.jpg?w=227" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">CSR</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://whatsmyage.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/food-desert-1.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">food-desert-1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://whatsmyage.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/01.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">01</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://whatsmyage.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/el-traje-de-gandhi.jpg?w=208" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">el traje de Gandhi</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Post Challenge: Stylish Imitation—The Choice</title>
		<link>http://catontherocks.wordpress.com/2012/09/11/stylish-imitation-the-choice/</link>
		<comments>http://catontherocks.wordpress.com/2012/09/11/stylish-imitation-the-choice/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2012 17:36:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Catalina</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[literature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creative writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPChallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[james joyce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[modernism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[short story]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://catontherocks.wordpress.com/?p=259</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Short story placing an ancient mythical plot in the modern world, supposedly in the style of James Joyce or modernism in general. Adapted for the Weekly Writing Challenge. The cell phone on the table just like last time I was here. Except last time she was here with me, looking at me lovingly from the [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=259&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://catontherocks.wordpress.com/2012/09/11/stylish-imitation-the-choice/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>22</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://catontherocks.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/id-10049493.jpg?w=99" />
		<media:content url="http://catontherocks.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/id-10049493.jpg?w=99" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ID-10049493</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/3fc39d791eb2fbc80c229fee7ab234c6?s=96&#38;d=monsterid&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">catontherocks</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://catontherocks.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/id-10049493.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ID-10049493</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Post Challenge: Jane Eyre aka Lucy</title>
		<link>http://soberistas.wordpress.com/2012/09/11/jane-eyre-aka-lucy-soberistas/</link>
		<comments>http://soberistas.wordpress.com/2012/09/11/jane-eyre-aka-lucy-soberistas/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2012 21:33:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>soberistas</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Lucy's page]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alcohol]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alcoholism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[booze]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPchallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drinking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jane Eyre]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new beginnings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sober]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sobriety]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://soberistas.wordpress.com/?p=345</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Ok, I haven’t lost the plot, or started drinking again. The following post is my effort for this week’s DP Challenge – to write in the style of your favourite author. The book that first touched me in the way that only a great book can, was Jane Eyre – here then, is an account [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=345&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:justify;"><em><a href="http://soberistas.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/bookcover.jpg"><br />
</a>Ok, I haven’t lost the plot, or started drinking again. The following post is my effort for this week’s DP Challenge – to write in the style of your favourite author. The book that first touched me in the way that only a great book can, was Jane Eyre – here then, is an account of the night I met my wonderful fiancé, written in the style of Charlotte Bronte. Let me know what you think – I loved writing it!</em></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><a href="http://soberistas.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/bookcover1.jpg"><img class="alignleft  wp-image-350" style="margin-left:3px;margin-right:5px;" title="bookcover" src="http://soberistas.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/bookcover1.jpg?w=200&h=301" alt="" width="200" height="301" /></a>I cannot begin to imagine what I was thinking when, as I was wont to do in those days, I entered the drinking establishment and requested yet another vessel of wine from the surly gentleman behind the bar. It must have been my sixth or seventh of the evening and my thoughts no longer belonged to me; it is true to say that I was beyond personal cognisance. My companion and I had frequented several inns that evening, and had arrived at the conclusion that we should indeed venture forth to our own abodes, as the night had drawn in and we were feeling fatigued and somewhat histrionic as a result of the excessive palliative liquid that we had imbibed.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Instead of departing for home, however, we made the decision to embark upon the short journey to what would become our penultimate destination; a dark but tolerably jovial inn, warm and invigorating after our short walk through the algid gloom outside. After purchasing our beverages, we sought to discover available chairs – the parlour room toward the rear of the hostel was packed full of revellers, and Reader, I must confess to staggering and lurching, owing to my drunken state. Finally, we almost fell upon a wooden bench alongside two ladies of fair countenance, and a gentleman who was swarthy and brooding.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">My recollection of the conversation is a little vague, now that so many months have passed, although I can summon up the first words that that gentleman spoke to me – “<em>Perhaps you do not recall, but we met some time ago, one evening last summer. You remarked upon my apparel &#8211; a shirt illustrated with an album cover of the musical four piece, The Smiths, of which you expressed your approval</em>.” As melodic as pealing bells, my heart leapt as we reacquainted ourselves and despite my addled mind, I felt as though I had arrived home, that I had reached my destiny.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Our conversation was not blighted with awkward silences, nor did we encounter difficulties in happening upon subjects that we held in common. I am no professed harlot, but so drawn to this man was I - as well as being intoxicated by the potency of the alcohol &#8211; that I found myself inching toward him, my hand reaching out to fondle his near thigh. He did not profess to bother &#8211; indeed his gentlemanly persuasions led him to grasp my palm, caressing it in his as though we had been lovers for decades.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">He showed himself to be a courteous and honourable man, a friend from the beginning, and the man who led me to the much longed for road to sobriety. That night represented the twinkling threshold of a wonderful chapter in my life – the unparalleled existence of living without the blur of alcohol; the birth of a redefined version of my self, originated by leaving the wine behind on that cold, January night.</p>
<p> Reader, I became engaged to him.</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://soberistas.wordpress.com/category/lucys-page/'>Lucy's page</a> Tagged: <a href='http://soberistas.wordpress.com/tag/alcohol/'>alcohol</a>, <a href='http://soberistas.wordpress.com/tag/alcoholism/'>alcoholism</a>, <a href='http://soberistas.wordpress.com/tag/books/'>books</a>, <a href='http://soberistas.wordpress.com/tag/booze/'>booze</a>, <a href='http://soberistas.wordpress.com/tag/dpchallenge/'>DPchallenge</a>, <a href='http://soberistas.wordpress.com/tag/drinking/'>drinking</a>, <a href='http://soberistas.wordpress.com/tag/health/'>health</a>, <a href='http://soberistas.wordpress.com/tag/jane-eyre/'>Jane Eyre</a>, <a href='http://soberistas.wordpress.com/tag/new-beginnings/'>new beginnings</a>, <a href='http://soberistas.wordpress.com/tag/reading/'>reading</a>, <a href='http://soberistas.wordpress.com/tag/relationships/'>relationships</a>, <a href='http://soberistas.wordpress.com/tag/sober/'>sober</a>, <a href='http://soberistas.wordpress.com/tag/sobriety-2/'>sobriety</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/345/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/345/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=345&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://soberistas.wordpress.com/2012/09/11/jane-eyre-aka-lucy-soberistas/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>42</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/289ac34771b59bffedfaf93832a27d4b?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">soberistas</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://soberistas.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/bookcover1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bookcover</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Post Challenge: Telepathy Not Required</title>
		<link>http://jenami.wordpress.com/2012/09/13/telepathy-not-required/</link>
		<comments>http://jenami.wordpress.com/2012/09/13/telepathy-not-required/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2012 14:59:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>jenami</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amwriting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPchallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stephen king]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://jenami.wordpress.com/?p=131</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[(Author&#8217;s note: trigger warning for quotes from Stephen King&#8217;s It concerning sexual abuse.) Looking back on my childhood reading habits, I realize that I was a terrible “girl.” As a young lassie growing up in the 80s, I should have gone to Beverly Cleary Elementary, moved on to Judy Blume Middle School, and graduated with honors from [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=131&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>(Author&#8217;s note: trigger warning for quotes from Stephen King&#8217;s <em>It </em>concerning sexual abuse.)</p>
<p>Looking back on my childhood reading habits, I realize that I was a terrible “girl.” As a young lassie growing up in the 80s, I should have gone to Beverly Cleary Elementary, moved on to Judy Blume Middle School, and graduated with honors from Sweet Valley High. (Full disclosure: I did read these authors. I read just about everything I could get my hands on.) But none of them spoke to me, inspired me to write. When I grew up, I wanted to write like Stephen King.</p>
<p>Stephen King is not a purveyor of  fine “literature.” <a href="http://en.wikiquote.org/wiki/Talk:Stephen_King" target="_blank">He’ll tell you so himself</a>. Fancy prose and valuable life lessons are not the point (though there are some mini philosophy lessons woven into his tales if you’re paying attention.)</p>
<p>The reason I relate to his stories? Psychology. Inner voice. Often it’s more about what his characters <em>don’t</em> say than what they do. Thanks to italics, we’re privy to what they think: what’s motivating the girl chained to the bed, or the dad trying to save his son from the monsters that have overrun the supermarket. It’s why most Stephen King movies, honestly, kind of suck. Because what makes his books scary is about the insanity within.</p>
<p>I relate to this. When I can’t sleep at night, it’s the thoughts running through my head that keep me from dozing. During the daylight hours, it’s having to quell the impulse to do something utterly irrational that makes me wonder if I’m crazy. And it’s scary as hell.</p>
<p>An example, if you will indulge me.</p>
<p>Beverly Marsh, one of the characters in <em>It</em>, suffered sexual abuse at the hands of her father. He excuses his behavior by telling her he’s just “worried about her.” Bevvie’s mother is no fool &#8211; she knows something’s not quite right in her little domestic circle, but she’s not ready to confront it. In this excerpt, Beverly is also awakening to the fact that her father’s concern for her is more than just paternal love.</p>
<blockquote><p>“Bevvie, does he ever touch you?”</p>
<p>“What” Beverly looked at her mother, totally perplexed. God, her father touched her every <em>day</em>. “I don’t get what you -”</p>
<p>“Never mind,” Elfrida said shortly. “Don’t forget the trash. And if those windows are streaked, you won’t need your <em>father</em> to give you blue devil.”</p>
<p>“I won’t</p>
<p>(<em>does he ever touch you</em>)</p>
<p>forget.”</p>
<p>“And be in before dark.”</p>
<p>“I will.”</p>
<p><em>(does he)</em></p>
<p><em>(worry an awful lot)</em></p></blockquote>
<p><em>(It</em>, p. 403)</p>
<p>King could have written in agonizing detail about Beverly’s thoughts and motivations. He did not. Instead, we get to experience what she is thinking directly. In my opinion, it’s more visceral, more moving than a paragraph of prose. It just works.</p>
<p>And it’s influenced me. In my novel (don’t tell me that you’re a blogger and don’t have at least the inner workings of novel or potential novel on your hard drive, or you can add “liar” to your c.v.), my protagonist is a teacher who wakes up one day to find that overnight the world has changed. Early in the story, she’s not sure exactly how &#8211; but it’s beginning to dawn on her that she’s a little different than everyone else. Here’s a brief passage in which she realizes she’s not in charge of her classroom anymore:</p>
<blockquote><p>“Sit down, Mr. Frye.” He didn’t appear to hear her, but just continued moving toward her, the look in his eyes intense, and&#8230;something else&#8230; fear?</p>
<p>“Biggie, PLEASE return to your seat.” The buzzing got even louder, roaring, crashing, her head pounding in rhythm to the throbbing of the noise. Blackness started to creep into her peripheral vision. Hal’s dry, reasonable voice fled.</p>
<p><em>SIT DOWN DAMMIT OH GOD IT HURTS WHY WON’T HE LISTEN TO ME</em></p>
<p>The boy stopped as if frozen, and the buzzing cut off abruptly, switched off. That was when the laughter began.</p></blockquote>
<p>There was no other way for me to write how Julia was feeling. Maybe it&#8217;s because of the way I read &#8211; quickly, pulling the gist from large description filled paragraphs in my haste to get to what happens next. Maybe it&#8217;s a reflection of my nature, impatient, mercurial. Or maybe it&#8217;s just mental release. Whatever it is, I&#8217;m heartened to know that it works.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/131/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/131/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=131&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://jenami.wordpress.com/2012/09/13/telepathy-not-required/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>17</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/9ba1ab62a8c0950a020ef48dbcfd2e34?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=R" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jenami</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Post Challenge: Stealing from Mamet</title>
		<link>http://anecdotaltales.wordpress.com/2012/09/10/stealing-from-mament-weekly-writing-challenge/</link>
		<comments>http://anecdotaltales.wordpress.com/2012/09/10/stealing-from-mament-weekly-writing-challenge/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2012 16:54:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>anecdotaltales</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Every Story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creative]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dpchallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[heist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mamet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[postaday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robbers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://anecdotaltales.wordpress.com/?p=830</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In “Anecdotal Tales”, stories will be told. Some will be fun, some will not. Some will be great, some will be less so. Some stories are true, some are merely possible. This is one of them. Stealing from Mamet (Weekly Writing Challenge) (This week’s Weekly Writing Challenge was aping style.  And I’ve already tackled Roald [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=830&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In “Anecdotal Tales”, stories will be told. Some will be fun, some will not. Some will be great, some will be less so. Some stories are true, some are merely possible. This is one of them.</p>
<p><strong>Stealing from Mamet (Weekly Writing Challenge)</strong></p>
<p>(<em>This week’s <a href="http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2012/09/10/weekly-writing-challenge-stylish-imitation/">Weekly Writing Challenge</a> was aping style.  And I’ve already tackled <a href="http://anecdotaltales.wordpress.com/2012/07/13/the-astounding-meeting-of-albert-play-so/">Roald Dahl</a>, so I thought I’d take a crack at David Mamet.</em>)</p>
<p>“<em>It’s only words… unless they’re true.</em>” –David Mamet</p>
<p>“It was crap.”</p>
<p>“What?”</p>
<p>“Crap.”</p>
<p>“You said that.”</p>
<p>“I know.”</p>
<p>“You know?”</p>
<p>“I’m aware.”</p>
<p>“Why don’t you elucidate upon your point?”</p>
<p><a href="http://anecdotaltales.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/cops_n_robbers.png"><img class="alignright  wp-image-831" style="width:196px;height:181px;" title="cops_n_robbers" src="http://anecdotaltales.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/cops_n_robbers.png?w=300&h=282" alt="" width="300" height="282" /></a>“It’s the thing.”</p>
<p>“The thing.”</p>
<p>“The thing that was supposed to go down last week.”</p>
<p>“It was supposed to?  So it didn’t?”</p>
<p>“Well, it did.  But it was a mess.”</p>
<p>“A mess like a cat makes on the kitchen floor when it’s been neglected by some high school girl?”</p>
<p>“More like the splatter of goo when a watermelon is dropped from a falling airplane.”</p>
<p>“Ah.”</p>
<p>“Yeah.”</p>
<p>“That kind of mess.”</p>
<p>“Exactly.”</p>
<p>“What was the play?”</p>
<p>“Haven’t you heard it?”</p>
<p>“I might have.”</p>
<p>“Jackson couldn’t keep his mouth shut if it was stapled shut and then vacuumed up tight by those guys that freeze dry beef.  I thought he’d have spilled it all by now.”</p>
<p>“Not so much spilled as dribbled.”</p>
<p>“He would be a dribbler.  He drools all over himself.”</p>
<p>“But you trusted him.”</p>
<p>“Not really.”</p>
<p>“Enough to help with your scheme.”</p>
<p>“Only barely.  Mostly it was that I knew he couldn’t scheme a way to stab me in the back.”</p>
<p>“So what went wrong?”</p>
<p>“The escape.”</p>
<p>“The exit?”</p>
<p>“The getaway.”</p>
<p>“Jackson ruined it?”</p>
<p>“Like a batch of cookie dough left out for two days.”</p>
<p>“But what about the snatch itself?”</p>
<p>“The snatch worked.  Just only.”</p>
<p>“How so?  Who was your alarm guy?”</p>
<p>“Moron.”</p>
<p>“The alarm guy was a moron?</p>
<p>“The alarm guy’s name was moron, far as I was concerned.  He had moron brains and moron fingers.  Tells me he cut the wires.  Moron says that we’re all clear to go.  Somehow moron didn’t notice that the wires to the panel were wired with an alarm.”</p>
<p>“Dang.”</p>
<p>“Dang is right.  Dang is the sound the prison door makes as it slams shut and leaves us all looking at the vertical window dressings made of pure iron with drugged up failures for roommates.”</p>
<p>“That wasn’t what did you in?”</p>
<p>“This wasn’t my first time having a faulty screw on my sidecar.  I still had the controls, I just took over.  While moron was working to silence the alarms, I went to work.  I knew where the diamonds were.  I knew what I was after.  And lemme tell ya Saul, those diamonds loved me.  They shined, they glittered; they all jumped into my hands like little bugs looking for food.  The diamonds and I, we were all chummy.  I grabbed ‘em, they smiled, and I ran outta that room.”</p>
<p>“The alarm wasn’t going off the whole time?”</p>
<p>“Oh, it was.  I left moron there trying to figure it out while I ran out to Jackson’s escape car.”</p>
<p>“That’s where it took a wrong-turn?”</p>
<p>“That’s where it slammed into a blasted cement wall.  You know who Jackson’s girl is?”</p>
<p>“Not really.  He told me she works for the city.”</p>
<p>“Yeah she does.  As a cop.”</p>
<p>“No kidding?”</p>
<p>“Not even a little.  Jackson said she was sick of bringing home squat.  She’s gotta pay for her gun, her uniform, and take abuse from bums like Jackson.  Thing is, she likes the dangerous side.  Y’know, why spend your nights in a cramped apartment all by yourself when she can hang out with a certain crowd.  A crowd she knows where to find.  Jackson said this woman was all kinds of trouble and she liked to deal that way.”</p>
<p>“So she was in on it?”</p>
<p>“That’s how he told it.  Even arranged a nice getaway vehicle.”</p>
<p>“You mean?”</p>
<div id="attachment_832" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://anecdotaltales.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/800px-police_car_with_emergency_lights_on.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-832" title="800px-Police_car_with_emergency_lights_on" src="http://anecdotaltales.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/800px-police_car_with_emergency_lights_on.jpg?w=300&h=199" alt="" width="300" height="199" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Pic from <a href="http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Police_car_with_emergency_lights_on.jpg">Wikipedia</a>.</p></div>
<p>“You ever see police men stop a squad car when responding to a burglary?  You don’t, because they don’t.”</p>
<p>“That’s quite a set up.”</p>
<p>“It’s a real nice set up.  From the tax-funded gas in the tires to the detective-repellant flashing lights on top.  Plus being able to drive sixty in a twenty-five ain’t a bad speed for a getaway car.”</p>
<p>“So what’d she do, get lost?”</p>
<p>“Oh no, she knew exactly where she was going.  She had the route all memorized.”</p>
<p>“How’s that a bad thing?”</p>
<p>“When she’s driving a couple of cons in the back of a police car to her station, it’s a very bad thing.”</p>
<p>“Shoot.”</p>
<p>“Yeah.”</p>
<p>“She turned you guys in?  Went all two-faced?”</p>
<p>“Apparently she was only trouble for cops.  Her bosses told her put on one face.  When the heist was done, she should pull an about-face.  Jackson was just dumb enough to believe a guy like him could get a dame like her.”</p>
<p>“So she gave you guys a nice pair of handcuffs?”</p>
<p>“I wasn’t the one going out with her; I had no qualms escaping.  Let Jackson take care of his own relationship problems.  If he wants to give the gal a promotion as a parting gift, that’s his affair.  Me, I took off.”</p>
<p>“Outran her and those other cops?”</p>
<p>“Like you wouldn’t believe.  They were there, those big fancy stairs leading to the station were there, and lots of guns were there, so I decided that there wasn’t a place I wanted to be.  I may be good at running a scam, but I run from bullets even better.”</p>
<p>“So you got nuthin?”</p>
<p>“I never have nuthin’.”</p>
<p>“How’d you make off with the jewels?”</p>
<p>“Shoved ‘em in a little travel belt I carry with me.  If it’s good enough when abroad, it’s good enough to fool a broad.”</p>
<p>“The cop didn’t know you made off with the loot?”</p>
<p>“Nope.  She saw me toss a bag in the backseat and figured that was it.”</p>
<p>“What was in the bag?”</p>
<p>“Moron’s dinner.”</p>
<p>“How’s that?”</p>
<p>“The moron likes to snack while he works.  I took it from him because his fingers were gettin’ all slippery and he couldn’t hold his moron tools or manage the wires.  Morons don’t get to eat if they ain’t gonna do the job first.”</p>
<p>“Did the moron get picked up too?”</p>
<p>“Haven’t checked, haven’t heard.”</p>
<p>“But Jackson got arrested.  That’s how he tells it.”</p>
<p>“Yeah.  I’m pretty sure he’s not enjoying the girlfriend’s handcuff skills.  Probably thought it’d be fun when he first hooked up with her.”</p>
<p>“Maybe he’ll find a new girlfriend in there.”</p>
<p>“Nah, he’s too ugly.”</p>
<p>“You’re sittin’ pretty though.  Got all that swag, and no one to split the profits with.”</p>
<p>“This is true.”</p>
<p>“Quite the thing.”</p>
<p>“A close thing.  Still a thing I can live with.”</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/830/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/830/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=830&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://anecdotaltales.wordpress.com/2012/09/10/stealing-from-mament-weekly-writing-challenge/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>30</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/eaff4f8211ad4b038197a09903b75024?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F2.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=R" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">anecdotaltales</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://anecdotaltales.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/cops_n_robbers.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cops_n_robbers</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://anecdotaltales.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/800px-police_car_with_emergency_lights_on.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">800px-Police_car_with_emergency_lights_on</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Writing Well for Blogs</title>
		<link>http://om.co/2012/09/11/writing-well-for-blogs/</link>
		<comments>http://om.co/2012/09/11/writing-well-for-blogs/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2012 18:30:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Om Malik</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blogging Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wisdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging tips]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://om.wordpress.com/?p=6364</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The biggest fallacy of writing on the web is the idea that there is unlimited space, and as such limitation of space is of no consequence. That is not quite true. Instead of space, the true limitation of the Internet is attention. The prolonged throat clearing or using words that make you reach for a [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=6364&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The biggest fallacy of writing on the web is the idea that there is unlimited space, and as such limitation of space is of no consequence. That is not quite true. Instead of space, the true limitation of the Internet is attention. </p>
<p>The prolonged throat clearing or using words that make you reach for a thesaurus don&#8217;t account for the paucity of attention that commands an economy of words and synthesis of thought, both presented with the crispness of a freshly laundered linen shirt. </p>
<p>A friend recently shared an article about Apple and Samsung&#8217;s creative process. The differences are stark, but for me what stood out about Apple was its ability to throw out a lot of work &#8212; actually scratch that, throw out great work &#8212; to aim for final simplicity. It is not about cramming all the features into the device, instead it is the right features. </p>
<p>Writing too is similar. When you have a minute-and-a-half of someone&#8217;s attention, simply putting forward a persuasive argument, a clear and simple story or factual news is creativity. That ability to edit everything down to the very essence in an elegant, interesting and enjoyable way that delights (and informs) is what writing is all about. </p>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=6364&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://om.co/2012/09/11/writing-well-for-blogs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>103</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/89c6ff98059617751fcf312690965fa0?s=96&#38;d=identicon" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">om</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>