<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2013 21:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Six Years Ago, I Was Dead</title>
		<link>http://therunawaymama.com/2013/03/05/six-years-ago-i-was-dead/</link>
		<comments>http://therunawaymama.com/2013/03/05/six-years-ago-i-was-dead/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2013 14:25:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>The Runaway Mama</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[anxiety]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[conversations to remember]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[death]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[molar pregnancy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[September 11th]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shopping]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://therunawaymama.com/?p=3059</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The other day, Dylan said to me, “Six years ago I was dead.”  We were at the gas station.  I was pumping gas, and Dylan and Riley were hanging out the window. I replied, “No, you weren’t dead.  You just weren’t born yet.” Then he said, “I was dead when I was in your belly.” [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3059&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:justify;">The other day, Dylan said to me, “Six years ago I was dead.”  We were at the gas station.  I was pumping gas, and Dylan and Riley were hanging out the window.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">I replied, “No, you weren’t dead.  You just weren’t born yet.”</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Then he said, “I was dead when I was in your belly.”</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">I replied, “No, you weren’t.  You were growing inside of me.”</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Then he said, “Look, I’m dead,” and his body went limp.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Then Riley said, “Look, I’m dead, too,” and he went limp next to his brother.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">“Neither of you are dead,” I said.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Then Dylan said, “Two years ago I was dead and now I’m back.”</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">After that zinger, I changed the subject.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">The ease with which my kids talk about, think about, and imitate death astounds me.  Equally surprising is the ease with which I talk about it with them.  Dylan has, on many occasions, asked me about death (thankfully he’s only had to mourn a fish so far), and I’ve had some <a href="http://therunawaymama.com/2011/12/25/merry-christmas-what-happens-when-you-die/" target="_blank">pretty darn good answers</a> (if I do say so myself).  The problem is that underneath my super cool, no big deal this-is-what-happens-when-you-die exterior, I’m a hot, flaming mess.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">You see, death is one thing.  Dying is another.  I don’t even like it when my boys go to birthday parties without me.  How am I supposed to die?  How am I supposed to be gone?  Forever?  Holy crap.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">I <i>don’t</i> know what happens after we die.  (Maybe Dylan <i>was</i> dead before he was born.)  Even more unsettling is that, if I’m being totally honest, the theory I consider to be the most likely is that nothing happens, which doesn’t leave me much to hang a hat on.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">So, how exactly does one prepare for the end?  For nothingness?  And as long as I’m on the subject, what’s my purpose and why am I here?</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Wait.  I’m sorry.  Do you think I have answers to these questions?  Ha!  If I contemplate for just a few seconds the notion that the earth is a speck of dust in an infinite universe, my chest tightens and I can’t catch my breath.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">I don’t like being out of control, which is why general anesthesia is so hard for me and why life’s lemons propel me to clean out closets and organize cabinets (or at least go shopping for these projects at the Container Store).  Every aspect of death – from how to when to where to why – is a crapshoot, so I can’t embrace it any more than I can Dylan going to sleepaway camp or – gulp – driving a car.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">I’ve lost my fair share of loved ones.  Their lives <i>and</i> deaths have not only given purpose to mine, but also amplified theirs.  I cherish the memories I have of them, the perspective they impart, the lessons they pass on, and the endless wisdom they share, even in death.   Whether I know it or not, my children and loved ones will have the same experience after I’m gone, which is a beautiful proposition, but it’s the “whether or not I know it” part with which I struggle.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">I don’t believe in anything enough to surrender to it.  After <a href="http://therunawaymama.com/2012/09/10/hills-are-no-big-deal-and-life-is-sweet/" target="_blank">9/11</a>, I desperately wanted to believe in something to make sense of why I was alive and others were dead, and I felt something eerily similar after my <a href="http://therunawaymama.com/2012/02/29/were-okay/" target="_blank">molar pregnancy</a>.  In the end, though, these tragedies didn’t give me faith; rather they made me keenly aware of what I don’t believe.  I don’t believe in fate, I don’t believe in a plan, and I don’t believe things happen for a reason, all of which make dying a tricky proposition.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">I certainly hope that by the time I’m an old lady – assuming I have the great fortune of growing old – I’ll have adopted a belief in something other than nothing or become exhausted enough with life to accept what does or doesn’t happen next.  In the meantime, I’ll obsess over the wrinkles developing in my cleavage (true story) and how my hands are starting to look like my mom’s (sorry mom), and I’ll live my life how I want my children to live theirs and how I want their children to live theirs and how I want their children’s children to live theirs.   <i>Chest tightening.  Can’t catch breath.  </i>And when overwhelming thoughts of death, nothingness, infinity, and my children’s children’s children take hold, I’ll do what I did after Dylan said, “Six years ago I was dead.”  I’ll change the subject.  Or, I’ll go to the Container Store.  (Ahh.)</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">p.s. Rest in peace, Uncle David.  Whether you know it or not, your lessons are coming fast and hard.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><a href="http://therunawaymama.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/park2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-3085" alt="watersunpark" src="http://therunawaymama.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/park2.jpg?w=300&#038;h=224" width="300" height="224" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3059/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3059/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3059&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://therunawaymama.com/2013/03/05/six-years-ago-i-was-dead/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/e1ab870008afab660923d7b504f77a92?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">therunawaymama</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://therunawaymama.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/park2.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">watersunpark</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Was The Irish Famine Genocide?</title>
		<link>http://robertnielsen21.wordpress.com/2013/03/05/was-the-irish-famine-genocide/</link>
		<comments>http://robertnielsen21.wordpress.com/2013/03/05/was-the-irish-famine-genocide/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2013 10:05:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Robert Nielsen</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Britain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Famine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Genocide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Great Famine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ireland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Irish Famine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Irish History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Irish Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Famine Plot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tim Pat Coogan]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://robertnielsen21.wordpress.com/?p=1184</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Some people claim that the Great Famine was an act of genocide committed by the British Empire against the Irish people. This theory is most popular among Irish-Americans (who strangely enough are more nationalist than people from Ireland) and on the internet, though it has little if any credence in Ireland. It has been booted [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1184&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.irishhistorylinks.net/History_Links/IrishFamineGenocide.html" target="_blank"><span style="color:#0000ff;">Some</span> </a><a href="http://thepressnet.com/2012/12/06/proving-the-irish-famine-was-genocide-by-the-british/" target="_blank"><span style="color:#0000ff;">people</span> </a>claim that the Great Famine was an act of genocide committed by the British Empire against the Irish people. This theory is most popular among <a href="http://www.irishcentral.com/story/news/periscope/proving-the-irish-famine-was-genocide-by-the-british----tim-pat-coogan-moves-famine-history-unto-a-new-plane-181984471.html" target="_blank"><span style="color:#0000ff;">Irish-Americans</span></a> (who strangely enough are more nationalist than people from Ireland) and on the <a href="http://www.eirefirst.com/archive/unit_6.html" target="_blank"><span style="color:#0000ff;">internet</span></a>, though it has little if any credence in Ireland. It has been booted out of <a href="http://enochered.wordpress.com/2011/02/05/the-famine-that-never-was/" target="_blank"><span style="color:#0000ff;">conspiracy theory</span></a> land after one of the most respected Irish historians; Tim Pat Coogan supported the allegation in his <a href="http://itsapoliticalworld.wordpress.com/2012/12/20/tim-pat-coogans-the-famine-plot-englands-genocidal-role-a-review/" target="_blank"><span style="color:#0000ff;">new</span> </a>book, <i><a href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/12729810-the-famine-plot" target="_blank"><span style="color:#0000ff;">The Famine Plot</span></a>.<span id="more-1184"></span></i></p>
<div id="attachment_591" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://robertnielsen21.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/fam_ejectment.gif"><img class="size-full wp-image-591" alt="An eviction - loss of house and land resulted in emigration or death" src="http://robertnielsen21.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/fam_ejectment.gif?w=500&#038;h=346" width="500" height="346" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">An eviction &#8211; loss of house and land resulted in emigration or death</p></div>
<p>The Great Famine (or Great Hunger as it is also known) was the most cataclysmic event in Irish history. Sparked by the failure of the potato crop (due to blight) it led to roughly one million deaths and roughly another million people to emigrate. Considering the pre-famine population was 8 million it was proportionally one of the worst famines in modern times. The population of Ireland has never reached that level again, making us one of the few (if not only) countries to have the same population that we did in 1820. Culturally, the Famine has been compared to the Holocaust in that scared Irish people for generations. It was the largest factor in the destruction of the Irish language and culture. It began a process of mass emigration that would drain the country of all vitality for the next 150 years as the best and brightest left.</p>
<p>The argument is that this famine was not a natural disaster but rather deliberate plan by the British authorities to destroy the Irish people. The famous 19<sup>th</sup> century Irish revolutionary John Mitchell famously said “God sent the blight, but the English sent the Famine.” What he meant was that despite the failure of the potato crop there was still enough food in the country to feed the population. Instead the cruel and greedy English exported the food leaving the Irish to starve. Reference is made to disgusting bigotry and anti-Irish prejudice in Britain at the time, particularly of the infamous <i>Punch</i> cartoons which compared the Irish to apes. The allegation is that the British deliberatively neglected the starving Irish in order to destroy them and clear the land.</p>
<div id="attachment_1185" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 505px"><a href="http://robertnielsen21.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/588486e.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1185" alt="The Famine Plot has reignited the claim that the Famine was an act of genocide by the British" src="http://robertnielsen21.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/588486e.jpg?w=495&#038;h=371" width="495" height="371" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The Famine Plot has reignited the claim that the Famine was an act of genocide by the British</p></div>
<p>The most controversial issue in Anglo-Irish affairs is the allegation that food was exported during the Famine. This was first claimed by Irish nationalists as a reason to end British rule and the Famine certainly put an end to the idea that Ireland would be a part of the United Kingdom for good. However, it is extraordinarily difficult to prove the claim true or false, and to my knowledge no one has. Records of exports simply weren’t kept or have since been lost. It is certainly true that some food was exported, but there is no way of knowing how much or if it would have prevented the Famine. Food was also imported, though again, it is unknown where this outweighed the food that was exported. The starving Irish had little money so merchants naturally (in their mind) sold it aboard where they could get a better price. Had a ban on exports been put in place, lives would have been saved, but how many is unknown.</p>
<p>The most controversial issue in Anglo-Irish affairs is the allegation that food was exported during the Famine. This was first claimed by Irish nationalists as a reason to end British rule and the Famine certainly put an end to the idea that Ireland would be a part of the United Kingdom for good. However, it is extraordinarily difficult to prove the claim true or false, and to my knowledge no one has. Records of exports simply weren’t kept or have since been lost. It is certainly true that some food was exported, but there is no way of knowing how much or if it would have prevented the Famine. Food was also imported, though again, it is unknown where this outweighed the food that was exported. The starving Irish had little money so merchants naturally (in their mind) sold it aboard where they could get a better price. Had a ban on exports been put in place, lives would have been saved, but how many is unknown.</p>
<p>Let’s take a moment to reflect on what genocide actually means. According to the United Nations Genocide Convention:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Any of the following acts committed with<strong> intent to destroy</strong>, in whole or in part, a national, ethnical, racial or religious  group, as such: killing members of the group; causing serious bodily or mental harm to members of the group; deliberately inflicting on the group conditions of life, calculated to bring about its physical destruction in whole or in part; imposing measures intended to prevent births within the group; [and] forcibly transferring children of the group to another group.&#8221; (emphasis added)</p></blockquote>
<p><span style="line-height:1.7;">The crucial question in whether or not it is genocide comes down to intent. Did the English government intend to destroy the Irish people? The answer is no. They were heartlessly negligent, but neglect is not the same as murder. There was never any plan to wipe out the Irish nor any actions that could be viewed as such. The government didn’t directly kill anyone nor did they deliberatively destroy any food. In fact the relief aid, pathetic as it was, does damage the genocide argument. After all, why would the government set up soup kitchens if it wanted the Irish to die?</span></p>
<p>It was not murder or genocide that killed so many, but neglect. The government believed in laissez-faire economics or what would now be called free market fundamentalism (<a href="http://robertnielsen21.wordpress.com/2012/08/25/laissez-faire-and-the-irish-great-famine/" target="_blank"><span style="color:#0000ff;">I have a post on the issue here</span></a>). They believed that the government should not interfere with the market or it would only make the situation worse. They believed (like many today) that aid to the Irish would only make them lazy and dependent on handouts. They believed Ireland was over-populated and welcomed emigration to America. There was certainly a lot of racism, but I believe the larger motivator was aristocratic disgust for the poor. The government didn’t believe that poor people should be helped no matter how desperate their situation or what their nationality was. This, and not some genocidal master plan, was why so little was done during the Famine.</p>
<p><em>(It is worth pointing out that <a href="http://www.drb.ie/blog/writers-and-artists/2013/02/25/was-the-famine-a-genocide-" target="_blank"><span style="color:#0000ff;">historians</span> </a>have <a href="http://www.irishtimes.com/newspaper/weekend/2013/0119/1224329030440.html" target="_blank"><span style="color:#0000ff;">criticised</span> </a>Coogan&#8217;s book. Having read it, I must agree that it lacks thoroughness and fails to back up its claim that the Famine was genocide. Little evidence is given and there are surprisingly few sources used.)</em></p>
<p>The Famine was the greatest calamity in Irish history. People needlessly died due to cold-hearted indifference and the elevation of the market above the lives of people. Nowhere near enough aid was given as prejudice won out over compassion. Lassiez faire turned into Leave them to die. But this was a crime of neglect, not genocide. There never was intent to destroy the Irish. Had the government really wanted to exterminate the Irish, they would have done more than let natural disasters run their course. The claims by Coogan and others, while passionate, simply do not have enough evidence to support themselves.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1184/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1184/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1184&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://robertnielsen21.wordpress.com/2013/03/05/was-the-irish-famine-genocide/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/b2ddcd530fd110bdf82945e8c5bc5664?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">rapn21</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://robertnielsen21.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/fam_ejectment.gif" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">An eviction - loss of house and land resulted in emigration or death</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://robertnielsen21.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/588486e.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The Famine Plot has reignited the claim that the Famine was an act of genocide by the British</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Choosing a New “ism” to Dread</title>
		<link>http://librarianshipwreck.wordpress.com/2013/03/04/choosing-a-new-ism-to-dread/</link>
		<comments>http://librarianshipwreck.wordpress.com/2013/03/04/choosing-a-new-ism-to-dread/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2013 12:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>TheLuddbrarian</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[7 Questions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[In Response]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Luddism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Philosophy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Smartphones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social Networking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tablets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technophiles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Evgeny Morozov]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jean-Paul Sartre]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Neil Postman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Response]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://librarianshipwreck.wordpress.com/?p=185</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It’s always fun to have a new ism. You can ponder the issues raised by the ism, write a book warning an unaware public about this ism (that you may or may not have made up), shake your fist at those who are so infatuated with the ism that they become ists, and generally feel [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=185&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It’s always fun to have a new ism. You can ponder the issues raised by the ism, write a book warning an unaware public about this ism (that you may or may not have made up), shake your fist at those who are so infatuated with the ism that they become ists, and generally feel pleased that you have found the perfect name for a foe against which you are now the de-facto first line of defense.</p>
<p>Such is the case with “Technological Solutionism” as explained by Evgeny Morozov in his NY Times op-ed “<a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/03/03/opinion/sunday/the-perils-of-perfection.html?pagewanted=1&amp;_r=1&amp;ref=opinionhttp://" target="_blank">The Perils of Perfection</a>” (published on March 2, 2013). In fairness, “solutionism” may not have originated with Morozov, but his op-ed certainly serves to bring this threatening ism to a wider audience, and seeks to direct attention to his upcoming book <i>To Save Everything, Click Here: The Folly of Technological Solutionism </i>– which will surely seek to point out the, shall we say, “folly of technological solutionism.”</p>
<p>The solutionism that Morozov decries is the way in which new technologies (and new apps for new technologies) aim to provide “solutions” for many of the challenges that are integral parts of the human condition. Morozov discusses human foibles like forgetting and ethical inconsistency and mentions ways in which technology companies are seeking to “perfect” away these problems, he writes:</p>
<blockquote><p>“All these efforts to ease the torments of existence might sound like paradise to Silicon Valley. But for the rest of us, they will be hell. They are driven by a pervasive and dangerous ideology that I call “solutionism”: an intellectual pathology that recognizes problems based on just one criterion: whether they are “solvable” with a nice and clean technological solution at our disposal. Thus, forgetting and inconsistency become “problems” simply because we have the tools to get rid of them – and not because we’ve weighed all the philosophical pros and cons.”</p></blockquote>
<p>Many of the “solutions” that Morozov warns against are indeed quite worrisome, such as technological eyewear that might make it so that people no longer see homeless people, or apps that would “friend source” all of our decisions. Much of Morozov’s tone comes from a (very healthy) skepticism towards the motives of these “solutionists” as he notes that “the ideology of solutionism is thus essential to helping Silicon Valley maintain its image.” With that questionable“image” being one of Silicon Valley as providing products that make the world a better place.</p>
<p>While Morozov does not take the position that there are no problems that require solutions (which would be an absurd position) he does note that “not all problems are problems, and that those problems that do prove genuine might require long and protracted institutional responses, not just quick technological fixes produced at “hackathons” or viral videos to belatedly shame Ugandan warlords into submission.”</p>
<p>Though I find the term “solutionism” slightly silly, I do not disagree with Morozov’s op-ed, and likewise I find his conclusions largely correct. And the above quoted bit about “problems” is spot on in my opinion. Truth be told I found myself wondering if Morozov is a Neil Postman fan, I kept waiting for Morozov to reference Postman’s technology questions (I posted on those <a href="http://librarianshipwreck.wordpress.com/2013/02/14/neil-postmans-6-questions-1-from-me/" target="_blank">here</a>) or Postman’s book <a href="http://www.indiebound.org/book/9780679745402" target="_blank"><i>Technopoly</i></a>.</p>
<p>After all, in <i>Technopoly</i> Postman wrote:</p>
<blockquote><p>“the computer argues, to put it baldly, that the most serious problems confronting us at both personal and public levels require technical solutions through fast access to information otherwise unavailable,” (Postman, 119).</p></blockquote>
<p>Postman didn&#8217;t call that &#8220;technological solutionism,&#8221; but he could have.</p>
<p><i>Technopoly </i>was first published in 1993, so while Morozov may be making some excellent points, points that are worth being restated as time goes by, this “solutionism” is nothing new. The problem is that we have been living in a society guided by such technological logic for quite awhile now. It is not, therefore, so much a problem of “solutionism” as it is a problem of the world that solutionism has wrought.</p>
<p>Which leads me to a nitpicky point, which I nevertheless feel is the crux of my problem with Morozov’s op-ed (as well as a source of much of my trouble with many other similar pieces about technology). It has to do with choices and personal agency. In poking fun at Seesaw (an app that “friend sources” your decisions) Morozov goes on to write:</p>
<blockquote><p>“Jean-Paul Sartre, the existentialist philosopher who celebrated the anguish of decision as a hallmark of responsibility, has no place in Silicon Valley. Whatever their contribution to our maturity as human beings, decisions also bring out pain and, faced with a choice between maturity and pain-minimization, Silicon Valley has chosen the latter – perhaps as a result of yet another instant poll.”</p></blockquote>
<p>My problem with the above statement is that I feel that it actually demonstrates exactly where Sartre is located in Silicon Valley, and furthermore that it puts too much onus on Silicon Valley and not enough on those who make use of the rubbish produced by Silicon Valley (myself included). As Sartre wrote (in <a href="http://www.indiebound.org/book/9780300115468" target="_blank"><i>Existentialism is a Humanism</i></a>):</p>
<blockquote><p>“Choice is possible; what is impossible is not to choose. I can always choose, but I must also realize that, if I decide not to choose, that still constitutes a choice,” (Sartre, 44).</p></blockquote>
<p>Sartre is there, probably shaking his head at the choices being made, but reminding us that these are still choices.</p>
<p>It may be the case that the gadgets and apps from Silicon Valley may seek to diminish “the anguish of decision” but we must choose this. We are not forced to use Seesaw, we are not forced to use smart phones, or tablets, and we are not forced to purchase wearable technology (at least we aren’t forced to do these things yet).</p>
<p>Technological Solutionism only presents a problem insofar as we accept the same solutionist logic that drives Silicon Valley. And if Silicon Valley has discovered that there is tremendous profit to be made in giving people the opportunity to outsource their choices, this is not ultimately something that should surprise us. The companies that Morozov is writing about are capitalist enterprises, and there is money to be made, they’re simply acting logically based on the profit motive.</p>
<p>It seems to me as though Morozov is pulling a bait and switch here, the problem is not the technological solutions, the problem is our willingness to choose technological solutions. And it is too convenient and irresponsible to pass the blame for our own hesitance to make choices onto Silicon Valley. Morozov’s sentence should read [italics are my adjustment]:</p>
<blockquote><p>“Whatever their contribution to our maturity as human beings, decisions also bring out pain and, faced with a choice between maturity and pain-minimization, <i>we as consumers have</i> chosen the latter – <i>Silicon Valley</i> <i>has encouraged us to buy their tools for doing this easily – and we have bought them.</i>”</p></blockquote>
<p>Facebook isn’t the problem. The problem is that we choose to have Facebook accounts.</p>
<p>Or, as Sartre put it: “what man needs is to rediscover himself and to comprehend that nothing can save him from himself,” (Sartre, 53).</p>
<p>Including technology.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration:underline;">This post references two books:</span></p>
<p>Postman, Neil. <i>Technopoly: The Surrender of Culture to Technology</i>. (Vintage Books, 1993).</p>
<p>Sartre, Jean-Paul. <i>Existentialism is a Humanism</i>. (Yale University Press, 2007)</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/185/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/185/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=185&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://librarianshipwreck.wordpress.com/2013/03/04/choosing-a-new-ism-to-dread/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://librarianshipwreck.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/sartrescomputer.jpg?w=147" />
		<media:content url="http://librarianshipwreck.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/sartrescomputer.jpg?w=147" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">OLYMPUS DIGITAL CAMERA</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/2f1601fa0501b25a98833b040cf887b3?s=96&#38;d=retro&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">theluddbrarian</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Writer Forced (By Amazon) to Refund Past Customers</title>
		<link>http://selfpubauthors.com/2013/03/03/if-a-publisher-offers-you-a-contract-for-your-self-published-book-will-you-be-forced-by-amazon-to-refund-past-customers-who-bought-it/</link>
		<comments>http://selfpubauthors.com/2013/03/03/if-a-publisher-offers-you-a-contract-for-your-self-published-book-will-you-be-forced-by-amazon-to-refund-past-customers-who-bought-it/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 17:05:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ruth Ann Nordin</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://selfpubauthors.com/?p=5417</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The answer just might be yes because this is exactly what is happening to Jamie McGuire.  Jamie originally self-published her book Beautiful Disaster and the sales were so good that a publisher wanted the book.  So now the book is with a publisher.  Cool, right?  You&#8217;d think so except for this thorn that cropped up.  Amazon is sending [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=5417&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The answer just might be yes because this is exactly what is happening to Jamie McGuire.  Jamie originally self-published her book <em>Beautiful Disaster </em>and the sales were so good that a publisher wanted the book.  So now the book is with a publisher.  Cool, right?  You&#8217;d think so except for this thorn that cropped up.  Amazon is sending out mass emails to people who bought <em>Beautiful Disaster</em> when it was self-published.  Amazon is offering a full refund for the $3.99 price it was when it was self-published PLUS the difference in price that the publisher is charging ($7.99).  And Jamie McGuire is the one paying the bill.  So Jamie is now paying every customer who wants a refund about $8.  Amazon&#8217;s not paying it.  She&#8217;s made it clear the publisher isn&#8217;t behind this.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.jamiemcguire.com/amazon-beautiful-disaster-emails/">Here&#8217;s Jamie McGuire&#8217;s blog post where she tells us what is going on.</a></p>
<p><strong>My thoughts on this:</strong></p>
<p>So what are we looking out here?</p>
<p>Is it now a liability to accept a contract with a publisher who wants your self-published book?  Your book took off and became such a big hit that you got the attention of a publisher.  So you unpublish the self-published edition and sign a contract with the publisher who then gets your rights and republishes the book.  Everything should be roses from there, but I guess it might not be.  Because Amazon might send out mass emails to your previous customers and offer to refund the book + the difference in what the publisher is asking.</p>
<p>At what point do we say, &#8220;This is ridiculous?&#8221;  It&#8217;s ridiculous as soon as it happens.  Is this a sign of things to come?  Will there be some other reason we&#8217;ll end up owing past customers money on books they bought months or years ago?  Where does this end?  At what other job would the person be required to pay back customers for services or goods they received far back to who knows when?  Can you imagine if your boss came to you and started taking money out of your current paycheck because your boss decided to refund some customers?  Like I said, the whole thing is ridiculous.  And yet, it&#8217;s happening.  So not only is it ridiculous but it&#8217;s also a nightmare.</p>
<p><strong>What can we do to help?</strong></p>
<p>1. <strong>I think we should spread Jamie McGuire&#8217;s story as much as possible.</strong>  I ask that you Tweet, Facebook, Google + (or do whatever you can to inform other authors about this).  Here&#8217;s the direct link to her post: http://www.jamiemcguire.com/amazon-beautiful-disaster-emails/.</p>
<p><strong>2. If you bought <em>Beautiful Disaster</em> when it was self-published, please don&#8217;t ask for a refund.  </strong>She&#8217;s the one who pays the bill, not Amazon.  It&#8217;s not fair that they&#8217;re doing this.  I implore you to do what you can to lighten her burden.</p>
<h2>*If I have misunderstood this situation at all, please correct me.  I tried to get my facts straight before posting this.</h2>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://selfpubauthors.com/category/uncategorized/'>Uncategorized</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5417/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5417/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5417/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5417/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5417/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5417/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5417/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5417/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5417/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5417/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5417/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5417/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5417/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5417/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=5417&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://selfpubauthors.com/2013/03/03/if-a-publisher-offers-you-a-contract-for-your-self-published-book-will-you-be-forced-by-amazon-to-refund-past-customers-who-bought-it/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>86</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/3faec0ff8591c283d9c2922c991d12fa?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ruthannnordin</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Day in the Life of a Freelance Journalist&#8212;2013</title>
		<link>http://natethayer.wordpress.com/2013/03/04/a-day-in-the-life-of-a-freelance-journalist-2013/</link>
		<comments>http://natethayer.wordpress.com/2013/03/04/a-day-in-the-life-of-a-freelance-journalist-2013/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2013 22:57:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Nate Thayer</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Free Speech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Freelance Journalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Freelance Journalist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet Journalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet media ethics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Journalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Journalistic Ethics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nate Thayer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Journalism ethics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media Ethics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[North Korea]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://natethayer.wordpress.com/?p=989</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A Day in the Life of a Freelance Journalist&#8212;2013 Here is an exchange between the Global Editor of the Atlantic Magazine and myself this afternoon attempting to solicit my professional services for an article they sought to publish after reading my story &#8220;25 Years of Slam Dunk Diplomacy: Rodman trip comes after 25 years of [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=989&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>A Day in the Life of a Freelance Journalist&#8212;2013</strong></p>
<p><strong>Here is an exchange between the Global Editor of the Atlantic Magazine and myself this afternoon attempting to solicit my professional services for an article they sought to publish after reading my story &#8220;25 Years of Slam Dunk Diplomacy: <em>Rodman trip comes after 25 years of basketball diplomacy between U.S. and North Korea&#8221; </em>  here <a href="http://www.nknews.org/2013/03/slam-dunk-diplomacy/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow nofollow">http://www.nknews.org/2013/03/slam-dunk-diplomacy/</a></strong><em><strong> at NKNews.org<br />
</strong></em></p>
<p><strong>From the Atlantic Magazine:</strong></p>
<p>On Mar 4, 2013 3:27 PM, &#8220;olga khazan&#8221; &lt;<a href="mailto:okhazan@theatlantic.com" target="_blank">okhazan@theatlantic.com</a>&gt; wrote:</p>
<p>Hi there &#8212; I&#8217;m the global editor for the Atlantic, and I&#8217;m trying to reach Nate Thayer to see if he&#8217;d be interested in repurposing his recent basketball diplomacy post on our site.</p>
<p>Could someone connect me with him, please?</p>
<p>thanks,<br />
Olga Khazan<br />
<a href="mailto:okhazan@theatlantic.com" target="_blank">okhazan@theatlantic.com</a></p>
<p><strong> From the head of NK News, who originally published the piece this morning:</strong></p>
<p>Hi that piece is copy right to NK News, so please engage us mutually.<br />
Thanks, tad</p>
<p><strong>From the Atlantic:</strong></p>
<p>Sure. Thanks Nate and Tad&#8230;I was just wondering if you&#8217;d be interested in adapting a version of that for the Atlantic. Let me know if you&#8217;d be interested.</p>
<p>thanks,</p>
<p>Olga</p>
<p><strong>From me:</strong></p>
<p>Hi Olga:</p>
<p>Give me a shout at <a href="tel:443%20205%209162" target="_blank">443 205 9162</a> in D.C. and I&#8217;d be delighted to see whether we can work something out.</p>
<p>Best,</p>
<p>Nate Thayer</p>
<p><strong>From the Atlantic:</strong></p>
<p>Sure, I&#8217;ll call you in a few minutes.</p>
<p><strong>After a brief phone call where no specifics were really discussed, and she requested I email her:</strong></p>
<p>Hi Olga: What did you have in mind for length, storyline, deadline, and fees for the basketball  diplomacy piece. Or any other specifics. I think we can work something out, but I want to make sure I have the time to do it properly to meet your deadline, so give me a shout back when you have the earliest chance.</p>
<p>best,</p>
<p>Nate Thayer</p>
<p><strong>From the Atlantic:</strong></p>
<p>Thanks for responding. Maybe by the end of the week? 1,200 words? We unfortunately can&#8217;t pay you for it, but we do reach 13 million readers a month. I understand if that&#8217;s not a workable arrangement for you, I just wanted to see if you were interested.</p>
<p>Thanks so much again for your time. A great piece!</p>
<p><strong>From me:</strong></p>
<p>Thanks Olga:</p>
<p>I am a professional journalist who has made my living by writing for 25 years and am not in the habit of giving my services for free to for profit media outlets so they can make money by using my work and efforts by removing my ability to pay my bills and feed my children. I know several people who write for the Atlantic who of course get paid. I appreciate your interest, but, while I respect the Atlantic, and have several friends who write for it, I have bills to pay and cannot expect to do so by giving my work away for free to a for profit company so they can make money off of my efforts. 1200 words by the end of the week would be fine, and I can assure you it would be well received, but not for free. Frankly, I will refrain from being insulted and am perplexed how one can expect to try to retain quality professional services without compensating for them. Let me know if you have perhaps mispoken.</p>
<p>best,</p>
<p>Nate</p>
<p><strong>From the Atlantic:</strong></p>
<p>Hi Nate &#8212; I completely understand your position, but our rate even for original, reported stories is $100. I am out of freelance money right now, I enjoyed your post, and I thought you&#8217;d be willing to summarize it for posting for a wider audience without doing any additional legwork. Some journalists use our platform as a way to gain more exposure for whatever professional goals they might have, but that&#8217;s not right for everyone and it&#8217;s of course perfectly reasonable to decline.</p>
<p>Thank you and I&#8217;m sorry to have offended you.</p>
<p>Best,</p>
<p>Olga</p>
<p><strong>From me:</strong></p>
<p>Hi Olga: No offense taken and no worries. I am sure you are aware of the changing, deteriorating condition of our profession and the difficulty for serious journalists to make a living through their work resulting in the decline of the quality of news in general. Ironically, a few years back I was offered a staff job with the Atlantic to write 6 articles a year for a retainer of $125,000, with the right to publish elsewhere in addition. The then editor, Michael Kelly, was killed while we were both in Iraq, and we both, as it were, moved on to different places. I don&#8217;t have a problem with exposure but I do with paying my bills.</p>
<p>I am sure you can do what is the common practice these days and just have one of your interns rewrite the story as it was published elsewhere, but hopefully stating that is how the information was acquired. If you ever are interested in  a quality story on North Korea and wiling to pay for it, please do give me a shout. I do enjoy reading what you put out, although I remain befuddled as to how that particular business model would be sustainable to either journalism and ultimately the owners and stockholders of the Atlantic.</p>
<p>I understand your dilemma and it really is nothing personal, I assure you, and I wish you the best of luck.</p>
<p><strong>So now, for those of you remained unclear on the state of journalism in 2013, you no longer are&#8230;..</strong></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/989/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/989/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=989&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://natethayer.wordpress.com/2013/03/04/a-day-in-the-life-of-a-freelance-journalist-2013/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>293</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/db77b7db610bc42635b7eab8a09f5d38?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">natethayer</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Give Me a Reason to Race</title>
		<link>http://angryjedi.wordpress.com/2013/03/05/1141-give-me-a-reason-to-race/</link>
		<comments>http://angryjedi.wordpress.com/2013/03/05/1141-give-me-a-reason-to-race/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2013 00:45:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Pete Davison</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal and Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Video Games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[narrative]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oneaday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[racing games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[story]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://angryjedi.wordpress.com/?p=5117</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Why are there no racing games with stories? No, wait, scratch that, why are there no racing games with good stories? Or at the very least well-told stories? It is surely not a difficult thing to do. You take the basic game structure from Wing Commander and replace all the space combat with racing cars around tracks and/or city streets. Then you [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=5117&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://angryjedi.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/page_11.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5118" alt="Page_1" src="http://angryjedi.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/page_11.jpg?w=625&#038;h=312" width="625" height="312" /></a>Why are there no racing games with stories? No, wait, scratch that, why are there no<i> </i>racing games with <em>good </em>stories? Or at the very least <em>well-told </em>stories?</p>
<p>It is surely not a difficult thing to do. You take the basic game structure from <em>Wing Commander </em>and replace all the space combat with racing cars around tracks and/or city streets. Then you profit. Why has no-one done this?</p>
<p>The few racing games out there that do have storylines of sort are generally half-assed efforts where all the plot is delivered through badly-written text put into the game as an afterthought, or they simply don&#8217;t carry their potential through far enough.</p>
<p>I can think of a few recent examples<i>. </i><em>Motorstorm Apocalypse</em>, though I didn&#8217;t play it, reportedly had a plot of sorts, but it fell into the former category above. <em>Motorstorm Apocalypse</em>, lest you&#8217;re unfamiliar, had you racing around a city that was blowing up and falling to pieces &#8212; surely an ideal situation for a rudimentary Michael Bay-style plot with some characters and shouting. It wouldn&#8217;t have to be a complex plot, just something to break up the racing with some motivational scenes that gave it some meaning.</p>
<p><em>Split/Second </em>had a go, too, with its TV show-style presentation, incredible electro-orchestral cinematic soundtrack and episodic structure. It stopped short of actually giving the game&#8217;s antagonists, the &#8220;Elite Racers&#8221;, any degree of personality (or indeed faces), though it did end on a cliffhanger (which will now never be resolved &#8212; thanks a <em>lot</em>, Disney).</p>
<p>Recent <em>Need for Speed </em>games have taken a pop at it too, but tend to lose interest after the introductory sequences. The closest example I&#8217;ve seen to what I&#8217;m looking for is <em>Need for Speed The Run</em>, but apparently &#8212; again, I haven&#8217;t played it &#8212; neither the racing nor the plot are particularly up to much. (I must say, I am curious to try it, though, purely to see how close they get to what I&#8217;m imagining in my head.)</p>
<p>There&#8217;s also a Japanese <em>eroge </em>called <em>Moero Downhill Night Blaze </em>that reportedly combines a visual novel with racing action, but judging by its required system specifications, I&#8217;m not counting on it being an especially spectacular offering on the racing front. (I do intend to play it, though, as the whole series sounds like fun in story terms, even if the racing ends up sucking.)</p>
<p>And then there&#8217;s <em>Midnight Club Los Angeles</em>, which occasionally has <em>Grand Theft Auto-</em>style cutscenes, but not nearly enough to carry a coherent plot.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m honestly bewildered as to why no-one has tried this properly yet. We live in an age where video games are more &#8220;cinematic&#8221; than ever, and yet the racing game genre is still following the same old conventions it&#8217;s been using since the PlayStation 1 era &#8212; and possibly before. I would pay good money for a racing game with a good, well-written plot &#8212; given that I never, <em>ever </em>complete racing games (<em>Split/Second </em>is, to date, the only exception), an unfolding narrative with interesting characters and a degree of overblown drama would be just the incentive I need to up my game and see the experience through to its conclusion.</p>
<p>If I had any clue how to make such a game &#8212; or indeed access to a team to make such a game &#8212; I would do so in a heartbeat. Sadly, though, I have a sneaking suspicion my desire to see a game like this will remain nothing but a far-off dream.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5117/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5117/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=5117&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://angryjedi.wordpress.com/2013/03/05/1141-give-me-a-reason-to-race/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
		<georss:point>51.449716 -2.149409</georss:point>
		<geo:lat>51.449716</geo:lat>
		<geo:long>-2.149409</geo:long>
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/b378543b7b9d5c512e903c152ea92dc7?s=96&#38;d=retro&#38;r=X" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">angryjedi</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://angryjedi.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/page_11.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Page_1</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Make a Better Soup; Be a Better Person</title>
		<link>http://southernbelly.wordpress.com/2013/03/04/make-a-better-soup-be-a-better-person/</link>
		<comments>http://southernbelly.wordpress.com/2013/03/04/make-a-better-soup-be-a-better-person/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2013 00:24:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>southern belly</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[guy fieri]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[soup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stock]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://southernbelly.wordpress.com/?p=937</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I tell people I have soup anxiety. I may have touched on this before. It is ridiculous. You don&#8217;t have to tell me that. It&#8217;s mostly the lack of substance. The brothy-ness and the fear of being hungry while our dinner companions talk for three more hours about their 8th grade tirades and how &#8216;nerdy&#8217; [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=937&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I tell people I have soup anxiety.</p>
<p>I may have touched on this before. It is ridiculous. You don&#8217;t have to tell me that.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s mostly the lack of substance. The brothy-ness and the fear of being hungry while our dinner companions talk for three more hours about their 8th grade tirades and how &#8216;nerdy&#8217; we all used to be. (Trust me, if you&#8217;re playing soccer in 8th grade, you&#8217;re probably NOT a nerd &#8212; or at least in my view of the word.)</p>
<p>But I really like soup! I do, I do. I promise. It&#8217;s just not the first thing that comes to mind when I think, &#8220;Oh, dinner&#8230;&#8221;</p>
<p>Understanding soup basics was huge in my learning how to cook better. Usually in culinary school they start you at stocks, soups and sauces. Since I haven&#8217;t attended culinary school, nor will I ever, I did like most self-taught cooks do &#8212; I jumped in it.</p>
<p>I mean I got all up in that sauce talk.</p>
<p>I learned about stock and bones and fat.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m not gonna talk like I&#8217;m some pro at making soups. But I&#8217;ve made some good soups, just like you folks. (Or who at least claim to make the best <a href="http://southernbelly.wordpress.com/2012/03/07/chicken-soup/">chicken soup</a>.) I&#8217;ve also talked about making different stocks as well. If you&#8217;re interested, just hit up that search engine. The world is full of people who can tell you how to make soup. I&#8217;m not different. I just thought I could bring a little humor to the conversation.</p>
<p><a href="http://southernbelly.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/385964_10100300345921589_759160379_n.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-945" alt="385964_10100300345921589_759160379_n" src="http://southernbelly.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/385964_10100300345921589_759160379_n.jpg?w=403&#038;h=403" width="403" height="403" /></a></p>
<p>First of all, eat roast chickens. Why? For the bones!<br />
Wrap them up tight, and stick em&#8217; in your freezer. Collect about 4-5 carcasses before you want to make a big batch. Your ratio of bones to veggies is so much more than you probably think. Probably equal to the amount of all the veggies, you should have bones, plus more. If they are raw carcasses (sometimes you can buy them like that), roast them in the oven till nice and brown, and then cover them with COLD water. Add your carrots, onions and celery. Maybe a few peppercorns, bay leaf, thyme and garlic. Oh yes, garlic. So good for you and your brothy-obsessed bodily functions.</p>
<p>Do the same with beef bones, if you have em&#8217;. But you probably don&#8217;t.</p>
<p>If you really want to impress someone with a killer chicken soup, make a double stock. This is when you use an already existing chicken flavored broth and add more bones to it. I mean, decadence.</p>
<p>Huge flavor. That&#8217;s what you really want, right? For example, if you&#8217;re making a chicken soup, boil your raw chicken in some water. After your chicken is done, throw in your bones and vegetables and crank down on that stock. And then, strain all that stuff out and continue to reduce your liquid. It&#8217;ll keep getting better, and better.</p>
<p>This will elevate your soup to another level. And at the risk of sounding even a little close to Guy Fieri, I&#8217;m gonna back off. Because that dude is an introverts nightmare.</p>
<p>I love soup that has something extra in it. Meaning, things besides vegetables. For chicken soup, we generally add rice or else ten minutes later, I&#8217;m eyeing that bag of Pirate&#8217;s Booty white cheddar corn puffs that sit not so far away from my subconscious and comfy brown chair.</p>
<p>Add lentils! Add beans! Add greens! Throw some chopped up kale in there during the last 15 minutes or so of cooking.</p>
<p>Add proper salt. Every time you make bland soup, some one else decides to make a Harlem Shake video. And we don&#8217;t want any more.</p>
<p>If your soup turns out to be too rich, add a few dashes of vinegar &#8212; either sherry or red wine or something of the like. I usually always add a hit or two of some kind of vinegar. Adds nice balance. And folks, it&#8217;s all about balance.</p>
<p>Then there are the flavor and umami boosting agents. Tomato paste, fish and/or mushroom sauce, and worcestershire. At least those are the most common you might have back behind your Sriracha sauce that you might, but shouldn&#8217;t, put on everything.</p>
<p>But hey, who am I to judge you and your need to make everything taste spicy.</p>
<p>So there.</p>
<p>Just a few options.</p>
<p>Maybe it was helpful. I know it&#8217;s helped me.</p>
<p>And remember: soup du jour</p>
<p><em>it&#8217;s the soup of the day</em></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/937/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/937/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=937&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://southernbelly.wordpress.com/2013/03/04/make-a-better-soup-be-a-better-person/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>17</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/4275414716df9dd480b9f066ac08bcca?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">southernbelly</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://southernbelly.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/385964_10100300345921589_759160379_n.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">385964_10100300345921589_759160379_n</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pollen and the Science of Failed Plant Sex</title>
		<link>http://contemplativemammoth.wordpress.com/2013/03/04/pollen-and-the-science-of-failed-plant-sex/</link>
		<comments>http://contemplativemammoth.wordpress.com/2013/03/04/pollen-and-the-science-of-failed-plant-sex/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2013 21:37:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jacquelyn Gill</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Explainers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Research]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[climate change]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[megafauna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[methods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[paleoecology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pollen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[research]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://contemplativemammoth.wordpress.com/?p=743</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Plants have sex. While flowers, cones, and fruits&#8211; basically the vaginas and uteruses of the plant world&#8211; feature prominently in human cultures, much of the actual, er, act of plant sex is invisible to us. As northerners dig out from under record-breaking snowfalls and eye the ground for the first crocuses and robins, folks to the south [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=743&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_746" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 415px"><a href="http://contemplativemammoth.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/800px-cactus_flower_pollen.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-746 " alt="Tall, skinny anthers from a cactus plant, coated with pollen at the tips." src="http://contemplativemammoth.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/800px-cactus_flower_pollen.jpg?w=405&#038;h=270" width="405" height="270" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Pollen-coated anthers on a cactus flower. Image from Wikimedia Commons.</p></div>
<p>Plants have sex. While flowers, cones, and fruits&#8211; basically the vaginas and uteruses of the plant world&#8211; feature prominently in human cultures, much of the actual, er, <em>act</em> of plant sex is invisible to us. As northerners dig out from under record-breaking snowfalls and eye the ground for the first crocuses and robins, folks to the south are already beginning to experience a trademark of spring (and the male equivalent in the sex lives of plants): pollen season. The microscopic powder produced by seed-bearing plants are not sperm, per se, but are in fact microgametophytes, or sperm-producing cells. The word &#8220;microgametophyte&#8221; packs a handy definition for those up on their ancient Greek: &#8220;micro&#8221; means tiny, &#8220;gamete&#8221; is a combination of &#8220;husband&#8221; and &#8220;wife,&#8221; and &#8220;-phyte&#8221; refers to anything plant-related. Basically, pollen is a sperm delivery system. If a pollen grain &#8220;gets lucky,&#8221; that is, it meets the flowers or cones of its species, it germinates, creating little tubes to deliver the sperm to the ovule, which is the female gametophyte. That&#8217;s plant sex, in a nutshell.</p>
<p>But what about the pollen that doesn&#8217;t make it to ovules, the <em>losers </em>in the world of plant procreation? What happens to all the unsuccessful pollen?</p>
<p>To answer that, you have to start with a different question: why do plants make so much pollen in the first place? As anyone with seasonal allergies knows, pollen gets everywhere, forming a fine yellow powder that coats cars and windows, and is even visible on the surface of lakes in regions with lots of conifers (the champions of pollen productivity). You may be tempted to think that all that pollen is a big waste, but it&#8217;s actually part of a very successful evolutionary strategy. Genetic variation is a good thing (cue the theme song for <em>Deliverance</em>), and so plants have evolved strategies to share their genetic material with as wide a range of potential mates as possible. Tobler&#8217;s First Law of Geography states that things that are closer to you tend to be more related, and so it follows that getting your pollen to the flowers and cones of other, faraway plants is a smart strategy if genetic diversity is the goal. Plants disperse their pollen in one of three ways: wind, animals, or (for a few aquatic plants) water. Of these, wind is the best method for getting your pollen to faraway plants, as long as there are enough potential individuals to reach. So, this strategy is especially common for weedy species (like ragweed) and for trees in the temperate zone (the tropics tend to have many more specialized animal pollen dispersers). In fact, <em>Ephedra</em> pollen from the American southwest has been found in sediment cores as far away as Ireland! Because this is a post about failed plant sex, we&#8217;re going to stick with the wind-pollinated (&#8220;anemophilous,&#8221; or wind-loving) plants, which produce those copious amounts of pollen that are so ubiquitous&#8211;and irritating for those with allergies&#8211; in the flowering season.</p>
<div id="attachment_747" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 415px"><img class=" wp-image-747  " alt="Center-hill-lake-pollen-tn1" src="http://contemplativemammoth.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/center-hill-lake-pollen-tn1.jpg?w=405&#038;h=303" width="405" height="303" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Pollen floating on a lake, where wind and currents have pushed it close to shore. This pollen has failed at sex, but wins at science! Image from Wikimedia Commons.</p></div>
<p>To get back to the original question, much of the pollen that doesn&#8217;t make it to other plants ends up in lakes and bogs. While people have been admiring pollen grains under a microscope since the mid-17th century, the idea that all that excess pollen might be ecologically useful didn&#8217;t take hold until a 1916 talk by <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lennart_von_Post">Lennart von Post</a>. von Post was a peat scientist working for the Swedish Geological Survey, and is known as the Father of Palynology (the study of pollen, from the Greek for &#8220;the study of things sprinkled around&#8221;).  He was the first person to appreciate the fact that the changing amounts of different kinds of pollen preserved in the peats could essentially be read as an archive, telling the story of vegetation around the bog. He realized that fluctuations in the pollen of various plants could be interpreted as signals that a new species had migrated into the region, flourished when its climate was optimal, or died when it was not, to be replaced by other plants more suited to the local conditions at the time (you can see the first-ever published pollen diagram <a href="http://www.mpiwg-berlin.mpg.de/en/research/projects/DeptII_Nordlund_PeatBogs">here</a>).</p>
<p>How does this work, exactly? For starters, lakes and bogs act as giant collectors, accumulating debris from the organisms in and around the surrounding watershed. This material (pollen, plant parts, charcoal, insect bits, and other debris) settles to the mud at the bottom of the lake or the top of the bog, where the cold, oxygen-depleted water of the former or the acidic conditions of the latter preserve the material through time. As this accumulates, it forms layers in the mud, with the deepest being the oldest. In other words, every lake and bog you see on the landcsape is an archive of environmental change through time. The bigger the lake or bog, the broader the &#8220;source area&#8221; of the pollen, and the greater the scale of the landscape history you&#8217;re able to reconstruct with pollen. In areas where the ice sheets reached their maximum extent, those archives may go back more than twenty thousand years; in the rift lakes of Africa, the records can span hundreds of thousands of years of earth&#8217;s history (though these are considerably harder to acquire).</p>
<p>Fortunately, pollen is incredibly resilient stuff, protected by a coating of one of the most resistent biopolymers known in nature, sporopollenin. In fact, sporopollenin is so resilient that its chemical makeup is not entirely known; it&#8217;s so effective at resisting breakdown by other chemicals that the usual techniques fail to determine its composition. Corrosive acids and bases have little effect on sporopollenin, though strong oxidizers like bleach will destroy pollen in minutes. The sporopollenin coating is handy when it comes to protecting the pollen on its long-distance journey to other plants, but it also helps preserve the pollen in the sedimentary archive. Thousands, or even <em>millions</em> of years after its parent plant has died, pollen-rich cores of mud and peat&#8211; like an ice core&#8211; can be extracted by paleoecologists like me. You read that right&#8211; pollen is even being extracted from shales&#8211;hard rock&#8211; <a href="http://isites.harvard.edu/fs/docs/icb.topic881205.files/Isotopic%20evidence%20of%20C4%20grasses%20in%20southwestern%20Europe%20during%20the%20Early%20Oligocene%20-%20Middle%20Miocene">from the Miocene</a> (23 million to 5.3 million  years ago), and scientists are testing its isotopic make-up to understand the evolution of grasslands and different photosynthesis strategies in grasses.</p>
<div id="attachment_14" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 330px"><a href="http://contemplativemammoth.files.wordpress.com/2011/07/silver-lake-gyttja.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-14  " alt="A core segment from Silver Lake, Ohio; gytta (right) transitioning to silty clay (left)." src="http://contemplativemammoth.files.wordpress.com/2011/07/silver-lake-gyttja.jpg?w=320&#038;h=240" width="320" height="240" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">A core segment from Silver Lake, Ohio; older, silty clay associated with cooler and drier climates on the left transitions to organic-rich mud, right. This mud will have to be dissolved with a lengthy series of chemical digestions to extract the pollen contained within.  Photo by Jacquelyn Gill.</p></div>
<p>Once the mud is taken back to the lab, sporopollenin&#8217;s resiliency shines. The trick to isolating pollen grains from everything else in your mud core&#8211; smooshy bits of leaves and other organic parts, sand, wind-blown dust, clay, etc.&#8211; is a series of chemical &#8220;digestions&#8221; designed to dissolve everything except those little microgametophytes of interest. Pollen analysts subject the samples to a careful series of treatments, designed not only to break down the unwanted material, but also to remove organic acids and other components of the mud in order to prepare it for further treatments down the chain. Strong acids and bases are added in succession, dissolving organic matter, carbonates, and sands (!), leaving a small fraction of the original cube of mud each sample starts out as. If you&#8217;ve done everything right, you&#8217;ve got mostly pollen at the end. Dab a little of it on a microscope slide, magnify it to four hundred times its actual size, and you become a paleo-detective, reconstructing the landscape scene from the pollen clues left behind by long-dead plants. In fact, palynology has become a useful tool in forensics, since it can provide valuable information about where bodies may have been at particular times (<a href="http://www.iceman.it/en/when-oetzi-died">including Ötzi the Ice Man</a>).</p>
<p>Pollen grains are quite distinctive under a microscope, which is a big reason for their usefulness. Not all pollen can be identified to the species level, though. For some trees, like oaks, the morphology is too variable within species, too similar to other species, or both. Under a microscope, oak pollen has the gestsalt of &#8220;oak&#8221; but an analyst can&#8217;t tell the difference between, say, a red oak and a white oak. Still, the amount of information recorded in the pollen record is remarkable, particularly when it comes to global change research. Pollen analysis has been used to reveal how plants responded to <a href="http://museum.state.il.us/pub/grimm/Publications/2011%20Grimm%20Donovan%20&amp;%20Brown%20QSR.pdf">cycles of severe drought in the Great Plains</a>, has captured the <a href="http://www.sciencemag.org/content/294/5547/1700.full.pdf?sid=f2e64852-d01a-4e87-90ea-32f68dfa79ef">widespread deforestation</a> immediately following the KT impact event that killed the dinosaurs, shown the <a href="http://www.geog.ucsb.edu/~cstill/GEOG167/Geog167%20Winter%202009%20Webpage/Geography%20167%20Main%20Page_files/Colinvaux-glacial-era-Amazon-Science-1996.pdf">persistence of the Amazon rainforest</a> during the colder, drier climates of the last ice age, elucidated the pre-settlement vegetation on <a href="http://www.nature.com/nature/journal/v307/n5946/abs/307047a0.html">Easter Island</a>, linked the end of the Age of Pyramids in ancient Egypt to <a href="http://www.usgs.gov/newsroom/article.asp?ID=3359#.UTUD41q4GH8">widespread drought</a>,  and shown how climate change and the extinction of the ice age herbivores caused the formation of completely <a href="http://www.sciencemag.org/content/326/5956/1100.short">novel communities</a> of plants (my research).</p>
<div id="attachment_745" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 370px"><a href="http://contemplativemammoth.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/misc_pollen.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-745  " alt="A range of different pollen grains of various shapes and sizes-- some like footballs, others like spiky balls. Black and white photograph from a scanning electron microscope." src="http://contemplativemammoth.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/misc_pollen.jpg?w=360&#038;h=274" width="360" height="274" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Scanning electron microscope image of a range of pollen grains. Image from Wikimedia Commons.</p></div>
<p>When you put many of these &#8220;fossil&#8221; pollen records together, you can map out how trees have <a href="http://www.sciencemag.org/content/292/5517/673.full?sid=dfa4d4a1-1cfe-424b-b762-323885c2c9a0">shifted their ranges and abundances</a> in response to past climate change, which is one of the primary clues about how well species may be able to keep pace with climate change in the future. <a href="http://www.ncdc.noaa.gov/paleo/pollen/viewer/webviewer.html">Check out these cool animations</a> of mapped tree distributions over the last 21,000 years to get the idea. According to the rates observed in the North American pollen record, tree populations were able to spread from 100 to 1000 meters a year, which is an order of magnitude <em>faster</em> than predicted based on observed seed dispersal distances today. This disagreement is known as &#8220;<a href="http://www.jstor.org/stable/10.2307/1313224">Reid&#8217;s paradox</a>,&#8221; and is an active area of research. The discrepancies between modern observations and the pollen record may be due to the fact that it&#8217;s difficult to observe long-distance seed dispersal in the field, and so it may be more common than we think. Or, there may have been <a href="http://www.nicholas.duke.edu/people/faculty/clark/pages/publications_old/McLachlan.ecology.2005.pdf">&#8220;cryptic&#8221; populations</a>, or &#8220;refugia,&#8221; hanging out in suitable microhabitats close to the ice sheets, acting as a sort of advance scout force ahead of the migratory front. These populations may have been so small as to essentially be invisible in pollen records at larger scales, which is why they&#8217;ve been unappreciated in the past. Another hypothesis is that paleo-seeds may have had help from <a href="http://www.jstor.org/stable/2845211">birds</a> or extinct megaherbivores, which is bad news for plants looking to hitch a ride in today&#8217;s fragmented landscape. All of these hypotheses can be tested with a combination of pollen analysis and other tools, like phylogeography (the geography of genetics) and computer modeling.</p>
<p>Ecologists and conservationists are increasingly turning to the lessons from pollen &#8211;from failed plant sex&#8211; for a long-term perspective on issues like conservation baselines, ecosystem resiliency, disturbance, and climate change. With apologies to those who suffer from seasonal allergies, we have a lot to thank the plants of the past for. Without a reproductive strategy that essentially relies on prodigious ejaculation, we&#8217;d know a lot less about what North American forests looked like before Europeans cut them down, or what extinct <a href="http://www.plosone.org/article/info%3Adoi%2F10.1371%2Fjournal.pone.0040025">moas ate</a>. Not bad for for a bunch of failures.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/743/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/743/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=743&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://contemplativemammoth.wordpress.com/2013/03/04/pollen-and-the-science-of-failed-plant-sex/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>12</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://contemplativemammoth.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/800px-cactus_flower_pollen.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://contemplativemammoth.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/800px-cactus_flower_pollen.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">800px-Cactus_flower_pollen</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/db380bb5257c426750827993c4600886?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">paleoecologist</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://contemplativemammoth.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/800px-cactus_flower_pollen.jpg?w=750" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Tall, skinny anthers from a cactus plant, coated with pollen at the tips.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://contemplativemammoth.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/center-hill-lake-pollen-tn1.jpg?w=750" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Center-hill-lake-pollen-tn1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://contemplativemammoth.files.wordpress.com/2011/07/silver-lake-gyttja.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">A core segment from Silver Lake, Ohio; gytta (right) transitioning to silty clay (left).</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://contemplativemammoth.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/misc_pollen.jpg?w=750" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">A range of different pollen grains of various shapes and sizes-- some like footballs, others like spiky balls. Black and white photograph from a scanning electron microscope.</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Parenting Politics&#8230;In My House</title>
		<link>http://themamafesto.wordpress.com/2013/03/02/parenting-politics-in-my-house/</link>
		<comments>http://themamafesto.wordpress.com/2013/03/02/parenting-politics-in-my-house/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2013 18:37:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>The Mamafesto</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mommy Wars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marissa Mayer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PhD In Parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sheryl Sandberg]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://themamafesto.wordpress.com/?p=2379</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[With heavy media focus on Yahoo!&#8217;s Marissa Meyer and Facebook&#8217;s Sheryl Sandberg, it&#8217;s no wonder that the topic of motherhood is as newsworthy as ever. Yet, this focus seems very narrow, limiting the discussion solely to mothers and work, when in reality we could stand to broaden the conversation to both parents and how they manage [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2379&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With heavy media focus on Yahoo!&#8217;s Marissa Meyer and Facebook&#8217;s Sheryl Sandberg, it&#8217;s no wonder that the topic of motherhood is as newsworthy as ever. Yet, this focus seems very narrow, limiting the discussion solely to mothers and work, when in reality we could stand to <a href="http://www.thefrisky.com/2013-02-04/mommie-dearest-mom-vs-dad-who-takes-the-lead/" target="_blank">broaden the conversation to both parents and how they manage the work/life balance</a>. Motherhood doesn&#8217;t exist in a bubble, and if we want to discuss the challenges facing working mothers, it would behoove us to look at how entire families manage their balancing acts. I&#8217;m not the only one who&#8217;d like to see a shift in how we talk about these things.</p>
<p>My friend Annie from <a href="http://www.phdinparenting.com/" target="_blank">PhD In Parenting</a> -  who has written about <a href="http://www.phdinparenting.com/blog/2013/2/24/marissa-mayer-and-sheryl-sandberg-when-executive-women-keep.html" target="_blank">Meyer and Sandberg before</a> -  is eager for the focus on the work/life balance to move beyond a women&#8217;s issue to one that is a parenting issue. In hopes of widening the conversation, Annie has put out a call, asking for parents to write about their own households  and what the parenting split looks like within it. I asked Annie more about her motivation behind this call for stories:</p>
<blockquote><p>There are two things that prompted me. One is the continued focus on work/life balance as a women&#8217;s issue. I&#8217;d like to see it be a people&#8217;s issue. Why do women need to worry about whether their workplace has family friendly policies, while men (and men&#8217;s bosses) just assume they&#8217;ll keep on doing what they did in the same way they did before they had kids? The other reason is that I keep being told that equally shared parenting is impossible if the mom breastfeeds. I know that isn&#8217;t true (it wasn&#8217;t in our home) and I want to provide some examples for how you can breastfeed and still maintain equality.</p></blockquote>
<p>I&#8217;m all for adding more stories to the narrative of parenting, and said that I would be happy to share my own&#8230;</p>
<p>We need to start by going back in time, about ten years ago. I was teaching high school social studies and was the primary wage earner while MD was in school full time working on his doctorate. That&#8217;s the way our unit of two worked for four years. I paid the bills, and MD wracked them up (well, okay, he wracked up student loans, but we&#8217;re still paying for them, so&#8230;.). Then, just as he finished his program, we got pregnant. Literally, on the day he graduated, I woke up, peed on a stick and bam &#8211; we were having a baby!</p>
<p>We also decided to move out of state that summer. MD had a job waiting for him, and I was finishing up my Masters thesis, which I had began two years earlier (Yes. I simultaneously worked full time while working on my MA). At the time we moved, I was already 6 months pregnant, and couldn&#8217;t fathom starting over teaching at a new school only to leave 3 months in for maternity leave, so I opted to focus on my studies. MD, with his new job, was the primary wage earner now. Our roles were reversed but things went on as usual.</p>
<div id="attachment_2381" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://themamafesto.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/374_44891769987_5159_n.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-2381" alt="If by usual you mean hula hooping in the yard while pregnant. Then, yeah. The usual." src="http://themamafesto.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/374_44891769987_5159_n.jpg?w=300&#038;h=218" width="300" height="218" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">If by usual you mean hula hooping in the yard while pregnant. Then, yeah. The usual.</p></div>
<p>I firmly believe that it was because we had both been the sole wage earner at a point in our relationship that we were able to easily slide into an equitable parenting relationship. We had already done away with the traditional gender roles, so we didn&#8217;t fall into that trap either accidentally or willingly.</p>
<p>When the kiddo was born, I was in the editing phase of my thesis, and still focused on my academics. MD was working, but manage to scrap together a month off between paid family leave, paid vacation, and unpaid time off from work. I also firmly believe that MD having an entire month off from work helped solidify are more equitable parenting structure, and I can only imagine the benefits our family would have received had he been eligible for more. (Alas, in this country,<a href="http://themamafesto.wordpress.com/2012/05/15/distraction/" target="_blank"> we know that ain&#8217;t happening</a>).</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s a breakdown of parenting in the Norman Nathman household through the years:</p>
<p>-When the kiddo was a wee one, neither of us slept much, but we slept enough. We breastfed, which necessitated me being up with the kiddo at all hours of the night. However, in the beginning, he was also making a lot of wet and dirty diapers. Since I was the one up to feed him, MD was the one to deal with the diapers. I was able to fall asleep much faster/easier and MD is the master of going right back to deep sleep, so he was fine. Breaking up the nighttime parenting like that caused less resentment on either of our parts and assured that we both got some sleep &#8211; which is totally better than no sleep. I&#8217;ll be honest and say that co-sleeping was also key for us. I know it doesn&#8217;t work for everyone, but being able to roll over, get my son nursing and essentially fall back to sleep was huge in allowing me to feel like I wasn&#8217;t running on fumes 24/7.</p>
<div id="attachment_2383" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://themamafesto.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/374_44891809987_7197_n.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-2383" alt="Our family of 3(6 years ago!)" src="http://themamafesto.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/374_44891809987_7197_n.jpg?w=300&#038;h=218" width="300" height="218" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Our family of 3<br />(6 years ago!)</p></div>
<p>-While MD was home in that first month, pretty much everything else was equal &#8211; we shared meal prep, cleaning, baby stuff, etc&#8230; After he went to work, only a few things changed. I took on a bit more responsibility when it came to household chores, most notably laundry and grocery shopping, but everything else remained fairly equal.</p>
<p>- Babywearing was our savior. Seriously. I know not every baby enjoys being worn, but EZ was all about it. MD would pop the kiddo into a sling or mei tai and head off on a walk or go do the dishes. I could get things done while wearing him that I doubt I could have accomplished otherwise. Babywearing helped keep us sane well into the toddler years, and prevented many arguments about nap time &#8211; both between parents and parent &amp; child.</p>
<div id="attachment_2380" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://themamafesto.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/257_23668954987_2117_n.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-2380" alt="257_23668954987_2117_n" src="http://themamafesto.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/257_23668954987_2117_n.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">A father, his son, and an Ergo.</p></div>
<p>-Now, with the kiddo being 6 (SIX!) years old, and both of us working, it&#8217;s a little bit different but still pretty equal. We both have strange schedules &#8211; since I work primarily out of the home, my time is a bit more flexible, however MD only works 4 days a week, so he has some flexibility as well. We split school drop off/pick up between ourselves depending on who is home or who has appointments, etc&#8230; EZ has a few after school activities that also get split evenly depending on who is home (as in, if MD is off work, he&#8217;s the one taking the kiddo). Grocery shopping is an even split now as well, same goes for cooking. We each tackle cleaning in our own ways. I prefer to clean as I go, whereas MD enjoys doing one huge deep clean every 2 weeks or so. It balances the housework nicely and we manage to have a decently clean house (save for the hundreds of Lego pieces that still manage to fall under foot).</p>
<p>-When he&#8217;s home, MD is the go-to parent when it comes to bedtime, and I only do it when he&#8217;s working past 8 (which happens 2x/week). The kiddo is old enough to do bath time by himself and he also pitches in with some chores. I&#8217;m more than happy to have him see his father fold laundry, wash dishes, make dinner, as well as seeing me take out the trash, do minor fix-it type jobs around the house, etc&#8230;</p>
<p>-As I type this, on a Saturday morning, MD and EZ are downstairs playing Wii after having read books together. I&#8217;ve worked on our taxes and typed up this post. Our weekends are usually split between things we want to do and things we have to do &#8211; each of us gets some alone time if we want/need it.</p>
<p>I don&#8217;t think of our family as remarkable in any sense, but I do think we&#8217;re outside the norm when it comes to our parenting split. I don&#8217;t think of my husband as my son&#8217;s babysitter and he doesn&#8217;t see himself in that role either. Sure there are days when I take on the brunt of household chores or parenting responsibilities, but the pendulum swings both ways. Next weekend I&#8217;ll be gone for a couple of days, but I have no worries over what will happen while I&#8217;m away. MD doesn&#8217;t live up to or default to the &#8220;big oaf&#8221; daddy trap &#8211; it&#8217;s insulting to both of us. He&#8217;s a parent just as much as I am. Our parenting methods might differ, but our goals are the same.</p>
<p>I will say though, that we do get some pushback from those outside our family. MD&#8217;s place of work sometimes doesn&#8217;t understand why he tries to rearrange his schedule to be able to attend school or sports events. When he wanted to take a month off after the birth if EZ, he was met with a bit of resistance and a lot of bewilderment from his boss who couldn&#8217;t comprehend <em>why</em> MD would want to be home with his family. Also, because I work from home, there&#8217;s a lot of expectation from others that I take on <strong>all </strong>of the housework since &#8220;it&#8217;s just so convenient!&#8221; There is still definitely an overall attitude that women &#8211; by default &#8211; take on the majority of household chores, regardless of their work status. If a woman chooses to be a homemaker, then I can understand that thought, but otherwise? We all live here, we all pitch in, it&#8217;s as simple as that. We&#8217;re raising our son so that he understands the value of equality, both inside the home as well as outside of it.</p>
<p>However, I would be remiss if I didn&#8217;t mention our village that helps us out, made up of both biological family and chosen family. Our intentional community of friends and relatives help us out from carpooling, playmates, shared meals,<a href="http://themamafesto.wordpress.com/2011/10/21/self-care-it-takes-a-village/" target="_blank"> in times of need</a>, etc&#8230; That helps lighten the load for all of us. We are also fortunate to have work that, despite some unique challenges, affords us with a good degree of flexibility.</p>
<p>All that said &#8211; it&#8217;s far from perfect here. There are days where the house is littered with rumpled baskets of clean clothes because nobody feels like folding them. We probably eat take out more than we&#8217;d prefer simply because we get too lazy/busy to cook. I&#8217;m fairly certain my kitchen floors haven&#8217;t been washed in months (they look clean, so&#8230;) and there&#8217;s usually a dirty pot or dish in the sink. But, for the most part we&#8217;re happy, healthy, and usually have clean underwear, so I&#8217;d say we&#8217;re managing pretty well.</p>
<div id="attachment_2385" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 233px"><a href="http://themamafesto.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/264681_10150361102009988_3174731_n.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-2385" alt="Yeah, it can get messy, but we have fun. " src="http://themamafesto.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/264681_10150361102009988_3174731_n.jpg?w=223&#038;h=300" width="223" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Yeah, it can get messy, but we have fun.</p></div>
<p>What about you? What&#8217;s the situation like in your house? Are their two working parents? One parent working the other at home? Just one parent? What does the work/life balance look like in your home?</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2379/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2379/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2379&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://themamafesto.wordpress.com/2013/03/02/parenting-politics-in-my-house/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>66</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://themamafesto.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/374_44891809987_7197_n.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://themamafesto.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/374_44891809987_7197_n.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">374_44891809987_7197_n</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/de400df62df5592d2a3c647842246ff7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">themamafesto</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://themamafesto.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/374_44891769987_5159_n.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">If by usual you mean hula hooping in the yard while pregnant. Then, yeah. The usual.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://themamafesto.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/374_44891809987_7197_n.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Our family of 3(6 years ago!)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://themamafesto.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/257_23668954987_2117_n.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">257_23668954987_2117_n</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://themamafesto.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/264681_10150361102009988_3174731_n.jpg?w=223" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Yeah, it can get messy, but we have fun. </media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How To Buy A Wolf Shirt</title>
		<link>http://shutupdad.wordpress.com/2013/03/04/how-to-buy-a-wolf-shirt/</link>
		<comments>http://shutupdad.wordpress.com/2013/03/04/how-to-buy-a-wolf-shirt/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2013 14:55:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Andrew</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Random]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Andrew Maxwell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comedy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gray wolf]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Moon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shut up dad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[T-shirt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thrift store]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wolf pack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wolf shirt]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://shutupdad.wordpress.com/?p=2600</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As most of you know, purchasing a new wolf shirt can be an important and painstaking process.  As difficult or even more so than buying a new car, a new home, or adopting a child.  You want to find that perfect wolf shirt that will not only meet your functional needs, but your fashion needs [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2600&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As most of you know, purchasing a new wolf shirt can be an important and painstaking process.  As difficult or even more so than buying a new car, a new home, or adopting a child.  You want to find that perfect wolf shirt that will not only meet your functional needs, but your fashion needs as well.  From someone that understands that burden, I&#8217;ve done my best to narrow down the most essential factors to make your purchasing process go as smooth as possible.  I will use a shirt I recently bought as an example.</p>
<p><a href="http://shutupdad.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2628" alt="1" src="http://shutupdad.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/1.jpg?w=560&#038;h=746" width="560" height="746" /></a></p>
<p><strong>1.  Eye Placement</strong> &#8211; Always take notice of the placement of the wolf&#8217;s eyes.  Are they glowing?  Are they sad?  Are they wise?  There are many factors to consider, but those are some great starters.  You&#8217;ll notice on my shirt, the eyes are glowing and piercing. You can feel them in your very soul.  He is the alpha wolf.  And he knows you.  All of you.  Even the parts of you that you hide from the rest of the world.  But in addition to that omniscient gaze, notice the large size of the eyes.  Not to mention they are centrally located for optimal viewing pleasure.  Eye coverage to this degree is a rarity.  The previous owner of this shirt was a fool for donating it.  And so were the employees at the thrift store for selling this priceless article of clothing for so cheap.  But I wasn&#8217;t going to tell them that.</p>
<p><a href="http://shutupdad.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/3-e1362359201713.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2631" alt="3" src="http://shutupdad.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/3-e1362359201713.jpg?w=560&#038;h=420" width="560" height="420" /></a></p>
<p><b>2.  Pack Member Presence </b>-  I know this is a touchy subject with most wolf enthusiasts.  But in my opinion, the inclusion of the other pack members is non negotiable.  Yes a lone wolf is very &#8220;cool&#8221;, and that rustic solitude can definitely be a thing of great beauty.  But people who wear those shirts are simply lying to themselves and insulting our intelligence.  Wolves are pack animals.  They depend on it for survival.  If you see someone with one of these shirts, laugh at them and tell them &#8220;Nice fannypack, loser.&#8221; (They will definitely be wearing one). As you can see my shirt has the full pack located at the bottom.</p>
<p><a href="http://shutupdad.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/2-e1362359420808.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2634" alt="2" src="http://shutupdad.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/2-e1362359420808.jpg?w=560&#038;h=420" width="560" height="420" /></a></p>
<p><strong>3.  Moon Or Lack There Of -</strong> Ask me this same question tomorrow, and honestly my answer might be different.  I go back and forth on this.  Should there be a full moon in view somewhere on the shirt for it to be an authentic &#8220;wolf shirt&#8221;?  I mean yes, a big bright moon in the background can be hauntingly beautiful.  But is it necessary?  Are wolves not amazing in the daytime?  Does freshly killed prey taste any better bathed in moonlight?  See my point?  It&#8217;s a tough one.  My shirt does not have a moon on it, and that may bother some people.  But I could argue that the giant eye size would make up for it.</p>
<p><a href="http://shutupdad.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/whmn.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2619" alt="whmn" src="http://shutupdad.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/whmn.jpg?w=560&#038;h=420" width="560" height="420" /></a></p>
<p><b>4.  Dreamcatchers -</b>  Does a wolf shirt look better with a dreamcater on it?  Yes.  Everything looks better with dreamcatchers on them.  Am I disappointed that my shirt does not have one?  Of course I am.  But sitting around lamenting about it wouldn&#8217;t change anything.</p>
<p><a href="http://shutupdad.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/wdrct.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2615" alt="wdrct" src="http://shutupdad.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/wdrct.jpg?w=334&#038;h=447" width="334" height="447" /></a></p>
<p><b>5.  Additional Animals</b> &#8211; A common misconception is that having additional animals (i.e. eagles and bears) on a shirt, can actually enhance the shirt.  To me that is a moot point.  If you&#8217;re buying a wolf shirt, you need to focus on the above criteria.  If you need extra &#8220;animal power&#8221;, then you&#8217;re clearly not a wolf purist, and you&#8217;re reading the wrong blog.  Although eagles and bears are great, I&#8217;ve always been more of a wolf guy.  It&#8217;s not something I chose.  I was born that way.  So to me personally, I don&#8217;t think they belong on a wolf shirt.</p>
<p><a href="http://shutupdad.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/mbwsh.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2613" alt="mbwsh" src="http://shutupdad.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/mbwsh.jpg?w=290&#038;h=300" width="290" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>Well I hope this helped.  Buying those shirts will still be difficult, and I don&#8217;t envy you.  But at least you&#8217;ll have some fodder for the fire going in.  Oh and I almost forgot.  My shirt rating.  I give it four out of five fangs.  It almost reaches perfection, but misses slightly due to the lack of  dreamcatchers.  So I had to deduct a fang.  Happy hunting!</p>
<span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='420' height='315' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/Rk_sAHh9s08?version=3&#038;rel=0&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2600/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2600/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2600&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://shutupdad.wordpress.com/2013/03/04/how-to-buy-a-wolf-shirt/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>104</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/9cd235859fc9ee971196660fcdb32abd?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">shutupdad</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://shutupdad.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://shutupdad.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/3-e1362359201713.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">3</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://shutupdad.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/2-e1362359420808.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://shutupdad.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/whmn.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">whmn</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://shutupdad.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/wdrct.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">wdrct</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://shutupdad.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/mbwsh.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mbwsh</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
