<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 21:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Hello, World</title>
		<link>http://scorenotfound.com/2013/03/10/hello-world/</link>
		<comments>http://scorenotfound.com/2013/03/10/hello-world/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2013 01:47:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Matt</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Asura's Wrath]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God of War]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GTA3]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Halo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[indie games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Paul Graham]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Power Rangers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rise Against]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[South Park]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[video games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[violence]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://scorenotfound.com/?p=4</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I have murdered countless innocents, even children. Armies have bowed before me. I have sown genocide across worlds. Worst of all, my atrocities entertained me. Of course, my horrific acts all occurred in video games, so I am about as well-adjusted as any modern twentysomething. Like most my age, the massive sum of time spent [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I have murdered countless innocents, even children. Armies have bowed before me. I have sown genocide across worlds. Worst of all, my atrocities entertained me.</p>
<p>Of course, my horrific acts all occurred in video games, so I am about as well-adjusted as any modern twentysomething. Like most my age, the massive sum of time spent in digital worlds is a subject not to dwell upon.</p>
<p>Today is the first day of my final spring break. During elementary and high school, this would have been a week spent mostly in my pajamas with a Nintendo controller because girls were either A.) icky or later B.) not talking to me.</p>
<p>Yet sometime during my undergraduate education, video games stopped being so important to me. My murderous, virtual campaigns began to bore me.</p>
<p>Think of an ex-girlfriend that you no longer care about. Looking back, you get annoyed remembering all the times she didn&#8217;t laugh at your jokes or wasn&#8217;t sensitive about that common problem that happens to plenty of guys and is definitely not a big deal (, right?). Yet you still miss the way you felt around her.</p>
<p>My passion for video games has decreased, but I still want them to be an important part of my life. <em>Halo 4</em> was a good game, but I am nostalgic for <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=s24wxO94uzE" target="_blank">breaking out of Ivory Tower</a> in <em>Halo 2</em>. However, I can play <em>Halo 2</em> anytime, but I know it won&#8217;t be the same. In the words of Tim McIlrath, <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4MjLKjPc7q8" target="_blank">&#8220;Maybe we&#8217;ve outgrown all the things that we once loved.&#8221;</a></p>
<p>Why has my passion diminished? Most video games make the same mistakes:</p>
<p><strong>1. An oversaturation of violence</strong> When I was a kid, violence was cool. I wasn&#8217;t watching <em>Power Rangers</em> for the fascinating interpersonal dynamics; I watched to see the Rangers beat up on poorly costumed bad guys (and to see the Pink Ranger). My fondness for violence only increased when playing with guns and blood in <em>Quake</em>.</p>
<p>But there&#8217;s an upper limit to the violence after which you just become desensitized. After <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6sS6U7pTrvs" target="_blank">gouging out Poseidon&#8217;s eyes</a> or <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nJqbQ7wVZ58" target="_blank">destroying a planet-sized monster</a>, who cares about blowing soldiers&#8217; heads off.</p>
<p>Plus, a large part of my enjoyment was its taboo nature. At the time, you wanted to be the kid whose parents let him watch <em>South Park</em> at age 6, but looking back, playing <em>GTA3</em> was sweetened because you had to to convince your mom that the game wasn&#8217;t that violent and was very respectful towards women. This parental interest about what you watch and play ends sometime during your early teens when drugs and sex become more pressing concerns than arrangements of pixels.</p>
<p><strong>2. A disrespect of my time </strong>I am a pretty lazy guy. Most of my friends are either in grad school or working at engineering firms. As a fifth year philosophy student, my schedule is probably not as hectic as most other adults. So if I can&#8217;t find time to play most games, how the hell can anyone else?</p>
<p>RPGs are the worst offender. If I only have a few hours a week to play, an 80 hr experience can easily stretch over a few months. My interest in the plot simply cannot be sustained for that long.</p>
<p>This problem extends to more than just the sum of all playtime. Too many games require a large investment of time before I can even be sucked into a game and see some noticeable progress.</p>
<p>Too frequently, my use case with many RPGs is:<br />
1. Listen to some dialogue to find out I need The Item in another town.<br />
2. Start heading towards that town.<br />
3. Fight wolves.<br />
4. Fight more wolves.<br />
5. Realize I am heading in the wrong direction.<br />
6. Fight giant rat.<br />
7. Drop some loot from my full inventory.<br />
8. Fight wolves again.<br />
9. Arrive at town.<br />
10. Listen to more dialogue to discover that The Item is somewhere else.</p>
<p>15 minutes in, my dog will decide now is a perfect time to demand a walk. I&#8217;ll shut off the console, take Kiva out, realize I accomplished nothing, and put the game aside until tomorrow.</p>
<div id="attachment_5" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 655px"><a href="http://scorenotfound.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/2012-11-06-14-25-33.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-5" alt="2012-11-06 14.25.33" src="http://scorenotfound.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/2012-11-06-14-25-33.jpg?w=645&#038;h=483" width="645" height="483" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Kiva, the game time killer</p></div>
<p>As limited as mobile games like Temple Run are, at least I get a full experience playing them while on the toilet.</p>
<p><strong>3. A meaningless virtual adventure</strong> This is the most fundamental problem of the three. Too many games rely on the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Monomyth">monomyth</a>, where a young hero heads out on an adventure to save the world and improve themselves along the way. This trope brings grandiosity and a sense of importance to games, but once you reach adulthood in real life, the virtual monomyth becomes hollow.</p>
<p>When you are in high school, it is hard to realize that you&#8217;re imprisoned in a fake life. Paul Graham, partner at Y Combinator, <a href="http://www.paulgraham.com/hs.html" target="_blank">explains it best</a>, &#8220;Your teachers are always telling you to behave like adults. I wonder if they&#8217;d like it if you did. You may be loud and disorganized, but you&#8217;re very docile compared to adults&#8230;Imagine the reaction of an FBI agent or taxi driver or reporter to being told they had to ask permission to go the bathroom, and only one person could go at a time&#8230;If a bunch of actual adults suddenly found themselves trapped in high school, the first thing they&#8217;d do is form a union and renegotiate all the rules with the administration.&#8221; Your actions and responsibilities are limited until age 18.</p>
<p>But once you hit adulthood, you are free to go on any adventure. Although the idea may seem distant, improving the world is a real goal you can fight for. Bill Gates does it every day. But adventures can also be personal. Visit Spain. Write a novel. Get the girl.</p>
<p>Real adventures trump virtual ones. This holds true at both a macro and micro level. Why climb Death Mountain when you can climb Mount Kilimanjaro? Why grind mobs to increase my level when I can grind at the gym to lose weight? While your virtual goals are normally easier to achieve, your real ones have more importance.</p>
<p>For this reason, games aimed at adults cannot rely so heavily on a sense of adventure to impart meaning to the player. Of course, real world responsibilities hinder our chances to work on real goals, so video games can fill a need for accomplishment quite easily. But games need to expand beyond this.</p>
<p>Video games are interesting because anything can happen inside their world. Physics and logic are the programmer&#8217;s plaything. The goal of a game should be to provide a unique experience not possible in any other medium.</p>
<p>For this reason, I&#8217;ve been drawn to mostly indie games recently. So many of them let me do something new, something I have never experienced.</p>
<p>As such, I have created this site to talk about all the indie games I am playing. Upcoming posts will be in-depth discussions on a single game. You can call them reviews. You can call them criticism. You can call them rants or ramblings.</p>
<p>But two major guidelines will instruct my writing.</p>
<p><strong>1. No scores</strong>, hence the name of this site. If you can&#8217;t tell how much I like a game by only skimming the post, then that&#8217;s a problem with my writing ability. Dumbing down my thoughts to a single number is disrespectful to you.</p>
<p><strong>2. Don&#8217;t read my reviews before playing the game.</strong> Most game reviews help you decide whether to purchase the product. In that case, telling you about the details about the graphics and game mechanics makes sense.</p>
<p>But that does not interest me. I want to talk about the higher-level concepts a game addresses. The themes that stay with you are more important than when the FPS lags.</p>
<p>If you agree with my philosophy, stick around. My first substantive post will be coming soon.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://scorenotfound.com/2013/03/10/hello-world/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/329ed6f3125f9ff9011fd4e8401e06ec?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">matthewwrench</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://scorenotfound.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/2012-11-06-14-25-33.jpg?w=645" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2012-11-06 14.25.33</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Short Fiction, or Bust</title>
		<link>http://silverfysh.wordpress.com/2013/02/21/short-fiction-or-bust/</link>
		<comments>http://silverfysh.wordpress.com/2013/02/21/short-fiction-or-bust/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2013 15:54:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sasha</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Digressions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fiction - Short Stories]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://silverfysh.wordpress.com/?p=6903</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p align="justify">The thing is, children: The short story will persist, and our attitude toward it will endure. The novel may die, resurge, die again, get resurrected endlessly by its legion detractors and champions; the essay will toy with medium and length and preoccupation and ethical standards; the novella will always be the special little snowflake it’s grown comfortably into; poetry will keep curdling our blood with its beauty, its inscrutability, and its conceit that it’s the best form for thought-and-soul that ever will be. And the short story will be in a corner, nursing a warmed beer, brooding over an overflowing ashtray, trying so obviously and awkwardly not to meet anyone’s eye for fear that it might seem too needy—and it’ll be there in that complicated metaphor of a corner <em>forever</em>. And, kids—we’ll all just have to deal with it. <a href="http://wp.me/pEpEj-1Nl">[Continue reading.]</a></p><img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=6903&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://silverfysh.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/img-20130108-01050.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-6905" alt="IMG-20130108-01050" src="http://silverfysh.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/img-20130108-01050.jpg?w=640&#038;h=480" width="640" height="480" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="text-decoration:underline;"><strong>(Or: A manifesto on the short story as form, despite my own misgivings)</strong></span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">There’s been a lot of hullaballoo around the interwebz about the state of the short story. Curiously and gratifyingly, the two more famous ones—the <i>New York Times</i>’ <span style="text-decoration:underline;"><a title="Good Fit for Today’s Little Screens: Short Stories, by Leslie Kaufman | The New York Times" href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/02/16/books/a-good-fit-for-small-screens-short-stories-are-selling.html?_r=0" target="_blank">rah-rah for the form</a></span> that set my Twitter feed abuzz a week ago, and Laura Miller’s (recent) <span style="text-decoration:underline;"><a title="Sorry, the short story boom is bogus, by Laura Miller | Salon.com" href="http://www.salon.com/2013/02/21/sorry_the_short_story_boom_is_bogus/" target="_blank">scathingly condescending retort</a></span>—don’t offer anything about short fiction’s death, or non-death. Both are about the form’s popularity among a reading public that, by habit and/or taste, tends to overlook it. (I guess this is a good thing, as we hear enough of that kind of twaddle about the novel—undoubtedly, it seems, the short story’s much cooler older brother. It’s twaddle that, I think, just distracts us from actual reading.)</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">So, fine, yay, the short story’s not dead. Then again, it’s never been dead. It’s been neglected, it’s been laughed at, it’s been coddled and tolerated—most of the time it’s been passed over because, to quote many a reader, “Short stories are just not my thing.” Shrug. Occasionally, short fiction shines beyond its little conclave of devotees—and the outside world begrudgingly accepts these samples, as an established city might open its gates to seeming barbarians. And the acceptance is always <i>despite</i> the form: <i>Oh, look at this amazing piece of literature, and it’s short fiction!</i> Shrug, again.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">But the short story has never gone away—mostly because, I think, no one’s bothered to organically initiate a lynching—which means it can’t contrive the comeback that will knock our socks off. (The flashiness thing, just not its style, man.) And it will never go away, because what short stories are very good at is simply existing, despite not having the Life—the humanity-saving gravitas—assigned so capriciously to the Novel. The short story <i>is</i>, because most of the time people leave it be. And it’s fucking thrived anyway. (An argument, I’m the first to point out, could be made for literature in general.)</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Anyway. <a title="Nash Tysmans @ WordPress" href="http://toynbeeconvector.wordpress.com/" target="_blank"><span style="text-decoration:underline;">My friend Nash</span></a> and I were talking about this earlier today, in exasperated whispers in a crazy-and-crazier workplace, as I rather uncharacteristically offered my two cents about the ruckus on my schizophrenic Twitter account [samples: <span style="text-decoration:underline;"><a title="@sashasilverfysh - Sasha Martinez on Twitter" href="https://twitter.com/sashasilverfysh/status/304412021951184898" target="_blank">01</a></span>, <span style="text-decoration:underline;"><a title="@sashasilverfysh - Sasha Martinez on Twitter" href="https://twitter.com/sashasilverfysh/status/304440975093293057" target="_blank">02</a></span>, <span style="text-decoration:underline;"><a title="@sashasilverfysh - Sasha Martinez on Twitter" href="https://twitter.com/sashasilverfysh/status/304591622128156672" target="_blank">03</a></span>]. And in that pocket of sanity Nash and I made for ourselves, I articulated something that I suppose I’ve figured out for myself long ago—one I suppose I can only draw out now because I’m both so fucking <i>frustrated</i> and <i>fangirly-thrilled </i>that we’re even getting our panties in a bunch. Over the short story—of all things to mind! (The grizzled short story is blinking its eyes against the glare of the spotlight: “What the hell are you looking this way for?” it asks, whilst trying so very hard not to smooth down its cowlick.)</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Basically: What marks the short story as a form, as a tradition, is its inherent strangeness—which has translated, over the years, into sheer uncoolness. The short story has never, and will not likely ever, reach the exalted status of the Novel—which, at least, provokes those aforementioned nauseating conversations about its mortality. (Not to mention the badge of honor it’s shaped itself into being; why doesn’t anyone ever reach for <i>The Great [Country of Origin] Short Story</i>?]</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">We’ve looked toward the short story as the runt trying to play grown up, and halfheartedly at that—only at the insistence of the people who admire it, write it, or need to sell it. It’s just not cool, and it’s difficult to boot. The worse ones feel even more of an affront than bad novels—at least the latter have the grace to give us meat. The best ones sap us of response: All that emotion, all that effort, into so condensed and concentrated a package—<i>Why the hell didn’t I read a novel instead?</i></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">The short story is something that even seasoned readers are loathe to poke, as though they sense that the form has never figured itself out beyond the boundaries it has set for itself. Poor thing. And lord, don’t even get them started on the average-of-ten-headed-hydra that is the short story collection or anthology. Off the top of my head: There are good parts in novels/novellas—but in collections, there are bad stories, and there may be worse scenes in each. With collections, you have to consider unevenness—you have to consider discreteness and unity at the same time.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">(A side note: Undoubtedly, to my mind, the form bears a pathetic existence compared to the novella, whose length—whose matter-of-fact awkwardness—gives it a charm with which to pull people in. The novella has the sensibilities of the short story, but the expansiveness of the novel. Or the other way around. Or it’s a long short story, or a very slim novel. The novella, basically, tricks us by straddling two made-finite-by-tradition forms. It’s the best of both worlds. Well done, novella, four for you.)</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Yes, approaching the short story—reading it, writing it, seeing it in a bookstore and wondering if one should buy it—requires a specialized sensibility. One that takes into account length, degree of expansiveness or concentration, its standing amid a pre-packaged collective, and the fact that it’s not a novel. What the hell do you <i>do</i> with a short story anyway? (The answer, forevermore in Sasha Land: You deal with it.)</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">(Another question I pose to The Great Literary Tradition: Where we ever comfortable talking about a single short story as one would talk about a novel or a novella or a poem? I suppose marketing has a hand in this: Who sells individual short stories? Give the public some heft, by Jove. But how would the greater discourse be if we figure this out? Lots of blogs out there dissect short fiction piecemeal, and rightly so. Maybe we’re wrong to be critical of short stories lumped together. Maybe we should just hold them up against the light, one by one, with the care, energy, and attention they demand.)</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">And in that parenthetical, I suppose, is why I’m mad about short stories. I mean, what I love about the form is precisely what constrains it: Its specificity, and the care it insists on drawing from both the writer who writes it and the reader who reads it, thinking, “What the hell did I get myself into and why is it so satisfying?” It’s an intellectual and emotional challenge for both roles. It’s something to admire. It manages to sprawl through careful distillation and painstakingly administered revelations; it succeeds by navigating through the morass that is language, by employing the narrative-as-ethics of the essay, by caring for the character as deeply (and sometimes, in a better, more clever way) as the novel which has built itself up by its raison d’être of championing humanity despite the occasional foibles that can make humanity so sucky.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">And its range, its hair-tearing range, despite the little-engine-that-could character that’s been pushed toward it (one that I know I’m doing, too, in this post that’s gotten way out of hand)! There are tricksters like Lydia Davis, who type up an elaborate sentence as a title and an add-on phrase as the text body itself. There are the gruff macho men that startle you with tenderness, as with Raymond Carver and Richard Yates. There are the doyennes, whom one can imagine to calmly sip tea at their porches as they excruciatingly yet gracefully cram whole lifetimes into twenty-pagers—like Alice Munro, who else? There are the girls with the chip on their shoulders, like Lorrie Moore; there are those who dissent either through twee-poignancy or false bravado, like Miranda July or Joan Silber or Simon Van Booy (this seems to be in vogue these days). There are the short story writers no one reads—like Harold Brodkey or Wilfrido Nolledo. And then there’s Chekhov. (Hah.)</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">And yet, what I can hate about the form is precisely that specialized sensibility it will always demand from me. I am, for example, a reader who prefers to polish off books in one sitting, a reader who wants to be devoured by sweeping tales or the emotional grip of volume and heft. And I am an impatient reader—and contrary to how the short story’s been touted for our ilk: Having me sit down with something, only to know that it will end too soon, sends alarms of deep and abiding frustration within me, too.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Yeah, I’m a confused duck. That I’m reading short stories at all—that I can pledge by them—is probably enough of an indication. But fuck me, right, short fiction? (Short fiction grumbles in response; it’s getting grumpy. It does that, in my head, especially when it sees that I’ve tangled myself in circular arguments. Right now, it’s barking at me to <i>git</i> and get off its goddamned property.)</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">The thing is, children: The short story will persist, and our attitude toward it will endure. The novel may die, resurge, die again, get resurrected endlessly by its legion detractors and champions; the essay will toy with medium and length and preoccupation and ethical standards; the novella will always be the special little snowflake it’s grown comfortably into; poetry will keep curdling our blood with its beauty, its inscrutability, and its conceit that it’s the best form for thought-and-soul that ever will be. And the short story will be in a corner, nursing a warmed beer, brooding over an overflowing ashtray, trying so obviously and awkwardly not to meet anyone’s eye for fear that it might seem too needy—and it’ll be there in that complicated metaphor of a corner <i>forever</i>. And, kids—we’ll all just have to deal with it.</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://silverfysh.wordpress.com/category/digressions/'>Digressions</a> Tagged: <a href='http://silverfysh.wordpress.com/tag/fiction-short-stories/'>Fiction - Short Stories</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/6903/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/6903/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=6903&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://silverfysh.wordpress.com/2013/02/21/short-fiction-or-bust/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>12</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://silverfysh.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/img-20130108-01050.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://silverfysh.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/img-20130108-01050.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG-20130108-01050</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/fd1aef8ce3bbd5166f52cd1e805e291a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Sasha</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://silverfysh.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/img-20130108-01050.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG-20130108-01050</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Narrative Opportunity</title>
		<link>http://rpseawright.wordpress.com/2013/03/10/the-narrative-opportunity/</link>
		<comments>http://rpseawright.wordpress.com/2013/03/10/the-narrative-opportunity/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2013 15:45:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bob Seawright</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Leading Off]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Communication]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Don Draper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Featured]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jon Hamm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mad Men]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Matthew Weiner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Narrative]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Narrative Fallacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nassim Taleb]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ronald Reagan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stories]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rpseawright.wordpress.com/?p=4346</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[We can be swayed by stories, but inspired too.<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4346&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Regular readers of this site know that I reference and write about what <a href="http://fooledbyrandomness.com/">Nassim Taleb</a> calls <em>the <a href="http://wiki.lesswrong.com/wiki/Narrative_fallacy">narrative fallacy</a></em> often.  It is our tendency to look backward and create a pattern to fit events and to construct a story that explains what happened along with what caused it to happen.  We all like to think that our decision-making is a rationally based process &#8212; that we examine the evidence and only after careful evaluation come to a reasoned conclusion as to what the evidence suggests or shows.</p>
<p>But we don&#8217;t.</p>
<p>Instead, we spend our time running around looking for stuff that we can exploit to support our pre-conceived notions.  We like to think we&#8217;re judges of a sort, carefully weighing the alternatives and possibilities before reaching a just and true verdict.  Instead, we&#8217;re much more like lawyers, looking for anything that we think might help to make our case and looking for ways to suppress that which hurts it.  As <a href="http://fivethirtyeight.blogs.nytimes.com/author/nate-silver/">Nate Silver</a> put it in a recent and <a href="http://www.pbs.org/idealab/2013/03/nate-silver-on-baseball-online-poker-politics-and-ny-times064.html">interesting interview</a>, &#8220;our brains are wired to build stories around essentially random data.&#8221;</p>
<p>That tendency is driven in large part, as Silver notes, by the way we are built.  We <a href="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=1571358">inherently prefer</a> words to numbers and narrative to data — often to the immense <a href="http://rpseawright.wordpress.com/2011/10/13/beguiled-by-narrative/">detriment of our understanding</a>.  Indeed, <a href="http://www.psychologytoday.com/blog/grand-rounds/201202/madmen-the-carousel-and-the-pang-nostalgia-in-the-walking-dead">we know</a> from neurobiology that when presented with evidence that our worldviews are patently false, we tend to refuse to engage our prefrontal cortex, the very part of the brain we need most to make sense of the new.  It should be obvious that this aspect of our make-up is problematic and potentially damaging to every decision we make, investing included.</p>
<p>Keeping one’s analysis and interpretation of the data reasonably objective – since analysis and interpretation are required for data to be actionable – is thus really, really hard even in the best of circumstances.  It is a key reason why I regularly maintain that while <em>information is cheap, meaning is expensive</em>.  Moreover, our inherent preferences  and desires mean that a good story can be really dangerous in that it can be used to sell almost anything, often with surprising ease.  That&#8217;s <em>the narrative risk.</em></p>
<p>Watch <a href="http://www.amctv.com/shows/mad-men">Mad Men</a>&#8216;s <a href="http://www.amctv.com/shows/mad-men/cast/don-draper">Don Draper</a> (<a href="http://www.amctv.com/shows/mad-men/cast/don-draper/jon-hamm">Jon Hamm</a>) use the power of words to sell a couple of Kodak executives on himself and his firm while turning what they perceive to be a technological achievement (the &#8220;wheel&#8221;) into something much richer and more compelling &#8212; the &#8220;carousel.&#8221;</p>
<span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='640' height='390' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/suRDUFpsHus?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Draper uses his depiction of the carousel not to tout its newness, but rather to conjure memories that allow us to circle back towards home, security and presumed truth, despite the chaos and uncertainty that seem to overwhelm us. We may even tear up in the process.  Notice how psychiatrist Steven Schlozman of the Harvard Medical School <a href="http://www.psychologytoday.com/blog/grand-rounds/201202/madmen-the-carousel-and-the-pang-nostalgia-in-the-walking-dead">describes it</a><strong>. </strong></p>
<blockquote><p><strong>&#8220;</strong>We remember what we remember not just for the facts but also for the feelings that go along with the facts, and the ability to balance feeling with fact is what keeps us out of trouble.  The converse, however, is also true. The inability to balance feelings with facts allows all hell to break loose.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>As I <a href="http://rpseawright.wordpress.com/2013/03/07/invest-like-buffett/">noted recently</a> in another context, this idea is consistent with <a href="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=1569106">research</a> showing that in order to help people understand the implications of various findings and conclusions &#8212; to persuade &#8211; we often need to do more than lay out a data-driven, logical argument.  Instead (or, better yet, in addition), we need to provide a sort of emotional charge.  Thus, for example, instead of simply showing people the numerical consequences of a certain action, we need to find a way to load the results with aversive emotion. &#8220;Load&#8221; is obviously a &#8212; well &#8212; <em>loaded</em> word.  But it was chosen to emphasize the magnitude of risk.</p>
<p>In the context Draper created, the carousel seems to sell itself.  I have watched this scene many times, and I always feel (more than think) that the &#8220;wheel&#8221; is not worthy of the talent that sells it.  Moreover, the line between being sold and being inspired is blurred to the point of disappearance.</p>
<p>Thus, like every superhero <a href="http://malavenda.wordpress.com/2012/07/03/superheroes-lessons-about-power-and-leadership/">forced to decide</a> whether to use his powers for good or evil and making the right choice, we needn&#8217;t use narrative trivially, much less to deceive or obfuscate.  Instead, we can use words to transcend the mundane &#8211; not just to make important points, but to make them stick.  Words can be motivational.  They can be great and can inspire greatness.</p>
<span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='640' height='390' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/nFcbpGK9_aw?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Narratives are crucial to how we make sense of reality.  They help us to explain, understand and interpret the world around us.  They also give us a frame of reference we can use to remember the concepts we take them to represent. As <a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2013/03/from-moneyball-to-money-bombs-what-sports-analytics-can-teach-political-nerds/273824/">reported recently</a> in <em>The Atlantic</em> in the context of sports and political analytics, &#8220;[d]ata is an incredibly valuable resource for organizations, but you must be able to communicate its value to stakeholders making decisions.&#8221;  We all recognize that value judgments are often powerfully and dangerously emotional.</p>
<p>As we have seen, great communicators (like Don Draper or, more accurately, <a href="http://www.amctv.com/shows/mad-men/crew/matthew-weiner">Matthew Weiner</a>) evoke images and emotions through the use of compelling narrative that can be used effectively to incite a strong response.  During the 1984 election campaign, for example, <a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/about/presidents/ronaldreagan/">Ronald Reagan</a> talked about our future in outer space and the importance of our going there while his soon-to-be-crushed opponent, Walter Mondale, kept talking about how much doing so was going to cost.  It isn&#8217;t hard to guess who captured people&#8217;s imagination.  Better still, watch <a href="http://www.reaganfoundation.org/pdf/RemarksUS_France_Ceremony_Normandy_Invasion060684.pdf">this address</a> and feel the power of Reagan&#8217;s communication skills.  I dare you to try not to be stirred.</p>
<span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='640' height='390' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/ZgDZdFQY3iM?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>If we are best to commemorate those who began the rescue of Europe, &#8221;the boys of Pointe du Hoc,&#8221; like Reagan we won&#8217;t focus upon a factual recitation of their amazing accomplishments.  Instead, we will inspire images that seem to put things in proper perspective.  In the words of the poet <a href="http://www.poetryfoundation.org/bio/stephen-spender">Stephen Spender</a>, they are men who in their “lives fought for life and left the vivid air signed with honor.”</p>
<p>Good investing isn&#8217;t possible without good math.  But piercing analysis isn&#8217;t any good if it isn&#8217;t implemented.  Stories and words, properly used, can get things done.  If you have a message to get across to inspire people to take action, don&#8217;t just stick to the data.  Tell good stories, evoke powerful images and conjure vivid memories.  That&#8217;s <em>the narrative opportunity</em>.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4346/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4346/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4346&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://rpseawright.wordpress.com/2013/03/10/the-narrative-opportunity/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://rpseawright.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/the-carousel.png?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://rpseawright.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/the-carousel.png?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The Carousel</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/2f18e42d91a8e23ab0c7d83b4ad19c16?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">rpseawright</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Weeds and Debris</title>
		<link>http://forthearchives.wordpress.com/2013/03/06/weeds-and-debris/</link>
		<comments>http://forthearchives.wordpress.com/2013/03/06/weeds-and-debris/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 02:11:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jessica Dofflemyer</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Daily Chronicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Time & Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Earth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://forthearchives.wordpress.com/?p=5339</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s understood that invasive species are bad for our island&#8217;s flora, and the debris afloat at sea is at epidemic proportions. Weeds and trash are no one&#8217;s friend. But what if I were an alien from another planet? What if I had no concept of friend or foe, good or bad? What if on my [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=5339&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s understood that invasive species are bad for our island&#8217;s flora, and the debris afloat at sea is at epidemic proportions. Weeds and trash are no one&#8217;s friend.</p>
<p>But what if I were an alien from another planet? What if I had no concept of friend or foe, good or bad? What if on my morning beach walk there was no story attached to any thing I encountered, not even a name.</p>
<p>With my E.T.-version of a camera, perhaps I&#8217;d pause to take photos of things that earthlings may dismiss.</p>
<p>Weeds and debris, framed within the neutral ground of simple curiosity,</p>
<p>And as I like to play with metaphors, I invite you to consider the overgrowth and refuse within ourselves. We all have a shadow side. What&#8217;s our story about it? Is it possible for us to view our &#8216;darkness&#8217; with an unbiased eye?</p>
<p>If so, what new perspectives might emerge by simply looking?</p>
<p><a href="http://forthearchives.net/"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5343" alt="2013-03-06purple_weed_big" src="http://forthearchives.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/2013-03-06purple_weed_big1.jpg?w=480&#038;h=360" width="480" height="360" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://forthearchives.net/"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5344" alt="2013-03-06purple_weed" src="http://forthearchives.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/2013-03-06purple_weed1.jpg?w=480&#038;h=640" width="480" height="640" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://forthearchives.net/"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5341" alt="2013-03-06dandelion2" src="http://forthearchives.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/2013-03-06dandelion21.jpg?w=480&#038;h=640" width="480" height="640" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://forthearchives.net/"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5340" alt="2013-03-06beach_net" src="http://forthearchives.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/2013-03-06beach_net1.jpg?w=480&#038;h=360" width="480" height="360" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://forthearchives.net/"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5342" alt="2013-03-06picnic" src="http://forthearchives.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/2013-03-06picnic1.jpg?w=480&#038;h=525" width="480" height="525" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5339/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5339/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=5339&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://forthearchives.wordpress.com/2013/03/06/weeds-and-debris/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f7dde93f2ce930592cc5aba249d669ea?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">forthearchives</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://forthearchives.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/2013-03-06purple_weed_big1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2013-03-06purple_weed_big</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://forthearchives.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/2013-03-06purple_weed1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2013-03-06purple_weed</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://forthearchives.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/2013-03-06dandelion21.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2013-03-06dandelion2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://forthearchives.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/2013-03-06beach_net1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2013-03-06beach_net</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://forthearchives.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/2013-03-06picnic1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2013-03-06picnic</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>I&#8217;ve Eaten Rattlesnake</title>
		<link>http://mommamindy.wordpress.com/2013/03/08/ive-eaten-rattlesnake/</link>
		<comments>http://mommamindy.wordpress.com/2013/03/08/ive-eaten-rattlesnake/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 21:25:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Mindy</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Bucket List]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[growing up]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[no fear]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[overcoming fear]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[taking chances]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bragging rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[conquering fears]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Helena]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Helena Junior High]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[junior high]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[middle school]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Montana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mr. Jewell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rattlesnake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trying new things]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://mommamindy.wordpress.com/?p=6836</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In 1977, my seventh grade homeroom teacher was a Viet Nam Vet.&#160; Mr. Jewell was enthusiastic and encouraging, and&#160; seemed too young to have the few streaks of gray hair that kept the girls from obsessing about him. But when he shared the rare stories of being in the jungles, we knew he’d earned his [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=6836&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><font size="3"></font></p>
<p><font size="3"></font></p>
<p><font size="3">In 1977, my seventh grade homeroom teacher was a Viet Nam Vet.&#160; Mr. Jewell was enthusiastic and encouraging, and&#160; seemed too young to have the few streaks of gray hair that kept the girls from obsessing about him. But when he shared the rare stories of being in the jungles, we knew he’d earned his silver.</font></p>
<p><font size="3">He tried to make Science fun.&#160; For a bunch of teenagers more concerned if they could afford HASH jeans or if they were going to get asked to slow dance during the first Helena Junior High school dance, it was a challenge.</font></p>
<p><font size="3">On a Saturday in September, he foraged into the Montana wilderness with a friend, a snake pole and a cage.&#160; He came back with our new classroom pet, a rattlesnake.&#160; The snake lived in the corner of the room where he was constantly watched by kids who absorbed his identity.</font></p>
<p align="center"><a href="http://www.freedigitalphotos.net/"><img style="background-image:none;border-bottom:0;border-left:0;padding-left:0;padding-right:0;display:inline;border-top:0;border-right:0;padding-top:0;" title="Rattlesnake" border="0" alt="Rattlesnake" src="http://mommamindy.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/id-10082751.jpg?w=646&#038;h=414" width="646" height="414" /></a></p>
<p><font size="3">Having the only teacher with a rattlesnake in their homeroom, made you cool.</font></p>
<p><font size="3">Snake was fed various creatures, but usually not during class time. </font></p>
<p><font size="3">Growing up in Montana, you learned to watch for rattlesnakes, the original settlers.&#160; You watched the sunny rocks while hiking, you listened for the rattle noise in the bushes. In the olden days, we were told to cut an X over an accidental&#160; bite to suck the blood and venom and spit it out. </font><font size="3">We were taught to identify snake head and pattern shapes to know friend or foe.</font></p>
<p><font size="3">Mr. Jewell taught us the foe could also be a friend.</font></p>
<p><font size="3">Then, after a year of being the cool kids with the rattlesnake in their classroom, we took one step further into the adventure.</font></p>
<p><font size="3">We ate our pet snake.</font></p>
<p><font size="3">I know this sounds like a scene from Lord of the Flies, but there wasn’t anything ritualistic or sadistic about it.&#160; <font size="3">He cooked the snake at home and brought it in, still snake shaped, in aluminum foil. </font></font></p>
<p><font size="3">Mr. Jewell, the coolest teacher in the world, presented it to us in a way we couldn’t resist. </font><font size="3">It was our chance to do something unusual.&#160; It was our chance to push ourselves to do something we were afraid of. </font></p>
<p><font size="3">He told us, “You can brag about this the rest of your life.”</font></p>
<p><font size="3">I listened to his urgings and like the majority of the other kids in the homeroom, timidly took a bite.&#160; It tasted like chicken.</font></p>
<p><font size="3">That summer, I moved from Montana to North Dakota. In trying to impress the flat-landers, on more than one occasion I was able to work into the conversation, “I ate rattlesnake one time.”</font></p>
<p><font size="3">In college, when much bragging was done inside and outside of classrooms, I was able to casually mention, “Well, I’ve eaten rattlesnake.”</font></p>
<p><font size="3">Moving to the the west coast where people love all kinds of exotic and ethnic foods, I’m still able to assert, “I’ve eaten rattlesnake.”</font></p>
<p><font size="3">It wasn’t just about the snake, I know now.&#160; It was about confidence and conquering.&#160; It was about taking chances. It was about having no regrets.&#160; (I’ve never been offered rattlesnake again.)&#160; Overcoming fear.&#160; Listening to an adult who knew more than you.&#160; It was a life-changing experience.</font></p>
<p><font size="3">Cuz’, you know what?</font></p>
<p><font size="5">I’ve eaten rattlesnake.</font></p>
<p><font size="3"></font></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/6836/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/6836/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=6836&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://mommamindy.wordpress.com/2013/03/08/ive-eaten-rattlesnake/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>18</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/631c0ab5b2b2ce40a3ecb0b528456190?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mommamindy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mommamindy.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/id-10082751.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Rattlesnake</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dynamics and Movement – A Love Story</title>
		<link>http://andrbov.wordpress.com/2013/03/07/dynamics-and-movement-a-love-story/</link>
		<comments>http://andrbov.wordpress.com/2013/03/07/dynamics-and-movement-a-love-story/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 15:53:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>andrbov</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[About Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[balla]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boccioni]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fine art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[futurism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://andrbov.wordpress.com/?p=344</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Futurism has always been one of my favorite artistic movement.   I remember the first time I went to an exhibition of Umberto Boccioni: I was a little child, my father  &#8211; a true art lover &#8211; drove me there. In front of each work he spoke for hours about every details, talking about the &#8220;philosophy&#8221; [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=344&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="color:#ff6600;"><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Futurism"><span style="color:#ff6600;">Futurism</span></a></span> has always been one of my favorite artistic movement.   I remember the first time I went to an exhibition of <span style="color:#ff6600;"><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boccioni"><span style="color:#ff6600;">Umberto Boccioni</span></a></span>: I was a little child, my father  &#8211; a true art lover &#8211; drove me there. In front of each work he spoke for hours about every details, talking about the &#8220;philosophy&#8221; of the artist and the deep impact the movement had on the italian culture of that period. I didn&#8217;t listen at all, but I was so raptured by all those strange compositions, with fabulous colors and dynamics, that when I started with photography I tried to recreate with my camera the emotions I felt that day.</p>
<p><a href="http://andrbov.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/dsc5277_2.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-327 aligncenter" alt="_DSC5277_2" src="http://andrbov.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/dsc5277_2.jpg?w=480&#038;h=319" width="480" height="319" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://andrbov.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/dynamism_of_a_dog_on_a_leash.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-342 aligncenter" alt="Dynamism_of_a_Dog_on_a_Leash" src="http://andrbov.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/dynamism_of_a_dog_on_a_leash.jpg?w=480&#038;h=403" width="480" height="403" /></a></p>
<p>One of the goals of futurism was to capture movement and dynamics. Note that artists like <span style="color:#ff6600;"><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Giacomo_Balla"><span style="color:#ff6600;">Balla</span></a></span> were strong influenced by photography as well. Combining<span style="color:#ff6600;"> <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Panning_%28camera%29"><span style="color:#ff6600;">panning </span></a></span>with long exposures gave me some good results. (above: <em>Dynamism of a Dog on a Leash </em>compared to a photo by me)</p>
<p><a href="http://andrbov.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/600px-umberto_boccioni_-_visioni_simultanee.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-343" alt="600px-Umberto_Boccioni_-_Visioni_simultanee" src="http://andrbov.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/600px-umberto_boccioni_-_visioni_simultanee.jpg?w=480&#038;h=480" width="480" height="480" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://andrbov.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/r006.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-341" alt="r006" src="http://andrbov.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/r006.jpg?w=480&#038;h=480" width="480" height="480" /></a></p>
<p>Above: Umberto Boccioni -<em> visioni simultanee </em>compared to a shot taken in a station by me</p>
<p>I think the way futurism inspired me in these shots is quite clear; nevertheless it was unconscious to me untill some days ago, when I stumbled on<span style="color:#ff6600;"> <a href="http://leannecolephotography.com/2013/03/04/influencing-me-antonio-lopez-garcia/"><span style="color:#ff6600;">this post</span></a> </span> by <a href="http://leannecolephotography.com/"><span style="color:#ff6600;">Leanne Cole</span> .</a> Reading his experience made me realize everything.. <em>Ex abrupto</em>, but definitely!</p>
<p>Another way I tried to get some results is with <span style="color:#ff6600;"><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multiple_exposure"><span style="color:#ff6600;">multiple-exposure</span></a></span></p>
<p><a href="http://andrbov.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/russoloriv.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-383" alt="russoloriv" src="http://andrbov.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/russoloriv.jpg?w=480&#038;h=310" width="480" height="310" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://andrbov.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/dsc2436_5.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-385" alt="_DSC2436_5" src="http://andrbov.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/dsc2436_5.jpg?w=480&#038;h=320" width="480" height="320" /></a></p>
<p>Above you can see a comparison between <span style="color:#ff6600;"><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Luigi_Russolo"><span style="color:#ff6600;">Luigi Russolo</span></a> </span><em>The revolt </em>and a shot made up with 3 exposures. This is an <em>in camera</em> technique, no post editing needed. And of course I also tried with portraits. Down here you have a photo of mine (double exp in) with the work of Boccioni <em>Dynamism of a man&#8217;s head</em></p>
<p><a href="http://andrbov.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/ritratto1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-387" alt="ritratto1" src="http://andrbov.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/ritratto1.jpg?w=441&#038;h=441" width="441" height="441" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://andrbov.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/5121.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-389" alt="512" src="http://andrbov.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/5121.jpg?w=420&#038;h=420" width="420" height="420" /></a></p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://andrbov.wordpress.com/category/about-photography/'>About Photography</a> Tagged: <a href='http://andrbov.wordpress.com/tag/art/'>art</a>, <a href='http://andrbov.wordpress.com/tag/balla/'>balla</a>, <a href='http://andrbov.wordpress.com/tag/boccioni/'>boccioni</a>, <a href='http://andrbov.wordpress.com/tag/fine-art/'>fine art</a>, <a href='http://andrbov.wordpress.com/tag/futurism/'>futurism</a>, <a href='http://andrbov.wordpress.com/tag/photography/'>photography</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/344/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/344/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/344/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/344/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/344/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/344/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/344/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/344/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/344/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/344/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/344/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/344/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/344/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/344/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=344&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://andrbov.wordpress.com/2013/03/07/dynamics-and-movement-a-love-story/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>26</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/5f296f84a1de5feeb9002c4d7e64c226?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">andrbov</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://andrbov.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/dsc5277_2.jpg?w=480" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">_DSC5277_2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://andrbov.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/dynamism_of_a_dog_on_a_leash.jpg?w=480" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Dynamism_of_a_Dog_on_a_Leash</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://andrbov.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/600px-umberto_boccioni_-_visioni_simultanee.jpg?w=480" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">600px-Umberto_Boccioni_-_Visioni_simultanee</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://andrbov.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/r006.jpg?w=480" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">r006</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://andrbov.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/russoloriv.jpg?w=480" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">russoloriv</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://andrbov.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/dsc2436_5.jpg?w=480" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">_DSC2436_5</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://andrbov.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/ritratto1.jpg?w=480" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ritratto1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://andrbov.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/5121.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">512</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Earn a Black Belt&#8230;In Front of the Conveyor Belt</title>
		<link>http://theglobetrottinggeek.wordpress.com/2013/03/08/how-to-earn-a-black-belt-in-front-of-the-conveyor-belt/</link>
		<comments>http://theglobetrottinggeek.wordpress.com/2013/03/08/how-to-earn-a-black-belt-in-front-of-the-conveyor-belt/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 00:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>alexbrueckner</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Life in Japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[conveyor belt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how-to]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kaiten zushi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life Abroad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[restaurant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[salmon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sushi]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://theglobetrottinggeek.wordpress.com/?p=736</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A version of this post also appears on Matador Network. When it comes to the cuisine of Japan, it’s difficult to think of a food more deeply ingrained in the culinary image than sushi. It’s almost instinctual to think of tiny handfuls of rice carefully molded and topped by slabs of freshly cut, glistening fish. The [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=736&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A version of this post also appears on <a title="Matador Network" href="http://matadornetwork.com/trips/how-to-eat-conveyor-belt-sushi-in-japan/" target="_blank">Matador Network</a>.</p>
<p>When it comes to the cuisine of Japan, it’s difficult to think of a food more deeply ingrained in the culinary image than sushi. It’s almost instinctual to think of tiny handfuls of rice carefully molded and topped by slabs of freshly cut, glistening fish. The art of sushi – because it truly is an art as much as it is a type of food – is basically synonymous with Japan itself, and there’s a good reason for that: its clean flavors, wildly varying textures, and beautiful colors perfectly represents the pure values and exotic details of Japanese society and traditions.</p>
<p>But not all sushi restaurants, as you can imagine, feature a few sushi masters slicing and dicing cuts of flounder, salmon, and tuna for a counter of customers. While that experience is absolutely not one to be missed, if you’re ever in Japan, definitely make it a priority to experience conveyor belt sushi. If sushi restaurants were a family, 回転寿司 (<i>kaiten-zushi</i>) would absolutely be the fun-loving, laidback youngest brother. It combines one of Japan’s finest culinary styles with the user-friendly convenience that permeates the society. (And it’s cheap, to boot!)</p>
<p>One of the many perks to <i>kaiten-zushi</i> dining is that you can scrape by without any extensive knowledge of Japanese. That being said, however, it still helps to know some basic tricks of the trade to get the most out of your meal.</p>
<p><b>Get settled in. </b>First thing’s first: when you sit down for conveyor belt sushi, don’t just start grabbing plates. Whatever restaurant you go to, you’ll probably be greeted with a setup similar to this.</p>
<div id="attachment_737" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 539px"><a href="http://theglobetrottinggeek.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/counter-setup.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-737" alt="A typical counter setup" src="http://theglobetrottinggeek.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/counter-setup.jpg?w=529&#038;h=396" width="529" height="396" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">A typical counter setup</p></div>
<p>That spigot in the middle is for hot water, and the brown wooden container to the left of it contains green tea powder. You’ll be provided with ceramic mugs; load a spoonful or two of powder into the mug, fill it up with hot water, and you’re set for drinks. Grab a pair of chopsticks and an お絞り(<i>oshiburi</i>, moist towel), and load up two small dishes with soy sauce and ガリ (<i>gari</i>, pickled ginger), which is in the black container to the right of the spigot. If you’re a fan of わさび (<i>wasabi</i>), don’t be afraid to ask one of the chefs for some extra.</p>
<p><b>Pay attention to your plates. </b>Once you’ve assembled your arsenal, start loading up on plates. Some chains, like Kappa Sushi and Otaru Zushi, have a set price of 100円 for all plates. Others, like Kantaro Sushi (my personal preference), have different styles of plates that correlate to different tiers of pricing. There will probably be a key of sorts at your table, so before you grab five of those silver plates, make sure they’re not 500円 each. Some restaurants have plates with computerized chips that can be read with a handheld scanner, but if an attendant counts up your plates when you’ve finished, stack them according to type as a common courtesy.</p>
<div id="attachment_740" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 410px"><a href="http://theglobetrottinggeek.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/kaiten-zushi-3.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-740" alt="A standard plate pricing guide. (Source: essential-japan-guide.com)" src="http://theglobetrottinggeek.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/kaiten-zushi-3.jpg?w=400&#038;h=300" width="400" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">A standard plate pricing guide. (Source: essential-japan-guide.com)</p></div>
<p><b>Soy sauce and rice don’t mix. </b>In my opinion, most sushi doesn’t need overly salty soy sauce for the best flavor. But if you’re a fan, just cover the fish in it, not the rice. Take the fish off of the rice with your chopsticks, dip it in the soy sauce, and then put it back. Trying to dip the entire thing will likely just end in losing half of your rice and ending up with soy sauce soup.</p>
<p><b>Use the </b><b>ガリ </b><b>right. </b>Pickled ginger isn’t actually meant as a garnish for your sushi. Instead, it’s to be used to cleanse your palate in between dishes. It ensures that flavors of vastly different sushi (like the very fishy yellowtail and the more subtle red snapper) don’t clash. Feel free to munch on it to your heart’s content between your flounder and your tuna, but don’t use it as a topping.</p>
<p><b>If it’s hot, crunchy, broiled, or fried, order it fresh. </b>Lots of dishes offered at 回転寿司　aren’t just the standard sushi cuts. You can order anything from fried octopus to hot pumpkin pudding.</p>
<div id="attachment_738" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 539px"><a href="http://theglobetrottinggeek.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/pumpkin-pudding.png"><img class="size-large wp-image-738" alt="For certain hot offerings, only the placard circulates on the belt. You'll have to order one from a chef." src="http://theglobetrottinggeek.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/pumpkin-pudding.png?w=529&#038;h=301" width="529" height="301" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">For certain hot offerings (like the pumpkin pudding I mentioned), only the placard circulates on the belt. You&#8217;ll have to order one from a chef.</p></div>
<p>One of my absolute favorite dishes is 炙り (<i>aburi</i>, broiled) salmon. It’s smooth, buttery, and warm on top and still raw underneath…but more than one rotation on the belt turns it cold, oily, and tasting like butane. I doesn’t matter if there are five of them circulating…I’ll still order one fresh to ensure it tastes the best. And something like 唐揚げ (<i>karaage</i>, fried chicken) or shrimp tempura can end up limp or soggy after only a few minutes. If your dish of choice is broiled, covered in a crunchy coating, or deep fried (basically, if it isn’t traditional sushi), abandon the belt and order that sucker fresh.</p>
<div id="attachment_714" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 539px"><a href="http://theglobetrottinggeek.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/aburisalmon.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-714" alt="Salivary glands activated." src="http://theglobetrottinggeek.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/aburisalmon.jpg?w=529&#038;h=396" width="529" height="396" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Salivary glands activated&#8230;but only if the aburi salmon is fresh.</p></div>
<p><b>If you don’t see what you like, don’t be afraid to order it. </b>Just because you don’t see something on the belt doesn’t mean that it’s unavailable. Don’t feel limited to eating only what you see. My favorite sushi cuts are ほたて (<i>hotate,</i> scallop) and 穴子 (<i>anago, </i>conger eel), but I rarely see either of them on the belt, so I don’t have any qualms about flagging a chef down and ordering what I want. Some restaurants, like Kappa Sushi, have computerized ordering screens. At Kappa, your order even arrives at your table on a miniature, cutely kitsch train.</p>
<p><b>When in doubt, order fatty. </b>とろ (<i>toro</i>) means a “fatty” cut of まぐろ (<i>maguro, </i>tuna), and in this case, fatty means “delicious.” If you see it on the cards marking plates of tuna on the belt, it means the meat is a higher quality. とろ is usually a bit more expensive, but it’s definitely worth it, as the meat just melts in your mouth.  If you’re going to splurge on one of the more expensive plates, make it this one.</p>
<p><b>Go when it’s busy. </b>It might seem counterintuitive, but you’ll have the highest quality meal when the restaurant is busiest. A ton of diners means that the sushi on the belt has a very quick turnover, which translates to you getting fresh cuts. Going when it’s nearly empty means that the belt will be mostly clear (Why load it up when there’s no one there to eat the food?) and that the sushi that <i>is</i> there will have been sitting under the lights for ages. Plus, the atmosphere in a bustling 回転寿司 joint, with people calling out orders and the sushi chefs working together like a well-oiled machine, is simply a blast to join.</p>
<p><a href="http://theglobetrottinggeek.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/booth-setup.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-739" alt="DSC_0407" src="http://theglobetrottinggeek.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/booth-setup.jpg?w=529&#038;h=396" width="529" height="396" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/736/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/736/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=736&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://theglobetrottinggeek.wordpress.com/2013/03/08/how-to-earn-a-black-belt-in-front-of-the-conveyor-belt/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://theglobetrottinggeek.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/booth-setup.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://theglobetrottinggeek.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/booth-setup.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0407</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/b9ef1f58119740a224290406266ccfca?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">alexbrueckner</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theglobetrottinggeek.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/counter-setup.jpg?w=529" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">A typical counter setup</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theglobetrottinggeek.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/kaiten-zushi-3.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">A standard plate pricing guide. (Source: essential-japan-guide.com)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theglobetrottinggeek.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/pumpkin-pudding.png?w=529" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">For certain hot offerings, only the placard circulates on the belt. You&#039;ll have to order one from a chef.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theglobetrottinggeek.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/aburisalmon.jpg?w=529" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Salivary glands activated.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theglobetrottinggeek.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/booth-setup.jpg?w=529" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0407</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Q&amp;A on Longform with Esquire’s Mike Sager</title>
		<link>http://beyondthenewyorker.wordpress.com/2013/03/06/a-qa-on-longform-with-esquires-mike-sager/</link>
		<comments>http://beyondthenewyorker.wordpress.com/2013/03/06/a-qa-on-longform-with-esquires-mike-sager/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2013 06:20:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>flynnmeagan</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Esquire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Garry Wills]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[longform]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mike Sager]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New Journalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Newark]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Playboy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Revenge of the Donut Boys]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rolling Stone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Man Who Never Was]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Someone You’re Not]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Washington Post]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Todd Marinovich]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tom Junod]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tom Wolfe]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://beyondthenewyorker.wordpress.com/?p=219</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[For every story he writes, Mike Sager, writer-at-large for Esquire, finds a way to love his subjects. From drug addicts to porn stars, military vets to once-great athletes, Sager has let them all shape him into the journalist he is today. Here, Sager talks about what makes a solid longform piece and reveals some of his [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=219&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For every story he writes, Mike Sager, writer-at-large for <i>Esquire, </i>finds a way to love his subjects. From drug addicts to porn stars,<a href="http://beyondthenewyorker.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/author_image_11.jpg"><img class="alignright  wp-image-228" alt="Mike Sager" src="http://beyondthenewyorker.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/author_image_11.jpg?w=88&#038;h=88" width="88" height="88" /></a> military vets to once-great athletes, Sager has let them all shape him into the journalist he is today. Here, Sager talks about what makes a solid longform piece and reveals some of his secrets to the craft. In addition: a close look into the making of his 1992 <i>Rolling Stone</i> piece <a href="http://www.maryellenmark.com/text/magazines/rolling%20stone/920S-000-026.html" target="_blank">“Revenge of the Doughnut Boys,”</a> which is about teenage car hijackers in Newark, N.J. It is also the title piece in his <a href="http://www.mikesager.com/revenge-of-the-donut-boys" target="_blank">Los Angeles Times Best-Seller</a>, one of Sager’s four collections of riveting longform journalism. Through it all, it comes down to one thing, he says: &#8220;Getting shit right.&#8221;<span id="more-219"></span><b><i></i></b></p>
<p><b><i>Meagan Flynn: After working for the Washington Post, what made you want to get into this longer, more in-depth writing?</i></b></p>
<p><b>Mike Sager:</b> I came into journalism because it seemed like a great way to practice my writing skills. [During college], I worked for the paper and the literary magazine, but I still decided I was gonna go to law school because I didn’t know how I was going to become a writer. That lasted three weeks. Eventually, I got a job as a copy boy at the Post. I worked nights until 3 a.m., and during the day I tried to write stories. Eventually I broke a big one, and then my boss, Bob Woodward of Watergate fame, gave me a promotion and made me a real reporter. I learned all the basics—how to do research, how to talk to people—at the Post. But what I really wanted to do was be a fine writer. So I left because I wanted to write different things. I was young when I started there, and they always thought I was young. I couldn’t grow up there.</p>
<p>First, I went around the world. I did a story for <i>Rolling Stone </i>in Thailand. I did another story for <i>Playboy </i>about beach volleyball players. That’s how I [got started] in magazine writing.</p>
<p><b><i>MF: When you sit down to begin a longform story after all the reporting is done, where do you start?</i></b></p>
<p><b>MS:</b> I do a lot of taping with a digital tape voice recorder. I tape everything then I transcribe everything. By the time I finish that, I kind of know what the story is. After I finish interviewing, I don’t necessarily know the story, but after I go through all my notes, the story becomes clear in my mind. I try to write in scenes, and I try to find a series of scenes that will symbolize the message I’m trying to get through. You start out doing small stories. At the newspaper, you’re told, “It’s a hot day—go cover the air conditioning repair guy in 104 degree heat.” You start small and then move up to bigger subjects.</p>
<p>It’s like playing an instrument. You learn to play “Mary Had a Little Lamb” on the piano, and then eventually you can play jazz. You put all those millions of little skills together. You learn the right hand, then you learn the left hand, then you learn chords. An there’s also a magical element. You can learn all the techniques, do all your research, fill up what I call a “bowl of details”&#8212;and then you make a collage, you put all the little pieces together. You’ve got this little magic. That’s what separates the Tom Junods and the Chris Jones from the whomevers. The great ones have magic.</p>
<p><b><i>MF: What are some elements in long pieces that you think are essential?</i></b></p>
<p><b>MS:</b> I’m a follower of the “New Journalism.” Their basic tenet involves using the elements of a novel—scene, setting, dialogue, characters, description, point of view, a story arc. The best way I can describe it is like it’s trying to write a movie in words. When you do that, you try to use the elements of drama so you have a storyline. Sometimes, with stories like <a href="http://beyondthenewyorker.wordpress.com/2013/03/05/on-mike-sagers-revenge-of-the-doughnut-boys-rolling-stone-october-1992/" target="_blank">“Revenge of the Donut Boys,”</a> there’s no story, so I have to spend a lot of time [to find it]. I have this “trash compactor theory of journalism.” You spend all this time with people and put it all together and compact it, and you see that there really was this overarching storyline while you were with them.</p>
<p><b><i>MF: A lot of your pieces illustrate harsh realities. What do you find to be so valuable in these stories, and what about them has kept you so drawn to them?</i></b></p>
<p><strong>MS: </strong>The basic thing is that I don’t want to be boring. I want to do stuff that’s cool. I wanted to write about things that had a lot to be written about. I wanted action. I always get this question, “Why have you been doing this?” Here’s the answer:</p>
<p>Most people have a boring life, so they want to read about things that are exciting. When I was at the Post, most of the people I worked with were from Ivy League schools. My thing has always been the “theory of the originals.” You don’t compete with people. You have to be No. 1 in a class of one. The [people I worked with] were really smart. They were intellectuals, but they were kind of sheltered. They weren’t as gonzo as me or what I wanted to be.</p>
<p>I’m just good with people. I’m not afraid of people who are better or worse than me. I treat everyone the same, whether it’s a crack dealer or the president. There’s a million people who want to be writers, but you have to have something unique that people want. I learned I had a talent. I wasn’t afraid to knock on someone’s door in the ghetto at midnight. [The reason I’m doing this] has a lot to do with that. It began that way in Washington, and that’s how they discovered me in New York.</p>
<p><b><i>MF: In “Revenge of the Doughnut Boys,” you took a news event and dug deeper, past just the headlines. What was toughest about approaching this one?</i></b></p>
<p><b>MS:</b> First of all, I wrote that back in a time when there was an economic slow-down in the magazine industry. I made a deal with <i>Rolling Stone</i> to be a columnist. I didn’t want to be a blah-blah columnist who just talks shit. I wanted to write a reported column. This one was difficult—it’s always difficult when you’re writing about juveniles. Newark felt very dangerous at the time. I remember driving down the street and hearing gunshots. The whole situation was very tentative, but you have to find a way in. I think your average reporter goes straight to the cops to write about illegal activities. The cops normally don’t understand. They see it from their point of view. This is something that’s become very important: The important thing about all of this stuff is finding the truth. The truth is always so much cooler than the hype. That’s what makes it worthwhile. [To be a journalist,] you have to feel what people are feeling. I call it suspension of disbelief. You put your prejudices aside, you go there, and you try to understand people’s points of view. That’s become very important.</p>
<p>In my book<i><a href="http://www.mikesager.com/the-someone-youre-not" target="_blank"> The Someone You’re</a></i><a href="http://www.mikesager.com/the-someone-youre-not" target="_blank"> Not</a> [Sager is speaking about it at the Tucson Festival of Books March 9-10], the title has a lot to do with what my work has been over the years. In “<a href="http://www.esquire.com/print-this/todd-marinovich-0509?page=all" target="_blank">The Man Who Never Was,” </a>[2010 National Magazine Award winner, profile writing] Todd Marinovich was a football star who fucked himself up with drugs. The story people like to believe, the one pushed in the press over the years, is that his father ruined him. But that’s not really what the story was—that’s what everyone thought it was. The thing that becomes really important is telling the story the way it is, instead of this simplistic, headline news. People think they know, but they don’t. That pisses me off. I hate when people don’t have things right. That’s what’s important.</p>
<p><b><i>MF: More conservative media may shy away from reporting stories like “Revenge of the Doughnut Boys.” So when you are out in the field reporting these kinds of stories, do you see it as your responsibility to give people the whole truth that they can’t find in other news media?</i></b></p>
<p><b>MS:</b> Yeah—exactly. The thing is, there’s kind of a continuum in the news business. In the newspaper, it’s “some people think this, some people think that.” It’s simple thinking. It’s changed a little bit because newspapers are discovering feature writing to keep newspapers alive. This is the appeal of longform: It’s not just longer, you spend so much more time. You get it. It’s a detail thing—going into a place you know nothing about, learning it, and writing about it.</p>
<p><b><i>MF: What should be a longformer’s biggest goal?</i></b></p>
<p><strong>MS:</strong> There was this writer Garry Wills—one of the older guys before me in the Tom Wolfe era. He said that the job of people who do longform is to let the dust settle on some event and then go in later, figure out how all the pieces went together, tell the real truth of the impact of the event on the people and the places.</p>
<p>People want instant stories today. Events happen and the press rolls into town with their satellite trucks and all that shit. It fucks up the story. It’s gotten so crazy. It takes time to really step back and see what history brings to bear.</p>
<p>What we’re trying to do [as longformers] is go in and kick some story’s ass. Get it right. I write my stories for my subjects. They don’t have to like everything, but they have to say I nailed it. I think I’ve been successful with that. I find a way to love my subjects—even the dead ones or the evil ones. That’s the bottom line of what my secret is. To me, with longform, it’s not <i>just </i>writing it. It’s doing all the research and writing without flowery language. As you go through this longform stuff, there are people who write in third person and there are people who write in first person. The challenge is putting yourself in the story but leaving yourself out of the verbiage. It doesn’t have to seem like it’s all about you.</p>
<p>One thing I do after I&#8217;ve transcribed all those tapes&#8212;my writing kind of takes on a bit of the voice of my subject has an accent like my subject. I use their rhythm and their little idioms. I think it’s another way of making the character come through. There’s little tricks I do that are a lot of work, but that’s how [I’ve been successful].</p>
<p><b><i>MF: What direction do you see longform heading?</i></b></p>
<p><b>MS:</b> I’d like to see it head in a direction where there are more women writers. With nearly 70 percent of people in J-school being women, it would be really nice if some of these women’s magazines stepped up and put a fucking longform story in the mag.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.mikesager.com/next-wave-americas-new-generation-great-literary-journalists" target="_blank">In my collection of 19 young writers,</a> we’re saying that longform is not dead, and that the Internet is the enabler, not the killer, of quality writing. People want to do it. Longform is enjoying more popularity than ever. Web sites like <a href="https://www.atavist.com/" target="_blank">the Atavist</a>, <a href="http://byliner.com" target="_blank">Byliner</a>, <a href="http://longform.org" target="_blank">Longform.org</a> are cropping up everywhere to help nurture and publish writers. And of course there’s the <a href="http://www.mikesager.com/" target="_blank">Sager Group</a>, too. The web is allowing us to harness the means of production.</p>
<p>The key is that you need to start short-form. Once you do a bunch of short stories, you see that long stories are short stories pieced together. Eventually, you’ll get the jazz.</p>
<p><em>See <a href="http://beyondthenewyorker.wordpress.com/2013/03/05/on-mike-sagers-revenge-of-the-doughnut-boys-rolling-stone-october-1992/">this post on Sager’s “Revenge of the Doughnut Boys”</a> from Beyond The New Yorker.</em></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/219/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/219/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=219&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://beyondthenewyorker.wordpress.com/2013/03/06/a-qa-on-longform-with-esquires-mike-sager/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/1fb5585652dadb53bc36f05de0d616ea?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">flynnmeagan</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://beyondthenewyorker.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/author_image_11.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mike Sager</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nakji Bokum, or, Old Ones in the Sink</title>
		<link>http://adventuresofaculinarymulticulturalist.wordpress.com/2013/03/07/nakji-bokum-or-old-ones-in-the-sink/</link>
		<comments>http://adventuresofaculinarymulticulturalist.wordpress.com/2013/03/07/nakji-bokum-or-old-ones-in-the-sink/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 01:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>The Last of the Thyme Lords</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Main dishes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Seafood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[korean]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lovecraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[seafood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smart remarks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spicy things]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://adventuresofaculinarymulticulturalist.wordpress.com/?p=78</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Scaring my mother with groceries is something of a guilty pleasure of mine.  It&#8217;s one of the few avenues of resistance left to a humble citizen of the People&#8217;s Republic of Food.  I&#8217;m also a big fan of the works of H. P. Lovecraft.  So when I passed the frozen fish section this week and [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=78&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_80" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 234px"><img class="size-medium wp-image-80     " title="Babies.... yum." alt="" src="http://adventuresofaculinarymulticulturalist.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/finished-octopus-dish.jpg?w=224&#038;h=300" width="224" height="300" /><p class="wp-caption-text">I dismembered, cooked, and ate a baby animal today. What worthwhile thing have you done with your life?</p></div>
<p>Scaring my mother with groceries is something of a guilty pleasure of mine.  It&#8217;s one of the few avenues of resistance left to a humble citizen of the People&#8217;s Republic of Food.  I&#8217;m also a big fan of the works of H. P. Lovecraft.  So when I passed the frozen fish section this week and spotted a package of baby octopus, I couldn&#8217;t resist.</p>
<p>I perhaps should have mentioned that I&#8217;ve got a gold medal in leaping before looking.</p>
<p>A few internet searches later, I knew a few things.  One: baby octopus is better than full-grown octopus (apparently the adults are a bit stringy).  Step ahead, as usual.  Two: either way they&#8217;re tough little sods and have to be tenderized.  The best way to do this is freezing them.  Step ahead again.  I mucked about on the Googles for a bit until I found the dish I was looking for.  One of the Korean restaurants in our neighborhood serves this dish, and I altered the online recipe somewhat to match what I recalled eating there.</p>
<p>When I brought said little sods out of the freezer this afternoon and left them into the sink to thaw, the Gastronomic Gestapo threw a hissy fit.  What the hell were those horrible tentacle monsters in her sink, get them out of there, oh god, o god, there were horrible tentacle monsters in her sink.  &#8221;<i>Ph&#8217;nglui mglw&#8217;nafh Cthulhu R&#8217;lyeh wgah&#8217;nagl fhtagn,&#8221;</i> I gurgled as best I could, but I don&#8217;t think the reference went through.</p>
<p>I had assumed when I bought the suckers (sorry) that they came cleaned.  Oh how wrong I was.  Now, mind, I&#8217;m not squeamish in a general way.  I&#8217;ve gutted many fish, squirrels, and other sundry critters without turning a hair.  But I hate eyeballs.  Eyeballs freak me out.  Octopus eyeballs are apparently worse than other sorts of eyeballs.  I gritted my teeth and cut around them.</p>
<p>My father, to my surprise, begged to try it when I brought it to the table.  I guess it provided a persuasive alternative to the bean soup we seem to live on most of the time.  I&#8217;ve been expecting my mother to yell &#8220;This! Is! Sparta!&#8221; any minute for a year.  He liked it, even though he&#8217;s no great seafood eater.</p>
<p>Mum wouldn&#8217;t touch the stuff with the bow of a steam yacht.</p>
<div id="attachment_81" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 234px"><img class="size-medium wp-image-81  " title="I'a Cthulhu!  I'a Dagon!" alt="" src="http://adventuresofaculinarymulticulturalist.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/octopus-dish-in-progress.jpg?w=224&#038;h=300" width="224" height="300" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Here you can actually see the octopus.</p></div>
<ul>
<ul>
<ul>
<li>1 lb baby octopus, frozen (about six of the buggers)</li>
<li>1/2 yellow onion</li>
<li>2 fresh green chilies</li>
<li>1 small red bell pepper</li>
<li>4 to 6 shiitake mushrooms</li>
<li>1 tablespoon sesame cooking oil</li>
<li>2 1/2 tbsp gochujang (Korean chili paste)</li>
<li>1 tbsp soy sauce</li>
<li>1 tsp sesame oil</li>
<li>5 cloves fresh garlic or 2 tbsp crushed garlic from a jar</li>
<li>1 tbsp sesame cooking oil (usually a mixture of sesame oil and some kind of vegetable oil)</li>
<li>1 tbsp sesame seeds</li>
<li>2 green onions</li>
</ul>
</ul>
</ul>
<p>Thaw the octopuses by running water gently over it and then letting it sit for a few minutes in a lukewarm bath. Cut tentacles from head.  In the center of the tentacles will be the beak.  Pop it out and take care not to cut your fingers.  Cut tentacles into two-tentacle sections. Open head and remove the insides.  Discard guts, beak and eyes. Cut head into equal sized strips (quarters or eighths).</p>
<p>Cut onion in half from top to bottom, then thinly slice (about 1/8 inch thick). Remove stem from chili/jalapeño peppers, cut in half from top to bottom, and slice into thin slivers. Cut bell pepper in half from top to bottom, then thinly slice into strips. Thinly slice mushroom caps.  Discard stems. Crush or mince garlic into a medium mixing bowl.  Add soy sauce, sesame oil, and gochujang.  Mix well.  Let stand at least fifteen minutes. Add octopus to sauce and let stand for fifteen to twenty minutes.</p>
<p>Heat a stir fry pan over high heat. Reduce heat to medium.  Quickly add sesame cooking oil, onion and peppers.  Stir fry for one minute. Add all other ingredients and stir fry for about five minutes.  Octopus sections should curl up when thoroughly cooked.  Garnish with sesame seeds and sliced green onions.  Serve with rice.</p>
<p>Serves 2 with rice.  Riceless, I devoured the whole shebang myself.</p>
<p>In his house in my stomach dead Cthulhu lies dreaming.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/78/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/78/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=78&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://adventuresofaculinarymulticulturalist.wordpress.com/2013/03/07/nakji-bokum-or-old-ones-in-the-sink/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>17</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/65e6ddf193dbeffe330cce422656dd98?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">thelastofthethymelords</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://adventuresofaculinarymulticulturalist.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/finished-octopus-dish.jpg?w=224" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Babies.... yum.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://adventuresofaculinarymulticulturalist.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/octopus-dish-in-progress.jpg?w=224" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">I&#039;a Cthulhu!  I&#039;a Dagon!</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Seb Lee-Delisle: Playing With Code</title>
		<link>http://blog.makezine.com/2013/03/06/seb-lee-delisle-playing-with-code/</link>
		<comments>http://blog.makezine.com/2013/03/06/seb-lee-delisle-playing-with-code/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2013 17:33:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Andrew Sleigh</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Art & Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Makers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[digital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Maker Faire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[programming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Seb Lee-Delisle]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blog.makezine.com/?p=287014</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The last 12 months have been a busy time for Seb Lee-Delisle. With a buzzing schedule of speaking, creative coding workshops, exhibitions and public events, it looks like this is the year he's found his feet as a digital artist.

His path has taken many turns. He started by dropping out of a computer science degree, then hopping around various creative digital disciplines, from desktop publishing to music production. In the early 2000s he began to carve out a career in multimedia production for the web. A growing client list led him to set up his own agency, Plug-in Media. But client work began to take its toll:

"We were doing probably the best work you could imagine, very creative, for high-profile clients, but the thing I realised was, even with the best clients, " he said. "I only spent about 10 percent of my time doing the stuff I really wanted to do and the other 90 percent negotiating, in meetings, scheduling, budgeting, and team management – all this extra stuff, which I wasn't that interested in doing. It was frustrating; I just wanted to do that 10 perent."<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=287014&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://blog.makezine.com/2013/03/06/seb-lee-delisle-playing-with-code/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a150838c277109d071d7fb81db9282f3?s=96&#38;d=retro&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Andrew</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://makezineblog.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/5388246284_df5b90b720_b.jpg?w=620" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Seb Lee-Delisle</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://makezineblog.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/7119633971_6cec88da09_b.jpg?w=620" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Pixel Phones</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://makezineblog.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/7999938984_df39e5fd7a_b.jpg?w=620" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Pixel Pyros</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://makezineblog.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/8202076905_acc30b0863_b.jpg?w=620" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Lunar Trails</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://makezineblog.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/8203173216_2680ef4bf6_h.jpg?w=620" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Lunar Trails</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
