<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2012 22:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Good Job New Zealand!</title>
		<link>http://twokiwisonabike.wordpress.com/2012/11/23/good-job-new-zealand/</link>
		<comments>http://twokiwisonabike.wordpress.com/2012/11/23/good-job-new-zealand/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2012 03:41:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>David and Sophie</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[New-Zealand]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://twokiwisonabike.wordpress.com/?p=318</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Today goal was to arrive via a scenic bike trail in Queenstown. We first had to continue a short 20 km stretch next to the busy road before passing through Gibson: one of New Zealand’s hot spots for wineries. It was beautiful cycling next to the vineyards and it both reminded us of the South [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=318&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Today goal was to arrive via a scenic bike trail in Queenstown. We first had to continue a short 20 km stretch next to the busy road before passing through Gibson: one of New Zealand’s hot spots for wineries. It was beautiful cycling next to the vineyards and it both reminded us of the South of France. The density of the camper vans increased as we neared one of the most famous adventure centers in the world. As a break we took a quick look at a bungi jumper that was jumping from a 50 m bridge. From that moment on we followed a ‘bikers and walkers’ only path throught the mountains. We visited an old and cozy little town called Arrowtown and continued for 70 km on this trail. A must do for anyone visiting Queenstown and a big thank you to the government of NZ for creating this wonderful trail.</p>
<div id="attachment_319" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 520px"><a href="http://twokiwisonabike.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dsc3402small.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-319" title="_DSC3402small" alt="" src="http://twokiwisonabike.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dsc3402small.jpg?w=590"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">David crossing a bridge about 50 meters above water. Scary on a bike!</p></div>
<div id="attachment_320" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 520px"><a href="http://twokiwisonabike.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dsc3406small.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-320" title="_DSC3406small" alt="" src="http://twokiwisonabike.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dsc3406small.jpg?w=590"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">70 km of Queenstown’s trail today.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_321" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 520px"><a href="http://twokiwisonabike.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dsc3408small.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-321" title="_DSC3408small" alt="" src="http://twokiwisonabike.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dsc3408small.jpg?w=590"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Who is up for some Salmon and pineapple.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_322" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 520px"><a href="http://twokiwisonabike.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dsc3409small.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-322" title="_DSC3409small" alt="" src="http://twokiwisonabike.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dsc3409small.jpg?w=590"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Try to find David. Sweet downhill.</p></div>
<p>Since the road to Milford Sounds and the west coast is very busy and to give our legs some rest, we will rent a car for 5 days and combine it with hikes to explore this region. We did not book anything in advance and were surprised to hear one of the Hertz representatives say that all cars were booked. Luckily we got a good deal with Apex for a car that would fit the bikes and would allow return to Greymouth (570 km north of Queenstown). Couscous with a delicious thai sauce in the center of Queenstown was a great way to end the day. Another 10 km of cycling in the sunset brought us to another hidden campsite near queenstown.</p>
<div id="attachment_323" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 520px"><a href="http://twokiwisonabike.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dsc3416small.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-323" title="_DSC3416small" alt="" src="http://twokiwisonabike.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dsc3416small.jpg?w=590"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Far away from home.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_324" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 520px"><a href="http://twokiwisonabike.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dsc3421small.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-324" title="_DSC3421small" alt="" src="http://twokiwisonabike.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dsc3421small.jpg?w=590"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Cycling into Queenstown.</p></div>
<div>
<div id="attachment_325" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 520px"><a href="http://twokiwisonabike.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dsc3428small.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-325" title="_DSC3428small" alt="" src="http://twokiwisonabike.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dsc3428small.jpg?w=590"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Bellies are full- ready for our ride to the campsite.</p></div>
</div>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/318/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/318/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=318&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://twokiwisonabike.wordpress.com/2012/11/23/good-job-new-zealand/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/da85f85eee280305ad772c104cb4058b?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ridingthegreatdivide</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://twokiwisonabike.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dsc3402small.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">_DSC3402small</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://twokiwisonabike.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dsc3406small.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">_DSC3406small</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://twokiwisonabike.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dsc3408small.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">_DSC3408small</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://twokiwisonabike.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dsc3409small.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">_DSC3409small</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://twokiwisonabike.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dsc3416small.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">_DSC3416small</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://twokiwisonabike.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dsc3421small.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">_DSC3421small</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://twokiwisonabike.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dsc3428small.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">_DSC3428small</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How I Came to See ‘Whiteness’ As Just Ordinarily Beautiful</title>
		<link>http://mabelkwong.com/2012/11/22/how-i-came-to-see-whiteness-as-just-ordinarily-beautiful/</link>
		<comments>http://mabelkwong.com/2012/11/22/how-i-came-to-see-whiteness-as-just-ordinarily-beautiful/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2012 01:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Mabel Kwong</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Asian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beauty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lifestyle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[people]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[skin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[White]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mabelkwong.com/?p=1330</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I used to be one of those people who honestly thought and held the perception that white-skinned Caucasians were the ultimate epitome of beauty. That is, when I was living in South East Asia, I genuinely regarded Caucasians and people with fair skin and blue eyes as physically attractive, thinking “whiteness” was what you needed [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1330&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I used to be one of those people who honestly thought and held the perception that white-skinned Caucasians were the ultimate epitome of beauty.</p>
<p>That is, when I was living in South East Asia, I genuinely regarded Caucasians and people with fair skin and blue eyes as physically attractive, thinking “whiteness” was what you needed in order to be beautiful inside out.</p>
<p>Whenever it was blazingly hot and sunny outside in Malaysia or Singapore and I wanted to go out, my mum would incessantly nag at me to stay in the shade or else I would “get all black” and ugly. I always naively obliged thinking she was Mrs. Know It All.</p>
<p>I would also always gawk in admiration at Caucasians who strolled around here as the thought “oh wow, they are so beautiful” whirled around in my head.</p>
<div id="attachment_1334" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 443px"><a href="http://themabelkwong.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/img_6476.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-1334" title="IMG_6476" alt="" src="http://themabelkwong.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/img_6476.jpg?w=433&#038;h=577" height="577" width="433" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">People in East Asia are known to use every means to shield themselves from the sun so as to not get tanned while outdoors. Photo by <a href="http://replacingink.blogspot.com.au">Replacing Ink</a>.</p></div>
<p>I’m definitely not the only one who (used to) thinks this way. Over the past century and up until today, there is a <a href="http://www.globalpost.com/dispatch/china-and-its-neighbors/091123/asia-white-skin-treatments-risks">craze</a> amongst people of Asian ethnicity – Chinese, Koreans, Japanese etc. – living in East Asia to look as white or fair-skinned as possible. Whitening beauty products are all the rage here, abundantly stocked on supermarket shelves and advertised more than a fair bit in newspapers.<span id="more-1330"></span></p>
<p>Quite a number of people in this region hold the superficial idea that being beautiful is equated to “looking as white as possible”. And this shallow trend in Asia shows no sign of slowing down.</p>
<p>Some reasons behind such a prolific phenomenon in East Asia struck me after a couple of years living in Melbourne. The so-called rigid aspects of Asian culture can be partially to blame (don’t get me wrong, I am very proud of my heritage).</p>
<p><strong>Asians in general are taught to abide by traditions and exercise filial piety, and this in turn simply reinstates the long-held belief in every generation that fair skin is the quintessence of beauty. </strong></p>
<p>Whiteness has always been a salient albeit a slightly <a href="http://usa.chinadaily.com.cn/weekly/2012-06/29/content_15533864.htm">evolving standard</a> in Chinese history. During the Han period in China, women of court boasted unearthly white Moon-like faces. Later in the Tang dynasty, reddish-white faces were a common sight among the women of this era. Empress Wu Zetian <a href="http://kaleidoscope.cultural-china.com/en/7Kaleidoscope5334.html">passed down</a> her royal skin whitening recipes to her daughter Princess Taiping who never questioned such techniques and emphatically sought to preserve them.</p>
<p>And today alabaster white skin tones are immensely popular in Asia for arguably this reason.</p>
<p>Don’t we all feel that inkling of ‘Asian shame’ if we are rebellious towards our parents or get a wigging from them? I would always fret over tan lines that materialised on my arms and legs after a school hiking excursion under the sun in Singapore and wondered what my parents would say.</p>
<p>As it has been for centuries in Asian cultures, we aren’t inclined to disrespect history. We aren’t exactly told to question but encouraged to adhere by traditional values and beliefs – think “study hard, get good grades” – and essentially shut up and listen most of the time. So the notion ‘whiteness equals beauty’ permeates today due to East Asians’ unconscious innate in-bred instincts to listen to repetitive advice on this subject and fervently pass these messages down to the next generation.</p>
<p>The preference and tendency to socialise with other Asians who share similar perspectives is also ostensibly another reason behind this whiteness craze. Bruce McConachie <a href="http://muse.jhu.edu/login?auth=0&amp;type=summary&amp;url=/journals/theatre_topics/v008/8.1mcconachie.html">writes</a> that sociologist Raymond Williams’ idea of “structures of feeling” designates the emotional bonding below the conscious level due to the collective experiences by a particular group. That is, we frequently gravitate towards and feel a sense of connection with those who possesses similar experiences as us.</p>
<p>While living in East Asia, most of my friends were of Asian background and we took much enjoyment in Asian-activities such as celebrating the Lunar New Year and yapping about traditional superstition.</p>
<p>And naturally we agreed that ‘dark skin’ is ugly given that it’s often associated with being ‘poor’ or dark skinned peasants planting rice in paddy fields under the scorching sun, and ‘whiteness’ pretty as it tends to be equated with high economic statuses or Caucasians decked out in spiffy business attire working in comfortable air-conditioned office buildings. Just like in the movies.</p>
<p>In essence, <strong>the more us Asians who had similar mindsets stuck together, the more the mentality ‘white is beautiful’ stuck in our heads – no one challenged this idea.</strong></p>
<p>This frame of mind can also be said to persist today due to the presence of relatively few <i>gwei los</i> or <i>gwei muis</i> in Asia. I gawked whenever I spied one of them in Singapore. Thinking back, I stared because <strong>compared to most of the other people around me that were of Asian descent, Caucasians simply looked different feature-wise. Exotic almost. And exotic is always attractive and eye-catching</strong>.</p>
<p>When I moved to Melbourne, I was immediately riveted by how everyone is constantly encouraged to be creative, to inquisitively think outside of the box. Individual opinion is highly valued in the Western world. During class discussions, I was always asked to speak my opinion on the topic thrown up in the air. Once my class was asked to deliberate the stereotypes of whites and non-whites and that got me thinking:</p>
<p>Is skin colour <i>really</i> justified as the benchmark for beauty? A beautiful personality?</p>
<div id="attachment_1338" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 429px"><a href="http://themabelkwong.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/img_6480.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-1338" title="IMG_6480" alt="" src="http://themabelkwong.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/img_6480.jpg?w=419&#038;h=558" height="558" width="419" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Me enjoying the sun in Melbourne. With sunscreen of course. Photo by <a href="http://replacingink.blogspot.com.au">Replacing Ink</a>.</p></div>
<p>No. As I’ve <a href="http://mabelkwong.com/2012/11/08/im-white-so-that-means-im-pretty-and-smart-right">mentioned</a>, at the end of the day, <strong>just as age is just a number, skin colour is just a colour</strong>.</p>
<p>I began thinking even more broadly as I met people from different backgrounds with different beliefs. Although I did meet people who did think “white was beautiful” at school, most were very proactive about sharing alternative opinions.</p>
<p>As such, I eventually developed a penchant for looking at both sides of the coin and not confining myself to thinking about one perspective in any given situation.</p>
<p>And when I walk out of my Melbourne flat, I see Caucasian after Caucasian person on the streets – alongside speckles of people of Asian ethnicity. A very common, bland sight that I’ve gotten used to seeing on an ordinary day.</p>
<p>So much so that I’ve come to realise “whiteness” and “non-whiteness” are both <i>merely physical features</i>.</p>
<p>What’s more interesting is having a spontaneous conversation with a white or non-white person, and seeing the nice things that they do. Which are never the same and always one-of-a-kind.</p>
<p>And that’s where real beauty emanates from.</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://mabelkwong.com/category/asian/'>Asian</a>, <a href='http://mabelkwong.com/category/opinion/'>Opinion</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1330/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1330/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1330/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1330/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1330/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1330/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1330/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1330/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1330/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1330/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1330/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1330/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1330/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1330/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1330&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://mabelkwong.com/2012/11/22/how-i-came-to-see-whiteness-as-just-ordinarily-beautiful/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>22</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f6083943592dcc90560d8d672936d91b?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">themabelkwong</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://themabelkwong.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/img_6476.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_6476</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://themabelkwong.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/img_6480.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_6480</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Power Lines</title>
		<link>http://dutchinaman.wordpress.com/2012/11/22/power-lines/</link>
		<comments>http://dutchinaman.wordpress.com/2012/11/22/power-lines/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2012 10:28:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>dutchinaman</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weekly Journal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chengdu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[china]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ge Honglin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hu Jintao]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jiang Zemin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jiebanren]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Party]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Steven Dorgelo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Xi Jinping]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dutchinaman.wordpress.com/?p=1332</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It’s a routine that goes back for many, many years. You will recognize it each time you visit a Chengdu school, or any school in China for that matter. It’s a routine that brings back long forgotten memories. It’s the routine of lining up; and it is not just at schools.  Lining up -do you [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1332&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://stevendorgelo.zenfolio.com/" target="_blank"><img class="alignleft" style="border:2px solid black;" title="Power Line" alt="" src="http://stevendorgelo.zenfolio.com/img/s4/v67/p1282859530-3.jpg" height="164" width="224" /></a></p>
<p>It’s a routine that goes back for many, many years. You will recognize it each time you visit a Chengdu school, or any school in China for that matter. It’s a routine that brings back long forgotten memories. It’s the routine of lining up; and it is not just at schools. <span id="more-1332"></span></p>
<p>Lining up -do you remember? Who did <em>not</em> have to line up in your younger years, back in the days of black boards, white chalk and stern teachers? Didn’t you have to line up whenever the whole class was leaving the room? There always was a line leader; someone had to be the first and no one liked to be last, right? And somehow, as little kid, you knew that being the first in line was worth a fight.</p>
<p>For most of the line leaders though, reality was hard and the glory short-lived. It always took light years and much teacher-yelling for a line to be formed. But once out of (her) sight, the line dissolved in total anarchy. As splinters of an exploding grenade all kids scattered themselves around the playground, each to their own secret hide-outs and to their own favorite groups.</p>
<p>The importance of lining up doesn’t stop when leaving the school. That is surely true in China, where this remainder of survival-of-the-fittest mentality is an unstoppable internal drive to be the first in line and to be the number one. Competition becomes even more serious in higher-up spheres, reaching a climax in front of the gates of heaven, <i>Tiananmen</i> Square, where the country’s leaders scheme in the <i>Zhongnanhai</i>. And ending the Party&#8217;s 18<sup>th</sup> National Congress last week, a gathering of China&#8217;s most poweful and best connected representatives of faraway provinces, these leaders of China have just formed their own new line with Xi Jinping as line leader. It took months of backstage fighting and stabbing and strategic maneuvering of protégées to form this line. Gone are the days when the current leader could appoint a <i>jiebanren</i>, or “chosen successor.” Now, yesterday&#8217;s leaders are today&#8217;s players: Jiang Zemin, the patriarch that formally left politics 10 years ago but never really said goodbye to the power that came with it, and Hu Jintao, who ruled the last 10 years, were both shouting their own orders and made their last moves in this typical Chinese political chess game, securing positions for their henchmen and through that, securing their own future. Finally, for the few minutes that the line held when they walked on stage, one sixth of the world’s population could see who their new leaders would be for the next decade, and in what ranking order. But unlike the rest of the world that wants thorough background checks of the second and third and fourth and even the last person in this line, most <a title="Common Prosperity" href="http://dutchinaman.wordpress.com/2011/01/15/common-prosperity/" target="_blank">common Chinese</a> don’t really care. For them, Beijing is as far away as Brussels and Strasbourg is for most Europeans. Or Washington for proud Texans.</p>
<p>Do believe me if I say that I was not planning to bother you with yet another political analysis on China that predicts the collapse of this last line of power due to internal fighting and external dissatisfaction. Simply because I know that that won’t happen: Ge Honglin, the mayor of Chengdu, told me so.</p>
<p>This is what happened. Over tea, he reminded me of that old Chinese saying: <i>“The mountains are high and the emperor is far away”</i>. Then he smiled a smile that revealed more than words can say. (Now this sounds as if I often have tea with him, which of course is NOT the case, but it does sound powerful and it makes me feel, for once, in front of the line again.) But I did have tea with him once. Somehow, I was part of a selected group of people that was invited to have tea with the mayor. All powerful men of industry that could and would help Chengdu to new heights and lasting greatness … and me. And so it was.</p>
<p><a href="http://stevendorgelo.zenfolio.com" target="_blank"><img class=" wp-image-1435 alignright" style="border:1px solid black;" title="Hua Cha" alt="" src="http://dutchinaman.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/hua-cha.jpg?w=394&#038;h=283" height="283" width="394" /></a>The teahouse was deep in the tea-producing mountains of Ya-an and we had to drive 2 hours to get there. Surrounded by motorized police we left downtown Chengdu at nine. All drivers were instructed to turn on their blinkers and, when approaching ‘commoners’ (gone are the days that these creatures were called comrades), to use the car horn instead of the brakes. On to the highway we went, in order of importance. First the darkened limousines, with of course the mayor as line leader, then the VIP buses and finally, at the very end, me and some colleagues in our own car. But don’t laugh at me for being at the tail end of the line; at least I was in the line –where were you?</p>
<p>And anyway, after I had assured myself of my value and importance, I was determined not to be at the tail for long. As soon as we hit the highway, we started to overtake the buses. In no time, we were in the middle of the line and at times, we could see the mayor’s car. Right in front of us was an old black VW Santana with tinted windows. I was surprised to see this ancient symbol of power here. For years, Santanas were used by party leaders as a confirmation of their superior status. But that was before Audi came to town. I assumed it was just the tea plantation owner and so we passed him too. Now we were only 5 Audi’s away from the mayor and six cars away from being the first in line. We would have passed the mayor and gone for the front seat, was it not that we reached the end of the highway.</p>
<p>The road became narrow and windy and now, policemen took control. Collectively, we disregarded all traffic rules and <a title="Fine Education" href="http://dutchinaman.wordpress.com/2011/02/12/fine-education/" target="_blank">ignored traffic lights</a>, regardless the color. This was safe: police had cordoned off all side roads hours before. Sharp looking policemen were stationed on every turn of the winding road that lead us up the mountain. Often, on previous trips, I had passed policemen like these standing motionless beside the road, complete with suit and cap and dignity and always with their left hand up in a somewhat demeaning gesture. And always in the middle of nowhere. It was quite intimidating and it used to make me slow down even if I wasn’t speeding, only to discover from up-close that they were dummies. Dusty dummies. But here they were real: no dust and no dignity. At last I understood the lack of real policemen in the rest of the country. The king needs his troops nearby.</p>
<p>In a large open courtyard in front of what once had been a Taoist temple, the mayor was seated, the tea was poured and his speech was ignored. We all knew what he was going to say. Every sentence would be a strategic homage to Beijing and to Hu’s ‘harmonious society’. To sooth the Party&#8217;s new line leader Xi, the mayor will soon adapt his speeches. Not his practices. Beijing–even in these modern days- is far and this king had his own plans. With weak compromises in the <i>Zhongnanhai</i>, local lords can be strong. Mark my words: Chengdu is going to be the center of the Middle Kingdom. Shanghai had done it: ignoring Beijing for years and under Zemin’s protection it returned to the long lost glory. Now it was Chengdu’s turn to be the first in line and provide a <i>jiebanren </i>and be the center of this new century that, mayor Ge is sure, will be the <a title="The Ideal State" href="http://dutchinaman.wordpress.com/2011/08/08/the-ideal-state/" target="_blank">era for the revival of China</a>.</p>
<p>And me, well, I have decided that I might be better off just looking for another line.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1332/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1332/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1332&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://dutchinaman.wordpress.com/2012/11/22/power-lines/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		<georss:point>30.658602 104.064857</georss:point>
		<geo:lat>30.658602</geo:lat>
		<geo:long>104.064857</geo:long>
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/bdd535cc1558bc32d3bbe674b8d1872b?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">dutchinaman</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://stevendorgelo.zenfolio.com/img/s4/v67/p1282859530-3.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Power Line</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dutchinaman.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/hua-cha.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Hua Cha</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Art Blogging vs. Conversational Blogging</title>
		<link>http://righttobitch.com/2012/11/21/art-blogging-vs-conversational-blogging/</link>
		<comments>http://righttobitch.com/2012/11/21/art-blogging-vs-conversational-blogging/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2012 21:43:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Adam S</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tips and tricks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wordpress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://righttobitch.com/?p=986</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[If you’re not tripping over an autograph line of rabid followers of your blog right now, I think I know the reason(s) why.  I know what you&#8217;re thinking, &#8220;sounds kind of uppity coming from someone with less than 200 followers&#8221;.  Don’t worry, I’ll get around to reading this myself too, eventually. Despite being a relative [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=986&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you’re not tripping over an autograph line of rabid followers of your blog right now, I think I know the reason(s) why.  I know what you&#8217;re thinking, &#8220;sounds kind of uppity coming from someone with less than 200 followers&#8221;.  Don’t worry, I’ll get around to reading this myself too, eventually.</p>
<p>Despite being a relative newcomer to the whole scene, to my credit, I’m a fast learner and a close observer of people and their habits.  And hot chicks.  Throughout my travels, I&#8217;ve noticed a lot of <i>stuff</i> that us <a class="zem_slink" title="Blog" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blog" target="_blank" rel="wikipedia">bloggers</a> do which I believe is counterintuitive to acquiring and maintaining a fan base &#8212; providing that this happens to be one of your goals.  That is what you want, isn’t it?  The debate goes on…</p>
<p>Allow me to break down my <a class="zem_slink" title="Eureka effect" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eureka_effect" target="_blank" rel="wikipedia">Eureka moment</a> for you.</p>
<p><strong>Eureka!</strong></p>
<p>The way I see it is that everything you’ll ever come across on a blogging site – regardless of what platform you use &#8212; falls somewhere along a continuum that is anchored by two different stylistic approaches.</p>
<p>At one end of the spectrum  is what I call the <i>Art Blog, </i>which is more or less an exhibit; and the second type is what I call a <i>Conversational Blog</i>, which is used for exactly that &#8212; starting conversations.  It’s difficult to distinguish the two from each other at first glance; however, a quick skim of any blog will reveal the <a class="zem_slink" title="Author" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Author" target="_blank" rel="wikipedia">author</a>&#8216;s motivation for creating his or her content.</p>
<p>Once you become familiar with this concept (that I invented just now), you’ll not only realize where your blog falls along the continuum, you&#8217;ll also understand what areas you may be lacking in.  Hopefully you&#8217;ll be able to increase your following by making the necessary adjustments.  Keep in mind that most blogs fall somewhere between these two styles.  Let&#8217;s delve deeper.</p>
<p>Dorothy, step forward into the world of Technicolor…</p>
<div id="attachment_990" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 255px"><a href="http://righttobitch.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/monet_umbrella2.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-990 " title="Monet_Umbrella" alt="" src="http://righttobitch.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/monet_umbrella2.jpg?w=245&#038;h=300" height="300" width="245" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Wait a second, you mean to tell me the &#8220;T&#8221; in Monet is silent? Did this happen recently?<br />Source: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Claude_Monet_011.jpg">Wikipedia</a></p></div>
<p><b>The Art Blog</b></p>
<p>The majority of posts found on an Art Blog are exactly that &#8212; works of Art.  Compositions are shared for the sole purpose of being observed and appreciated.  <a class="zem_slink" title="Art blog" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Art_blog" target="_blank" rel="wikipedia">Art Blogs</a> are the poets, stream of consciousness writers, story-tellers, comic-strip artists, etc.  Successful Art Blogs usually have a lot of <i>likes</i>, though they normally lack any significant interaction beyond that.  Sometimes, if it’s a particularly great piece, many will drop an appreciative comment, but the conversation abruptly tails off at “<a class="zem_slink" title="Great Comet" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Great_Comet" target="_blank" rel="wikipedia">Great</a> job!”  Really, what else can be said?  Again, whatever was posted was meant to be looked at, not hashed up and down.</p>
<p>Art Blogs are like museums.  When visiting one, the guest usually strolls about casually, looks around, stops, stares, maybe sits for a minute, contemplates, wanders off, and eventually leaves with a sense of appreciation for whatever was on display.  It’s rare to happen upon a conversation during a visit.  It’s not the type of setting that really promotes “mingling” with random strangers.  That’s not to say that it doesn’t happen.  Art lovers talk art, but the displays are usually designed to stir the emotions of the observer on a personal level.  Plus, most pieces are open for wide interpretation – like a mangled ball of steel, for instance.</p>
<p>Writers of Art Blogs are probably aware of what they are already.  They’ve constructed this type of setting for exactly the reasons listed.  Most authors are either content with creating pieces to be appreciated, or use their blog strictly as a medium for online-journaling.  There’s nothing wrong with that.  Many will grow large followings based on their commitment to producing high-quality, artful content.</p>
<p><b> The Conversational Blog</b></p>
<p>On the flip side is the Conversational Blog.  Content found on this type of page is constructed with the intention of promoting interaction with and among readers.  The author usually bases his or her posts on topics that are meant to be viewed by a larger audience by comparison.  Topics can often times be controversial in nature, and/or are emotionally-charged.   A crafty author of one always leaves the piece open-ended by the end.  If executed well, the article will continue to be expanded in the comment section by other readers – <i>engaged</i> readers.  Write that down.  I just wrote it down too.  Wait a second, this is confusing now…</p>
<p>Conversational Blogs also incorporate other bloggers into their posts and/or pages.  They&#8217;re not only excellent networkers, but also good cultivators of friendly &#8220;blog neighborhoods&#8221; (bloggerhoods?  Hmm, I like that…) within the bigger sphere. Inviting guest bloggers and contributors, dual-posting, and reblogging are all tools that they use to help solidify and grow their audiences.   By incorporating these tools and techniques into their pages, they&#8217;re not only promoting themselves, they&#8217;re also practicing good &#8220;<a class="zem_slink" title="Public relations" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Public_relations" target="_blank" rel="wikipedia">PR</a>&#8221; .  By doing so, they increase the likelihood of future interaction with their fan base.</p>
<p>This type of approach doesn’t require a particular format or genre.  Conversational blogs incorporate a wide variety of content.  News, politics, <a class="zem_slink" title="Surreal humour" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Surreal_humour" target="_blank" rel="wikipedia">random humor</a>, medicine – whatever &#8212; the possibilities are endless.  However, the goal is always the same &#8212; to pose or imply questions that elicit responses with the intention of opening a dialogue.</p>
<p>******</p>
<div id="attachment_987" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://righttobitch.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/beavis_and_butt-head-400x3001.gif"><img class="size-medium wp-image-987  " title="Beavis_and_Butt-head-400x300" alt="" src="http://righttobitch.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/beavis_and_butt-head-400x3001.gif?w=300&#038;h=225" height="225" width="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Speaking of great conversationalists&#8230;<br />Source:  <a href="http://villains.wikia.com/wiki/Beavis_and_Butt-head">wikia.com</a>,                                           Characters:  <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Beavis_and_Butt-head">Beavis and Butthead</a></p></div>
<p><strong>Cultivating a <a class="zem_slink" title="Fan (person)" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fan_%28person%29" target="_blank" rel="wikipedia">Fan Base</a></strong></p>
<p>This may come as a surprise to some, but there are a lot of folks out there that want to engage with you.  The challenge is to attract them and build a relationship from there.</p>
<p>When someone takes the time to read through one of your posts, don’t just thank them for the visit, seize the opportunity and speak.  There are some interesting characters out there (like me) that are frothing to spar, share a story, or provide a laugh.  Why pass on an opportunity that you&#8217;ve tried so hard to cultivate?  By going into social-phoebe mode, you’re only setting yourself back and creating more work.</p>
<p>A post a day is difficult to do – especially when nobody’s reading.</p>
<p>When you&#8217;re hopping around and looking for a conversation, you&#8217;ll find that some will oblige, and others will decline.  It’s worth a shot either way.  After all, growing a following is based not only on consistently producing interesting content, it’s also about being likable.   Charming is the word I prefer.</p>
<p>People are smart enough to pick up on sincerity, despite the fact that many operate through a persona.  They also know whether you appreciate them or not, and it’s up to you to convey that.</p>
<p><strong>More Free Tips </strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Shtick &#8216;em Up</strong> &#8211; Most bloggers have a shtick. If you&#8217;re one of them, ask yourself if it&#8217;s a concept that will limit your writing, long-term.  Personally, I consider this question daily.  I may be limiting myself in the long-run.  Don&#8217;t place limitations on your blog.  It&#8217;s hard enough as it is.  Variety is the spice of life, or something like that&#8230;</li>
<li><strong>Good Writing vs. Good Blogging</strong> &#8211; Being an excellent writer is one thing.  Being an excellent blogger is something different all together.  Consider this article.  Where do you fall within the spectrum?  Have your efforts been fruitful?  Again, ask yourself if what you write about is something that an audience would want to engage in.</li>
<li><strong><strong>Brevity is Key</strong> &#8211; </strong>There&#8217;s nothing that deters me as a reader more than an extremely lengthy post.  I think I speak for most when I say this, but I don&#8217;t want to read a three thousand word submission.  Ever.  I hate books, and three thousand words is getting close to a book.   Succinct and effective is the key.  Get to the point, make it a good one.</li>
<li><strong>Quality, Not Quantity</strong> &#8211; If you&#8217;re in a hurry to post something daily, you might want to consider not only how it affects the quality of your content, but also how your audience is reacting to the frequency of your posts.  With so many blogs out there, and with each of us following our fair share of them, it&#8217;s likely that most followers aren&#8217;t reading your stuff on a daily basis &#8212; unless it&#8217;s top-shelf, every day.  It takes a lot of time to be a &#8220;follower&#8221;.  Being mindful of that, it&#8217;s safe to assume that most people are selective about what they read.  Also remember, it takes time to produce something high-quality, even if it&#8217;s only a thousand words.  Be selective.  Otherwise, you might not only burn yourself out,  you&#8217;ll also burn your audience out too.</li>
</ul>
<p>Hopefully you&#8217;ll  find this article useful.  If you&#8217;re like myself, you&#8217;re always looking for ways to improve your stuff.  Interacting with an audience can be just as fulfilling as the writing part.    So, considering all this begs the question:</p>
<p><strong>Are you the Curator of an Art Blog or the Mediator of a Conversational Blog?</strong></p>
<p>Let&#8217;s get this party started&#8230;</p>
<h6 class="zemanta-related-title" style="font-size:1em;">Related articles</h6>
<ul class="zemanta-article-ul">
<li class="zemanta-article-ul-li"><a href="http://www.zemanta.com/blog/the-art-of-writing-blog-comments/" target="_blank">The Art of Writing Blog Comments</a> (zemanta.com)</li>
<li class="zemanta-article-ul-li"><a href="http://clownonfire.wordpress.com/2012/11/01/zen-and-the-art-of-blogging/" target="_blank">Zen and the Art of Blogging</a> (clownonfire.wordpress.com)</li>
<li class="zemanta-article-ul-li"><a href="http://mokshis.com/writing-persuasive-blog-entries-greater-roi-tips/" target="_blank">Art of Writing Persuasive Blog Entries for Greater ROI</a> (mokshis.com)</li>
</ul>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/986/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/986/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=986&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://righttobitch.com/2012/11/21/art-blogging-vs-conversational-blogging/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>144</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/8ec1b3c8aa2034586e16c3ae17fe8972?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=R" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">righttobitch</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://righttobitch.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/monet_umbrella2.jpg?w=245" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Monet_Umbrella</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://righttobitch.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/beavis_and_butt-head-400x3001.gif?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Beavis_and_Butt-head-400x300</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Movie Emergencies</title>
		<link>http://brittawrites.com/2012/11/21/movie-emergencies/</link>
		<comments>http://brittawrites.com/2012/11/21/movie-emergencies/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2012 18:05:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>brittawrites</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Britta Watches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Antichrist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[film essay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Iron Man]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Movie Emergencies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Shining]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brittawrites.com/?p=435</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Does anyone else know the feeling I&#8217;m talking about? Where you absolutely must talk about a movie Right Now or go insane? That, to me, is a movie emergency. I coined the phrase (or perhaps unconsciously stole the phrase, if it existed before) immediately after watching Antichrist by Lars von Trier. It wasn&#8217;t that I [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=435&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Does anyone else know the feeling I&#8217;m talking about? Where you absolutely must talk about a movie Right Now or go insane? That, to me, is a movie emergency.</p>
<p>I coined the phrase (or perhaps unconsciously stole the phrase, if it existed before) immediately after watching <em>Antichrist</em> by Lars von Trier. It wasn&#8217;t that I was excessively disturbed by the film, or even that I was shocked by it, just that I had to talk to someone about it, preferably immediately and in excruciating detail. I texted my movie friends and told them that I needed to talk about <em>Antichrist </em>right away. It was a film emergency.</p>
<div id="attachment_436" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 539px"><a href="http://brittawrites.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/willem-dafoe-antichrist-tree.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-436" title="Willem Dafoe Antichrist tree" alt="Antichrist von trier" src="http://brittawrites.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/willem-dafoe-antichrist-tree.jpg?w=590"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Who wouldn&#8217;t want to dissect this in excruciating detail?</p></div>
<p>There&#8217;s a sort of catharsis that has to ocurr after a Film Emergency. The well-up of opinions, tension, desire, fear and pure insane <em>emotion</em> during certain films has to come out somehow. I have so many thoughts rushing through my agonizingly-slow brain that I have to exorcise them or threaten submersion.</p>
<p>A lot has been written by people much smarter than me about film&#8217;s communal aspect. It&#8217;s something we experience collectively&#8211; whether literally (in a movie theater) or symbolically (in that we all see the same movie, largely regardless of time and space). It gives us a language and a set of symbols to be agonizingly decoded&#8211; a way of speaking to one another through memories. &#8220;Do you remember when . . . ?&#8221; &#8220;What about . . . ?&#8221; &#8220;What did you think of . . . ?&#8221;</p>
<p>Films inspire such deep, intense, and overall <em>unfufilled </em>emotions within us. It&#8217;s why people buy the t-shirts and the action figures, write the fan-fiction and the RPs, go to conventions and get tattoos. These are all expressions of the unfufilled emotions that film leaves in us, a reliving of the experience of being so excited, so enraptured. Everytime I talk about a movie with someone, it&#8217;s reliving the experience of seeing it for the first time, an adrenaline rush that can never be re-experienced in full.</p>
<div id="attachment_447" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 426px"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/lilyrollins/2997718332/"><img class=" wp-image-447 " title="The shining twins costume" alt="" src="http://brittawrites.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/the-shining-twins-costume.png?w=416&#038;h=511" height="511" width="416" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Some people also (awesomely) force their children to relive movies.</p></div>
<p>Art has, more or less, always been a communal experience&#8211; it&#8217;s a pretty small leap from the Salons of France in the mid 16th century to a Sex Pistol&#8217;s concert in England in 1977. But film offers us something unique in its communal experience&#8211; it&#8217;s no more a purely-intellectual memory than it is a purely emotional rush. It hooks itself up directly to our brain, burrowing inside like an alien tentacle and rewiring our experience to feed our mind directly. We&#8217;re force fed images and sounds and phrases slightly faster than our brain can process and some of the exhiliration comes from just trying to keep up.</p>
<p>When you watch the film again, you don&#8217;t get that same experience. It&#8217;s a new experience, a completely different one, where we are not molested by images and sounds but are instead seeking them, uncovering the things we may have missed last time. We&#8217;re taking a walk through the move landscape and upturning tables and houseplants, trying to find new little morsels of food to munch on. The characters go on around us and restless eyes jump from faces to doors as we anticipate an action.</p>
<div id="attachment_450" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 539px"><a href="http://www.tested.com/tech/1851-how-filmmakers-manipulate-you-by-tracking-your-gaze/"><img class=" wp-image-450" title="eye tracking in a movie" alt="Eye-tracking study for There Will Be Blood" src="http://brittawrites.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/eye-tracking-in-a-movie.jpg?w=529&#038;h=264" height="264" width="529" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Eye-tracking study for There Will Be Blood that shows where audience&#8217;s restless attention is drawn</p></div>
<p>Film does not offer more information than other art forms, but instead intensely condenses information. Perhaps our Move Emergencies are ways of sifting through and pulling apart this information, volleying it off others and sparring for their dissections as well. It&#8217;s as if film dumps a great, tangled ball into our collective laps and we must pull it apart piece by piece afterwards.</p>
<p>This is ultimately the great joy and great frustration of film. We all have to play coroner and dissect it, analyzing what made us feel a certain way (good or bad). Was it the dramatic setting? Was it the well-known star with the personal baggage? Was it that one climactic moment we relive again and again?</p>
<div id="attachment_451" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 539px"><a href="http://brittawrites.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/iron-man-jericho.png"><img class="size-full wp-image-451" title="Iron Man jericho" alt="Iron Man Jericho" src="http://brittawrites.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/iron-man-jericho.png?w=590"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">All of the above?</p></div>
<p>Whatever the pleasure we derive from reliving film, in intense bursts or over the course of a lifetime, the greatest moment of realization for me is that I will be able to think about this film and find something new. Who knows where the element of Emergency comes in&#8211; maybe that&#8217;s just pure impatience&#8211; but when anything arouses that level of inspection and reflection, I thank the movie gods.</p>
<p>And on a very related note, I have so many things to say about <em>Alien</em>. Be on the lookout.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/435/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/435/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=435&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://brittawrites.com/2012/11/21/movie-emergencies/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>37</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://brittawrites.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/antichrist-beggars.png?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://brittawrites.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/antichrist-beggars.png?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Antichrist beggars</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c5f23e6119b9be8745a283c3894db8e9?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">brittawrites</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://brittawrites.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/willem-dafoe-antichrist-tree.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Willem Dafoe Antichrist tree</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://brittawrites.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/the-shining-twins-costume.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The shining twins costume</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://brittawrites.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/eye-tracking-in-a-movie.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">eye tracking in a movie</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://brittawrites.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/iron-man-jericho.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Iron Man jericho</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>It Isn’t That Bad, Guys&#8230;</title>
		<link>http://isharacomix.org/2012/11/21/it-isnt-that-bad-guys/</link>
		<comments>http://isharacomix.org/2012/11/21/it-isnt-that-bad-guys/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2012 18:15:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Barry Peddycord III</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Graduate Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[academia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grad school]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[phd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[socializing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://isharacomix.org/?p=1732</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[So apparently this blog entry got Freshly Pressed! I&#8217;ll be honest, I had some mixed feelings about this article being the one to get hit by the spotlight. It&#8217;s an important article, but it really doesn&#8217;t serve as a representative sample of what I write about. I&#8217;ve selected a few others that may provide a [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1732&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>So apparently this blog entry got <a href="https://wordpress.com/#!/fresh/">Freshly Pressed</a>! I&#8217;ll be honest, I had some mixed feelings about this article being the one to get hit by the spotlight. It&#8217;s an important article, but it really doesn&#8217;t serve as a representative sample of what I write about. I&#8217;ve <a href="http://isharacomix.org/2012/08/29/lets-raise-the-bar/">selected</a> <a href="http://isharacomix.org/2012/09/15/i-may-be-a-closet-humanities-major/">a few</a> <a href="http://isharacomix.org/2012/11/12/taking-part-in-a-virtual-discussion/">others</a> that may provide a more well-rounded view of who I am and what I do. If you&#8217;re new, welcome aboard! I hope you enjoy the ride!</em></p>
<p>#phdchat is a Twitter chat session that is held on Wednesdays at 19:30 GMT (which is like 14:30 in the afternoon for me) for scholars to discuss theses, dissertations, and research, and while I&#8217;ve been following it for months, it happened to occur while I was available to interact on my feed, so I decided to join in on the topic of &#8220;how do you know when a dissertation is done&#8221;? Being a fan of considering the Ph.D. as process of developing self-regulation and metacognition, my immediate response is that finding the answer to that question is one of learning objectives of the doctoral program itself. As <a href="http://www.csc.ncsu.edu/people/tmbarnes">Dr. Tiffany Barnes</a> (sitting right next to me at the time) said: &#8220;If you&#8217;re asking that question, you aren&#8217;t there yet.&#8221; <span id="more-1732"></span></p>
<p>I was following the chat, half-engaged while working on a project, when I noticed a tweet by <a href="http://twitter.com/Comprof1">@Comprof1</a> that I absolutely had to respond to:</p>
<blockquote><p>@EmmaBurnettx @lizith @ajwooff @NSRiazat Midway is when you realize this isn&#8217;t &#8220;your&#8221; thesis, but your work approved by others. #phdchat</p></blockquote>
<p>If you know me, you know that taking ownership of one&#8217;s research is a huge part of my philosophy on Graduate education and a life of research in general. I wanted to reply by saying that it was a very sad and depressing way to view the thesis-writing process&#8230; but something made me stop in my tracks.</p>
<p>This blog entry isn&#8217;t about my philosophy of taking ownership of your work. It&#8217;s about how when I read my very sincere reply, it didn&#8217;t look very sincere. In fact, it felt like I was reading one of the self-deprecating jokes that make up a large bulk of Graduate Student culture. I was genuinely worried that what I was writing would not be taken seriously, and restructured my reply so that it better represented how I felt. Why would I feel that way?</p>
<p>This &#8220;humor&#8221;, if you can really call it that, is something that is prevalent among Graduate Students. We poke fun at ourselves for choosing a &#8220;life of poverty&#8221;. We bemoan spending &#8220;far too long&#8221; in Universities doing research that nobody cares about with adversarial advisors that work us to the bone. I&#8217;ve been there, I&#8217;ve <a href="http://phdcomics.com/">read the comics</a>, and I&#8217;ve probably engaged in some of that in my blog. But when I do, it&#8217;s just a joke, because I could not be happier or <em>more proud of myself</em> for choosing the career I&#8217;ve chosen. That much should be apparent from the tone of this blog. Some of my colleagues make fun of me for being as positive about my research as I am: they tell me I&#8217;m trying too hard, that I&#8217;m young and naive, and that one day I&#8217;ll realize that I&#8217;m wrong. My first issue with that is that it&#8217;s only <em>self</em>-deprecating when you are making fun of yourself &#8211; don&#8217;t rain on my parade, guys. But even more troubling is that it makes me wonder <em>to what extent do Graduate students believe this stuff</em>, and <em>how do others perceive us when this is our attitude</em>?</p>
<p>I understand that the reason why self-deprecating humor is so prevalent is because it builds a sense of solidarity. When we&#8217;re beat down and exhausted, it&#8217;s encouraging to see that we aren&#8217;t the only ones going through our troubles. The Ph.D. can be a lonely path where even our colleagues have trouble understanding what we do each day. However, we&#8217;ve all had to put up with frustrating departmental policies, absent-minded advisors, and long nights in the lab. The suffering essentially becomes the common ground between us, no matter our disciplines. The problem is that while it produces solidarity between <em>us</em>, it makes us harder to relate to with the rest of society &#8211; the people who will supposedly benefit from the research that we are doing. It makes us inaccessible to the non-academic.</p>
<p>Is this attitude really how we want to be perceived?</p>
<p>We, as Grad Students, are the driving forces behind many of the scientific advancements in this world. Our work is moving mountains and changing lives. The common ground between us should not be the hard times that come and go, but the passion for our field that makes us stay with it <em>in spite</em> of the difficulties.</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://isharacomix.org/category/graduate-life/'>Graduate Life</a> Tagged: <a href='http://isharacomix.org/tag/academia/'>academia</a>, <a href='http://isharacomix.org/tag/culture/'>culture</a>, <a href='http://isharacomix.org/tag/grad-school/'>grad school</a>, <a href='http://isharacomix.org/tag/life/'>life</a>, <a href='http://isharacomix.org/tag/phd/'>phd</a>, <a href='http://isharacomix.org/tag/socializing/'>socializing</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1732/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1732/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1732&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://isharacomix.org/2012/11/21/it-isnt-that-bad-guys/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>28</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/39aa2aa615ea1d30d79a37f4557f1e0e?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">isharacomix</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Where the Guys Give Roses</title>
		<link>http://hotpotdc.wordpress.com/2012/11/21/where-the-guys-give-roses/</link>
		<comments>http://hotpotdc.wordpress.com/2012/11/21/where-the-guys-give-roses/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2012 17:18:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dani</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thoughts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[early morning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flowers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Indian market]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[market]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mehrauli flower market]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new delhi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[off the beaten path]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Qutab Minar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[real Delhi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[roses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tourism]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://hotpotdc.wordpress.com/?p=6034</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[An early morning trip to the flower market shows why sometimes the guide books don't know everything.<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=6034&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a title="Mehrauli Flower Market_MG_2588November 19, 2012 by dani920, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/danidumm/8205421547/"><img alt="Mehrauli Flower Market_MG_2588November 19, 2012" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8480/8205421547_5d29fd7a19_c.jpg" height="534" width="800" /></a></p>
<p><em>This is a bit of a sleep-deprived post so apologies for any strange errors or abrupt transitions&#8230;busy week to share hopefully soon.</em></p>
<p>The sunrise in Delhi is something worth getting up early for. It&#8217;s winter now in Northern India and the sun rises after 6:30 and seems to stop and hang half-way up the horizon. It takes up so much space in the sky that it&#8217;s hard to believe its the same sun with which I&#8217;ve risen my whole life.  It shimmers in an arresting shade of reddish-gold and makes everything the light touches appears washed in a hazy, soft pink glow.</p>
<p><a title="Mehrauli Flower Market_MG_2597November 19, 2012 by dani920, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/danidumm/8206507384/"><img alt="Mehrauli Flower Market_MG_2597November 19, 2012" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8058/8206507384_c230b92176_c.jpg" height="534" width="800" /></a></p>
<p>This morning we set out far earlier than usual, in search of a supposedly stunning wholesale flower market open only just past dawn at the Hanuman Temple near Connaught. For anyone who&#8217;d like to cut to the chase, I&#8217;ll tell you now: that market no longer seems to exist.</p>
<p>A man sitting on a blanket surrounded by pairs of shoes asked me to remove mine as soon as I stepped off the sidewalk-a sign as sure as any that I was in the wrong place.  I walked barefoot through the temple crowd anyway though, carrying 15-month-old Will and his companion, &#8220;Monkey,&#8221; hoping in vain that the flower market might be found somewhere just beyond the worshippers.  I bought a wreath for the temple and wondered which of the beggars, who turn out in the hundreds here to receive free food and donations from temple parishioners, needed my money the most. I felt out of place and confused. As I tried to collect my shoes from the shoe watcher, a tall man with wearing a mangey shawl and vacant eyes came lurching after us yelling, reaching for Will and demanding money. People shouted for me to give him money, to not give him money, to give <em>them </em>money and suddenly everyone was watching a bewildered foreigner handing out rupees like they were flyers for a new high-rise apartment complex in Gurgaon.  I beat an embarrassed retreat back to our car, realizing suddenly that this might be exactly the sort of Indian experience that makes some people hate it here.</p>
<p>The truth about India though, the truth about any country really, is that you will only like the place as much as you like the people there whom you are lucky enough to meet.  And, contrary to what it might seem to any tourist trying to make their way around Connaught, there are far many more good people in Delhi than not.</p>
<p><a title="Mehrauli Flower Market_MG_2603November 19, 2012 by dani920, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/danidumm/8205416691/"><img alt="Mehrauli Flower Market_MG_2603November 19, 2012" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8349/8205416691_ed8c60259e_c.jpg" height="800" width="525" /></a></p>
<p><a title="Mehrauli Flower Market_MG_2590November 19, 2012 by dani920, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/danidumm/8205419307/"><img alt="Mehrauli Flower Market_MG_2590November 19, 2012" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8341/8205419307_a14ec55f18_c.jpg" height="800" width="520" /></a></p>
<p>Our new driver is one of them.  Chris and I realized that if we really wanted to see Delhi we would need not just a vehicle with which to get around, but a person with an inborn understanding of Delhi to drive it (and, quite honestly, someone to circle the block wherever we go because parking is usually quite scarce).  R is our housekeeper&#8217;s nephew and when she talks about him, her love and admiration for him practically radiates out of her face.  We are beginning to understand why.</p>
<p>R is one of those good-down-to-his-bones sorts of people and he&#8217;s also slowly getting used to me and my little quests around town. When I came back to the car without finding a flower market, he asked if I would like to drive clear across the city to find a flower market near Mehrauli that one of his friends had told him about.  He laughed a little knowingly when I said yes.</p>
<p>About 5 minutes away from Qutab Minar (still on my list to go see) and in the middle of a seemingly quiet neighborhood, we parked next to a cluster of scooters, the passengers&#8217; seats all piled 3 feet high with stacks of  bundled stems and maroon and gold marigolds.</p>
<p><a title="Mehrauli Flower Market_MG_2583November 19, 2012 by dani920, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/danidumm/8205423877/"><img alt="Mehrauli Flower Market_MG_2583November 19, 2012" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8339/8205423877_678c915b0d_c.jpg" height="534" width="800" /></a></p>
<p>From there I edge my way through the crowd and found myself in an open-air market, surrounded on all sides by the walls of restaurants and apartment buildings. Cast-off leaves and foliage bedded the ground in soft piles and a million and one rose petals buried the normal din and noise of a busy market beneath the whisper-soft sounds of so many flowers being bundled and moved around the small space.   Hundreds of thousands of lilies and roses and daisies, ginger flowers, gladiolas and so many flowers I&#8217;d never seen before lined the tiny walkways between vendors.  Along the walls, on a raised platform, women sat wrapped in heavy woolen shawls, delicately stringing marigolds and jasmine blossoms together to form the long beautiful chains that are used here to decorate temples and special occasions. When I lived in Chennai, women would buy miniature versions of these flower chains and wear them in their hair, leaving behind a trail of otherworldly fragrance that banished all sewer and street smells in their wake.</p>
<p><a title="Mehrauli Flower Market_MG_2586November 19, 2012 by dani920, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/danidumm/8205422633/"><img alt="Mehrauli Flower Market_MG_2586November 19, 2012" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8060/8205422633_e4f423dbc9_c.jpg" height="530" width="800" /></a></p>
<p>The haze and the smell of the flowers and that beautiful golden-blush glow from the sunrise made the market feel more like a dream than a real place and Will and I both smiled.  As I wandered, vendors rummaged through their piles of orphan blossoms and, beaming, offered carefully de-thorned rose blossoms to Will and I.  When I asked how much I should pay, they just shook their heads, said something about smiles and walked away.</p>
<p>Markets are interesting to me, I get a kick out of seeing how they work, what&#8217;s for sale, how to pronounce what&#8217;s for sale, how it should be cooked or used or displayed.  I find that whenever I&#8217;m genuinely excited, genuinely fascinated by what&#8217;s going on around me, people respond in kind and share with me small tidbits about themselves and the places in which I meet them. These little interactions are grounding.  Like tiny threads,  each one of them gently ties me a little closer to Delhi, tugging me&#8211;if only briefly&#8211;out of the expat bubble I usually inhabit.</p>
<p><a title="Mehrauli Flower Market_MG_2609November 19, 2012 by dani920, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/danidumm/8206504020/"><img alt="Mehrauli Flower Market_MG_2609November 19, 2012" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8069/8206504020_6cc3783875_c.jpg" height="534" width="800" /></a></p>
<p>We left the flower market with 2 dozen jasmine flowers and 7 rolls of something like tissue paper&#8211;an item I&#8217;d been desperately trying to find in Delhi for weeks and weeks now and finally found for sale amidst the flowers.  Afterwards we headed to INA market to pick up a few things for Thanksgiving.</p>
<p>The INA parking lot is crazy at most hours of the day. Usually R drops me off and circles the block while I bumble and blunder my way across the slick, broken tiles to find what I need. But two freshly-slaughtered chickens and a big bag of flour, plus Will in his baby carrier, is a bit much for even me to carry by myself; and since the market was still nearly empty so early in the morning, R parked and came with me.</p>
<p>And that&#8217;s the other thing about needing to know good people to really fall in love with a country. No matter how good I get at navigating that market, I&#8217;ll never be a native Dillite&#8211;and it&#8217;s a completely different experience to go with someone who is. The interactions are smoother, we visit specific stalls purposefully, seemingly picking our vendors based on cues of quality or relation that are invisible to me.  I learn a lot.</p>
<p>I ran into the chai-wallah from <a href="http://hotpotdc.wordpress.com/2012/10/28/early-morning-at-ina-market/">this post</a> while we were buying some flour. He remembered me and offered another 10 rupee cup of chai from his traveling tankard of brew.  The shopkeepers all laughed, but I bought.  It&#8217;s not everyday that I&#8217;m at the market with a free hand to wrap around a steaming styrofoam mug of chai and in the company of good people with whom to share it.</p>
<p><a title="Mehrauli Flower Market_MG_2612November 19, 2012 by dani920, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/danidumm/8206502886/"><img alt="Mehrauli Flower Market_MG_2612November 19, 2012" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8208/8206502886_049b0fef1b_c.jpg" height="800" width="534" /></a></p>
<p><a title="Mehrauli Flower Market_MG_2605November 19, 2012 by dani920, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/danidumm/8206505114/"><img alt="Mehrauli Flower Market_MG_2605November 19, 2012" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8487/8206505114_611a07e061_c.jpg" height="534" width="800" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/6034/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/6034/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=6034&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://hotpotdc.wordpress.com/2012/11/21/where-the-guys-give-roses/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>48</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://hotpotdc.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/mehrauli-flower-market_mg_2605november-19-2012-e1353516742101.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://hotpotdc.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/mehrauli-flower-market_mg_2605november-19-2012-e1353516742101.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mehrauli Flower Market_MG_2605November 19, 2012</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/41f5a1dccaef8fd7e93fcc1d3aa50452?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">danichris8</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8480/8205421547_5d29fd7a19_c.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mehrauli Flower Market_MG_2588November 19, 2012</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8058/8206507384_c230b92176_c.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mehrauli Flower Market_MG_2597November 19, 2012</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8349/8205416691_ed8c60259e_c.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mehrauli Flower Market_MG_2603November 19, 2012</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8341/8205419307_a14ec55f18_c.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mehrauli Flower Market_MG_2590November 19, 2012</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8339/8205423877_678c915b0d_c.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mehrauli Flower Market_MG_2583November 19, 2012</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8060/8205422633_e4f423dbc9_c.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mehrauli Flower Market_MG_2586November 19, 2012</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8069/8206504020_6cc3783875_c.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mehrauli Flower Market_MG_2609November 19, 2012</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8208/8206502886_049b0fef1b_c.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mehrauli Flower Market_MG_2612November 19, 2012</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8487/8206505114_611a07e061_c.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mehrauli Flower Market_MG_2605November 19, 2012</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Potentially Last Ever Blog Post</title>
		<link>http://happyflowerwordzoo002.wordpress.com/2012/11/21/the-potentially-last-ever-blog-post/</link>
		<comments>http://happyflowerwordzoo002.wordpress.com/2012/11/21/the-potentially-last-ever-blog-post/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2012 19:19:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>happyflowerwordzoo002</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Angst]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Postaday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[short story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WP Daily Post]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funny Maybe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Language Arts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Musing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Word Press Daily Prompt]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://happyflowerwordzoo002.wordpress.com/?p=1443</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The Final Last Words Ever I knew my kidnappers had arrived at a decision when I heard their few words between the grunts and the slurping at their coffees. &#8216;She knows too much.&#8217; &#8216;We&#8217;ll have to bury the body deep.&#8217; &#8216;That son is a piece of trash.&#8217; &#8216;A mistake to wait longer.&#8217; The rich smell [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1443&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://happyflowerwordzoo002.wordpress.com/2012/11/21/the-potentially-last-ever-blog-post/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>18</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/8c25abb897fc550953171758476252fa?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">happyflowerwordzoo002</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Kitty Hawk</title>
		<link>http://adelpheans.wordpress.com/2012/11/19/kitty-hawk/</link>
		<comments>http://adelpheans.wordpress.com/2012/11/19/kitty-hawk/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2012 23:52:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Gemma Kaneko</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Arts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prose]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flash fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://adelpheans.wordpress.com/?p=677</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I am poised for the greatest achievement of my life. It, of course, will be followed by many more. I will probably be a quarterback (even though I’m getting a late start, because I’m not tall enough for the team yet), or a judo instructor, or at least a scientist who cures cancers and invents [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=677&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I am poised for the greatest achievement of my life. It, of course, will be followed by many more. I will probably be a quarterback (even though I’m getting a late start, because I’m not tall enough for the team yet), or a judo instructor, or at least a scientist who cures cancers and invents the hoverboard, but <i>for real</i>. But those are for later. Those are for when I am living in California in a big house all by myself, watching brush fires from my swimming pool (I saw it on Discovery because I thought it was Shark Week, and even though it wasn’t, it was still cool).</p>
<p>Now, I am getting ready. I am preparing myself with great calm. This takes patience (which apparently I’m not very good at, says Mom and Mrs. Thomacelli, and EVERYONE), this takes stillness (something else I’m not very good at). I had to do a lot to get here. First, I had to make sure the way was clear, like runways at airports. One time, when we were flying to this beach in Mexico, we had to wait in the plane for two extra hours because there was a deer on the runway. We got there really late but that was actually more fun. The streets were noisy and crowded, the air was dark and blurry, but I didn’t even need to hold anyone’s hand. We ate churros on the way to the hotel, and I got cinnamon all over my shirt. I’m planning on going back very soon, maybe even next week, if this all works out.</p>
<p>After I made a clear path, I had to climb up into the fort. It’s not really hard – there are stairs and everything – but I had to get a really good spot. That means getting on top of the rails, and that is a lot harder. I wore my good sneakers on purpose. They’re new, probably cooler than anyone else’s, even if they don’t have lights in them. They got me here, so when I’m famous, I’ll definitely endorse Nike. I’ll even be in their commercials for free, as long as I get new shoes every year.</p>
<p>Now, I am standing here, on top of the railing, taking deep breaths. I know about bone density (Mrs. Thomacelli made us color pictures of the insides of birds in science), but I think that my bones aren’t too dense yet. After all, I’m not allowed on most roller coasters, so they’re probably not fully developed. Besides, I made a parachute, just in case. That’s safety.</p>
<p>I take a breath. I let it out, just like in judo. I brush the band-aids on my knees, remembering the last time, remembering the woodchips in my mouth and the Tootsie Pop I got in the office. This time, I won’t need them.</p>
<p>I take a breath. I let it out, making sure to focus all my energy, just like mom does in yoga. I flex my toes, tight in my new sneakers. Maybe Nike will make shoes with little wings on the sides, and my name will be all over the laces.</p>
<p>You know, people keep telling me I’m too old for this, and that come on Ray, you should know better by now. But I think that the reason that people say that is because they’re afraid that I’ll be able to do it. When they were little (and they had light bones) they didn’t practice hard enough and they were too scared of getting skinned knees.</p>
<p>I take a breath. I let it out, just like when dad told me not to be afraid when the plane took off. I forgot to bring gum, but it’s okay because ears only pop inside airplanes. He will be so proud of me, and next time, he’ll bring his video camera and we can watch it after my Saturday soccer game.</p>
<p>The last time, I really felt it, but only for a little bit. It was a big rush of air and my heart was bouncing up and down in my chest and then it all stopped. That’s how I know I’m getting closer. That’s how I know.</p>
<p>I take a deep breath. I let it out.</p>
<p>I take off.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/677/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/677/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=677&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://adelpheans.wordpress.com/2012/11/19/kitty-hawk/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>17</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://adelpheans.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/boyrunninginfield.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://adelpheans.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/boyrunninginfield.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">running boy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/97d585cfed4faf8b57cabb5f730234bd?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gemmakaneko</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Walkways, Finished</title>
		<link>http://shariblaukopf.com/2012/11/21/walkways-finished/</link>
		<comments>http://shariblaukopf.com/2012/11/21/walkways-finished/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2012 17:56:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Shari Blaukopf</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://shariblaukopf.com/?p=2329</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There was a great debate in the comments section of yesterday&#8217;s sketch about the educational value of posting an unfinished or unsuccessful work. I was very torn about what to do, but in the end the teacher in me won out. A few days ago I started this street scene but never completed it. My [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2329&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There was a great debate in the comments section of yesterday&#8217;s sketch about the educational value of posting an unfinished or unsuccessful work. I was very torn about what to do, but in the end the teacher in me won out.</p>
<p>A few days ago I started this street scene but never completed it. My first wash was wet-on-dry and I wasn&#8217;t very satisfied so I tried to wash it out and paint wet-in-wet. This turned out to be a disaster because the pigment I had used in the sky stained the paper. My intention was to have a gray mix in the upper right corner but when I attempted to rinse it, the blue washed away and I was left with a horrible brown stain in the sky. No matter. I persisted to add colour but the underpainting gave a dirty glow to everything. I abandoned mid-way through.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">
<p style="text-align:center;">
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://shariblaukopf.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/walkways_unfinished.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-2331" title="Walkways_unfinished" alt="Walkways_unfinished" src="http://shariblaukopf.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/walkways_unfinished.jpg?w=472&#038;h=343" height="343" width="472" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:left;"> A few days later I made a colour sketch to clarify the direction I was going to take and posted that yesterday. Below is the finished painting. This time I chose a 300lb Winsor Newton paper and proceeded with caution. It is easy to get overly excited when you are starting a painting and jump right into adding colour to the paper. But in this case, planning the values first and the colours second helped me to know where I was going.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://shariblaukopf.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/walkways1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2333" title="Walkways" alt="Walkways" src="http://shariblaukopf.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/walkways1.jpg?w=590&#038;h=483" height="483" width="590" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2329/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2329/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2329&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://shariblaukopf.com/2012/11/21/walkways-finished/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>67</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/5045f21d6aa553668c7d6fba46e42823?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">rondosblaukopf</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://shariblaukopf.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/walkways_unfinished.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Walkways_unfinished</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://shariblaukopf.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/walkways1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Walkways</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>