<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2012 22:02:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Post Challenge: Telepathy Not Required</title>
		<link>http://jenami.wordpress.com/2012/09/13/telepathy-not-required/</link>
		<comments>http://jenami.wordpress.com/2012/09/13/telepathy-not-required/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2012 14:59:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>jenami</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amwriting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPchallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stephen king]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://jenami.wordpress.com/?p=131</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Looking back on my childhood reading habits, I realize that I was a terrible “girl.” As a young lassie growing up in the 80s, I should have gone to Beverly Cleary Elementary, moved on to Judy Blume Middle School, and graduated with honors from Sweet Valley High. (Full disclosure: I did read these authors. I [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=131&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Looking back on my childhood reading habits, I realize that I was a terrible “girl.” As a young lassie growing up in the 80s, I should have gone to Beverly Cleary Elementary, moved on to Judy Blume Middle School, and graduated with honors from Sweet Valley High. (Full disclosure: I did read these authors. I read just about everything I could get my hands on.) But none of them spoke to me, inspired me to write. When I grew up, I wanted to write like Stephen King.</p>
<p>Stephen King is not a purveyor of  fine “literature.” <a href="http://en.wikiquote.org/wiki/Talk:Stephen_King" target="_blank">He’ll tell you so himself</a>. Fancy prose and valuable life lessons are not the point (though there are some mini philosophy lessons woven into his tales if you’re paying attention.)</p>
<p>The reason I relate to his stories? Psychology. Inner voice. Often it’s more about what his characters <em>don’t</em> say than what they do. Thanks to italics, we’re privy to what they think: what’s motivating the girl chained to the bed, or the dad trying to save his son from the monsters that have overrun the supermarket. It’s why most Stephen King movies, honestly, kind of suck. Because what makes his books scary is about the insanity within.</p>
<p>I relate to this. When I can’t sleep at night, it’s the thoughts running through my head that keep me from dozing. During the daylight hours, it’s having to quell the impulse to do something utterly irrational that makes me wonder if I’m crazy. And it’s scary as hell.</p>
<p>An example, if you will indulge me.</p>
<p>Beverly Marsh, one of the characters in <em>It</em>, suffered sexual abuse at the hands of her father. He excuses his behavior by telling her he’s just “worried about her.” Bevvie’s mother is no fool &#8211; she knows something’s not quite right in her little domestic circle, but she’s not ready to confront it. In this excerpt, Beverly is also awakening to the fact that her father’s concern for her is more than just paternal love.</p>
<blockquote><p>“Bevvie, does he ever touch you?”</p>
<p>“What” Beverly looked at her mother, totally perplexed. God, her father touched her every <em>day</em>. “I don’t get what you -”</p>
<p>“Never mind,” Elfrida said shortly. “Don’t forget the trash. And if those windows are streaked, you won’t need your <em>father</em> to give you blue devil.”</p>
<p>“I won’t</p>
<p>(<em>does he ever touch you</em>)</p>
<p>forget.”</p>
<p>“And be in before dark.”</p>
<p>“I will.”</p>
<p><em>(does he)</em></p>
<p><em>(worry an awful lot)</em></p></blockquote>
<p><em>(It</em>, p. 403)</p>
<p>King could have written in agonizing detail about Beverly’s thoughts and motivations. He did not. Instead, we get to experience what she is thinking directly. In my opinion, it’s more visceral, more moving than a paragraph of prose. It just works.</p>
<p>And it’s influenced me. In my novel (don’t tell me that you’re a blogger and don’t have at least the inner workings of novel or potential novel on your hard drive, or you can add “liar” to your c.v.), my protagonist is a teacher who wakes up one day to find that overnight the world has changed. Early in the story, she’s not sure exactly how &#8211; but it’s beginning to dawn on her that she’s a little different than everyone else. Here’s a brief passage in which she realizes she’s not in charge of her classroom anymore:</p>
<blockquote><p>“Sit down, Mr. Frye.” He didn’t appear to hear her, but just continued moving toward her, the look in his eyes intense, and&#8230;something else&#8230; fear?</p>
<p>“Biggie, PLEASE return to your seat.” The buzzing got even louder, roaring, crashing, her head pounding in rhythm to the throbbing of the noise. Blackness started to creep into her peripheral vision. Hal’s dry, reasonable voice fled.</p>
<p><em>SIT DOWN DAMMIT OH GOD IT HURTS WHY WON’T HE LISTEN TO ME</em></p>
<p>The boy stopped as if frozen, and the buzzing cut off abruptly, switched off. That was when the laughter began.</p></blockquote>
<p>There was no other way for me to write how Julia was feeling. Maybe it&#8217;s because of the way I read &#8211; quickly, pulling the gist from large description filled paragraphs in my haste to get to what happens next. Maybe it&#8217;s a reflection of my nature, impatient, mercurial. Or maybe it&#8217;s just mental release. Whatever it is, I&#8217;m heartened to know that it works.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/131/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/131/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=131&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://jenami.wordpress.com/2012/09/13/telepathy-not-required/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/9ba1ab62a8c0950a020ef48dbcfd2e34?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jenami</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Post Challenge: Stealing from Mamet</title>
		<link>http://anecdotaltales.wordpress.com/2012/09/10/stealing-from-mament-weekly-writing-challenge/</link>
		<comments>http://anecdotaltales.wordpress.com/2012/09/10/stealing-from-mament-weekly-writing-challenge/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2012 16:54:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>anecdotaltales</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Every Story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cops]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creative]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dpchallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[heist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mamet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[postaday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robbers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://anecdotaltales.wordpress.com/?p=830</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In “Anecdotal Tales”, stories will be told. Some will be fun, some will not. Some will be great, some will be less so. Some stories are true, some are merely possible. This is one of them. Stealing from Mamet (Weekly Writing Challenge) (This week’s Weekly Writing Challenge was aping style.  And I’ve already tackled Roald [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=830&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In “Anecdotal Tales”, stories will be told. Some will be fun, some will not. Some will be great, some will be less so. Some stories are true, some are merely possible. This is one of them.</p>
<p><strong>Stealing from Mamet (Weekly Writing Challenge)</strong></p>
<p>(<em>This week’s <a href="http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2012/09/10/weekly-writing-challenge-stylish-imitation/">Weekly Writing Challenge</a> was aping style.  And I’ve already tackled <a href="http://anecdotaltales.wordpress.com/2012/07/13/the-astounding-meeting-of-albert-play-so/">Roald Dahl</a>, so I thought I’d take a crack at David Mamet.</em>)</p>
<p>“<em>It’s only words… unless they’re true.</em>” –David Mamet</p>
<p>“It was crap.”</p>
<p>“What?”</p>
<p>“Crap.”</p>
<p>“You said that.”</p>
<p>“I know.”</p>
<p>“You know?”</p>
<p>“I’m aware.”</p>
<p>“Why don’t you elucidate upon your point?”</p>
<p><a href="http://anecdotaltales.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/cops_n_robbers.png"><img class="alignright  wp-image-831" style="width:196px;height:181px;" title="cops_n_robbers" src="http://anecdotaltales.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/cops_n_robbers.png?w=300&h=282" alt="" width="300" height="282" /></a>“It’s the thing.”</p>
<p>“The thing.”</p>
<p>“The thing that was supposed to go down last week.”</p>
<p>“It was supposed to?  So it didn’t?”</p>
<p>“Well, it did.  But it was a mess.”</p>
<p>“A mess like a cat makes on the kitchen floor when it’s been neglected by some high school girl?”</p>
<p>“More like the splatter of goo when a watermelon is dropped from a falling airplane.”</p>
<p>“Ah.”</p>
<p>“Yeah.”</p>
<p>“That kind of mess.”</p>
<p>“Exactly.”</p>
<p>“What was the play?”</p>
<p>“Haven’t you heard it?”</p>
<p>“I might have.”</p>
<p>“Jackson couldn’t keep his mouth shut if it was stapled shut and then vacuumed up tight by those guys that freeze dry beef.  I thought he’d have spilled it all by now.”</p>
<p>“Not so much spilled as dribbled.”</p>
<p>“He would be a dribbler.  He drools all over himself.”</p>
<p>“But you trusted him.”</p>
<p>“Not really.”</p>
<p>“Enough to help with your scheme.”</p>
<p>“Only barely.  Mostly it was that I knew he couldn’t scheme a way to stab me in the back.”</p>
<p>“So what went wrong?”</p>
<p>“The escape.”</p>
<p>“The exit?”</p>
<p>“The getaway.”</p>
<p>“Jackson ruined it?”</p>
<p>“Like a batch of cookie dough left out for two days.”</p>
<p>“But what about the snatch itself?”</p>
<p>“The snatch worked.  Just only.”</p>
<p>“How so?  Who was your alarm guy?”</p>
<p>“Moron.”</p>
<p>“The alarm guy was a moron?</p>
<p>“The alarm guy’s name was moron, far as I was concerned.  He had moron brains and moron fingers.  Tells me he cut the wires.  Moron says that we’re all clear to go.  Somehow moron didn’t notice that the wires to the panel were wired with an alarm.”</p>
<p>“Dang.”</p>
<p>“Dang is right.  Dang is the sound the prison door makes as it slams shut and leaves us all looking at the vertical window dressings made of pure iron with drugged up failures for roommates.”</p>
<p>“That wasn’t what did you in?”</p>
<p>“This wasn’t my first time having a faulty screw on my sidecar.  I still had the controls, I just took over.  While moron was working to silence the alarms, I went to work.  I knew where the diamonds were.  I knew what I was after.  And lemme tell ya Saul, those diamonds loved me.  They shined, they glittered; they all jumped into my hands like little bugs looking for food.  The diamonds and I, we were all chummy.  I grabbed ‘em, they smiled, and I ran outta that room.”</p>
<p>“The alarm wasn’t going off the whole time?”</p>
<p>“Oh, it was.  I left moron there trying to figure it out while I ran out to Jackson’s escape car.”</p>
<p>“That’s where it took a wrong-turn?”</p>
<p>“That’s where it slammed into a blasted cement wall.  You know who Jackson’s girl is?”</p>
<p>“Not really.  He told me she works for the city.”</p>
<p>“Yeah she does.  As a cop.”</p>
<p>“No kidding?”</p>
<p>“Not even a little.  Jackson said she was sick of bringing home squat.  She’s gotta pay for her gun, her uniform, and take abuse from bums like Jackson.  Thing is, she likes the dangerous side.  Y’know, why spend your nights in a cramped apartment all by yourself when she can hang out with a certain crowd.  A crowd she knows where to find.  Jackson said this woman was all kinds of trouble and she liked to deal that way.”</p>
<p>“So she was in on it?”</p>
<p>“That’s how he told it.  Even arranged a nice getaway vehicle.”</p>
<p>“You mean?”</p>
<div id="attachment_832" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://anecdotaltales.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/800px-police_car_with_emergency_lights_on.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-832" title="800px-Police_car_with_emergency_lights_on" src="http://anecdotaltales.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/800px-police_car_with_emergency_lights_on.jpg?w=300&h=199" alt="" width="300" height="199" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Pic from <a href="http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Police_car_with_emergency_lights_on.jpg">Wikipedia</a>.</p></div>
<p>“You ever see police men stop a squad car when responding to a burglary?  You don’t, because they don’t.”</p>
<p>“That’s quite a set up.”</p>
<p>“It’s a real nice set up.  From the tax-funded gas in the tires to the detective-repellant flashing lights on top.  Plus being able to drive sixty in a twenty-five ain’t a bad speed for a getaway car.”</p>
<p>“So what’d she do, get lost?”</p>
<p>“Oh no, she knew exactly where she was going.  She had the route all memorized.”</p>
<p>“How’s that a bad thing?”</p>
<p>“When she’s driving a couple of cons in the back of a police car to her station, it’s a very bad thing.”</p>
<p>“Shoot.”</p>
<p>“Yeah.”</p>
<p>“She turned you guys in?  Went all two-faced?”</p>
<p>“Apparently she was only trouble for cops.  Her bosses told her put on one face.  When the heist was done, she should pull an about-face.  Jackson was just dumb enough to believe a guy like him could get a dame like her.”</p>
<p>“So she gave you guys a nice pair of handcuffs?”</p>
<p>“I wasn’t the one going out with her; I had no qualms escaping.  Let Jackson take care of his own relationship problems.  If he wants to give the gal a promotion as a parting gift, that’s his affair.  Me, I took off.”</p>
<p>“Outran her and those other cops?”</p>
<p>“Like you wouldn’t believe.  They were there, those big fancy stairs leading to the station were there, and lots of guns were there, so I decided that there wasn’t a place I wanted to be.  I may be good at running a scam, but I run from bullets even better.”</p>
<p>“So you got nuthin?”</p>
<p>“I never have nuthin’.”</p>
<p>“How’d you make off with the jewels?”</p>
<p>“Shoved ‘em in a little travel belt I carry with me.  If it’s good enough when abroad, it’s good enough to fool a broad.”</p>
<p>“The cop didn’t know you made off with the loot?”</p>
<p>“Nope.  She saw me toss a bag in the backseat and figured that was it.”</p>
<p>“What was in the bag?”</p>
<p>“Moron’s dinner.”</p>
<p>“How’s that?”</p>
<p>“The moron likes to snack while he works.  I took it from him because his fingers were gettin’ all slippery and he couldn’t hold his moron tools or manage the wires.  Morons don’t get to eat if they ain’t gonna do the job first.”</p>
<p>“Did the moron get picked up too?”</p>
<p>“Haven’t checked, haven’t heard.”</p>
<p>“But Jackson got arrested.  That’s how he tells it.”</p>
<p>“Yeah.  I’m pretty sure he’s not enjoying the girlfriend’s handcuff skills.  Probably thought it’d be fun when he first hooked up with her.”</p>
<p>“Maybe he’ll find a new girlfriend in there.”</p>
<p>“Nah, he’s too ugly.”</p>
<p>“You’re sittin’ pretty though.  Got all that swag, and no one to split the profits with.”</p>
<p>“This is true.”</p>
<p>“Quite the thing.”</p>
<p>“A close thing.  Still a thing I can live with.”</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/830/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/830/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=830&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://anecdotaltales.wordpress.com/2012/09/10/stealing-from-mament-weekly-writing-challenge/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>16</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/eaff4f8211ad4b038197a09903b75024?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F2.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=R" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">anecdotaltales</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://anecdotaltales.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/cops_n_robbers.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cops_n_robbers</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://anecdotaltales.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/800px-police_car_with_emergency_lights_on.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">800px-Police_car_with_emergency_lights_on</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Writing Well for Blogs</title>
		<link>http://om.co/2012/09/11/writing-well-for-blogs/</link>
		<comments>http://om.co/2012/09/11/writing-well-for-blogs/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2012 18:30:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Om Malik</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blogging Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wisdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging tips]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://om.wordpress.com/?p=6364</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The biggest fallacy of writing on the web is the idea that there is unlimited space, and as such limitation of space is of no consequence. That is not quite true. Instead of space, the true limitation of the Internet is attention. The prolonged throat clearing or using words that make you reach for a [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=6364&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The biggest fallacy of writing on the web is the idea that there is unlimited space, and as such limitation of space is of no consequence. That is not quite true. Instead of space, the true limitation of the Internet is attention. </p>
<p>The prolonged throat clearing or using words that make you reach for a thesaurus don&#8217;t account for the paucity of attention that commands an economy of words and synthesis of thought, both presented with the crispness of a freshly laundered linen shirt. </p>
<p>A friend recently shared an article about Apple and Samsung&#8217;s creative process. The differences are stark, but for me what stood out about Apple was its ability to throw out a lot of work &#8212; actually scratch that, throw out great work &#8212; to aim for final simplicity. It is not about cramming all the features into the device, instead it is the right features. </p>
<p>Writing too is similar. When you have a minute-and-a-half of someone&#8217;s attention, simply putting forward a persuasive argument, a clear and simple story or factual news is creativity. That ability to edit everything down to the very essence in an elegant, interesting and enjoyable way that delights (and informs) is what writing is all about. </p>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=6364&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://om.co/2012/09/11/writing-well-for-blogs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>41</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/89c6ff98059617751fcf312690965fa0?s=96&#38;d=identicon" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">om</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Abandoning the Space Shuttle: A Lesson for Educators</title>
		<link>http://spacesforlearning.wordpress.com/2012/09/13/abandoning-the-space-shuttle-a-lesson-for-educators/</link>
		<comments>http://spacesforlearning.wordpress.com/2012/09/13/abandoning-the-space-shuttle-a-lesson-for-educators/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2012 11:24:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>pamelamoran</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://spacesforlearning.wordpress.com/?p=1142</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The U.S. Department of Education, and more than a few state-level departments, could take a lesson from NASA.  On a recent evening, I had the opportunity to again hear one of my favorite local celebrities; Kathy Thornton, engineer, professor, UVa associate dean, and a 4-mission retired space shuttle astronaut. Kathy doesn’t hold back when it [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1142&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span style="text-align:center; display: block;"><a href="http://spacesforlearning.wordpress.com/2012/09/13/abandoning-the-space-shuttle-a-lesson-for-educators/"><img src="http://img.youtube.com/vi/2EFuLap5Pgg/2.jpg" alt="" /></a></span>
<p>The U.S. Department of Education, and more than a few state-level departments, could take a lesson from NASA.  On a recent evening, I had the opportunity to again hear one of my favorite local celebrities; <a href="http://www.seas.virginia.edu/pubs/enews/enews_may10/thornton.php">Kathy Thornton</a>, engineer, professor, UVa associate dean, and a 4-mission retired space shuttle astronaut. Kathy doesn’t hold back when it comes to sharing her informed perspectives on space. She’s earned that right, having been key to several major payload deployments into space including the first service work on the <a title="Hubble story" href="http://www.astronomynow.com/mag/0912/HubbleInterviews.html">Hubble telescope</a>. She’s a real-deal spacewalker. And, she’s fascinated with the human narrative of exploration. She began her talk with an image of one of the earliest maps of the globe in existence.</p>
<div id="attachment_1143" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 330px"><a href="http://spacesforlearning.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/ptolemy_world_map.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1143" title="Ptolemy_World_Map" src="http://spacesforlearning.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/ptolemy_world_map.jpg" alt="" width="320" height="219" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Ptolemy World Map (Wikipedia image)</p></div>
<p>So, what does Kathy’s focus on the narrative of human exploration have to do with education?</p>
<p>Kathy Thornton created a metaphor in my mind as she spoke. Here’s what she shared. The 20th century shuttle program had to die so that NASA could get back to its primary mission of exploration, rather than maintaining its current state as a commercial cargo mover. Instead of continuing the same trajectory, NASA administrators made a tough choice. They decided to redirect the energy and thought of their teams and funding of the shuttle program away from their current work. Otherwise, the current program doomed NASA’s astronauts to circling the globe in low space orbit, over and over and over again. I thought that night &#8211; just like kids doomed to sitting in rows, facing the same direction, doing 20th century test prep worksheets over and over and over again.</p>
<div id="attachment_1144" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 228px"><a href="http://spacesforlearning.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/earths-orbit-the-silhouet-002.jpg"><img class="wp-image-1144 " title="Earths-orbit-The-silhouet-002" src="http://spacesforlearning.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/earths-orbit-the-silhouet-002.jpg?w=218&h=165" alt="" width="218" height="165" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Captured by Earth&#8217;s Orbit: Photographer: NASA/AFP/Getty Images</p></div>
<div id="attachment_1145" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 248px"><a href="http://spacesforlearning.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/schooldesks.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1145 " src="http://spacesforlearning.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/schooldesks.jpg" alt="" width="238" height="158" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Captured in School Desks</p></div>
<p>When she finished speaking, I couldn’t help but think that <em>we educators</em> <em>are caught in low orbit work, too.</em></p>
<p>This week, I also chatted with assistant principals (who meet together monthly) about our current work to stop our own version of the 20th century shuttle program. We discussed one entry point into a different kind of space exploration &#8211; learning spaces where kids search, connect, communicate, and make learning in and out of school. They described their own perspectives on the meaning of space, what optimal learning looks like in contemporary spaces &#8211; wherever those spaces exist, and what they see and hear among learners experiencing optimal learning.</p>
<div id="attachment_1146" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 178px"><a href="http://spacesforlearning.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_1668.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-1146" title="IMG_1668" src="http://spacesforlearning.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_1668.jpg?w=168&h=226" alt="" width="168" height="226" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Kindergartners Skyping on 3rd Day of School</p></div>
<p>Assistant principals used words that described spaces for learning as non-temporal, open, flexible, social; existing in both physical and virtual worlds, inside and outside the walls of school. They described optimal learning as engendering curiosity, passion, joy, interest, questions, pursuit, creativity, critical thought, collaboration, enthusiasm, excitement, commitment, reflection. They asked each other to consider new “space” words such as maker, cultural, connected, choice-driven, interactive, interdependent, and independent.</p>
<p>As assistant principals shared metacognitively about their own work to explore new territory and space, I wondered how we might make sense across our nation’s education communities of the real need to abandon America’s 20th century educational version of the shuttle program? How could we leverage our best transformational &#8211; not reformational &#8211; thinking to take us on a journey of learning exploration, rather than shuttling test prep cargo? How can we make sure our teachers and students aren’t consigned to more decades of exploring 20th century content, pedagogy, and tools?</p>
<p>If NASA is doing it, shouldn’t we also “go boldly where no educators have gone before?”</p>
<p>As we ended the conversation, I challenged the assistant principals to spend time every week looking for examples of optimal learning &#8211; learning that transcends 20th century standards of learning, tests, and grades that have been re-treaded into 21st century text, on and off of screens. As a friend of mine commented once to our state department of education staff, “if you take an old car, put new tires on it and repaint it, you’ve still got an old car.” Much of what we are doing in the name of contemporary learning today is nothing more than driving the same old vehicle, whether a metaphor of ‘99 Buick or ‘92 <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Space_Shuttle_Endeavour">space shuttle</a>.</p>
<p><a href="http://spacesforlearning.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/buick.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-1147 aligncenter" title="buick" src="http://spacesforlearning.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/buick.jpg?w=233&h=175" alt="" width="233" height="175" /></a><br />
NASA is taking risks right now to dream a new human narrative of space exploration that moves beyond orbiting Earth or even traveling back to the moon. They couldn’t do that without abandoning the shuttle program. It’s why they’re now paying about <a title="Cost to fly astronauts on Russian space ship" href="http://www.space.com/11125-nasa-russia-soyuz-deal-spaceflights.html">$63 M</a> per American astronaut seat on Russian space vehicles. It’s why they’re investing in commercial sector space vehicle venture work to replace NASA’s ownership of it. It’s why <a href="http://www.popsci.com/technology/article/2012-08/popsci-qampa-how-do-you-drive-car-mars">Curiosity</a> is on Mars right now. They’ve made tough decisions about the future that a <a title="Scientific Illiteracy" href="http://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2007/02/070218134322.htm">mostly scientifically illiterate American public</a> (72%) doesn’t understand or consider as particularly important.</p>
<p>But, NASA staff knows that you can’t get to and past Mars if you keep flying circles around the Earth. Kathy said it well to the gathering of business community members that night.</p>
<p>“Our kids must invent their future. We need to help them build the foundation to do that well.”</p>
<p>I think we need to stop flying in 20th century educational circles, too.</p>
<div id="attachment_1148" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 263px"><a href="http://spacesforlearning.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/curiosity.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1148" title="curiosity" src="http://spacesforlearning.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/curiosity.jpg" alt="" width="253" height="199" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Curiosity on Mars</p></div>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1142/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1142/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1142&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://spacesforlearning.wordpress.com/2012/09/13/abandoning-the-space-shuttle-a-lesson-for-educators/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/34809f41a7b68933611f5fb9624ab379?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">pamelamoran</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://spacesforlearning.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/ptolemy_world_map.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ptolemy_World_Map</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://spacesforlearning.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/earths-orbit-the-silhouet-002.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Earths-orbit-The-silhouet-002</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://spacesforlearning.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/schooldesks.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://spacesforlearning.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_1668.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_1668</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://spacesforlearning.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/buick.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">buick</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://spacesforlearning.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/curiosity.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">curiosity</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>News That&#8217;s Good Snooze</title>
		<link>http://thesarakellyblog.com/2012/09/12/news-thats-good-snooze/</link>
		<comments>http://thesarakellyblog.com/2012/09/12/news-thats-good-snooze/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2012 04:23:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sara</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newspaper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[North County Times]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Papa Doug]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Diego]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[U-T]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thesarakellyblog.com/?p=114</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Remember the Telecommunications Act of 1996? Okay, remember newspapers? Some people still read them. In print, even. As newsrooms at big-city dailies shrink in response to declining ad revenues, print readership keeps sliding. But not as quickly as one might think. For a long time neighborhood papers and publications serving niche communities have enjoyed far [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=114&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_117" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 226px"><a href="http://thesarakellyblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/newspapers.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-117" title="newspapers" src="http://thesarakellyblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/newspapers.jpg?w=216&h=162" alt="" width="216" height="162" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Photo by DRB62 via Flickr &#8230; because there are no newspapers here to shoot.</p></div>
<p>Remember the Telecommunications Act of 1996? Okay, remember newspapers? Some people still read them. In print, even.</p>
<p>As newsrooms at big-city dailies shrink in response to declining ad revenues, print readership keeps sliding. But not as quickly as one might think. For a long time neighborhood papers and publications serving niche communities have enjoyed far greater success at retaining dedicated readers than their big-city siblings.</p>
<p>That simple fact is worth noting this week, as most of San Diego basically snoozes through news that <a href="http://www.utsandiego.com/" target="_blank"><em>U-T San Diego</em></a> owner Doug Manchester (who insists, according to every media report, on being called “Papa Doug”) just announced his purchase of Southern California community papers the <a href="http://www.nctimes.com/" target="_blank"><em>North County Times</em></a> and the <a href="http://www.nctimes.com/californian/" target="_blank"><em>Californian</em></a>.</p>
<p>A decade ago this news would’ve been met with crazy protest. Now, though, print journalism’s dedicated defenders are few and basically drowned out by a new generation of independent journalists who’ve been self-publishing online since they could write. You know—journos who don’t remember the bad (and in some ways good) old days when you had to spend years fetching coffee for crotchety old editors before earning your first byline.</p>
<p>It’s early yet, and Manchester, a real estate developer who leans right, hasn’t yet announced whether he’ll merge the <em>North County Times</em> with its downtown rival or maintain it as its own going concern. But aside from the journalists directly involved, there’s not a whole lot of public concern—if outcry is the measure.</p>
<p>Why? Is it because San Diego’s a conservative media market by nature? Is it because our demo skews too old and disinterested? Is it because newspaper news just isn’t very sexy anymore? Could all three factors be to blame?</p>
<p>When I worked as an editor at papers in Philadelphia and Pittsburgh, newspaper ownership was a big deal. Back in 1997, when the small Philly-based newspaper chain I worked for bought an alternative weekly in Pittsburgh and moved me out there on three days’ notice to take over, the community was outraged.</p>
<p>There were protests. There were fliering campaigns. I was vilified by the city’s entrenched journalists. A well-known communist activist led a demonstration outside my office, stacking newspapers at the front door so high one day I had to dig my way through just to feed my fish.</p>
<p>Looking back, I can’t help feeling a bit sad that communities aren’t quite so eager to defend their newspapers anymore. Sure, San Diego’s dominant conservative economy, driven by a strange combination of tourism and the military, is no <em>fin de siècle</em> Pittsburgh. But something tells me today’s Pittsburghers are somewhat less passionate about their print publications. Just like the residents of most big cities today.</p>
<p>This is hardly a new thing. And I’m guilty too. Because as soon as holding companies and real estate moguls started buying up newspapers, the storied world of big-city journalism became a little less special to me. Maybe you feel the same. Maybe you don&#8217;t. Let me know.</p>
<a name="pd_a_6531164"></a>
<div class="PDS_Poll" id="PDI_container6531164" data-settings="{&quot;url&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/static.polldaddy.com\/p\/6531164.js&quot;}" style="display:inline-block;"></div>
<div id="PD_superContainer"></div>
<noscript><a href="http://polldaddy.com/poll/6531164">Take Our Poll</a></noscript>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=114&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thesarakellyblog.com/2012/09/12/news-thats-good-snooze/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/178dece07727219a38fcd43adeaee193?s=96&#38;d=retro&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Sara</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thesarakellyblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/newspapers.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">newspapers</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Uyuni Panoramas</title>
		<link>http://strollingsouthamerica.wordpress.com/2012/08/31/uyuni-panoramas/</link>
		<comments>http://strollingsouthamerica.wordpress.com/2012/08/31/uyuni-panoramas/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2012 13:20:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>strollingsouthamerica</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Bolivia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photo Essay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cactus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cementerio de Trenes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Laguna Blanca]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Laguna Colorada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Laguna Verde]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Salar de Uyuni]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uyuni]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://strollingsouthamerica.wordpress.com/?p=948</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There&#8217;s something about the panorama style that suits the Uyuni three day tour so well. The way the vistas are distorted seems to mimic the strange giddy feeling of being at high altitude in a landscape so different from anywhere else on Earth. Click a picture to see it bigger. Filed under: Bolivia, Photo Essay [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=948&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://strollingsouthamerica.wordpress.com/2012/08/31/uyuni-panoramas/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>35</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/20a093acc0ef08cf8ef7f3c0e7f8131b?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">strollingsouthamerica</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://strollingsouthamerica.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/20120825-140426.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">20120825-140426.jpg</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://strollingsouthamerica.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/20120825-140456.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">20120825-140456.jpg</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://strollingsouthamerica.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/20120825-132400.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">20120825-132400.jpg</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://strollingsouthamerica.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/20120825-140611.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">20120825-140611.jpg</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://strollingsouthamerica.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/20120825-140644.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">20120825-140644.jpg</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://strollingsouthamerica.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/20120825-140743.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">20120825-140743.jpg</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://strollingsouthamerica.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/20120825-140830.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">20120825-140830.jpg</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://strollingsouthamerica.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/20120825-140903.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">20120825-140903.jpg</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://strollingsouthamerica.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/20120825-140943.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">20120825-140943.jpg</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://strollingsouthamerica.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/20120825-141012.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">20120825-141012.jpg</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://strollingsouthamerica.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/20120825-141043.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">20120825-141043.jpg</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://strollingsouthamerica.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/20120825-141116.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">20120825-141116.jpg</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Synchronized</title>
		<link>http://vagabondwithfamily.wordpress.com/2012/09/12/synchronized/</link>
		<comments>http://vagabondwithfamily.wordpress.com/2012/09/12/synchronized/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2012 14:02:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>vagabondwithfamily</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blogs About Anything]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[high school]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nostalgia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[old girlfriends]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[romance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sentimental yearnings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[teenage love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the 1980's]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Warwick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[youth]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vagabondwithfamily.wordpress.com/?p=202</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Dizzy.  Rolling out of control.  Scenery, like the internal images of a rotating kaleidoscope in the hands of an eagerly entertained youngster, flashed by in a mixture of shapes and sizes.  Intoxicated by the rush of doing something utterly different, wondering if we had lost all sense of reality, and feeling as if my heart [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=202&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://vagabondwithfamily.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/5638122219_92957b9a00_o1.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-321" title="Lady in Red" src="http://vagabondwithfamily.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/5638122219_92957b9a00_o1.jpg?w=133&h=150" alt="" width="133" height="150" /></a>Dizzy.  Rolling out of control.  Scenery, like the internal images of a rotating kaleidoscope in the hands of an eagerly entertained youngster, flashed by in a mixture of shapes and sizes.  Intoxicated by the rush of doing something utterly different, wondering if we had lost all sense of reality, and feeling as if my heart would never be one complete piece again, I found myself with arms wrapped tightly around my chest, rolling sideways down a dew-dampened grassy hillside in the nascent light of day.  It was June some-teenth, 1987, in the middle of our town at the local cemetery on the morning after high school graduation and our senior all-night party, a night which begat a mere two hours of interrupted catnaps in the back of my 1979 Chevy Impala.  Despite feeling as if those few moments were catapulting me into another realm of consciousness, the realization hit me upon my final revolution at the bottom of the hill that my life was to continue without her.  Two teenagers in love, we would, in a few moments, go our separate ways.  Forever.</p>
<p>Nowadays, over two decades later, most memories of my senior-year girlfriend have lost their edge.  No longer do I recall with vivid sharpness the majority of our moments shared, for the twenty-plus intervening years wreak havoc on the everyday details of yesteryear—especially that last year of high school.  Oft I am found wondering if my mind can be trusted to do justice to all that we entailed.  However, I suppose I am accepting of all this diminished recollection and atrophy of nostalgia as a natural process in life.  For the most part, I am willing to chalk it up as inevitable, but there are vestiges of those days that still tenaciously linger in the deepest recesses of my heart.  Years of countless life experiences, thousands of miles literally and figuratively traveled in between, and lovers and loves that have come and gone in my life like cab drivers on a rush-hour Manhattan street all bury images of her under piles of more-easily-recalled, recent sentiment. And even after finding the love of my life, my wife, and knowing that she and I were meant to be through the ages, I can admit that my senior year girlfriend will forever have an indelible place in my heart, if only a fraction of all that I have had and all that I will be.</p>
<p>To have shared a few months of our lives together during that last year of secondary school all came at the right time.  For at least the last year-and-a-half beforehand, I had experienced so many ups and downs with nearly uncontrollable teenage angst, my parent’s disruptive divorce, and a move from New York to Virginia and then back to New York to finish six months of schooling there before graduation.  Though I had a good circle of friends that gave life a good dose of meaning at the time, I was riddled with self-doubt about life, feeling as if I was stuck between perpetually abandoned and incessantly melancholic.  So it was with her, Christine, that I found a sense of adolescent stability, albeit just for a few months towards the end of that year.  We, simply put, had fun.  Events that all senior years comprise were shared.  Good-bye parties.  Prom.  Parties to celebrate our pending manumission.  After school get-togethers.  Parties for the sake of partying.  It was a frenetic, exciting time, for we didn’t have many cares in the world when we walked hand in hand or embraced for hours.</p>
<p>Regardless of the dust-covered cobwebs that mask the details of my relationship with her, moments of<em> us</em> do find their way back to me from time to time.  For instance, she bestowed upon me the nickname “Mr. Hands” at a party one night when we found ourselves in a dark back bedroom with perhaps a dozen other friends surrounding us in semi-privacy.  With no need to detail her rationale, one can suffice it to say that those last weeks before graduation were a frenzy of bonding, emotionally and physically, and that evening was no exception.  Perhaps it was the underlying knowledge that we would soon part ways or maybe just teenage desires manifesting themselves all at once.  Sentimental yearnings like to label it as the former in order to paint such images with a hue of innocence.  Whatever it was, “Mr. Hands” was developing a sense that she was someone with whom he would soon entrust a responsibility of eternal remembrance.</p>
<p>Driving in my car together just to fill time because teenagers had nothing else to do in such a rural town, watching television after school with friends in her family room, and chatting on the phone until day’s end are other hazy recollections of our abridged paragraph in the story of life together, yet none of those times can compare to the events the week of graduation because I had made a decision then to move the day after graduation to Minnesota, a state halfway across the nation—which was, for a provincial teenager, seemingly halfway around the globe.  We had known she was to go to college in New York state later that fall, so we would have, otherwise, only had a few months of summer love to inscribe in our hearts and etch in our psyches, but the pronouncement of my imminent departure to take place the day after graduation immediately terminated any hopes of building more together.  It was with that knowledge that those last few days became profoundly surreal, all leading to a consummation of our teenage hopes and shared desires; two days before graduation, with tears still flowing and cheeks damp from hours of weeping together over our fast-approaching parting of ways, we shared a tenderness that completed our time together.  Within a mere two days, we would say goodbye.  Within a matter of moments, we left an impression on our hearts to last a lifetime.</p>
<p>At sometime during the all-night festivities after graduation earlier that evening, Christine and I danced to Chris Deburgh’s “Lady in Red”.  I felt like a man for the first time, in the full sense of the word, when I looked at her and realized she was herself wearing a red sweater.  I had experienced an unsurpassed intimacy of the heart those few days, so with maturity of foresight, I devised a way to forever remember our time together.  As if I had a pre-destined knowledge of my vagabond lifestyle and waywardly ways awaiting me in the years ahead, I knew that I wanted another substantive, tangible experience with which to connect with her, forever.  Hours later, I drove her to a place that I felt would increase the chance of recollection later in life: the local cemetery.  And it was there that we promised we would forever remember each other at that moment as we lied down in wet grass at the top of a hill to begin our whimsical, rolling descent downward.  Our existence for that moment, the last time I ever saw Christine, was… synchronized.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/202/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/202/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=202&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://vagabondwithfamily.wordpress.com/2012/09/12/synchronized/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/65c900412fe25f2d28109a2b6833ebe2?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">vagabondwithfamily</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://vagabondwithfamily.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/5638122219_92957b9a00_o1.jpg?w=133" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Lady in Red</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Breaking Up and The X</title>
		<link>http://jenibo.com/2012/09/11/breaking-up-and-the-x/</link>
		<comments>http://jenibo.com/2012/09/11/breaking-up-and-the-x/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2012 02:43:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>jenibo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food and Drink]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Romance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[breaking up]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[breakup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[college]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pictures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[postaday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The X]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://jenibo.com/?p=1447</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;m lying on my parents&#8217; living room floor with my chin on a crocheted pillow, a stomach full of caramel popcorn, and at least fourteen mosquito bites on my pudgy legs from this past Sunday at Hot Fiance&#8217;s house where we celebrated his mom&#8217;s birthday. Despite the itching and three days of spoiled-brat-part-time-jobbing this week, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1447&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m lying on my parents&#8217; living room floor with my chin on a crocheted pillow, a stomach full of caramel popcorn, and at least fourteen mosquito bites on my pudgy legs from this past Sunday at Hot Fiance&#8217;s house where we celebrated his mom&#8217;s birthday. Despite the itching and three days of spoiled-brat-part-time-jobbing this week, I think I&#8217;ll be okay. I think I can manage to smile a little more, laugh, even, at the pages and pages of journal entries I found time to peruse earlier about an overbearing boyfriend who thought he should come over right away to discuss his feelings about my Myspace conversations with Explorer earlier that year and the way I failed to mention how very close we were to being just slightly more than friends. Like, sorry, The X.</p>
<p><a href="http://jenibo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/09112012e.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1449" title="09112012e" src="http://jenibo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/09112012e.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="507" /></a></p>
<p>Years and years later, I&#8217;d think<em> that was significant</em>. And <em>people need to know about us</em>. I&#8217;d think I should write my thoughts on the nearest Post-It and save it in my purse for the future when I can empathize with The X and remember driving through town one day after school, telling him how much of a Real Boyfriend he looked like when he wore his Ray-Bans.</p>
<p><a href="http://jenibo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/09112012d.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1448" title="09112012d" src="http://jenibo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/09112012d.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="507" /></a></p>
<p>I still have a hard time with that. When we were dating, I told him of a dream I had in which we were in some kind of open car on the highway with a white sheet above us, blowing in the wind. I could see the sun on his face, and he touched mine. We were laughing as he steered with his feet, and I felt safe and cool and as if I&#8217;d be happy there forever. Breaking up was my idea, but that didn&#8217;t mean I wasn&#8217;t hurt or angry for all the times he made me sit on the couch in his two-bedroom apartment picking the feathers out of his pillows while he told me the exact words I should have said to keep from upsetting him. It wasn&#8217;t nice, and I needed to be a lesbian or a murderer to vent my frustration.</p>
<p><a href="http://jenibo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/09112012h.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1452" title="09112012h" src="http://jenibo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/09112012h.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="504" /></a></p>
<p>And the anger makes me feel crazy, so I think I should write a story about a crazy person&#8211;a woman with a good man like Hot Fiance, reason to be upset, and the fear that her mind is no longer her own but a vessel for something she never meant to keep. But I&#8217;ll probably never write it, because all I know about being insane is so Hollywood or teenagery and every reason for illness I can imagine seems so trivial that it just makes me sick and embarrassed for whoever I believe he made me become.</p>
<p><a href="http://jenibo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/09112012f.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1450" title="09112012f" src="http://jenibo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/09112012f.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="497" /></a></p>
<p>I meant to have goals for this month. I wrote these down at work, but stuffed them at the bottom of my purse with all my other grand ideas because I&#8217;m not sure I can follow through and if I can&#8217;t, I don&#8217;t want to be reminded by a Post-It on my mirror that I didn&#8217;t. Hot Fiance is always supportive and suggested I take part in &#8220;<a href="https://twitter.com/#!/search/shaytember" target="_blank">Shaytember</a>&#8221; which I was all for until it begun and all I could think of were stupid goals and Positivity, which I&#8217;m not even sure I agree with.</p>
<p><a href="http://jenibo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/09112012i.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1451" title="09112012i" src="http://jenibo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/09112012i.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="627" /></a></p>
<p>Breaking up with The X was a grueling process that took months. I remember telling him that I needed a holiday, and made sure he listened to this <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rQJOUqh_NxY" target="_blank">song</a>. It was very twenty-ish and juvenile, but his insisting that I stay and my inability to forcefully disagree meant he&#8217;d have to listen to <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RNKDHmNcIvI" target="_blank">this</a> and <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lZmqWBDGCpg" target="_blank">this</a> and <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NPgH56TFsDo" target="_blank">this</a> and <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KMuOZJZlBZY" target="_blank">this</a> (which was not a completely accurate representation of my feelings, but still expressed some of the feelings I could not rightly communicate) until he got the message. Suffice it to say, something worked, and the day I felt we were <em>really</em> broken up was the night he proposed, the night I saw <em>he</em> was the crazy one, the night he threw his cellphone to the pavement in the dark and drove away feeling pretty stupid.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1447/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1447/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1447&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://jenibo.com/2012/09/11/breaking-up-and-the-x/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>64</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/8f4d488f8d779709bbb3056b493070d4?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jenibo</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jenibo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/09112012e.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">09112012e</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jenibo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/09112012d.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">09112012d</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jenibo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/09112012h.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">09112012h</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jenibo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/09112012f.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">09112012f</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jenibo.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/09112012i.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">09112012i</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Toronto Film Festival &amp; the Fine Art of Celebrity Stalking</title>
		<link>http://breezyk.wordpress.com/2012/09/11/tiff-and-the-fine-art-of-celebrity-stalking/</link>
		<comments>http://breezyk.wordpress.com/2012/09/11/tiff-and-the-fine-art-of-celebrity-stalking/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2012 13:20:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>breezyk</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[James Franco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Selena Gomez]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TIFF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Toronto]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://breezyk.wordpress.com/?p=3158</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Well folks, it&#8217;s that time of year again: when the red carpets get rolled out, the champagne flows like water and A-List celebs fill the streets of Toronto. No, not my birthday, fools.  Y&#8217;all know Ryan and I prefer to celebrate that with a nice bottle of Beaujolais and a quiet night in: Of course, what I&#8217;m REALLY talking about here is TIFF: the Toronto [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3158&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well folks, it&#8217;s that time of year again: when the red carpets get rolled out, the champagne flows like water and A-List celebs fill the streets of Toronto.</p>
<p>No, not my birthday, fools.  Y&#8217;all know Ryan and I prefer to celebrate that with a nice bottle of Beaujolais and a quiet night in:</p>
<div id="attachment_3174" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 500px"><img class="size-full wp-image-3174 " title="meryan3" src="http://breezyk.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/meryan3.jpg" alt="" width="490" height="312" /><p class="wp-caption-text">&#8220;Oh Ryan- I just love quiet nights in with you. Not even the fact that my head is 3x the size of yours can get in the way of our love&#8221;</p></div>
<p>Of course, what I&#8217;m REALLY talking about here is TIFF: the Toronto International Film Festival.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3180" title="tiff3" src="http://breezyk.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/tiff3.jpg" alt="" width="490" height="245" /></p>
<p>Now for me, film festival time usually means putting my stalkin&#8217; pants on and trawling the streets of Toronto with camera in hand, stopping only to stare in the windows of the Ritz Carlton while making this face:</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3167" title="kimkrazy" src="http://breezyk.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/kimkrazy.jpg" alt="" width="398" height="498" /></p>
<p>Until I get escorted off the premises.</p>
<p>This year, however, I was given the chance to kick my stalking up a notch when my friend Michelle offered  me an extra ticket to the premiere of the movie <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt2101441/"><em>Spring Breakers.</em></a></p>
<p>A chance to see a cool movie and some celebs IRL? Sign me up. Plus, this was totally one of those things you could  post on facebook to make yourself seem all cool and in the &#8220;scene&#8221; when really all you did was shell out 40 bucks and hit &#8220;Refresh&#8221; an exorbitant amount of times on your web browser.</p>
<p>The movie, directed by Harmony Korine, is about four college girls (Selena Gomez, Vanessa Hudgens, Ashley Benson and Rachel Korine) who rob a restaurant in order to fund their spring break trip to Saint Petersburg, Fla. Once there, they wind up hooking up with a corn-rowed, silver toothed drug dealer named &#8220;Alien&#8221; (James Franco) who gets them into some seriously un-Disney sh*t.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-3183" title="springbreakers" src="http://breezyk.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/springbreakers.jpg?w=1024&h=268" alt="" width="1024" height="268" /></p>
<p>Sounds Oscar-worthy, right??</p>
<p>Since my 8-year-old-niece Lola is in love with Selena and for some reason is under the impression that I look exactly like her (ok, I paid her to say it), my ultimate goal was to solidify my role as &#8220;best aunt ever&#8221; by meeting Selena and taking a real photo with her to replace this splitscreen I <del>keep under my pillow and stare at every night</del> made once as a joke for a blog post and never looked at again:</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3161" title="meselenasplitscreen2" src="http://breezyk.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/meselenasplitscreen2.jpg" alt="" width="490" height="281" /></p>
<p>We arrived at the theatre somewhat late and were in a mad rush to pick up our tickets when we were stopped directly in our tracks by an oncoming limo.  The door opened, and out walked Selena Gomez and Vanessa Hudgens. Not even 2 feet away from us.</p>
<p>I was like:<br />
<a href="http://s1094.photobucket.com/albums/i452/breannk1/?action=view&amp;current=faint.gif" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter" style="border:0 currentColor;" src="http://i1094.photobucket.com/albums/i452/breannk1/faint.gif" alt="Photobucket" width="319" height="176" border="0" /></a></p>
<p>Needless to say,  by the time I came to, I totally missed my opportunity to <del>become besties with</del> get a picture with Selena. Good thing I can still buy my niece&#8217;s affection with McDonald&#8217;s and other sh*t she&#8217;s not supposed to have.</p>
<p>Anyway, we watched the red carpet progression for a while, listening to hundreds of tweens shouting &#8220;SELENA I LOVE YOU&#8221; and &#8220;WHERE&#8217;S JUSTIN BIEBER&#8221; before making our way into the movie.</p>
<p>Now, the movie itself was sort of interesting and arty and all, but my enjoyment of it was somewhat hindered by the following factors:</p>
<ul>
<li>apparently they don&#8217;t serve popcorn at TIFF screenings?? Call me un-kla$$y, but for me, a movie without popcorn is like Ice without Coco. It just doesn&#8217;t work.</li>
<li>I had chosen to wear my hair in a sock bun for the event:</li>
</ul>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3181" title="sockbun2" src="http://breezyk.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/sockbun2.jpg" alt="" width="360" height="450" /></p>
<p>which, although incredibly chic and red-carpet looking, also renders it damn near impossible to sit back in your chair like a normal person.</p>
<p>Finally, after an hour and a half of shifting hungrily in my seat, the movie was over and the cast &amp; director came onstage for a brief Q&amp;A.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-3165" title="tiff" src="http://breezyk.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/tiff.jpg?w=922&h=691" alt="" width="922" height="691" /></p>
<p>This was cool, but would have been way MORE fun had my friend not grabbed my hand and pulled it back down whenever I tried to ask one of my many stupid (albeit hilarious) questions.</p>
<p>After the Q&amp;A we hightailed it to the back entrance where we knew the stars would be exiting the theatre. Unfortunately, we weren&#8217;t the only ones who knew the secret and had to jostle into position with hundreds of other fans.</p>
<p>As I got my iPhone out and preset my instagram filter to &#8220;<em>You wish your life was this cool</em>&#8220;, I remembered an interview I saw recently with a 16-year-old American girl known as &#8220;<em>Stalker Sarah</em>&#8220; for her talent of hunting down celebrities and getting her photo taken with them. Sarah has photos with over 5,000 celebrities, and prides herself in knowing all of the best stalking tactics.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3182" title="sarah" src="http://breezyk.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/sarah.jpg" alt="" width="490" height="327" /></p>
<p>As I dodged random elbows and struggled to see past the 6&#8217;4 man in front of me,  I wondered to myself, &#8220;<em>What would Stalker Sarah do?&#8221;&#8230;</em> while at the same time cursing my own name for not having the same alliterative potential.</p>
<p>Un (?)fortunately my question remained rhetorical, because just then the cast busted out of the theatre and <em>Running of the Bulls: Toronto Edition</em> commenced. Somehow I managed to snap the following pic before I met my untimely demise of being trampled to death by a gaggle of crazed Selena Gomez fans:</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-3164" title="selena" src="http://breezyk.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/selena.jpg?w=614&h=819" alt="" width="614" height="819" /></p>
<p>Just kidding. I&#8217;m totally still alive. But what a way to go.</p>
<h2 style="text-align:center;">Question of the Day: Ever been to a movie premiere? Ever had a star sighting?</h2>
<p style="text-align:center;"> </p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3158/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3158/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3158&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://breezyk.wordpress.com/2012/09/11/tiff-and-the-fine-art-of-celebrity-stalking/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>51</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/074733a320f565b357cea64d1720a00b?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">breezyk</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://breezyk.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/meryan3.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">meryan3</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://breezyk.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/tiff3.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tiff3</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://breezyk.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/kimkrazy.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">kimkrazy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://breezyk.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/springbreakers.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">springbreakers</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://breezyk.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/meselenasplitscreen2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">meselenasplitscreen2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://i1094.photobucket.com/albums/i452/breannk1/faint.gif" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Photobucket</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://breezyk.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/sockbun2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sockbun2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://breezyk.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/tiff.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tiff</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://breezyk.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/sarah.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sarah</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://breezyk.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/selena.jpg?w=768" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">selena</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Are Happy Online Personas a Lie or a Matter of Protocol?</title>
		<link>http://godsofadvertising.wordpress.com/2012/09/10/are-perpetually-happy-online-personas-a-big-lie-or-simply-a-matter-of-protocol/</link>
		<comments>http://godsofadvertising.wordpress.com/2012/09/10/are-perpetually-happy-online-personas-a-big-lie-or-simply-a-matter-of-protocol/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2012 14:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Steffan1</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[depression]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online personas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[our true selves]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shiny happy people]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media guidelines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media protocol]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the idealized self]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://godsofadvertising.wordpress.com/?p=6526</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Status update: &#8220;Posing with the Beaver!&#8221; One of the wonders of social media is that it allows us to present only what we want of ourselves to the world. Wrinkles, warts and divorces remain hidden. We put our best face forward and keep ugliness and negativity far from curious eyes. We show only virtues and [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=6526&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://godsofadvertising.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/images1.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-6527" title="images" src="http://godsofadvertising.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/images1.jpg?w=460" alt=""   /></a></p>
<p>Status update: &#8220;Posing with the Beaver!&#8221;</p>
<p>One of the wonders of social media is that it allows us to present only what we want of ourselves to the world. Wrinkles, warts and divorces remain hidden. We put our best face forward and keep ugliness and negativity far from curious eyes. We show only virtues and rarely defects of body and character. Frankly, we are being more than pleasant. We are presenting idealized versions of ourselves: who we aspire to be versus (perhaps) who we really are. Facebook is the textbook example but the myriad other microblogging platforms provide ample camouflage as well. Duh, you say. Why would anyone want to share anything less than bliss in his or her personal life let alone Tweet about it?</p>
<p>The dilemma (if dilemma is even the right word) is that everyone is living a kind of virtual lie and one that grows bigger and deeper with every status update and adorable photograph we upload. Say a gal posts only sugar and spice and everything nice; her idealized self, the woman she hopes to be and wants others to think she is. But what if that same person is, in fact, seriously depressed or even suicidal? Is it a kind of betrayal to her friends and family to be falsely presenting all that positivity? Is it dangerous? On the other hand, is bad news better left unsaid? Does it fall under the category of “too much information?”</p>
<p><a href="http://godsofadvertising.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/images-1.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-6533" title="images-1" src="http://godsofadvertising.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/images-1.jpg?w=460" alt=""   /></a></p>
<p>Status update: &#8220;I ripped Bob&#8217;s face off for betraying me!&#8221;</p>
<p>I don’t know the answer. After all, I’m just as shiny and happy on Facebook as you are. I post photographs of my adorable children just like you do. I am happy. We are “totally enjoying dinner at Café Louise!” Or I am “so looking forward to Lily’s dance recital tomorrow.” And so on. The bitter argument I had with my spouse last night is never communicated. My disdain for dance recitals is avoided like the plague. God forbid my numerous Facebook “friends” think I have challenges at home or am anything less than a perfect husband or father.</p>
<p>Et tu?</p>
<p>When I scroll through your Facebook pages I rarely see anything but delighted and happy people. Sure, you post snarky comments about this politician or that pop star but when it comes to you and yours you are as positive as a Disney Princess.</p>
<p><a href="http://godsofadvertising.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/aa09_18.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-6530" title="AA09_18" src="http://godsofadvertising.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/aa09_18.jpg?w=300&h=200" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a></p>
<p>Status update: &#8220;Gary may be gay but our love will last forever!&#8221;</p>
<p>Some people are braver than others: like the man who shares his battle with cancer or the woman who opens up about her struggle to land a job. So, yes, there are plenty of examples of self-disclosure taking place online. Yet, the vast majority of us don’t “go there.” Our Facebook pages are like a fifties-era sitcom. Sis and Johnny love school and sports and going on vacation. Father’s knows best. And mom is always “That Girl!”</p>
<p>I don’t expect any of us will change this &#8220;Life is Beautiful!&#8221; approach to social networking but I am calling bullshit. Life is messy and complicated. Relationships implode. People get sick and die. Children are maladjusted. In the end shit happens all the time. Just not on Facebook.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/6526/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/6526/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=6526&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://godsofadvertising.wordpress.com/2012/09/10/are-perpetually-happy-online-personas-a-big-lie-or-simply-a-matter-of-protocol/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>98</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/265771772e4a486da4c17fd0014080ed?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">SRP</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://godsofadvertising.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/images1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">images</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://godsofadvertising.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/images-1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">images-1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://godsofadvertising.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/aa09_18.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">AA09_18</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>