<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2012 20:02:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>A Day In the Life of a Depressed Person</title>
		<link>http://knockedoverbyafeather.wordpress.com/2012/10/22/a-day-in-the-life-of-a-depressed-person/</link>
		<comments>http://knockedoverbyafeather.wordpress.com/2012/10/22/a-day-in-the-life-of-a-depressed-person/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2012 15:13:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>merbear264</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[depression]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://knockedoverbyafeather.wordpress.com/2012/10/22/a-day-in-the-life-of-a-depressed-person/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[6:00 am-  Wake up. (Unless the pill I chose to take the night before for insomnia (4 to choose from) worked just a little to well! 6:30 am-  Make sure my 15 year old has lunch, eats breakfast and is ready for the drive to the bus stop. (Thankfully my husband does this. He is [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=35&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>6:00 am-  Wake up. (Unless the pill I chose to take the night before for insomnia (4 to choose from) worked just a little to well!</p>
<p>6:30 am-  Make sure my 15 year old has lunch, eats breakfast and is ready for the drive to the bus stop. (Thankfully my husband does this. He is wonderful)</p>
<p>6:45-9:00 am- Drink my two cups of coffee, catch up on words with friends, check out whats new on facebook, read the news. Say goodbye to my husband before he leaves for work.</p>
<p>9:15 am- So..I am alone. Well, not really, I have my dog who is my constant companion these days. I can&#8217;t even go pee without her following me. But I am thankful for her. We play a game of catch with her stuffy, I give her treats, she snuggles with me. I talk to her and she just stares up at me with her loving eyes. She doesn&#8217;t care if I say screw it and go back to bed.</p>
<p>9:30 am- Once I have decided against going back to the comfort of my bed, possibly still warm from my body heat, I decide what I am going to do today. Oh crap, I forgot to take my pills! Ok, that&#8217;s done. The kitchen needs cleaning, So does the upstairs bathroom. Or I could just mess around online some more. I could read, if I had the attention span. I double check to see if I have any appointments or obligations outside of my house, which I don&#8217;t. Sigh of relief that I don&#8217;t have to shower and get dressed. The day is free.</p>
<p>10:00 am- 12:00 &#8211; Wander around house. Do a little of this and a little of that so I don&#8217;t go back to bed. When I was well and working, I remember I just wished for more time to myself. Now I just wish I had a function again. Remember the awful dream I had last night about having a anxiety attack at work.</p>
<p>12:00- 3:00 pm &#8211; This is the worst part of the day. I am still wearing my jammy pants. If I can keep myself occupied during this time frame, it means the day wasn&#8217;t a complete fail. I plan whats for supper that night, neatly arranging all the ingredients on the counter. I have always been a planner, but nowadays I find myself planning every move. If I know what I am going to do next, it keeps me focused. I look out the window at the world I no longer feel a part of. I should take my dog for a walk, but it exhausts me. I will not cry. I will not feel sorry for myself. I try to remind myself that although I have numerous diagnoses, none of them will kill me outright. If I start to feel suicidal again, I will end up back at the hospital. I do not want that. So I fight. Come on Maggie, lets play another rousing game of stuffy.</p>
<p>3:30- 5:00 pm- The family is home. I start dinner, though usually my husband will tell me he&#8217;s got it tonight. I am not sure why, although I suspect that it might be because I drop things, burn myself, and he is just very nice. But I have been doing better lately. I feel like things are back to normal, where I would come home after a 10 hour day and make dinner, no sweat. Please let me make the mashed potatoes, so I feel like I accomplished something today.</p>
<p>5:00 pm- 8:00 pm- I am at the point where I am not sure if it&#8217;s the meds or just me, but I am so ready for bed. We watch tv. I talk to my daughter about her day. Friends and school, she needs a new belt, and her math teacher is so funny. (I think she has a crush on him.) My husband talks and try&#8217;s to make me laugh. And I do. There are moments when I feel normal. I still have my sense of humor most of the time. I try so hard to engage in conversation that doesn&#8217;t revolve around my illness. I know I need to do this.</p>
<p>7:00- 9:00 pm- I get a bit excited as bedtime draws near. I decide what pill I will take tonight. If my muscles are twitching and sore from the Fibromyagia I will take a Flexeril. If my anxiety is high, a Risperdol. If I choose to take nothing, I know the chances of a good night sleep is nil. But I made it through another day. I didn&#8217;t cry today. I didn&#8217;t have an anxiety attack. I fought the urge to hide from this world by taking a nap. Each day is a struggle. But, damnit, I will NOT give up! Someday I will have my life back. Someday&#8230;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/35/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/35/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=35&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://knockedoverbyafeather.wordpress.com/2012/10/22/a-day-in-the-life-of-a-depressed-person/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/eb1ea208adeb79bd1797750745828d37?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">merbear264</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>This WILL Happen To You</title>
		<link>http://curmudgeon-at-large.com/2012/10/21/this-will-happen-to-you/</link>
		<comments>http://curmudgeon-at-large.com/2012/10/21/this-will-happen-to-you/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2012 13:19:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Curmudgeon-at-Large</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncurmudgeonized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[daily life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[decisions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inevitable event]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[musings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[regrets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thoughts]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://curmudgeon-at-large.com/?p=365</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Death and taxes (in some form or another) are inevitable.  But I am writing about the one other inevitable event that will happen in the life of each and every one of you. There exists, right now, an item that you have been meaning to rid yourself of for some time.  No, it has to be [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=365&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://curmudgeon-at-large.com/2012/10/21/this-will-happen-to-you/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>35</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/1836fa93bb0f3886c33e9530dc564a83?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F1.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">curmudgeonal</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What to Look For During the Final Presidential Debate</title>
		<link>http://pheonixreview.wordpress.com/2012/10/22/what-to-look-for-during-the-final-presidential-debate/</link>
		<comments>http://pheonixreview.wordpress.com/2012/10/22/what-to-look-for-during-the-final-presidential-debate/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2012 14:34:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>pheonixfounder</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Current Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social Commentary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2012]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[afghanistan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[debate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[foreign policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[libya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Obama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[presidential]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Romney]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[syria]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://pheonixreview.wordpress.com/?p=304</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Tonight, President Barack Obama and former MA Governor Mitt Romney, will meet for the final political showdown of this general election cycle.  Currently, the scorecard reads 1-1 for both candidates, with Romney being the victor at the first debate, and Obama at the second.  Tonight will determine the ultimate winner of the debate series, unless tonight&#8217;s debate [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=304&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://pheonixreview.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/romney-obama.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-305" title="romney obama" alt="" src="http://pheonixreview.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/romney-obama.jpg?w=300&#038;h=253" height="253" width="300" /></a>Tonight, President Barack Obama and former MA Governor Mitt Romney, will meet for the final political showdown of this general election cycle.  Currently, the scorecard reads 1-1 for both candidates, with Romney being the victor at the first debate, and Obama at the second.  Tonight will determine the ultimate winner of the debate series, unless tonight&#8217;s debate ends in a draw.</p>
<p>The final debate will focus on foreign policy, an often overlooked topic during this election season.  With voters mostly concerned with economic woes, readjusted tax rates, unemployment, and health care, foreign policy has gotten little attention in these past few months.  However, tonight, foreign policy will be in the spotlight, thus exemplifying the candidates&#8217; prowess (or lack thereof) in dealing with global issues.</p>
<p>The situation in Libya will lead the discussion, as it was the most recent international issue that has garnered political attention.  Slowly, more and more information is coming to light about the terrorist attack that left four Americans, including Ambassador Chris Stevens, dead.  President Obama will be on the defensive, as he is ultimately responsible for the protection of American citizens abroad.  Obama will have to convince Americans that he handled the situation diligently and appropriately, a difficult feat.</p>
<p><a href="http://pheonixreview.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/syria.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-306" title="Syrian rebels raise their weapons" alt="" src="http://pheonixreview.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/syria.jpg?w=300&#038;h=180" height="180" width="300" /></a>The situation in Syria will also come to light tonight.  While media attention has dwindled in this last year and half, the Syrian civil war will again become a topic of discussion.  Again, Obama will be on the defensive, detailing why America has not been involved in the conflict providing humanitarian assistance, training local troops, or assisting intelligence efforts.  In previous debates, Romney has already set the stage for Obama&#8217;s failure to intervene, saying that he instead delegated the task to the United Nations and the Security Counsil, an elite body that initiates any and all hardcore directives within the UN.  Russia and China, two of the five permanent countries that sit on the Council, have vetoed efforts to intervene in Syria as both nations have compelling incentives to see the conflict continue.</p>
<p>The debate will also center on the war in Afghanistan, which is coming to a close by 2014.  Here, Obama will be on the offense, using the ostensible success in this regard to paint Romney as unfit to be a commander-in-chief.  Futhermore, President Obama can tout his success in finding and murdering al Qaeda leader Osama bin Laden last year.  This puts Romney in an awkward position, as he will have to laud Obama&#8217;s leadership efforts, while still persuading voters that he is still better suited to do the job.</p>
<p>The debate might also shift to China.  Here, the debate could get interesting as a discussion on China will not deal with arms or military efforts, but economic warfare.  Romney has candidly stated that he will label China a currency manipulator, a label that comes with plenty of political and economic ramifications.  If there&#8217;s enough time, Obama just might outline why such a stance is unfeasible.</p>
<p>The gravitas of tonight&#8217;s debate is pretty much set; both candidates will try to prove that they are knowledgeable enough on global concerns.  But debates are increasingly focusing more on style and image, and less on content.  Since debate winners and losers are determined not by how well a candidate answers a question, but the manner in which they do so, pay attention to the tone and mannerisms of our candidates tonight.</p>
<p>Romney lost the last debate because his composure faltered under a coolly assertive President Obama.  Romney tonight will be ready for Obama&#8217;s calmly direct assertiveness.  Romney will be more conscious of his presence, and (hopefully) not speak on the fly about issues that he&#8217;s not too familiar with.  He doesn&#8217;t want another facepalm moment when Candy Crowley corrected him.  Obama will continue his assertive composure, as voters enjoyed his polite way of tearing into Romney.</p>
<p>And pay attention to the moderator too.  After Jim Lehrer&#8217;s dismal performance at the first debate, successive moderators have had more presence coordinating speaking times, and shutting the candidates up when they&#8217;re talking a bit too much.  Bob Schieffer will be under scrutiny to see just how well he can assert his authority over two supremely powerful men.</p>
<p>Tonight is the candidates <strong>LAST CHANCE</strong> at meeting face to face.  This is an all-or-nothing final call for the candidates to state their cases to Americans while standing side by side with one another.  It&#8217;ll be very interesting to see how this plays out, as there is no more room for errors or missteps.  This is the night for ultimate perfection.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/304/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/304/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=304&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://pheonixreview.wordpress.com/2012/10/22/what-to-look-for-during-the-final-presidential-debate/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>22</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/0ff84d5977a24ec06045f7c2ca2b44bc?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">pheonixfounder</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://pheonixreview.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/romney-obama.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">romney obama</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://pheonixreview.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/syria.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Syrian rebels raise their weapons</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Amanda Todd, Cyberbullying, and the Open Internet</title>
		<link>http://thisconjecture.wordpress.com/2012/10/17/amanda-todd-cyberbullying-and-the-open-internet/</link>
		<comments>http://thisconjecture.wordpress.com/2012/10/17/amanda-todd-cyberbullying-and-the-open-internet/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2012 22:42:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ossington</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[conjecture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ethics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[freedom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[future]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[morality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[philosophy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thoughts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amanda todd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anonymity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[censorship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FREEDOM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[INTERNET]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thisconjecture.wordpress.com/?p=287</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There has been a lot of talk recently about this incident of a youth suicide as a consequence of bullying. It&#8217;s interesting not simply because a poor young girl suffered, nor because she was caused to take her own life, but because much attention and worry has been put upon the means by which she [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=287&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There has been a lot of talk recently about this incident of a youth suicide as a consequence of bullying. It&#8217;s interesting not simply because a poor young girl suffered, nor because she was caused to take her own life, but because much attention and worry has been put upon the means by which she was caused to do so, namely the internet.</p>
<p>As per the (uncorroborated) facts, it sounds like the person who perpetrated this was an adult. This raises the concern of pedophilia. Pedophilia and harassment, truly a terrible combination.</p>
<p>Where for are we to then look for a resolution of this? We cannot bring the girl back, nor will punishing the perpetrator do a whole lot to stop such things from happening (not to say that shouldn&#8217;t/ will not occur). Websites like 4chan, reddit, youtube, really any website where people act and speak from a position of anonymity have always been places where hate is thrown about as if it were a plush play ball, and trolling a game. Ought we to remove the resource of anonymity? What ought we do? Ought we do anything at all?</p>
<p>I believe that to react to this case, at all, would be a mistake. <strong>No good legislation ever comes from knee-jerk reactions.</strong> And I do not believe that we ought to here do that.</p>
<p>I think the problem is one of morality. You knew I was going to say that, and perhaps saying so is a cop-out. People will believe what they believe, and as many people get stepped upon, they&#8217;re going to continue to stomp upon others. I have even heard claims which amount to bullying being natural, and what we perceive to be a wave of online hate is actually nothing novel, but since we&#8217;re all connected we can just see it all now.</p>
<p>When it comes down to it, I think we need to continue to teach our kids well, and to as adults not allow the adults which we deal with to be dicks. Perhaps that&#8217;s the key. Out jerks for what they are, make being an asshole a socially reprehensible act.</p>
<p>As per what ought to be done with respect to the internet? I argue nothing. Anonymity doesn&#8217;t just protect those who do evil, it also protects those who do good, and those who simply do. I view the internet as the backbone of international freedom. States and groups can do and act as they please, but with the internet they cannot get a whole lot by us. Without the internet, powerful people and populous groups could do just about anything, get away with it, and really none of us would know.</p>
<p>When I see people attacking the openness of the internet for things like child pornography, hacking, and harassment, I recoil with fright. I believe we&#8217;re always going to have such things, but we&#8217;re not always going to have a free and open internet. And it is worth keeping the internet open and free, if only for good information (with the bad) and for keeping a free line of communication between all the citizens of the Earth.</p>
<p>Put it this way, if in the time of slavery in the United States there was accounts of sexual abuse in the underground railroad, ought those who depend upon it for their own freedom scrap it in favour of protecting those affected? No. Of course not, because the problems associated with having no underground railroad are larger than these other problems which are going to happen anyway.</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>We cannot kill the current state of the internet to protect people, because keeping the internet open and free is a great means to protect the very same people.</strong></p></blockquote>
<p>Now, I am not condoning these terrible things. I am just asking for patience. We need to keep the internet as it is and we need to turn our focus onto the citizens which constitute our world(s).</p>
<p>It&#8217;s really terrible what happened to that girl, and all the other horrible things which occur on the internet ought themselves to be stopped/rectified/known by every soul that lives to be bad. But we&#8217;re not going to be able to do this if we scapegoat that resource which we require to make it through this period of transition which is causing all the world(s)&#8217; joints to creak and groan.</p>
<p>The internet isn&#8217;t our savior in the sense of Christ without sin, rather the internet is more like a human in that it has a lot of good, a lot of bad, and everything in between. And like a child, depending on how we treat it and what we put into it, and how we interact with it, it will become better or worse accordingly.</p>
<p>I hope we can treat the internet better than we did that poor girl. And perhaps if we can do so then the internet (as an aggregate of information and people) will be in a better position to protect a similar such person in the future.</p>
<p>- J</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/287/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/287/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=287&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thisconjecture.wordpress.com/2012/10/17/amanda-todd-cyberbullying-and-the-open-internet/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/0b95920ada06f49632af5552664f5cb1?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">atestamentofsentience</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Full of Hot Air!</title>
		<link>http://supernovacondensate.net/2012/10/21/full-of-hot-air/</link>
		<comments>http://supernovacondensate.net/2012/10/21/full-of-hot-air/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2012 14:36:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>invaderxan</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[physics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mad science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[silliness]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://supernovacondensate.net/?p=4121</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[One of my favourite things to do from time to time on this blog is to answer peoples&#8217; random silly science questions with&#8230; well&#8230; random silly science. And a friend of mine asked me a brilliant question the other day. A question about squeaky voices and helium balloons. Really really big helium balloons! ❝How many [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4121&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://supernovacondensate.net/2012/10/21/full-of-hot-air/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>33</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/902facdb9d4eeada9a9e6dce1734c886?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">invaderxan</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://supernovacondensate.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/felix-baumgartner.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Just imagine the view from up there...</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://supernovacondensate.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/felix-baumgartner2.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Up, up and awa-ay in my beautiful balloon...</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://supernovacondensate.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/fun-with-helium-1.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Apparently the gas laws have a use after all. Who knew?</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://supernovacondensate.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/fun-with-helium-2.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Deflated.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://supernovacondensate.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/fun-with-helium-3.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Incidentally, you breathe 10.5 million times in a year, so this could last you a good few months. You know, if you could breathe helium...</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Voting Rights</title>
		<link>http://eileenslovak.com/2012/10/19/voting-rights/</link>
		<comments>http://eileenslovak.com/2012/10/19/voting-rights/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2012 20:31:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Eileen Slovak</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Random Thoughts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[American]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[candidates]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[golf]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[informed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[values]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Veterans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[voting rights]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://eileenslovak.com/2012/10/19/voting-rights/</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Distracted by the coverage of the upcoming Presidential election, I cannot write about anything else.  It is unfathomable to me that there are people who are either apathetic or uninformed when it comes to politics.  Maybe my fixation is a result of living in close proximity to where all the action happens, near our Nations [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=166&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Distracted by the coverage of the upcoming Presidential election, I cannot write about anything else.  It is unfathomable to me that there are people who are either apathetic or uninformed when it comes to politics. </p>
<p>Maybe my fixation is a result of living in close proximity to where all the action happens, near our Nations Capitol.   Every time I enter the city, I feel a swell of American pride, awe and patriotism.  Ironically, the population in this area is somewhat sheltered from the problems of the rest of the Country.  The struggle is not as magnified here, where house prices and employment levels remain high. </p>
<p>I was not engaged at one time and am unsure of when I changed my mind and decided to start paying attention.  I remember feeling about politics the way I felt about golf. <em> How boring! </em> Then I started to play golf, not so much by choice but to participate in client tournaments and began to understand the fascination of wanting to get that little ball into that little hole in fewer strokes than the other guy or gal.  My competitive nature took over. </p>
<p><strong>By that same token, there is nothing boring about politics.  If that is what you think, you are merely uninformed.  If that is what you think, you have not been watching the debates. </strong></p>
<p>Could politics be an interest that develops with age? </p>
<p>Now, being at an age and in an income bracket where so many decisions made by politicians, directly affect me, have I simply just woken up? </p>
<p>Is it because I have Veterans in my family? </p>
<p>Perhaps it is due, in part, to my friends and family members in the military or due to my personal experience of military life.  </p>
<p>Maybe, my interest magnified after living in Europe and witnessing their economic and Healthcare issues. </p>
<p>Or, simply put, maybe I feel I am caught in the middle, as a member of the middle class, the knot in the tug of war between the political parties and a member of the gender they are currently squabbling over? </p>
<p>The only problem with this theory is that “we the people” are all affected by the decisions politicians make, whether they tell us what they are doing with our money or not, whether we realize what is happening in the world and how our country is tied to it or not, whether we are aware or not. </p>
<p>As an informed voter, I seek information via multiple television news sources, newspapers, magazines, the radio, the internet and in discussions with others.  It is not hard.  I absorb information while exercising, cooking, checking e-mail and driving, all with minimal effort.  I do not take much stock in celebrity endorsements.  Why trust a professional actor to be truthful?  Rather, I make my own decisions based on my values.  I have the advantage of knowing what those beliefs are and where the candidates stand on issues that are important to me.  Finally, I abhor desperate attempts by the candidates to smear one another or to placate me. </p>
<p>I may be a candidate’s worst nightmare.</p>
<p>For women in America, voting rights began in 1920, less than 100 years ago.  Respecting this right means that I know how fortunate I am to be an American woman.  Respecting this, means that I take my rights seriously.  Whichever candidate for whom you cast your vote, please, respect the right enough to make an informed decision.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/166/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/166/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=166&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://eileenslovak.com/2012/10/19/voting-rights/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>15</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/102fc445b4f3bf2127166bdbf2429a8a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">eileenslovak</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Opening Lines From Troubled Indie Novels</title>
		<link>http://breadandfriday.wordpress.com/2012/10/20/opening-lines-from-troubled-indie-novels/</link>
		<comments>http://breadandfriday.wordpress.com/2012/10/20/opening-lines-from-troubled-indie-novels/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2012 13:55:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>foxpudding</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Doom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Literature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mischief]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trouble]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://breadandfriday.wordpress.com/?p=1120</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Having defeated the zombie uprising, the ghouls were now suing in federal court for freer access to the nation’s cemeteries. from Toothpicks After Dark, by Jeremy Jeremiazocket “Do I need to nail every puppy to the barn, or just the ones who sound like whimpering demons?” asked Jessica around the nails in her mouth. from [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1120&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://breadandfriday.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/picking_teeth_by_teoteoteo.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1121" title="OLYMPUS DIGITAL CAMERA" alt="" src="http://breadandfriday.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/picking_teeth_by_teoteoteo.jpg" height="438" width="584" /></a></p>
<p>Having defeated the zombie uprising, the ghouls were now suing in federal court for freer access to the nation’s cemeteries.<br />
from <em>Toothpicks After Dark</em>, by Jeremy Jeremiazocket</p>
<p>“Do I need to nail every puppy to the barn, or just the ones who sound like whimpering demons?” asked Jessica around the nails in her mouth.<br />
from <em>Jessica of Willowsnips</em>, by Sally Ann Kittycuddle</p>
<p>“Forget it, Marge, I’m not letting you adopt an ungrammatical horse,” said Nelson.<br />
from <em>Mr. Bob, the Badly Talking Horse</em>, by Wilberrrrr Hutchinsuchin</p>
<p>“There is a certain type of publisher which insists on classifying anything with a teen protagonist as young adult,” thought thirteen year old Buck Stitt as he absent-mindedly buggered his Aunt Clara.<br />
from <em>Fifty Shades of Buck</em>, by Jerry X. Pedience</p>
<p>Charlotte  liked nothing better than to walk about naked in the mausoleum eating boiled eggs and drinking Carlsberg beer, ripping off a random fart against the cold marble of Uncle Fred’s sarcophagus.<br />
from <em>Charlotte’s Web Site</em> by E. B. White</p>
<p style="padding-left:240px;">&#8212;Don Whittington</p>
<p><a href="http://breadandfriday.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/bute-mausoleum.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1122" title="bute-mausoleum" alt="" src="http://breadandfriday.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/bute-mausoleum.jpg" height="438" width="584" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1120/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1120/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1120&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://breadandfriday.wordpress.com/2012/10/20/opening-lines-from-troubled-indie-novels/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>22</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/cfd2f6ecc48f5b7ae94f967c2452c1cd?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">foxpudding</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://breadandfriday.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/picking_teeth_by_teoteoteo.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">OLYMPUS DIGITAL CAMERA</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://breadandfriday.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/bute-mausoleum.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bute-mausoleum</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>NaNoWriMo: Embrace the Icky Sticky!</title>
		<link>http://davefarmersblog.wordpress.com/2012/10/15/nanowrimo-embrace-the-icky-sticky/</link>
		<comments>http://davefarmersblog.wordpress.com/2012/10/15/nanowrimo-embrace-the-icky-sticky/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2012 22:40:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dave Farmer</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[NaNoWriMo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Icky Sticky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[National Novel Writing Month]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plot twist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://davefarmersblog.wordpress.com/?p=5080</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Whether you&#8217;re a seasoned writer or a NoWriMo virgin, sooner or later you&#8217;ll probably reach a point I call The Lifeless River Bed of Despondency and Meh. This is where the initial adrenaline rush has driven your Storymobile across the rich and vivid fictional landscape only to find it splutter and grind to a halt. [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=5080&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://davefarmersblog.wordpress.com/2012/10/15/nanowrimo-embrace-the-icky-sticky/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>66</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/4d0425b41cd5870cf04d391f85342300?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F1.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">noobcake</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://davefarmersblog.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/ickysticky.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ickysticky</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://davefarmersblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/loveitliveit.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">loveitliveit</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>My Dark Secret</title>
		<link>http://1suburbanchic.wordpress.com/2012/10/17/my-dark-secret/</link>
		<comments>http://1suburbanchic.wordpress.com/2012/10/17/my-dark-secret/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2012 02:23:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>1suburbanchic</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Infertility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Abortion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Teen Pregnancy]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://1suburbanchic.wordpress.com/?p=303</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I have been going back and forth on when I should share this.  When I started my blog, I had no doubt I would eventually share it.  In part, I have been going through a healing process the past few months and I feel this is a step towards true healing. But, most importantly, I [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=303&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I have been going back and forth on when I should share this.  When I started my blog, I had no doubt I would eventually share it.  In part, I have been going through a healing process the past few months and I feel this is a step towards true healing. But, most importantly, I wanted to reach out to anyone who might be going through the same thing.</p>
<p><em>Note: I will probably end up deleting this post eventually, this sensitive subject is highly confidential personally.  But something inside me is saying that someone needs to hear this.</em></p>
<p>The year 2004, was a blur. I was a single mother, just coming out of a divorce.  A young-minded 25-year-old, I felt like I was invincible.  I was on a Divorcee Honeymoon.  Having fun was my life&#8217;s goal.  Last month, 8 years ago, we had just been through 3 of 4 hurricanes.  The power was out for 4 days in this little condo. We cooked out of the fireplace.  At night, we played board games by candlelight.  I had a friend, he was just a friend.  But, was it cabin fever? Was it curiosity? I am not sure.  But it was not a relationship either of us needed to pursue.  One-night-stand.</p>
<p>This month, 8 years ago, I jumped up. No symptoms, nothing out of the ordinary.  I just knew, I needed to take a test. Something in me was different.  And there it was a clear and quick answer&#8230;&#8230;. positive. I was pregnant.  Me, a &#8220;good girl&#8221; but already divorced, already a single mother: pregnant.  And this time, with no one to turn to.  My first thought, should I even call him?  I did. His answer, &#8220;you better take care of it.&#8221; So I did. I called the doctor. I went to a specialist, and at the time with my given diagnosis I would have been a high-risk pregnancy patient.  At that time I was diagnosed with Systemic Lupus. I was severely sick in the past, and my doctor was telling me the &#8216;worst case scenario&#8217; that I would be on bed rest the entire last half of the pregnancy.  I ran it through my mind, prayed, became numb, even put off the first appointment.  But I didn&#8217;t want it to draw out, I did what I thought I had to do: went to the clinic. I had an abortion.</p>
<p>My heart became numb, hate grew to its worst in my heart.  And I tried to forget.</p>
<p>See, last year, the same doctor that gave me the high-risk prognosis, took away my diagnosis of SLE.  Was I healed? Or had I not carried the disease all that time?  And for the first time in years, I realized that had he not told me I was going to be high-risk I would have kept the baby.</p>
<p>I said I tried to forget, yet I have not.  My unborn baby has been in the forefront of my thoughts many times through the day.  Often in my thoughts, my afterthoughts, and in my prayers.  She would have been 7, she might have shared the same birthday month as me and her eldest brother.  Sometimes I would imagine if she was with me in the car driving the kids to school.  And slowly, in the past few months, I have come to the realization that I need to let her go.  I need to let her be at peace, as she is in a much better place than I could ever have given her at that time.</p>
<p>I have dealt with the guilt, the sadness, the anger.  I hurt and ache, not because I am struggling now.  It&#8217;s the feeling that I would never want my children to hurt at my doing.  As much as I love my children, she would have been loved the same. I wished I could tell her that.</p>
<p>As I live month to month now <em>trying</em> to have a baby, I can&#8217;t help but wonder if I&#8217;m even worthy of the blessing, another chance. I pray, but I cringe. I am hopeful, yet cautious.</p>
<p>I have been seeing a lot of information on October 15th.  A day of remembrance for the Unborn Child.  For those lost in miscarriage, those who have not been conceived.  Not knowing if she fits into this day of remembrance, but I remember her&#8230; Often.  And she is my unborn child.</p>
<p><em>I am not writing this to advocate or not advocate for this sensitive subject.  My experiences have no bearing on a woman&#8217;s right to choose.  I am more writing this from an &#8220;infertile&#8221; point of view.  I want to share with you the dynamics of my darkest secret as someone who has now dealt with infertility for 3 years. </em></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/303/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/303/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=303&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://1suburbanchic.wordpress.com/2012/10/17/my-dark-secret/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>76</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/b509dd7a212af392d60db7b2c6907a8e?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">1suburbanchic</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is Time Travel Loopy? Or Is It Just Me?</title>
		<link>http://ozexpat.wordpress.com/2012/10/19/is-time-travel-loopy-or-is-it-just-me/</link>
		<comments>http://ozexpat.wordpress.com/2012/10/19/is-time-travel-loopy-or-is-it-just-me/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2012 17:23:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>creeped</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Existential]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cinema]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[film review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Looper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[time travel]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ozexpat.wordpress.com/?p=926</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Over the last couple of days, I have been ruminating my own theory on time travel. On Tuesday night, JD and I went to see the time-travel-actioner-cum-mind-screw-thriller, Looper. For those who haven&#8217;t heard of the film, I can&#8217;t be bothered outlining the synopsis. You can read one here or here. Or if you can watch the trailer here.  [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=926&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://ozexpat.wordpress.com/2012/10/19/is-time-travel-loopy-or-is-it-just-me/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>105</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://ozexpat.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/movie-quality-gradient.png?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://ozexpat.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/movie-quality-gradient.png?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Movie Quality Gradient</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/5ec5e2043c593cba217ab4147495393e?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">creeped</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ozexpat.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/looper-poster-quad_1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Looper-poster-quad_1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ozexpat.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/movie-quality-gradient.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Movie Quality Gradient</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ozexpat.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/physicist_stephen_hawking_in_zero_gravity_nasa1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Physicist_Stephen_Hawking_in_Zero_Gravity_NASA</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>