<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2013 20:02:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Stripped of My Desire to Create</title>
		<link>http://michellestodden.wordpress.com/2013/02/21/stripped-of-my-desire-to-create/</link>
		<comments>http://michellestodden.wordpress.com/2013/02/21/stripped-of-my-desire-to-create/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2013 03:11:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>michellestodden</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[desire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exercise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kids]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lost my muse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weight]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://michellestodden.wordpress.com/?p=2478</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve been out of commission for a while.  Not as in a my-organs-were-removed/repaired-and-I&#8217;m-recuperating sort of way, but in an I&#8217;ve-lost-all-drive-to-write sort of way.  Personally, the former would be easier for me to deal with.  I have a pretty high pain tolerance and not all organs are necessary for survival.  Just ask Slim Goodbody. I attempted to [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2478&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve been out of commission for a while.  Not as in a my-organs-were-removed/repaired-and-I&#8217;m-recuperating sort of way, but in an I&#8217;ve-lost-all-drive-to-write sort of way.  Personally, the former would be easier for me to deal with.  I have a pretty high pain tolerance and not all organs are necessary for survival.  Just ask Slim Goodbody.</p>
<div id="attachment_2492" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 186px"><a href="http://michellestodden.wordpress.com/2013/02/21/stripped-of-my-desire-to-create/tumblr_m7p19gbmk71rn2nm0o1_500/" rel="attachment wp-att-2492"><img class=" wp-image-2492  " alt="Bask in my greatness." src="http://michellestodden.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/tumblr_m7p19gbmk71rn2nm0o1_500.jpg?w=176&#038;h=300" width="176" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">You know you want it.</p></div>
<p>I attempted to pinpoint when the creative breakdown was conceived, but I failed to locate that nefarious moment.  I&#8217;ve no recent traumatizing situations to speak of, save for my friend&#8217;s Christmas party where she kept dumping out my drink in order to wash my glass.  I would set down my glass to talk to someone and then turn back around to take a sip of wine only to discover it sprouted legs and trotted away.  (I must warn you that one has to watch their plate around her, too.  It&#8217;s a compulsion she&#8217;s trying to tame.)</p>
<p>At any rate, my desire to create also sprouted legs and trotted away because I cannot summon a spark to save my wit.  But here&#8217;s the real kicker:  up until a few days ago, I didn&#8217;t even care.  The last time I can recall honestly giving a hoot about my writing was at the very beginning of the year.  My muse apparently jumped ship shortly thereafter, and who can blame her?  Apathetic behavior doesn&#8217;t exactly encourage your muse to whisper sweet nothings into your ear.</p>
<p>So what happened status-post amputation of 2012 that caused my creative decay?  Because my lack of desire hasn&#8217;t invaded other areas of my life.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve been highly focused on my physical and mental well-being since the beginning of the year.  Returning to my pre-Maya shape is one of my (seemingly unattainable) goals.  I gained weight throughout the last quarter of last year and it affected everything in my life.  My energy level plummeted, my mood sunk, my washer and dryer shrunk ALL of my clothes.  It was crazy.  Thus, dropping the weight isn&#8217;t <em>all</em> about my quest to build a sweet backside.  I keep a food log of what I eat and drink (wine has deliciously evil calories) so that I can hold myself accountable.  I exercise 5-6 days a week&#8211; jogging, walking a couple of miles during my lunch hour, working out to Bob Harper&#8217;s bitch of a<a href="http://www.amazon.com/Bob-Harper-Pure-Super-Strength/dp/B003ULW71Q/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1361394776&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=bob+harper+strength+dvd" target="_blank"> strength dvd</a>, working out to Jillian&#8217;s exercise dvds, even doing <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Brazil-Butt-Lift-BASE-Kit/dp/B00337MOMO/ref=sr_1_1?s=movies-tv&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1361394927&amp;sr=1-1&amp;keywords=brazil+butt+lift+leandro+carvalho" target="_blank">Brazil Butt Lift</a> workouts&#8211; and I&#8217;ve only managed to drop <em>almost</em> one size in eight weeks.  Almost, but not quite.  Needless to say, I am frustrated with my lack of bodily shrinkage.  My bubble butt and my thunder thighs are like adult children who won&#8217;t leave the nest.</p>
<p><del>My financial state still sucks.  I&#8217;m not going to go into detail right now, but it sucks.  Granted, I am far better off than most of the world</del> (<a href="http://www.statisticbrain.com/world-poverty-statistics/" target="_blank">World Poverty Statistics</a>), <del>so I truly shouldn&#8217;t complain.  In fact, I feel like a twat for even whining about my financial state</del>.</p>
<p>My financial state is fine, so that&#8217;s not it.</p>
<p>I think my work is draining me of all my creative spunk.  I love my boss and I am truly grateful to have a great job, but the endless corporate paperwork and red-tape and mounds of billing and unbelievably dense people wear me down.  By the time I arrive home, I&#8217;m a mental zombie.  I push myself through a workout and then cook dinner, wash dishes, play games and read to the girl, bath time, clean up, and then attempt to space out in a chair while the girl makes me sing the numbers 1 through 100 with her.  And then we sing ABC&#8217;s.  And then play &#8220;Alphabet.&#8221;  (<a href="http://www.schoolzone.com/flash-cards/alphabet-flash-cards" target="_blank">Alphabet flash cards</a> with words and pictures&#8211; all of which she has memorized and 3/4 of which she can spell upon quizzing.  She&#8217;s already smarter than I will ever be.)  When she&#8217;s finally done trying to stimulate my mind, Maya crashes around 10:30 and I am wiped out.  Understandably.  (And now you see how exciting my life is.)  I try to get up early to write, but it simply isn&#8217;t happening yet.  My body refuses to budge before 6:15.</p>
<p>Something has to give.  I need time to relax and create.  I don&#8217;t want to give up time with my kid, because even though she sometimes drives me bats, she&#8217;s a prodigious sponge who eagerly drinks in everything I teach.  We&#8217;re starting on beginner reading books and addition/subtraction and French lessons not because I want her to but because she LOVES it (her sitter is French, hence the French language thing).  Numbers are fun to her and I want to encourage her to learn as much as she can (while she still thinks it&#8217;s a game).  I can&#8217;t&#8211; I won&#8217;t&#8211; trade her developing, freakishly smart brain for my story.  Forget it.</p>
<p>I could give up work, but that means not having a home and car and food and having to go on welfare, which would make my self-confidence plummet and I would somehow end up with a bunch of cats and become a homeless hoarder pushing around a shopping cart full of one pre-schooler and her Alphabet cards, towels and mis-matched socks, lampshades, and old VHS tapes.  I know it.</p>
<div id="attachment_2525" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://michellestodden.wordpress.com/2013/02/21/stripped-of-my-desire-to-create/dscn0961/" rel="attachment wp-att-2525"><img class="size-medium wp-image-2525" alt="This would be my new home.  Wipe your feet at the door, please.  " src="http://michellestodden.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/dscn0961.jpg?w=300&#038;h=205" width="300" height="205" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">This would be my new home. Wipe your feet at the door, please.</p></div>
<p>So we&#8217;re down to my body.  I will trade my body for creative gain.  Well, not trade my actual body.  I&#8217;m not sacrificing a kidney to gain a screenplay or anything like that.  But maybe it&#8217;s time to drop a day of exercise and see what happens.  Go down to 4 or 5 days and play around with my diet. Throw in a light smoothie in place of dinner here and there.  (This does mean I&#8217;ll have to buy a blender.)  Purchase some Spanx and call it good.  Who knows.  Maybe I&#8217;ll have more energy in the long run.</p>
<p>I have to give it a shot.  My characters are moping about because I haven&#8217;t had them out to play.  I feel like a bad parent.  They <em>want</em> me to let them out, too.  Dick is straining to hold back sarcastic remarks; Priti&#8217;s nose twitches with my every peek into their world; and Adam and Rebecca sit next to each other, hands close but not touching, and wait to see in which direction I will nudge their cracked relationship.  But my desire to set my characters free and run around is not entirely present.  Almost there, but not quite.  Perhaps this rambling, go-nowhere blog entry will help me release whatever (bad writing maybe?) holding me back.</p>
<p>Anyone else have this happen?  Does the heaviness of everyday life (or your body) strip you of your desire to create for a period of time?  Any suggestions?</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://michellestodden.wordpress.com/category/health/'>Health</a>, <a href='http://michellestodden.wordpress.com/category/life/'>Life</a>, <a href='http://michellestodden.wordpress.com/category/writing/'>Writing</a>  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2478&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://michellestodden.wordpress.com/2013/02/21/stripped-of-my-desire-to-create/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>20</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/d771abf1ce50d5a21a4ce2673662c525?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">michellestodden</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://michellestodden.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/tumblr_m7p19gbmk71rn2nm0o1_500.jpg?w=176" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Bask in my greatness.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://michellestodden.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/dscn0961.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">This would be my new home.  Wipe your feet at the door, please.  </media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chronicles of Reverse Culture Shock: Restaurants (My Kingdom for a Bing-Bong)</title>
		<link>http://anageonism.wordpress.com/2013/02/22/restaurants-bing-bong-and-tipping/</link>
		<comments>http://anageonism.wordpress.com/2013/02/22/restaurants-bing-bong-and-tipping/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2013 16:08:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>stupiduglyforeigner</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture Shock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life in Korea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture shock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[korea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[restaurants]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://anageonism.wordpress.com/?p=1654</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[“Well, when I lived in Asia…” begin so many of my sentences these days. Moving away is hard, and as it turns out, so is moving back. Chronicles of Reverse Culture Shock is a series devoted to these difficulties, and is also an outlet so that I don’t become That Guy Who Won’t Shut Up [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1654&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 394px"><a title="Bask by stupiduglyforeigner, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/anageonism/6249653162/"><img alt="Bask" src="http://farm7.staticflickr.com/6159/6249653162_5b7d1ceee6_z.jpg" width="384" height="256" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Time for Korean food by the bucket.</p></div>
<p><i>“Well, when I lived in </i>Asia<i>…” begin so many of my sentences these days. Moving away is hard, and as it turns out, so is moving back. Chronicles of Reverse Culture Shock is a series devoted to these difficulties, and is also an outlet so that I don’t become That Guy Who Won’t Shut Up About Korea to all of his friends. </i></p>
<p>A Korean restaurant in Korea is a beautiful, efficient kind of place. You enter, sit at your table, and order essentially within the first moments. The menus are not terribly voluminous, and the assumption is that if you entered this restaurant in the first place, you knew what you were coming for. (Many restaurants specialize in exactly one kind of dish, so you say how many of the foods you want and in what, if any, variations.) The waiters disappear, and rush back with your steaming bowl or your rack of raw ingredients and leave you to it. They will not check on you, they will not make small talk, they will not feign interest, and they will not interact with you unless they you summon them by the convenient doorbell on your table (<i>bing-bong!</i>). They give you food and then leave you alone, and at the end of the meal you take the bill, which was already at your table, and pay elsewhere and never ever think of leaving them a tip. The people operating the restaurant are unobtrusive, practically invisible, more spectral visions of humans, ghosts carrying trays that exist only in your peripheral vision.</p>
<p>Which is to say that a Korean restaurant in Korea is my idea of paradise.</p>
<p><span id="more-1654"></span></p>
<p>When I first arrived, of course, the process was a little jarring. I was used to highly attentive wait staff, indentured young people who hovered off in the middle distance constantly watching though only interrupting precisely when needed. My cup would never go empty, because someone in a dress shirt and an embarrassing nametag would rush to my aid the moment we passed a critical beverage threshold. My food would arrive hot, and exactly synchronously with the food of my companions, and it would come with a side of blowsy smalltalk. I could be wished happy birthday, or talk about my work, or about the weather, or about television. Something innocuous and comforting and sweet, and the waiter could coolly lull me into the belief that they cared, and I in turn would give them money for nursing the illusion that the world was not a scary, desolate place full of people who hated every stranger they saw. I knew this restaurant tango, had grown with it, had seen it as the way of the world.</p>
<p>So to be in Korea, where the waiters will never look you in the eye and will only come if you summon them by scream or electronic buzzer, seemed impersonal and terrifying. What a cold, robotic world! No one pretends to like me or pays attention to how much drink I have drunk!</p>
<p>The acclimation, however, was swift. Korean waiters respond to a shout or a buzz with practiced speed and efficiency. The middle-man is often cut out, and food preparation is left to my own hands. Interruptions only arise if a waiter or restaurateur feels they can improve the deliciousness of my meal for me, either through dips or assembling the constituent ingredients to one harmonious, perfected whole. The table is littered with so many dishes I don’t even know what to do with all of them, and it becomes my fiefdom, my own precious Tetris territory of bowls and chopsticks and eternally replenished side-dishes.</p>
<p>The most space-aged restaurants have specialty bing-bongs on their tables, adorned with specialized buttons detailing the nature of your needs. Press this button for more beer, this one for soju, this one for more meat. Press three for more ambrosia. Press 10 for a side of unicorn shavings. Press six for the table to convert into a time machine that takes you on a magical journey to old prospector times. Press 9 for an alternate dimension where everyone is actually a frog and the sky is made of ice cream. Press the central button to call an operator for any other inquiries. Minimize human interaction, maximize rate of gorging, and enjoy your glorious futuristic magic table.</p>
<p>I fell in love with the system. Whatever semblance of hope I derived from the training-mandated waiter smalltalk in Canada, I could probably squeeze from my eating companions. Whatever marvels experienced from an efficient kitchen could easily be replaced in my heart by a central grill and the power to wield my own tongs. And I didn’t have to tip anyone.</p>
<p>But now I am back in the homeland, and every excursion to a restaurant is fraught with anxiety and terror. I feel, in some ways, like I am speaking with earphones in: always too loud or too quiet, unaware of how I come off, incapable of speaking like a human being. I am Pinocchio just recently transformed into a real boy, and I still haven&#8217;t worked out all of the quirks. I am a robot, and have not yet been taught this human emotion called love, nor with it the ability not to freak out in a restaurant. It feels like all my capabilities for normal, socialized restaurant interactions have completely withered.</p>
<div class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 394px"><a title="First udon by stupiduglyforeigner, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/anageonism/7293614074/"><img alt="First udon" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8156/7293614074_34dd13e167_z.jpg" width="384" height="256" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">In Japan, you just order by vending machine, and everything turns out okay.</p></div>
<p>Why are the waiters all talking and smiling at me? Are they making fun of me, or planning to steal my wallet? Am I allowed to summon them in some capacity, or is it deemed rude? A “hello?” A polite wave? Gentle eye contact? Signal fire? Will they think me boorish and impatient for not waiting until they finish up with table six, will they deem my needs sufficient or treat me with disdain for the rest of the meal?</p>
<p>Why does this menu have so many <i>things</i> in it? We’re not in a grocery store. I already made the decision to enter the restaurant, and everything else should be taken care of for me. And are those prices in won? Hong Kong dollars, perhaps? Because if they’re in local currency, then we are being gouged, and maybe we should probably make a run for it.</p>
<p>The greatest struggle comes when I go to a Korean restaurant in Canada, a strange borderland, the interstitial grab-bag of restaurant culture effluvia that I cannot begin to decipher. Can I summon a waiter? Should I order in Korean or English? Exactly how pretentious am I allowed to be while consuming this food, judging its flavour and authenticity with permanently upturned nose? And tips&#8211;I’m paying at the cash register, and there is no tip jar. Or there is a tip jar, but the value of currency currently inside of it is pitiful. Or I paid at my table, but the waiter did what a Korean waiter would do, so do I tip them like a Korean or a Canadian waiter? My hands begin to tremble as I clutch loose quarters and loonies in my greedy fist. Sweat is pooling in every crevice I have. If I mangle this, I will either look like a cheapskate or an over-generous rube. If I mangle any other part of the restaurant action, I seem like maybe I was raised by wolves&#8211;wolves that didn&#8217;t go out to restaurants very often. If I do the wrong thing with the waiters, if I do things in the wrong restaurant order, if I mishandle the various equipment on the table&#8212;&#8211;</p>
<p>I think maybe I’ll just start eating at home.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1654/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1654/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1654&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://anageonism.wordpress.com/2013/02/22/restaurants-bing-bong-and-tipping/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>15</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/93e3fb215f447a36c2518e397ce17a74?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">stupiduglyforeigner</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm7.staticflickr.com/6159/6249653162_5b7d1ceee6_z.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Bask</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8156/7293614074_34dd13e167_z.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">First udon</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>John McPhee Discusses Chronological Structure</title>
		<link>http://richardgilbert.me/2013/02/13/john-mcphee-on-chronological-structure/</link>
		<comments>http://richardgilbert.me/2013/02/13/john-mcphee-on-chronological-structure/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 04:43:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Richard Gilbert</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[craft, technique]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[essay-narrative]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[memoir]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[narrative]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NOTED]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[structure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[theme]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[John McPhee]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://richardgilbert.me/?p=4220</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Chronology is useful but hostile to thematic content, the writer says. You can build a structure in such a way that it causes people to want to keep turning pages. A compelling structure in nonfiction can have an attracting effect analogous to a story line in fiction.—John McPhee, in The New Yorker “There’s nothing wrong [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4220&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://richardgilbert.me/2013/02/13/john-mcphee-on-chronological-structure/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/865f85d6dec304d99ef51947699fa5be?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">richardgilbert</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://richardgilbert.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/futuristic-ceiling-x.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Futuristic Ceiling x</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://richardgilbert.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/mcpheeart.gif" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">McPheeArt</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Atheist Jew Meets Churchy Jesus Girl: A Discussion</title>
		<link>http://eastmeetsbreast.wordpress.com/2013/02/20/atheist-jew-meets-churchy-jesus-girl-a-discussion/</link>
		<comments>http://eastmeetsbreast.wordpress.com/2013/02/20/atheist-jew-meets-churchy-jesus-girl-a-discussion/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2013 23:04:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Britt</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Church]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DP Challenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Episcopalian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Faith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gay Marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jewish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Religion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Steve Safran]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://eastmeetsbreast.wordpress.com/?p=412</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Steve is a non-religious Jew, and I am an observant Episcopalian, but we both value irreverence. Recently, Stevie wrote this to me in an email: “As you might guess, the only thing I know about Vestry is that the word ‘rector’ is hilarious. I would love to sit down and discuss religion with you at [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=412&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p><em>Steve is a non-religious Jew, and I am an observant Episcopalian, but we both value irreverence. Recently, Stevie wrote this to me in an email:</em></p>
<p>“As you might guess, the only thing I know about Vestry is that the word ‘rector’ is hilarious. I would love to sit down and discuss religion with you at some point. Religious discussions in this country are all about &#8216;me versus you, and I&#8217;m right.&#8217; People who are religious genuinely fascinate me. I often envy them their beliefs. However I tend to infuriate the believers, with my rampant joke-laden atheism.”</p>
<p><em>Steve drafted a list of topics, and we both promised not to get all huffy. What follows is a transcript of our virtual “sit down.” I hope we don&#8217;t offend, and that maybe you&#8217;ll share your take on God, Life, and Whatnot, too.</em></p></blockquote>
<p><strong>ON ONE&#8217;S RELIGION:</strong></p>
<p>STEVE:<br />
I call myself very Jewish and not religious. That&#8217;s what I like about Judaism. It&#8217;s à la carte. My Bar Mitzvah was in a Unitarian church because my temple was still under construction. I call myself a &#8220;Jewnatarian.&#8221; If I were Christian, I&#8217;d go with Unitarianism. It&#8217;s hip to say &#8220;I&#8217;d like to be Buddhist,&#8221; but that requires meditation, and there&#8217;s stuff on TV.</p>
<p>BRITT:<br />
I like Jewnatarian. Unitarians don’t subscribe to a divine Jesus, seeing Him more like a moral Michael Jordan: a bit super-human in his awesomeness, and thus, someone to emulate. Being Jewish is a birthright you cannot escape… but God gifted His chosen people with good bagels, Yiddish-spewing grandparent hilarity, and irrepressibly sexy teenage girls. Adding the “religious” component of Being Jewish with all that Hebrew-learning and rule-following is exhausting, and gets in the way of a good bacon cheeseburger. So although Zealot Sister will balk at your à la carte approach to religion, as… well… not very religious, I understand being choosy. I found all of the beauty and tradition of the Catholic Church over in the pews with the Episcopalians. But this crowd of Christians aims for the broadest interpretation of Scripture to include all of us… especially our fabulous gay friends.</p>
<p><a href="http://eastmeetsbreast.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/love.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-426" alt="LOVE" src="http://eastmeetsbreast.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/love.png?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>We believe in One Holy Catholic (meaning everyone) and apostolic Church. It’s right there in The Creed… and I wear a cross to remind me of The Big Picture. Being a responsible “religious” person also means a perpetual auditing of Bible 101. Only by attending Church and Bible study sessions can we learn what God’s teaching means in this world. The Bible was never meant to be studied in isolation. Faith needn’t be blind, and for thoughtful people, “religiousity” will likely wax and wane.</p>
<p>STEVE:<br />
I followed your first paragraph, but you lost me on the second. Why must one attend a given building and the meetings therein to relate to meaning in the world? It’s true, Judaism has the whole Talmudic tradition. But even there, the goal isn’t to find answers – it’s to ask more questions. It’s nice to be part of a faith where a perfectly good “answer” ends with the suffix “-ish.”</p>
<p>BRITT:<br />
I don’t want to lose you. One mustn’t do anything to know God! However, to understand how Bible teachings relate to today (or to <em>your</em> life), that is most responsibly done with some sort of guidance&#8211; maybe from someone with a PhD and a snazzy white collar? An example: with sufficient smarts and determination, one could possibly learn everything a medical student learns… but would you go to the “homeschooled” doctor? Why should the study of a religious practice be any different?</p>
<p><strong>ON FAITH:</strong></p>
<p>BRITT:<br />
Faith is the sticky wicket. For those of us who claim to be religious, it would seem that Faith should be as constant as a heartbeat. But, it’s not. The religious people I relate to (drink with) tend to work on this part the hardest. On the other hand, those with the arrogance to dismiss Faith entirely sound sadly unenlightened to me (this article in particular drives me bonkers &#8220;<a href="http://ireport.cnn.com/docs/DOC-910282?fb_action_ids=10151416686831397&amp;fb_action_types=og.recommends&amp;fb_source=aggregation&amp;fb_aggregation_id=288381481237582)">Why I Raise My Children Without God</a>&#8220;) Those with no Faith at all should be a great deal funnier about it. Also, many of these same people sanction Santa and tooth fairy lies with a near religious zeal. Admittedly, if you think they’re <em>all</em> fiction, you gotta go with the ones that deliver iPhones and cash.</p>
<p>STEVE:<br />
I don’t know if we’re funnier, but we do have more fun. Why is religion so full of rules against fun? Plus they are <em>so</em> anti-women. The Catholic Church won’t allow female priests&#8211; or contraception. No premarital sex. And as anyone who has had post-marital sex will tell you, if you can’t have premarital sex, there’s not much left on your horizon. Jews kept the women upstairs in the sanctuary before they realized “Hey&#8211; there’s women here. Maybe get them a seat we should?” Then there are the religions that, well, you know, kill the women for behaving like women and… why isn’t Britt making this argument?</p>
<p>BRITT:<br />
The topic here is Faith, not Religious Rules. So, here’s a quote from a rabbi: “Let’s say, for argument’s sake, that there is even the slightest chance that there is a God. Then wouldn’t learning about Him be the most important thing to do?” The key here is learning. That’s why I go to Church: to learn, even if what I take away on any given Sunday is something-ish.</p>
<p>I have little faith in a community that scorns Faith: even a faith-less community is more agreeable one that is all shout-y and against it. Religion attempts to access Truth as much as science does, just with fewer t-tests and, unfortunately, more than a handful of loud, unreliable reviewers.</p>
<p>But please don&#8217;t caught up in arbitrary rules of religions you don’t study! The Catholic Church, at times, leans more heavily toward tradition than Scripture. So what? You’re not Catholic. Leave them be to have all of their married sex and gazillion babies. It’s not your religion. In our country, women have the luxury of finding a religion that honors their participation. I cannot explain why Zealot Sister chooses to follow such difficult rules any more than I can explain why Jason (our favorite Orthodox Jew) has two sets of plates. I don&#8217;t know enough about any religion to criticize people who follow them, but I have great respect for Zealot Sister and Jason who study their religions and try their best to honor their guidelines.</p>
<p>The rules are easy targets for dismissal of Faith, so let&#8217;s be clear: The Bible is not a rule book, but a record of God’s presence and the life of Jesus. Paul offers this regarding strict adherence to dietary guidelines (e.g., arbitrary rules): “eat the food or not, as you please, but give no offense to others and do all for the glory of God.” You do your thing, I’ll do mine, and let there be no quibbling. I like that.</p>
<p><strong>ON LIFE:</strong></p>
<p>STEVE:<br />
A considerable improvement on the alternative, but in need of a rewrite.</p>
<p>BRITT:<br />
Really, Stevie… On Life? All I know is that those Life Is Good products are more irritating than people who can’t shut up about politics. I have no idea why this condescendingly simple message delights the masses… and yet a God is Good coffee mug would have people giving wide berth around your cubicle. And isn’t there all sorts of “life” that is no good at all? Mushy brain on a ventilator? Not so good. No stick figure t-shirt for that.</p>
<div id="attachment_418" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 533px"><a href="http://eastmeetsbreast.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/life-is-good.png"><img class="size-full wp-image-418" alt="This is so, so wrong... so obviously I think it's oddly funny." src="http://eastmeetsbreast.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/life-is-good.png?w=720"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">I imagine Jesus is wicked funny, totally has this t-shirt, and looks great in yellow.</p></div>
<p>I also tend to think a little God infusion wouldn’t hurt when someone’s Life seems empty, sad, broken, ill fated, unfairly difficult, or about to end. I don’t believe prayers are answered, exactly, but moments of real humility on my knees asking for guidance have been instructive to me. And if you feel it, the Holy Spirit is fantastic at reminding you of the beauty and connectivity of the Life in all of us. What makes this worldview palatable (and you and me friends) is admitting that people who talk like this sound utterly insane.</p>
<p>STEVE:<br />
OK, even I should have been less flip. Life is pretty great. Neat stuff. Arrogant to think that we’re the center of it and that we’re the only ones who invented the sandwich. For every billion planets, I bet there are thousand variations on corned beef. Some may be silicon based, but even a, well, sand-based sandwich could work.</p>
<p>There are still religions that insist that you take literally that we are the center of the universe. Or – again – they will kill you. Just try to get corned beef then. Even dry corned beef.</p>
<div id="attachment_419" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 283px"><a href="http://eastmeetsbreast.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/alien.png"><img class="size-full wp-image-419" alt="A sandwich-eating alien is only ever one click away." src="http://eastmeetsbreast.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/alien.png?w=720"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">On her planet, she&#8217;s the Queen of Sandwich&#8230; and a Lutheran.</p></div>
<p><strong>ON DEATH:</strong></p>
<p>STEVE:<br />
The end. Game over. Not to happen again. Like being asleep, except without worrying about forgetting about finals. Kind of the ultimate final, actually. Terrible invention. That’s what I mean about needing a rewrite.</p>
<p>BRITT:<br />
Oh, Steve. I hate that I agree with you here. But then my Faith creeps in (and also C.S. Lewis with <a href="http://www.goodreads.com/work/quotes/1215780-the-great-divorce">The Great Divorce</a>) with the slimmest possibility of something more. Scientist Britt can’t argue it well, though.</p>
<p><strong>ON GOD&#8217;S LOVE</strong></p>
<p>BRITT:<br />
Cathy George, our rector (hee hee) advised us at Lenten time not fixate on trying to be holy. “You are already holy.” God’s love makes us holy, and God loves all of us. A Ma often cites evidence of God’s love for our family, but I don’t think that way. Good luck is not God’s love. There’s no such thing as circumstantial confirmation that we’re in good with The Big Guy. God’s love is constant, and the proof we’re looking for when our Faith is flagging. For me, it’s something I actually feel. Unfortunately bad writers have been making believers sound stupid and corny for ages (like <a href="http://www.insetdesigns.com/footprints_in_the_sand-1.html">this</a> nonsense).</p>
<p>STEVE:<br />
I don&#8217;t like it when people shoehorn &#8220;God&#8221; as a metaphor into things. As in &#8220;&#8216;God&#8217; is really about the love you feel when…&#8221; or &#8220;You see God in the face of a newborn child.&#8221; I don&#8217;t see any such thing. I see beauty, yes. I see something wonderful and amazing. But it seems that calling that &#8220;God&#8221; is stretching the original description rather than admitting it&#8217;s a different concept.</p>
<p>BRITT:<br />
But it’s not entirely different. I’ll admit it’s an easy explanation to a complicated theological question. But as a small child, those giant cloth banners embroidered with God Is Love put an earthly tag on something indescribable. Moments of beauty aren’t God, per se, but they do summon the teeniest essence of Him… and are, thus, divine!</p>
<p>STEVE:<br />
I need to throw this back at you as a question – how do you feel God’s love?</p>
<p>BRITT:<br />
Brace yourself for the crazy, but remember that you know me to be a smarter than average blond girl with all sorts of science degrees and a good degree of skepticism. I also love to make fun of just about everything. But you asked, so here goes. God’s love is unsullied belief in your own worth. For me, ironically, it means getting on my knees and admitting my complete incompetence to understand anything. Regarding God, we’re all idiots. But in those moments of prayer (meditation? begging for impossible things?), God’s love feels warm, calm. Do you know deep down&#8211; in spite of school shootings and war and Kardashians&#8211; that people are inherently good (that you are inherently good)? That’s God’s love. It’s omnipresent and free, but in our busy, angry world, it’s easy to overlook. Plus, there’s stuff on TV.</p>
<p><strong>ON SCIENCE AND RELIGION</strong></p>
<p>STEVE:<br />
&#8220;The wonderful thing about science,&#8221; said Neil DeGrasse Tyson, &#8220;is that it&#8217;s true whether you believe it or not.&#8221; You may have seen this quote floating around Facebook. He said it on “Real Time with Bill Maher” in response to someone saying he didn&#8217;t believe in something scientific. I love this quote and it summarizes my relationship with religion perfectly.</p>
<p>BRITT:<br />
I loathe Bill Maher. He argues so smugly (and so poorly) against religion, and also thinks people like me are loons. Picking through the Bible or highlighting any number of religious beliefs out of context is just poor journalism. Back in college I thought science and religious beliefs were at odds, so I dismissed the latter to embrace what I could see and prove. Now I realize that they can co-exist. And now, I might even put forward this: “The wonderful thing about God, is that He exists whether you believe or not.”</p>
<div id="attachment_415" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 533px"><a href="http://eastmeetsbreast.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/bill-maher.png"><img class="size-full wp-image-415" alt="I'm right... you crazy!" src="http://eastmeetsbreast.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/bill-maher.png?w=720"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">I&#8217;m right&#8230; and you crazy!</p></div>
<p>STEVE:<br />
OK, Bill Maher is a dick. Given. Atheist zealots are every bit as irritating as religious door-knockers. But we’re talking proof, not faith. A star cluster exists, demonstrably. Life evolved – and did so over millions of years. This is not up for discussion. I can look in a sky and see such wonders that the founders of religion couldn’t have imagined.</p>
<p>“There are more things in heaven and earth Horatio than are dreamt of in your philosophy.” – Hamlet, Act 1, Scene 5. Great line, but dammit – he had to put “heaven” in there.</p>
<p>If “God” and his scribes knew all His wonders, surely He would have thought to include them in his teachings: “Not only is man an amazing creation of Mine – but whoa! You have got to see the work I do with galaxy clusters, quasars, collapsing stars, dark matter, and – oh yes – a few planets right near by.” He might have gone on less about fish.</p>
<p>BRITT:<br />
Laughing too hard to comment. And God in quotations is killing me.</p>
<p><strong>ON COMFORT:</strong></p>
<p>STEVE:<br />
I take no comfort from otherworldly things. That&#8217;s scary. That&#8217;s something I envy in religious people. I can find comfort in my children, loved ones and friends. But I gather it&#8217;s not the same comfort.</p>
<p>BRITT:<br />
God isn’t otherworldly. He’s right here.</p>
<p>STEVE:<br />
You’re not mentioning comfort.</p>
<p>BRITT:<br />
The comfort: I’m never, never alone. Strip away Bernie, my kids, my pretty stucco life and ask me if I still have the Comfort of God? I dunno. But last year, when there were moments when I didn’t know if I’d be here to have this discussion, my sole comfort came from God. You can’t knock that.</p>
<p><strong>ON FANATICISM:</strong></p>
<p>BRITT:<br />
Blech. Religious fanaticism always excludes, hurts, even kills.</p>
<p>STEVE:<br />
I love people who have faith and kindness. (Although I don&#8217;t see why you need faith to be kind.) I do dislike fanatics &#8211; those who say their way is the only way. When you go from belief to fanaticism, that&#8217;s when the Holy Hand Grenades tend to come out. Fanaticism also leads to hooligans and tedious, low-scoring soccer games.</p>
<div id="attachment_422" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 533px"><a href="http://eastmeetsbreast.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/soccer-fan1.png"><img class="size-full wp-image-422" alt="In these hats, we trust." src="http://eastmeetsbreast.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/soccer-fan1.png?w=720"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">In these hats, we trust.</p></div>
<p>BRITT:<br />
I completely agree that Faith has little to do with kindness, or even human decency. Faith is a personal matter. Kindness is a public one.</p>
<p><strong>ON THE BEAUTY OF THE UNIVERS</strong>E</p>
<p>STEVE:<br />
Oh God, it fucking rocks. Wait &#8211; I just invoked God. Maybe there&#8217;s something there.</p>
<p>BRITT:<br />
Of course there is. Make fun all you want (I insist!), but there are other Jewnatarians out there just waiting to set up folding chairs with you in some temple basement. In the meantime, I’m going to drag you to the <a href="http://www.redeemerchestnuthill.org/">Redeemer</a>. There’s a whole Bible study group of women who have been praying for you. (Can you feel it?)</p>
<p>STEVE:<br />
I like that. Can they pray for me to have less back hair?</p>
<div id="attachment_416" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 533px"><a href="http://eastmeetsbreast.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/back-hair.png"><img class="size-full wp-image-416" alt="Half atheist?" src="http://eastmeetsbreast.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/back-hair.png?w=720"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Results may vary.</p></div>
<p><a href="http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2013/02/18/writing-challenge-image-vs-text/">(DP Challenge)</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/412/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/412/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=412&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://eastmeetsbreast.wordpress.com/2013/02/20/atheist-jew-meets-churchy-jesus-girl-a-discussion/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>34</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/eceb4c9eeb9f4e7a46803fa57dedc3ea?s=96&#38;d=retro&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mewhinneylee</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://eastmeetsbreast.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/love.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">LOVE</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://eastmeetsbreast.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/life-is-good.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">This is so, so wrong... so obviously I think it&#039;s oddly funny.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://eastmeetsbreast.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/alien.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">A sandwich-eating alien is only ever one click away.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://eastmeetsbreast.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/bill-maher.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">I&#039;m right... you crazy!</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://eastmeetsbreast.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/soccer-fan1.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">In these hats, we trust.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://eastmeetsbreast.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/back-hair.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Half atheist?</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Let\&#8217;s Talk About Muses</title>
		<link>http://lcspoering.wordpress.com/2013/02/06/lets-talk-about-muses/</link>
		<comments>http://lcspoering.wordpress.com/2013/02/06/lets-talk-about-muses/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2013 04:36:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>L.C. Spoering</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inspiration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://lcspoering.wordpress.com/?p=49</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Or not. Because that&#8217;s just stupid. Moreover, I&#8217;m interested in the actual topic of inspiration versus just sit down and work. In the interest of full disclosure: I am not good at anything but writing. I have a creative brain but little in the way of skills. My crafting is almost always a one-time thing. [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=49&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Or not. Because that&#8217;s just stupid.</p>
<p>Moreover, I&#8217;m interested in the actual topic of inspiration versus just sit down and work.</p>
<p>In the interest of full disclosure: I am not good at anything but writing. I have a creative brain but little in the way of skills. My crafting is almost always a one-time thing. I would never call myself a good artist (and I believe my art school instructors would hasten to agree with me). I have no skill with language or math, a terrible memory for history and facts, and a sort of stereotypical dislike for science. In short, I could never be anything but a writer. I just suck at everything else.</p>
<p>I do not think I am special. If anything, I&#8217;d say I&#8217;m more pathetic than your average bear. My skills are rooted in sitting around and amusing myself with imaginary people, and then typing what I think. It&#8217;s not a far cry from a monkey with a typewriter, except for the fact I rarely throw feces.</p>
<p>You did catch the <em>rarely</em> part, right?</p>
<p>I don&#8217;t believe in inspiration. Inspiration sounds entirely too divine to describe what I do. I sit,  I think, and my brain does its job. WELL DONE, BRAIN. Here&#8217;s a cookie in the form of endorphins brought on by sex and wine.</p>
<p>I fear for those writers who elevate the process to something akin to a religious experience. We are not God, even in our little made-up worlds. Stories, in order to function, require a more articulate hand than that of God. It&#8217;s tinkering, not a great flood or&#8230; something (let&#8217;s be honest here: not only am I not a Biblical scholar, but I don&#8217;t really care, either. I was raised by apathetic agnostics, after all. Our spiritual beliefs are summed up with an &#8220;eh, I suppose something could be out there. Or not.&#8221;)</p>
<p>To believe one is evolved, elevated, in such a way is dangerous dangerous thinking. To claim one needs inspiration to churn out a clump of words is ridiculous. Wouldn&#8217;t you think a neurosurgeon refusing to operate because he was &#8220;lacking inspiration&#8221; horrifying? How self-indulgent.</p>
<p>Okay, fine, a writer isn&#8217;t really saving lives (let&#8217;s not get too metaphorical here). But the commentary still stands.</p>
<p>A writer is a writer because they write. Sitting around and not writing is, what, a thinker? And he doesn&#8217;t even <em>move</em>.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ll be here all week, people.</p>
<p>PS. I misspelled &#8220;inspiration&#8221; every single time I attempted it in this post. My inability to spell can be a topic for another time.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/49/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/49/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=49&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://lcspoering.wordpress.com/2013/02/06/lets-talk-about-muses/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>49</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/3d342dd90021395a7883a8cfbf81e79b?s=96&#38;d=retro&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lcspoering</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Seeing the World Through Google-Coloured Glasses</title>
		<link>http://prakkypedia.prakky.com.au/2013/02/21/seeing-the-world-through-google-coloured-glasses/</link>
		<comments>http://prakkypedia.prakky.com.au/2013/02/21/seeing-the-world-through-google-coloured-glasses/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2013 23:15:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Prakky</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[privacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://prakkypedia.prakky.com.au/?p=2113</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Yesterday a car did a burn-out in my street. It was noisy and disruptive and smelly and offensive. I could see the car doing it. I could read the registration number. And I thought: if I was wearing Google Glasses right now, I could record this. And then perhaps pass it onto the police for them [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2113&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><b>Yesterday a car did a burn-out in my street. It was noisy and disruptive and smelly and offensive.</b></p>
<p>I could see the car doing it. I could read the registration number. And I thought: if I was wearing <a title="Google Glasses explanation, Wikipedia" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Project_Glass" target="_blank">Google Glasses</a> right now, I could record this. And then perhaps pass it onto the police for them to follow up. Or post to YouTube for the audiences who like that type of thing.</p>
<p>I’m excited by Google Glasses.</p>
<p>I love the idea of easily being able to capture and share images and video. This includes sharing imagery with others live.</p>
<p><b>But I’m also pondering what could go wrong.</b></p>
<p>If Google Glasses become widely used, there’s potential for a massive impact on our behaviour and in particular the way we interact with each other.</p>
<p>Imagine somebody wearing Google glasses and sharing their experience while they’re:</p>
<ul>
<li>being sanctioned in the workplace</li>
<li>in a classroom where a teacher is reprimanding a student</li>
<li>witness to a street fight</li>
<li>having an argument with their spouse</li>
<li>being interviewed for a job</li>
<li>at the scene of an accident where a resuscitation is taking place</li>
</ul>
<div id="attachment_2115" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 265px"><a href="http://prakky.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/prakkygoogleglasses2.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-2115" alt="Mega artistic vision of a Google Glasses future by Prakky" src="http://prakky.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/prakkygoogleglasses2.jpg?w=255&#038;h=300" width="255" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Mega artistic vision of a Google Glasses future by Prakky</p></div>
<p>If you and I are having an important conversation – even a dispute – and I put on my pair of Google Glasses, how would you react?</p>
<p>Some spaces – schools, workplaces – may ban such devices. But what’s to stop a person walking down a street capturing that image of you littering / jaywalking / falling over/ picking your nose?</p>
<p><i>Sure. We’re all going to be super well behaved so it won’t matter.</i></p>
<p>Which raises the question: could Google Glasses’ content be the subject of witness accounts and therefore court proceedings? What does that mean – not just for us but for Google as a company?</p>
<p><b>Think sexting is a problem now?</b></p>
<p>Imagine the ease of filming – and live sharing – your girlfriend or boyfriend disrobing, showering, dancing around naked and so on. (Sure, wearing Google glasses may reduce your chances of reaching said intimacy, but hey …)</p>
<p>Do celebrities wish the paparazzi and Twitter and Instagram hadn’t been invented? Just wait until the world’s wearing Google Glasses!</p>
<p>There were complaints when Google Streetview was relatively new, and captured images of some people doing embarrassing things. We seem to have learned to live with Streetview now. (The Google Streetview capture of our house shows one of my son’s putting out the rubbish bins. A rare moment captured for the world). And yes, we already have the technology to be able to share images and video quickly and easily. But we’re talking about <i>glasses</i> here, people! Minimalist-looking glasses which could become ubiquitous and make us think twice about what we do in our everyday lives for fear of being on the world’s stage or having our recorded actions pored over later by others without context.</p>
<p>Don’t get me wrong. I can see that Google Glasses can be used for good rather than evil.</p>
<div id="attachment_2116" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 281px"><a href="http://prakky.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/prakkygoogleglasses.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-2116" alt="Google Glasses cartoon" src="http://prakky.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/prakkygoogleglasses.jpg?w=271&#038;h=300" width="271" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Not that I cook .. but, envisioning Google Glasses future at the family dinner table</p></div>
<p>It’s the same case with social media. We have wonderful supportive communities online. We also  have horrendous and hurtful trolling. It comes down to unpredictable and wide-ranging human behaviour.</p>
<p><b>For some, the glasses may have sensational impacts:</b></p>
<ul>
<li>Medical practitioners might share what they’re viewing and seek advice from colleagues</li>
<li>Coaches and teachers can impart advise and knowledge over distances</li>
<li>‘Citizen journalists’ could share footage</li>
<li>Families can share special moments with those who can’t be there: cutting the birthday cake, saying I Do, sending a grandchild to their first day of school</li>
<li>We could more easily document our lives for future generations</li>
</ul>
<p>Here in Adelaide, roving radio reporters like ABC radio’s Spence Denny could capture what they’re seeing. Today, Spence describes events on air for the studio journalists and listeners, and also shares images on social media. But if he can capture that burst water main with his Google Glasses?</p>
<p>Of course, I’m not the first person to ask these questions and envisage a scary future. <a title="TNW article on Google Glasses" href="http://thenextweb.com/google/2012/09/16/do-google-glasses-present-serious-privacy-problem-overreacting" target="_blank">The Next Web </a>said: “The glasses situation comes down to each of us deciding how much is too much sharing and when we’ve finally lost too much privacy” .  But most criticism seems to revolve around the potential of ads being pushed at us, and Google storing data about our behaviour and movements, rather than an examination of how it may change us.</p>
<p><a title="ABC news blog" href="http://abcnews.go.com/blogs/technology/2012/04/google-glasses-will-you-want-google-tracking-your-eyes/" target="_blank">Jonathan Macintosh</a> made a video about the privacy implications of Google glasses, demonstrating what it might look like to the wearer, should Google layer the experience with advertising:</p>
<p><span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='640' height='390' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/_mRF0rBXIeg?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span></p>
<p>Sure, you don’t have to wear Google glasses.</p>
<p><i>But our Google Glasses experience can be impacted by others.</i></p>
<p><b>We may not be the wearer. But we may be star of the film.</b></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2113/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2113/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2113&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://prakkypedia.prakky.com.au/2013/02/21/seeing-the-world-through-google-coloured-glasses/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>71</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/1b16d63ba0e67d158167bd98783d95a6?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">prakky</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://prakky.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/prakkygoogleglasses2.jpg?w=255" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mega artistic vision of a Google Glasses future by Prakky</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://prakky.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/prakkygoogleglasses.jpg?w=271" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Google Glasses cartoon</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Enchantments in Autumn, Part 3: When We Walked through Forests of Gold</title>
		<link>http://leerentz.wordpress.com/2013/01/26/the-enchantments-in-autumn-part-3-when-we-walked-through-forests-of-gold/</link>
		<comments>http://leerentz.wordpress.com/2013/01/26/the-enchantments-in-autumn-part-3-when-we-walked-through-forests-of-gold/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2013 01:43:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>leerentz</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[autumn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cascades]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hiking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[landscape]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lee rentz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[national forests]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outdoor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recreation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[washington]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alpine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alpine larch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[backpacking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[camp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[camping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cascade mountains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cascade Range]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Enchantments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gnome tarn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[golden]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[golden larches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[high]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Inspiration Lake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lower enchantments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[okanogan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pacific northwest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[perfection lake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prusik peak]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[subalpine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Washington State]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://leerentz.wordpress.com/?p=5768</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Golden Alpine Larches reflecting in the turquoise waters of Crystal Lake Our goals for the two days in the Lower Enchantments were modest: we wanted to explore the shores of Inspiration Lake and Talisman Lakes, and hike up to Gnome Tarn to get the classic and oft-repeated photograph of Prusik Peak reflecting in the tarn. [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=5768&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the_enchantments-950.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5876" alt="Backlit Alpine Larches at Crystal Lake in The Enchantments" src="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the_enchantments-950.jpg?w=720"   /></a><em>Golden Alpine Larches reflecting in the turquoise waters of Crystal Lake</em></p>
<p>Our goals for the two days in the Lower Enchantments were modest: we wanted to explore the shores of Inspiration Lake and Talisman Lakes, and hike up to Gnome Tarn to get the classic and oft-repeated photograph of Prusik Peak reflecting in the tarn. Distances are not long up here, so our day hikes were to be at a leisurely pace, allowing us to photograph these Indian Summer days to our heart&#8217;s content.</p>
<p>One hike took us to Prusik Pass. When we reached the pass, there was a cold torrent of wind funneled over this low place on the ridge. We had to put on extra layers, and we watched as the forest fires on distant ridges blew up in billows of fresh smoke. I was photographing when I heard a sudden shout of horror: one of our group had his camera on a tripod, and a sudden blast of wind tossed it right off a ledge onto the rocks below, damaging an expensive piece of equipment. I learned a quick lesson by his experience, and clung to my gear as the wind howled.</p>
<p><a href="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-520.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5801" alt="Prusik Peak Viewed from Gnome Tarn in The Enchantments" src="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-520.jpg?w=720"   /></a><em>Prusik Peak reflecting in Gnome Tarn</em></p>
<p>From Prusik Pass, we bushwhacked up and over a ridge to get to Gnome Tarn. The tarn was diminished in size by a seasonal drought, so the shores were extensive and muddy. Clouds skittered across the sky in the high winds, sending their shadows racing to keep up. A Peregrine Falcon zoomed overhead. Below us, a pair of male Mountain Bluebirds, the color of sky captured in feathers, were a perfect complement to the golden Alpine Larch needles where they foraged.</p>
<p>Since the shore was so muddy, I laid down atop a plastic bag and waited patiently or impatiently for the sun to light up the peak in between long periods of shadows. I also waited for the wind to subside, so that the ripples on the tarn would diminish, making for a better reflection. With my companions, I waited &#8230; and waited &#8230; and got chilled almost to the bone. But the peak was finally revealed enough that I got some good pictures of The Enchantments&#8217; iconic peak. Toward dark, the clouds grew thicker, and several of us decided that the peak had passed. The most persistent among us (not me) hung on longer, and got the best pictures of the day. Oh well; it&#8217;s always hard to know when to hold em or fold em in poker, and sometimes photography is the same way.</p>
<p><a href="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-528.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5802" alt="Prusik Peak Viewed from Gnome Tarn in The Enchantments" src="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-528.jpg?w=720"   /></a><em>Prusik Peak at Gnome Tarn, where sunlight and shadow fleetingly crossed the peak</em></p>
<p>We cooked a late dinner of Backpacker&#8217;s Pantry Pad Thai and crawled into our tents. Or at least most of us did, I stayed  out in the dark to try and get a few more pictures. The sky had cleared substantially by now, though there were still some clouds racing by. I was struck by the look of all four of our tents lit up by headlamps, so I asked everyone to cooperate for photos of the group of illuminated tents looking like fragile, glowing nylon fairies in the night. Then I noticed the clouds over a distant ridge; a full moon was rising and backlighting the clouds that were racing over the ridge.</p>
<p><a href="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-554.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5805" alt="Tents Lit Up at Deep Twilight in The Enchantments" src="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-554.jpg?w=720"   /></a><em>Our tents lit by faeries or headlamps at deep twilight after our cold photo session at Prusik Peak</em></p>
<p><a href="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-558.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5806" alt="Corona around Rising Moon in The Enchantments" src="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-558.jpg?w=720"   /></a><em>The rising moon created a corona of light on the racing clouds</em></p>
<p><a href="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-593.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5807" alt="Corona around Rising Moon in The Enchantments" src="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-593.jpg?w=720"   /></a><em>The full moon revealed briefly by a tear in the clouds</em></p>
<p><a href="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the_enchantments-769.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5823" alt="Alpine Larch Shadows by Moonlight on Granite in The Enchantments" src="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the_enchantments-769.jpg?w=720"   /></a><em>Later, the full moon cast larch shadows over smooth granite, and illuminated larches and peaks under the starry sky</em></p>
<p>The next morning was to be our hike into the Upper Enchantments, which I&#8217;ll describe in another blog post, but before beginning that hike we went about our regular morning activities. These included a pre-dawn hike up the rocky slope behind camp to Inspiration Lake, where there was lovely dawn light on the surrounding peaks–and where the outhouse was located. Actually, it was not really an outhouse, since the vault toilet had a seat, but no walls. It was more like a throne with a great view through a sheer curtain of golden larch needles. It was beautiful enough to encourage us to &#8220;Skip to the loo &#8230;&#8221; Sitting there, I knew I was missing some great light, so I tried to speed things along, and eventually finished and ran down to where I had left my camera and tripod. Fortunately, I was not too late and was able to capture the red glow on the ragged peaks towering over the lake.</p>
<p><a href="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the_enchantments-777.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5826" alt="Morning Light on Enchantment Peaks above Inspiration Lake" src="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the_enchantments-777.jpg?w=720"   /></a><em>Early red light on the peak above Inspiration Lake</em></p>
<p><a href="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the_enchantments-797.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5828" alt="Karen Rentz Videotaping Inspiration Lake in The Enchantments" src="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the_enchantments-797.jpg?w=720"   /></a><em>Karen creating a dawn video of the beautiful light on Inspiration Lake–and thank goodness for that warm layer of down!</em></p>
<p>Each morning was cold in The Enchantments; after all, we were in the mountains in October, when the golden Alpine Larches were spreading the word that the end of warmth was near. One of our group was a young guy with not much meat on his bones, and he shivered and lay wide awake all night. He said:  &#8220;It was almost the worst night of my life.&#8221; When I asked him what night had been worse, he replied &#8220;Well, I can&#8217;t think of any.&#8221; He decided he had gotten all the great pictures he needed, and decided to hike out on his own, two days early. It&#8217;s a good thing he got out when he did, because the next morning it was 16°F, which makes me shiver just thinking about it. It was so cold that it was painful to brush our teeth, and the water bottles were nearly frozen solid.</p>
<p><a href="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the_enchantments-802.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5829" alt="Icy Water Bottle with Prusik Peak in The Enchantments" src="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the_enchantments-802.jpg?w=720"   /></a><em>Ice formed overnight in our water bottles when the temperature dipped to 16°F</em></p>
<p><a href="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the_enchantments-1050.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5903" alt="Mountain Bluebird Feather on Ice in The Enchantments" src="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the_enchantments-1050.jpg?w=720"   /></a><em>Mountain Bluebird feather on thin ice at the edge of an inlet stream for Perfection Lake; the ice surface had an almost featherlike texture and there were tiny air bubbles trapped in the ice</em></p>
<p><a href="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the_enchantments-861.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5849" alt="Needle Ice Pushing Up Through Soil in The Enchantments" src="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the_enchantments-861.jpg?w=720"   /></a><em>Needle ice formed in wet soil on the shore of Perfection Lake</em></p>
<p>We met occasional hikers in the high country, with more as the days sped by and people realized that The Enchantments weren&#8217;t going up in flames. I often wear a University of Michigan baseball cap, which advertises my alma mater. It is amazing how many people I encounter in the Pacific Northwest who grew up in Michigan, went to the University of Michigan, then moved out West for better economic opportunities. It is a real brain drain for Michigan, but that is another story.</p>
<p>Anyway, on one morning near Perfection Lake, there was a pretty, young woman hiking alone. She struck up a conversation when she saw my cap: it turned out that she had grown up in Ann Arbor and had recently gotten her medical degree from the University of Michigan Medical School and was now doing her emergency room residency at a Seattle hospital. Her mother from Michigan had hiked as far as Snow Lakes with her, but the steep climb from there was too much for her Midwestern legs, so she stayed back in camp. The bad part about meeting a new young doctor, as I get older, is the nagging feeling that &#8220;surely she can&#8217;t be old enough to be a doctor!&#8221;</p>
<p>Old and young Alpine Larches, blazing gold, were everywhere in the Lower Enchantments. As the week wore on and the cold and high winds took their toll, more and more needles lost their color and fell, but there were still concentrations of intense gold.</p>
<p><a href="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-462.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5791" alt="Hiker with Prusik Peak and Perfection Lake in Autumn in The Ench" src="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-462.jpg?w=720"   /></a><em>One of my companions looking across Perfection Lake toward Prusik Peak, with a vast panorama of golden Alpine Larches</em></p>
<p>I grew up in the Midwest and have lived in the Northeast and the Rocky Mountains, so I am well-acquainted with autumn colors: Red Maples burn with scarlet intensity in the Upper Peninsula of Michigan; Sugar Maples glow brilliantly in Vermont; and Trembling Aspens shiver with golden light in Colorado. Here in the Northwest, autumn color was a bit of a disappointment until I learned about the timberline Alpine Larches. These are unusual, in that larches are a decidious conifer that somewhere along the evolutionary path strayed from the law that conifers are evergreen. Even here in Washington, the Evergreen State, they drop their needles.</p>
<p><a href="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the_enchantments-926.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5868" alt="Autumn Alpine Larch Needles along Perfection Lake in The Enchant" src="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the_enchantments-926.jpg?w=720"   /></a><em>Alpine Larch with golden needles and a cone, with the aqua waters of Perfection Lake forming a beautiful backdrop</em></p>
<p>For a tree living at timberline, where snow falls by the foot rather than by the inch, there are certain advantages to losing needles. The trees don&#8217;t have to carry as heavy a snow load with all the needles gone, so branches are less likely to break. Without needles, the larches don&#8217;t have to feed hungry Mountain Goats all winter. The trees don&#8217;t suffer as much from the dessicating effects of frigid winter winds. Perhaps most important, the vital amino acids, which are the building blocks for healthy needles, are safely tucked away in the roots and trunks of these trees living on the edge.</p>
<p><a href="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the_enchantments-1081.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5910" alt="Alpine Larches along Leprechaun Lake in The Enchantments" src="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the_enchantments-1081.jpg?w=720"   /></a><em>Alpine Larches along Leprechaun Lake</em></p>
<p><a href="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the_enchantments-942.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5872" alt="Autumn Alpine Larches Glowing along Perfection Lake in The Encha" src="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the_enchantments-942.jpg?w=720"   /></a><em>Peak of color along Perfection Lake, aka Rune Lake</em></p>
<p><a href="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the_enchantments-897.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5861" alt="Looking up at Alpine Larches in Autumn in The Enchantments" src="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the_enchantments-897.jpg?w=720"   /></a><em>Convergence</em></p>
<p><a href="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-514.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5800" alt="Alpine Larch near Timberline in The Enchantments" src="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-514.jpg?w=720"   /></a><em>Seemingly growing from granite, this Alpine Larch looks like a bonsai; it has been stunted by the desiccating winds blowing near Prusik Pass</em></p>
<p><a href="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-502.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5798" alt="Shield Lake from Prusik Pass in The Enchantments" src="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-502.jpg?w=720"   /></a><em>Shield Lake on the Lost World Plateau, shaped like one of the Red Delicious apples that nearby Wenatchee was always known for, viewed from Prusik Pass</em></p>
<p>The other trees growing at timberline were the Whitebark Pines. These pines were more scattered than the larches, and have a fascinating co-evolutionary relationship with Clark&#8217;s Nutcrackers that I described in an earlier post about <a title="Clark's Nutcrackers in Banff National Park" href="http://wp.me/peJRU-X6" target="_blank">Clark&#8217;s Nutcrackers in Banff National Park</a>. We observed several of the nutcrackers flying through The Enchantments, commuting to their favorite trees. Whitebark Pines are threatened by White Pine Blister Rust, a disease imported from another part of the world, and by the Pine Bark Beetle, which has exploded in population as our climate has warmed.</p>
<p>Huckleberry leaves were scarlet, but there weren&#8217;t many berries to sample: it was another bad year for the bears. Mountain Bog Gentians bloomed in our campsite, and there were occasional purple asters along the trails. I associate these species with the last gasp of the dying summer in the high country, but it&#8217;s nice that they provide a bit of vivid purple to the landscape.</p>
<p><a href="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-539.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5803" alt="Autumn Huckleberry Leaves and Weathered Wood in The Enchantments" src="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-539.jpg?w=720"   /></a><em>Scarlet Huckleberry leaves with a fallen Alpine Larch trunk</em></p>
<p><a href="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-541.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5804" alt="&quot;I Love You&quot; Message Made of Twigs in The Enchantments" src="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-541.jpg?w=720"   /></a><em>Awwww! </em></p>
<p><a href="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the_enchantments-953.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5878" alt="Weathered Wood of an Old, Dead Tree in The Enchantments" src="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the_enchantments-953.jpg?w=720"   /></a><em>Gracefully weathered lines of a very old Alpine Larch trunk</em></p>
<p><a href="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the_enchantments-964.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5880" alt="Fallen Alpine Larch Needles at Edge of Perfection Lake in The En" src="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the_enchantments-964.jpg?w=720"   /></a><em>When fallen Alpine Larch needles gather at the edge of a tarn, the end of autumn is nigh</em></p>
<p>We camped on Perfection Lake, or was it Rune Lake? Both names are used. The U.S. Forest Service originally established the place names of The Enchantments, and used such workable but rather dull names such as Perfection Lake, Inspiration Lake, and Isolation Lake. But the names got complicated when Bill and Peg Stark began visiting The Enchantments starting in 1959, and gave new names to the lakes, tarns, and peaks, based upon the legend of King Arthur and Norse mythology. Thus Perfection Lake also became Rune Lake. Inspiration Lake became Talisman Lake. Gnome Tarn is a name of their creation, as is Aasgard Pass. The place names of The Enchantments are now officially a blend of the two naming conventions, and there is enough overlap to cause plenty of confusion. Which makes the experience more fun. Myself: I love all the mythological names.</p>
<p><a href="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the_enchantments-973.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5882" alt="Karen Rentz Cooking Breakfast in The Enchantments" src="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the_enchantments-973.jpg?w=720"   /></a><em>Karen cooking breakfast on one of our cold mornings</em></p>
<p><a href="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the_enchantments-936.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5870" alt="&quot;Honolulu Girl&quot; Snowman Made by Karen Rentz in The Enchantments" src="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the_enchantments-936.jpg?w=720"   /></a><em>Snow for snowmen was scarce, but Karen make &#8220;Hula Girl&#8221; from a remnant snowbank of dirty snow, along with a skirt of fallen larch needles for modesty</em></p>
<p><a href="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the_enchantments-864.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5851" alt="Autumn-colored Sedges in The Enchantments" src="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the_enchantments-864.jpg?w=720"   /></a><em>Even grasses can take up the spirit of the season</em></p>
<p><a href="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-424.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5781" alt="Autumn Campsite on Perfection Lake in The Enchantments" src="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-424.jpg?w=720"   /></a><em>Can you imagine a more beautiful setting for a campsite?</em></p>
<p>On these golden days in the Lower Enchantments, there was plenty of leisurely time for watching a pair of Meadow Voles leap from their grassy nest, and examining the texture of ice forming on the edge of a pond. Sometimes, people get so wrapped up in hiking long distances in the mountains that they fail to stop and smell the gentians. Not us: we revel in these long days of nature observation and photography.</p>
<p>A highlight was twice seeing a Douglas Squirrel race by, along the shore of Talisman Lake, with a big mushroom in its mouth. Mushrooms are a favorite food of squirrels, and they often store a mushroom among the twigs of a shrub, perhaps to dry it out for later storage or perhaps to let the rain leach out toxins. I&#8217;m not sure which, but I find the behavior fascinating. Can it really be instinctive to temporarily store a mushroom in the open? Other wildlife was scarce; the marmots had apparently already entered hibernation. We saw a single Pika and found its stored haypiles near our camp.</p>
<p><a href="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-425.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5782" alt="Inspiration Lake in Autumn in The Enchantments" src="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-425.jpg?w=720"   /></a><em>Inspiration Lake, aka Talisman Lake, just above our campsite</em></p>
<p><a href="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-483.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5794" alt="Karen Rentz Crossing Log over Creek in The Enchantments" src="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-483.jpg?w=720"   /></a><em>Karen crossing a log bridge over the outlet for Talisman Lake; we had a long stop here while I temporarily repaired my broken pack waist strap with duct tape (the kind young man who gave me the tape laid down on this log while waiting for my time-consuming repair to be completed, and he somehow rolled off the log into the stream and got soaked!).</em></p>
<p><a href="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-448.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5786" alt="Autumn Alpine Larch along Inspiration Lake in The Enchantments" src="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-448.jpg?w=720"   /></a><em>Alpine Larch along Talisman Lake</em></p>
<p><a href="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the_enchantments-1011.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5898" alt="Mountain Bog Gentian Blooming in The Enchantments" src="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the_enchantments-1011.jpg?w=720"   /></a><em>Gentians in bloom near our campsite</em></p>
<p><a href="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-488.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5795" alt="Alpine Larches at Peak Color with Perfection Lake in The Enchant" src="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-488.jpg?w=720"   /></a><em>Rune Lake viewed from a high granite outcrop above the lake</em></p>
<p><a href="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-426.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5783" alt="Tree Shadows on Inspiration Lake in The Enchantments" src="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-426.jpg?w=720"   /></a><em>Larch shadows crossing the beautiful green waters of Talisman Lake</em></p>
<p><a href="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-499.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5797" alt="Little Annapurna from Prusik Pass Trail in The Enchantments" src="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-499.jpg?w=720"   /></a><em>Trail through a subalpine meadow, with Little Annapurna in the distance</em></p>
<p><a href="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-458.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5790" alt="Prusik Peak and Perfection Lake in Autumn in The Enchantments" src="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-458.jpg?w=720"   /></a><em>One last fond look at the magic of the Lower Enchantments: Prusik Peak, Alpine Larches, and Rune Lake</em></p>
<p>In the next and final installment of &#8220;The Enchantments in Autumn&#8221; story, I&#8217;ll go above timberline to the Upper Enchantments, which has a stark beauty all its own.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><strong>For more information about hiking in The Enchantments, go to <span style="color:#ff6600;"><a title="The Enchantments at the WTA" href="http://www.wta.org/go-hiking/hikes/enchantment-lakes" target="_blank"><span style="color:#ff6600;">Washington Trails Association</span></a></span> and <span style="color:#ff6600;"><a title="Enchantments Permit" href="http://www.recreation.gov/permits/Enchantment_Permit_Area/r/wildernessAreaDetails.do?page=detail&amp;contractCode=NRSO&amp;parkId=72280" target="_blank"><span style="color:#ff6600;">Recreation.gov</span></a></span>. To read my other blogs about The Enchantments, go to <span style="color:#ff6600;"><a title="The Enchantments in Autumn: the Long Ascent" href="http://wp.me/peJRU-1tN" target="_blank"><span style="color:#ff6600;">The Long Ascent</span></a></span><span style="color:#ff6600;"><span style="color:#ff6600;"> <span style="color:#000000;">and <span style="color:#ff6600;"><a title="Mountain Goats in the Enchantments" href="http://wp.me/peJRU-1vJ" target="_blank"><span style="color:#ff6600;">Mountain Goats</span></a></span></span></span></span>.  There is also a good web site that is based upon the autumn experiences of the Starks and another couple called <span style="color:#ff6600;"><a title="50 Years in The Enchantments" href="http://www.enchantments50.com" target="_blank"><span style="color:#ff6600;">50 Years in the Enchantments</span></a></span>.</strong></p>
<p><strong>To see my web site, which includes photographic prints for sale, please go to <span style="color:#ff6600;"><a title="Lee Rentz Photography" href="http://leerentz.com/" target="_blank"><span style="color:#ff6600;">LeeRentz.com</span></a></span> (just ask to email you a small version of a particular photograph you like if you can&#8217;t find it on the site; my website is not up to date) </strong></p>
<p><strong>To see thousands of my photographs in large file sizes for use in magazines or other printed materials or electronic media, go to my <span style="color:#ff6600;"><a title="Lee Rentz PhotoShelter Website" href="http://leerentz.photoshelter.com" target="_blank"><span style="color:#ff6600;">PhotoShelter Website</span></a></span></strong></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5768/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5768/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=5768&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://leerentz.wordpress.com/2013/01/26/the-enchantments-in-autumn-part-3-when-we-walked-through-forests-of-gold/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>69</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/2d1fbe0592c02d2e71dd6d8eadbe4a71?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">leerentz</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the_enchantments-950.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Backlit Alpine Larches at Crystal Lake in The Enchantments</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-520.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Prusik Peak Viewed from Gnome Tarn in The Enchantments</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-528.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Prusik Peak Viewed from Gnome Tarn in The Enchantments</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-554.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Tents Lit Up at Deep Twilight in The Enchantments</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-558.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Corona around Rising Moon in The Enchantments</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-593.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Corona around Rising Moon in The Enchantments</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the_enchantments-769.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Alpine Larch Shadows by Moonlight on Granite in The Enchantments</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the_enchantments-777.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Morning Light on Enchantment Peaks above Inspiration Lake</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the_enchantments-797.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Karen Rentz Videotaping Inspiration Lake in The Enchantments</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the_enchantments-802.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Icy Water Bottle with Prusik Peak in The Enchantments</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the_enchantments-1050.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mountain Bluebird Feather on Ice in The Enchantments</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the_enchantments-861.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Needle Ice Pushing Up Through Soil in The Enchantments</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-462.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Hiker with Prusik Peak and Perfection Lake in Autumn in The Ench</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the_enchantments-926.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Autumn Alpine Larch Needles along Perfection Lake in The Enchant</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the_enchantments-1081.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Alpine Larches along Leprechaun Lake in The Enchantments</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the_enchantments-942.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Autumn Alpine Larches Glowing along Perfection Lake in The Encha</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the_enchantments-897.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Looking up at Alpine Larches in Autumn in The Enchantments</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-514.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Alpine Larch near Timberline in The Enchantments</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-502.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Shield Lake from Prusik Pass in The Enchantments</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-539.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Autumn Huckleberry Leaves and Weathered Wood in The Enchantments</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-541.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">&#34;I Love You&#34; Message Made of Twigs in The Enchantments</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the_enchantments-953.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Weathered Wood of an Old, Dead Tree in The Enchantments</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the_enchantments-964.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Fallen Alpine Larch Needles at Edge of Perfection Lake in The En</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the_enchantments-973.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Karen Rentz Cooking Breakfast in The Enchantments</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the_enchantments-936.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">&#34;Honolulu Girl&#34; Snowman Made by Karen Rentz in The Enchantments</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the_enchantments-864.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Autumn-colored Sedges in The Enchantments</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-424.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Autumn Campsite on Perfection Lake in The Enchantments</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-425.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Inspiration Lake in Autumn in The Enchantments</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-483.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Karen Rentz Crossing Log over Creek in The Enchantments</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-448.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Autumn Alpine Larch along Inspiration Lake in The Enchantments</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/the_enchantments-1011.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mountain Bog Gentian Blooming in The Enchantments</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-488.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Alpine Larches at Peak Color with Perfection Lake in The Enchant</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-426.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Tree Shadows on Inspiration Lake in The Enchantments</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-499.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Little Annapurna from Prusik Pass Trail in The Enchantments</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://leerentz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/the_enchantments-458.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Prusik Peak and Perfection Lake in Autumn in The Enchantments</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Equality in America and the Myth of Social Immobility</title>
		<link>http://mcleanparlor.com/2013/02/21/eqaulity-in-america-and-the-myth-of-social-immobility/</link>
		<comments>http://mcleanparlor.com/2013/02/21/eqaulity-in-america-and-the-myth-of-social-immobility/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2013 16:15:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>J. Palmer</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Inequality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rhetoric]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Welfare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brookings Institution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Columbia University]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[data manipulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joseph Stiglitz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social mobility]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mcleanparlor.wordpress.com/?p=76</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In The New York Times’ series on inequality in America, Columbia professor and Nobel laureate Joseph Stiglitz recently argued that measurable social mobility in America is incongruent with the often ascribed “land of opportunity” label.  Stiglitz did reference data from a reputable source (The Brookings Institution) to draw his conclusions, but his interpretation of said [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=76&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a title="Link to Stiglitz article" href="http://www.businessinsider.com/the-american-dream-is-now-a-myth-2012-6"><img class="aligncenter" alt="wealth and inequality" src="http://static6.businessinsider.com/image/4bbcbdbb7f8b9acb194a0300-593-446/wealth-and-inequality.gif" width="417" height="313" border="0" /></a></p>
<p>In The <a href="http://opinionator.blogs.nytimes.com/category/the-great-divide/">New York Times’ series</a> on inequality in America, Columbia professor and Nobel laureate Joseph Stiglitz recently argued that measurable social mobility in America is incongruent with the often ascribed “land of opportunity” label.  Stiglitz did reference <a href="http://www.brookings.edu/research/papers/2007/11/generations-isaacs">data</a> from a reputable source (The Brookings Institution) to draw his conclusions, but his interpretation of said data is perplexing.</p>
<p>According to Stiglitz, “only 58 percent of Americans born into the bottom fifth of income earners move out of that category, and just 6 percent born into the bottom fifth move into the top.”</p>
<p>The word “only” in that statement is an interesting rhetorical choice. I don’t know exactly what percentage of America’s poorest children the professor thinks should be moving out of the untouchable caste, but 58% seems pretty good. And while 6% seems rather paltry when I pay sales tax on a Burger King Whopper, the fact that 6 out of 100 of the most indigent kids in America can go from dirt poor to filthy rich sounds almost too <i>good</i> to be true.</p>
<p>This is certainly all a matter of perspective, right? Maybe not.<span id="more-76"></span></p>
<p>Stiglitz is obviously concerned with the 42% of American children who are quite literally stuck in a cycle of poverty, and this is noble. No decent non-Republican human being would argue that these 42% are undeserving of assistance just because others were able to succeed. However, Stiglitz completely ignored the flip-side to upward mobility in America: downward mobility. Maybe he simply overlooked it—or maybe, more likely, he dismissed it because the facts don’t support his thesis.</p>
<p>I would never have imagined that so many of America&#8217;s poorest were able to climb at least one rung of the social ladder. The revelation that so many could (whether thanks to government assistance or despite government dependency) made me wonder about my preconceptions about the richest Americans. Before reading the Stiglitz article, I always thought it was a general rule that the poor got poorer and the rich got richer, generationally speaking anyway. Since Stiglitz made no mention of what happens to kids born to the richest parents, I went to the source.</p>
<p>The Brookings report indicated that 61% of children born into families at the top income quintile FALL into a lesser bracket. That’s right “only” 39% of the richest kids stay the richest kids. Relatively speaking, this means that if you were solely concerned with social mobility, you would be statistically better off being born into one of the poorest families (58% chance of moving up) than being born into one of the richest families (61% chance of moving down).</p>
<p>I don’t deny that more equality of opportunity in this country is needed in order to ensure that everyone has the best possible chance to reach the socio-economic status they desire. I am a strong advocate for government assistance, public education, and universal health care. However, people like Joseph Stiglitz, who support similar agendas for helping the poor, are doing themselves and the progressive cause a disservice when they try to shape a debate with deceptively selective data and phrases like “only 58%.”</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/76/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/76/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=76&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://mcleanparlor.com/2013/02/21/eqaulity-in-america-and-the-myth-of-social-immobility/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>46</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/fa1cd70c251dc6ecc137f7099c5d0a54?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">politicdiscourse</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://static6.businessinsider.com/image/4bbcbdbb7f8b9acb194a0300-593-446/wealth-and-inequality.gif" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">wealth and inequality</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Flightless</title>
		<link>http://thewordsisaw.wordpress.com/2013/02/21/flightless/</link>
		<comments>http://thewordsisaw.wordpress.com/2013/02/21/flightless/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2013 07:05:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>The Words I Saw</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Short stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hunger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poverty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[short story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Words I Saw]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thewordsisaw.wordpress.com/?p=1201</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I remember watching them high up in the sky, so high I had to squint my eyes. I remember Papa taking me to the falls where they would dive with the water, quickly lost to the mist-filled canyon beneath us. I remember the evenings sat on Mama’s lap, outside our brick home, listening to them [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1201&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://thewordsisaw.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/africa-by-peter-reid.jpeg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1212" alt="© Peter Reid" src="http://thewordsisaw.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/africa-by-peter-reid.jpeg?w=720"   /></a>I remember watching them high up in the sky, so high I had to squint my eyes. I remember Papa taking me to the falls where they would dive with the water, quickly lost to the mist-filled canyon beneath us. I remember the evenings sat on Mama’s lap, outside our brick home, listening to them sing to the stars and me. That’s how I want to remember them, and not as this small pile of bones, with their flesh lost to the red arid-soil before me.</p>
<p><i>Bones are all that remain of the starved</i>, Papa once told me. <i>But we live off them; they feed us Daya, because the sugar company needs them to bleach their cane</i>. I look at my rice sac, thinking back to Papa’s words, haunting me. <i>But they’re just bones in the end; like all of us, aren’t they?</i> I want to say to him.</p>
<p>I dust it clean and pinch the tiny breastbone between my fingers, before dropping it into my sac. It clinks like a note I had once played on a long wooden instrument at school. I had hit it with a stick, the instrument, and it sounded just like tapping two bones together. I peer inside against the smell. Not many of them are birds; they’re too big to be birds, too big to be animal.</p>
<p>It’s almost as tall as me now, and too heavy to lift, but if I drag it then my sac slides easy enough over the land, causing a red mist to rise up behind me. I pull as the rough hemp cuts into my shoulder. I squint against the pain as I mimic the sound of that musical note I had once played.</p>
<p align="center">*</p>
<p>‘Mama,’ I call out after arriving at our tent home. ‘Mama, I found lots Mama!’</p>
<p>But Mama doesn’t respond. I tie my sac tightly shut, and turn to see the amber sky deepening over the village. Sand is lifted by the rising winds of dusk, causing everything to shimmer beneath the descending darkness. I see him, leaning against the canvas walls of my neighbour’s home, staring at me and my sac. I want to take it inside, but Mama says we live with Death close enough already, without inviting it into our homes as well. So I push my sac up against the tent, turning to see that the man I don’t know has gone. I open the flap and walk inside.</p>
<p>‘Mama,’ I say running to lower myself into her arms. ‘What’s wrong, why are you crying?’</p>
<p>The blanket I had placed over her before leaving in the morning to collect had barely moved. She remains lying on the floor, with my baby brother asleep by her side.</p>
<p>‘Oh Daya, my sweet girl, Mama is not well today.’</p>
<p>She then begins violently coughing. I hold her tightly in my arms.</p>
<p>‘It’s OK Mama; I collected half a sac today. The sugar men will give us twenty cents for half a sac. We will eat tomorrow.’</p>
<p>‘Tomorrow,’ she says before closing her eyes.</p>
<p>I stand and walk around Mama to kiss Rudo on the head. He was born in the village and never saw our brick home, or Papa. When I’m not collecting then I tell Rudo about our life before; I tell him about Papa. I miss Papa. I felt safe when he was alive, as he could collect much better than me.</p>
<p>I pull my dusty clothes off and place them in one corner for tomorrow, as Mama’s wheezing breath fills the growing silence of the night. I light our only candle to get ready for bed, shadows dance around me in its flickering light. After putting on one of Papa’s old blue t-shirts, which falls all the way to my shins, I cross to the door to tie it shut. But first, I peer out to see my sac, illuminated under the glare of the moon. I briefly look up to see a world of stars above me.</p>
<p>‘Please God,’ I whisper.</p>
<p>Turning, I blow out the candle and find Mama’s side in the darkness. I lie pressed up against her and close my eyes, listening to her breath in order to drown out the hunger that’s constantly punching me in my belly.</p>
<p align="center">*</p>
<p>‘Papa was a great man,’ I tell Rudo, as he sits chewing his fingers on my lap. ‘We were never hungry when Papa was alive; he was a wise man and could make bird traps out of sticky berries. Mama would then pluck the Dusky Larks, roast them, and then we would sit just here,’ I tap the earth beneath us, ‘in a circle, laughing and eating larks. Yes, Papa was a great man Rudo, but,’ I look at Mama drifting between her delusions and dreams, ‘Death took him from us.’</p>
<p>Rudo giggles and climbs up my chest to begin chewing my nose.</p>
<p>‘<i>Mira</i> Baby,’ <i>stop </i>I say, ‘it’s sticky,’ I add, laughing and hugging him tightly.</p>
<p>I like my mornings with Rudo. Before Mama wakes I sit and play with him. I let myself be nine again. But once Mama is up I must start work again, because if I don’t try and find food, if I don’t care for us, then no one will.</p>
<p>After placing Rudo on the edge of Mama’s frayed blanket, I pull Papa’s t-shirt up over my head and quickly run from the morning chill to the corner of the tent. My work clothes scratch against my skin from all the dirt trapped inside them. The river is a morning away, so I can only wash them once a week. I pick up the broom, which stands taller than me, and fill the dawn silence with the shiver of bristles sweeping dust. Rudo begins scratching at the ground. I work around him, laughing as he crawls after the brush-head at my feet.</p>
<p>When I sweep I think about our brick home, and how tidy Mama used to keep it, and how Mama and Papa both wailed on their knees, crying out to God, when the bad men came and bulldozed it. I sweep and see a sea of us, lost in our own country, all walking together to this: I sweep a pile of dust to the door and, after opening it, force a small grey cloud outside into the face of the rising sun.</p>
<p>The engine of a truck hums in the horizon. I smile, now knowing that for at least today and tomorrow we will not die, for twenty cents will buy enough maize to feed us.</p>
<p>‘Mama,’ I call. ‘The sugar men are here.’</p>
<p>Rudo claps his hands together before patting Mama on the head. She fights to wake but her dreams are too safe to leave. Gazing back outside, I watch people beginning to exit their tents around me, carrying their sacs to the truck which hoots its horn. Two men step out and begin assessing the sacs, before tossing them on the back of the truck and handing out coins. I look down at my own sac, but it is gone.</p>
<p>‘No!’ I cry. ‘My bones, my bones have been stolen!’</p>
<p>My mouth is filled by a desperate saltiness, as my tears crash from the brink of my lip. I turn to look back at Mama and Rudo, who has also fallen asleep beside her, with his bulging belly rising and falling beneath his tiny ribs. I run.</p>
<p>‘<i>Pamusoro</i>, <i>pamusoro</i>,’ <i>excuse-me </i>I say, pulling at the jacket of the man who is giving out coins. ‘My sac was stolen but I collected half, please give me twenty cents to feed my family.’</p>
<p>He raises the clipboard in his hand and slaps me around the face with it, hard enough to knock me to the ground.</p>
<p>‘No bones, no money,’ he hisses, before kicking the dusty soil over me.</p>
<p>‘But I will get you half a sac next time; just give me twenty cents for today. My Mama and baby brother are starving. I’m starving, please.’</p>
<p>He raises the clipboard high above my head, as I scramble away between the legs of my neighbours.</p>
<p align="center">*</p>
<p>The soil crumbles as I dig down, sifting amongst the rubbish buried within it. I lift my hoe to try again, but my empty stomach feels as though it might collapse under the strain. The hoe drops to the ground, as I bring my hand to my belly to soothe it, with my vision misted by the sun’s hot rays.</p>
<p>‘Papa,’ I say, ‘I can’t dig Papa, my hunger eats me.’</p>
<p>Papa looks up at me and smiles, as he avidly turns over the soil picking up bone after bone.</p>
<p>‘We dig to eat, Daya; the sugar company will reward us for our hard work.’</p>
<p>I lean over and collect my hoe, seeing a partially covered bone beside its stone-scratched metal head. I scrap it free with my fingers, and tap it against the hoe’s wooden handle. It makes the right note so I stumble to the white sac and drop it inside.</p>
<p>‘But Papa,’ I say again, turning back to the shrunken man, with his blue t-shirt hanging loser each day, ‘I don’t want to scavenge anymore; the other girls laugh at me Papa.’</p>
<p>He forces his hoe into the ground and pushes his curved spine up straight as he turns to face me; his breaths falter as he fills his lungs with the sticky-air.</p>
<p>‘It’s not scavenging Daya,’ he says, looking out across the rubbish heap we’re stood upon, lifting us high up into the cloudless sky. ‘We dig to survive, and there’s nothing wrong about surviving.’ Papa lifts his hoe before breaking though the heap’s crust, releasing the potency of poverty further more. ‘There’s nothing wrong in survival Daya, and never let anyone tell you otherwise – understand?’</p>
<p>‘Yes Papa,’ I reply, but my words are cast astray on the breeze, lost with my dreams.</p>
<p>I sigh and turn to my sac, with them rattling inside as I shake it. I begin to drag it behind me, stopping to look for Papa once more, but my vision clears with the setting sun, and Papa is gone. I often cry while I’m out on the heap, as it’s the one place where I’m always alone.</p>
<p align="center">*</p>
<p>I don’t know what it’s like elsewhere in the world, but here, in my village, suffering seems to find its way into all of us.</p>
<p>‘<i>Mhoro</i>!’ I call out, pushing the air in the top of my sac downwards to make it bulge at the bottom.</p>
<p>A flickering light seeps beneath the walls of the tent, licking at the darkness by my feet.</p>
<p>‘Hello,’ I call again. ‘Mother Amadika, <i>mhoro</i>, it’s me – Daya.’</p>
<p>The flap drops and I am bathed in light, blinded, and unable to find the eyes of the black silhouette before me.</p>
<p>‘What is it child?’</p>
<p>My vision adjusts to see the vibrant colours of her dress, tainted by hardship and sweat.</p>
<p>‘Mother Amadika, please take these bones I have collected, and all for a little bit of maize.’</p>
<p>Her towering figure and heavy breasts fall forwards as she lifts the sac, assessing its value, before carrying it inside.</p>
<p>‘I have little maize to give,’ she says, no louder than a whisper.</p>
<p>I follow her into the tent; a small fire warms a pot in one corner, with the flames ravaging the air around them. Mother Amadika lifts a small tin bowl and lowers herself beside the pot, scraping at the contents with a metal spoon. I turn to the sound of the wheezing man, lying along the far canvas wall – his body shaking with fever.</p>
<p>‘I can give no more.’</p>
<p>Mother Amadika places the bowl into my outstretched hand, too hot to hold on its bottom. I look at the few spoonfuls of porridge; there’s barely enough to feed Rudo, let alone Mama and me.</p>
<p>‘<i>Ndatenda</i> Mother Amadika,’ <i>thank you </i>I say stepping away.</p>
<p>I stop at the entrance, trapped by my thoughts. I turn and face Mother Amadika, whose curly her hair is cut short like mine.</p>
<p>‘He’s dying, isn’t he?’ I ask, pointing at her son, now lying still with his eyes wide-open – searching.</p>
<p>She walks towards me and places her heavy hand on my shoulder.</p>
<p>‘We’re all dying Daya, but,’ her sadness clenches me tighter, ‘some of us are freed from this life much sooner than others.’ She lets my shoulder go and lifts the flap, covering me in shadow. ‘Now run home child. Don’t get caught with that maize in your hands.’</p>
<p>‘I won’t Mother Amadika, <i>ndatenda</i>.’</p>
<p>I hug the warm bowl close to my chest and run quickly, skipping over the black festering puddles.</p>
<p align="center">*</p>
<p>I hear his cries from far away.</p>
<p>‘Rudo!’ I call, running quicker towards our home. ‘I’m coming Rudo!’</p>
<p>I dash towards the full moon that hangs like a beacon, directing me towards the village’s end, while dodging the shadows calling out to me to sit with them, to keep them company just for tonight.</p>
<p>‘Rudo,’ I shout, tearing at the door shielding his screams inside.</p>
<p>I enter our home and edge my way through the darkness, placing the bowl of maize on the floor, before collecting Rudo in my arms.</p>
<p>‘It’s OK Baby, I’m here.’</p>
<p>His screams fade as he digs his head into my neck, clenching me tighter.</p>
<p>‘Mama,’ I say, lowering to find her hand in the darkness; it’s as cold as a pebble exposed to a winter’s night. ‘Mama?’ I say again.</p>
<p>I place Rudo back on the floor; his sniffles are accompanied by my scrambling to light our candle. The match sparks and I meet it with the blackened wick, before the tent is given a shimmering light. I slowly walk back to Mama and lean over her; her eyes peer right through me. I fall with my tears to her side, and hold her before kissing her cheek. I push back her hair, and see that her pain has now left her. I wish her goodnight.</p>
<p>‘<i>Urare zvakanakat</i> Mama,’ I whisper, pulling the blanket up to cover her face, ‘kiss Papa for me.’</p>
<p>I look over Mama at Rudo; his little hands and parting smile are covered in sticky porridge. Moonbeams fight their way through the many holes in our canvass walls, creating a pattern of stars in the black universe behind him.</p>
<p>‘It’s just us now Baby,’ I say.</p>
<p align="center">*</p>
<p>The soil trickles between my fingers, before I smooth it with my palm as Rudo plays with two sticks beside me.</p>
<p>‘We’ll be OK now Rudo,’ I say to him, taking the sticks before tying them into a small cross with some string. ‘Now Papa can take care of Mama, and I will be able to feed us better.’</p>
<p>Rudo reaches out for the cross, but I place it into the centre of the newly turned soil.</p>
<p>‘Come Baby.’</p>
<p>I stand and pull him up into my arms. Stumbling, I begin to walk away but I’m soon drawn towards a small slope, and the sound of scraping being carried up it on the morning breeze. I wait with the moment; familiar with the noise of collecting; familiar with Death’s song. A man, the stranger, staggers up the horizon before me, with my white rice sac sliding over the land behind him. I look down at Mama, hidden beneath the red arid soil. I lean over with Rudo still in my arms and pull out the cross. <i>May they never find her,</i> I say silently.</p>
<p>I hold Rudo and head towards our tent home; humming in his ear like Papa would once do to me. But he points at something over my shoulder and burbles the word, <i>Mama. </i>I smile with Rudo’s first word, but I turn as he says <i>Mama</i> once again.</p>
<p>There, pecking at the soil above Mama’s grave, is a small bird so white, I imagine the feathers of an angel could not fall any purer. I stand and stare, before watching the bird, and Mama, fly away.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://thewordsisaw.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/freshly-pressed-circle.png"><img class="size-full wp-image-1207 aligncenter" alt="" src="http://thewordsisaw.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/freshly-pressed-circle.png?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">My thanks to photographer Peter Reid from Green Horizons for accompanying photo - <a title="Green Horizons website" href="http://www.greenhorizons.eu/" target="_blank">www.greenhorizons.eu</a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">© Matthew Small 2013</p>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1201&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thewordsisaw.wordpress.com/2013/02/21/flightless/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/add687650d7be120e6790e8271541dc4?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">thewordsisaw</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thewordsisaw.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/africa-by-peter-reid.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">© Peter Reid</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thewordsisaw.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/freshly-pressed-circle.png" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>It&#8217;s Not Just a Cat Toy</title>
		<link>http://lynnsimon.wordpress.com/2013/02/18/its-not-just-a-cat-toy/</link>
		<comments>http://lynnsimon.wordpress.com/2013/02/18/its-not-just-a-cat-toy/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2013 04:17:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>lynnsimon</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[cats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[paper project]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photoshop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPchallenge]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://lynnsimon.wordpress.com/?p=769</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[If he&#8217;s honest with himself, the cat will admit that this toilet paper tube is now 100% more entertaining than it was when he first started playing with it. (When it was still just a tube. That&#8217;s so boring. We can do better than that.) I made that spiraling dangly thing just for him. Is [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=769&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If he&#8217;s honest with himself, the cat will admit that this toilet paper tube is now 100% more entertaining than it was when he first started playing with it. (When it was still just a tube. That&#8217;s so boring. We can do better than that.)</p>
<p><a href="http://lynnsimon.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/cattoy.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-770" alt="cattoy" src="http://lynnsimon.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/cattoy.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>I made that spiraling dangly thing just for him. Is he grateful? Not that I can tell.</p>
<p>The above photograph was bad from the start (poor lighting), and I over-brightened and over-sharpened it in Photoshop, just to make it somewhat viewable. Anyway, it&#8217;s still a bad photo, but something about it started to intrigue me. I liked the shapes, and the shadow of the spiral.</p>
<p>I decided to mess around with Photoshop filters. The Cutout filter yielded this&#8230;</p>
<p><a href="http://lynnsimon.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/cattoy1.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-771" alt="cattoy1" src="http://lynnsimon.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/cattoy1.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>&#8230;which was kind of interesting, but not enough on its own. I took the Cutout file and copied it into a file with the original photo. With the Cutout on a layer above the original, and the Blending mode set to Multiply, I ended up with this:</p>
<p><a href="http://lynnsimon.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/cattoy2.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-773" alt="cattoy2" src="http://lynnsimon.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/cattoy2.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>Which is an improvement on the original, I think. The same file, but with the Blending Mode set to Exclusion results in this:</p>
<p><a href="http://lynnsimon.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/cattoy3.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-774" alt="cattoy3" src="http://lynnsimon.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/cattoy3.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>Cool!</p>
<p>Returning to the original photo, I used a filter that I have <strong><em>never</em> </strong>had any success with. The Stained Glass filter. Always a disaster. So, why even bother trying it? That&#8217;s the triumph of hope over experience. And&#8230;</p>
<p><a href="http://lynnsimon.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/cattoy4.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-775" alt="cattoy4" src="http://lynnsimon.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/cattoy4.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>OMG! I really kind of love that!</p>
<p>Every time I use Photoshop filters I hear voices in my head, the clamor of professionals saying, <em><strong>Take a competent picture to begin with! Filters are</strong><strong> cheating!</strong></em> And I get what they&#8217;re saying. I really do.</p>
<p>On the other hand, this started out as a toilet paper tube. You know?</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/769/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/769/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=769&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://lynnsimon.wordpress.com/2013/02/18/its-not-just-a-cat-toy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>61</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://lynnsimon.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/cattoy2.jpg?w=108" />
		<media:content url="http://lynnsimon.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/cattoy2.jpg?w=108" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cattoy2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/493ffbc98a5251a54ac04a2e90994bc9?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lynnsimon</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lynnsimon.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/cattoy.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cattoy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lynnsimon.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/cattoy1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cattoy1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lynnsimon.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/cattoy2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cattoy2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lynnsimon.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/cattoy3.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cattoy3</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lynnsimon.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/cattoy4.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cattoy4</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
