<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2012 00:02:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Toilet Paper: A History</title>
		<link>http://thefrailestthing.com/2012/07/25/toilet-paper-a-history/</link>
		<comments>http://thefrailestthing.com/2012/07/25/toilet-paper-a-history/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2012 23:20:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Michael Sacasas</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science and Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Seinfeld]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thefrailestthing.com/?p=4921</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Seinfeld excelled at criticism of the everyday. A few months ago, in a fine essay in the NY Times, Sam Anderson suggested that Roland Barthes was the father of pop cultural criticism and that we are all now cultural critics in the Barthian vein, &#8220;decoding everything.&#8221; Perhaps. But if Barthes gave us serious criticism of [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4921&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Seinfeld</em> excelled at criticism of the everyday. A few months ago, in <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2012/05/27/magazine/how-roland-barthes-gave-us-the-tv-recap.html?pagewanted=all">a fine essay</a> in the <em>NY Times</em>, Sam Anderson suggested that Roland Barthes was the father of pop cultural criticism and that we are all now cultural critics in the Barthian vein, &#8220;decoding everything.&#8221; Perhaps. But if Barthes gave us serious criticism of popular culture, Seinfeld taught us to be ironic critics of the utterly mundane. Case in point: toilet paper.</p>
<p>Consider this exchange from <a href="http://www.seinfeldscripts.com/TheFacePainter.html">&#8220;The Face Painter&#8221;</a> episode:</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">George: Take toilet paper for example. Do you realize that toilet paper has<br />
not changed in my lifetime? It&#8217;s just paper on a cardboard roll, that&#8217;s it.<br />
And in ten thousand years, it will still be exactly the same because really,<br />
what else can they do?</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">Siena: That&#8217;s true. There really has been no development in toilet paper.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">George: And everything else has changed. But toilet paper is exactly the same,<br />
and will be so until we&#8217;re dead.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">Siena: Yeah, you&#8217;re right George. What else can they do?</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">George: It&#8217;s just paper on a roll, that&#8217;s it. And that&#8217;s all it will ever be.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">Siena: Wow.</p>
<p>Now stick with me. I know you&#8217;re probably wondering why I&#8217;m writing about toilet paper, but there is a point here. George reminds us that ubiquitous technologies tend to become naturalized (reified if you prefer) and veil their very contingent history. In other words, there has been development in toilet paper as Jerry points out later in the episode:</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">George: I saw Siena again.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">Elaine: Siena?</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">Jerry: Yeah, he&#8217;s dating a crayon.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">George: We discussed toilet paper.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">Jerry: Toilet paper?</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">George: Yeah, I told her how toilet paper hasn&#8217;t changed in my lifetime, and<br />
probably wouldn&#8217;t change in the next fifty thousand years and she was<br />
fascinated, fascinated!</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">Jerry: What are you talking about?</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">Elaine: Yeah.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">Jerry: Toilet paper&#8217;s changed.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">Elaine: Yeah.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">Jerry: It&#8217;s softer.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">Elaine: Softer.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">Jerry: More sheets per roll</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">Elaine: Sheets.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">Jerry: Comes in a wide variety of colors.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">Elaine: Colors.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">George: Ok, ok, fine! It&#8217;s changed, it&#8217;s not really the point. Anyway, I&#8217;m<br />
thinking of making a big move.</p>
<p><img class="alignright  wp-image-4923" title="TP" src="http://thefrailestthing.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/tp.jpg?w=275&h=206" alt="" width="275" height="206" />Toilet paper has a history. Of course it has a history. But who thinks of it? Like George, we take most of our technology for granted. Of course, we pay a lot of attention to certain technologies, usually the newest and most innovative. But we don&#8217;t think too much about those other technologies that have become more or less part of our natural environment, the <a title="Electrification, Refrigerators, and the Social Construction of Technology" href="http://thefrailestthing.com/2011/09/28/electrification-refrigerators-and-the-social-construction-of-technology/">refrigerator</a> for example. But these very mundane technologies have, in fact, carried rather significant consequences when you think about it. The refrigerator significantly reordered our relationship to food and dining, and consequently impacted household labor, the rhythms of daily life, and nutrition and health. These are no small things, but for all of this the refrigerator is hardly thought of as a revolutionary technology. Instead, the arrangements it facilitated are now more or less taken for granted.</p>
<p>Toilet paper, in case you&#8217;re wondering, was in use  in China as early as the fourteenth century and it was made in 2&#8242; x 3&#8242; sheets. Everywhere else, and in China before then, people made use of what their environment offered. Leaves, mussel shells, corncobs were among the more common options. The Romans (<a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ExWfh6sGyso">what have they ever done for us!</a>) used a sponge attached to the end of a stick and dipped in salt water. And yes, as you may have heard, in certain cultures the left hand was employed in the task of scatological hygiene, and in these cultures the left hand retains a certain stigma to this day.</p>
<p>Until the late-nineteenth century, Americans opted for discarded reading material. It&#8217;s not clear if this is why Americans still today often take reading material into the bathroom, or if the practice of reading on the toilet yielded a eureka moment subsequently. In any case, magazines, newspapers, and almanacs were all precursors to the toilet paper as we know it today. It has been claimed that the Sears and Roebuck catalog was also known as the  &#8221;Rears and Sorebutt&#8221; catalog. <em>The Farmer&#8217;s Almanac</em> even came with <a href="http://qctimes.com/news/opinion/editorial/columnists/bill-wundram/article_865b5f0c-9c1d-11de-81cf-001cc4c03286.html">a hole punched in it</a> so that it could be hung and the pages torn off with ease.</p>
<p>Toilet paper in its present form first appeared in 1857 thanks to <a href="http://itotd.com/articles/542/the-story-of-toilet-paper/">Joseph Gayetty</a>. It was thoughtfully moistened with aloe. In 1879, the Scott Paper Company was founded by brothers Edward and Clarence Scott. They sold toilet paper in an unperforated role. By 1885, perforated roles were being sold by Albany Perforated Wrapping Paper Company.</p>
<p>In 1935, Northern Tissue advertised its toilet paper to be &#8220;splinter-free.&#8221; Apparently, early production techniques managed to embed splinters in the paper. Three cheers for innovation! And finally, in 1942, two-ply toilet paper was introduced in St. Andrew&#8217;s Paper Mill in the UK. An odd development considering wartime austerity and rationing. Speaking of rationing, the <a href="http://nobodys-perfect.com/vtpm/index.html">Virtual Toilet Paper Museum</a> (you&#8217;re learning all sorts of things in this post) reports that the first toilet paper shortage in the US took place in 1973. Presumably, it was overshadowed by the oil embargo.</p>
<p>The point, of course, is that all technology has a history and that what we now take to be innovative and revolutionary will one day become ordinary and commonplace. This, of course, borders on cliche. The point, however, is to remember that before any technology became a naturalized and taken-for-granted part of society there were choices to be made. Forgetting that technology has a history is a way of refusing responsibility.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4921/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4921/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4921&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thefrailestthing.com/2012/07/25/toilet-paper-a-history/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/d9948d17a8c9258c89f32ad590dc7fab?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lmsacasas</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thefrailestthing.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/tp.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">TP</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Letter to parents</title>
		<link>http://arewegoingtodoanythingtoday.wordpress.com/2012/07/24/letter-to-parents/</link>
		<comments>http://arewegoingtodoanythingtoday.wordpress.com/2012/07/24/letter-to-parents/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2012 02:26:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>woundeddragonfly</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[frustrations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Letters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parents]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[school supplies]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://arewegoingtodoanythingtoday.wordpress.com/?p=11</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There are so many things I wish I could say, but alas, I am not allowed. Ok, anyone who actually knows me, knows that I would NEVER say these things, but this is how I really feel, and this is the truth; at least it&#8217;s my truth. Dear Parent/Guardian, I am looking forward to a [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=11&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There are so many things I wish I could say, but alas, I am not allowed. Ok, anyone who actually knows me, knows that I would NEVER say these things, but this is how I really feel, and this is the truth; at least it&#8217;s my truth.</p>
<p>Dear Parent/Guardian,</p>
<p>I am looking forward to a great year with your student.  I have spent my summer learning new strategies, and looking at ways to improve student learning.  Not a day has gone by that I didn&#8217;t at least think about something I would like to do or change in order to enhance student learning.  I have ignored statements made about what I do with my summers, ignored reports of testing on the news, and done what I know is right.  I know, that if I do my best to help and teach all students, tests will take care of themselves.</p>
<p>Every summer, not only do I prepare curriculum, but also prepare my classroom.  I believe that no student should have to receive a lower grade because they can&#8217;t afford basic supplies.  I stock my room with $1500-$1800 worth of supplies from my own money.  I go to trainings year round.  I go to school an hour early, and will stay late to help your child do the very best they can.  I don&#8217;t ask for much in return.  Here&#8217;s what I would like:</p>
<p>1. Respect my time.  If your student stays late, please pick them up.<br />
2. Don&#8217;t speak negatively about teachers in front of your student.  It undermines our ability to be the authority figure in the classroom.  If I can&#8217;t discipline your child because you have told them not to worry about what a teacher says, it disrupts the learning of others.  If it were the other way around, would you be up at the school demanding a conference because your child couldn&#8217;t learn in that environment?<br />
3. I don&#8217;t mind providing supplies when needed, but please don&#8217;t take advantage of me. I don&#8217;t make enough to support 110 children.<br />
4.  I need more than 24 hours to grade 110 essays.  Don&#8217;t call or email complaining that grades aren&#8217;t updated.<br />
5. Guess what, sometimes students lie; sometimes teachers make mistakes (we are human after all). If something is bothering you, please call or email so we can discuss it before you jump to conclusions.</p>
<p>If you have any questions or concerns, please don&#8217;t hesitate to contact me.</p>
<p>I am sure I have left some things out, but this is what comes to mind as I begin to shop for supplies.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/11/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/11/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=11&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://arewegoingtodoanythingtoday.wordpress.com/2012/07/24/letter-to-parents/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/e8b76424c91535e18c08322fddcae9ed?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">woundeddragonfly</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Oh the Places We&#8217;ve Been!</title>
		<link>http://makinglifepretty.wordpress.com/2012/07/23/oh-the-places-weve-been/</link>
		<comments>http://makinglifepretty.wordpress.com/2012/07/23/oh-the-places-weve-been/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2012 03:08:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>lizchack</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Crafty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DIY]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lovey Dovey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[charting your travels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diy travel map]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[map]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel pins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vintage map travel map]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://makinglifepretty.wordpress.com/?p=782</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve come to realize I really enjoy maps. They are so fascinating. Cities, towns, lakes, rivers although all discovered not all discovered by yours truly. I catch myself staring at them for hours. Thinking about how long it would take me to drive to San Francisco if I fly to Portland. (I mean it&#8217;s like [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=782&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve come to realize I really enjoy maps. They are so fascinating. Cities, towns, lakes, rivers although all discovered not all discovered by yours truly. I catch myself staring at them for hours. Thinking about how long it would take me to drive to San Francisco if I fly to Portland. (I mean it&#8217;s like RIGHT there relative to Jersey)  I&#8217;ve also come to realize I enjoy travel more than I once thought. This combination fueled a fun and forever evolving project.</p>
<p>Upon a semi recent trip to my wonderful college roomie&#8217;s house I got pretty jealous she beat me to the punch.  Over at <a href="http://creatingconfidence.wordpress.com/2011/12/21/where-in-the-world/">Creating Confidence</a> you can see roomie&#8217;s version of her &#8220;travel map&#8221;.</p>
<p>Because Mr. Fiance and myself have really only ventured to the greater Americas we started simple with a map of North and Central America. I found a really nice vintage map from the 1960&#8242;s with gorgeous coloring. Little bit of spray glue, foam core board, and skills from Art School I mounted the map so I had something to pin into.</p>
<p><a href="http://makinglifepretty.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/vintage-map-of-north-america.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-786" title="vintage-map-of-north-america" src="http://makinglifepretty.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/vintage-map-of-north-america.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="661" /></a></p>
<p>I then took a quick trip to Office Depot, grabbed some map pins and hurried home. The colors left a lot to be desired. (White, Black, Red)</p>
<p><a href="http://makinglifepretty.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/map-pins-before.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-783" title="map-pins-before" src="http://makinglifepretty.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/map-pins-before.jpg?w=500&h=332" alt="" width="500" height="332" /></a></p>
<p>Quick can of spray paint and I fixed that problem</p>
<p><a href="http://makinglifepretty.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/map-pins-spray-paint-pink.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-785" title="map-pins-spray-paint-pink" src="http://makinglifepretty.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/map-pins-spray-paint-pink.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="332" /></a></p>
<p>Future Hubs and I decided that rather than just including trips we went on together we would also include trips we&#8217;ve gone alone. Pink represents my travels, blue his, and white is where we&#8217;ve been together.</p>
<p><a href="http://makinglifepretty.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/map-with-pins.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-826" title="map-with-pins" src="http://makinglifepretty.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/map-with-pins.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="731" /></a></p>
<p>I&#8217;m still working on a frame to enclose the whole project but for now it&#8217;s just fine hanging raw. He may have significantly more pins West of the Mississippi but I&#8217;ve got the East coast dead and buried. He&#8217;s got me beat on furthest North, Canada, but I&#8217;ve traveled way closer to the equator than he has, Nicaragua. It&#8217;s also exciting to see how many white (us) trips we&#8217;ve taken.</p>
<p><a href="http://makinglifepretty.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/east-coast-pins-travel-map.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-824" title="east-coast-pins-travel-map" src="http://makinglifepretty.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/east-coast-pins-travel-map.jpg?w=500&h=332" alt="" width="500" height="332" /></a></p>
<p>The most exciting thing about this slightly lovey dovey project is how it will always be evolving. Removing a pink or a blue pin to replace with a white one, adding a new color once our traveling changes from &#8220;us&#8221; to &#8220;all of us&#8221; (ie potential future family trips) Just look at all that blank yet to be pinned and conquered map. Looking forward to hitting all 50 states and further.</p>
<p><a href="http://makinglifepretty.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/florida-pins-travel-map.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-825" title="florida-pins-travel-map" src="http://makinglifepretty.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/florida-pins-travel-map.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="753" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/782/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/782/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=782&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://makinglifepretty.wordpress.com/2012/07/23/oh-the-places-weve-been/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/6cfc3a00ae5bef5e711554c29b97737d?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lizchack</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://makinglifepretty.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/vintage-map-of-north-america.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">vintage-map-of-north-america</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://makinglifepretty.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/map-pins-before.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">map-pins-before</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://makinglifepretty.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/map-pins-spray-paint-pink.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">map-pins-spray-paint-pink</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://makinglifepretty.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/map-with-pins.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">map-with-pins</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://makinglifepretty.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/east-coast-pins-travel-map.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">east-coast-pins-travel-map</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://makinglifepretty.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/florida-pins-travel-map.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">florida-pins-travel-map</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Off My Chest &#8211; The Facebook Edition</title>
		<link>http://rowine.wordpress.com/2012/07/24/i-need-to-get-something-off-my-chest-the-facebook-edition/</link>
		<comments>http://rowine.wordpress.com/2012/07/24/i-need-to-get-something-off-my-chest-the-facebook-edition/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2012 19:52:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bethany</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[things I don't like]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rowine.wordpress.com/?p=339</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I don&#8217;t know how to say this nicely so I&#8217;m just going to come out and say it &#8211; Facebook sucks. It has jumped the shark, gone the way of neon and legwarmers, had a fat lady singing, whatever colorful phrase you want to use to describe something that used to be fun and relevant [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=339&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://rowine.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/0278615_facebook_sucks_xlarge.png"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-340" title="0278615_facebook_sucks_xlarge" src="http://rowine.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/0278615_facebook_sucks_xlarge.png?w=300&h=266" alt="" width="300" height="266" /></a></p>
<p>I don&#8217;t know how to say this nicely so I&#8217;m just going to come out and say it &#8211; Facebook sucks. It has jumped the shark, gone the way of neon and legwarmers, had a fat lady singing, whatever colorful phrase you want to use to describe something that used to be fun and relevant but has now been overrun by the digital equivalent of crazy cat ladies and paste eating conspiracy theorists, all armed with absolutely no sense of humor and a <a href="http://www.someecards.com/">someecard </a>account.</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s address the major culprits one at a time.</p>
<p><span id="more-339"></span></p>
<p>SOMEECARDS (or anything remotely resembling a someecard). If you have a Facebook account you have seen them. You&#8217;ve seen hundreds if not thousands of them. Today. They are ridiculous post card- type things meant to look like what would happen if a slightly gifted middle school art student made pencil renderings of all the characters in a Dicken&#8217;s book and then let grown up people with too much time on their hands write shit on them.</p>
<p>Very, VERY rarely one will come up that&#8217;s chuckle worthy, but you know what? I can&#8217;t laugh. Because all I can think about is stabbing the person who posted it. We&#8217;ve all been tempted. We&#8217;ve all had our mouse hovered over the &#8216;share&#8217; button, thinking, &#8216;You know what? This one is actually funny.&#8217; Admit it.</p>
<p><a href="http://rowine.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/sommee.png"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-341" title="sommee" src="http://rowine.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/sommee.png?w=300&h=210" alt="" width="300" height="210" /></a></p>
<p>The worst offenders are the ones who preface it by saying, &#8216;I know that these aren&#8217;t usually funny, and I normally never post them, but I just had to share&#8217;. STOP IT. Stop it now. You&#8217;re part of the problem.</p>
<p>If I were Mark Zuckerberg (in between laughing about how rich I am and bathing in champagne) I would make my programmers work around the clock to remove the &#8216;share this on facebook&#8217; option from that site. It is the single biggest reason Facebook sucks now.</p>
<p>Followed by anything asking you to &#8216;like&#8217; something because then something is going to happen. My personal favorite (and that actually sparked my Facebook rage) was this:</p>
<p><strong>If this post can get a MILLION likes, my dad is going to stop doing drugs. </strong></p>
<p>Really? Do you really think that&#8217;s true? Maybe. If you were on DRUGS. How did that convo go?</p>
<p>Kid &#8211; Dad. DAD. Put down the pipe. We need to talk.</p>
<p>Dad &#8211; *exhales* *blows crack smoke rings in kid&#8217;s face* What is it, son?</p>
<p>Kid &#8211; Dad. I really, REALLY, like really want you to stop doing drugs. What can I do to make you see it&#8217;s wrecking our family, you&#8217;re health, my childhood? You are very, very likely making me almost incapable of having a normal adulthood. What&#8217;s the ONE THING that I can do to get you to stop?</p>
<p>Dad &#8211; One million likes on Facebook. Or it ain&#8217;t happening.</p>
<p>NO ONE DOES THAT.</p>
<p>Or how about &#8216;share this if you remember&#8217; shit.</p>
<h6>Age Test: If you remember these two skaters, and why they were in the news, click &#8220;Like&#8221;</h6>
<div>
<div>
<div><img src="https://sphotos-a.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-prn1/s480x480/531592_479523548742417_991706124_n.jpg" alt="Age Test: If you remember these two skaters, and why they were in the news, click &quot;Like&quot;" width="300" height="300" /></div>
</div>
</div>
<p>Like ·  · <a title="Send this to friends or post it on your timeline." href="https://www.facebook.com/ajax/sharer/?s=2&amp;appid=2305272732&amp;p%5B0%5D=120971461264296&amp;p%5B1%5D=1675512" rel="dialog">Share</a> · <a title="Show/Hide comments and likes" href="https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=479523548742417&amp;set=a.334784389883001.91845.120971461264296&amp;type=1">286,03316,0079,032</a> · <a href="https://www.facebook.com/photo.php?fbid=479523548742417&amp;set=a.334784389883001.91845.120971461264296&amp;type=1"><abbr title="Tuesday, July 10, 2012 at 11:59pm">July 10 at 11:59pm</abbr></a> · I could give less than one shit if you remember Tonya Harding and Nancy Kerrigan. Hit me up when you got something to share on Jeff Gillooly. Now THAT I want to know about.</p>
<p>Can we also please, PLEASE stop it with the long, rambling inspirational quotes. Do you know anyone who has ever been inspired by reading one of those? ANYONE? Go ahead. Ask all your friends. I&#8217;ll wait.</p>
<p>No one? I didn&#8217;t think so.</p>
<p>I don&#8217;t think I even need to touch on Farmville/Mafia Wars/Any game you can play on Facebook, ever, or ads. I think we can collectively agree as a civilized society that they suck. But, they are also easily avoidable. Just don&#8217;t click or play. They aren&#8217;t assaulting your eyeballs every time you want to check to see how many people &#8216;liked&#8217; your last post.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not ALL bad. There are still things I love about Facebook.</p>
<p>Pictures of your kids &#8211; believe it or not, I truly like watching your kids grow and change. I don&#8217;t get to see all of you a lot, and most of you are my friends and family. This is the only chance I get to see the little munchkins, so post away.</p>
<p>Pictures of your vacation &#8211; I am only saying this because I post a lot of mine. Just kidding! I like your&#8217;s too! It&#8217;s totally working! I will turn to Casey and say, &#8216;Sweetie? Did you see this! Megan is camping again! We need to camp. They look like they&#8217;re having fun. Also. They clearly aren&#8217;t home. Let&#8217;s go use their hot tub!&#8217;</p>
<p>Funny updates &#8211; some of you really make me chuckle.</p>
<p>Relevant updates &#8211; there are a lot of current events out there, and some of you have very compelling and things to say about them. Thank you for making me think.</p>
<p>The ability to promote your blog &#8211; cause duh.</p>
<p>Arab Spring.</p>
<p>Facebook can be a powerful tool. For something that started out as a way to check out the hot freshman in the dorm across the quad, it&#8217;s come along way. I will stick around to see what happens next, but just know that if you post a someecard, I am judging you.</p>
<p>Yours in Twitter, Where It&#8217;s Safer,</p>
<p>Bethany</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/339/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/339/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=339&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://rowine.wordpress.com/2012/07/24/i-need-to-get-something-off-my-chest-the-facebook-edition/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/3f62b9283ef25df2bda9684afe884e4d?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mindbling</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://rowine.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/0278615_facebook_sucks_xlarge.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">0278615_facebook_sucks_xlarge</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://rowine.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/sommee.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sommee</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="https://sphotos-a.xx.fbcdn.net/hphotos-prn1/s480x480/531592_479523548742417_991706124_n.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Age Test: If you remember these two skaters, and why they were in the news, click &#34;Like&#34;</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Top ESP Searches: Volume 1</title>
		<link>http://espblog.com/2012/07/23/top-esp-searches-volume-1/</link>
		<comments>http://espblog.com/2012/07/23/top-esp-searches-volume-1/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2012 23:15:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Winston</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[What The Fuck?]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Call Center]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Musings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SEO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stupid]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thoughts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Searches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://espblog.com/?p=771</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Even though most of the clicks on ESP are from a loyal base of highly intelligent readers, there are some genuine morons that find their way over to ESP as well. WordPress has a nifty little thing called, &#8220;Top Searches&#8221; on the admin page. It displays all the top search terms, words, and phrases that [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=771&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 650px"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/linderrox/3104156263/"><img title="new magnifying glass" src="http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3175/3104156263_23ddf519e0_z.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="426" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Who needs glasses when you have a giant magnifying glass?</p></div>
<p><em>Even though most of the clicks on ESP are from a loyal base of highly intelligent readers, there are some genuine morons that find their way over to ESP as well. WordPress has a nifty little thing called, &#8220;Top Searches&#8221; on the admin page. It displays all the top search terms, words, and phrases that people use to get to ESP. In the early days, no one was really able to find ESP, as it barely made a dent on the ol&#8217; Google. Yet as ESP has grown over the last year and half, more and more people are finding the blog through various search engines. Since I can see all the search terms, I can clearly tell that a fair amount of the people finding ESP are pretty fucking stupid. Allow me to elaborate with few of the top searches:</em></p>
<p><strong>&#8220;My Wife Thinks I&#8217;m Stupid&#8221;</strong></p>
<p>This is the top search for ESP, with variations such as, &#8220;Wife says I&#8217;m dumb&#8221; and &#8220;Wife thinks me stupid.&#8221; The dumbasses searching are always lead to my post entitled, <a title="My Wife Thinks I’m Stupid" href="http://espblog.com/2012/05/02/my-wife-thinks-im-stupid/">My Wife Thinks I&#8217;m Stupid</a>. All I have to say in response to that is, really? I mean, really? If a guy has to go online and search, &#8220;My wife thinks I&#8217;m stupid,&#8221; his wife is obviously right. What is he hoping to find with the search? A magic cure for stupidity? If that were the case, this blog surely wouldn&#8217;t exist. The entire Southern portion of the US wouldn&#8217;t exist either.</p>
<p><strong>&#8220;DJ Jazzy Jeff&#8221;</strong></p>
<p>I included a picture and a little dialogue about Will Smith, greatest rapper of all time, in a post called, <a title="She’s Just A Receptionist" href="http://espblog.com/2012/03/26/shes-just-a-receptionist/">She&#8217;s Just A Receptionist</a>. Why in the fuck are people searching online for Jazzy Jeff, Will Smith&#8217;s cool sidekick on <em>The Fresh Prince</em>? Who has such little time in their day to allow them to say, &#8220;I wonder what Jazzy Jeff is up to?&#8221; I&#8217;ll answer that question for you: Not a fucking thing. Though you can feel free to peruse his official website, follow him on Twitter, listen to his terrible CD&#8217;s, or learn about him through the most accredited encyclopedia of all, Wikipedia. Or just watch reruns of <em>The Fresh Prince</em>, laugh when he gets thrown out of Uncle Phil&#8217;s house, and then forget about him completely.</p>
<p><span id="more-771"></span><strong>&#8220;I Work In A Call Center. The People That Call In Are Stupid&#8221;</strong></p>
<p>Uh, yeah, no shit. I said that same thing on my first day, and hence started ESP. I&#8217;m not sure where those searches end  up, maybe it&#8217;s the first post, <a title="Call Me Winston" href="http://espblog.com/2011/03/28/hello-world/">Call Me Winston</a>. Again, what is the motive behind this search? Counseling for those exposed to massive amounts of stupidity? A support group for those affected by too much unintelligence? I definitely need those. Maybe they were looking for a blog that ridiculed all the fucking morons that call into a customer service line. Look no further my long-suffering call center employee friends.</p>
<p><strong>&#8220;I&#8217;m An Old Lady And I Need Help&#8221;</strong></p>
<p>This is another popular search term, and it always leads to my past post of the same name, <a title="I’m An Old Lady And I Need Help!" href="http://espblog.com/2011/04/14/im-an-old-lady-and-i-need-help/">I&#8217;m An Old Lady And I Need Help!</a> There are a few things wrong with this picture. First of all, old ladies don&#8217;t know how to use computers, and therefore can&#8217;t search on Google. Even if they could, in moments of peril, shouldn&#8217;t they call 911 instead of hitting up Google? Don&#8217;t they have those lifeline button things, like the ones on the &#8220;Help, I can&#8217;t get up&#8221; commercials? It&#8217;s not like it&#8217;s &#8220;Help, I can&#8217;t connect to the Internet to figure out why I can&#8217;t get up&#8221; commercial. If some old lady did fall down, my blog sure as shit wouldn&#8217;t be of much use. Just in case some technologically savvy old ladies do find my blog in future moments of peril, here&#8217;s an important number for them: 9-1-1.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/771/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/771/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=771&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://espblog.com/2012/07/23/top-esp-searches-volume-1/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>31</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/20a19db9ad2a0dba15804fd95f0980f1?s=96&#38;d=wavatar&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">winstonesp</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3175/3104156263_23ddf519e0_z.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">new magnifying glass</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mass Murder is not a Political Opportunity</title>
		<link>http://consideragain.com/2012/07/24/mass-murder-is-not-a-political-opportunity/</link>
		<comments>http://consideragain.com/2012/07/24/mass-murder-is-not-a-political-opportunity/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2012 00:58:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>consideragain</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[All Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Current Issues]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Regulations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aurora]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[batman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[colorado]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dark knight rises]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gun control]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[james holmes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://consideragain.com/?p=320</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Last week, at a midnight showing of Dark Knight Rises (the new Batman movie), a madman named James Holmes brutally opened fire in a crowded movie theater, killing 12 and wounding 58 others. If you haven&#8217;t heard the story yet, read it here. I think one of the best quotes to reflect on is by [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=320&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://consideragain.com/2012/07/24/mass-murder-is-not-a-political-opportunity/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>33</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://consideragain.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/batman.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://consideragain.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/batman.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Batman</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/50be4fab7bd893e3a5ec9653cf67e6c1?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">consideragain</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>lomo lovin</title>
		<link>http://brittneyburkholder.wordpress.com/2012/07/24/lomo-lovin/</link>
		<comments>http://brittneyburkholder.wordpress.com/2012/07/24/lomo-lovin/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2012 02:56:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>brittneyburkholder</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[35mm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[color]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[expired film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hipster]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[light leak]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lomo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lomography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nyc]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[park]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stripes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Washington Square Park]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brittneyburkholder.wordpress.com/?p=233</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[someone gave me their old Lomo LC-A for my birthday. which, I think, is one of the nicest things you could possibly do for someone. there was some old film in it too, so these are all technically double exposures, but a lot of them you can&#8217;t really tell&#8230; but the wacky lomo + expired [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=233&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;">someone gave me their old Lomo LC-A for my birthday. which, I think, is one of the nicest things you could possibly do for someone.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">there was some old film in it too, so these are all technically double exposures, but a lot of them you can&#8217;t really tell&#8230; but the wacky lomo + expired film colour! I love colour so much!</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://brittneyburkholder.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/63620001.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-225" title="63620001" src="http://brittneyburkholder.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/63620001.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="331" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://brittneyburkholder.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/63620021.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-232" title="63620021" src="http://brittneyburkholder.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/63620021.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="331" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://brittneyburkholder.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/63620010.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-227" title="63620010" src="http://brittneyburkholder.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/63620010.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="754" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">“Mere color, unspoiled by meaning, and unallied with definite form, can speak to the soul in a thousand different ways. ” &#8211; Oscar Wilde</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://brittneyburkholder.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/63620006.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-226" title="63620006" src="http://brittneyburkholder.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/63620006.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="331" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://brittneyburkholder.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/63620020.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-231" title="63620020" src="http://brittneyburkholder.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/63620020.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="331" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://brittneyburkholder.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/63620013.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-229" title="63620013" src="http://brittneyburkholder.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/63620013.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="331" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">“Why do two colors, put one next to the other, sing? Can one really explain this? no. Just as one can never learn how to paint.” - Pablo Picasso</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://brittneyburkholder.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/63620019.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-230" title="63620019" src="http://brittneyburkholder.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/63620019.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="331" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://brittneyburkholder.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/63620012.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-228" title="63620012" src="http://brittneyburkholder.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/63620012.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="331" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">“The purest and most thoughtful minds are those which love color the most. ” &#8211; John Ruskin</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/233/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/233/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=233&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://brittneyburkholder.wordpress.com/2012/07/24/lomo-lovin/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c6e1ab35e817848538b12109e294c612?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">brittneyburkholder</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://brittneyburkholder.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/63620001.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">63620001</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://brittneyburkholder.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/63620021.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">63620021</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://brittneyburkholder.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/63620010.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">63620010</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://brittneyburkholder.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/63620006.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">63620006</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://brittneyburkholder.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/63620020.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">63620020</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://brittneyburkholder.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/63620013.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">63620013</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://brittneyburkholder.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/63620019.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">63620019</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://brittneyburkholder.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/63620012.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">63620012</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Writing the Unseen: Collision</title>
		<link>http://annaldavis.net/2012/07/25/writing-the-unseen-collision/</link>
		<comments>http://annaldavis.net/2012/07/25/writing-the-unseen-collision/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2012 16:49:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>annaldavis</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[psychology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spirituality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://annaldavis.net/?p=1005</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[What we cannot see, and yet know instinctively, is that writing is an act of war.<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1005&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://annaldavis.net/2012/07/25/writing-the-unseen-collision/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>34</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/24ade462a24cb05774adbbe9d5968e1a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">annaldavis</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://annaldavis.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/the-lord-of-the-rings-the-fellowship-of-the-ring1.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">the-lord-of-the-rings-the-fellowship-of-the-ring1</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Conical Combat Linkages</title>
		<link>http://ptsdandcombat.com/2012/07/21/conical-combat-linkages/</link>
		<comments>http://ptsdandcombat.com/2012/07/21/conical-combat-linkages/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2012 19:10:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Rod Deaton</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture at War]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Living Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Professional Relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Respect, Honor, Duty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[combat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Desert Storm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[military]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OEF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OIF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[post traumatic stress disorder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PTSD]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[veteran]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ptsdandcombat.com/?p=1177</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Sometimes it takes some days for an encounter with a combat veteran to sink in. Sometimes it takes some days just to decide how much I dare let it sink in. I’ve talked of this man before, in Buddy, Got the Time? He’s sharp, insightful, witty. He can be cutting (hilariously so, I might add). [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1177&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sometimes it takes some days for an encounter with a combat veteran to sink in. Sometimes it takes some days just to decide how much I dare let it sink in.</p>
<p>I’ve talked of this man before, in <a href="http://wp.me/p25Yro-ec"><em>Buddy, Got the Time?</em></a> He’s sharp, insightful, witty. He can be cutting (hilariously so, I might add). He’s a Desert Storm vet.</p>
<p>He’s been trying to make his life work for over twenty years.</p>
<p>He’s been doing much better at that since we’ve begun working together. His combat nightmares have dramatically reduced. His relationships, though still, shall we say, on the complex side, have calmed, at least some. He has been able to work more regularly, and he has come up with some very doable, very challenging long-range business plans.</p>
<p>We hadn’t spoken for a few weeks, primarily because of my being in and out of town. When we did, I heard it in his voice.</p>
<p>&#8220;Been a tough couple of weeks, Doc.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;What’s been up?&#8221; I respond.</p>
<p>&#8220;The nightmares. But they’re totally different this time. It’s weird. They’re not about combat. They’re about guys I knew back in Desert Storm. None of them died, but somehow I keep meeting them in my dreams. And these aren’t good meetings, Doc. They’re confusing, upsetting. There’s one dream I’ve had a good five times, and every time I bolt up after it and can’t fall back asleep.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;What happens?&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;There’s this senior officer I served under. He’s just standing there, not even in his combat gear, looking at me. He’s covered in blood, sand, dirt. He’s upset, and he keeps talking, keeps trying to tell me something, keeps reaching out to me. But I can’t understand a word he’s saying.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;What was he like,&#8221; I ask, &#8220;the real man, as a person, to you?&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;He was like John Wayne,&#8221; he answered, his voice brightening slightly. &#8220;He even sort of walked like Wayne did. He was a man of few words, but he knew what to do, when to do it, and he knew how to lead. He could be calm when no one else was. He took charge. He was quite the guy, almost like a big brother to me. And that’s what’s so strange: in my dream, he looks so lost, desperate, trying to tell me something, I know it, but I can’t understand a thing. It’s not him, Doc. But it is.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;How long have you been having the dream?&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;The last two weeks, I’d say.&#8221; He paused. &#8220;I’m trying to think if there was anything that went on then. I really hadn’t thought about that before right now.&#8221; He paused again.</p>
<p>&#8220;Anything?&#8221; I finally asked.</p>
<p>Still no words, but then, slowly, &#8220;You know, that’s right. That BBC show, about the guys in Afghanistan. Yeah, that’s it. It really upset me.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;What happened in it?&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;It’s not so much what happened as what was happening. These guys had taken direct hits. They’d lost several men. But you know what they were doing over there? Helping Afghans learn to farm. Can you believe it? It was agriculture class. And guys were dying for it.&#8221;</p>
<p>His voice had become more distant. I could almost feel him in front of that television, open-mouthed, furious, but too shocked to do anything about it.</p>
<p>&#8220;I mean,&#8221; he continued, his tempo picking up, &#8220;that’s crazy! Crazy! There’s a f***ing war going on, we’re sending these guys to battle, and for <em>gardening</em>? Look, I understand: the best thing we ever did when I was over there, the one thing I’m still proud of, is that we completed a big public works project that saved the lives of I-don’t-know-how-many people. I get it: we’re trying to help the locals, show them we’re not horrible people. But what, Doc, what?&#8221;</p>
<p>I hadn’t heard him this animated in quite a while.</p>
<p>&#8220;What–&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;What the f*** are we doing over there?,&#8221; he continued. &#8220;Where has all this death, this destruction gotten us? What is it about these politicians? None of them served. What do <em>they</em> know? My job was to watch out for young kids like those kids over there who are plowing fields or whatever they’re doing–and getting killed! I was a kid myself. I mean, if you want us to do good works, send us to do good works, fine, we’re the best, we can do that. But to send us over to fight, to kill, to die–and then to <em>garden</em>? Are you, like, for real, man? This is crazy, Doc, f***ing crazy.&#8221;</p>
<p>He was on a roll. I couldn’t have stopped him had I even wanted to.</p>
<p>&#8220;And you know what else? I just remembered this, too. It was around that time that I had this really serious talk with my daughter. She told me she wanted to talk to me as an adult, not as my little girl. So we did. And you know what she said to me?&#8221;</p>
<p>I couldn’t even utter a mere &#8220;what?&#8221;. Clearly he had too much to say, right then, now, <em>now</em>.</p>
<p>&#8220;She said that she’s sick and tired of people telling her that she should have known me before I went over to Desert Storm, that she should have known the man I ‘used to be.’ She looked right at me, Doc, and she dropped the F-bomb. I’m not kidding: I’d never heard her say that in her entire life. She looked at me and said, ‘Don’t they f***ing get it? <em>You’re</em> my Dad. <em>You’re</em> the man I’ve always known. I don’t care what you were like before. I care about who you are <em>now</em>. I care about you trying to care of yourself, trying to take care of us. Why can’t people just let you be who you are?’&#8221;</p>
<p>Silence. On both our parts. It was one of those silences that I dread, a silence that dares me to say one, single word, a silence that shakes me at my core, demanding that I say something, anything, all the while laughing at me because it knows there is nothing to say, nothing to do except feel the silence shake me, shake, shake.</p>
<p>Then I thought it. I waited a few moments. I asked it.</p>
<p>&#8220;Is that what your officer is trying to ask you? Why did we do all this? Why did this happen to us, back then, now? We’re covered in blood, sand, dirt, we’re just . . . why?&#8221;</p>
<p>For at least fifteen, maybe even thirty seconds, he said nothing.</p>
<p>&#8220;Doc, &#8221; he finally said, in a whisper that shouted, &#8220;I’m proud that I served my country. I’m proud that I made people’s lives better when I could. I’m proud of the men I served with. I honor the men I sent home to be buried. But, Doc, some days, I just don’t know, I don’t think I can take another g**d***ed minute. Do they know what they’re doing, do they have a clue, these politicians, these bureaucrats? Do they know what they’re creating? This is gonna take years, Doc, years to clean up the mess they started! And I’m just talking about the men and women who are coming back! And why? Why? For vegetables? Are you kidding me? <em>Vegetables</em>?&#8221;</p>
<p>I can’t fully describe to you how it is to sit with someone who feels that, says that, lives that so deeply. It was not the first time for me to be in such a position, but he was so passionate, truthful, precise. Like so many combat veterans whom I have served, he both despises war and acknowledges its inevitability, even, as is the opinion of many, its necessity. He’s no pacifist, but he’s no warmonger. He believes that what he values can sometimes be insane. He believes sometimes that he is insane to value what he values. Yet that is who he was. That is who he is. That is who he hopes he will always be.</p>
<p>&#8220;After war, Doc, nothing connects in a straight line. There’s no direct, uncomplicated connection between you and your spouse, your kids, your family, your coworkers, clients, nobody. It’s almost as if I’m back in engineering class. Life doesn’t develop linearly in any way whatsoever, but almost, what, geometrically. You know, a lot of the guys you see probably wouldn’t put it that way, but that’s really it. Everything multiplies, expands, spins, and the line, it becomes like a cone, a vortex, and you can’t even figure out which end is the tip.&#8221;</p>
<p>After a few seconds, he then chuckled.</p>
<p>&#8220;What is it?&#8221; I asked.</p>
<p>&#8220;Maybe you can blog about this one, eh, Doc? What could we call these things? How about ‘conical combat linkages’? We could do CCL for short. Yeah, that’s it. Conical combat linkages. Vortex after vortex after vortex.&#8221;</p>
<p>By this point, I’m simply stunned. I haven’t a clue what to say. The word <em>vortex</em> is living out its meaning inside my head, swirling, like the Charybdis that nearly swallowed Odysseus, like the tornadoes that periodically stroll down our Midwest alley.</p>
<p>&#8220;I’m so sorry,&#8221; I finally say. Stupid. A <em>stupid</em> thing to say. I’m ashamed of myself before the last syllable has the audacity to pass through my vocal chords. Stupid, stupid, stupid.</p>
<p>He’s a good man, though. He actually laughs. I haven’t heard this voice at any point in this conversation so far.</p>
<p>&#8220;Doc,&#8221; he drawls–and I mean, drawls. &#8220;It ain’t your fault, guy.&#8221;</p>
<p>I thank him.</p>
<p>And I wonder.</p>
<p>What <em>do</em> I believe about war, about peace, as a citizen of this country, as a Mennonite by choice, as a psychiatrist by trade, as one guy listening to the heart of another guy, that guy’s heart gritting its teeth, letting its jaw drop in incredulity, in exhaustion, left saying nothing? How many times have I said it in this blog–and yet how many times have I truly, truly asked myself: what venti, nonfat lattes did you give up, Rod? This War ain’t your fault, guy?</p>
<p>Really?</p>
<p>Maybe it wasn&#8217;t such a stupid thing to say after all.</p>
<p>The linkages swirl, between me and this veteran, between him and his ex-wife, his children, his siblings, between me and the next man or woman I’ll interview the next time I step into my office–&#8221;next in line, please!&#8221;– between me and a nation, between me and a faith tradition, a family tradition, between me and a wife, three children, a world. Conically. Combat half a globe away geometrically expands all my linkages, all <em>our</em> linkages.</p>
<p>The vortices will demand our attention. They’ll get what’s due them. That’s the way of vortices. Even Odysseus found that out. Pay now. Pay later.</p>
<p>Whether or not you eat all your vegetables.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1177/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1177/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1177&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://ptsdandcombat.com/2012/07/21/conical-combat-linkages/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>16</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/05302909306f4908710d1986a2f2ad44?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ptsdandcombat</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How I Spent the 4th of July on a Motorcycle in Vietnam</title>
		<link>http://yearonawhim.wordpress.com/2012/07/25/how-i-spent-the-4th-of-july-on-a-motorcycle-in-vietnam/</link>
		<comments>http://yearonawhim.wordpress.com/2012/07/25/how-i-spent-the-4th-of-july-on-a-motorcycle-in-vietnam/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2012 19:44:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jessica</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Motorcycles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[My Version of Extreme]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Solo Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Southeast Asia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vietnam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dalat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[easyrider vietnam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[motorcycle vietnam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mui ne]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nha trang]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vietnam mountains]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://yearonawhim.wordpress.com/?p=1074</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[One of the best things about traveling solo* is the freedom it gives you to make impractical, ridiculous, somewhat expensive decisions on the fly. Don&#8217;t get me wrong: as we traveled together, Hayley and I were always eventually able to agree on what we wanted to do in each place and what our budgets were. [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1074&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One of the best things about traveling solo* is the freedom it gives you to make impractical, ridiculous, somewhat expensive decisions on the fly. Don&#8217;t get me wrong: as we traveled together, Hayley and I were always eventually able to agree on what we wanted to do in each place and what our budgets were. But there&#8217;s nothing quite like deciding at 4:00 a.m. that your trip is going to take a major detour, then waking up a few hours later and making it happen without consulting anyone.</p>
<p>So, a few weeks ago, I made a spur-of-the-moment decision to ditch my <a title="Night Buses in Vietnam: the Good, the Bad, and the Scary" href="http://yearonawhim.wordpress.com/2012/07/24/night-buses-in-vietnam-the-good-the-bad-and-the-scary/">sleeper-bus routine</a> in Vietnam and hit the open road on a mode of transportation that had terrified me up until <a title="Riding Motorbikes in Vietnam (With a Little Confidence and a Lot of Help)" href="http://yearonawhim.wordpress.com/2012/07/19/riding-motorbikes-in-vietnam-with-a-little-confidence-and-a-lot-of-help/">earlier that very day</a>.</p>
<div id="attachment_1079" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://yearonawhim.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dscn5230.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1079" title="DSCN5230" src="http://yearonawhim.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dscn5230.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="450" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">My new mode of transport, with the contents of my life strapped to the rear: backpack, laptop, wallet, passport.</p></div>
<p>Vietnam&#8217;s sleeper-buses are efficient, I suppose, if not incredibly comfortable or reassuringly safe. But after covering the bulk of the country cramped and virtually sleepless in a top bunk hurtling down the road, well, you start to wonder if maybe there isn&#8217;t a better way of getting around.</p>
<p>Splashing around in the ocean in Nha Trang with new friends late one night, the idea of catching my 7:00 a.m. bus to Mui Ne just a few hours later began to sound unreasonable, unappealing&#8230; unthinkable, if you want to know the truth. So I slept through my morning alarm, marched out the door at 8:00, and put a two-day motorcycle tour on my credit card at 8:10. It set me back about three times what my ticket to cover the entire country by sleeper bus had, and I had no idea if I&#8217;d enjoy it or spend the next two days in white-knuckled terror. But my mind had been made up. Impractical or no, a motorcycle had to be better than the bus.</p>
<div id="attachment_1112" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://yearonawhim.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dscn52411.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1112" title="DSCN5241" src="http://yearonawhim.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dscn52411.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="450" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The open road.</p></div>
<p>From Nha Trang I&#8217;d head inland, motor up into the mountains of Dalat, then cruise back down south along the coast to the beachfront town of Mui Ne. All on the back of a bike.</p>
<div id="attachment_1082" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 272px"><a href="http://yearonawhim.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/screen-shot-2012-07-23-at-3-11-09-pm.png"><img class="size-full wp-image-1082" title="Screen shot 2012-07-23 at 3.11.09 PM" src="http://yearonawhim.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/screen-shot-2012-07-23-at-3-11-09-pm.png" alt="" width="262" height="367" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Nha Trang up top, Dalat inland, and Mui Ne down on the southern coast.</p></div>
<p>The next morning, breakfast bahn-mi in hand, I stood outside my hotel and watched as Jolly pulled up. My driver wasn&#8217;t exactly what I&#8217;d pictured: easily in his 60s, decked out in a plaid shirt and sandals, Jolly hardly looked bad-ass enough to pilot motorcycles for a living. But then again, I still hardly felt bad-ass enough to ride one. I handed over all of my earthly possessions, watched skeptically as Jolly strapped them to the bike, popped on my helmet, and climbed awkwardly up onto the back of the seat. I had a faint, ironic realization that it was the fourth of July, and that I&#8217;d be celebrating America&#8217;s most patriotic holiday by motorcycling through Vietnam. And then we were off.</p>
<div id="attachment_1083" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://yearonawhim.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dscn5266.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1083" title="DSCN5266" src="http://yearonawhim.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dscn5266.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="450" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Heeeeeere&#8217;s Jolly!</p></div>
<p>Within an hour we were well outside the city, working our way up curvy, nearly deserted roads as we headed to Dalat. As we passed through small towns or by roadside stands, we&#8217;d stop for lunch or for fresh-pressed sugar cane juice, swinging in hammocks slung up under tin roofs while stray chickens strutted around us. We weren&#8217;t in any hurry to get to Dalat &#8212; in fact, I&#8217;d told Jolly specifically that Dalat wasn&#8217;t the draw for me. I was far more interested in the mountainous roads we&#8217;d have to take to get there, the vignettes of daily life we&#8217;d pass along the way. <a title="Night Train to Chiang Mai" href="http://yearonawhim.wordpress.com/2012/06/09/night-train-to-chiang-mai/">Once again</a>, the journey &#8211; not the destination &#8211; was the whole point.</p>
<div id="attachment_1084" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://yearonawhim.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dscn5305.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1084" title="DSCN5305" src="http://yearonawhim.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dscn5305.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="450" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Somewhere between Nha Trang and Dalat</p></div>
<p>Along the way, Jolly would act as my vegetarian food interpreter, finagling special-order veggies and tofu at hole-in-the-wall little restaurants. He&#8217;d pull the bike over the second he heard me start snapping off rapid-fire pictures at drive-by viewpoints. I felt the dust in my face and the wind on my arms, and started to wonder what I&#8217;d ever seen in sleeper-buses in the first place. They were cheap and convenient, sure, but only barreled along at night, when Vietnam&#8217;s huge vistas sat darkened and removed behind a thick layer of window. This felt more like the real Vietnam: I could smell it, touch it, taste it, interact with it. I could scrub it off my face at the end of the day and clap it off the soles of my shoes.</p>
<div id="attachment_1085" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://yearonawhim.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dscn5263.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1085" title="DSCN5263" src="http://yearonawhim.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dscn5263.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="450" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The kind of view you can&#8217;t get from the bus</p></div>
<div id="attachment_1104" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 460px"><a href="http://yearonawhim.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dscn5280.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1104" title="DSCN5280" src="http://yearonawhim.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dscn5280.jpg" alt="" width="450" height="600" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The only other person on the road&#8230;</p></div>
<p>The next day, we shot off from Dalat and back down the mountainsides toward Mui Ne. The valleys turned to flat, red earth; the forests gave way to peanut fields and sandy coastline. The air went from chilly and foggy to warm and salty. And I could see and feel it all as it happened.</p>
<div id="attachment_1110" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://yearonawhim.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dscn5420.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1110" title="DSCN5420" src="http://yearonawhim.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dscn5420.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="450" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Back on flat land.</p></div>
<p>What&#8217;s more: I got a chance to look daring, if only for one photo. And for that alone, I&#8217;d do the whole thing again.</p>
<div id="attachment_1106" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://yearonawhim.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dscn5270.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1106" title="DSCN5270" src="http://yearonawhim.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dscn5270.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="450" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Jolly insisted I pose for this picture at the front of the bike, not in my usual post at the back. He seemed to think people might believe I actually drove this thing at some point. Misguided optimism.</p></div>
<p><em>*Now seems like a great time to address a question I&#8217;ve been getting kind of a lot lately: What happened to Hayley?</em></p>
<p><em>Don&#8217;t fret: we didn&#8217;t have a falling out or get sick of each other. In fact, when we finally did separate, a few days after arriving in Vietnam, it was amid much sniffling and hugs. The truth is, we split up because Hayley&#8217;s much better at managing her time and finances than I am.</em></p>
<p><em>Being the Sensible Brit that she is, Hayley actually purchased her July 2nd ticket back to Auckland weeks in advance. She&#8217;d given herself a deadline to get back to Queenstown, find a job, and start replacing all that money she&#8217;d spent on our two months of vacation. So by the time we reached Vietnam on June 21st, she already knew she&#8217;d need to get through everything south of Hanoi quick-style.</em></p>
<p><em>I, being more of the Irresponsible American type, waited much longer to book my flight back to Auckland. This resulted in a one-way ticket for July 21st and quite a bit of time to kill before then. After a quick visit to Halong Bay together, I had time to head north to <a title="Two Treks in Sapa" href="http://yearonawhim.wordpress.com/2012/07/15/two-treks-in-sapa/">Sa Pa</a> while Hayley opted to shoot directly down to <a title="The Best-Dressed Backpacker in Hoi An" href="http://yearonawhim.wordpress.com/2012/07/13/the-best-dressed-backpacker-in-hoi-an/">Hoi An</a>. So while much of our time in Vietnam overlapped, she remained a city or two ahead of me up until she left Asia. (For those dedicated Hayley fans out there: she&#8217;s now living in <a title="Bueller?" href="http://yearonawhim.wordpress.com/2012/04/23/bueller/">Queenstown</a>, which was exactly what she&#8217;d wanted, working as a cashier at the local supermarket).</em></p>
<p><em>So, unless otherwise specified, you can assume I&#8217;m traveling solo throughout the rest of my Asia posts.</em></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1074/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1074/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1074&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://yearonawhim.wordpress.com/2012/07/25/how-i-spent-the-4th-of-july-on-a-motorcycle-in-vietnam/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://yearonawhim.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dscn52411.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://yearonawhim.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dscn52411.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSCN5241</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/8b17c6fdb06c1bb9ce69ecf1c3924b60?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jessicaquandt</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://yearonawhim.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dscn5230.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSCN5230</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://yearonawhim.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dscn52411.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSCN5241</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://yearonawhim.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/screen-shot-2012-07-23-at-3-11-09-pm.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen shot 2012-07-23 at 3.11.09 PM</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://yearonawhim.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dscn5266.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSCN5266</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://yearonawhim.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dscn5305.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSCN5305</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://yearonawhim.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dscn5263.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSCN5263</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://yearonawhim.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dscn5280.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSCN5280</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://yearonawhim.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dscn5420.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSCN5420</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://yearonawhim.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dscn5270.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSCN5270</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>