<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 21:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>The Lady Who Saw Kennedy</title>
		<link>http://robpixaday.wordpress.com/2013/01/21/the-lady-who-saw-kennedy/</link>
		<comments>http://robpixaday.wordpress.com/2013/01/21/the-lady-who-saw-kennedy/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2013 16:20:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>robpixaday</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[absurd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[musings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thoughts]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://robpixaday.wordpress.com/?p=6291</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[When I was very young, John F. Kennedy ran for President. Yes, I’m that old. One of our neighbors was in the city when Kennedy arrived to campaign for votes. She happened to be in the crowd on the street and saw him. She saw him. She didn’t touch him or shake his hand or [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=6291&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://robpixaday.wordpress.com/2013/01/21/the-lady-who-saw-kennedy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>15</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/cbe894da004b1bfea6542d1c759945f7?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F0.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">robpixaday</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://robpixaday.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/tinyladywhosawkennedy.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Did she bring any snickerdoodles? (Drawn by Robin King - All rights reserved)</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rwenzori Journal</title>
		<link>http://timetoeatthedogs.com/2013/01/21/rwenzori-journal/</link>
		<comments>http://timetoeatthedogs.com/2013/01/21/rwenzori-journal/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2013 18:15:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Michael Robinson</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Expeditions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Explorers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://timetoeatthedogs.com/?p=3296</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[For the past three weeks, I’ve been in Uganda doing research on my next book, Lost White Tribe: Explorers, Scientists, and a Theory of Race that Changed Africa (New York: Oxford University Press, 2015). The book begins in 1876 in East Africa, where the journalist and explorer Henry Morton Stanley encountered four Africans whose light [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3296&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_3297" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 280px"><img class="size-full wp-image-3297" alt="Bamwanjara Pass, 14,600 ft (4450 m), Rwenzori Mountains" src="http://timetoeatthedogs.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_8125.jpg?w=720"   /><p class="wp-caption-text"><span style="color:#000000;">Bamwanjara Pass, 14,600 ft (4450 m), Rwenzori Mountains</span></p></div>
<p><span style="color:#000000;"><i>For the past three weeks, I’ve been in Uganda doing research on my next book, </i>Lost White Tribe: Explorers, Scientists, and a Theory of Race that Changed Africa <i> (New York: Oxford University Press, 2015). The book begins in 1876 in East Africa, where the journalist and explorer Henry Morton Stanley encountered four Africans whose light complexion and European features “aroused [his] curiosity to the highest pitch.” They came from the slopes of Gambaragara, a snow-capped mountain west of Lake Victoria. That such a towering range existed in the heart of equatorial Africa was astonishing enough. “But what gives it peculiar interest,” Stanley wrote, “is, that on its cold and lonely top dwell a people of an entirely distinct race, being white, like Europeans.”</i></span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;"><i> Stanley&#8217;s story had the ring of the fantastic about it, but was taken seriously by scientists, explorers, and the general public &#8212; and came to be supported by evidence ranging from the origin stories of the Hebrew Bible, the discovery of ancient ruins in Egypt and Zimbabwe, the kingship legends of African cultures, and the physical differences observed &#8212; by Stanley and many others &#8212; among African tribes. The existence of white tribes of Africa was a theory, defenders claimed, supported by many pillars. </i>Lost White Tribe<i> traces the rise and fall of this theory, the Hamitic Hypothesis, and the scientific expeditions that gave it life.</i></span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;"><i> After completing my research at Makerere University in Kampala, I took a bus west to Kasese, and then hired a motorcycle taxi to Kilembe.  This small town was the gateway to the Rwenzoris, the tallest mountain range in Africa. Just east of here Stanley glimpsed the massive blue silhouette of Gambaragara (now called Mt. Stanley) for the first time. I spent eight days on Mt. Stanley with a Bakonzo guide and porters, recording what I could of the mountain, its people, and my own subjective experiences. Here are some brief excerpts:</i></span></p>
<div id="attachment_3298" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 280px"><img class="size-full wp-image-3298" alt="Kilembe, Western Uganda. Gateway to the Rwenzoris." src="http://timetoeatthedogs.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_7855.jpg?w=720"   /><p class="wp-caption-text"><span style="color:#000000;">Kilembe, Western Uganda. Gateway to the Rwenzoris.</span></p></div>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">10 January 2013</span><br />
<span style="color:#000000;"> Sine Camp 8576 ft (2596m)</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">At 9:30 we walk into Kilembe village, past wooden huts and kiosks, men raking coffee beans, selling cell phone time, children driving cows. Rows of single-level dormitories stretch off to the left covered by rusty metal roofs,  goats graze the courtyards between.  The dorms were originally built as housing units for workers of the British copper mining company that came here years before. Now muzungu money enters the valley only from coffee sales or trekkers like me. The presence of whites is now rare enough to peak interest. Or fear. As we climb the trailhead, we pass a woman bringing her children to work the vertical fields of bananas and cassava ahead. Her daughter, about three years old, is ahead of us on the trail. As the girl sees us approach, separating her from her mother, she begins to cry. When she sees me, her cries grow sharp. I remove my sunglasses thinking it will help. Bad idea. She screams, covers her eyes, leaps off the trail. Scary muzungu.</span></p>
<div id="attachment_3299" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 280px"><img class="size-full wp-image-3299" alt="William Kiminywa finds a path through the mud." src="http://timetoeatthedogs.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_8088.jpg?w=720"   /><p class="wp-caption-text"><span style="color:#000000;">William Kiminywa finds a path through the mud.</span></p></div>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">11 January 2013</span><br />
<span style="color:#000000;"> Kalalama Camp 10,327 ft (3147m)</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">My guide William Kiminywa is Bakonzo, a member of an ethnic group that inhabits the lowlands of the Ruwenzoris, from Western Uganda to Eastern Congo. All of the porters are Bakonzo too, mostly from Kilembe. He’s heard no talk of “white Africans” living on the mountains, but clearly the mountains are a place of the sacred and the strange. William will not say the names of the mountains that tower above us on both sides of the valley – 13,000ft pinnacles that drop straight down to the heather trees of the valley. He writes out the names in my journal instead. Unwise to say the original Bakonzo names out loud. He is no mere folklorist though. William knows the Rwenzoris like no one else. We hike through knee-deep swamps and bogs, oceans of mud. He always sees a way through though – rocks, branches, tussocks invisible to me – stepping stones through the black ooze. I call him the mud whisperer. He laughs. But its true, his knowledge goes deep, sensory and academic. Where I see a mass of ferns and heather, he sees colobus monkeys, dikas, rock hyrax, turacos. He points them out to me quietly with his walking pole, whispering their Latin names so as not to scare them away. I nod, write, take pictures.</span></p>
<div id="attachment_3300" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 280px"><img class="size-full wp-image-3300" alt="Blue Monkeys, 12,000 ft." src="http://timetoeatthedogs.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_8008.jpg?w=720"   /><p class="wp-caption-text"><span style="color:#000000;">Blue Monkeys, 12,000 ft.</span></p></div>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">12 January 2013</span><br />
<span style="color:#000000;"> Bugata Camp 13,327 ft (4062m)</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">Today we approach the lower arm of Mt. Stanley. We are now closer to the mountain than Stanley was in 1876 when he climbed a small mountain near the Katonga River and “caught a passing glimpse of the king of mountains Gambaragara.” It was at the summit of this great mountain, Stanley’s African troops told him, that the white Gambaragarans lived amid the snow and craters lakes. Still, my head is elsewhere today. Tess completes in the final round of an oratory contest in Bloomfield, a big event in her life and  to miss it hurts a bit. More than a bit. I feel the isolation of the mountains as we go higher. William is fantastic, and his crew of porters are polite, knowledgeable, professional, but no companions. I am a client, not a friend. The porters bring food, supplies, then retreat to their own tents. Tea and biscuits at 4pm, even in rainstoms, on windy cliffs. When I visit their quarters to talk, they stand, go silent. I’m unshaven, unshowered, caked with mud, but I’m still the Earl of Grantham and I’ve come to servants’ quarters unannounced. My liberal politics, my critiques of colonialism, Victorian explorers, mean nothing here. I enter a fixed role, one that’s been set in place in Africa for hundreds of years and is kept in place by all kinds of trekkers organizations here, Kilimanjaro, maybe the Himalayas too? (I must ask the Everest people). I’m head muzungu. It’s Upstairs Downstairs, only at altitude. Where’s my pith helmet?</span></p>
<div id="attachment_3301" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 280px"><img class="size-full wp-image-3301" alt="Summit of Mt. Stanley, border between Uganda and Congo, dividing point between the watersheds of the Congo and Nile Rivers." src="http://timetoeatthedogs.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_8143.jpg?w=720"   /><p class="wp-caption-text"><span style="color:#000000;">Summit of Mt. Stanley, border between Uganda and Congo, dividing point between the watersheds of the Congo and Nile Rivers.</span></p></div>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">15 January 2013</span><br />
<span style="color:#000000;"> Margherita Camp  14,714 ft (4485m)</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">We leave at 3 am for the summit, headlamps on. I stay very close to William. I never know if the blackness covers a slope or sheer void. After an hour of hiking we’re in snow, then glacier. We take thirty minutes to put on crampons and harnesses, rope up. The march across Elena Glacier is calming after the rocks. Black sky and an ocean of white, just the sound of our feet. We descent a sharp pinnacle of rocks, then we’re on Margherita Glacier. This is not calming. The glacier is steep here, very steep, and the wind howls. I don’t know how many knots but its enough to push flinty pieces of ice up the 50° slope towards the summit and into the skies over Congo. They hit us and keep moving. The air is so thin, it cracks my lips and it’s impossible to catch my breath. I shuffle like an old man. William seems unaffected. Three hours of this and we are finally the rocky crown. It’s so hard to move up this craggy face, I have to crawl at points towards the summit. When we’re there, I stand and sob. I can’t help it. An accumulation of feelings over the six day ascent, and longer perhaps, the three weeks in Kampala and Western Uganda. There are many points of contact between Stanley’s description, those of his African soldiers, and what I see here. The ice and snow, the small lakes in the shadow of the glacier, the great elevation. But there are no lost whites up here – well &#8212; none except for me. And maybe there’s something to that. Stanley wasn’t the only one to think he saw white people in weird places. Not a product of lying, I think, but, more likely wishful thinking. A racial Rorschach test. It may have given Stanley – already a lonely man &#8212; some comfort to imagine Africans who shared his color, his features, perhaps his kinship, so far from home.</span></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3296/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3296/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3296&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://timetoeatthedogs.com/2013/01/21/rwenzori-journal/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/32ac32e7e113804d5b36acbe79508b95?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F0.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Michael</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://timetoeatthedogs.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_8125.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Bamwanjara Pass, 14,600 ft (4450 m), Rwenzori Mountains</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://timetoeatthedogs.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_7855.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Kilembe, Western Uganda. Gateway to the Rwenzoris.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://timetoeatthedogs.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_8088.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">William Kiminywa finds a path through the mud.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://timetoeatthedogs.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_8008.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Blue Monkeys, 12,000 ft.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://timetoeatthedogs.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_8143.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Summit of Mt. Stanley, border between Uganda and Congo, dividing point between the watersheds of the Congo and Nile Rivers.</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>To the Author of \&#8221;7 Reasons Jesus Was Gay\&#8221;</title>
		<link>http://tylerlehmann.wordpress.com/2013/01/17/to-the-author-of-7-reasons-jesus-was-gay/</link>
		<comments>http://tylerlehmann.wordpress.com/2013/01/17/to-the-author-of-7-reasons-jesus-was-gay/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2013 08:23:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Tyler Lehmann</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christianity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gender stereotyping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[homophobia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[homosexuality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jesus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lgbt]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tylerlehmann.wordpress.com/?p=315</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;m a big fan of Thought Catalog, so naturally I came across your post “7 Reasons Jesus Was Gay”. After reading this piece, I&#8217;d like to tell you that as a gay Christian myself, I am extremely disappointed that you would choose to make us a laughingstock by posting this kind of material. Every day, LGBT [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=315&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://tylerlehmann.wordpress.com/2013/01/17/to-the-author-of-7-reasons-jesus-was-gay/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/7bb0fd827cf8733ff00042ac0fb7d39a?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F1.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tylerlehmann</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tylerlehmann.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/gay-jesus.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gay jesus</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>An Amateur Blogger&#8217;s Tips For Creating A Better-Than-Amateur Blog</title>
		<link>http://sitdownatatypewriterandbleed.wordpress.com/2013/01/19/an-amateur-bloggers-tips-for-creating-a-better-than-amateur-blog/</link>
		<comments>http://sitdownatatypewriterandbleed.wordpress.com/2013/01/19/an-amateur-bloggers-tips-for-creating-a-better-than-amateur-blog/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2013 18:14:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>janinerussell</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Musings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://sitdownatatypewriterandbleed.wordpress.com/?p=543</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[When I surpassed 50 followers, I wrote a post thanking all my readers for listening, and got a lot of feedback. I got asked how I created a blog that 50 people thought was worth reading in just 2 months, so I decided to make this post. (Not that I think my blog is super [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=543&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When I surpassed 50 followers, I wrote a post thanking all my readers for listening, and got a lot of feedback. I got asked how I created a blog that 50 people thought was worth reading in just 2 months, so I decided to make this post. (Not that I think my blog is super great or anything. Cause I don&#8217;t. I just try to make something that I would want to read.) So here are some ideas that might help take your blog to the next level.</p>
<p>Actually, I liked that thing I just said. Let&#8217;s make that #1.</p>
<p><strong>1. Make a blog you would want to read.</strong></p>
<p>This is your space. You have freedom to make it something that is 100% uniquely you. So don&#8217;t be afraid to change things that aren&#8217;t working for you to make it better. I&#8217;ve redone my &#8220;About Me&#8221; page, which should be quite simple, about 10 times. And I will continue to do so until I&#8217;m happy with it. This step will also help you figure out who you are writing for. Knowing your audience will help you write posts that those people will find interesting.</p>
<p><strong>2. Feel what you write. </strong></p>
<p>When I&#8217;m creating a post, it usually takes no more than a few minutes to fully formulate it (and maybe you can tell? I hope not.). That&#8217;s because I write about things that are important to me, or that I&#8217;m passionate about, and it all flows out very naturally. <span style="font-size:13px;line-height:19px;">Don&#8217;t be afraid to infuse your personality into your style of writing, either. </span><span style="font-size:13px;line-height:19px;">This isn&#8217;t a grade 9 essay. If you&#8217;re trying to struggle through a post, why are you writing about that topic in particular? Is there something else that really spikes your interest instead? </span></p>
<p><strong>3. What are you trying to accomplish here?</strong></p>
<p>Come up with an overall theme. It doesn&#8217;t have to be too specific. If you are just writing about whatever comes to mind, and sometimes it&#8217;s really dull, your readers will be able to tell. Even a very general idea, like &#8220;travelling&#8221; or &#8220;food&#8221; or &#8220;parenting&#8221; will make your blog flow better and keep you focused.  And you don&#8217;t want your blog to seem bipolar or schizophrenic in its content. (Metaphorically, of course. I mean don&#8217;t try to do everything at once. You might have two very clear themes, which would make two awesome blogs. Putting them together, though, might make your blog seem confusing and overly broad. A blog about schizophrenia would probably be really cool.)</p>
<div class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 250px"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/35237096343@N01/675520667" target="_blank"><img class="zemanta-img-inserted zemanta-img-configured" title="Writer's Block" alt="Writer's Block" src="http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1119/675520667_7572f0614c_m.jpg" width="240" height="160" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Writer&#8217;s Block (Photo credit: thorinside)</p></div>
<p><strong>4. Look around for inspiration.</strong></p>
<p>There are so many awesome blogs out there! Check some of them out! And don&#8217;t be afraid to like things and leave comments. It&#8217;s an easy way to possibly bring traffic into your site as well from people with similar interests. Notice how people are using titles, pictures, videos, menus, categories, etc. and how those things make the blog unique or easy to navigate.</p>
<p><strong>5. Watch your tone.</strong></p>
<p>I was reading one blog where the person was just bitching about things. And as good as it feels to get that stuff off your chest every once in a while, it isn&#8217;t too pleasant to read. Reading hate just spikes my blood pressure and gets me all worked up. I do that enough on my own, thanks. So think about how you want your work to come across, and speak accordingly. Swearing too much is also a no-no because it makes you sound rude and uneducated. (But like all rules, there is a time and a place for swearing, depending on what you blog about. If I see a cookie recipe riddled with curse words, I will flip a table.) AND TRY NOT TO YELL. IT IS ALSO VERY UNPLEASANT.</p>
<p><strong>6. Not everything you write will be a goldmine.</strong></p>
<p>I have done a lot of posts where no one liked it, and that whole day just became a big crevice in my stats report. That&#8217;s good, though, because now I know what people don&#8217;t care to read about, or maybe it was the style of writing that pushed people away. Making mistakes is a good thing because it gives you feedback you can learn from. Even the best writers write terrible things sometimes.</p>
<p><strong>7. Post often.</strong></p>
<p>I follow a lot of blogs, but some of them only get updated once a month or so. And now I&#8217;m questioning why I&#8217;m following them since they never say anything. Also, after a few hours your posts get pushed down the list and replaced by newer ones, so posting often increases your chances of bringing in new readers. You don&#8217;t need to post every day, but if you can make some sort of schedule where you&#8217;re posting at least once per week, your readers will hang on to hear what you have to say next.</p>
<p><strong>8. Tag smartly.</strong></p>
<p>I was definitely guilty of not doing this when I first started. Tags are a good thing to help people who would be interested in your blog discover it. Think about what you might search for, though, and use only those tags. For example, if last Wednesday your dog got sick and you had to take it to the hospital, don&#8217;t take it &#8220;Wednesday, dog, sick, hospital&#8221;, but instead using things like &#8220;dog lovers, family&#8221; etc. No one is looking for posts about Wednesdays.</p>
<p><strong>9. Don&#8217;t be afraid to say what you mean.</strong></p>
<p>Some of the best posts I&#8217;ve read are about things that people are hesitant to talk about. A little bit of controversy can be a good thing if you&#8217;re able to do it respectfully and not attacking people who have conflicting views. It will keep your blog interesting, and make people want to hear what you have to say next. Don&#8217;t be afraid to shake things up once in a while.</p>
<p><strong>10. This is not a diary.</strong></p>
<div class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 250px"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/49503155381@N01/2475835909" target="_blank"><img class="zemanta-img-inserted zemanta-img-configured" title="Dear Diary" alt="Dear Diary" src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2185/2475835909_1caef515d2_m.jpg" width="240" height="161" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Dear Diary (Photo credit: incurable_hippie)</p></div>
<p>Well, actually some might be, but those are the exception. You don&#8217;t need to give all the details of everything you&#8217;ve ever done, especially not the boring ones. Whenever I&#8217;m writing something, I ask myself if I would care about what I&#8217;m reading. And a lot of the time I scrap it because no one cares. But that&#8217;s a risk you take when you go off on tangents. Which is why you should edit things. A few hours later your post will sound very different to you than it did the second you were writing it. Which is why I wrote this post yesterday, and published it today.</p>
<p>Hope some of this helps! WordPress has a help page with lots of neat tips as well, so for more inspiration I recommend going there next.</p>
<p>Rock on.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/543/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/543/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/543/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/543/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/543/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/543/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/543/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/543/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/543/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/543/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/543/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/543/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/543/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/543/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=543&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://sitdownatatypewriterandbleed.wordpress.com/2013/01/19/an-amateur-bloggers-tips-for-creating-a-better-than-amateur-blog/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>40</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/4890b4a122979f869857b25a4daeba07?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F1.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">janinerussell</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm2.static.flickr.com/1119/675520667_7572f0614c_m.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Writer&#039;s Block</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2185/2475835909_1caef515d2_m.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Dear Diary</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Yuanfen or Destiny Without Fate</title>
		<link>http://unamericanclassic.wordpress.com/2013/01/17/yuanfen/</link>
		<comments>http://unamericanclassic.wordpress.com/2013/01/17/yuanfen/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2013 06:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jake Smith</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[death]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[old age]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[story]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://unamericanclassic.wordpress.com/?p=18</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;I love you,&#8221; he said. &#8220;You&#8217;ll understand it one day.&#8221; She laughed. She didn&#8217;t know what to say. It wasn&#8217;t as clear to her as it was to him. She could never understand how some people seemed so sure of matters of the heart. He knew, though. He knew that even though they were to [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=18&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;I love you,&#8221; he said. &#8220;You&#8217;ll understand it one day.&#8221;</p>
<p>She laughed. She didn&#8217;t know what to say. It wasn&#8217;t as clear to her as it was to him. She could never understand how some people seemed so sure of matters of the heart.</p>
<p>He knew, though. He knew that even though they were to part ways soon, he would return to her, the pillar of strength. He would return, battle-scarred and broken, and she would nurse him back to life. She would stand over him and stare, her hand resting on his thumping chest and worry resting on her troubled brow. He would look up at her with dry, parched lips and she would raise a mason jar of smoke, hope, and poetry to his mouth. He would drink deeply, and as his head fell to the pillow, he would see the road behind him and the smoldering ruins in the distance. He would be assured that he was home, that his oasis had been with her, his muse, the whole time. Just as he thought, those many years ago when he thought those many years ago.</p>
<p>He was wrong about one thing, however. She never did understand. She was always a tad unsure that it would last. Until their hair turned gray and their eyes turned pale, she had her doubts.</p>
<p><em>© Jacob A. Smith and An Un-American Classic 2013.</em></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/18/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/18/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=18&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://unamericanclassic.wordpress.com/2013/01/17/yuanfen/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>15</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/35b9231539e456af4d58aaa65ef2e3ac?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">unamericanclassic</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bring On the Beauty</title>
		<link>http://rachelrhenry.wordpress.com/2013/01/15/bring-on-the-beauty/</link>
		<comments>http://rachelrhenry.wordpress.com/2013/01/15/bring-on-the-beauty/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2013 06:45:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Rachel Henry</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[appreciation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beauty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[musings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rachelrhenry.wordpress.com/?p=593</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I just received in the mail my first in a long time ridiculously expensive relative to my income bracket purchase, perhaps the first ever that is not a bicycle. It’s way too nerdy and grown up of an item for such an event, but I’ve been staring at my new “upcycled wooden desk trays,” vintage [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=593&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I just received in the mail my first in a long time ridiculously expensive relative to my income bracket purchase, perhaps the first ever that is not a bicycle. It’s way too nerdy and grown up of an item for such an event, but I’ve been staring at my new “upcycled wooden desk trays,” vintage distressed French country style, and feeling really happy ever since I opened the package. Perhaps nothing I’ve bought in my life has come with so many adjectives attached.</p>
<div class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 245px"><img class=" wp-image " id="i-594" alt="wooden desk trays labeled &quot;in&quot; and &quot;out&quot; with scrabble tiles" src="http://rachelrhenry.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/desk_trays_big.jpg?w=235&#038;h=176" width="235" height="176" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Upcycled wooden desk trays from <a href="http://www.etsy.com/shop/VintageChichibean">Vintage Chichibean</a> on <a href="http://www.etsy.com/">Etsy</a></p></div>
<p>Let me express my appreciation for the word “upcycled.” I am generally not a fan of creating words unless you can do it as well as Roald Dahl, but upcycled is a brilliant marketing word, appealing to people’s vanity and environmental consciousness all at once.</p>
<p>I admire not only the description but also the physical presence of my desk trays. I like the size and shape of them, the heft, the way they’re cleverly slotted together. I like the unevenness of the paint and the yellow-green color that is more attractive than yellow-green has any business being.</p>
<p>The way buying new stuff can make us happy used to worry me. I have a complicated relationship with the physical, which I suspect I share with many Americans. On one hand, we are deluged with marketing telling us that our appearance matters more than anything else, and on the other, we hold onto our Puritan forebearers’ attitude that physical things are not particularly worthy or holy and possibly downright sinful.</p>
<p>But we are physical beings, and we are drawn to and enlivened by beauty of various types, many of which we experience through our senses. Few would argue that a painting by Rembrandt or Monet is shallow because its beauty is physical.</p>
<p>I’m not saying I’m going to sprinkle holy water on my desk trays (that would be blessed vintage distressed French country style), but I welcome them both for the enjoyment they’re already bringing me and for the reminder that beauty comes in many forms, and we need them all.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/593/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/593/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=593&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://rachelrhenry.wordpress.com/2013/01/15/bring-on-the-beauty/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>15</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/76d880c3058da7bdde6e572785887774?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">rachelrhenry</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://rachelrhenry.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/desk_trays_big.jpg?w=560" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">wooden desk trays labeled &#34;in&#34; and &#34;out&#34; with scrabble tiles</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is a Traffic Jam a Tribe?</title>
		<link>http://wearenotconnected.wordpress.com/2013/01/16/is-a-traffic-jam-a-tribe/</link>
		<comments>http://wearenotconnected.wordpress.com/2013/01/16/is-a-traffic-jam-a-tribe/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2013 14:28:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Mark</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CONNECTION]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[communitas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commute]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[people]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[psychology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[religion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ritual]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[road rage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[traffic]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://wearenotconnected.wordpress.com/?p=305</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[For many the commute to and from work is a daily ritual. I don&#8217;t just mean this in the slang &#8216;repetitive waste of time&#8217; sense of the word either. It&#8217;s also true in a very primordial, tribal sense. Think of it like this: driving to work is like going on a mammoth hunt. It&#8217;s you [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=305&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://wearenotconnected.wordpress.com/2013/01/16/is-a-traffic-jam-a-tribe/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>40</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/794d3e3d7f6b4a71af58c72c3c0ae917?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mstarmach</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://wearenotconnected.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/tribaltrafficjam.png?w=640" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Is a traffic jam a tribe?</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://wearenotconnected.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ritualprocess.png?w=640" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The Ritual Process</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://wearenotconnected.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/feedback.png?w=640" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Feedback loop</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://wearenotconnected.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/highwaylove.png?w=640" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Makin&#039; love on the free-love freeway</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>My Friend Dramane is Volunteering for the War</title>
		<link>http://aricvisser.wordpress.com/2013/01/21/my-friend-dramane-is-volunteering-for-the-war/</link>
		<comments>http://aricvisser.wordpress.com/2013/01/21/my-friend-dramane-is-volunteering-for-the-war/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2013 17:07:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>aricvisser</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[English]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mali]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[war]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://aricvisser.wordpress.com/?p=109</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This is a story about a man named Dramane – a story that has a beginning but no end – at least I don’t know how it is going to end…so let’s start at the beginning. Dramane was my first friend that I made after my family arrived in Spain. In the second week of [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=109&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://aricvisser.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/dramane.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image" id="i-110" alt="Image" src="http://aricvisser.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/dramane.jpg?w=710" /></a></p>
<p>This is a story about a man named Dramane – a story that has a beginning but no end – at least I don’t know how it is going to end…so let’s start at the beginning.</p>
<p>Dramane was my first friend that I made after my family arrived in Spain. In the second week of September the sun still screams at anyone who dares venture outside in Zaragoza, but the calendar calls all the kids to school anyway, so I took my daughter’s hand and walked her through the park and into the schoolyard of what would be her first real school.  I forced a big smile and said encouraging things, but my daughter just stared back at me with a look of “But dad, you never taught me any Spanish” on her face.  I gave her a hug, and took a big breath and swallowed hard as she walked in with her new classmates who would spend the next few months talking at her with no response.  When all the children were inside, the parents began filing out, chatting and catching up on news and gossip from the summer.  I just stood there for a moment and then started for the door, where I would see Dramane for the first time.  He wasn’t chatting and catching up.  He was just standing in the back and smiling, then darted out &#8211; satisfied grin in tow.</p>
<p>For a few days each morning was identical.  My daughter was brave and Dramane stood in the back and smiled after seeing his twin boys hop up the steps into the school. But then after about a week, Dramane came over, shook my hand and simply said “Hi.  I’m Dramane.”  I told him my name and stood there looking at his smile.  I don’t know that I had ever seen anyone smile that much.  As Americans, we often get made fun of for smiling all the time in public, which is fine, because it is absolutely true, but on that morning, and for mornings to come, Dramane made me look practically miserable in comparison.</p>
<p>For the next two weeks it was always the same, a firm hand shake, a “how are you” and an enormous smile.  We became friends, at least I considered him my friend, and I hoped he thought the same of me.  We told each other about our home towns &#8211; mine in the United States, his in Mali &#8211; and we talked about the school.  We shared our “immigrant experiences,” and I ridiculously imagined that we had so much in common.</p>
<p>One morning he took me for coffee and showed me his business – one of those storefronts where you can get on the internet, make copies, use a phone or send a moneygram to a loved one back home.  He ran the place with his brother.  That day he told me more about his family. He told me about his wife and how the paperwork to get her to Spain was impossible.  He told me that he had a two-year-old son, also in Mali. He told me about driving back and forth to bring his family things, describing a car trip that would make a coast-to-coast U.S. road trip look like a lap around the block.</p>
<p>I never went to his shop again, but we always shook hands and said hello without fail.  I found what I thought was a link between us, an immigrant experience that we shared, and knew that no one else in the schoolyard quite understood us.  We were different, and although eventually I started talking to the Spanish parents, Dramane never did.  He just stood in the back and smiled like he always did.</p>
<p>&#8212;&#8211;</p>
<p>Now the weather has turned colder and the schoolyard chats have been shorter.  Up until this week I hadn’t seen Dramane in a while and wondered where he had gone.  I no longer think that we share a common immigrant experience, and realize that it was a fantasy to think that we ever did, and never did that become more clear than when I saw Dramane last Friday and shook his hand for the first time in a while.</p>
<p>“Hey Dramane, how are you?”</p>
<p>“Aric, I’m good, How are you.”</p>
<p>“Good.  I’m good.  Hey what ever happened with your wife’s papers?”</p>
<p>“Oh, she is here now.  I don’t know, maybe you have seen her?”</p>
<p>“Wow! Great news. And your son?”</p>
<p>“We had to leave him in Mali.  His papers did not go through.”</p>
<p>“I’m so sorry.”</p>
<p>“It’s o.k.  I am leaving soon anyway.”</p>
<p>“Where are you going?”</p>
<p>“I’m going to Mali.  I am volunteering to fight in the war.”</p>
<p>“You’re doing what?”</p>
<p>“I’m going to fight.  They are taking volunteers.”</p>
<p>“Why would you do that?”</p>
<p>“Aric, you need to understand, this is no way to live.  I can’t stay here, and I can’t just go back and live in the sand.  What am I going to do, live in a village in the middle of the desert?  I can’t do this anymore, so I will go home and fight.”</p>
<p>I didn’t know what to say.  I just stood there looking for words and Dramane just stood there smiling and shaking my hand.  He probably noticed that I didn’t know what to say, so he just said, “ I will be fine.  It’s no big deal.”</p>
<p>But of course it is a big deal, but all I could come up with at that moment was “good luck.  I really don’t want this to be the last time I see you.  Be careful.”</p>
<p>He assured me that he would, turned and walked away…</p>
<p>I walked home thinking about Dramane.  He was going to fight, and I didn’t even know what side he was on, hell, I didn’t even know what the sides were.  I went home and looked it up.  It’s complicated.  Why does it always have to be so complicated in West Africa?  It’s about religion, or not, because it is really about cultural differences from hundreds of years ago, or not.  It’s about al-Qaida.  It’s about money. It is about oil.  It is about colonialism.  It is about the French.  It is about poverty.  It always seems to be about poverty.  It’s about the Tuareg, a nomadic North African people who impossibly have a Volkswagen named after them.  Do we name cars after ethnic groups?  Is that actually something that we, as privileged westerners get to do? You can read for yourself what it is about <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-17582909" target="_blank">here</a>. It is about all of those things and none of those things, but whatever it is, it is enough to make Dramane want to fight, and perhaps kill other human beings.</p>
<p>There is no moral to this story without an end. Only that we live in a big world, where sometimes people leave to go fight, and when that happens, the lucky ones stay home. I don’t know what Dramane believes in, or if he will actually take up arms against his countrymen, but if he does, I hope that he is safe.  I will think of him when he is gone, and perhaps while he is away I will embrace my big fat American smile and start shaking some more hands.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/109/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/109/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=109&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://aricvisser.wordpress.com/2013/01/21/my-friend-dramane-is-volunteering-for-the-war/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f58887bb5a07ce6b68f65774a0fc4f3a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">aricvisser</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://aricvisser.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/dramane.jpg?w=710" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Paris: The City of White</title>
		<link>http://afrenchfryeinparis.wordpress.com/2013/01/21/the-city-of-white/</link>
		<comments>http://afrenchfryeinparis.wordpress.com/2013/01/21/the-city-of-white/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2013 14:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>A French Frye in Paris</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Montmartre]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Paris]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sacre coeur]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[snow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[winter]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://afrenchfryeinparis.wordpress.com/?p=1726416220</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[How do you enjoy snow in Paris? You go out in search of hills, of course! And there&#8217;s probably no better place to find them than what used to be a sparse, windmill-dotted countryside outside the city limits: Montmartre. There was a sense of event in the city this weekend as Paris got hit with [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1726416220&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>How do you enjoy snow in Paris? You go out in search of hills, of course!</p>
<p><a href="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0480a1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1726416288" alt="IMG_0480a" src="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0480a1.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>And there&#8217;s probably no better place to find them than what used to be a sparse, windmill-dotted countryside outside the city limits: Montmartre.</p>
<p>There was a sense of event in the city this weekend as Paris got hit with the most snow it&#8217;s seen in 24 years, and not wanting to miss out on the spectacle I abandoned the promise of a cozy peaceful Sunday at home and schlepped a camera and many layers of clothing into the great white tundra. I expected the picturesque streets; what I didn&#8217;t expect was to see so many Parisians, who are normally reserved and measured, giving into pure unadulterated playfulness.</p>
<p><a href="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0488a.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-1726416226" alt="IMG_0488a" src="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0488a.jpg?w=490&#038;h=326" width="490" height="326" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0506a.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-1726416227" alt="IMG_0506a" src="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0506a.jpg?w=490&#038;h=326" width="490" height="326" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0508a.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-1726416228" alt="IMG_0508a" src="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0508a.jpg?w=490&#038;h=326" width="490" height="326" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0527a.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-1726416229" alt="IMG_0527a" src="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0527a.jpg?w=490&#038;h=326" width="490" height="326" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0556a.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-1726416224" alt="IMG_0556a" src="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0556a.jpg?w=490&#038;h=326" width="490" height="326" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0555a.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1726416223" alt="IMG_0555a" src="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0555a.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>And where there&#8217;s no hill, you make do:</p>
<p><a href="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0536a.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1726416237" alt="IMG_0536a" src="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0536a.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>The area buzzed with a sense of village community and camaraderie, and the weather only strengthened the feeling of rural and rustic that Montmartre does so well.  It made you forget you were in a city at all, and with snow like this being so rare here, around every corner was a reminder that you were witness to a fleeting version of Paris, one to be revered and locked into the memory banks.</p>
<p><a href="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0499a1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1726416244" alt="IMG_0499a" src="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0499a1.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0599a.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1726416241" alt="IMG_0599a" src="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0599a.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0549a.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1726416239" alt="IMG_0549a" src="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0549a.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0582a.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1726416240" alt="IMG_0582a" src="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0582a.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>And for every charming landscape there were an equal number of quiet details to complete the wintry scene:</p>
<p><a href="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0493a.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1726416249" alt="IMG_0493a" src="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0493a.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0496a.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1726416250" alt="IMG_0496a" src="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0496a.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0563a.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1726416252" alt="IMG_0563a" src="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0563a.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0637a.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1726416247" alt="IMG_0637a" src="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0637a.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0501a.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1726416251" alt="IMG_0501a" src="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0501a.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0598a.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1726416254" alt="IMG_0598a" src="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0598a.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0609a.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1726416255" alt="IMG_0609a" src="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0609a.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0620a.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1726416246" alt="IMG_0620a" src="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0620a.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0584a.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1726416253" alt="IMG_0584a" src="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0584a.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>One detail I was happy to have at hand were the metal pylons along most streets, which had always seemed to serve a dual purpose &#8212; to prevent sidewalk parking and to protect pedestrians &#8212; but which now assumed an indispensable third function as an aide to hoist myself up some of the more slippery slants:</p>
<p><a href="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0580a.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1726416259" alt="IMG_0580a" src="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0580a.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>The usually bustling <em>Place du Tertre</em> was subdued and still, with only the most dedicated (or broke?) of outdoor painters braving the elements for the occasional commissioned portrait:</p>
<p><a href="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0615a.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1726416260" alt="IMG_0615a" src="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0615a.jpg?w=720"   /></a><br />
And of course you can&#8217;t leave the area without acknowledging the big white elephant in the room, which had received an extra shade of white to its already milky exterior:</p>
<p><a href="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0643a.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1726416242" alt="IMG_0643a" src="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0643a.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0650a.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1726416262" alt="IMG_0650a" src="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0650a.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>As its gargoyles displayed just how freaking cold it was, regardless of how much hellfire you happen to have been born out of:</p>
<p><a href="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0662a.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1726416266" alt="IMG_0662a" src="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0662a.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0656a.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1726416264" alt="IMG_0656a" src="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0656a.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0658a.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1726416265" alt="IMG_0658a" src="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0658a.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>And then the winter&#8217;s afternoon slipped away from Montmartre, the sun and temperature coasting down the snowy hills into night, and locals and visitors alike admired an elevated view of the city akin to that of a tray of warm <i>pâtisseries</i> lined up in a bakery window, freshly dusted with a coat of powdered sugar for the pleasure and delight of all who pass by.</p>
<p><a href="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0668a1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1726416275" alt="IMG_0668a" src="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0668a1.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0722a.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1726416256" alt="IMG_0722a" src="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0722a.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p><em>(Stay tuned for a second series of snowy shots from other parts of the city, coming soon!)</em></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1726416220/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1726416220/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1726416220&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://afrenchfryeinparis.wordpress.com/2013/01/21/the-city-of-white/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>121</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a224468dd28be814cb41db01d0c5c718?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">elke12</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0480a1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0480a</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0488a.jpg?w=490" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0488a</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0506a.jpg?w=490" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0506a</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0508a.jpg?w=490" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0508a</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0527a.jpg?w=490" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0527a</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0556a.jpg?w=490" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0556a</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0555a.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0555a</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0536a.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0536a</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0499a1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0499a</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0599a.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0599a</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0549a.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0549a</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0582a.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0582a</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0493a.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0493a</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0496a.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0496a</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0563a.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0563a</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0637a.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0637a</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0501a.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0501a</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0598a.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0598a</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0609a.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0609a</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0620a.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0620a</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0584a.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0584a</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0580a.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0580a</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0615a.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0615a</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0643a.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0643a</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0650a.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0650a</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0662a.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0662a</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0656a.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0656a</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0658a.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0658a</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0668a1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0668a</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://afrenchfryeinparis.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0722a.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0722a</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Year in Reading</title>
		<link>http://10mh.net/2013/01/20/a_year_in_reading/</link>
		<comments>http://10mh.net/2013/01/20/a_year_in_reading/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2013 16:10:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Joanne Greenway</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[The Golden Country]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book review]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Doris Lessing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ebooks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[goodreads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Haruki Murakami]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ian Fleming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Iris Murdoch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Our Man in Abiko]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sean Lotman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wu Ming]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://10mh.net/?p=2781</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It seems that &#8216;inspired by&#8217; is the term to use when one is shamelessly borrowing another&#8217;s good idea. With that in mind, this post is inspired by/pinched from Sean Lotman&#8217;s wonderful post of the same name. You are encouraged to take a look at the original as well as this weak derivative. An earlier post [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2781&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://10mh.net/2013/01/20/a_year_in_reading/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>53</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/ab457c4d537ccfb4f453454c7655b3c6?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Julia Smith</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://10mh.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/me-reading.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Engrossed in a book, Singapore, Christmas 2010</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
