<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 21:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>On Never Moving On</title>
		<link>http://j-bo.net/2013/01/27/on-never-moving-on/</link>
		<comments>http://j-bo.net/2013/01/27/on-never-moving-on/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2013 20:12:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>J-Bo</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adventure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anxiety]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[attachment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[experience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[friendship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grief]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[insecurity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[loss]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nostalgia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[phases]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reflection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vacation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wisdom]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://j-bo.net/?p=806</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I look out my window at hundreds of tiny cars as my plane descends into Denver. There are so many people in the world. I get predictably overwhelmed by this thought whenever I am at a baseball stadium, a concert, or looking down at a city from the sky. There are millions and billions of [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=806&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I look out my window at hundreds of tiny cars as my plane descends into Denver. <i>There are so many people in the world</i>. I get predictably overwhelmed by this thought whenever I am at a baseball stadium, a concert, or looking down at a city from the sky.</p>
<p>There are millions and billions of people, <i>everywhere</i>. I share personal histories with a few of them because we happened to be at the same place at the same time for one fleeting, overlapping moment in our lives. And yet somehow these histories with these people are unshakeable. Somehow they still matter, years later. They are still worth traveling great distances for.</p>
<p>Over the course of the weekend I will spend time with three different people from three different phases of my life: Anahitta from middle school, Scott from study abroad, and John from grad school. All three have, at one point, been my closest friend.</p>
<p>So it’s strange that anxiety and dread have outweighed my excitement leading up to this trip. I left work early yesterday with a crippling stomachache. I went to bed with a fever over one hundred. I had already made myself sick with my longing for what I feared might not still be there.</p>
<p>My curse has always been caring too much. I am nostalgic to a fault. I never get over anything. It has brought deep satisfaction to my relationships and rich color to my life, but it has also made me a selfish friend. My biggest fear is always that the people I love will move on into happy new lives without me. I haven’t always taken the natural ebbs and flows of relationships with grace.</p>
<p>I am so afraid of being the one who is left hanging on tighter. Of being rejected by those who once loved me. I don’t know where this fear comes from, but it is what caused me to hesitate in reaching out to these friends in the first place. It is why, with two of them, (the two who already live in Colorado), I suggested only that we meet for lunch.</p>
<p>Just for lunch. Because to ask for more than that would be to risk being a burden, or that they might say no. I understand, on some level, that this is illogical. These are people I used to do <i>everything </i>with. Scott and I traveled a continent together. John and I basically lived at each other’s apartments and at IHOP whenever we weren’t sleeping or in class.</p>
<p>But what if they no longer remember all those times and jokes and moments that transpired between us? What if they’ve moved on?</p>
<p>I am exhausted when Anahitta and I find each other at the airport. It is past midnight, but it is an amazing sixty degrees outside as we sit in our rental car trying to figure out how to start the damn thing. It’s a red Mini Cooper with white racing stripes. Not what we requested. The key isn’t really a key. How the hell do you start this piece of crap? It’s so late. We laugh until we can’t breathe. We always laugh until we can’t breathe. She is the only person who has ever been able to make me laugh like this. She moved away when we were sixteen.</p>
<p><a href="http://jbodotnet.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/anahitta.jpeg"><img class="size-full wp-image" id="i-807" alt="Image" src="http://jbodotnet.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/anahitta.jpeg?w=514" /></a><i>^Anahitta and me in 2005, at the St. Louis airport the night a big storm caused all the power to go out. All the employees abandoned their posts. It was pure chaos. Of course we had to take advantage of this opportunity to photograph ourselves in all the normally-forbidden airport areas, such as the conveyer belt.</i></p>
<p>At the hotel, Anahitta and I reminisce about 7<sup>th</sup> grade and all those afternoons at Leah’s house spent waiting for <i>Bye Bye Bye </i>to come on TRL. We may have different ethnicities, skin colors, and religions, but we will both always know exactly what it was like to be thirteen in America in the year 2000. So we remember <i>precisely</i> how important <i>Bye Bye Bye </i>was. Is.</p>
<p>We pull up all the classic music videos on YouTube. Britney Spears, Destiny’s Child, O-Town. And we dance.</p>
<p>The next afternoon, Scott saves us from the ghetto in which I booked our hotel (oops) and shows us the real city. He is not buying this “meet for lunch” thing. He wants to see me, he wants to spend time, he insists. This makes me so happy.</p>
<p>Scott and I share a million memories about Australia over dinner the first night, memories of travel and friendship and adventures gone wrong that I suddenly realize I have been suppressing <i>because they were so good</i>. Because there was no tangible way to take them home with me without feeling alienated from everyone and everything in my other life. Things I was afraid to remember because I was afraid he’d forget and I didn’t want to be the only one left with the memory. But he remembers things I don’t even remember. Like how mad he got the day I hitchhiked down the mountain.</p>
<p><a href="http://jbodotnet.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/scott5.jpeg"><img class=" wp-image" id="i-809" alt="Image" src="http://jbodotnet.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/scott5.jpeg?w=310&#038;h=414" width="310" height="414" /></a></p>
<p><i>^Scott and me in my Australia dorm room in 2007. These are the types of things you routinely find yourself doing when you have a limited internet quota.</i></p>
<p>“I was so depressed when I came home from Australia,” I admit to Scott after the waitress sets down our bison burgers. Then I lean in and add, hopefully, “Did you get depressed too?”</p>
<p>“Of course I did,” he says, no hesitation. “I knew it would be a long time until we’d all get to be together again. We still haven’t been.”</p>
<p>He tells me that when he thinks about pure happiness and perfection, he thinks about Australia. He still keeps the photographs over his bed. I am so relieved he has felt the way I have, all this time. I make a mental note to put my photographs back up.</p>
<p>Later, Anahitta and I help Scott attempt a handstand on our hotel bed at the exact time of night his goofy side (his &#8220;little boy mode,&#8221; I used to call it) would always come out in Australia. I am amazed at how someone I knew for five months five years ago can still feel so familiar to me.</p>
<p>He spends most of the weekend with us.</p>
<p><a href="http://jbodotnet.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/photobooth.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image" id="i-814" alt="Image" src="http://jbodotnet.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/photobooth.jpg?w=674" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://jbodotnet.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0054-1.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image" id="i-817" alt="Image" src="http://jbodotnet.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0054-1.jpg?w=710" /></a></p>
<p>On Sunday, Anahitta and I have lunch with John. John and I share so many good memories from grad school that I’m sure Anahitta must be bored out of her mind. But there are just so many. And they simply <i>must</i> be shared. My God we pulled a lot of pranks.</p>
<p><a href="http://jbodotnet.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/john2.jpeg"><img class=" wp-image" id="i-819" alt="Image" src="http://jbodotnet.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/john2.jpeg?w=392&#038;h=377" width="392" height="377" /></a></p>
<p><em>^John and me the day we helped orchestrate the great Brown Bag Prank of 2010, in which our whole cohort showed up to our department’s “brown bag meeting” dressed in costumes made entirely out of brown bags.</em></p>
<p>John is also up for more than lunch. He takes us through downtown Boulder. We go into a bookstore and, within minutes, John and I are sequestered at the corner of a book display, our eyes lit up, speaking rapidly about every thought we’ve had since we last spoke.</p>
<p>I think maybe the biggest thing John has done for me is given me permission to give voice to all my deepest, weirdest thoughts. He understands exactly what I mean when I say things like I get a perverse satisfaction from spending time with people I don’t like, or that being a therapist makes me feel disgusted with myself, or that I had an existential crisis buying a couch. And I know what he means when he says he has built secret rooms in his metaphorical house or that he is profoundly affected by the wind. At times the rest of the bookstore seems to grow silent. I don’t think anyone in the room, or the world, could possibly follow the pace and range of topics and darkness and lightness and humor and metaphors of this conversation. But to us, it makes perfect sense.</p>
<p>On Monday morning Anahitta and I return the red Mini Cooper with white racing stripes. We still hate this car.</p>
<p>I ask Anahitta what her favorite part of the weekend was as we ride the shuttle to our gates. She does not mention riding the gondola into the mountains. She says her favorite was the night we had dinner at the mall and bought sweaters. Because it felt like something we could do any day.</p>
<p>I can’t follow that answer. It’s the perfect answer.</p>
<p>Alone at my gate, I feel like I have been hit by a tidal wave. I have re-lived three major parts of my life in the past three days. It’s a lot to sort out.</p>
<p>These three friends have allowed me to be three past selves: the silly pre-teen whose successful day is one in which she has laughed until she can’t breathe, the easily-excitable twenty-year-old getting her first real taste of adventure, and the grad student trying to balance her hunger for knowledge and wisdom with her propensity for naïveté and pranks.</p>
<p>I think of two things as I board my plane.</p>
<p>First, I think of what my supervisor told me on the last day of grad school when I said I was sad to leave my friends. “Whenever I get to see the friends I went to school with,” she said, “I know that they still know me better than anyone.”</p>
<p>The other thing I think about is the line that has gone through my head whenever I have had to say my final goodbye to someone before one of us moves away. I always think, <i>I will never have a friend like that again. </i>I thought that ten years ago with Anahitta, five years ago with Scott, and two years ago with John. And a lot of times in between.</p>
<p>And now I know for sure that it’s true. It was true every time. It’s always true.</p>
<p>But now, for the first time, I understand that this is not a sad thing. It has never meant that I will spend the rest of my days mourning. It has meant that I have been opened up to new parts of life and myself. It means that I have been lucky.</p>
<p>It means that, out of all the millions and billions of people in the world below my airplane as it takes off into the sky, I get to call a few of them my friends. And that when I get to see them two years from now, five years from now, ten years from now, and fifty years from now—I will know that nothing has changed.</p>
<p>You can read more about my attachment anxiety <a href="http://j-bo.net/2012/06/12/on-moving/">here</a> and <a href="http://j-bo.net/2011/08/08/good-grief/">here</a>.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/806/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/806/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=806&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://j-bo.net/2013/01/27/on-never-moving-on/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>35</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/56731d841905e6ebd12d938faac012fb?s=96&#38;d=wavatar&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">juliaboriss</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jbodotnet.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/anahitta.jpeg?w=514" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jbodotnet.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/scott5.jpeg?w=443" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jbodotnet.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/photobooth.jpg?w=674" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jbodotnet.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0054-1.jpg?w=710" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jbodotnet.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/john2.jpeg?w=490" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>On the Second Anniversary: Censorship Concerns</title>
		<link>http://arablit.wordpress.com/2013/01/25/on-the-second-anniversary-censorship-concerns/</link>
		<comments>http://arablit.wordpress.com/2013/01/25/on-the-second-anniversary-censorship-concerns/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2013 03:28:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>mlynxqualey</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[censorship]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://arablit.wordpress.com/?p=13289</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[At a recent news conference, the Egyptian Initiative for Personal Rights noted that, two years after January 25, many abuses of state power continue. Censorship is among these abuses: Attacks on journalists have been growing (see: Index on Censorship, AFP, others). Lawsuits against journalists, creatives, and commentators for &#8220;insulting the president&#8221; have reached, according to the Arab [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=13289&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>At a recent news conference, the Egyptian Initiative for Personal Rights noted that, two years after January 25, <a href="http://eipr.org/en/pressrelease/2013/01/17/1595">many abuses of state power continue</a>.</em></p>
<p><a href="http://arablit.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/images1.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-13290" alt="images" src="http://arablit.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/images1.jpg?w=720"   /></a>Censorship is among these abuses: Attacks on journalists have been growing (see: <a href="http://www.indexoncensorship.org/2012/12/egypt-press-freedom-ashraf-khalil/">Index on Censorship</a>, <a href="http://www.google.com/hostednews/afp/article/ALeqM5jwkxFCiYmV98bxXo5yVRBKvYaToQ?docId=CNG.a63e78354ecead9d2d1929c90d0217e4.a81">AFP</a>, others). Lawsuits against journalists, creatives, and commentators for &#8220;insulting the president&#8221; have reached, according to the Arab Network for Human Rights Information, a &#8220;<a href="http://english.ahram.org.eg/NewsContent/1/64/62968/Egypt/Politics-/Insulting-president-lawsuits-reach-year-peak-under.aspx">112-year high</a>.&#8221; Even the English-language press, traditionally freer, is being squeezed: Apparently Hani Shukrallah, the editor of <em>Ahram Online,<a href="https://twitter.com/HaniShukrallah/status/292649107414204416"> </a></em><a href="https://twitter.com/HaniShukrallah/status/292649107414204416">is being pushed into early &#8220;retirement.&#8221;</a></p>
<p>(Presumably this was the reason for the &#8220;<a href="http://www.ikhwanweb.com/article.php?id=30599">lack of solidarity</a>&#8221; yesterday when there were threats directed at the Muslim Brotherhood&#8217;s paper.)</p>
<p>In other sectors, textbooks <a href="http://www.egyptindependent.com/news/education-ministry-faces-heat-after-deleting-unveiled-feminist-textbooks">have been altered</a>. <a href="http://english.alarabiya.net/articles/2013/01/24/262239.html">EgyptAir&#8217;s in-flight movies</a> are going under new scrutiny.</p>
<p>Certainly, all the problems in Egypt&#8217;s cultural sector cannot be laid at the doorstep of censorship, nor of the Muslim Brotherhood. Theater director Galal El-Sharkawy told <i>Al-Ahram </i>last December that Egyptian theater simply continues its downward spiral. &#8220;But this is due to the Mubarak regime; what we witness today is a continuity of ending the arts in Egypt.&#8221;</p>
<p>Still &#8212; despite the beauties of a number of visual-art projects that have sprung up in the last two years, and <a href="http://weekly.ahram.org.eg/News/1121/17/Revolution-on-the-shelf.aspx">the surge in revolution-themed narratives</a> &#8212; censorship, instability, and fear of censorship create a difficult environment for longer-form artistic developments.</p>
<p>Those who support censorship in Egypt also might be able to count on help from John Brennan, who has been nominated by the US President Barack Obama to run the CIA. Apparently, Brennan’s <a href="http://www.scribd.com/doc/121759580/John-Brennan-MA-these-at-UT-Austin" rel="nofollow">1980 graduate thesis at the University of Texas</a> argued for increased state censorship in his case study, Egypt.</p>
<p>Not everyone is pessimistic. Publisher Sherif Bakr, of Al Arabi Publishing and Distributing, looks forward to more books on more new subjects in 2013, more translations, new independent bookstores, and &#8220;more professionalism&#8221; in book production.  And in a recent interview with Mai Elwakil and Andeel at the <em>Egypt Independent, </em>pioneering political cartoonist Amro Selim remained steadfast:</p>
<p><em id="__mceDel"><span id="more-13289"></span></em></p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">We need to constantly push the boundaries whether they are set by society, the political regime or even a newspaper’s editors. If people equate your critique of a bearded political Islamist figure with atheism, then you must do it more, all the time, on purpose.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">This is ground that we are gaining. It is a battle with possible lawsuits and threats. But we must continue.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">We went through a lot to be able to draw the president every day. We won ground under Mubarak’s rule. At the beginning of Al-Dostour, I told them that we must shatter the god-like image of the ruler who we cannot draw.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">We started drawing him from the back, and bit-by-bit we turned him around, until making a cartoon of him became the norm. Then we drew his sons, Gamal and Alaa.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">We were very happy when these cartoons were published. Before that, if Mubarak were ever represented, it would be with Egypt holding him like her beloved son.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">We have come a long way in a society that asked us to “respect” the ruler. Now, they want us to go back.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">When you see people dying or losing their eyes and limbs, you find yourself addressing topics fiercely. When you hear about the virginity tests and find the authorities and public defending them, I feel we have to strike back with the same intensity, even if some will be offended. Society will not change unless you challenge it.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">As for editorial policies, they can be navigated through a mixture of negotiations and subtlety. I believe there is a communication channel between cartoonists and readers that even editors might miss. It is amusing to experiment with overcoming censorship.</p>
<p><strong>And poetry for the Second Anniversary, from Mostafa Ibrahim:</strong></p>
<p>Ibrahim&#8217;s collection of colloquial poetry, inspired by the first Jan 25 uprising, was recently published by BQFP.</p>
<span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='640' height='390' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/Pc_H4jENC9g?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/13289/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/13289/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=13289&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://arablit.wordpress.com/2013/01/25/on-the-second-anniversary-censorship-concerns/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/6d2ab4e5874adf3d0efba7ed5c7b5b25?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mlynxqualey</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://arablit.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/images1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">images</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Jane Austen’s “Darling Child” Meets the World</title>
		<link>http://sarahemsley.com/2013/01/28/jane-austens-darling-child-meets-the-world/</link>
		<comments>http://sarahemsley.com/2013/01/28/jane-austens-darling-child-meets-the-world/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2013 09:30:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sarah Emsley</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Jane Austen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[JASNA Nova Scotia Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pride and Prejudice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alex Clark]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bridget Jones's Diary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Celebrating Pride and Prejudice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[E.L. James]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fifty Shades of Grey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jane Austen's "darling Child"]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jane Austen's Letters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[JASNA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[JASNA Nova Scotia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[literature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pride and Prejudice 200th anniversary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pride and Prejudice and Zombies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stephanie Meyer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twilight]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://sarahemsley.com/?p=1349</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Jane Austen didn’t like the way her mother read Pride and Prejudice aloud. Mrs. Austen read too quickly, “—&#38; tho’ she perfectly understands the Characters herself, she cannot speak as they ought” (Letters, 4 February 1813). Jane writes to her sister Cassandra that she’s grateful for Cassandra’s praise of the novel because she has been [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1349&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Jane Austen didn’t like the way her mother read <i>Pride and Prejudice</i> aloud. Mrs. Austen read too quickly, “—&amp; tho’ she perfectly understands the Characters herself, she cannot speak as they ought” (<i>Letters</i>,<i> </i>4 February 1813). Jane writes to her sister Cassandra that she’s grateful for Cassandra’s praise of the novel because she has been having “some fits of disgust” recently. She is at home in Chawton without Cassandra, keeping the secret of her authorship from her neighbours and enduring the irritation of listening to her mother’s interpretation of her characters. She can’t control what other people do with the language of her characters, and she can’t control the errors in the printing: “The greatest blunder in the Printing that I have met with is in page 220—Vol. 3. where two speeches are made into one.” She’s just written one of the greatest books in English literature, and she must know she’s accomplished something very important, but the fact that the book is now out in the world being judged and interpreted by others is making her restless.</p>
<div id="attachment_1350" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 178px"><a href="http://sarahemsley.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0674.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-1350   " alt="At our JASNA NS meeting yesterday: one &quot;200th&quot; balloon, plus four that said &quot;50th Anniversary.&quot; Thanks, Anne and Carole." src="http://sarahemsley.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0674.jpg?w=168&#038;h=168" width="168" height="168" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">At our JASNA NS meeting yesterday: one &#8220;200th&#8221; balloon, plus four that said &#8220;50th Anniversary.&#8221; Thanks, Anne and Carole.</p></div>
<p>A few days before this letter, she wrote to Cassandra with the good news that “I have got my own darling Child from London”: <i>Pride and Prejudice </i>had just arrived in Chawton (<i>Letters</i>, 29 January 1813). Jane Austen’s “darling Child” has come to visit, and the way she uses this metaphor, I don’t think she means that the publication of her novel is its birth. When she talks about reading the proofs for <i>Sense and Sensibility</i>, her first published novel, two years earlier, she says, “I can no more forget it, than a mother can forget her sucking child” (<i>Letters</i>, 25 April 1811). If the proofs of the novel are already a nursing child, hungry for more from its creator, the birth of the novel must happen when the author completes the manuscript.</p>
<p>The publication, therefore, must be the mature (revised) child’s introduction to the world, and we could debate the age at which this happens. <i>Pride and Prejudice</i> was born long before January 28, 1813, the date on which it was published. (I’ve sometimes referred to its 200th birthday in 2013, but I ought to be careful to call today the 200th anniversary of the novel’s publication instead.) First conceived of as <i>First Impressions</i> in 1796, the story went through several developmental stages, about which Austen critics can and do speculate, yet we’ll never know exactly what happened as <i>First Impressions</i> was transformed into the novel that would become world famous as <i>Pride and Prejudice</i>. Like any mother, Jane Austen worried about her child at every stage of its development, and about how the life of that child would unfold.</p>
<p>In her letter, when she thanks Cassandra for her praise, Jane acknowledges that despite being bothered by the way their mother read the book aloud, “Upon the whole however</p>
<div id="attachment_1353" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 250px"><a href="http://sarahemsley.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0679.jpg"><img class="wp-image-1353 " alt="At the JASNA NS celebration of P&amp;P yesterday. (Note JASNA 2013 AGM P&amp;P tea in the background.)" src="http://sarahemsley.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0679.jpg?w=240&#038;h=206" width="240" height="206" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">At the JASNA NS celebration of P&amp;P. Thanks, Julie. (Note JASNA 2013 AGM P&amp;P tea in the background.)</p></div>
<p>I am quite vain enough &amp; well satisfied enough” (<i>Letters</i>,<i> </i>4 February 1813). She tries to insist to herself and to her sister that she’s happy with the book, yet she immediately turns again to criticism, joking (and I’m quite sure this is a joke, though not all critics have thought so) that “The work is rather too light &amp; bright &amp; sparkling;—it wants shade;—it wants to be stretched out here &amp; there with a long Chapter—of sense if it could be had, if not of solemn specious nonsense—about something unconnected with the story; an Essay on Writing, a critique on Walter Scott, or the history of Buonaparte—or anything that would form a contrast &amp; bring the reader with increased delight to the playfulness &amp; Epigrammatism of the general stile.”</p>
<p>Jane Austen is at the same time completely confident about her achievement in <i>Pride and Prejudice</i>, and utterly unsatisfied with the publication of the novel. Sharing the novel with the world means leaving herself and her work open to criticism, criticism that she hasn’t dealt with History, Literature, and Politics (and she has been criticized many times for not addressing these things directly), and it means allowing other people to read and interpret the story and characters in their own ways.</p>
<p>And my, have those readers ever taken liberties with the story and characters.</p>
<p>I’ll limit myself right now to a very short list of the various responses to <i>Pride and Prejudice</i>: this novel has inspired more sequels, prequels, and adaptations than any of Jane Austen’s other novels. As you already know, even in the last two decades our culture has produced everything from the 1995 A&amp;E/BBC/Colin Firth’s wet shirt tv series, to <i>Bridget Jones’s Diary</i>, to <i>Pride and Prejudice and Zombies</i>, to <a href="http://sarahemsley.com/2013/01/08/pride-and-prejudice-for-babies/">board books designed to introduce babies to the novel</a>. Maybe you’ve already made the connection between these two pieces of information as well: that Stephanie Meyer’s best-selling <i>Twilight</i> books and movies about vampires are inspired by <i>Pride and Prejudice</i>, and that E.L. James’s phenomenally best-selling erotic novel <i>Fifty Shades of Grey</i> (and its own sequels) began life as <i>Twilight</i> fan-fiction.</p>
<p><i>Pride and Prejudice</i> sells, and it now sells both itself and a huge range of stories inspired by, or capitalizing on, its own popularity.</p>
<p>When it was first published, the title page said only, “By the author of <i>Sense and <a href="http://sarahemsley.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0666.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-1352" alt="Editions of P&amp;P" src="http://sarahemsley.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0666.jpg?w=300&#038;h=192" width="300" height="192" /></a>Sensibility</i>,” and Jane Austen’s authorship was a secret from nearly all the world. Some members of her family knew, and while she wasn’t ready to tell her neighbours, she clearly took pleasure in knowing that those neighbours knew about the book. She wrote to Cassandra that “you must be prepared for the Neighbourhood being perhaps already informed of there being such a Work in the World, &amp; in the Chawton World!” She found her niece Fanny’s praise “gratifying,” and confessed that “my hopes were tolerably strong of <i>her</i>, but nothing like a certainty.” Sharp, critical, and even cynical at times herself, Jane appears to have been sensitive about her writing, to have longed for praise even as she claimed not to need too much of it. She said of Fanny that “Her liking Darcy and Elizth is enough. She might hate all the others, if she would” (<i>Letters</i>, 9 February 1813).</p>
<p>Countless people over the past two hundred years have joined Fanny Knight and Cassandra Austen in liking Darcy and Elizabeth, and in praising <i>Pride and Prejudice</i>. Most of them have been in Britain, North America, and Australia, but according to <a href="http://www.independent.co.uk/arts-entertainment/books/features/romance-that-never-loses-its-sparkle-the-worlds-most-influential-novel-ever-8449400.html"><i>The Independent</i></a>, “China, India, and Russia are beginning to swot up on all things Austen.” The World has known Jane Austen’s “darling Child” for two centuries now, and it doesn’t seem likely to forget <i>Pride and Prejudice</i> any time soon.</p>
<p>I agree with <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/commentisfree/2013/jan/06/jane-austen-darling-child-turns-200">Alex Clark</a>, who makes the excellent point about the “cultural fetishisation” of <i>Pride and Prejudice</i> that “we should separate our regard for a book from all the white noise that surrounds it.” She emphasizes, “That’s not to say that we should wish <i>Pride and Prejudice</i> to be less well thought of than it is.” Yet how do we begin anew to talk about this novel, without wet shirts and zombies, without white noise or shades of grey? We begin at the beginning, of course: “It is a truth universally acknowledged, that a single man in possession of a good fortune, must be in want of a wife.”</p>
<p>In the next few weeks, I’m going to be rereading <i>Pride and Prejudice</i> and blogging about the novel itself. I hope you’ll join the conversation about rediscovering Austen’s masterpiece by commenting here on my website, and/or on <a href="https://www.facebook.com/sarahlbemsley">Facebook</a> and Twitter (<a href="https://twitter.com/Sarah_Emsley">@Sarah_Emsley</a>).</p>
<p>Let me start by asking you, not about your favourite film adaptation or sequel, but about your favourite quotation from the novel. If you had to choose just one line, what would it be? Here’s mine: “Happy for all her maternal feelings was the day on which Mrs. Bennet got rid of her two most deserving daughters.”</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1349/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1349/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1349&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://sarahemsley.com/2013/01/28/jane-austens-darling-child-meets-the-world/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/dcf8d8fdd5f30cf8c48c9a605f5b67bd?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sarahemsley</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://sarahemsley.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0674.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">At our JASNA NS meeting yesterday: one &#34;200th&#34; balloon, plus four that said &#34;50th Anniversary.&#34; Thanks, Anne and Carole.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://sarahemsley.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0679.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">At the JASNA NS celebration of P&#38;P yesterday. (Note JASNA 2013 AGM P&#38;P tea in the background.)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://sarahemsley.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_0666.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Editions of P&#38;P</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>I Can\&#8217;t Get No Disinfection</title>
		<link>http://clotildajamcracker.wordpress.com/2013/01/24/i-cant-get-no-disinfection/</link>
		<comments>http://clotildajamcracker.wordpress.com/2013/01/24/i-cant-get-no-disinfection/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2013 00:31:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>clotildajamcracker</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://clotildajamcracker.wordpress.com/?p=11391</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[If you drop a toothbrush in the toilet and there is nobody there to see it, did it really happen?  Only if it wasn&#8217;t your toothbrush.  You can sterilize, disinfect and call a priest to exorcise  bacteria on that toothbrush, but it isn&#8217;t going to do any good.  You can boil that toothbrush until you&#8217;re [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=11391&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you drop a toothbrush in the toilet and there is nobody there to see it, did it really happen?  Only if it wasn&#8217;t your toothbrush.  You can sterilize, disinfect and call a priest to exorcise  bacteria on that toothbrush, but it isn&#8217;t going to do any good.  You can boil that toothbrush until you&#8217;re blue in the face, but I can guarantee one thing.  You aren&#8217;t going to find one person in their right mind to brush their teeth with that toothbrush, because once something has fallen into the toilet, it&#8217;s never the same.</p>
<p>I, myself, am like a defiled dental hygiene product that has fallen into the watery abyss of a forgotten latrine.  I suppose I could blame everyone else, it would make me feel better.  It&#8217;s the noble thing to do.  When I blame myself I start feeling that life just isn&#8217;t worth living and I don&#8217;t care any more. In the summer, I leave buckets of water out for the mosquitos to swarm around and I don&#8217;t even put on mosquito repellant.  I&#8217;m fearless.  I&#8217;ll just walk right out into a swarm of those vicious little vampires.  I could get the West Nile Virus, I don&#8217;t care.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve never told anyone this before, but I buy grapes that aren&#8217;t organic, and I eat them without even washing them.  Yeah, I&#8217;m crazy like that.  I guess you&#8217;re wondering why someone would go insane and put their life on the line like this.  I&#8217;ll tell you why.  It&#8217;s just the way I am.  I was just born like this.  I guess I was born with some masochistic gene that makes me want to go out of my way to torture myself.  That&#8217;s the only explanation I have for it.  That is, it&#8217;s the only explanation if I don&#8217;t feel like blaming others for my problems.  But if I were to blame someone, I guess I would blame my family.  It is a proven scientific fact that those first few years of life cause a lasting imprint on a person. This imprint will last a person their whole life and there really isn&#8217;t anything that anyone can do about it.  A strange person can try to blend in with society, but it doesn&#8217;t work.  Everyone has that sneaking suspicion that there is something that just isn&#8217;t right.   <a href="http://clotildajamcracker.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/wp_000772.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-6718" alt="WP_000772" src="http://clotildajamcracker.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/wp_000772.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" width="300" height="225" /></a></p>
<p>Conformity is quite valuable in our society.  Everyone is trying to blend in.  Nobody wants to stand out.  Just go with the flow and everything will be hunky dory and peachy keen. Yeah, everyone knows this.  It&#8217;s common sense.  Mothers teach this to their children in order to protect them from embarrassment and ridicule.  Guess whose mom forgot to tell her that you shouldn&#8217;t bring zany ideas out into public? Yeah, that&#8217;s right.  My mother.</p>
<p>In all the madness and confusion of always trying to scrape together enough money to pay the bills and the taxes, I was sort of forgotten.  Yes, my very own mother was far too busy to teach me about life the, universe, and everything.  It&#8217;s the mother&#8217;s job to protect the young from harm, and if the mother isn&#8217;t watching her little goslings, someone else will.  My great  grandmother, Mabel, took me under her wing, and told me that my entire family had been enticed by the beast that was controlling the world.  Maybe it was true, and maybe it wasn&#8217;t, but how was I supposed to know right from wrong and good from bad.  I was just a kid.  I hadn&#8217;t seen movies.  I hadn&#8217;t read Shakespeare or Oscar Wilde.  All I knew were the fairy stories of yore, told to me from the only person who had time to help me tie my shoes.  Which, by the way were made from synthetic materials that came from petroleum that was made of the blood of the beast.  Those things had to go, as well as anything else that was made of plastic.</p>
<p>Had I been an aborigine living in the bush, this might have worked out just fine.  But I wasn&#8217;t.  I was a normal American kid who had to attend public school like everyone else.  I learned the hard way, that homemade leather soled moccasins were not a socially acceptable thing to wear to school.</p>
<p><a href="http://clotildajamcracker.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/article-new_ehow_images_a07_9s_28_homemade-moccasins-800x800.jpg"><img alt="article-new_ehow_images_a07_9s_28_homemade-moccasins-800x800" src="http://clotildajamcracker.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/article-new_ehow_images_a07_9s_28_homemade-moccasins-800x800.jpg?w=225&#038;h=300" width="225" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>No matter how hard I cried, no matter how many letters my great grandmother Mabel wrote to the school and the school board, they still made me wear sneakers to P.E.  They laughed when I told them about the evils of the unholy beast who wanted to take over the world.  They scorned me and put me to shame when I refused to sit in a plastic chair at a plastic desk.  Looking back, I don&#8217;t think it was such a good thing to stand up for what I believed in.  It sure would have been nice to have someone there by my side at school.  Someone who would be on my side and stand up for me.  But alas, I had no one.</p>
<p>Well, I did have a sister.   I wouldn&#8217;t exactly say that she was on my side.  She was the exact opposite of a loving compassionate sibling.  You know what that whore of Babylon did to me?  She told everyone that I used an out house.  Oh, sure it was true, and it seemed like a good thing at the time.  I was told that using the plastic toilet would summon a dark evil beast that would prey upon my soul.  It could have been true. Who knows.  Everyone is always saying that there is something wrong with the world today.  Maybe nobody has a soul anymore.  Maybe there really is a dark and evil beast who preys on those who use plastic.  Maybe it&#8217;s true, and maybe it isn&#8217;t.  But I do know one thing for sure.  If this sounds like madness; if I sound a bit off my rocker, then there is only one reason for it.</p>
<p>I am nothing more than a toothbrush that was dropped into a toilet.  After what I&#8217;ve been through, and after what I&#8217;ve seen; I will never be the same. I fear nothing.  I use public restrooms and I don&#8217;t open the door with paper towels.  I use my bare hands!  And sometimes&#8230;.I don&#8217;t even wash them.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/11391/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/11391/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=11391&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://clotildajamcracker.wordpress.com/2013/01/24/i-cant-get-no-disinfection/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>77</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/ad1bf3481b13da405a6fa3d4be84a0f4?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">clotildajamcracker</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://clotildajamcracker.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/wp_000772.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">WP_000772</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://clotildajamcracker.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/article-new_ehow_images_a07_9s_28_homemade-moccasins-800x800.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">article-new_ehow_images_a07_9s_28_homemade-moccasins-800x800</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Be Kind</title>
		<link>http://lunchsketch.com/2013/01/24/be-kind/</link>
		<comments>http://lunchsketch.com/2013/01/24/be-kind/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2013 13:15:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lunch Sketch</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[People]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[compassion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drawing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kindness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kurt Vonnegut]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mr rosewater]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Na Son Nguyen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sketch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vietnamese children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yêu]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://lunchsketch.com/?p=2336</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[3.5 Lunchbreaks Hello, babies. Welcome to Earth. It&#8217;s hot in the summer and cold in the winter. It&#8217;s round and wet and crowded. At the outside, babies, you&#8217;ve got about a hundred years here. There&#8217;s only one rule that I know of, babies — God damn it, you&#8217;ve got to be kind. ~ Kurt Vonnegut [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2336&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://lunchsketch.com/2013/01/24/be-kind/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>48</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://lunchsketch.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/be-kind.jpg?w=100" />
		<media:content url="http://lunchsketch.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/be-kind.jpg?w=100" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Be Kind</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/8075abccc9474eaab19e504dd4065c79?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F2.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gman12345</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lunchsketch.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/be-kind.jpg?w=396" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Be Kind</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>When Do I Make the Call?</title>
		<link>http://acanvasoftheminds.wordpress.com/2013/01/27/when-do-i-make-the-call/</link>
		<comments>http://acanvasoftheminds.wordpress.com/2013/01/27/when-do-i-make-the-call/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2013 14:32:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>DeeDee</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Anxiety (NOS - not otherwise specified)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Attention Deficit Disorder (ADD)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Attention Deficit Hyperactivity Disorder (ADHD)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bipolar Disorder (BD)/manic-depression]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Coping Strategies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Emotions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Major Depressive Disorder (MDD)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mental Health Care]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Psychiatrists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Support]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Symptoms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Therapy/Therapists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Triggers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weakenesses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[help]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[intervention]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reaching out]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[safety plan]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://acanvasoftheminds.wordpress.com/?p=2496</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Everyone tells me I hold out too long. I don&#8217;t ask for help often enough or soon enough. I tell them that I don&#8217;t know when to ask; they don&#8217;t seem to understand. I&#8217;m learning to recognize when things are going awry and when what I&#8217;m feeling should be considered &#8220;unacceptable&#8221; because it&#8217;s suffering, not [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2496&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://acanvasoftheminds.wordpress.com/2013/01/27/when-do-i-make-the-call/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>49</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f245db5039b00811eb0d6bdae9bf5d61?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">disorderlychickadee</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://acanvasoftheminds.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/whentocall.jpg?w=512" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">When To Call</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>School Lockdowns:  Can We Please Calm Down?</title>
		<link>http://formingthethread.wordpress.com/2013/01/28/school-lockdowns-can-we-please-calm-down/</link>
		<comments>http://formingthethread.wordpress.com/2013/01/28/school-lockdowns-can-we-please-calm-down/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2013 05:01:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>The Color of Lila</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Crime]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Color of Lila]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Columbine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[First Responders]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Guns]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Panic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Safety]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sandy Hook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[School Lockdowns]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Toys]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://formingthethread.wordpress.com/?p=2831</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Run a quick search on &#8220;school locked down&#8221; and it seems that this has become a commonplace occurrence lately.  Sometimes the lockdowns make sense: a violent crime is committed nearby and the perpetrator is at large.  Someone makes a threat.  Someone reports seeing a student with a possible firearm.  Some of those reports turn out [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2831&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://formingthethread.wordpress.com/2013/01/28/school-lockdowns-can-we-please-calm-down/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>48</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://formingthethread.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/school-lockdown.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://formingthethread.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/school-lockdown.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">school-lockdown</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/425d511a977a596c8599c8f23ddac205?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">thecoloroflila</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://www.carlwalther.com/images/cp88_limegreen_2.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://formingthethread.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/nerfgun.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">NerfGun</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Happy Birthday, Colette!</title>
		<link>http://windagainstcurrent.com/2013/01/27/happy-birthday-colette/</link>
		<comments>http://windagainstcurrent.com/2013/01/27/happy-birthday-colette/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2013 03:05:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Johna Till Johnson</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Literature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Philosophy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Society]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Biography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Colette]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[French Writers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://windagainstcurrent.com/?p=15048</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[You probably knew this, but January 28th is the 140th birthday of the French writer Colette.

Okay, you probably didn't know that. You might not even remember who Colette is, though chances are, you're familiar with at least one of her works.

And you're probably wondering why you should care about her birthday, or her.

Let me take a step back. This year,  Vlad and I have adopted a new tradition: We've selected a pantheon of personal heroes, and heroines---people whose spirits and lives matter to us---and are making a conscious effort to celebrate their birthdays.

Colette's is the first, but there will be plenty of others.

So why did we select her?

<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=15048&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>By Johna Till Johnson </strong></p>
<p><span style="color:#ff0000;"><em><strong>Freshly Pressed</strong> on the WordPress.com home page!</em></span></p>
<p>You probably knew this, but January 28th is the 140th birthday of the French writer <a title="American Society of Authors and Writers: Sidonie-Gabrielle Colette" href="http://amsaw.org/amsaw-ithappenedinhistory-012805-colette.html" target="_blank">Colette</a>.</p>
<div id="attachment_15049" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 256px"><a href="http://patrickmurfin.blogspot.com/2012/01/celebrating-colette.html" target="_blank"><img class="wp-image-15049    " title="Colette, in costume" alt="Colette, in costume" src="http://windagainstcurrent.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/colette-yoga.jpg?w=246&#038;h=228" width="246" height="228" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Colette, in costume&#8230;</p></div>
<p>Okay, you probably <em>didn&#8217;t</em> know that. You might not even remember who Colette is, though chances are, you&#8217;re familiar with at least one of her works.</p>
<p>And you&#8217;re probably wondering why you should care about her birthday, or her.</p>
<p>Let me take a step back. This year,  Vlad and I have adopted a new tradition: We&#8217;ve selected a pantheon of personal heroes, and heroines&#8212;people whose spirits and lives matter to us&#8212;and are making a conscious effort to celebrate their birthdays.</p>
<p>Colette&#8217;s is the first, but there will be plenty of others.</p>
<p>So why did we select her?</p>
<p><span id="more-15048"></span></p>
<p>Colette was in many ways a woman ahead of her time. She was a prolific and  brilliant writer, and supported herself throughout her life with her creative endeavors.</p>
<p>Her work included fiction, journalism, and memoirs; a contemporary described her as &#8220;the best living writer in France&#8221;, though most of her work is unfamiliar to American readers.</p>
<p>In the U.S., she&#8217;s most famous for the novella <a title="Wikipedia: Gigi" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gigi" target="_blank"><em>Gigi</em></a>, which became a <a title="Wikipedia: Gigi (1951 play)" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gigi_%281951_play%29" target="_blank">Broadway play</a>, and then a <a title="Wikipedia: Gigi (1958 film)" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gigi_%281958_film%29" target="_blank">movie</a>, starring previously-unknown actress Audrey Hepburn.  (See? You&#8217;ve probably heard of the play or the movie, even if you&#8217;d forgotten who wrote it.)</p>
<p>In addition to being a writer, she was an actress, a dancer, and a businesswoman: She started a line of cosmetics that played off the phenomenal success of the main character of one of her early novels. This kind of &#8220;product merchandising&#8221; didn&#8217;t become commonplace until the middle of the 20th century&#8212;but Colette pioneered it early on.</p>
<div id="attachment_15051" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 215px"><a href="http://epdlp.com/escritor.php?id=1593" target="_blank"><img class="wp-image-15051 " title="Colette in her later years" alt="Colette in her later years" src="http://windagainstcurrent.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/colette.jpg?w=205&#038;h=227" width="205" height="227" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Colette in her later years</p></div>
<p>Her accomplishments are impressive, and towards the end of her life she was recognized for them:  She was <a title="New York Times: Colette Is Dead in Paris at 81; Novelist Wrote 'Gigi' and 'Cheri'" href="http://www.nytimes.com/books/99/10/17/specials/colette-obit.html" target="_blank">admitted to the Belgian Academy of French Language and Literature</a> (the French Academy refused to admit a woman), was the second woman in history to be made a grand officer of the Legion of Honor, and was the first woman to be given a funeral of state in France.</p>
<p>But her achievements weren&#8217;t the reason we selected her.</p>
<p>It was her spirit: astonishingly forward-looking (if somewhat unorthodox), determinedly hedonistic, down-to-earth, and above all, true to herself.</p>
<p>She believed in the value of physical exercise&#8212;at a time when most women were warned that athleticism would damage their &#8220;womanly organs&#8221; and undermine their femininity. And she had a remarkably healthy attitude toward exercise:  She did it because it felt good and she enjoyed the play of her shapely muscles, not to burn calories.   Although she kept in spectacular shape for much of her life, she strongly disapproved of the &#8220;cult of slimness&#8221; that was just beginning to emerge.</p>
<p>In fact, Colette was all about feeling good for its own sake, not to meet any outside standards.</p>
<p>She loved sunshine, gardening, and &#8220;digging in the good earth&#8221;. (She set up her gymnastics bars so she could exercise outside, thereby predating CrossFit by more than a century.)</p>
<p>She was an adventuress, spending several years working as a dance-hall actress (a profession anathema to well-brought-up young French girls). This was both a way to earn a living (imperative after her first marriage ended) and a way to gather material for her work.</p>
<p>And she loved good food, which she defined as steak, oysters, fresh cream, and anything &#8220;fresh out of the garden&#8221;. (Again, a strikingly modern perspective, entirely in tune with the current &#8220;real food&#8221; movement.)</p>
<p>Her love life was unconventional&#8212;though not necessarily any more so than that of her male peers. Presumably because she was a beautiful woman, though, it got&#8212;and continues to get&#8212;a lot of attention. (Really, people: Why does <a title="The Physics of the Universe: ERWIN SCHRÖDINGER (1887 - 1961)" href="http://physicsoftheuniverse.com/scientists_schrodinger.html" target="_blank">the fact that Erwin Schrödinger lived openly with his wife a<em>nd</em> his mistress</a> not even merit a mention in his Wikipedia entry, while <a title="Wikipedia: Colette" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Colette" target="_blank">Colette&#8217;s entry</a> covers her romantic history in depth before even <em>mentioning</em> her awards and honors?)</p>
<div id="attachment_15292" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 262px"><a href="http://windagainstcurrent.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/43936.gif" target="_blank"><img class="wp-image-15292  " title="Young Colette" alt="Young Colette" src="http://windagainstcurrent.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/43936.gif?w=252&#038;h=293" width="252" height="293" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Colette&#8217;s last words: &#8220;What a beautiful life I&#8217;ve had.&#8221;</p></div>
<p><strong></strong>What was also unusual was her refusal to apologize for her romantic choices. She divorced her first husband for philandering, and when her second did the same, she seduced his son (thereby, unsurprisingly, causing the end of that marriage). Her third marriage&#8212;to a much younger man&#8212;endured until her death. (I don&#8217;t mean to shortchange her other significant relationship, a long-term affair with a French noblewoman that ended rather tragically.)</p>
<p>Her choices weren&#8217;t always wise&#8212;but they were hers.</p>
<p>And that&#8217;s the point of Colette&#8212;she did what made sense to her. She looked at life with clear eyes that saw through hypocrisy, and kicked convention to the curb when it didn&#8217;t suit her.</p>
<p>We&#8217;re honoring Colette by savoring steak and oysters with some friends and colleagues. We think she&#8217;d approve.</p>
<p>Happy birthday, Colette, and many happy returns&#8230;  to Colette, and the upcoming heroes and heroines of 2013.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/15048/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/15048/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=15048&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://windagainstcurrent.com/2013/01/27/happy-birthday-colette/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>76</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/35c9a7423d9e6ed45d54bbe32d250f0c?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">windagainstcurrent2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://windagainstcurrent.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/colette-yoga.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Colette, in costume</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://windagainstcurrent.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/colette.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Colette in her later years</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://windagainstcurrent.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/43936.gif" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Young Colette</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Frozen Pizza: How Instagram And Vine Are Fueling The Frivolous</title>
		<link>http://currenteditorials.com/2013/01/25/frozen-pizza-how-instagram-and-vine-are-fuelling-the-frivolous/</link>
		<comments>http://currenteditorials.com/2013/01/25/frozen-pizza-how-instagram-and-vine-are-fuelling-the-frivolous/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2013 22:46:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Eric Leamen</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[All Posts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Editorials]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Must Read]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pizza]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stupid]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[videos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vine]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://currenteditorials.com/?p=7512</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[That is a frozen piece of pizza, on the ground, covered in snow. I found it in the parking lot this morning as I was leaving school. I posted an Instagram of it. At the outset of the new year, I set some social media goals for myself. Things like learning to better leverage Twitter [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=7512&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://currenteditorials.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/frozenpizzahero.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7521" alt="FrozenPizzaHero" src="http://currenteditorials.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/frozenpizzahero.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>That is a frozen piece of pizza, on the ground, covered in snow. I found it in the parking lot this morning as I was leaving school. <a href="http://instagram.com/p/U60VmXBlMw/">I posted an Instagram of it.</a></p>
<p>At the outset of the new year, I set some social media goals for myself. Things like learning to better leverage Twitter as a networking tool, expanding my presence and my brand online, and trying to take more Instagram photos. I hoped to achieve that last one by taking at least one Instagram photo each day for the entire year. For the first few weeks, I did quite well. I started taking photos of everything, some days posting more than one. On occasion, more than five.</p>
<p>Last night, I renounced my quest to post one Instagram a day.</p>
<p>The reason was something that became readily apparent to me just a few days in, but which I ignored until last night. I was taking pictures of stupid, useless stuff. Stuff that my followers probably didn&#8217;t care about. Stuff that I really didn&#8217;t care about. Stuff like a piece of frozen pizza. I was taking pictures for the sake of meeting a quota, and that made Instagram lose all meaning. It wasn&#8217;t fun anymore. It felt like work.</p>
<p>The easy answer would be that it was stupid of me to set an &#8220;Instagram quota&#8221; for myself, and that of course it starts to feel like work when you force yourself to continually do something even when you don&#8217;t want to. But what I realized during my experiment is that the quality of my photos really had nothing to do with the quota. Even everyday, casual use of Instagram, Twitter, Facebook, and the like, often results in stupid, meaningless, irrelevant posts.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve now become hyperaware of this fact. While composing a Tweet, I often stop and think, &#8220;Why am I saying this? Will someone find this funny? Does this Tweet have any meaning?&#8221; That often ends with a, &#8220;Screw it, I shouldn&#8217;t post this&#8221;, at which point I abandon the half-finished Tweet. The same can be said for Instagram. &#8220;Does everyone really need to see this? Is it artistic? Do I want to preserve this photo for later?&#8221; And Facebook. &#8220;Why did I post that? Am I just fishing for a reaction? Am I bragging?&#8221; Delete.</p>
<p>Perhaps what set me off yesterday was the introduction of Vine, Twitter&#8217;s new video sharing service that many are already calling &#8220;the Instagram for video&#8221;. Just like my Instagram photos were starting to feel meaningless, so too were most of the &#8220;first Vines&#8221; I saw posted yesterday. Vines of people Tweeting about Vine. Vines of people making coffee. Vines of people drinking coffee. Vines of dogs. Vines of cats. Vines of people dressed like cats. Vines of a dying Tweetie Bird. Vines of people eating food. I&#8217;ve yet to post a Vine, because I feel as if I have nothing Vine-worthy to record.</p>
<p>I get that part of the fun of these services &#8211; especially on launch day &#8211; is playing around with them, experimenting, posting stupid stuff, or funny stuff, or completely and wildly random stuff. But at some point we have to stop and think, &#8220;Why am I doing this? Does anyone care about this?&#8221;.</p>
<p>Services like Instagram and Vine are fuelling the frivolous. Many people, myself included, are fooled into this false belief that we always have something interesting to say or share. I think it&#8217;s important to be aware of this false sense of importance, to step back a little bit and ask ourselves if what we&#8217;re doing means something. Next time you post a Tweet, take an Instagram photo, update your Facebook status, or record a Vine, ask yourself &#8220;Why am I posting this? Does it really matter?&#8221;. Think critically about what you choose to post online. I know I will.</p>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=7512&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://currenteditorials.com/2013/01/25/frozen-pizza-how-instagram-and-vine-are-fuelling-the-frivolous/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://currenteditorials.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/frozenpizzahero.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://currenteditorials.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/frozenpizzahero.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">FrozenPizzaHero</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/2d78509b92578b5ee2bcccc8e388a3f9?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=R" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">EL</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://currenteditorials.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/frozenpizzahero.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">FrozenPizzaHero</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pemberley by Accident</title>
		<link>http://opencurtains.wordpress.com/2013/01/27/pemberley-by-accident-2/</link>
		<comments>http://opencurtains.wordpress.com/2013/01/27/pemberley-by-accident-2/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2013 14:10:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Open the Curtains</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Peak District]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[history]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jane Austen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[landscape]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[literature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lyme Park]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pride and Prejudice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stately home]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://opencurtains.wordpress.com/?p=1601</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[With the road atlas spread out in front of us, I put the finishing touches to the set of complex instructions that my friend and I would have to follow the next morning as we headed south, attempting to avoid a) getting ourselves lost, b) driving into another quarry, and c) Manchester. Despite having looked [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1601&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With the road atlas spread out in front of us, I put the finishing touches to the set of complex instructions that my friend and I would have to follow the next morning as we headed south, attempting to avoid a) getting ourselves lost, b) driving into another quarry, and c) Manchester. Despite having looked forward to Yorkshire so much it had not turned out quite as we&#8217;d expected. We&#8217;d been on the road about two weeks already, and the day&#8217;s events had had a somewhat dispiriting effect on us.</p>
<p>‘I hope the Peak District’s good. Derbyshire&#8217;d better be better than Yorkshire anyway or I think we might have to just drive straight home.’</p>
<blockquote><p><i>With the mention of Derbyshire, there were many ideas connected. It was impossible for her to see the word without thinking of Pemberley and its owner.</i></p></blockquote>
<p>‘Of course it’ll be good,’ I replied confidently, ‘Mr Darcy lives there!’</p>
<p><a href="http://opencurtains.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/2012-06-10-kinder-scout-20.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-1603" title="Noe Stool, Kinder Plateau, Derbyshire" alt="" src="http://opencurtains.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/2012-06-10-kinder-scout-20.jpg?w=240&#038;h=180" width="240" height="180" /></a><a href="http://opencurtains.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/darcy-elizabeth-pemberley.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-1604" title="Darcy and Elizabeth at Pemberley, picture credit: BBC (1995)" alt="" src="http://opencurtains.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/darcy-elizabeth-pemberley.jpg?w=300&#038;h=170" width="300" height="170" /></a></p>
<p><span id="more-1601"></span></p>
<blockquote><p><i>‘Adieu to disappointment and spleen… Oh! what hours of transport we shall spend!’</i></p></blockquote>
<p>Unfortunately this proved all too true the next day, though not quite in the manner that Miss Austen intended in her beloved text. Having successfully circumnavigated Manchester we found ourselves stuck in traffic for two hours in Stockport on our way to the Peaks.</p>
<p>I reached for the map to see if there was anywhere to pull off.  A country park was marked in less than a mile, so I suggested we stretch our legs and have lunch to revive us for the next stage of our journey.</p>
<p>As we turned into the entrance we found it flanked by surprisingly formal looking pillars.  The drive lead through gently rolling parkland, a herd of deer spreading out through the landscape.</p>
<p>It clearly wasn’t a country park, but a country estate.  And not just any country estate.</p>
<blockquote><p>The park was very large, and contained great variety of ground. They entered it in one of its lowest points, and drove for some time through a beautiful wood stretching over a wide extent&#8230;  <i>They gradually ascended for half a mile, and then found themselves at the top of a considerable eminence, where the wood ceased, and the eye was instantly caught by Pemberley House, situated on the opposite side of a valley, into which the road with some abruptness wound.</i></p></blockquote>
<p><a href="http://opencurtains.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/juliesummerfield1.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-1643" style="width:315px;" alt="juliesummerfield" src="http://opencurtains.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/juliesummerfield1-e1359304828554.jpg?w=310&#038;h=207" width="310" height="207" /></a><a href="http://opencurtains.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_1068.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-1610 alignnone" style="width:274px;" title="Lyme Hall/Pemberley courtyard" alt="" src="http://opencurtains.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_1068.jpg?w=274&#038;h=214" width="274" height="214" /></a></p>
<p>Lyme Park has become one of the most recognisable vistas of an English country house, thanks to the BBC – and of course, Colin Firth in a wet shirt.  For all the jokes, we’d accidentally arrived at the location used to film Mr Darcy’s fictional home in the famous 1995 adaptation. Clearly this required more than just a stroll. After all even Elizabeth Bennet couldn&#8217;t turn down the opportunity to go poking round Pemberley, even if she did think its owner somewhat repulsive at the time. Thanks to the National Trust and its cheap membership for those under 26 we were even able to do so for free.</p>
<p>Entering a familiar-looking courtyard we mounted a flight of steps and were admitted to the hall.  Almost immediately a custodian stepped in to prevent photography, flash or otherwise.  Stately homes seem defined by red tape, and in this case red ropes with hanging arrows that funnelled visitors along the preferred route.  Dim hallways were lined with long windows and tapestries, punctuated by finial-legged tables, strategic lamps, and ornaments.  Among the lavish furnishings was an extensive clock collection: tall grandfathers, ticking mantle clocks, chiming carriage clocks; the functional to the elaborate, mostly working, all showing different times.</p>
<p>Despite the house being representational of one that so many people would consider the ideal residence, it felt strangely inhospitable. It might have been grand, but it felt more like a museum than a house. Having been so carefully designed to conform to the idea of aesthetic perfection, and then frozen in time by the National Trust to provide an example of what exactly that would have been like to walk around in was somewhat disconcerting. Stately homes that are open for public viewing are always confusing to me: partly interesting for the artefacts and architecture, some of which is beautiful, some fun to mock because of its over-decorative ugliness, but always at the same time slightly hollow. How different an experience would it have been for Lizzy to walk round a similarly grand house full of expensive furniture, paintings and posh paraphernalia, but one that was of the contemporary idea of what was desirable and stylish, and one that was really lived in?</p>
<p>Lyme Hall was not a house I could live in. I would have liked the run of it, though, with no one to look over my shoulder whilst I peered into cupboards and boxes, opened doors sealed for years, blowing dust from objects of curiosity, pulling those unread volumes off the shelves in the library, finding out what all those rooms really are that we can never get to see. In reality visitors are only admitted to a minute portion of the internal workings. What is in the rest of it? Truly here is the province of fiction, but the potential secrets to be uncovered are, for me, a greater thrill than the romanticism of an Austenite fairytale.</p>
<p>We didn’t stay long, it being an unexpected diversion meant only to be a lunch break.</p>
<p>There was just enough time for a quick photo opportunity by That Lake before we got back in the car. As neither Mr Darcy nor Colin Firth looked likely to appear we left the formal grandeur for wilder riches awaiting in the Peaks.</p>
<p><img class="wp-image-1629 alignleft" title="The real lake at Lyme Park, credit: anothernoone" alt="" src="http://opencurtains.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/pemberley-lake1-e1359292494437.png?w=312&#038;h=319" width="312" height="319" /><img class="wp-image-1627 alignnone" title="picture credit: BBC (1995)" alt="" src="http://opencurtains.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/lake-scene.jpg?w=267&#038;h=212" width="267" height="212" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>More on this?</strong></p>
<p><span style="color:#008080;">2013 is the <a title="200th anniversary of Pride and Prejudice" href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-21078941" target="_blank">200th anniversary </a>of the publication of Jane Austen&#8217;s <em>Pride and Prejudice</em>, from which, for the less than obsessed of you my dear readers, the quotes in this piece were taken. On 27th January 1813 <a href="http://sarahemsley.com/2012/10/16/pride-and-prejudice-at-200/" target="_blank">the first published copy of the novel found its way to the author herself</a>. </span></p>
<p><span style="color:#008080;">My friend and I were visiting <span style="color:#3366ff;"><a title="Lyme Park" href="http://www.nationaltrust.org.uk/lyme-park/" target="_blank"><span style="color:#3366ff;">Lyme Park </span></a></span>(which is actually in Cheshire, but still in the Peak District), near Stockport, used for the exterior Pemberley scenes in the BBC adaptation. <a title="Sudbury Hall" href="http://www.nationaltrust.org.uk/sudburyhall/" target="_blank">Sudbury Hall</a> at Ashbourne (actually in Derbyshire) was used for the interior. Both are National Trust properties and for book lovers 2013 will be a good time to visit Lyme Park as an exhibition will be hosted there celebrating 70 years of Puffin, the children&#8217;s division of Penguin books who brought us Stig, Spot, and The Very Hungry Caterpillar. </span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;"><strong><span style="color:#333333;">You may also like:</span><span style="color:#008080;"> </span></strong><span style="color:#3366ff;"><a title="It’s Beginning To Look A Lot Like Wordsworth" href="http://opencurtains.wordpress.com/2012/04/15/wordsworth/"><span style="color:#3366ff;">It&#8217;s Beginning to Look a Lot Like Wordsworth</span></a></span></span></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1601/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1601/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1601&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://opencurtains.wordpress.com/2013/01/27/pemberley-by-accident-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>36</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/eb5d8b09089d38271c44003029586383?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">opencurtains</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://opencurtains.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/2012-06-10-kinder-scout-20.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Noe Stool, Kinder Plateau, Derbyshire</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://opencurtains.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/darcy-elizabeth-pemberley.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Darcy and Elizabeth at Pemberley, picture credit: BBC (1995)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://opencurtains.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/juliesummerfield1-e1359304828554.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">juliesummerfield</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://opencurtains.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_1068.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Lyme Hall/Pemberley courtyard</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://opencurtains.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/pemberley-lake1-e1359292494437.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The real lake at Lyme Park, credit: anothernoone</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://opencurtains.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/lake-scene.jpg?w=625" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">picture credit: BBC (1995)</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
