<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2012 20:02:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>What I Learned About Blogging During NaBloPoMo</title>
		<link>http://pinkbriefcase.wordpress.com/2012/12/05/what-i-learned-about-blogging-during-nablopomo/</link>
		<comments>http://pinkbriefcase.wordpress.com/2012/12/05/what-i-learned-about-blogging-during-nablopomo/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 16:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>pinkbriefcase</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[freshly pressed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nablopomo]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://pinkbriefcase.wordpress.com/?p=1142</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[So, this thing happened. It was called NaBloPoMo, and it was a national blog posting month, where some bloggers committed to trying to post in their respective spaces every single day for the entire month. You know, I&#8217;m not sure why we pick November for this when it is already No-Shave November and National Novel [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1142&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="size-full wp-image-1033 alignleft" alt="NaBloPoMo_teaser" src="http://pinkbriefcase.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/nablopomo_teaser.jpg?w=590"   /></p>
<p>So, this thing happened.  It was called <a class="zem_slink" title="NaBloPoMo" href="http://www.nablopomo.com/" target="_blank" rel="homepage">NaBloPoMo</a>, and it was a national blog posting month, where some bloggers committed to trying to post in their respective spaces every single day for the entire month.  You know, I&#8217;m not sure why we pick November for this when it is already <a class="zem_slink" title="No-Shave November" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/No-Shave_November" target="_blank" rel="wikipedia">No-Shave November</a> and <a class="zem_slink" title="National Novel Writing Month" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/National_Novel_Writing_Month" target="_blank" rel="wikipedia">National Novel Writing Month</a> and contains Veterans&#8217; Day and Thanksgiving, but I&#8217;m pretty okay with it nonetheless.  Here are a few thoughts I have about the experience and some ideas I&#8217;ve gathered for making my blog better in the coming year.</p>
<p><strong>Lesson one: substance matters <del>as much as</del> more than frequency.</strong></p>
<p>Sure, more-frequent blogging keeps my page views up, but page views aren&#8217;t everything when the quality of your work starts to suffer.  Lame, awkward, cliché posts are only going to keep even the most dedicated readers [Hi, Mom and Dad!] coming back for so long. After a few lame posts I started to feel embarrassed of my content and decided that I&#8217;d have to really write <em>something</em> or not post at all.  This decision was made the day after a photo-only post that I thought would hold down the fort on the day I was too tired to write.  A dear friend told me the next day, &#8220;So that fake blog you wrote?  I clicked over and was disappointed.&#8221;  And honestly, that&#8217;s how I felt too!  So, here are my goals for the blog in the coming year:</p>
<ol>
<li><em><strong>A Content Calendar. </strong> So many blogger advice posts out there say that this is the way to go, and I think it is time for me to try it out too.  Now, having a content calendar may reduce the spontaneity of my blogs, but I think it will help keep things consistent and help me to meet my readers&#8217; expectations.  So, I&#8217;ve made plans for the rest of the month and will be trying out a few new things to see how it goes.  I&#8217;m not committed to a full calendar &#8212; it may be better for my style to pre-select topics for one or two posts each week and let the remaining posts come as the inspiration does, but we&#8217;re going to try it out before making that decision.
<p></em></li>
<li><em><strong>Target content. </strong> The most successful blogs have a subject matter or two that attract a certain type of reader &#8212; a niche, in other words.  To build up a readership that will actually leave comments and engage in dialogue about issues I care about, I&#8217;ll have to actually write about those issues and maintain relationships with the kind of readers who will leave those kinds of comments.  Thus far, my content is a little all-over-the-place, and I kind of like that.  So, I won&#8217;t be picking one topic, but I will be keeping this in mind and will try to tie each blog post back to the things that this blog is really about:  maintaining a positive work-life balance, physically, emotionally, spiritually, and adventure-ly.  I&#8217;ll still write about what I am passionate about:  cooking, religion, politics, social justice, travel and history, but I will try to keep in mind the reason I&#8217;m writing at all &#8212; to remember that no matter how busy and crazy life gets, who I am inside really matters, and what I care about deserves to have a place in my schedule.
<p></em></li>
<li><em><strong>A network of bloggers.</strong>  This year, I have fallen in love with some new bloggers.  As I study and attempt to emulate their successful blogging patterns, it is clear that these bloggers are real-life friends with many other bloggers, and that they all work together to cross-promote, collaborate, encourage and support each other.  When one blogger writes a book or joins an exciting initiative, their network supports the action, sends over blog traffic, and provides public and enthusiastic encouragement. It&#8217;s kind of beautiful. I&#8217;m not entirely sure how to find my own network, but I know that really connecting with my subject matter and readers is the first step.  So, I&#8217;m going to work harder at &#8220;Like&#8221;-ing and Commenting on other posts, at using my twitter accounts to encourage dialogue and at supporting my special friends who are also blogging about their life-encounters.  Lately, my blog reading has been done by <a class="zem_slink" title="Google Reader" href="http://www.google.com/reader" target="_blank" rel="homepage">Google Reader</a>, so my favorites may not even know how dedicated I am to reading their content.  That is about to change. </em></li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Lesson two:  words aren&#8217;t enough.  </strong></p>
<p>When I decided to start this whole thing, one if my first tasks was to download a photo widget from <a class="zem_slink" title="BlogHer" href="http://www.blogher.com" target="_blank" rel="homepage">BlogHer</a> to add to my sidebar.  I discovered (1) that my sidebar had disappeared sometime since I last revised my blog theme, (2) that a full sidebar with a single photo widget is kind of awkward-looking, and (3) that lazy plans for filling up a sidebar can only get you so far.</p>
<p>Basically, my blog needs a makeover, in the beauty department.  Nothing screams AMATEUR like poorly photoshopped headers, random formatting glitches, and blurry snapshots.  Here are my plans for the new year:</p>
<ol>
<li><em><strong>Professional photography</strong>. And no, not by me, obviously. I&#8217;m thinking it would be cool to have some new photos related to the blog&#8211;I&#8217;m going to pick out a cool new briefcase and try to get really creative and fun. And honestly, it&#8217;s time for this. I need a professional headshot for my linked in account and with this I can kill two birds with one stone.
<p></em></li>
<li><em><strong>To learn all about widgets, sidebars, and other blogging gadgets and  gizmos</strong>.  I honestly have no idea what a lot of these things are about.  What in the world is <a class="zem_slink" title="HTML" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTML" target="_blank" rel="wikipedia">HTML</a>?  And how do I change fonts, font sizes, etc.?  I have no idea, but I want to find out.</em></li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Lesson three:  Blog challenges are fun!</strong></p>
<p>So, I&#8217;m not sure I&#8217;m going to post a blog every single day forever &#8212; but it was a pretty fun challenge!  I did pretty well at it for about 60% of the month, and was almost perfect during pre-Thanksgiving November.  There are blog challenges going on all the time, and trying something different with your writing shifts your perspective and deepens your sensitivity as a writer.  It&#8217;s a good idea.</p>
<ol>
<li><em><strong>First up</strong>:  <a class="zem_slink" title="WordPress" href="http://wordpress.org" target="_blank" rel="homepage">WordPress</a>&#8216;s <a href="http://dailypost.wordpress.com/tag/writing-challenge/" target="_blank">weekly writing challenge.</a>  I may not do it every week, but I&#8217;m going to throw in the ones I find interesting from time-to-time and encourage you to do it with me.  It could be really fun!
<p></em></li>
<li><em><strong>Community challenges</strong>.  Once I find a blogging community or two that fits into my writing genre(s), I&#8217;d like to participate in link-ups as well.  This connects back to the first and second lessons too, but I would really like to learn how people network together, how bloggers choose partners and get guest bloggers, and how to build a conversation in this space.  All in due time, of course. </em></li>
</ol>
<p>So, that&#8217;s a wrap.  NaBloPoMo, or post-almost-every-day-in-November-until-Thanksgiving-distracts-you-from-everything was a success.  I&#8217;m so glad I did it and hope to carry these lessons into my blogging for the next year.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1142/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1142/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1142&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://pinkbriefcase.wordpress.com/2012/12/05/what-i-learned-about-blogging-during-nablopomo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>12</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/ad22d3af945d729f0008aa9084b26b4b?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">pinkbriefcase</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://pinkbriefcase.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/nablopomo_teaser.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">NaBloPoMo_teaser</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Does It Still Have To Hurt So Much?</title>
		<link>http://meizac.wordpress.com/2012/12/02/why-does-it-still-have-to-hurt-so-much/</link>
		<comments>http://meizac.wordpress.com/2012/12/02/why-does-it-still-have-to-hurt-so-much/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2012 04:28:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>meizac</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adults]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[behaviour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[divorce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[friendships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hurt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[men]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ruined]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[separation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://meizac.wordpress.com/?p=3873</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s been a long time since it happened. Nearly seven years, actually. I made clear in a previous post that I blame him for this. As with any relationship, I know I have to take responsibility for my own shortcomings, and I do. They pale in comparison to what he did to me; what he did [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3873&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s been a long time since it happened.</p>
<p>Nearly seven years, actually.</p>
<p><span id="more-3873"></span></p>
<p>I made clear in a previous post that <span style="text-decoration:underline;"><a href="http://meizac.wordpress.com/2012/07/31/i-blame-him/">I blame him</a></span> for <span style="text-decoration:underline;"><a href="http://meizac.wordpress.com/2012/08/21/here-it-is/">this</a></span>. As with any relationship, I know I have to take responsibility for my own shortcomings, and I do. They pale in comparison to what he did to me; what he did to us.</p>
<p>And why does it still have to hurt so much?</p>
<p>When will it stop hurting?</p>
<p>Without question, I am over him. I no longer love him. I haven&#8217;t for a long time. I do not hate him. It would not bother me in the least if I never spoke to or saw him again. (Of course, this can&#8217;t happen (and I won&#8217;t allow it to happen), because we have Z and M.)</p>
<p>What I am not over is how much he hurt me. He&#8217;s not only hurt me, he&#8217;s hurt me in such a way as to have a long-term impact on any and all relationships I may have. He&#8217;s hurt me in such a way as to have a long-term impact on any and all relationships I already have.</p>
<p>When I need to talk to or just be in the presence of someone the most, I can&#8217;t bear the thought of it. I can&#8217;t bear the thought of confiding in someone else.</p>
<p>The depth of the pain is too much to bear.</p>
<p>When will it stop hurting?</p>
<p>When will I be able to return to some version of the woman I was before this?</p>
<p>I thought I was getting better. I mean, I&#8217;ve told the story of what happened to so many people these past few months, and I&#8217;ve done it nearly every time without feeling anything. Like it was just something that happened. That, sure, it was a big deal at the time, but I&#8217;m good now. In fact, I told the story to someone today, and I was fine.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m not fine.</p>
<p>I came home to relieve him from his childcare responsibilities, so he could go back to his place, and we, of course, got into an argument. He was angry with me about something. I can&#8217;t even remember what. Then, he made me feel like hell about all the time I&#8217;ve been away from the kids lately (even if I am still with them more than he is) because of work and school.</p>
<p>Then, I was sorting through some things looking for items to donate to the local women&#8217;s shelter, and I came across all the e-mails, letters and receipts from seven years ago. (I had them tucked away in case I need them when it comes time to get into all the legal stuff.)</p>
<p>I forgot they were there.</p>
<p>I immediately broke down.</p>
<p>I didn&#8217;t even need to read them (and I didn&#8217;t).</p>
<p>Sunk to the floor and started sobbing.</p>
<p>Haven&#8217;t stopped crying, actually.</p>
<p>I can barely see through the tears as I write this.</p>
<p>And, as much as I need to talk to someone, I don&#8217;t feel I can.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s no one close by that I either trust enough or is in a position for me to bother with my stuff. And, for the couple of friends I do trust (but who aren&#8217;t in a position for me to bother them), when does it stop? Even if I did call them or ask them to come and just sit with me, when is enough enough?</p>
<p>It doesn&#8217;t matter how much I try, I still cannot put to words exactly how deeply I feel the humiliation of him telling other people the most intimate details of our life, in explicit detail&#8230;so they could spit them back at me or so I could read about them in e-mail exchanges.</p>
<p>It doesn&#8217;t matter how much I try, I still cannot put to words exactly how deeply I feel the betrayal&#8230;after he managed to break down the walls to get me to trust him; to get me to declare him &#8220;the best person I know,&#8221; when someone asked why I was marrying him.</p>
<p>I doesn&#8217;t matter how much I try, I still cannot put to words exactly how deeply it all hurts.</p>
<p>I often feel like I&#8217;ll never fully recover from this.</p>
<p>Why does it still have to hurt so much?</p>
<p>When does it stop hurting?</p>
<p>And why does it make everything else that hurts hurt so much more?</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3873/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3873/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3873&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://meizac.wordpress.com/2012/12/02/why-does-it-still-have-to-hurt-so-much/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>29</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/ac9ead918b48cb52f835893f338c5217?s=96&#38;d=monsterid&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">meizac</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Who Killed Jovan Belcher? Professional Sports and Emotional Illness</title>
		<link>http://samepageteam.com/2012/12/05/who-killed-jovan-belcher-professional-sports-and-emotional-illness/</link>
		<comments>http://samepageteam.com/2012/12/05/who-killed-jovan-belcher-professional-sports-and-emotional-illness/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 12:36:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>samepageteam</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Football]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[athletes committing crimes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emotional health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[football]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jovan Belcher]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mental illness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NFL]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rae Carruth]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://samepageteam.com/?p=1827</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[By: Chris Dagonas Jovan Belcher and Rae Carruth.  These are two of the many professional athletes who have killed a loved one.  Their stories, though not exactly parallel, bring up an issue that is often ignored when professional athletes commit atrocities.  Namely, does the culture of sports prevent young men from committing crimes, or does [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1827&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://samepageteam.com/2012/12/05/who-killed-jovan-belcher-professional-sports-and-emotional-illness/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a639e164b412a2de4f29a6f74e48fb89?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">samepageteam</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://samepageteam.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/unknown.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Jovan Belcher</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://samepageteam.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/images.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Rae Carruth</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://samepageteam.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/images1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Belcher&#039;s Bentley towed from the grisly scene</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://samepageteam.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/unknown1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Carruth, as a Federal Prisoner</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lend a Hand</title>
		<link>http://petearmetta.com/2012/12/03/lend-a-hand-pete-armetta/</link>
		<comments>http://petearmetta.com/2012/12/03/lend-a-hand-pete-armetta/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2012 21:14:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Pete Armetta</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Poetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[encouragement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[help]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hot shower]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lend a hand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pete armetta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-reliance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smoke]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tough love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tough times]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://petearmetta.com/?p=5015</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[you could come take a nap then a hot shower too and of course i will make you a meal take some time to relax but i&#8217;m sorry i can&#8217;t really do more beyond all of that the rest you&#8217;re gotta do for yourself we could go have some fun take a ride around town [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=5015&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://petearmetta.com/2012/12/03/lend-a-hand-pete-armetta/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>21</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://petearmetta.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/lendahand.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://petearmetta.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/lendahand.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lendahand</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/19463e7c5bfb0b61f956fa234d2983f8?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">armetta</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://petearmetta.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/lendahand1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lendahand</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Doubleplusungood</title>
		<link>http://themercenaryresearcher.wordpress.com/2012/12/03/doubleplusungood/</link>
		<comments>http://themercenaryresearcher.wordpress.com/2012/12/03/doubleplusungood/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2012 12:10:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Rutabaga the Mercenary Researcher</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Language]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Philosophy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Random Thoughts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Words]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[1984]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dictionary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[George Orwell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[language]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newspeak]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plusgood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plusungood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[words]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://themercenaryresearcher.wordpress.com/?p=579</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I admit it – I’m a word nerd; derived from the Latin Dictum Nerdica.  I’m also a Grammar Geek (ok, ok Grammaticus Geekicus). I think I was the only kid in 7th grade typing English that liked to diagram sentences.  My typing sucked but I could spot an appositive a mile away. I’m fond of adjectives, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=579&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I admit it – I’m a <b>word nerd</b>; derived from the Latin <i>Dictum Nerdica</i>.  I’m also a <b>Grammar Geek</b> (ok, ok <i>Grammaticus Geekicus). </i>I think I was the only kid in 7<sup>th</sup> grade typing English that <b>liked </b>to diagram sentences.  My typing sucked but I could spot an appositive a mile away.</p>
<div id="attachment_580" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 305px"><a href="http://themercenaryresearcher.wordpress.com/2012/12/03/doubleplusungood/wordnerd/" rel="attachment wp-att-580"><img class="size-large wp-image-580" alt="Credit: http://www.someecards.com" src="http://themercenaryresearcher.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/wordnerd.jpg?w=295&#038;h=212" height="212" width="295" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Credit: http://www.someecards.com</p></div>
<p>I’m fond of adjectives, adverbs, nouns, verbs, gerunds, prepositions etc. (Please be advised: I don’t quite trust the subjunctive case, however). Our lexicon is rich with variety – we have so much freedom to express ourselves using layers of meaning, double entendre, metaphor, subtle shades of description; we have synonyms abound to choose from; we have slang – we have it all.  Yet we also have this:</p>
<p><i>I don’t understand why we have to have so many words to describe something- why can’t we just have the one and be done?</i></p>
<p><i>Why do you have to use such big words? Do you think you’re better than me? </i></p>
<p>I want to rip my hair from my head and run screaming at these sentiments.  Why would anyone want to relegate themselves to a limited vocabulary? Who wants to live with the choice of <a title="Newspeak" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Newspeak" target="_blank">plusgood </a> or <a title="Newspeak" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Newspeak" target="_blank">plusungood</a>*? I do not.  I need words – I love words. I love to collect them, pore over them, roll them around in my mind until I find the precise word to express exactly how I’m feeling or the message I want to convey.  And I often misuse words, at times to my chagrin, but there’s a lesson to be learned in that as well. It takes a little courage to use a new word. We are all of us vulnerable when trying out a new skill – and like many things, it takes practice before we feel truly confident.</p>
<div id="attachment_581" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 532px"><a href="http://themercenaryresearcher.wordpress.com/2012/12/03/doubleplusungood/words/" rel="attachment wp-att-581"><img class="size-large wp-image-581" alt="Interesting words ~ Photo Credit: http://djmorel.com/2010/06/09/a-caboodle-of-fancy-words-from-the-new-york-times/" src="http://themercenaryresearcher.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/words.jpg?w=522&#038;h=295" height="295" width="522" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Interesting words ~<br />Photo Credit: http://djmorel.com/2010/06/09/a-caboodle-of-fancy-words-from-the-new-york-times/</p></div>
<p>I also love sharing words – I want you to find delight in a new word. I don’t want to obfuscate with words &#8211; I want to open up a window to something new.  But you might think “I don’t know that word – it intimidates me”.  Words do not intimidate; they just are – they may be new and unfamiliar but you always have the ability to rectify the situation from ‘the unknown’ to ‘the known’.   A dictionary is a beautiful reference tool.</p>
<p>And never be afraid to inquire about the meaning of word. It does not imply ignorance – it shows a willingness to expand one’s mind and absorb something new. It means someone is listening to what is being said and desires to learn the meaning.   It expands one’s world as well.  My son is never shy about asking the meaning of an unfamiliar word – he never feels intimidated by ‘big’ words – it is that child-like wonder and curiosity that allows his mind to grow and take in new experiences. Adults need that too.   I firmly believe that the more we are willing to explore knowledge unknown to us the more we are open to new ideas. If I choose to limit myself to 4 adjectives, for example – my world is that much narrower and my mind that much more closed to anything that is not covered by those 4 adjectives.  I may not be willing to accept something unknown or different because I have made myself believe that ‘not knowing’ is equated to admitting ‘ignorance’ or I’ve convinced myself that the other person thinks they are superior to me.  This is just not so -</p>
<p>I’m not denying that people use language to obscure meaning – however, many people take wonderful things and use them for a nasty purpose – but we shouldn’t blame words when clearly the bloviating idiot uttering them is at fault.  I sincerely hope that when I use language in a playful manner that people are not thinking that I’m showing off or trying to make them feel dull &#8211; I’m just writing that which tickles my fancy.  I’m a huge fan of an awkward turn of phrase and arcane words.</p>
<p>Where am I going with all this? I don’t know – I just wanted to talk about words and how much I love them and how I think about them…Expressing these random thoughts makes me less <a title="Go on - look it up - " href="http://dictionary.reverso.net/english-definition/fratchy" target="_blank">fratchy</a> (It’s ok – you can look it up, I had to as well – I hope you like it…it’s become a favorite of mine).</p>
<p>If you’re interested &#8211; this is one of my favorite daily emails: <a title="MMMMMMMM....Words....." href="http://www.wordsmith.org/awad/" target="_blank">A Word a Day</a>; if not – that’s ok too.</p>
<p>Do you, per chance, have a favorite word?<br />
________________________________________________________________</p>
<p><i>*1984 ~ George Orwell….haven’t read it? It&#8217;s a good read – </i></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/579/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/579/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=579&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://themercenaryresearcher.wordpress.com/2012/12/03/doubleplusungood/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>101</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/87b78f47e0214c64a740123d3c69d105?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F2.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">rutabagamercenaryresearcher</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://themercenaryresearcher.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/wordnerd.jpg?w=295" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Credit: http://www.someecards.com</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://themercenaryresearcher.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/words.jpg?w=522" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Interesting words ~ Photo Credit: http://djmorel.com/2010/06/09/a-caboodle-of-fancy-words-from-the-new-york-times/</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dress Me in Lace and Awkwardness</title>
		<link>http://psychobabblepants.wordpress.com/2012/11/28/dress-me-in-lace-and-awkwardness/</link>
		<comments>http://psychobabblepants.wordpress.com/2012/11/28/dress-me-in-lace-and-awkwardness/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2012 04:57:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lyssapants</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blind dates]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boutique]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Charlotte's Web]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[colonoscopy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ebay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[firefighters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gown]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[milk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[My Big Fat Greek Wedding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Oprah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poop jokes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[underwear]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wedding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wedding dress]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://psychobabblepants.wordpress.com/?p=1396</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Shopping for a wedding dress is awkward. vulnerable. Fucking scary. First of all, they make you write all of your identifying information down on a pretty piece of paper.  They even ask where you keep all your porn, so you know they really have you by the ladyballs. Each boutique is different on purpose, because [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1396&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Shopping for a wedding dress is awkward. vulnerable. Fucking scary.<br />
First of all, they make you write all of your identifying information down on a pretty piece of paper.  They even ask where you keep all your porn, so you know they really have you by the ladyballs.</p>
<p>Each boutique is different on purpose, because <em>they</em> don&#8217;t want you to get too comfortable.  Who are <em>they</em>, you ask?  <em>They</em> are the The Powers That Be.  The bridal industry.  Those doctors who insist you get an exploratory colonoscopy &#8220;just to rule some things out.&#8221;</p>
<p>What do I mean by <em>different</em>?  I mean that all the rules change, bro.  In one place I was allowed to paw through the gowns like my cat paws through a pile of dead rodents.  <em>Expensive albino</em> rodents.  And in another place I wasn&#8217;t allowed to touch anything.  Indeed, I couldn&#8217;t even scratch my own ladyball without my <del>keeper</del> attendant yelling at me and swatting my hand away.</p>
<p>Another variable involves <em>unmentionables</em>.  When I first went dress shopping, I didn&#8217;t know what to expect, and so I made sure I wore my best skivvies with minimal amounts of unsightly holes and skid marks, just to be safe.  You know, I even removed my leg hair and made sure my head hair was in socially acceptable condition.  The preparation that went into this expedition wasn&#8217;t unlike the grooming needed for a blind date where you were promised some <del>second base action</del> good conversation.</p>
<p>Once I was half naked in front of huge mirrors and cold because I was missing all my winter leg fuzz, I had to actually put some dresses on.  Getting into a dress was like trying to claw my way up through an igloo that had collapsed on top of me.  I could feel my world closing in on me.  It was hard to breathe.  My arms were stuck up over my head, groping through endless, fluffy white matter.  I could hear my attendant, just barely, reassure me from the other side.  <em>Don&#8217;t worry</em>, she said, <em>I&#8217;ll get you out.  Even if I have to </em>cut<em> you out!  </em></p>
<p>I requested that if she couldn&#8217;t get me out to please refrain from cutting of any kind and call <a href="https://psychobabblepants.wordpress.com/2012/11/02/vote-with-me-baby-one-more-time/">some hot firefighters to sexily rip me out.  And have some cold glasses of milk ready and waiting</a>.  At that point, who needs a bachelorette party, amirite?</p>
<p>Once I emerged with a second degree tulle-burn from the white abyss, a complicated pattern of zipping, tugging, lacing, and clamping ensued.  For a moment I was not sure if I felt more like Kate Winslet in Titanic when her mom is doing up her corset and reminding her -yet again- that the money&#8217;s all gone, or if I felt more like the stuffing in a Thanksgiving turkey.  Eh, the latter involves more butter so I&#8217;ll go with that.</p>
<p>Then I was made to stand there displayed on a platform while people took my picture and commented on various parts of my body as if I were that amazingly tasty-looking pig from Charlotte&#8217;s Web.  And don&#8217;t get me wrong, because I <em>am</em> rather tasty, but where the hell is my motherly, not-at-all-creepy, talking spider who is supposed to save me from torture and almost certain death?!  You and your web of <em>lies</em>!</p>
<p>Taking all this into account, I am somehow supposed to have an opinion about which dress<del> I like the best</del> doesn&#8217;t make me look like a <a href="http://www.film.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/08/fat-greek-wedding-2-250-1345063817.jpg">Big Fat Greek sparkly snowstorm</a>.  There are so many things to take into account.  It&#8217;s gotta be slutty, but not <em>too</em> slutty.  Pure and chaste, but not <em>too</em> pure and chaste.  It&#8217;s a delicate balance. And remember, all this is provided the dress costs less than what Oprah&#8217;s &#8220;s&#8221; shaped poop goes for on eBay.</p>
<p>So there you have it.  I feel like a poor barnyard animal lost in a snowstorm.  With no firefighter milk and no under the shirt action in the car on the way home from that cheap restaurant with the colorful crap on the walls because Blind Date Man &#8220;thought it would be fun.&#8221;</p>
<p>I must be a masochist, because even after all this, I am still going back for more.  I have an appointment at yet another new boutique for a week from Sunday.</p>
<p>Wish me luck!</p>
<br /> Tagged: <a href='http://psychobabblepants.wordpress.com/tag/blind-dates/'>blind dates</a>, <a href='http://psychobabblepants.wordpress.com/tag/boutique/'>boutique</a>, <a href='http://psychobabblepants.wordpress.com/tag/charlottes-web/'>Charlotte's Web</a>, <a href='http://psychobabblepants.wordpress.com/tag/colonoscopy/'>colonoscopy</a>, <a href='http://psychobabblepants.wordpress.com/tag/ebay/'>Ebay</a>, <a href='http://psychobabblepants.wordpress.com/tag/firefighters/'>firefighters</a>, <a href='http://psychobabblepants.wordpress.com/tag/gown/'>gown</a>, <a href='http://psychobabblepants.wordpress.com/tag/humor/'>humor</a>, <a href='http://psychobabblepants.wordpress.com/tag/milk/'>milk</a>, <a href='http://psychobabblepants.wordpress.com/tag/my-big-fat-greek-wedding/'>My Big Fat Greek Wedding</a>, <a href='http://psychobabblepants.wordpress.com/tag/oprah/'>Oprah</a>, <a href='http://psychobabblepants.wordpress.com/tag/poop-jokes/'>poop jokes</a>, <a href='http://psychobabblepants.wordpress.com/tag/underwear/'>underwear</a>, <a href='http://psychobabblepants.wordpress.com/tag/wedding/'>wedding</a>, <a href='http://psychobabblepants.wordpress.com/tag/wedding-dress/'>wedding dress</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1396/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1396/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1396&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://psychobabblepants.wordpress.com/2012/11/28/dress-me-in-lace-and-awkwardness/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>44</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/e33d3ca47f05c9fdfacb2c8bf9b77ade?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lyssapants</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>No, Our Son Doesn’t Have Leukemia. He’s Autistic and Took Dexedrine.</title>
		<link>http://lifeandink.com/2012/12/05/no-our-son-doesnt-have-leukemia-hes-autistic-and-took-dexedrine/</link>
		<comments>http://lifeandink.com/2012/12/05/no-our-son-doesnt-have-leukemia-hes-autistic-and-took-dexedrine/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 13:20:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Life&#38;Ink</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Aspergers: General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aspergers: The Preschool Years]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aspergers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Autism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dexedrine in an autistic child]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[medication]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[motherhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parenting special needs children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[special needs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ted]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://lifeandink.com/?p=9339</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Medicine. Good grief. It&#8217;s the topic I have yet to mention, even once, in the 14 months I have been writing about Ted and our journey with Aspergers. Until now. For eight years we put prescription pharmaceuticals in our child&#8217;s body. There. I said it. And for eight years we wondered, did all those syrups, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=9339&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://lifeandink.com/2012/12/05/no-our-son-doesnt-have-leukemia-hes-autistic-and-took-dexedrine/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>33</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/52e9aec1fa7db61194692bf9af12db45?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mylifeandink</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lifeandinkdotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/polaroid-beach-teddy1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Polaroid beach Teddy</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Aging Facefully</title>
		<link>http://lifeintheboomerlane.wordpress.com/2012/12/05/aging-facefully/</link>
		<comments>http://lifeintheboomerlane.wordpress.com/2012/12/05/aging-facefully/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 15:01:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Life in the Boomer Lane</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[aging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[baby boomers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boomer humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boomers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[celebrity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[celebrity news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commentary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fame]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women over 50]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[baby boomer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[celebs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[facial aging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Goldie Hawn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[looking younger than one's age]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[observation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[older actresses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women of a certain age]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://lifeintheboomerlane.wordpress.com/?p=4609</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A favorite activity of celeb mags, when they aren’t detailing Taylor Swift’s boyfriend du jour or the imminent break up and/or marriage of Brad Pitt and Angelina Jolie, is to haul out photos of older actresses and to shriek “More beautiful than ever!” “Never ages!” “What is her Secret?” “These Older Actresses Get Hotter Every [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4609&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://lifeintheboomerlane.wordpress.com/2012/12/05/aging-facefully/goldie/" rel="attachment wp-att-4610"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-4610" alt="goldie" src="http://lifeintheboomerlane.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/goldie.jpg?w=300&#038;h=250" height="250" width="300" /></a></p>
<p><strong>A favorite activity of celeb mags, when they aren’t detailing Taylor Swift’s boyfriend du jour or the imminent break up and/or marriage of Brad Pitt and Angelina Jolie, is to haul out photos of older actresses and to shriek “More beautiful than ever!” “Never ages!” “What is her Secret?” “These Older Actresses Get Hotter Every Year!”</strong></p>
<p><strong>A favorite subject is Goldie Hawn.  In photo after photo, throughout the years, she flashes before our eyes. </strong> An adorable and hot twenty-something.  An adorable and hot thirty-something.  An adorable and hot forty-something. An adorable and hot fifty-something.  An adorable and hot sixty-something (67, to be exact).</p>
<p><strong>So it may come as a shock to some of us to have seen the latest photo of La Goldie in all her natural 67-year-old glory. </strong> Sans personal make up artist.  Sans personal hair stylist.  And most of all, in the moment, as opposed to fixing her facial expression to be camera-ready.  (If any of you have ever been out in the world and pass by a mirror unexpectedly,  you may know what I mean).</p>
<p><strong>Let’s get real here</strong>. Goldie Hawn is a great looking woman.  But she isn’t a great looking 30-year-old.  She is a great looking 67-year-old.  She has “good bones.” She works hard to maintain her body and she has, at her disposal any number of cosmetic procedures to help keep her face in line and her lips out of line.  But age is age. And cellular structure, whether it resides in the bodies of the most humble or the most famous, obeys natural law.  It is oblivious to how famous, how rich, how entitled, how desperate we may be.</p>
<p><strong>By elevating Goldie Hawn (and Demi Moore and Sophia Loren and Helen Mirren) to a category that defies natural law is to demean the age that they are.</strong>  Can we just acknowledge that Goldie Hawn is a great looking woman, period, without comparing her to a chronological age she left in the dust decades ago?</p>
<p><strong>And while we are at it, let’s bring this down to Real World level</strong>.  Let’s compliment/support each other, not by saying inane things like, “You look ten years younger than your age!” but instead to “You are a fabulous looking women.”  If I hear one more woman tell me that everyone she knows thinks she looks ten years younger than her age, I might spit.</p>
<p><strong>Now back to the photo that started all the fuss</strong>.  It’s Goldie, looking like she is headed to or away from the gym.  She is wearing a form-fitting tank top (I stopped wearing those in 1992).  Her hair is long and healthy (Damn her).  She is looking down (never the best view of anyone’s face, over age 12).  Her facial sags and wrinkles are on full view.  Give the woman a break.</p>
<p><strong>Now Husband is enamored of taking photos of me, in the moment, that would put Goldie’s photo to shame</strong>. He thinks it’s funny.  I think his camera is on borrowed time. I have no issue with morning hair (which does defy natural law) or seeing my face without make up (it’s how it looks most of the time, anyway.)  I do have an issue with seeing myself without a smile on my face.  I’ve noticed that the older I get, the bigger my smile is in photos.  This means that either I’m happier with life as the years go by, or that I’ve realized that smiling is a natural face lift. Or  maybe both.</p>
<p><strong>Here’s to you, Goldie</strong>.  You rock. If I hit the gym regularly for two years and spend hours pumping iron, will I be able to wear a tank top like yours at age 67?  Alas, I’ll never find out. I’m too lazy. But I will keep reminding myself to walk around with a perpetual smile on my face.</p>
<p>Say “cheese.”  Just don’t eat it.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4609/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4609/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4609&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://lifeintheboomerlane.wordpress.com/2012/12/05/aging-facefully/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>133</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/0b4e511d50588658c1d660b6f54b5d99?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lifeintheboomerlane</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lifeintheboomerlane.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/goldie.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">goldie</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sucking the Life Out Of the Holidays</title>
		<link>http://yeahandanotherthing.com/2012/11/27/sucking-the-life-out-of-the-holidays/</link>
		<comments>http://yeahandanotherthing.com/2012/11/27/sucking-the-life-out-of-the-holidays/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2012 17:56:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Susan</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crazypants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[holiday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[on being southern]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[porches]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ranting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thanksgiving]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://yeahandanotherthing.com/?p=2216</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[You know how you think your family is crazy? You’re right. They are. You are the only sane one and you’re pushing the rock of sagacity uphill. Both ways. In the snow. Give in. Just give in. There’s a yard sign I’ve seen around the internet that says something to the effect of how in [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2216&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://yeahandanotherthing.com/2012/11/27/sucking-the-life-out-of-the-holidays/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>43</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/6c67ecb2da8a0dee330e07f423035e28?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">snw71201</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://yeahandanotherthing.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/jingle-birds.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jingle birds</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>I Will Never Be Classy</title>
		<link>http://essaalroc.com/2012/12/04/i-will-never-be-classy/</link>
		<comments>http://essaalroc.com/2012/12/04/i-will-never-be-classy/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 02:37:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>essaalroc</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comedy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ebooks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://essaalroc.com/?p=992</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A few weeks back, I did a post bemoaning my inability to write a sex scene. At the time, I considered it one of the very rare areas of difficulty for me…at least in writing. I’m mainly bad at everything else I do. Dating, parenting, parallel parking, doing that thing with your thumb where it [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=992&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A few weeks back, I did a post bemoaning my inability to <a title="I Can’t Write a Sex Scene" href="http://essaalroc.com/2012/11/08/i-cant-write-a-sex-scene/">write a sex scene</a>. At the time, I considered it one of the very rare areas of difficulty for me…at least in writing. I’m mainly bad at everything else I do. Dating, parenting, parallel parking, doing that thing with your thumb where it looks like you’re taking it off but you’re really not, pretty much everything is an ‘area of opportunity for me’. Except for writing. I always thought I was ok at writing.</p>
<p>Then today, I had to turn down a job. Why? Because I was incapable of doing the writing required for it. The subject matter? G-rated humor.</p>
<p>In the past, I worked for this company that runs a clever little website. You upload a photo, it uploads a caption for the photo. They hired me before to create those captions. It was actually a really fun job. 100 snarky, mean and sarcastic one liners. As I am the queen of caustic one liners, I whipped those things off like it was nothing. They were very pleased with my work and a little frightened of me as a person.</p>
<p>Then, they asked me to do it again. But this time, no snark. Instead, these captions would be for parents and grandparents needing baby picture captions and whatnot.  “Sure,” I said. “I can do G-rated. How hard can it be?”</p>
<p>Famous last words.</p>
<p>Today, I spent 2 hours (not even exaggerating) staring at a photo of a cute little baby boy with a sad face. I stared and I waited for inspiration…and waited…and waited. Oh and inspiration came, but it came in the form of my true, blue-style humor. Every thought that came to me was a mean quip about how annoying children are, about drunk babies, about breast feeding, about people who breastfeed for way to long. Then I thought about how ugly this kid was getting the longer I looked at him. Nothing clean. Nothing nice. All hilarious. The things I said about that baby in my head today will haunt me to my grave…and also make me chuckle a little. Then, I pictured the horrified look on some grandmother’s face as her adorable grandson&#8217;s picture was plastered with the caption “Stupid broken condom!!!” and I chuckled even more.</p>
<p>I am a terrible person.</p>
<p>I never thought that I would run into an area so large that I was incapable of writing about. Just as I was working thought my sex scene issues, with the help of a large amount of tequila and many, many photos of Julian McMahon,  I ran into an entire genre that isn’t just difficult for me to write. It’s impossible.</p>
<p>Here’s the thing; I was born a cynic. When my parents took me to see E.T., two year old Essa stormed out while everyone was sobbing, declaring that it was ‘sappy bullshit’. I don’t get the warm fuzzies. I don’t believe in happy endings (unless they are the kind you get at an unlicensed massage parlor) and I flinch if someone mentions feelings. It was how I was designed. For the most part, it’s done ok for me. Then this happens.</p>
<p>I’d like to say I’m going to work on it, but I probably won’t, because I know it’s a futile task. I will never be classy and I will never be clean. I will always be wrapped in a hard shell of cynicism and I will never giggle over baby shoes or tell a joke suitable for a church picnic. Even if I tried, it would all ring false and it wouldn’t be funny, it would just be sad.</p>
<p>Some of my favorite authors are clean. I absolutely love Dave Barry, but I could never be like him. His posts are family friendly and I am the exact opposite. I’m for ‘restricted audiences’. I’m the girl you don’t invite to the wedding because she gets in a drunken fight. I’m the girl you don’t ask to come to the funeral, because crying skeeves me out. I’m the girl that doesn’t get an invitation to the baby shower, because at the last one, I gave the expectant mother a pack of cigarettes and a bottle of gin. I am not ‘family friendly’. I am ‘family enemy’ and there is really nothing I can do but embrace it.</p>
<p>God bless those who appreciate blue humor.</p>
<p>***On another note, not related to my suckish writing, I released a novella today that is wildly inappropriate, filled with profanity, but lacks the sex scene that I am not yet comfortable enough to write. You can check out my new book, The Apology, <a href="http://www.amazon.com/The-Apology-ebook/dp/B00AHI5R8K">here</a>.***</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/992/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/992/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=992&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://essaalroc.com/2012/12/04/i-will-never-be-classy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>56</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/00d56b05769400e11d086fb8586227e6?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">essaalroc</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
