<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2013 20:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>The Only Thing Worse Than a Disney Princess is a Disney Prince</title>
		<link>http://allisms.wordpress.com/2012/12/30/the-only-thing-worse-than-a-disney-princess-is-a-disney-prince/</link>
		<comments>http://allisms.wordpress.com/2012/12/30/the-only-thing-worse-than-a-disney-princess-is-a-disney-prince/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 03:35:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>thegrapefruitspoon</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Gender]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[disney]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gender roles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prince]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[princess]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[relationships]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://allisms.wordpress.com/?p=94</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[But seriously, y&#8217;all. The traditional Disney Prince has about as much sparkle and panache as something completely lacking in sparkle and panache. He has  a creative name like &#8220;The Prince&#8221; &#8220;Prince Charming&#8221; &#8220;Prince Phillip&#8221; &#8220;Prince Eric&#8221; or &#8220;Prince Adam&#8221; (that&#8217;s the actual name of the Beast, apparently), and no personality. Ok, well, the Beast has [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=94&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>But seriously, y&#8217;all.</p>
<p>The traditional Disney Prince has about as much sparkle and panache as something completely lacking in sparkle and panache. He has  a creative name like &#8220;The Prince&#8221; &#8220;Prince Charming&#8221; &#8220;Prince Phillip&#8221; &#8220;Prince Eric&#8221; or &#8220;Prince Adam&#8221; (that&#8217;s the actual name of the Beast, apparently), and no personality. Ok, well, the Beast has a personality, but the only thing anyone else does is be obsessively fixated on some girl he met once in the woods.</p>
<p>Has anyone ever thought that maybe the reason that little boys (generally) don&#8217;t like playing princess games is because there&#8217;s nothing for them to DO? What prince is actually interesting enough that a little boy would want to dress up like him? What prince actually does anything that a little boy (or anyone for that matter) would want to do? Hey, Mom, today I&#8217;m going to roleplay as Prince Charming. I will stand stiffly in a corner and watch my minion put shoes on women. Then I will be Prince Eric and float on some driftwood. Then I will be an abusive alcoholic, sorry, I mean, I will be the Beast.</p>
<p>I mean, yeah, there&#8217;s a couple of cool fights, but mostly being a Prince is about being in the right place at the right time with a willing pair of lips. It&#8217;s about falling in &#8220;love&#8221;for no reason. It&#8217;s about being a plot point, a blank slate, a projection screen. These men don&#8217;t have journeys or emotional arcs (or emotions), they just have thrones, pretty faces, and nothing else to do with their time. Their only reason for existence is to save the girl, so what are they supposed to do when the girl no longer needs saving? Talk to her? (Seriously, does anyone else find it disturbing that when Eric falls in love with Ariel, she is MUTE?)</p>
<p>Stupid message #1: Little girls, these shallow men with no personalities deserve to be loved for no other reason than that they are <strong>there.</strong></p>
<p>Stupid message #2: Little boys, the way you get to be loved is to be a shallow man with no personality who does <strong>the &#8220;right&#8221; things. </strong></p>
<p>Why, hello there, Nice Guy Syndrome!</p>
<p>Stupid message #3: The way for little boys to find meaning in their lives is to save a woman. Woman=answer to your life problems.</p>
<p>Stupid message #4: <strong>Men don&#8217;t need to be saved. </strong></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/94/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/94/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=94&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://allisms.wordpress.com/2012/12/30/the-only-thing-worse-than-a-disney-princess-is-a-disney-prince/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/9b0b26b86a8132c417078350c626abc3?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">thegrapefruitspoon</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Peeling Back the Layers of the Watercolor Still Life</title>
		<link>http://davidtripp.wordpress.com/2013/01/01/peeling-back-the-layers-of-the-watercolor-still-life/</link>
		<comments>http://davidtripp.wordpress.com/2013/01/01/peeling-back-the-layers-of-the-watercolor-still-life/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 14:10:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>davidtripp</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[nostalgia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[watercolor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Art I]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[charcoal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hemingway]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Imagism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Proust]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robie Scucchi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[still life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[William Carlos Williams]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://davidtripp.wordpress.com/?p=3044</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Ernest Hemingway could not write about Michigan until he was in Paris, and could not write about Paris until he had returned to the United States.  On this first day of the New Year, I am returning to my ninth grade in House Springs Missouri, at Northwest High School.  In Proustlike fashion, this still life [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3044&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_3038" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 460px"><a href="http://davidtripp.wordpress.com/2012/12/31/final-art-studio-posting-of-2012-watercolor-still-life-still-growing/new-year-final/" rel="attachment wp-att-3038"><img class="size-full wp-image-3038" alt="Watercolor Still Life in the Man Cave" src="http://davidtripp.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/new-year-final.jpg?w=590"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Watercolor Still Life in the Man Cave</p></div>
<p>Ernest Hemingway could not write about Michigan until he was in Paris, and could not write about Paris until he had returned to the United States.  On this first day of the New Year, I am returning to my ninth grade in House Springs Missouri, at Northwest High School.  In Proustlike fashion, this still life with the kerosene lantern is transporting me back to my Art I class, period 1, when we walked into class and saw a collection of at least fifteen objects assembled in the middle of the classroom, and the table arranged in a circle about the perimeter.  Each of us was given a full-size sheet of newsprint paper (perhaps 18 x 24&#8243;), a charcoal pencil, a blending stump and a kneaded eraser.</p>
<p>Immediately, a girl protested: &#8220;Mr. Scucchi, I cannot fit all that on this paper!&#8221; Coolly, the teacher replied: &#8220;Did you ever draw a house?&#8221;  Discussion over.  Time to draw.</p>
<p><em>At college there was an ancient Greek vase on the table in the seminar room where our class in Greek was held.  Fresh from Michigan, I had never seen anything before with lines so simple and yet so beautiful, and I marveled at it day after day.  In those hours of a student&#8217;s trancelike wonder there was born the resolve, unconscious at first, to go to Greece.  </em></p>
<p>The Art I students would sit before this giant still life for three weeks, fifteen instructional periods.  And in those periods, I became lost in wonder at the kerosene lantern, the focal point (for me) to this immense pile of objects that included a jug, a Ruffino wine bottle with straw bottom, corn scoop, football helmet, antique water pump, bricks and drapery.</p>
<p>With charcoal pencil and blending stump, I became absorbed with the textures of the kerosene lantern, the complications of a smoky globe with highlights and scratches and thin wires wound about it, the rusted and pitted armature catching highlights and absorbing shadows, the thinness of the bail that arced above the lantern, and the issues of rendering this delicate piece of iron with charcoal as it presented itself as a string of highlights, mid-tones and shadows.  I realize now that, as a ninth-grader, I was not as dull as I and my peers had regarded me.  It is a certainty that I was not academically astute or interested, but during those days I realized that I was visually alert and interested in these objects.</p>
<p>No Ideas but in Things.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3044/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3044/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3044&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://davidtripp.wordpress.com/2013/01/01/peeling-back-the-layers-of-the-watercolor-still-life/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>18</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f762cf3603560fa677c6f92da3c2691a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">davidtripp</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://davidtripp.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/new-year-final.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Watercolor Still Life in the Man Cave</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cultural Dynamics: Love and Marriage</title>
		<link>http://incipientideas.wordpress.com/2013/01/01/cultural-dynamics-love-and-marriage/</link>
		<comments>http://incipientideas.wordpress.com/2013/01/01/cultural-dynamics-love-and-marriage/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 16:14:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>incipientideas</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thoughts]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://incipientideas.wordpress.com/?p=204</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[My parents are married. They have the legal papers to prove it. They&#8217;re yellowed and old like antique documents and they&#8217;re in Chinese. They file for taxes together, sign property papers together, make mortgage payments together, have joint bank accounts. They call themselves husband and wife, if asked. They don&#8217;t fight&#8230; much. They get along [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=204&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;"><img class="aligncenter" alt="" src="http://manwifeanddog.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/marriage-cartoon-proposal.jpg" width="448" height="244" /></p>
<p>My parents are married.</p>
<p>They have the legal papers to prove it. They&#8217;re yellowed and old like antique documents and they&#8217;re in Chinese.</p>
<p>They file for taxes together, sign property papers together, make mortgage payments together, have joint bank accounts.</p>
<p>They call themselves husband and wife, if asked.</p>
<p>They don&#8217;t fight&#8230; much.</p>
<p>They get along and even though sometimes he rolls his eyes when he thinks she&#8217;s being a little insensible or silly and sometimes she&#8217;ll sigh with frustration when she thinks he&#8217;s being lazy and unhelpful, they don&#8217;t <em>really</em> fight.</p>
<p>They raised us well. Amazingly well, I&#8217;d say, and for that, I am grateful. My dad taught me how to sharpen my work ethic, how to prioritize and be practical, how to do complicated physics problems that my teacher in high school never made clear. My mom taught me how to be sympathetic, how to care for people and how to care a little too much sometimes, how to be stubborn and how to take care of myself.</p>
<p>They do not kiss. I&#8217;ve only seen them kiss once- New Year&#8217;s Eve two years ago when Ryan Seacrest was counting down with the rest of Times Square and all the kids egged the parents on- &#8220;Kiss! Kiss! You have to, it&#8217;s gonna be midnight!&#8221;- and they finally gave in and did it. Briefly. A quick peck. And &#8220;gave in&#8221; being the key words.</p>
<p>Are they in love? I don&#8217;t know.</p>
<p>When I was younger, I used to badger them with questions about how they met, how he proposed, what their wedding was like. I was a starry-eyed romantic at a young age and I wanted to know.</p>
<p>Their answers?</p>
<p><em>We were introduced.<br />
</em><em>He just asked.<br />
</em><em>Not too big.<br />
</em></p>
<p>I drank those answers in like cough medicine. Reluctantly. As a kid growing up with ideals of happily ever afters, how was I supposed to accept that my parents didn&#8217;t fall hopelessly in love, didn&#8217;t have a story worthy of fairy tales? At that point, I didn&#8217;t believe they were in love. Now, I&#8217;m not so sure.</p>
<p>My parents&#8217; story is still incomplete in my mind, mostly because they don&#8217;t really share the details with my brother and me. They sort of brush it off as unimportant and the topic tends to fizzle out before it even gets the chance to be broached. All I know is that they met, they wed, and they began their lives together. There were no bells and whistles, no white lace wedding, no tropical honeymoon, no big shebang that I expected as a little kid. I used to be horrified that they didn&#8217;t wear their wedding rings, and especially that they&#8217;d forget their anniversaries each year, but my parents would just chuckle and say &#8220;It&#8217;s just a date&#8221;.</p>
<p>Western ideals of &#8220;love&#8221; are so different from those that my parents grew up with. It&#8217;s okay, maybe, that here in North America, we paint pictures of falling madly in love with The One and having a flawless wedding- a perfect series of snapshots to cherish and remember forever.</p>
<p>And just because Eastern culture- one that I could never claim to fully understand- might have a different schema for love and marriage, doesn&#8217;t mean I can say that a couple isn&#8217;t actually in love.</p>
<p>My parents don&#8217;t stare into each other&#8217;s eyes over dinner and hold hands when they walk through the grocery store aisles. But she&#8217;ll rest her head on his shoulder when she&#8217;s tired and he&#8217;ll carry her bag for her when she tries on clothes in the dressing room. They&#8217;ll watch TV together on the couch and they&#8217;ll tease each other once in a while from across the room.</p>
<p>Maybe my parents are in love. Maybe they aren&#8217;t.</p>
<p>I don&#8217;t know how much it really matters, to be honest. They <em>do</em> love each other. And maybe the only interpretation of &#8220;in love&#8221; that matters for them is their own. They&#8217;re happy. They&#8217;re not perfect, but I can safely say that despite the cultural differences, they truly do inspire me.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/204/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/204/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=204&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://incipientideas.wordpress.com/2013/01/01/cultural-dynamics-love-and-marriage/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>40</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/bd3a1266404c2c4f06d520fa2f36f00c?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">incipientideas</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://manwifeanddog.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/marriage-cartoon-proposal.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Augmenting Your Vision with Heat and Distance Sensing.</title>
		<link>http://hackaday.com/2012/12/20/we-are-the-borg-we-will-add-heat-and-distance-sensing-to-your-vision/</link>
		<comments>http://hackaday.com/2012/12/20/we-are-the-borg-we-will-add-heat-and-distance-sensing-to-your-vision/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2012 22:15:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Mike Szczys</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[wearable hacks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[borg]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eye patch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ir sensor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ultrasonic sensor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vision]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://hackaday.com/?p=92042</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[[Gregory McRoberts] was born with reduced vision in one eye and has never experienced the three dimensional sight which most of us take for granted. Recently he was inspired by the concept of a hearing aid to build a device which can augment his vision. Behold, the very Borg-like eye-patch that he wears to add distance and [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=92042&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-92043" alt="we-are-borg" src="http://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/we-are-borg.jpg?w=580&#038;h=385" width="580" height="385" /></p>
<p>[Gregory McRoberts] was born with reduced vision in one eye and has never experienced the three dimensional sight which most of us take for granted. Recently he was inspired by the concept of a hearing aid to build a device which can augment his vision. Behold, the very Borg-like <a href="http://blog.ocad.ca/wordpress/gdes3b16-fw201202-01/2012/12/augmented-vision/">eye-patch that he wears to add distance and heat to his palette of senses</a>.</p>
<p>The hardware he chose is an Arduino-compatible Lilypad board. It is wired to an ultrasonic rangefinder and an infrared sensor which monitor the area in front of him. The function of his right eye is still capable of seeing light and color, so a pair of LED boards are mounted on the inside. One is connected to the thermal sensor, displaying blue when below eighty degrees Fahrenheit and red when above. The other LED is green and flashes at a different speed based on the range sensor&#8217;s reading.</p>
<p>This is distracting when a person with normal sight wears it because of the intensity of the LEDs. We found [Gregory's] explanation of this (called <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Helmet_fire">Helmet Fire</a>) quite interesting.</p>
<p>[via <a href="http://www.adafruit.com/blog/2012/12/19/augmented-vision-eyepatch-wearablewednesday/">Adafruit</a>]</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://hackaday.com/category/wearable-hacks/'>wearable hacks</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/92042/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/92042/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=92042&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://hackaday.com/2012/12/20/we-are-the-borg-we-will-add-heat-and-distance-sensing-to-your-vision/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>27</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/1aac8835fba7c550fea5a53cd1b0dfb8?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F1.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mike Szczys</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hackadaycom.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/we-are-borg.jpg?w=580" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">we-are-borg</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Grass Is Greener Where You Water It</title>
		<link>http://bekahoutsidethebox.com/2012/12/31/the-grass-is-greener-where-you-water-it/</link>
		<comments>http://bekahoutsidethebox.com/2012/12/31/the-grass-is-greener-where-you-water-it/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 01:30:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bekahoutsidethebox</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[About]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Self Care]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yoga]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[experiment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grass]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mindfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Neil Barringham]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[satya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stories]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://bekahoutsidethebox.com/?p=322</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Someone close to me once said that I have a &#8220;catastrophic imagination&#8221; because I have a strong tendency to imagine the worst. A friend doesn&#8217;t return a phone call &#8211; obviously they hate me. In a dark alley &#8211; obviously I&#8217;m about to get raped, mugged, and murdered. Start to get sick &#8211; obviously I&#8217;m [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=322&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_323" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 280px"><a href="http://randomactsofkindnezz.wordpress.com/tag/neil-barringham/"><img class=" wp-image-323 " alt="" src="http://bekahoutsidethebox.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/pinned-image.jpeg?w=270&#038;h=384" width="270" height="384" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">{Photo Credit :: Random Acts of Kindness}</p></div>
<p>Someone close to me once said that I have a &#8220;catastrophic imagination&#8221; because I have a strong tendency to imagine the worst. A friend doesn&#8217;t return a phone call &#8211; <em>obviously</em> they hate me. In a dark alley &#8211; <em>obviously</em> I&#8217;m about to get raped, mugged, and murdered. Start to get sick &#8211; <em>obviously</em> I&#8217;m about to die. Can&#8217;t do a particular yoga pose &#8211; <em>obviously</em> I&#8217;m a terrible yogi. You get the picture &#8230;</p>
<p>And (of course) it&#8217;s not just that I imagine these things once and move on, oh no. All of these stories tend to swirl around in my head over and over and over again. Thinking this way has become so habitual that I barely even register when I&#8217;m doing it anymore, and once you <em>think</em> something often enough, it <em>almost</em> seems to become true. Maybe you can relate?</p>
<p>But I heard this clever twist on a familiar saying the other day: <strong>the grass is greener where you water it</strong>. And it occurred to me that investing my mental and emotional energy in these sort of repetitive negative thoughts was essentially like &#8220;watering&#8221; them &#8230; and so long as I continue to water them, they will continue to flourish. Plus, our stores of mental and emotional energy are limited, and if we&#8217;re expending large quantities on thinking about what we <em>don&#8217;t</em> want to happen, that leaves little energy left over for the good stuff!</p>
<p><strong>A different approach? </strong></p>
<p>Over the past few days I have been thinking a lot about what a different approach might entail and I certainly do not have all of the answers. (Sorry to disappoint! ;)) But I do know how I would like to go about getting started with exploring (and maybe even breaking) this habit, and if you can relate to the above, maybe you&#8217;d like to start here too:</p>
<ul>
<li><span style="line-height:13px;"><strong>Noticing.</strong> (Really, this is always the first step, right?) Becoming aware of the thoughts and the simple fact that they&#8217;re happening. Noticing what feelings arise before, during, and after engaging in the habitual behavior. </span></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Getting curious. </strong>Asking questions about what is <em>really</em> going on here. Examining where these thoughts are originating from and paying attention to what triggers these negative patterns of thinking.</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><strong>Returning to the facts. </strong>Imaginary catastrophes are just that &#8211; imaginary, made up, not real. They are often rooted in our fears about what might happen in the future or our reactions to things that happened in the past. But, returning to the facts brings us back to the present and back to the Truth.</li>
</ul>
<p>Will this work? Will noticing, getting curious, and returning to the facts help me (and you) learn how to &#8220;water&#8221; the areas of our lives that we want to thrive? Stay tuned, let&#8217;s find out together &#8230;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/322/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/322/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=322&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://bekahoutsidethebox.com/2012/12/31/the-grass-is-greener-where-you-water-it/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>80</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://bekahoutsidethebox.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/pinned-image.jpeg?w=105" />
		<media:content url="http://bekahoutsidethebox.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/pinned-image.jpeg?w=105" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Pinned Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/af2b0226921b9a6a0cf0e3c4dd5d5acc?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bekahoutsidethebox</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://bekahoutsidethebox.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/pinned-image.jpeg?w=450" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rooftops</title>
		<link>http://thebluehourmagazine.com/2012/12/31/rooftops-heather-minette/</link>
		<comments>http://thebluehourmagazine.com/2012/12/31/rooftops-heather-minette/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 08:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bluehourmagazine</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Poetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Heather Minette]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Journey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Poets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reckoning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wisdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Womanhood]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thebluehourmagazine.com/?p=1353</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I looked for her on the rooftops of Brooklyn, the makeshift balconies of Manhattan, and the subway in between. On the mountaintops of Spain, the dirty pubs of Dublin, and every European train. On southern country roads, and the foothills of Tennessee, and a lake house preserving childhood dreams. In the classrooms of philosophers and [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1353&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I looked for her on the rooftops of Brooklyn,<br />
the makeshift balconies of Manhattan,<br />
and the subway in between.</p>
<p>On the mountaintops of Spain,<br />
the dirty pubs of Dublin,<br />
and every European train.</p>
<p>On southern country roads,<br />
and the foothills of Tennessee,<br />
and a lake house preserving childhood dreams.</p>
<p>In the classrooms of philosophers and mystics,<br />
the offices of scholars,<br />
and the garden of a Buddhist.</p>
<p>In a home painted yellow,<br />
behind an ill-fitting apron,<br />
and white picket fence.</p>
<p>In the cramped apartments of men who wrote,<br />
and drank,<br />
and beneath the sheets of those who understood.</p>
<p>On the folded pages of library books,<br />
the texture of painted canvas,<br />
and the sound of piano keys.</p>
<p>I looked for her through my bedroom window,<br />
barefoot and hardly clothed,<br />
not lonely, but alone.</p>
<p>I looked for her,<br />
and did not find her,<br />
but instead, created her.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1353/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1353/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1353&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thebluehourmagazine.com/2012/12/31/rooftops-heather-minette/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>32</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/5abfe9208968b9e6f64ae7b114fb9511?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bluehourmagazine</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>And They Lived Fearlessly Ever After . . .</title>
		<link>http://oliotalk.wordpress.com/2012/12/31/and-they-lived-fearlessly-ever-after/</link>
		<comments>http://oliotalk.wordpress.com/2012/12/31/and-they-lived-fearlessly-ever-after/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 14:28:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>skaushiva</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[People]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Places]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Abuse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amanat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Candlelight vigil]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Damini]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Delhi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jantar Mantar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life of Pi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Memories of Fear]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nirbhaya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rape]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Women's freedom]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://oliotalk.wordpress.com/?p=280</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[ &#160; So then, what is it about this 23 year-old girl who raised the conscience of India on December 16, 2012? Was it the barbaric way in which she met her end? Was she the last straw that broke the back of an overladen camel? Was it her young age, her thwarted ambitions and aspirations, or her [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=280&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size:11px;line-height:17px;"> </span>&nbsp;</p>
<div id="attachment_292" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://oliotalk.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/fearless.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-292 " title="Cry against violence on women" alt="After Amanat - the fight continues" src="http://oliotalk.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/fearless.jpg?w=300&#038;h=224" width="300" height="224" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Pink Rising in India?</p></div>
<p>So then, what is it about this 23 year-old girl who raised the conscience of India on December 16, 2012?</p>
<p>Was it the barbaric way in which she met her end?</p>
<p>Was she the last straw that broke the back of an overladen camel?</p>
<p>Was it her young age, her thwarted ambitions and aspirations, or her<br />
parents’ unfulfilled hopes, dreams and expectations?</p>
<p>Was it her last wish, to be able to survive and make it out of her nightmarish ordeal?</p>
<p>All the above perhaps, and maybe just something more.</p>
<div></div>
<p>She did not step out with her friend that night on a mission to alter the conscience of her country. She had no intentions to lift the blinders off the eyes of a male-dominated society either. She was clearly not out to get the media to christen her with a fancy new name. And it perhaps did not matter one bit to her or her family if she were labeled a brave-heart or not, while she struggled to survive at the hospitals.</p>
<p>Look again, look beneath all those glossy labels that were bestowed upon her and you will find just another young girl, with her whole life ahead of her. Someone who was out at the cinemas one weekend and stepped into the wrong bus on her way back home, for which she paid with her life. And yes, it happened in the ugliest possible way right around dinnertime in the capital of our country.</p>
<p>Over a decade ago, my college curriculum included a documentary titled <i>‘Memories of Fear’</i>, a film by Madhushree Dutta. I still remember how sensitively and accurately it captured the fears a girl grows up with in her journey to womanhood and beyond.</p>
<p>What was called fear in my mother’s days became awareness for the world at large with the passage of time. The truth is that the vacuum that builds up in a girl’s stomach as she quickens her pace through a desolate road, looking back every other minute to ensure there is no other shadow lurking behind her, is nothing but fear.</p>
<p>Fear is the single common heirloom, that as girls in India, we all inherit from our mothers, grandmothers, aunts, sisters and friends. Fear for self-preservation, and of men who can do things to hurt and shame us. We learn to weave this fear seamlessly into our lives and never even realize when it becomes second nature. This perpetual fear eats into a woman’s carefree spirit and keeps her on guard at all times.</p>
<p>A friendly pat from an uncle on the bottom, or a male colleague’s claims of great working chemistry are both met with suspicion, followed by the cold shoulder. While we can turn a deaf ear to despicable remarks about certain parts of our body from a group of rogue teens, it takes longer to deal with the trauma of being groped on a crowded bus.</p>
<p>We figure ways of avoiding a run-in with the neighbourhood lech, and develop at least three different tactics of accepting coins from shopkeepers without having our palms unnecessarily felt. Even on a student budget, we willingly pay a premium for balcony seats at the cinema to avoid the flashers in the front stalls. As a general rule, we prefer the safety of aisle seats both in air and on ground. We have heard about hidden recording devices and two-way mirrors in changing rooms, and are alert even before we take off our stoles. We prefer to avoid places, situations and people who make us uncomfortable or give us the creeps. Many friendships do get affected, and sometimes, even years of trust come under scrutiny too. Personal freedom and professional progress are rarely unfettered for a woman.</p>
<p>Between growing up to be a lady and becoming independent in a society that is full of frustrated and perverted men on the prowl, it should not come as a surprise that girls grow up faster. Do we even have a choice?</p>
<p>As protests continue across the nation for this young girl who has lost her life most tragically, everybody seems to have their own views on what needs to be changed, who needs to be blamed or how the offenders should be dealt with. I do pray and wish that these protests and vigils bring about some meaningful change for all of us. But I also think it is time to dig a little deeper.</p>
<p>Decades past our independence, on the brink of a day when a jolly ride into space is no longer just a dream, it is a shame that in the world’s largest democracy, a woman cannot be guaranteed a life free from the fear of being manhandled, attacked, abused, shamed, ridiculed or victimized in any form simply because she is physically weaker. Long before we encourage our sons to be MBA’s, consultants, doctors, engineers or scientists, we need to teach them to first be humane.</p>
<p>They say that she was out to watch Life of Pi that fateful night.</p>
<p>Ironically, a movie that is a story of survival against all odds by relying on faith. She did not make it after a fortnight, but perhaps in her fight for survival lies a cue for all of us, to have the faith that we can indeed bring about change if we continue to make ourselves heard.</p>
<p>I am not giving up hope yet.</p>
<p>Someday, I hope little girls in my country will be living in a time when they can relate to fairytales again.</p>
<p>PS: For those interested,  I had written an article on this subject way back in 2009 as well.</p>
<p><a href="http://oliotalk.wordpress.com/2009/03/08/flagging-fear/" rel="nofollow">http://oliotalk.wordpress.com/2009/03/08/flagging-fear/</a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/280/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/280/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=280&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://oliotalk.wordpress.com/2012/12/31/and-they-lived-fearlessly-ever-after/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>125</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c83413071d2517087b54973a42a514b7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">skaushiva</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://oliotalk.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/fearless.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Cry against violence on women</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>2012 On My Mobile Phone</title>
		<link>http://echwaluphotography.wordpress.com/2012/12/07/2012-on-my-mobile-phone/</link>
		<comments>http://echwaluphotography.wordpress.com/2012/12/07/2012-on-my-mobile-phone/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2012 14:45:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>echwaluphotography</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Potrait]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Poverty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Random]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2012 on Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[African Landscape]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[African Market]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[African on Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[African Photographer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Belfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Landscape Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile Phones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Night Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Northern Ireland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photographing Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Portraits]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Road side market]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uganda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ugandan Photographer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ugandan photography]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://echwaluphotography.wordpress.com/?p=2720</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The United States economy is nine times the size of Africa&#8217;s, but Africa has twice as many mobile phones according to Harvard Business Review (HBR). Visually, Africa’s story is silently being told through these little gadgets. Unfortunately, many will remain as such. Silent. I am a perfect example on how good stories are photographed and [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2720&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The United States economy is nine times the size of Africa&#8217;s, but Africa <a href="http://blogs.hbr.org/cs/2012/07/africas_true_mobile_revolution.html">has twice as many mobile phones</a> according to Harvard Business Review (HBR).</p>
<p>Visually, Africa’s story is silently being told through these little gadgets. Unfortunately, many will remain as such. Silent.<a href="http://echwaluphotography.wordpress.com/2012/12/07/2012-on-my-mobile-phone/01-7/" rel="attachment wp-att-2721"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-2721" alt="01" src="http://echwaluphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/011.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>I am a perfect example on how good stories are photographed and stashed because they were taken on a mobile phone.</p>
<p>No wonder the only other thing more personal in my possession except my mind is a mobile phone. And that in itself underlines how important this tool is, not just in my personal life but professional one as well.<a href="http://echwaluphotography.wordpress.com/2012/12/07/2012-on-my-mobile-phone/02-10/" rel="attachment wp-att-2722"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-2722" alt="02" src="http://echwaluphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/021.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>Not until 15 months ago, a mobile phone to me was about making calls, texting and storing relevant phone contacts. And yes, playing some games too. That role however has drastically changed as i professionally grew as a photographer.<a href="http://echwaluphotography.wordpress.com/2012/12/07/2012-on-my-mobile-phone/03-14/" rel="attachment wp-att-2723"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-2723" alt="03" src="http://echwaluphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/031.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>Today I see a mobile phone as a very important documentary tool. Perhaps one of the most important tools. I know many of you might not necessarily believe me but here are my reasons.</p>
<p><b><i>Professional Camera</i></b></p>
<p>Just what is a professional camera? Honestly, I don’t have an answer to this question. This year alone, I have got over a dozen “professional camera advice” request from some of my followers. In return, I have always given a fair recommendation.<a href="http://echwaluphotography.wordpress.com/2012/12/07/2012-on-my-mobile-phone/04-10/" rel="attachment wp-att-2724"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-2724" alt="04" src="http://echwaluphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/041.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>I believe there are no professional cameras but people are. A perfect example is an <a href="http://lightbox.time.com/2012/08/16/an-iphone-in-congo-photos-by-michael-christopher-brown/#1">“iPhone in DR Congo”</a> , a photo project done by Michael Christopher Brown about the effects of minerals on every life of a Congolese.</p>
<p><b><i>Personal Moments</i></b></p>
<p>The most personal, naughty, moments in life are mostly taken using a mobile phone. These are the pictures that in our memories the longest. They are usually poorly composed with suicidal lighting but rich in terms of reality, originality and honesty. They speak volumes about who we really are. Maybe that’s why many people hold their phones close to their chests because there is a lot we protect beyond the naughty text messages in our <em>inboxes</em>.<a href="http://echwaluphotography.wordpress.com/2012/12/07/2012-on-my-mobile-phone/05-9/" rel="attachment wp-att-2725"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-2725" alt="05" src="http://echwaluphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/051.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p><b><i>Invisibility</i></b></p>
<p>A mobile camera is perhaps the most open, yet secretive camera anyone can have. There is this casualness associated with people taking pictures using a phone. I have many times dropped by heavy camera gear for my Nokia Lumia 800 to record everyday life in Kampala unnoticed. And on every occasion, I haven’t infuriated anyone.<a href="http://echwaluphotography.wordpress.com/2012/12/07/2012-on-my-mobile-phone/010-8/" rel="attachment wp-att-2726"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-2726" alt="010" src="http://echwaluphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/010.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>I remember for example n October this year when I took a picture of the peace sculpture at the Kololo Independence grounds. At the time, there was ongoing preparation at the ground for the celebration of Uganda’s 50<sup>th</sup> anniversary. The presidents security personal were all over the place. Cameras were not allowed within the vicinity that day, BUT mobile phones were allowed.</p>
<p><strong><i>Light Weight</i></strong></p>
<p>On a normal day my backpack usually has, two heavy cameras, two lenses (Wide angle and a zoom), a laptop, an extension, phone chargers, iPod charger, laptop charger, lens cleaners, head phones, face towel, water, etc. Whenever I drop that for a phone, it feels like carrying one piece of a crisp. Very light. Fatigue does not come in as fast as it would have.<a href="http://echwaluphotography.wordpress.com/2012/12/07/2012-on-my-mobile-phone/06-8/" rel="attachment wp-att-2727"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-2727" alt="06" src="http://echwaluphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/061.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p><strong><i>Price Value</i></strong></p>
<p>I recently met a guy who looked to be genuinely interested in photography. He was telling me how the prices of what he called professional cameras are prohibitive. In the very conversation, he was over the moon, bragging about the eminent arrival of his iPhone 5. I broke it down for him this way.<a href="http://echwaluphotography.wordpress.com/2012/12/07/2012-on-my-mobile-phone/07-7/" rel="attachment wp-att-2728"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-2728" alt="07" src="http://echwaluphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/07.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>One of my favourite cameras is<a href="http://www.bhphotovideo.com/c/product/753766-REG/Canon_5757B002_EOS_Rebel_T3_Digital.html"> a Canon EOS Rebel T3 on Amazon</a>. It costs a paltry $550. (12.2MP APS-C CMOS Sensor, 18-55 EF-S Lens, 100-6400 ISO, 720p HD Movie Mode, 3 fps Continuous Shooting……). <a href="http://www.amazon.com/s/ref=nb_sb_noss_1?url=search-alias%3Delectronics&amp;field-keywords=iphone+5&amp;rh=n%3A172282%2Ck%3Aiphone+5&amp;ajr=2">An iPhone 5</a> on the hand costs $784. So which is cheaper?<a href="http://echwaluphotography.wordpress.com/2012/12/07/2012-on-my-mobile-phone/08-7/" rel="attachment wp-att-2729"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-2729" alt="08" src="http://echwaluphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/08.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>A lot of people walk around with “professional cameras”-read Mobile Phones and do not even realize it.</p>
<p>A camera does not have to weigh 5kg to qualify as a professional one. It does not have to make the 20 mega pixel mark to join the professional rank.<a href="http://echwaluphotography.wordpress.com/2012/12/07/2012-on-my-mobile-phone/09-6/" rel="attachment wp-att-2730"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-2730" alt="09" src="http://echwaluphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/09.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>Food for thought; what if <a href="http://www.novinite.com/view_news.php?id=133119">this picture of Gaddafi</a> was captured on a fake phone-We call them: Chinese Phones in Uganda. Imagine what your iPhone, Nokia, Samsung or Alcatel could have done!<a href="http://echwaluphotography.wordpress.com/2012/12/07/2012-on-my-mobile-phone/011-jpeg/" rel="attachment wp-att-2731"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-2731" alt="011.jpeg" src="http://echwaluphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/011-jpeg.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2720/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2720/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2720&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://echwaluphotography.wordpress.com/2012/12/07/2012-on-my-mobile-phone/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/b7d6ea3e7a567224697103002f8db850?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">echwaluphotography</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://echwaluphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/011.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">01</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://echwaluphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/021.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">02</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://echwaluphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/031.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">03</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://echwaluphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/041.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">04</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://echwaluphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/051.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">05</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://echwaluphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/010.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">010</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://echwaluphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/061.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">06</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://echwaluphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/07.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">07</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://echwaluphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/08.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">08</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://echwaluphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/09.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">09</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://echwaluphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/011-jpeg.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">011.jpeg</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Monomyth, Joseph Campbell, and Me</title>
		<link>http://deliberatedonkey.wordpress.com/2012/12/26/the-monomyth-joseph-campbell-and-me/</link>
		<comments>http://deliberatedonkey.wordpress.com/2012/12/26/the-monomyth-joseph-campbell-and-me/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2012 01:35:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Melanie</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[A Day in a Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[domestic violence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[heros journey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[intimate partner violence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[joseph campbell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[men hit women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the hero with a thousand faces]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[violence against women]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://deliberatedonkey.wordpress.com/?p=3436</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Damn I hate it when this happens. I didn&#8217;t pick up this book to learn something about myself. It&#8217;s not me I was trying to impress. The quick synopsis that won&#8217;t get you even a &#8220;D&#8221; on any pop-quiz is this: The Hero With a Thousand Faces is Joseph Campbell&#8217;s influential study of world mythology. He set out to explain [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3436&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://deliberatedonkey.wordpress.com/2012/12/26/the-monomyth-joseph-campbell-and-me/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>74</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/2d4854fad14d7af9c5cd0d9d8c26972f?s=96&#38;d=wavatar&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tendingweeds</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://deliberatedonkey.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/heros-journey.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">&#34;We have not even to risk the adventure alone; for the heroes of all time have gone before us, the labyrinth is fully known; we have only to follow the thread of the hero-path.&#34;</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How To See Your New Year\&#8217;s Resolution Through</title>
		<link>http://daveknickerbocker.wordpress.com/2012/12/27/how-to-see-your-new-years-resolution-through/</link>
		<comments>http://daveknickerbocker.wordpress.com/2012/12/27/how-to-see-your-new-years-resolution-through/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2012 14:43:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dave Knickerbocker</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Random Thoughts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adventure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christianity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[God]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jesus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Motivation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New Year]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pruis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Religion and Spirituality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Resolution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Snow Storm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Toyota]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://daveknickerbocker.wordpress.com/?p=2576</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This morning I noticed a Toyota Prius trying to get up a small hill that is very gradual.  It&#8217;s a small car that does wonders with gas mileage . . . normally. Northeast Ohio, where I live, was hit by a load of snow yesterday (Yes, the day after Christmas. Bummer.).  We used to live [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2576&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://commons.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Toyota_Prius_III_20090710_front.JPG" target="_blank"><img class="zemanta-img-inserted zemanta-img-configured" title="Toyota Prius III" alt="Toyota Prius III" src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/e/ed/Toyota_Prius_III_20090710_front.JPG/300px-Toyota_Prius_III_20090710_front.JPG" width="300" height="201" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Toyota Prius III (Photo credit: Wikipedia)</p></div>
<p>This morning I noticed a Toyota Prius trying to get up a small hill that is very gradual.  It&#8217;s a small car that does wonders with gas mileage . . . normally.</p>
<p>Northeast Ohio, where I live, was hit by a load of snow yesterday (Yes, the day <em>after</em> Christmas. Bummer.).  We used to live in Rochester, NY, where there was an abundance of snow removal equipment. That was because there was quite a bit of snow up there on a regular basis. In fact, our first winter there it was the snowiest city in the United States (except for Alaska).  After the first major snow storm that year I was amazed to see a small snow plow being driven by an employee of our town. It was just the right size for the sidewalk! Pretty cool.</p>
<p><span id="more-2576"></span>We don&#8217;t get that much snow where we live now.  When it does snow a ton the plows don&#8217;t get around as quickly because we aren&#8217;t equipped to remove so much at one shot.</p>
<p>The New Year is right around the corner.  It&#8217;s the time when we take a look at ourselves with constructive criticism. <em>What is it that I need to change about myself? Boy, I really let myself go last year!</em>  I like to think that the Holy Spirit capitalizes on this time of year. We could help him out by listening to his prodding about how he&#8217;d like to transform us a little more. Maybe a lot more. Sometimes that voice you hear isn&#8217;t you trying to improve yourself. Often times it&#8217;s God.</p>
<p>Identifying the goal is the first step. Then you must agree to try to accomplish it. After agreeing to accomplish it, we need to use the right tools to make it happen. We fail at our New Year&#8217;s Resolutions at this final step more often than the rest. Zechariah 4:6 says &#8220;‘Not by might nor by power, but by my Spirit,’ says the Lord Almighty. (NIV)&#8221;</p>
<p>And so the little Prius struggled in the depths, spinning and whirring to get the job done. He&#8217;d back up ten feet and charge forward to plow his way through, but to no avail.  I wonder what kind of mileage that guy got today.  From the looks of it, he had about six feet to the gallon in the minute that I watched. Eventually, he gave up. He had struggled valiantly, but he just wasn&#8217;t equipped for the task.</p>
<p>What hill is it that God wants you to conquer this year? Don&#8217;t take a Prius to an SUV party. God has the power you&#8217;ll need.  Stop depending on your own, because you&#8217;re just spinning your wheels.</p>
<p>Happy New Year!</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2576/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2576/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2576&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://daveknickerbocker.wordpress.com/2012/12/27/how-to-see-your-new-years-resolution-through/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>33</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/3d5145cd2bf0f0fb18b72ea421b65b7c?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jezknick</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/e/ed/Toyota_Prius_III_20090710_front.JPG/300px-Toyota_Prius_III_20090710_front.JPG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Toyota Prius III</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
