<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2012 21:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>The Problem With 12/12/12, 12/25/12 and Etc.</title>
		<link>http://sunnysideupwithbacon.wordpress.com/2012/12/12/the-problem-with-121212-122512-and-etc/</link>
		<comments>http://sunnysideupwithbacon.wordpress.com/2012/12/12/the-problem-with-121212-122512-and-etc/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2012 01:58:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Kathryn G</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[12/12/12]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[random]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thoughts]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://sunnysideupwithbacon.wordpress.com/?p=1423</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Up until a few minutes ago, I was one of those people who had to have a very special 12/12/12. It&#8217;s going to be the last day where the month, date and the last two digits of the year will be identical; obviously, it won&#8217;t ever happen again. So initially, I wanted that day to [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1423&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://sunnysideupwithbacon.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/december12.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image" id="i-1532" alt="Image" src="http://sunnysideupwithbacon.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/december12.jpg?w=580" /></a></p>
<p>Up until a few minutes ago, I was one of those people who had to have a very special 12/12/12. It&#8217;s going to be the last day where the month, date and the last two digits of the year will be identical; obviously, it won&#8217;t ever happen again. So initially, I wanted that day to be extra special. I was just telling my friends the other day that we had to do <em>something </em>to &#8220;celebrate.&#8221;</p>
<p>Then earlier, I suddenly realized something. December 12, 2012 is just like any other day. <em>They all won&#8217;t ever happen again. </em></p>
<p>I think a lot of us get too caught up in petty little things like this. We use &#8220;special&#8221; things with &#8220;special&#8221; appearances as an excuse to treat everything else, well, un-specially. Why is it that on Valentine&#8217;s Day people show more affection toward one another than on any other days? Why is it that people are more grateful on Thanksgiving? Why are they kinder and more loving during the Christmas season?</p>
<p>The only leverage those days have over all the other days in the year is that they have a name, a title. Besides that, they&#8217;re all the same. Why can&#8217;t we just be kinder and more loving period? Why can&#8217;t we be as grateful as we are on Thanksgiving all throughout the year? Why can&#8217;t we simply show the same Valentine&#8217;s Day affection every day?</p>
<p>I know it doesn&#8217;t seem all that significant. But if you will look at a calendar, how many special days are there compared to all the non-special ones? That is literally hundreds of days when people might feel that being a kind person isn&#8217;t really someone they need to be [yet], that taking your husband or your wife for granted may not be okay but is still socially understandable, that taking a moment to appreciate everything you have will just distract you from school or work or Facebook.</p>
<p><i>That&#8217;s hundreds of days when we can be our best selves, when we can be a blessing to others, when we can do good&#8230; yet we choose not to because December 26 is not December 25. </i><em><br />
</em></p>
<p>A few days ago, I saw a homeless man when I walked out of a restaurant and gave him a few bucks. My friend looked at me questioningly so I told her, &#8220;It&#8217;s Christmas season.&#8221; Do you see? At the time, I was sure I was doing something nice. Now, I&#8217;m not so sure anymore. Now, I feel like I did that not out of the kindness of my heart, but out of this need I have to act on my idea of what the Christmas season should be like.</p>
<p>Look at it from the man&#8217;s point of view. <em>Does he really have to endure the whole year and wait until Christmas for someone to actually help him? </em>The same question goes for anyone else who isn&#8217;t in a good place in life. Because I think a lot of people, I have to say, myself included, would wait until Christmas to feel the need to help others.</p>
<p>Now is usually the time when someone will say things like, &#8216;Live every day like it&#8217;s your last&#8217; or &#8216;Every day should be like Valentine&#8217;s Day&#8217; or &#8216;Carpe diem.&#8217; But I won&#8217;t because one, it&#8217;s cliche and, therefore, has probably lost its desired effect on people, and; two, technically, I kind of already did when I mentioned them.</p>
<p>I will just say this instead: Always be nice. <img src='http://s0.wp.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif' alt=':)' class='wp-smiley' /> </p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1423/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1423/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1423&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://sunnysideupwithbacon.wordpress.com/2012/12/12/the-problem-with-121212-122512-and-etc/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/ea2a6db879c48c72fc207bd7887d4134?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">iamryn</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://sunnysideupwithbacon.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/december12.jpg?w=580" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>\&#8221;I\&#8217;m Spiritual, Not Religious.\&#8221;</title>
		<link>http://ehyde.wordpress.com/2012/12/05/im-spiritual-not-religious/</link>
		<comments>http://ehyde.wordpress.com/2012/12/05/im-spiritual-not-religious/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 02:53:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Eric Hyde</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Musings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christianity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[church]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[church tradition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[religious]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spiritual]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ehyde.wordpress.com/?p=661</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[“I’m spiritual, not religious” I wish I had a back massage for every time I’ve heard this line. What gets me most is the presupposition it stems from, that “spiritual” is the assumed equivalent of “good” and “religious” is the assumed equivalent of &#8220;evil.&#8221; Who made up this language game? Honestly, who decided that “spiritual” [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=661&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://ehyde.wordpress.com/2012/12/05/im-spiritual-not-religious/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>82</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/9e6e5ffc090c99f27e2b09e7a05a2341?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ehyde</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ehyde.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/spiritual-no-religious-2.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Spiritual no Religious 2</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hanging Up the Tutu</title>
		<link>http://25tofly.com/2012/12/11/hanging-up-the-tutu/</link>
		<comments>http://25tofly.com/2012/12/11/hanging-up-the-tutu/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2012 20:12:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>becca3416</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[How I Knew]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Inspirational]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[25tofly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[About Me]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ballet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Becca Cord]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[becca on fire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[career advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dancer turned writer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funny]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Inspiration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nutcracker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Performing arts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pointe shoes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WordPress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing challenges]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://25tofly.com/?p=2310</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[If you follow my blog regularly, you know I don&#8217;t get serious too often. Ever, really. A lot of bloggers are naturals at this stuff, but it is actually a real challenge for me to write about something serious, especially when it is about me. Humor is safe for me, while anything outside of that realm makes [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2310&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you follow my blog regularly, you know I don&#8217;t get serious too often. Ever, really. A lot of bloggers are naturals at this stuff, but it is actually a <em>real</em> challenge for me to write about something serious, especially when it is about me. Humor is safe for me, while anything outside of that realm makes me feel extremely vulnerable. But, with everything going on during the week of a <a title="Let's get physical" href="http://clownonfire.wordpress.com/2012/12/12/lets-get-physical/" target="_blank">Becca on Fire</a>, I not only have a little extra confidence in my fingertips, but I also feel that it is the perfect opportunity to open up a bit to my readers. So, here goes my attempt to inspire.</p>
<p>Before I began writing this post, I sat with a blinking cursor on the left side of my screen and the &#8220;about me&#8221; page of my blog on the right side of the screen.</p>
<p><em>I&#8217;m only good at funny. That&#8217;s what I do. It is easy to be funny. For me. Shit, this is going to be more of a challenge than I thought. I can&#8217;t even inspire <a title="jack" href="http://25tofly.com/2012/10/25/getting-robbed-by-your-cat/" target="_blank">Jack </a>to poop inside the litter box, so what can I possibly have to write about inspiration? Oh well, just <strong>write</strong>.</em></p>
<p>After all of that staring, I noticed something about how I describe myself. Take a look at my<a title="about me" href="http://25tofly.com/about/" target="_blank"> &#8220;about me&#8221; </a>page. I begin by proudly acknowledging a very important part of what makes me Becca. I was a dancer.</p>
<div id="attachment_1690" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 294px"><img class="size-full wp-image-1690" alt="becca cord in a tutu" src="http://25andfly.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dance2-e1347387983261.jpg?w=590"   /><p class="wp-caption-text">Before I was writing I was a confectionery delight in pointe shoes.</p></div>
<p>For seventeen years, I was first and foremost, a dancer. Make that a <em>great</em> dancer. A passion that consumes you for such a long period of time is hard to shake and even harder to accept that you <em>must</em> shake, which was apparent by the blurb I&#8217;d written. So, I guess I should more accurately say that what I was looking at was a statement about what <em><strong>used</strong><strong> t</strong><strong>o</strong></em> make me Becca.</p>
<p>Before anyone ever put the notion in my head that making a profession of performing arts was &#8220;impractical,&#8221; I never thought twice about any other course for my life. I entered college as a dance major, was an important member of the college dance team, and had every intention of performing until my age got the best of me (at which point I planned to teach). Everyone knew me as the dancer even if they didn&#8217;t know me at all. That is how integral it was to my identity.</p>
<p>After about a year in college, I began to realize that the performing arts program I was in was not up to par with my experience level. This is not a case of my comedic ego either, the program was simply a joke. A cop-out for lazy freshmen who would rather mock an art form than write an essay. On top of that, my parents continually dropped not-so-subtle hints that I may want to consider a different calling. Something more <em>lucrative. </em></p>
<p>It infuriated me that they didn&#8217;t <em>get</em> it. Get <strong>me</strong>. It infuriated me even more that I pretty much had no other option but to drop the program because of its lack in advancement. It was holding me back as a dancer. It infuriated me, because everyone would think I gave up on my passion to become an office drone (at the thought of which nauseated me).</p>
<div id="attachment_2549" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 410px"><a href="http://commutertheology.wordpress.com/"><img class=" wp-image-2549 " alt="snoopy in business" src="http://25andfly.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/snoopy.jpg?w=400&#038;h=526" width="400" height="526" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Street art doesn&#8217;t lie.</p></div>
<p>Before I knew it, I was a performing arts drop-out and a month from being another indifferent graduate of the school of business. What happened? I over analyzed every incoming external influence telling me to cash out before I lost big, that&#8217;s what happened. That, stirred together with my own doubts and insecurities as a dancer. I didn&#8217;t want to start over at a new university, but I also couldn&#8217;t stay enrolled in the Ballet 101 classes that I took when I was three years old.</p>
<p>I had  become the one thing that I had almost forgotten I&#8217;d sworn not to be, Miss play-it-safe.  Sure, I&#8217;d find a job. That job would pay well enough for me to live as comfortably as I always have. People would see me as &#8220;successful&#8221;, but I wouldn&#8217;t stop thinking, &#8220;Is this <em>it</em>?&#8221;. I would eventually become that forty-year-old woman still bragging about how many pirouettes she could do twenty years ago while shamefully dodging conversation about her soul draining day job.</p>
<p>So, back to my &#8220;about me&#8221; page. Obviously, even five years since I have laced a pointe shoe, I am still coming to terms with &#8220;dancer&#8221; no longer being my main identifier. While I still have strong emotions associated with that time in my life, l do not regret the way everything panned out. I&#8217;ll tell you why. Then you can forget that I ever wrote anything so comically disappointing and go back to envisioning me in my underwear.</p>
<p>You see, had I not experienced this loss, I wouldn&#8217;t be here writing this. That&#8217;s right, I am tying this into writing, because that wasn&#8217;t predictable at all. The fact of it all, is that I could have made a career out of dance, but then I would have never known the dispassionate alternative that I experienced for several years after stepping out of that studio for the last time.</p>
<p>It is my strong belief that I would have eventually become complacent and dropped my dancing career out of pure inability to truly appreciate my love for it. I have been writing again for almost a year now, and because of this, I have the appreciation for writing that I never knew how to have for dance. And now I know what it is like to lose it.</p>
<p>So, while I no longer see dance in my future, what I do see in my future is a passion that is equally as important to me in a different way. Think of it in terms of relationships. You love and you lose. Those losses teach you to appreciate love for what it is. You then find love again in places that you never expected. You become enthralled again when you thought you never would. This time, you know to hold on to it. You know not to abandon it or take it for granted. And you won&#8217;t.</p>
<p><a href="http://25andfly.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/signature.png"><img title="signature" alt="becca cord signature" src="http://25andfly.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/signature.png?w=189&#038;h=100" width="189" height="100" /></a></p>
<div class="pd-rating" id="pd_rating_holder_5672555_post_2310"></div>
<h6 class="zemanta-related-title" style="font-size:1em;">Related articles</h6>
<ul class="zemanta-article-ul">
<li class="zemanta-article-ul-li"><a href="http://clownonfire.wordpress.com/2012/12/11/a-red-headed-woman/" target="_blank">A Red-Headed Woman</a> (clownonfire.wordpress.com)</li>
</ul>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://25tofly.com/category/how-i-knew/'>How I Knew</a>, <a href='http://25tofly.com/category/humor-2/'>Humor</a>, <a href='http://25tofly.com/category/inspirational-2/'>Inspirational</a> Tagged: <a href='http://25tofly.com/tag/25tofly/'>25tofly</a>, <a href='http://25tofly.com/tag/about-me/'>About Me</a>, <a href='http://25tofly.com/tag/art/'>Art</a>, <a href='http://25tofly.com/tag/ballet/'>Ballet</a>, <a href='http://25tofly.com/tag/becca-cord/'>Becca Cord</a>, <a href='http://25tofly.com/tag/becca-on-fire/'>becca on fire</a>, <a href='http://25tofly.com/tag/blog/'>blog</a>, <a href='http://25tofly.com/tag/blogging/'>Blogging</a>, <a href='http://25tofly.com/tag/business/'>business</a>, <a href='http://25tofly.com/tag/career-advice/'>career advice</a>, <a href='http://25tofly.com/tag/dance/'>Dance</a>, <a href='http://25tofly.com/tag/dancer-turned-writer/'>dancer turned writer</a>, <a href='http://25tofly.com/tag/education/'>Education</a>, <a href='http://25tofly.com/tag/funny/'>Funny</a>, <a href='http://25tofly.com/tag/humor/'>humor</a>, <a href='http://25tofly.com/tag/inspiration/'>Inspiration</a>, <a href='http://25tofly.com/tag/life/'>life</a>, <a href='http://25tofly.com/tag/marketing/'>Marketing</a>, <a href='http://25tofly.com/tag/nutcracker/'>Nutcracker</a>, <a href='http://25tofly.com/tag/performing-arts/'>Performing arts</a>, <a href='http://25tofly.com/tag/pointe-shoes/'>Pointe shoes</a>, <a href='http://25tofly.com/tag/wordpress/'>WordPress</a>, <a href='http://25tofly.com/tag/work/'>work</a>, <a href='http://25tofly.com/tag/writing-challenges/'>writing challenges</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2310/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2310/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2310&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://25tofly.com/2012/12/11/hanging-up-the-tutu/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>191</slash:comments>
		<georss:point>0.000000 0.000000</georss:point>
		<geo:lat>0.000000</geo:lat>
		<geo:long>0.000000</geo:long>
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/32f4b115691f837ea89ec7b1994fda10?s=96&#38;d=&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">becca3416</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://25andfly.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dance2-e1347387983261.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">becca cord in a tutu</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://25andfly.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/snoopy.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">snoopy in business</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://25andfly.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/signature.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">signature</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Letterpress</title>
		<link>http://amaryllislog.wordpress.com/2012/12/09/letterpress/</link>
		<comments>http://amaryllislog.wordpress.com/2012/12/09/letterpress/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2012 20:50:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>amaryllislog</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[craft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gifts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Guiness World Records]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hatch Show Print]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[letterpress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Minnesota Centerfor the Book Arts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recipe cards]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yee Haw Industries]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://amaryllislog.wordpress.com/?p=1619</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I learned how to print on a letterpress yesterday. It was an awesome experience. Here&#8217;s the back story; although most of the work I do is for the corporation I work for, from time to time we do pro bono work. Almost a year ago we did a letterhead system for the Minnesota Center for [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1619&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1622" alt="LP_7" src="http://amaryllislog.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/lp_7.jpg?w=590"   /></p>
<p>I learned how to print on a letterpress yesterday. It was an awesome experience. Here&#8217;s the back story; although most of the work I do is for the corporation I work for, from time to time we do pro bono work. Almost a year ago we did a letterhead system for the <a href="http://www.mnbookarts.org/">Minnesota Center for Book Arts</a>. As a thank you they allowed us to come for a day and learn to press type. It was just a small group of us, with lofty ideas. Quickly I figured out it takes a lot of time to set up type and prepare it for the press.</p>
<p>As you would expect, I took tons of pictures. The place is beautiful, full of old cool things including wood and lead type. There are drawers full of type and old advertising images. It was a surprise in each drawer. We probably spent the first hour just making discoveries. I think it dawned on all of us that we were going to need to make decisions and move along quickly if we wanted to make something in a day.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1650" alt="LP_3" src="http://amaryllislog.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/lp_3.jpg?w=590"   /></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1651" alt="LP_2" src="http://amaryllislog.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/lp_2.jpg?w=590"   /></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1652" alt="LP_1" src="http://amaryllislog.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/lp_1.jpg?w=590"   /></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1627" alt="LP_12" src="http://amaryllislog.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/lp_12.jpg?w=590"   /></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1626" alt="LP_11" src="http://amaryllislog.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/lp_11.jpg?w=590"   /></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1620" alt="LP_1_ds_eh" src="http://amaryllislog.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/lp_1_ds_eh.jpg?w=590"   /></p>
<p>David decided to make a poster for a friend&#8217;s band in the style of <a href="http://www.ryman.com/about/hatch/index.html">Hatch Show Print</a> and <a href="http://www.yeehawindustries.com/home.html">Yee Haw Industries</a>. Ed, well Ed&#8217;s a funny guy, he was making a poster for his 7 year old son who has decided he wants to be in the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Guinness_World_Records">Guinness World Records</a> for having the largest Afro, never mind he&#8217;s a white kid. The standard right now is 4 feet across in diameter. So instead of an Afro we&#8217;ve been calling it a Wafro…fair enough.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1634" alt="LP_20" src="http://amaryllislog.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/lp_20.jpg?w=590"   /></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1632" alt="LP_18" src="http://amaryllislog.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/lp_18.jpg?w=590"   /></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1637" alt="LP_23_eh_ha" src="http://amaryllislog.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/lp_23_eh_ha.jpg?w=590"   /></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1638" alt="LP_24" src="http://amaryllislog.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/lp_24.jpg?w=590"   /></p>
<p>It&#8217;s starting to come together nicely!</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1628" alt="LP_14" src="http://amaryllislog.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/lp_14.jpg?w=590"   /></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1645" alt="LP_29" src="http://amaryllislog.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/lp_29.jpg?w=590"   /></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1640" alt="LP_26" src="http://amaryllislog.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/lp_26.jpg?w=590"   /></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1636" alt="LP_22" src="http://amaryllislog.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/lp_22.jpg?w=590"   /></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1630" alt="LP_16" src="http://amaryllislog.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/lp_16.jpg?w=590"   /></p>
<p>Heidi went with a little simpler plan, greeting cards…</p>
<p>Oh what did I decided to make, well since this is all happening close to Christmas I wanted to make something I could give away. I&#8217;m not sure if I have told you too much about my Mom, she was an excellent cook in her day and really excelled in all things kitchen related, as in extraordinary! But now my mom has dementia and has forgotten a lot and can no longer cook. She loves the holidays but really can&#8217;t get out and shop anymore, so I thought I would make recipe cards using her name and print out some of her favorite holiday recipes for baked goods and give a set to family members from both of us.</p>
<p>My original plan was really elaborate but I had to scale back as I got into the details of setting the type and making the cards come to life.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1648" alt="LP_34" src="http://amaryllislog.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/lp_34.jpg?w=590"   /></p>
<p>I used a mix of wood type and metal type. I titled the cards &#8220;June&#8217;s treats&#8221;. The image above is the start of setting the type…</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1633" alt="LP_19" src="http://amaryllislog.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/lp_19.jpg?w=590"   /></p>
<p>At this point I&#8217;m prepping the press and building out the card. I have probably already spent 4 hours on this.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1647" alt="LP_32_blanks" src="http://amaryllislog.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/lp_32_blanks.jpg?w=590"   /></p>
<p>Pretty simple cards but I&#8217;m really happy with them. I pulled about 60 images.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1646" alt="LP_30_recipe_cards" src="http://amaryllislog.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/lp_30_recipe_cards.jpg?w=590"   /></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1631" alt="LP_17_cu_cards" src="http://amaryllislog.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/lp_17_cu_cards.jpg?w=590"   /></p>
<p>I wrote up the cards last night and made little packets tied with twine.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1654" alt="LP_gifts" src="http://amaryllislog.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/lp_gifts1.jpg?w=590"   /></p>
<p>The dining room table is now gift central…prepping, and packing for Christmas.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1644" alt="LP_28" src="http://amaryllislog.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/lp_28.jpg?w=590"   /></p>
<p>Parting shot of Heidi, truly a very satisfying day!</p>
<p>And one last plug; if you are in or around Minneapolis check out Minnesota Center for Book Arts. It&#8217;s really an incredible organization, with classes, a little history center and a shop. There is also a publisher located in the center.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1619/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1619/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1619&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://amaryllislog.wordpress.com/2012/12/09/letterpress/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://amaryllislog.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/lp_9-e1355086191270.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://amaryllislog.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/lp_9-e1355086191270.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">LP_9</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/1da0dd73abd4d7e87ee56a7d2d43e9ef?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">amaryllislog</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://amaryllislog.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/lp_7.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">LP_7</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://amaryllislog.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/lp_3.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">LP_3</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://amaryllislog.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/lp_2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">LP_2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://amaryllislog.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/lp_1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">LP_1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://amaryllislog.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/lp_12.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">LP_12</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://amaryllislog.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/lp_11.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">LP_11</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://amaryllislog.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/lp_1_ds_eh.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">LP_1_ds_eh</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://amaryllislog.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/lp_20.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">LP_20</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://amaryllislog.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/lp_18.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">LP_18</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://amaryllislog.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/lp_23_eh_ha.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">LP_23_eh_ha</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://amaryllislog.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/lp_24.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">LP_24</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://amaryllislog.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/lp_14.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">LP_14</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://amaryllislog.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/lp_29.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">LP_29</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://amaryllislog.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/lp_26.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">LP_26</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://amaryllislog.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/lp_22.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">LP_22</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://amaryllislog.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/lp_16.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">LP_16</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://amaryllislog.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/lp_34.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">LP_34</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://amaryllislog.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/lp_19.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">LP_19</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://amaryllislog.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/lp_32_blanks.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">LP_32_blanks</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://amaryllislog.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/lp_30_recipe_cards.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">LP_30_recipe_cards</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://amaryllislog.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/lp_17_cu_cards.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">LP_17_cu_cards</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://amaryllislog.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/lp_gifts1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">LP_gifts</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://amaryllislog.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/lp_28.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">LP_28</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Christmas Pining: A Matter of Difference</title>
		<link>http://philosophermouseofthehedge.wordpress.com/2012/12/11/christmas-pining-a-matter-of-difference/</link>
		<comments>http://philosophermouseofthehedge.wordpress.com/2012/12/11/christmas-pining-a-matter-of-difference/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2012 21:06:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>philosophermouseofthehedge</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christmas traditions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christmas tree]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[growing up Texas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[holidays]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opposites attract]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://philosophermouseofthehedge.wordpress.com/?p=12804</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It was a mixed marriage. Those did happen. The tall and short of it. She said violin He called fiddle. He preferring plays by Shakespeare. She adoring Robert Burns poetry. She a competitive bridge player reading books by experts for plans. He bluffing each bridge hand with a poker face It&#8217;s the opposites attract thing. She [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=12804&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It was a mixed marriage.</p>
<p>Those did happen.</p>
<div id="attachment_12820" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 486px"><img class=" wp-image-12820" alt="I Love Lucy. Nov 14, 1955 episode. (US public domain. Published without copyright notice:(1923-1977) / commons.wikimedia.org)" src="http://philosophermouseofthehedge.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/i-love-lucy-nov-14-1955-episode-us-public-domain-published-without-copyright-notice-1923-1977commons-wikimedia-org.jpg?w=476&#038;h=394" width="476" height="394" /><p class="wp-caption-text"></p>
<p></a> Not two of a kind. (Image: &#8220;I Love Lucy&#8221;, 11/14/1955. US public domain: published without copyright during 1923-1977. Commons.wikimedia.org)</p></div>
<p>The tall and short of it.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">She said violin</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">He called fiddle.</p>
<p>He preferring plays by Shakespeare.</p>
<p>She adoring <a title="Poetry and life of national poet of Scotland, Robert Burns (Poetry Foundations site)" href="http://www.poetryfoundation.org/bio/robert-burns" target="_blank"><strong><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Robert Burns</span></strong></a> poetry.</p>
<p>She a competitive bridge player reading books by experts for plans.</p>
<p>He bluffing each bridge hand with a poker face</p>
<div id="attachment_12819" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 333px"><img class=" wp-image-12819" alt="Publicity photo of &quot;The Munsters&quot; Aug.28,1964. CBS (US public domain. No copyright markings(1923-1977), for media/commons.wikimedia.org)" src="http://philosophermouseofthehedge.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/pulicity-photo-of-22the-munsters22-aug-281964-cbs-us-public-domain-no-copyright-markings1923-1977-for-mediacommons-wikimedia-org.jpg?w=323&#038;h=415" width="323" height="415" /><p class="wp-caption-text"></p>
<p></a> (Image: &#8220;The Munsters&#8221; Episode 8/28/1964. CBS publicity photo for media. No copyright. markings, 1923-1977. Commons.wikimedia.org)</p></div>
<p><strong>It&#8217;s the opposites attract thing.</strong></p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">She dipped and flowed through ballroom dancing.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">He <a title="Square dance lesson video" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yLebXcRZeSg" target="_blank"><strong>allemande left</strong></a> through dance squares.</p>
<p>Together, they choreographed life.</p>
<div id="attachment_12818" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 484px"><img class=" wp-image-12818" alt="before 1910. Becker,Friar Laurence's Cell, photo by Goupil(commons.wikimedia.org:US public domain. expired copyright, Eu. artist life+70yrs)" src="http://philosophermouseofthehedge.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/before-1090-beckerfriar-laurences-cell-photo-by-goupilcommons-wikimedia-orgus-public-domain-expired-copyright-eu-artist-life70yrs.jpg?w=474&#038;h=422" width="474" height="422" /><p class="wp-caption-text"></p>
<p></a> &#8220;Tis but thy name that is my enemy&#8230;&#8221;. Shakespeare. Act II si.ii from Romeo and Juliet. (Image: Friar Laurence&#8217;s Cell. Becker before 1910. Photo by Goupil. US public domain. expired copyright, Eu: artist life+70yrs./ Commons.wikimedia.org)</p></div>
<p><strong>Until Christmas</strong></p>
<p>She was all traditional: deep Williamsburg green with red velvet bows, white candles, and holly branches. Classic. elegant.</p>
<p>He was multicolored stings of lights on the house, wide red ribbon wrapped on porch posts like candy canes &#8211; with a lighted Santa&#8217;s head floating disemboweled &#8211; or strangled  - by extension chords.</p>
<p>All joy.</p>
<p><strong>She was practical and fair (to the penny) about giving presents so as &#8220;not to show favorites&#8221;. </strong></p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">One big one and stocking ones was enough.(Don&#8217;t be greedy.)</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">And &#8220;presents should always be something you really wanted but wouldn&#8217;t buy for yourself.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>He always placed an apple and an orange in each stocking. </strong></p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">As a farm kid, those were luxury items since they weren&#8217;t grown on the farm.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">Important you remember where you came from &#8211; and what&#8217;s important.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">And NEVER socks or underwear as Christmas presents. EVER. (more childhood memories?)</p>
<p>Pacing through life differently, but pulling together.</p>
<p><strong>One thing held in agreement: a pine tree is not a Christmas tree. </strong></p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">(Nor are silver aluminum ones.)</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">We grew pines: sappy, sticky, bushy.</p>
<p><strong>It would be a <a title="Santa and Sons. Douglas fir Christmas trees grown here" href="http://www.santasons.com/douglas-fir-christmas-trees.htm" target="_blank">Douglas fir:</a></strong></p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">Totally different smell.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">Totally different soft short needles.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">Totally special: from a different state.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">With branches spaced apart, so hanging ornament could swing and be seen.</p>
<p><strong>But the decorating styles.</strong></p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">She carefully placed the heavy silver icicles on the tree one by one while humming traditional carols.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">He danced with the kids and flung globs of icicles at the tree: whole handfuls. All wildly shrieking, &#8220;Ho, ho, ho!&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>Despite the cultural norm, we never went to church on Christmas.</strong></p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">&#8220;Leave room for all those who only go then.&#8221;</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">God knows who we are.</p>
<p><strong>We&#8217;d pack into the car and drive to the country</strong>.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">Small frame house with fireplace and wood stove for heat.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">Water drawn by bucket from the well.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">And a long way to walk in the cold if you needed the bathroom.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">(There was a chamber pot under the kids&#8217; beds at night, but no. Everyone would know.)</p>
<p><strong>After the car was unpacked and fires started, we&#8217;d go sit outside.</strong></p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">In the cold,</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">On concrete steps or old rough benches.</p>
<div id="attachment_12815" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 476px"><img class=" wp-image-12815 " alt="Quintuplet Cluster by NASA/Don Figer/STSci (Public domain: NASA Hubble./ commons.wikimedia.org)" src="http://philosophermouseofthehedge.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/quintuplet-cluster-1999-nasa-don-figerstsci-public-domainnasa-hubble-commons-wikimedia-org.jpg?w=466&#038;h=465" width="466" height="465" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Quintuplet Cluster by NASA/Don Figer/STSci (Public domain: NASA Hubble./ commons.wikimedia.org)</p></div>
<p><strong>He&#8217;d look up and say, &#8220;Look at all the stars. Couldn&#8217;t be a finer church than this. This is the way it was back then.&#8221;</strong></p>
<p>And we&#8217;d sing a carol or two.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">Loudly and joyfully.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">No neighbors near and the animals didn&#8217;t mind.</p>
<p><strong>Now, I pace preparations so it&#8217;s calm just before.</strong></p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">Select the perfect apple and orange for each stocking.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">Carefully drape the mylar icicles one by one on the tree.</p>
<p>And then go outside late Christmas night.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">The cool air.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">The smell of pines.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">The stars as the roof of the grandest cathedral.</p>
<div id="attachment_12816" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 486px"><img class=" wp-image-12816 " alt="NGC 288 HST. Hubble telescope sees stars (ESA/Hubble and NASA. Public domain/commons.wikimedia.org)" src="http://philosophermouseofthehedge.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/ngc-288-hst-hubble-telescope-stars-esahubble-and-nasa-public-domaincommons-wikimedia-org.jpg?w=476&#038;h=474" width="476" height="474" /><p class="wp-caption-text">NGC 288 HST. Hubble telescope sees stars (ESA/Hubble and NASA. Public domain/commons.wikimedia.org)</p></div>
<p><strong>Silent Night.</strong></p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">Just right.</p>
<p>Merry,</p>
<p>Phil, the Philosopher Mouse of the Hedge</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/12804/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/12804/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=12804&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://philosophermouseofthehedge.wordpress.com/2012/12/11/christmas-pining-a-matter-of-difference/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>52</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/97756c328953c2e60b434d1b396f1978?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">philosophermouseofthehedge</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://philosophermouseofthehedge.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/i-love-lucy-nov-14-1955-episode-us-public-domain-published-without-copyright-notice-1923-1977commons-wikimedia-org.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">I Love Lucy. Nov 14, 1955 episode. (US public domain. Published without copyright notice:(1923-1977) / commons.wikimedia.org)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://philosophermouseofthehedge.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/pulicity-photo-of-22the-munsters22-aug-281964-cbs-us-public-domain-no-copyright-markings1923-1977-for-mediacommons-wikimedia-org.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Publicity photo of &#34;The Munsters&#34; Aug.28,1964. CBS (US public domain. No copyright markings(1923-1977), for media/commons.wikimedia.org)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://philosophermouseofthehedge.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/before-1090-beckerfriar-laurences-cell-photo-by-goupilcommons-wikimedia-orgus-public-domain-expired-copyright-eu-artist-life70yrs.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">before 1910. Becker,Friar Laurence&#039;s Cell, photo by Goupil(commons.wikimedia.org:US public domain. expired copyright, Eu. artist life+70yrs)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://philosophermouseofthehedge.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/quintuplet-cluster-1999-nasa-don-figerstsci-public-domainnasa-hubble-commons-wikimedia-org.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Quintuplet Cluster by NASA/Don Figer/STSci (Public domain: NASA Hubble./ commons.wikimedia.org)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://philosophermouseofthehedge.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/ngc-288-hst-hubble-telescope-stars-esahubble-and-nasa-public-domaincommons-wikimedia-org.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">NGC 288 HST. Hubble telescope sees stars (ESA/Hubble and NASA. Public domain/commons.wikimedia.org)</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Argentines Know I&#8217;m From Somewhere Else</title>
		<link>http://freedmantravels.wordpress.com/2012/12/11/how-argentines-know-im-from-somewhere-else/</link>
		<comments>http://freedmantravels.wordpress.com/2012/12/11/how-argentines-know-im-from-somewhere-else/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2012 18:36:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>freedman121</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Argentina]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[South America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Buenos Aires]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[expat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Latin America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://freedmantravels.wordpress.com/?p=992</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[During my semester abroad in Buenos Aires I often had moments where I was not recognized as a foreigner. This may be because I was simply walking on the street and there was no way for passers by to tell, or perhaps because I was saying very little and trying to act inconspicuous. I am [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=992&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://freedmantravels.wordpress.com/2012/12/11/how-argentines-know-im-from-somewhere-else/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/df679ed7970cb08ab58d35715da5393c?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">freedman121</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://camp4online.com/images/2178-0032-12L.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Nalgene</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Finding Home: Our Soul Cultures</title>
		<link>http://tradingplacesglobal.wordpress.com/2012/12/11/finding-home-our-soul-cultures/</link>
		<comments>http://tradingplacesglobal.wordpress.com/2012/12/11/finding-home-our-soul-cultures/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2012 14:15:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Shelley Seale</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[EXPLORE]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[feature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[India]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tradingplacesglobal.wordpress.com/?p=1417</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Have you ever had that moment when traveling to a new and unfamiliar place—maybe you&#8217;ve already journeyed all over the world, maybe it&#8217;s one of your first experiences—but suddenly, you are somewhere you know you were just meant to be. A place that resonates deep inside you; a place where you feel more like yourself [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1417&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://tradingplacesglobal.wordpress.com/2012/12/11/finding-home-our-soul-cultures/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>35</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tradingplacesglobal.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/8763_10152291488275720_1159281748_n.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tradingplacesglobal.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/8763_10152291488275720_1159281748_n.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">8763_10152291488275720_1159281748_n</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a1f39fe8efde66f0f3e2b3d52f774453?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Namaste</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tradingplacesglobal.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/192573_10152300818350720_168143492_o.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">192573_10152300818350720_168143492_o</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tradingplacesglobal.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/224105_10152274006455705_1178568661_n-1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">224105_10152274006455705_1178568661_n (1)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tradingplacesglobal.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/399233_10152292273630720_1113346512_n.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">399233_10152292273630720_1113346512_n</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Will I Raise My Children?</title>
		<link>http://kimberlyavalos.wordpress.com/2012/12/11/how-will-i-raise-my-children/</link>
		<comments>http://kimberlyavalos.wordpress.com/2012/12/11/how-will-i-raise-my-children/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2012 18:48:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>The Cultural Columnist</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parenting]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://kimberlyavalos.wordpress.com/?p=93</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Three years ago I had been working at a kid’s summer camp as a camp counselor in Parsippany, New Jersey. I was having a bad day. My boss called me over to his “bench” and asked me what was wrong. I answered I was sorry for crying but I was having a bad day. He [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=93&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://kimberlyavalos.wordpress.com/2012/12/11/how-will-i-raise-my-children/imagescaw1q7tc/" rel="attachment wp-att-94"><img class="size-full wp-image-94 aligncenter" style="width:298px;height:209px;" alt="imagesCAW1Q7TC" src="http://kimberlyavalos.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/imagescaw1q7tc.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>Three years ago I had been working at a kid’s summer camp as a camp counselor in Parsippany, New Jersey. I was having a bad day.</p>
<p>My boss called me over to his “bench” and asked me what was wrong.</p>
<p>I answered I was sorry for crying but I was having a bad day.</p>
<p>He insisted for me to tell him what was bothering me, in sort of an annoyed tone that indicated he probably didn’t take me seriously.</p>
<p>I didn’t want to tell him for any particular reason except I didn’t like him, and didn’t trust him with my personal problems.</p>
<p>That was confirmed when he said what could possibly be bothering a teenager. He added that I wasn’t a married man with two children and two jobs.</p>
<p>So I told him. My house had gone into foreclosure because my parents were struggling with the mortgage payments. I had to leave work early to take care of my three-year-old sister while my parents went to work. I hadn’t slept well for the past few nights because I work all-day/late-night shifts during the weekends at a catering hall and had to wake up early for this job.</p>
<p>That provoked some surprise, but he didn’t let go of his pride.</p>
<p>He insisted I shouldn’t be worrying about that stuff, because I am too young and those aren’t my problems. That those are issues my parents should be enduring and I shouldn’t be involved or burdened with them.</p>
<p>He went on and on how I should be focused on school work and how I shouldn’t bother myself with issues I would have enough of as I got older.</p>
<p>As a sixteen year old, I was somewhat confused if he was right, and I reflected on my upbringing.                                                          ____________</p>
<p>I had a great childhood. My wonderful mother provided me with enriching experiences that nourishes the childhood mind: such as trips to parks as well as other countries. She read me many books and involved me in activities and took us to parties and allowed us to socialize.</p>
<p>But I cannot ignore that the hardships of life were not kept from me as I got older. Not intentionally, but things happen. Some I learned as they directly affected me in my life but others I also witnessed as they affected others.</p>
<p>I was maybe ten when I learned a family member was adopted. She didn’t know and I am not sure if she even knows today. But I was told it was a secret and that her parents wanted to keep that from her.</p>
<p>My cousin moved in with us with her grandma shortly after. I learned that she called her “mom” because she raised her. Her father was in Spain. My cousin was told that her mother left her when she was a child and her dad couldn’t take her to Spain because of the paperwork. The reality, however, was that her grandma took her from her mother and didn’t allow her to see her and her father moved to Spain to ignore his responsibilities as a father.</p>
<p>My father cheated on my mother when I was fourteen. My mother found out she was pregnant soon after, with his child of course, but in an effort to make his big mistake less terrible, my father paid for a DNA test to confirm the baby was his. Whether it was for attention or whether he really thought he could prove my mom was unfaithful as well, I don’t know.</p>
<p>When my beautiful sister was born, my mom did not have the luxury to stay at home and care for her. So I did, along with my other sister.</p>
<p>I’ve had my share of adversity, and although it caused me great suffering, I wouldn’t have had it any other way. Because I am a better person because of it. These experiences shaped who I am and who I will become. I am someone attuned to a sometimes painful reality and not ignorant to what life is about. I have grown as a person when dealing with it. I am not scornful, or angry, or resentful, and I should be. Because, like I said, I am a better person.</p>
<p>So then my boss says these are adult problems. And I should have nothing to do with them, that I should ignore the struggles of my family, even though they affect my family.</p>
<p>But on the other hand, I can’t help but wonder how easier it would have been to not have to deal with everything. After all, ignorance truly is bliss.</p>
<p>So the big question that rose from all this is how will I raise my children? Will I keep them from witnessing, experiencing, or enduring hardships in exchange for the ignorant happiness of childhood innocence?</p>
<p>Parents nowadays seem to go for the extremes: either an extremely privileged life for their children or one where “adult problems” become their children’s problems as well.</p>
<p>I think I’ll go for the balance. Although hardships teach wisdom, humility, and acceptance, too much adversity results in a pretty tragic lifestyle. And there’s no surprise that a privileged life is one disconnected from reality. You have to keep it real.</p>
<p>This does not mean I will vent to my children of the difficulties I will go through, but it will be no secret. I will not shun them from what life may take away or throw at us because these experiences are for growth and learning. But I will not shun them from what life can offer either. Because above all, life is to be enjoyed.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/93/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/93/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=93&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://kimberlyavalos.wordpress.com/2012/12/11/how-will-i-raise-my-children/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>42</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/22a7e15dda0f47dd77f036d3d7c6962e?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">kimberlyavalos</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://kimberlyavalos.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/imagescaw1q7tc.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">imagesCAW1Q7TC</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Three Realistic Commercials the Public Deserves</title>
		<link>http://drewthegoose.wordpress.com/2012/12/11/three-realistic-commercials-that-the-public-deserves/</link>
		<comments>http://drewthegoose.wordpress.com/2012/12/11/three-realistic-commercials-that-the-public-deserves/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2012 17:49:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>drewgieseke</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Lists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comedy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commerical]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[funny]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kay jewelers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pizza hut]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[under armour]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://drewthegoose.wordpress.com/?p=166</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As an individual who has taken four marketing classes (two of which were in high school), I feel as though I’m a bit of an expert when it comes to analyzing advertisements. I’ve always enjoyed watching commercials because they can be dissected in fun and interesting ways, and now that we don’t have DVR at [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=166&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone" alt="" src="http://a3.img.mobypicture.com/cfb21e50b464395fb11c66032ba96227_view.jpg" width="600" height="447" /></p>
<p>As an individual who has taken four marketing classes (two of which were in high school), I feel as though I’m a bit of an expert when it comes to analyzing advertisements. I’ve always enjoyed watching commercials because they can be dissected in fun and interesting ways, and now that we don’t have DVR at my apartment, we have no choice but to watch them. After careful consideration (like 20 minutes), I’ve come up with three realistic commercials that the public deserves to see.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>1. Pizza Hut</p>
<p>Lately Pizza Hut’s commercials have been featuring their latest abortion, the Big Dinner Box, which includes two rectangular pizzas, garlic bread, cinnamon dippers, some chicken wings or something, and sauces all for only $10. This sounds like a fantastic bargain, especially if you’re looking to have a heart attack.</p>
<p>The public deserves the truth. Pizza Hut’s next advertisement needs to stick with the same format that they’ve been using. Two or three young guys are sitting around on red couches, talking about how they don’t have enough money to feed themselves. One guy remembers having a nightmare about Pizza Hut and their new box of cholesterol, and they go through their apartment to find <i>exactly</i> the $10 that they needed – I shouldn’t have to explain why this is wrong. They call and place their order.</p>
<p>Pizza guy shows up, “That’ll be $13.78.” The two guys look at each other. “Oh shit, I thought it was only $10?” They forgot the delivery charge, plus taxes. Because they’re stoned out of their minds – did you see that coming? In exchange, they give the driver some weed and everybody’s cool. Finally! Time for the guys to dig in. They each grab a slice and take the biggest bite you’ve ever seen. There’s a loud <i>crunch</i>. They inspect the pizza. Turns out, it’s cardboard. Somebody at the Pizza Hut store put tomato sauce, processed cheese, and pepperoni flakes on a rectangular piece of cardboard. The two guys eat it anyway, because hey, they can’t let that weed go to waste.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>2. Under Armour</p>
<p>Everyone has seen those obnoxious Under Armour commercials. They’re the ones where there’s a bunch of jacked 30-year-olds yelling at each other in some high school football locker room. They’re pumped up, man. They’re going to beat the shit out of some kids that haven’t even hit puberty yet.</p>
<p>In reality, <i>maybe</i> 5 percent of people that wear Under Armour actually look and act like that. The public deserves a commercial where you’ve got some flabby country-looking guy shivering out in the cold. He’s hunting, obviously, and didn’t wear the proper attire to keep himself warm. Instead of the typical Under Armour montage (guys wearing cleats and football pants – no shirt – and running up bleachers), you have this guy working late nights at the local gas station. He’s selling people scratcher tickets, mopping up puke, getting robbed at gunpoint, selling alcohol to minors, etc. Finally, he saves up enough money to buy a $60 long-sleeve Under Armour shirt that fits him until he washes it. He looks into the mirror with the shirt on, belly hanging out, and says, “Dammit.”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>3. Kay Jewelers</p>
<p>By far the most annoying commercials on TV today are the Kay Jeweler ads. If you’re ever having trouble deciding whether you should get married or not, watch a Kay commercial. Chances are that you’ll want to treat your love life like it’s a VH1 reality dating show after watching one of Kay’s ads. There’s one in particular where some dude proposes on a plane, and everybody onboard loves it. A more realistic ad would have the same proposal, except half the people are groaning and rolling their eyes. But that’s not good enough.</p>
<p>The public deserves a <i>real</i> proposal. A girl walks out of the bathroom at the local high school. Her eyes are red from crying and her head is hung low. She approaches her boyfriend, who begins to console her. “Everything will be alright, we can do this.” They move in together and drop out of school. They fight and she smokes. He drinks because his older brother works at the bar just down the road. One day, he comes home from his job working as a part-time mechanic. He drops a little black box from Kay Jewelers onto the fold-up card table that she’s sitting at.</p>
<p>“Since I got you pregnant, we might as well get married.”</p>
<p>“Okay.”</p>
<p>Screen cuts to black background with “Kay Jewelers” in silver writing.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/166/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/166/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=166&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://drewthegoose.wordpress.com/2012/12/11/three-realistic-commercials-that-the-public-deserves/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>43</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/5799c1ce40e519ec98c429e4c9ff5510?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">drewgieseke</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://a3.img.mobypicture.com/cfb21e50b464395fb11c66032ba96227_view.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pregnan-sucky</title>
		<link>http://curiodyssey.wordpress.com/2012/12/11/pregnan-sucky/</link>
		<comments>http://curiodyssey.wordpress.com/2012/12/11/pregnan-sucky/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2012 18:06:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>kt</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Comedy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pregnancy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[B.C.]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Damn you Anthem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Louisville]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lump]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nausea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pregnan-sucky]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://curiodyssey.wordpress.com/?p=150</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I am pregnant. I am pregnant and unable to move off the couch. I am pregnant and a newlywed and instead of wearing cute, slinky things for my new husband, I live in bathrobes and don&#8217;t shower for days. I am pregnant and it sucks. I am excited, don&#8217;t get me wrong, but only as [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=150&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I am pregnant. I am pregnant and unable to move off the couch. I am pregnant and a newlywed and instead of wearing cute, slinky things for my new husband, I live in bathrobes and don&#8217;t shower for days. I am pregnant and it sucks. I am excited, don&#8217;t get me wrong, but only as excited as one can be in between bouts of barfing.</p>
<p>This baby is due exactly 9 months and 2 days after our wedding date which is cute and efficient, but it was not my plan to be pregnant so soon. My husband and I had plans to spend the better part of our first year of marriage here in Kentucky near my family and our friends, getting our affairs in order before moving to Canada in June. Now instead of June it looks like we will be moving up to B.C. much earlier than planned and probably while it is still snowing- so much for easing into my new surroundings starting with the perfect Canadian summer. Oh how plans change.</p>
<p>I wanted to be in Canada before starting the baby-making because Kristan&#8217;s family farm in B.C. is the quietest, cleanest, most serene place I have ever been. I envisioned myself having a beautiful, calm pregnancy surrounded by gorgeous wilderness way out in the middle of nowhere. Instead, Anthem kicked me off my birth control months before my wedding (See: <a title="Baby by Anthem" href="http://curiodyssey.wordpress.com/2012/12/11/baby-by-anthem/">Baby by Anthem</a>), and while they did not technically impregnate me, I blame them for the fact that I am here in Louisville, pregnant, and far from the serene wilderness I had imagined.</p>
<p>The city, while fun, is not my idea of peaceful. We live downtown and it is noisy all day and night with cars and airplanes and sirens and music screaming from stereos. It is so bright at night that you can practically read without a lamp on and I often need to sleep with an eye mask on to get any rest at all, though the stupid mask falls off all night and keeps me up anyway. The city is crowded and people are irritating and scary- particularly on the roads where everyone turns into Stupidicus from Goofy&#8217;s driving videos. Instead of resting on a porch in a rocking chair high up in the Rocky Mountains, I am tossing and turning at night and cursing at people cutting me off in traffic and putting in ear plugs just so I can read peacefully on my couch. Here we are, my little Lump and me, in the noisy city, doing this thing despite my visions to the contrary.</p>
<p>I am excited to be pregnant, like I said. I waffled back and forth most of my life about wanting children until I met Kristan and then there was no question- from the moment I met him I knew this man would be a great partner and a great father. In fact, I started taking prenatal vitamins less than 6 months into our relationship- I was that sure about this one. While motherhood was not always a definite in my mind, I always coveted a cute pregnant belly in the same way I wished for my little boobies to sprout when I was a pre-teen. I was wrong about the boobies: they are far more trouble than they are worth, and even though I am far from having that cute, classic, pregnant-girl silhouette, I know already that I was poorly mistaken about this too.</p>
<p>This pregnancy thing is not fun, not glowing, and certainly not peaceful. I would like to rename it &#8220;pregnan-sucky,&#8221; because that is how it feels. I anticipated morning sickness and nausea, but those were just words that I thought I knew the meaning of and, as it turns out, I was very, very wrong. Nausea to me implies an upset stomach and an achy body, which I have, but this is not a nausea that I have ever known. Being a person who is prone to motion sickness, I am used to nausea and find it is usually tolerable and treatable with a short nap. THIS thing is not just nausea, and it&#8217;s not just morning either. This thing is the worst headache of my life all day, every day, and I was totally unprepared for the crushing, head-splitting, brain pain that accompanies this &#8220;beautiful event.&#8221; I feel like Peter from the movie The Office Space, when he tells the hypnotist that every day is the worst day of his life, to which the hypnotist replies &#8220;that&#8217;s messed up.&#8221; Yes, yes it is messed up.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m sure that my sickness is also exacerbated by the fact that I am a total wimp and complain all the time about how bad I feel. I am sure that if I simply switched my attention to something else I could possibly distract myself from my misery, but so far I have been unsuccessful with any strategy besides just wallowing in it. &#8220;It&#8217;ll be over soon,&#8221; and &#8220;it&#8217;ll all be worth it in the end,&#8221; are common, infuriating mantras that people spew at me all the time- words that are not comforting in the least because it&#8217;s not later I am worried about- it&#8217;s right now and the fact that my head&#8217;s about to explode like one of Gallagher&#8217;s watermelons. Saying these things to me while I am so pathetically miserable is like saying &#8220;I know how you feel,&#8221; when someone you love dies. It&#8217;s inappropriate people.</p>
<p>Another completely unhelpful bit of advice: &#8220;eat some crackers before you get out of bed to help control the nausea.&#8221; There is no amount nor type of food or beverage that prevents or even relieves this a tiny bit. A delicious pizza can distract me for a minute, but there are still a whole lot of non-pizza minutes in a day that must be tolerated. So the best thing I can do so far is to stay horizontal. I lay on the couch or in bed for 22 hours of the day right now because standing up escalates the pain exponentially and makes me 100% more prone to barfing. With Kristan home over the weekends it is much easier because he cooks for me when I am hungry and brings me what I need so I can rest. He is all about me and this baby eating homemade, unprocessed foods and he bakes fresh bread and makes casseroles and whole turkeys and all kinds of other delicious things nightly, which, unfortunately, I can barely eat any of because this baby seems to tolerate only foods with yellow #7 and red #40. It&#8217;s a travesty. I have the best husband in the world cooking for me and instead I hide Cheetos and Big Red in my car to sustain myself. This child is going to look like it was fathered by an oompa loompa.</p>
<p>While I already feel like an unfit mother, it is at least a little comforting to know that I am not the only one feeling duped and hating those smiling, lying women on the cover of books like <em>What to Expect When You&#8217;re Expecting</em>. There are actual books out there written by women like me &#8211; books based on the true reality and misery of this pregnancy thing, such as  <em>Pregnancy Sucks</em> by Joanne Kimes who writes the blog <a href="http://www.sucksandthecity.com">Sucks and the City</a>, and <em>It Sucked Then I Cried</em> by Heather Armstrong, author of the blog <a href="http://dooce.com">Dooce</a>. At least I know I am not alone in being unable to lie and tell people that this is fun and I feel great when in reality I want to roll up in a ball and cry. I haven&#8217;t read either book but I definitely will while I&#8217;m stuck here, glued to my couch, feeling pregnan-sucky.</p>
<br /> Tagged: <a href='http://curiodyssey.wordpress.com/tag/b-c/'>B.C.</a>, <a href='http://curiodyssey.wordpress.com/tag/damn-you-anthem/'>Damn you Anthem</a>, <a href='http://curiodyssey.wordpress.com/tag/humor/'>humor</a>, <a href='http://curiodyssey.wordpress.com/tag/louisville/'>Louisville</a>, <a href='http://curiodyssey.wordpress.com/tag/lump/'>Lump</a>, <a href='http://curiodyssey.wordpress.com/tag/marriage/'>marriage</a>, <a href='http://curiodyssey.wordpress.com/tag/nausea/'>nausea</a>, <a href='http://curiodyssey.wordpress.com/tag/pregnan-sucky/'>pregnan-sucky</a>, <a href='http://curiodyssey.wordpress.com/tag/pregnancy/'>pregnancy</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/150/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/150/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/150/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/150/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/150/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/150/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/150/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/150/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/150/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/150/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/150/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/150/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/150/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/150/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=150&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://curiodyssey.wordpress.com/2012/12/11/pregnan-sucky/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>32</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a5d23b33b04d8131fa17ade821198b18?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">katesum</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
