<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2012 23:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Guatemala: Spiritual Earthquakes</title>
		<link>http://stealthchristian.wordpress.com/2012/11/06/guatemala-spiritual-earthquakes/</link>
		<comments>http://stealthchristian.wordpress.com/2012/11/06/guatemala-spiritual-earthquakes/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2012 22:17:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>beth</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[christianity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[guatemala]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jesus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mission]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spirituality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transformation]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://stealthchristian.wordpress.com/?p=591</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Our mission team, the Guatemalan coordinator, the Guatemalan pastor, and an interpreter are all gathered in the church in Guatemala City. Carlo the digital tune master has cool sounds wafting in the background.  Someone supplied us with instant coffee and pastries filled with cheese and ham. This meeting is to give us a chance to [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=591&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Our mission team, the Guatemalan coordinator, the Guatemalan pastor, and an interpreter are all gathered in the church in Guatemala City. Carlo the digital tune master has cool sounds wafting in the background.  Someone supplied us with instant coffee and pastries filled with cheese and ham. This meeting is to give us a chance to share our experiences: our five-day medical mission is over. We’d provided medical care and distributed food, among other things, to villagers in Tierra Linda.</p>
<p>“A lot of people don’t need food, they need love,” the coordinator tells us. “You don’t need to talk a lot to them &#8211; just your presence is enough. Children never forget someone playing with them, someone sharing their heart.”</p>
<p>The mission doctor, who’s a surgeon back home, stands. “I have problems at work and problems at home.” His self-control begins to disintegrate. “The problems affect my spiritual life. I was growing away from the Lord.” He grips the chair in front of him and looks down until he can talk without his voice cracking. “The harmony of the team has put things back in perspective.” He hugs a team member and sits down.</p>
<p>Dave helped in the dental clinic. He’s a storage facility manager in real life. He stands. “I have a confession to make.” His face is blotchy with raw emotion. “I expected to come here and see poor, lazy people. I was wrong.” He whips his glasses off to mop up tears with his sleeve. “I was wrong. They are industrious people with faith.”</p>
<p>Tom, a nurse, says, “This is where we come to have God work on our hearts.”</p>
<p>Many others on the mission team share their lessons learned. Some of the testifiers are men, many are women. All swab tears and struggle to tell their stories without breaking down.</p>
<p>Those of us listening are swallowing big lumps in our throats. The meeting has been going on a long time. I gotta go to the bathroom. Variations of the sentiment “It seems like we get more than we give,” reaches cliché status.</p>
<p>Then the Guatemalan pastor goes to the lectern. Carlo decreases the decibels of a jazz riff.</p>
<p>Reading our minds, the pastor asks, “In five days, what can you do?” The pastor’s question grabs our attention.  “An earthquake that lasts five seconds can change people’s lives.”</p>
<p>Earthquakes are a regular phenomenon in Central America. I experienced one years ago in Taiwan that flattened tall buildings, pulverized villages, and rerouted rivers.</p>
<p>The pastor says, “You created a spiritual earthquake!”</p>
<p>Tears blur my vision.</p>
<p>Of course, the pastor is right. We call it “quality time” in the States. It’s not the amount of time we spent in Guatemala that made a difference in people’s lives. It’s what we did, sharing ourselves in Jesus’ name.</p>
<p>And now I’m thinking that the same is true no matter where we are. It’s how we share our hearts that matters, not how much clock time we eat up doing it.</p>
<p>The pastor ends with a phrase that rhymes in Spanish, and is translated as “You need courage to be different so you can make a difference.” He cites Romans 12:2 “Do not conform to the pattern of this world, but be transformed by the renewing of your mind. Then you will be able to test and approve what God’s will is—his good, pleasing and perfect will.”</p>
<p>It’s clear from everyone’s testimonies and the pastor’s comments that we received more than we gave. Or more accurately, we received something different from what we gave. A spiritual earthquake shredded our stereotypes, recalibrated mindsets, reset defaults.</p>
<p><a href="http://stealthchristian.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/guat-grandma-grand.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-592" title="guat grandma &amp; grand" alt="" src="http://stealthchristian.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/guat-grandma-grand.jpg?w=300&#038;h=232" height="232" width="300" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/591/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/591/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=591&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://stealthchristian.wordpress.com/2012/11/06/guatemala-spiritual-earthquakes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/57237e4b1c3301cf744d19fb6b32895d?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">apples33d</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://stealthchristian.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/guat-grandma-grand.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">guat grandma &#38; grand</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Impossible Things</title>
		<link>http://gregoryblake.net/2012/11/04/impossible-things/</link>
		<comments>http://gregoryblake.net/2012/11/04/impossible-things/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2012 07:30:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Greg</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Anki SRS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[C#]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Epistemology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Futurism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Japanese]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Knowledge Acquisition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mastery vs. Competence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Methodology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Programming]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://gregoryblake.net/?p=211</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Last week Thursday, I chatted briefly with a coworker about my experiences working in C#. My day job requires that I program on occasion, and so I do. My coworker wants to learn how to code, and so I&#8217;m teaching. You&#8217;d think I&#8217;d be a terrible teacher. My code&#8217;s functional, but inelegant. My relationship to [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=211&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last week Thursday, I chatted briefly with a coworker about my experiences working in C#.</p>
<p>My day job requires that I program on occasion, and so I do. My coworker wants to learn how to code, and so I&#8217;m teaching.</p>
<p>You&#8217;d think I&#8217;d be a terrible teacher. My code&#8217;s functional, but inelegant. My relationship to programming and math are the same as my view towards water. Definitely has purpose, but no desire to be drowned in it. I don&#8217;t enjoy the act of programming, like I enjoy the act of writing. I just enjoy the result. Hence, I&#8217;ll never be elevated to programming black belt.</p>
<p>When I told my coworker this, he responded, &#8220;What do you mean? You&#8217;re coding right now. What more&#8217;s there to it?&#8221;<span id="more-211"></span></p>
<p>&#8220;It takes me minutes googling examples and referencing others&#8217; code. Real programmers don&#8217;t constantly need Google search and MSDN. Also, I can only code for fifteen minutes straight at a time before my eyes get grindy. My tolerance is increasing all the time, but this is where I am. Besides, if I loved it, I&#8217;d be way, way better, because I&#8217;d have made an Anki deck for MSDN libraries and have memorized all the facts. Boom, no more referencing. Forget code master, I&#8217;d be a code god.&#8221;</p>
<p>In Japanese, I defeated the very problem stymieing my C# learning. I recognize all the grammar, and can even use it if given time, but I lack the vocabulary to meaningfully create. So I search my Japanese dictionary, or MSDN for methods to invoke, since I&#8217;ve used those things too rarely. A master runs a compiler with the virtuoso skill of a novelist at composition, and because I&#8217;m unwilling to slog through the tedious fact memorization for programming, I&#8217;ll never elevate myself beyond a merely serviceable programmer.</p>
<p>Is this a problem? No. My productivity&#8217;s still high. I&#8217;m rarely to never blocked. But this is mainly thanks to a keen understanding of epistemology and methodology. In short, my knowledge base sucks, but my knowledge acquisition rate&#8217;s pretty damn high. I&#8217;ve got super-studying for my superpower, and that&#8217;s about it, other than my chiseled jawline and razor-sharp wit.</p>
<p>So what&#8217;s my point here? Facts are a bitch is my point.</p>
<p>For these purposes, a fact would be a question that can be answered in ten seconds or less. In other words, if you can make a flash card of it. Facts are the building blocks of higher creative functions, and are usually acquired through sheer brute-force memorization.</p>
<p>The modern world overwhelms us with facts, and I&#8217;ve heard constant complaints about how impossible it is to manage all the data a functional professional needs. I never understood this, because if you&#8217;ve got a great reference manual or a search engine, and some time to burn, facts pale before the power of effective epistemology and methodology. The problem is, people still think that thorough experts exist. I&#8217;m certainly thorough, but I&#8217;m rarely an expert. Experts know the facts, whereas I just go and look them up.</p>
<p>In some cases, local storage of facts cannot be avoided. Think speaking a foreign language, programming languages, medicine, and so on. How then, do these professionals manage their fact-load? No different than any other time in history. Through brute-force memorization.</p>
<p>On a tangential note, this weekend, my mom mentioned that many students in her algebra classes get problems wrong due to arithmetic errors. She expresses her frustration succinctly: &#8220;How can I teach algebra when I&#8217;m busy teaching math?&#8221; Here&#8217;s another teacher, tripped up by facts. Mom can&#8217;t teach methodology or epistemology, or any higher function things, because the building blocks for her students to understand the more complex discourse don&#8217;t exist.</p>
<p>So here&#8217;s a question. Why do we keep having teachers hit on facts? What if a teacher didn&#8217;t have to?</p>
<p>It&#8217;s no teacher&#8217;s job to teach me the 8311 vocabulary words that I have in my JLPT1 deck for Anki. Why should it be a teacher&#8217;s job to teach students their multiplication tables out to 20? Imagine if Anki did that, and we added all those facts to it over time. The students would be reviewing subject matter from their entire school career constantly, so that even high school seniors would still see the 2+2 flash card once every 3 years or so. That 8311 card deck of mine? I only review 60 of those cards a day due to the concept of Spaced Repetition, i.e., that if you get a card right, you need to see it less.</p>
<p>We&#8217;d spend less time teaching each fact, so we&#8217;d spend more time teaching more facts, or we could teach people how to cope with information processing and understanding which facts matter to them, a much more important endeavor in this information-glutted world. We could teach critical thinking.</p>
<p>Imagine the compound learning a child could acquire if we implemented this starting with the alphabet and arithmetic in kindergarten? The number of reviews grows infinitesimal over the course of a couple years, but the net effect would be infrequent refreshers of everything the student learned since kindergarten, reactive to the needs of each individual student&#8217;s memory. We do this for facts in science, literature, history, whatever we want our munchkins&#8217; brains filled with.</p>
<p>Imagine a world where retention rates on last year&#8217;s subjects exceeded 90%. Imagine a world where reviewing last year&#8217;s work wasn&#8217;t the teacher&#8217;s job. Imagine a world where a teacher could focus on teaching new things, rather than rehashing old things. What would that world be like? What would those students&#8217; stupid friggin&#8217; standardized test scores be like?</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a nice thought.</p>
<p>Incidentally, I&#8217;m building a prototype mod to Anki with this eventual purpose in mind. I doubt it&#8217;ll catch on, but mom wants something to help drill arithmetic into struggling kids in a tailored way, and I can think of no better out of the box solution.</p>
<p>And so even now, programming&#8217;s not a bad tool for a man who believes in impossible things.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/211/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/211/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=211&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://gregoryblake.net/2012/11/04/impossible-things/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/587210a456b74eb76ff55a63a05131f7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">kenseimaedhros</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Pace Of Change</title>
		<link>http://hdthomas.wordpress.com/2012/11/06/the-pace-of-change/</link>
		<comments>http://hdthomas.wordpress.com/2012/11/06/the-pace-of-change/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2012 20:35:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Huw Thomas</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pagan's Sphinx]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[research for writers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://hdthomas.wordpress.com/?p=855</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[How life has changed. It used to be so different. Does anyone else remember their shelves groaning under the weight of all those books? For a writer it&#8217;s incredibly easy now. Want to research some obscure topic? Just go to Google and start searching. But take a moment and &#8211; unless you were born any [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=855&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://hdthomas.wordpress.com/2012/11/06/the-pace-of-change/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/9c4a675f19c83ee59c2a0f2eb53390f8?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">huwt</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hdthomas.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/clock.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">clock</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Theory of Love</title>
		<link>http://entropy.wordpress.com/2012/11/06/a-theory-of-love/</link>
		<comments>http://entropy.wordpress.com/2012/11/06/a-theory-of-love/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2012 22:55:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>entrope</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[absurd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[random observations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[oh dear]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[philosophy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[things to live up to]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[warnings]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://entropy.wordpress.com/?p=1759</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I know that there are uses for categories and labels.  They are very useful for categorizing people, for putting a layer of distance between yourself and someone that you need to leave behind for whatever reason.  Even when you don&#8217;t need the distance and it&#8217;s just a function of trying to make life easier.  I&#8217;m an [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1759&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I know that there are uses for categories and labels.  They are very useful for categorizing people, for putting a layer of distance between yourself and someone that you need to leave behind for whatever reason.  Even when you don&#8217;t need the distance and it&#8217;s just a function of trying to make life easier.  I&#8217;m an INTP.  You&#8217;re an ESFJ.  This means that we should some how be able to predict each other.  I&#8217;m a Cancer, you&#8217;re an Aries.  I already know this is going to end in disaster.</p>
<p>Except, of course, you never fall in love with someone&#8217;s resume.  And all of those traits that land you in the DSM really just mean that you&#8217;re relentlessly flawed and therefore relentlessly human.  I don&#8217;t know anyone who isn&#8217;t a little screwy in some way or another.</p>
<p>So what are you going to do?  Love is already as improbable as an aardvark.  It&#8217;s classic risk-taking behavior that ought to be treated by medication.  It&#8217;s a disease in and of itself.  It&#8217;s also the only thing worth throwing yourself at in this mess we call life.</p>
<p>And we&#8217;ve been lied to about what it is and what it looks like.  It isn&#8217;t always Prince Charming.  Sometimes it is  your best friend that you never saw that way before.  Sometimes it is an idea or a cause.  Sometimes it&#8217;s the whole mess of humanity.</p>
<p>Romantic comedies lie, television shows lie, trashy romance novels lie.  It&#8217;s not clean, it isn&#8217;t clear cut, it isn&#8217;t something you do once and then you get to coast for the rest of your life in a champagne bubble of bliss.   There&#8217;s no classic story arc here.   You don&#8217;t meet, misunderstand once, meet again, and live happily ever after.  If you get that arc at all, it&#8217;s one that&#8217;s repeated once a day.  Maybe once a week.  Once a month if you&#8217;re lucky and once a year if you&#8217;re exceptional.</p>
<p>Every day you get up and you get dirty and you get cut and sometimes those cuts get infected.  Some days you hang on by your teeth and some days by your broken fingernails.  You fight and you f*ck and you fall down, and then you get up the next morning and you do it all over again.  You go further, grow more compassion, do things a rational person would never do, hurt each other, rebuild stronger than before&#8230;</p>
<p>And as long as you&#8217;re doing it together, as long as your strongest impulse is to defend the space for your partner to grow, as long as your partner is as close to being home as you can get, as long as you&#8217;re in it together&#8230;  I say go for it.  Get dirty.  Do it all wrong, then try again tomorrow.  Duke it out (metaphorically).  There&#8217;s space in-between the unrealistically optimistic love songs and the kick him to the curb love songs.  Space for it to be impossible and be forever and ever amen too.  Room for patience.  Room to let the other guy be imperfect and let you down.  Good reasons to set your ego aside, to stop thinking about yourself altogether for a time, and do what he needs done even if you don&#8217;t like it.  Because God knows you&#8217;re going to need the same treatment at some point.</p>
<p>Love that lasts isn&#8217;t sunshine and roses.  It lasts because even when you hate your partner the most, you still want to wake up next to them tomorrow morning.  It lasts because the one person who can cut you the deepest is the only person who can help you heal.</p>
<p>Obviously, I&#8217;m not talking about the kind of love that involves real fists and knives.</p>
<p>All I&#8217;m saying is that life and love are messy.  Embracing it makes at least as much sense as fighting it.  I&#8217;d rather be messy and imperfect with the person that fits.  It&#8217;s better than following all the rules with someone who doesn&#8217;t fit, as if you can tie your life up in a pretty bow like they do on TV.  I don&#8217;t care that it isn&#8217;t anyone&#8217;s idea of perfect; I know who I want to be eating breakfast with in 20 years.  Which means I&#8217;m going to show up again tomorrow.  And the day after that.  For as long as I can, to hell with supposed to and should.</p>
<p>So there you go.  I&#8217;m sure there&#8217;s a DSM entry for that too.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1759/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1759/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1759&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://entropy.wordpress.com/2012/11/06/a-theory-of-love/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/fa64837eb7a7e19c0ec5d4ac31d35fa2?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F0.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">arwilliams</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Exit Polls: Top Issues For Voters</title>
		<link>http://politicalticker.blogs.cnn.com/2012/11/06/exit-polls-top-issues-for-voters/</link>
		<comments>http://politicalticker.blogs.cnn.com/2012/11/06/exit-polls-top-issues-for-voters/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2012 00:43:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>wallacegw</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[2012]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CNN Senior Writer Joe Von Kanel]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://politicalticker.blogs.cnn.com/?p=263184</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[(CNN) &#8212; What issues are on voters&#8217; minds? The exit polls give some insights. &#8211; Follow the Ticker on Twitter: @PoliticalTicker &#8211; Check out the CNN Electoral Map and Calculator and game out your own strategy for November. The early exit poll results show the economy is the number one issue on voters&#8217; minds. Sixty [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=263184&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>(CNN) </strong> &#8212; What issues are on voters&#8217; minds?</p>
<p>The exit polls give some insights.<br />
<span id="more-263184"></span><br />
<strong>&#8211; Follow the Ticker on Twitter: <a href="http://twitter.com/politicalticker">@PoliticalTicker</a></strong></p>
<p><strong>&#8211; Check out the<a href="http://www.cnn.com/election/2012/ecalculator"> CNN Electoral Map and Calculator</a> and game out your own strategy for November.</strong></p>
<p>The early exit poll results show the economy is the number one issue on voters&#8217; minds. Sixty percent called it the most important issue. Health care is a distant second at 17%. It&#8217;s followed by the deficit at 17% and foreign policy at 4%.</p>
<p>Twenty-four percent of the voters in this exit poll say their family&#8217;s financial situation is better today than it was four years ago. Thirty-four percent say it&#8217;s worse today while 41% say their financial situation is the same.</p>
<p>As for what today&#8217;s voters are looking for in a candidate, 29% want someone who has a vision for the future and a nearly identical number, 28%, want someone who shares their values. Twenty percent say the top quality they were looking for is whether a candidate cares about people like them, while 19% want a strong leader.</p>
<p>The exit polls provide a window into voters&#8217; thoughts in some of the mostly-closely watched states of Florida, Virginia, Ohio and New Hampshire.</p>
<p>Early exit poll results from Florida indicate 67% of today&#8217;s voters are white, 16% are Hispanic, 13% are black and 1% are Asian. Forty-nine percent of today&#8217;s Florida voters say President Obama would better handle Medicare while 47% say Romney. Twenty percent of Florida&#8217;s voters &#8211;one in five&#8211; waited until late in the campaign to decide which presidential candidate to support, while 78% say they made up their minds before October 20th.</p>
<p>In Virginia, early exit polls show 21% of today&#8217;s voters identify themselves as white evangelicals or born-again Christians, while 79% say they are not. Virginia voters are split down the middle in their opinion of both presidential candidates. Fifty percent say they have a favorable opinion of President Obama while 49% view him unfavorably. Forty-eight percent say they have a favorable opinion of Mitt Romney while 50% view him unfavorably.</p>
<p>Sixteen percent of today&#8217;s Virginia voters served in the military while 84% have not served. Across Virginia today, 19% of the voters live in the Washington D.C. suburbs while 16 percent live farther out in the northern Virginia exurbs. Twenty-five percent of today&#8217;s Virginia voters live in the Richmond area or eastern part of the state, 22% live in central or western Virginia and 19% live in the Tidewater region of the state.</p>
<p>The early exit polls from New Hampshire show 44% of today&#8217;s voters identify themselves as independents. Twenty-nine percent are Democrats while 27% are Republicans. When asked to describe their vote for president today, 73% say they strongly favor their candidate, 19% say they like their candidate but have reservations and 7% say they disliked all the other candidates. Forty-eight percent of New Hampshire voters say President Obama would best handle the economy while 49% say Romney.</p>
<p>In the all-important swing state of Ohio, exit polls indicate 39% of today&#8217;s voters are Democrats while 30% are Republicans and 31% are independents. Twenty-one percent of today&#8217;s Ohio voters are in a household that includes a union member while 79% are not. When it comes to the auto bailout, 59% of today&#8217;s Ohio voters approve of the federal government&#8217;s aid to U.S. automakers while 36% disapprove.</p>
<p>More voters in the swing states of Florida, New Hampshire, Ohio and Virginia blame George W. Bush than Barack Obama for the state of the U.S. economy.</p>
<p>According to early exit polls in Florida, 53% of today&#8217;s voters say Bush is more to blame for the country&#8217;s current economic problems while 41% say Obama.</p>
<p>In New Hampshire, exit polls show 54% blame Bush while 41% blame Obama.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s less of a gap in Ohio and Virginia. In both states, 50% of today&#8217;s voters say Bush is more to blame for the country&#8217;s current economic problems. In Ohio, 41% say Obama is more to blame and in Virginia 45% say Obama.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/263184/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/263184/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=263184&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://politicalticker.blogs.cnn.com/2012/11/06/exit-polls-top-issues-for-voters/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/380b8d00d1ee706fa1da0db0fd82e3df?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">wallacegw</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Patterns and Predictability</title>
		<link>http://yeayeapueblo.com/2012/11/06/patterns-and-predictability/</link>
		<comments>http://yeayeapueblo.com/2012/11/06/patterns-and-predictability/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2012 20:54:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Crystle</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Fall]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hiking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Home]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Washington]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://yeayeapueblo.com/?p=1731</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Growing up in Bakersfield, CA means I&#8217;m well conditioned to brutally hot summers and cool foggy winters: those are pretty much the only two seasons we saw down there, and they were painfully redundant. Two hour fog delays were common anytime visibility dropped in the valley from the phenomena, which made it a welcome happenstance [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1731&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://yeayeapueblo.com/2012/11/06/patterns-and-predictability/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>22</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/e3c30e1fb4c2702b739a7b021cc0d644?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">yeayeapueblo</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://yeayeapueblo.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/nearby-woods1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">William B Ives Trail</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://yeayeapueblo.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/20121105-img_2191.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Olympia Fog</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://yeayeapueblo.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/nearby-woods.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Washington Ferns</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://yeayeapueblo.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/20121105-img_2178.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">William B Ives Trail</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://yeayeapueblo.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/20121105-img_2228.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Olympia Fog</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://yeayeapueblo.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/20121105-img_2249.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Washington Mushroom</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://yeayeapueblo.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/nearby-woods2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">William B Ives Trail</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>No More Fracking Kale!</title>
		<link>http://kitchenslattern.com/2012/11/06/no-more-fracking-kale/</link>
		<comments>http://kitchenslattern.com/2012/11/06/no-more-fracking-kale/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2012 12:36:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>WSW</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Friendly Advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UGH Healthy Eating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Flatulence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Folic acid]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[indigestion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kale]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York City]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pork]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Soylent Green]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://kitchenslattern.com/?p=3079</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[What is all the fuss about? May I speak frankly? Thank you. I hate kale. I mean I really, really loathe it. Even more than okra, even more than radishes. It&#8217;s not for lack of trying it either. I have nibbled the ubiquitous superfood in salads, baked it into chips, steamed, buttered, braised and sautéed [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3079&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://kitchenslattern.com/2012/11/06/no-more-fracking-kale/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>75</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/1988ae13d4682dad80334daa552a7c47?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=R" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">wswinslow</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://kitchenslattern.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/kool-kale.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">kool-kale</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://kitchenslattern.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/2009_03_19-lardons.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2009_03_19-Lardons</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Hidden Devastation of Hurricane Sandy</title>
		<link>http://whitemaroon.wordpress.com/2012/11/06/the-hidden-devastation-of-hurricane-sandy/</link>
		<comments>http://whitemaroon.wordpress.com/2012/11/06/the-hidden-devastation-of-hurricane-sandy/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2012 12:58:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jon</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Caribbean]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cuba]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Haiti]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hurricane Sandy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jamaica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Santiago de Cuba]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://whitemaroon.wordpress.com/?p=224</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[When the storm surges flooded New York on October 29th, and hurricane-strength winds made land fall in New Jersey, wreaking havoc across twenty-four states, from Florida to Maine and as far west as Michigan and Wisconsin, the eyes and resources of the world&#8217;s media were already focused on the United States. Hurricane Sandy provided them [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=224&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://whitemaroon.wordpress.com/2012/11/06/the-hidden-devastation-of-hurricane-sandy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/af19b3ec6ac66ff9d8c005cdfad7628a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">albarrojo</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://whitemaroon.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/hurricane_sandy.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">hurricane_sandy</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Them &amp; Us: Obama, Romney, Ireland, and Inspirational Politics</title>
		<link>http://parallelevision.wordpress.com/2012/11/06/them-us-obama-romney-ireland-and-inspirational-politics/</link>
		<comments>http://parallelevision.wordpress.com/2012/11/06/them-us-obama-romney-ireland-and-inspirational-politics/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2012 14:46:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>alfla</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Sober Thoughts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[abortion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[barack obama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children's referendum]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[equal marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hurricane sandy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[irish politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lgbt rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mitt romney]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poverty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the x case]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[US election]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://parallelevision.wordpress.com/?p=1982</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Glancing through your Facebook or Twitter feeds today, you&#8217;d be forgiven for thinking that Irish people are obsessed with politics. Obama, Romney, electoral votes, the effects of Sandy, the queues in Florida, the voter registration laws, the number of press-ups Michelle Obama can muster and the relative smugness of the Romney children. We care. What [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1982&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:left;"><a href="http://somadjinn.deviantart.com/"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1983" title="Irish-American Flag from http://somadjinn.deviantart.com/" alt="" src="http://parallelevision.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/irish-american-flag.jpg?w=590"   /></a>Glancing through your Facebook or Twitter feeds today, you&#8217;d be forgiven for thinking that Irish people are obsessed with politics.</p>
<p>Obama, Romney, electoral votes, the effects of Sandy, the queues in Florida, the voter registration laws, the number of press-ups Michelle Obama can muster and the relative smugness of the Romney children.</p>
<p>We care.</p>
<p>What I&#8217;ve only seen one post about, of course, is Irish politics. In four days we are having a referendum on children&#8217;s rights in this country, and yet nobody is talking about it. Part of this may be down to the fait accompli feeling surrounding the vote (which, by the way, won&#8217;t be accompli if people are too apathetic to reach quorum &#8211; <em>Update: as pointed out in comments, Irish referenda don&#8217;t have quora, which is&#8230; better?</em>). But as far as I can see, the majority of this can be put down to this: Irish politics has lost the ability to inspire, if indeed it ever had it.</p>
<p>The obvious rebuttal to such a statement is to suggest that the US election is not inspirational, it is merely a spectacle that is being shoved down our throats by a Western-obsessed media. And while it&#8217;s true that pretty much every news site is live blogging the Presidential election as if it were the X Factor final, I suspect that the truth is far more depressing.</p>
<p>At some point, it became impossible to feel passion and hope for Irish politics.</p>
<p>During this US election cycle (which I have been sucked into as much as anyone else) there have been a couple of major social issues on the table: the treatment of the poor, the possibility of equal marriage, and the threats to a woman&#8217;s right to choose.</p>
<p>Irish bloggers and commenters have been aghast at Mitt Romney&#8217;s opinion on the so-called 47%, his opposition to equal marriage, and his party&#8217;s vehement attempts to restrict abortion laws that have been in place since the early 70s.</p>
<p>What people are less concerned with, it seems, is how these issues are dealt with by our own government. Let&#8217;s not forget that on the issue of equal rights for the LGBT community, we are still in a position where we can&#8217;t adopt and cannot marry. And for those who believe that civil partnerships get the job done, I&#8217;d urge them to look at the <a href="http://www.marriagequality.ie/getinformed/marriage/faqs.html" target="_blank">Marriage Equality report</a> detailing the 150+ differences between partnership and marriage.</p>
<p>On poverty, we have two parties &#8211; one in power and one on a path to resurgence &#8211; that have been responsible for crippling this country and placing the burden of earth-shattering repayments on those most at risk.</p>
<p>And on a woman&#8217;s right to choose, <a href="http://www.thejournal.ie/pro-choice-march-dublin-2-615912-Sep2012/" target="_blank">our people are rising up</a> but our leaders are barely even talking about it &#8211; and have for twenty years <a href="http://www.irishexaminer.com/features/x-case-and-the-letter-of-the-law-184761.html" target="_blank">ignored an edict</a> directing that the slightest of wriggle room be given to the concept.</p>
<p>Of course US politics is a spectacle &#8211; everything in the US is. New York&#8217;s experience of Sandy was an Oscar-winning and heart-wrenching tale of man versus nature, while the countries she barrelled through on her way there were <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/commentisfree/2012/nov/02/hurricane-sandy-hit-caribbean-media" target="_blank">buried on page six</a>. It&#8217;s what the media does, and as the supposed kings of media it&#8217;d be odd if things weren&#8217;t so clear-cut.</p>
<p>But what&#8217;s wrong with a little spectacle? What&#8217;s wrong with believing that people&#8217;s lives can be more than just day-to-day drudgery and nuance, and that sometimes our experiences can rise to the level of fable? That the best version of that skewed concept we call the American Dream can exist in the experience of their First Family? That we should be passionate, and emotional, and bull-headed about the fate of a country?</p>
<p>Perhaps it&#8217;s a life raised on The West Wing and The Daily Show that&#8217;s done it, but at some point most of the people I know became superlatively au fait with the specificities and issues of a country they&#8217;ve never lived in. Perhaps it is just media coverage that does it.</p>
<p>Or perhaps it&#8217;s something else.</p>
<p>Over the weekend myself and some friends were discussing The Two Marys &#8211; Robinson and McAleese. The former&#8217;s autobiography hit shelves recently, filled with the experiences of a woman who battled a distinctly unfriendly political climate to become our first female President, and then went on to champion countless causes as part of the UN and in other enterprises.</p>
<p>Mary McAleese was not just a perfect representation of but an active participant in the slow evolution of &#8220;The North&#8221; from battleground and political football to subject of a thousand tourist ads.</p>
<p>Our current President is also a champion of the arts, minority rights and more &#8211; and has <a href="http://www.irishtimes.com/newspaper/opinion/2012/1105/1224326139461.html" target="_blank">done a strong job</a> in a role that is constitutionally handcuffed.</p>
<p>In the Senate-while-we-have-it, there are also causes for inspiration &#8211; people like David Norris, who are outspoken on issues of equality in Irish society (and who teamed up with McAleese in the 80s to dismantle Ireland&#8217;s anti-homosexuality laws).</p>
<p>But beyond the Aras and the Senate, things fall away.</p>
<p>In short, there is something rotten at the heart of the Irish Oireachtas.</p>
<p>Our jaws drop at Mitt Romney and the concept that a political system can be bought by the highest bidder, yet we&#8217;re complacent as the twin cancers of nepotism and boys&#8217; clubs choke the idea of a diverse Irish political system.</p>
<p>Perhaps it&#8217;s the power. The only recent examples of truly passionate politics lie in the President and the Senate, two areas where the position is often largely ceremonial. Maybe the Oireachtas just attracts those hungry for the power that their parents and grandparents fed on like scarabs.</p>
<p>But shouldn&#8217;t we expect better? Shouldn&#8217;t we be outraged?</p>
<p>In my entire life, no TD has ever inspired me. And while &#8220;inspiring&#8221; might be a dirty word in a time of X Factor contestant stories and a US electorate with cookie-cutter attitudes to important issues, it&#8217;s a vital component of any system of governance. Do we want rulers who dodge questions, hide behind committee structures, and choose to follow popular opinion rather than informing truly progressive public debate?</p>
<p>Where are our great orators? Where are the great men and women to embody the Irish combination of rebellion and poetry? Where are those who would put their heads above the parapet?  Where are our fucking leaders?</p>
<p>I&#8217;m not sure. But I don&#8217;t think we&#8217;re doing anything right now that will ensure that an Irish child today will grow up to be a statesman (or woman), and not just a politician.</p>
<p>So while it&#8217;s heartening to see people care about politics of any kind, it&#8217;s disturbing that we have grown long-sighted in our outrage, unable to see that the rot at home is more pervasive and difficult to weed out than that across the pond.</p>
<p>In 24 hours, my news feeds will &#8211; depending on the trajectory of tonight&#8217;s count &#8211; be filled with celebrations or commiserations</p>
<p>And in Ireland, nothing will have changed.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1982/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1982/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1982&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://parallelevision.wordpress.com/2012/11/06/them-us-obama-romney-ireland-and-inspirational-politics/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>21</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c9d9a040a9760fe1d493206014a26fff?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">alfla</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://parallelevision.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/irish-american-flag.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Irish-American Flag from http://somadjinn.deviantart.com/</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Particle Physicists Unwilling To Call Election</title>
		<link>http://freakofnature.wordpress.com/2012/11/07/particle-physicists-unwilling-to-call-election/</link>
		<comments>http://freakofnature.wordpress.com/2012/11/07/particle-physicists-unwilling-to-call-election/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2012 09:14:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>freakofnature</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Silly]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://freakofnature.wordpress.com/?p=224</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Mainstream media outlets around the world have declared Barack Obama the victor in yesterday&#8217;s US presidential elections, but particle physicists at CERN say that the race is still too close to call. With every state except Florida reporting, the New York Times announced that Obama had won the popular vote and easily gained the electoral [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=224&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://freakofnature.wordpress.com/2012/11/07/particle-physicists-unwilling-to-call-election/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>16</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/67f21631a6b6603eb38a3bb0275c60bb?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">freakofnature</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://freakofnature.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/cern-election-small1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">CERN election small</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>