<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 22:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Bob Dylan, Modest Mouse, and the End of the World</title>
		<link>http://70dayweekend.com/2012/11/29/bob-dylan-modest-mouse-and-the-end-of-the-world/</link>
		<comments>http://70dayweekend.com/2012/11/29/bob-dylan-modest-mouse-and-the-end-of-the-world/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2012 19:26:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>70dayweekend</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Throwback Thursday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bob dylan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[catastrophism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ecology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[environmentalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[isaac brock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[modest mouse]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://70dayweekend.com/?p=2051</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This isn’t really a throwback Thursday though that is what I usually write. But I am not quite sure what it is… So I read this book recently called Catastrophism: The Apocalyptic Politics of Collapse and Rebirth put out last month by PM Press. It’s about political tendencies that have an aspect of end-of-the-world gloom [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2051&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://70dayweekend.com/2012/11/29/bob-dylan-modest-mouse-and-the-end-of-the-world/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f3b21e47fad1fa198b71c929b674fef4?s=96&#38;d=&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">70dayweekend</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://70dayweekend.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dylanmm.png" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Watching A Friend Die On Facebook</title>
		<link>http://grieftastic.wordpress.com/2012/11/27/watching-a-friend-die-on-facebook/</link>
		<comments>http://grieftastic.wordpress.com/2012/11/27/watching-a-friend-die-on-facebook/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2012 21:38:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Nicole Kristal</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brain tumor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[facebook friendships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grief]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[highly sensitive person]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[watching a friend die on facebook]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://grieftastic.wordpress.com/?p=183</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Tara and I hadn&#8217;t spoken for 16 years but when she friended me on Facebook in 2009, clicking &#8220;accept&#8221; was a no brainer. I messaged her immediately. Ms. Mitchell! Do you ever age? Bitch. p.s. Hi Tara! p.p.s. You look lovely! She responded&#8230; I am timeless. p.s. Hello Nicole! p.p.s. Wish you were next door&#8230; Tara [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=183&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tara and I hadn&#8217;t spoken for 16 years but when she friended me on Facebook in 2009, clicking &#8220;accept&#8221; was a no brainer. I messaged her immediately.</p>
<h4><em>Ms. Mitchell!</em></h4>
<h4><em>Do you ever age? Bitch.</em></h4>
<h4><em>p.s. Hi Tara!</em><br />
<em>p.p.s. You look lovely!</em></h4>
<p>She responded&#8230;</p>
<h4><em>I am timeless.</em></h4>
<h4><em>p.s. Hello Nicole!<br />
p.p.s. Wish you were next door&#8230;</em></h4>
<p>Tara was my next door neighbor in the dorms my freshman year of college. She liked Cat Stevens and the Violent Femmes. She smoked clove cigarettes out of her window and played the flute. She was 6 feet tall (or 5&#8217;12&#8243; as she liked to put it) and was asked so frequently about her height that she posted it on her nametag at a waitressing job because she got tired of people asking.</p>
<p>Tara had taken me to my first &#8220;Rocky Horror Picture Show&#8221; and taught me when to throw the bread. She introduced me to my first pot dealer, though Tara never smoked weed. She once had driven me to hunt for Benadryl during an ice storm because I was allergic to her family&#8217;s cat. I had only good memories associated with Tara.</p>
<p>After accepting her friend request, I lost track of her, seeing pictures here and there on Facebook, noticing one of Tara in a hospital bed and assuming a torn ligament or minor surgery because of our age. Then one day I clicked on a photo and learned she wasn&#8217;t in for minor surgery. Tara was in for a brain tumor. From there I found a blog she&#8217;d been writing since her diagnosis in 2009 shortly after my mom passed away. She&#8217;d been fighting a life-threatening tumor for three years, and I hadn&#8217;t even noticed. I don&#8217;t even think Tara was in my News Feed.</p>
<p>If this had happened in another decade, Tara would have remained out of my social circle. And maybe years later I would have heard about her condition while reconnecting with an old college friend. But now I was personally connected through a few mouse clicks, watching this woman, now 34, go through chemotherapy, brain surgery, and physical therapy, wearing the brave smile that people facing their own mortalities sport so you won&#8217;t worry about them or their positive &#8220;gonna beat this&#8221; attitude.</p>
<p>I wrote Tara a snail mail letter (it seemed more personal) apologizing for not realizing what she was going through for so long, blaming Facebook but at the same time knowing it was the only thing that had enabled me to learn of her condition. Pictures of her with a cane digressed into photos of her strapped in a wheelchair, her left side paralyzed, a smile on her face, puffy from steroids.</p>
<p>As I watched her body deteriorate, I witnessed the misguided bright-sided Facebook wall posts from Tara&#8217;s friends who had never experienced cancer. Comments like, &#8220;Boy, I wish I could get out of going to work like you&#8221; and &#8220;Wow, rehab looks fun. Is it like the dorms?&#8221; I wrote Tara asking her how she handled all this asinine commentary. She understood the intent but admitted, yeah, she&#8217;d love to be well enough to go to work — and no, struggling to learn how to walk again was nothing like college.</p>
<p>I mailed her a &#8220;Fuck Cancer&#8221; hat similar to the one I&#8217;d purchased for my mother. She posted an Instagram photo of it with a &#8220;This gave me a laugh, thanks Nicole!&#8221; to her Facebook wall. During a late night Facebook IM session, Tara admitted that as an only child,  she was aching for alone time but couldn&#8217;t get it — her parents were her caregivers 24/7. She couldn&#8217;t go to the bathroom by herself because of her mobility issues and the only time her folks left her with a friend she had a life-threatening seizure that &#8220;really freaked everyone out.&#8221; Tara joked that she was now on lockdown and as an &#8220;HSP&#8221; (highly sensitive person) this change in lifestyle had been even more unnerving.</p>
<p>Her HSP reference reminded me that in college, Tara and I had bonded over the &#8220;Highly Sensitive Person,&#8221; a book by a therapist named Elaine Aron who knew my mother. I wrote Aron for advice about what Tara could do to achieve alone time. Elaine advised Tara to use silence to achieve solitude. Tara said she&#8217;d try it.</p>
<p>I sent Tara a mix of folk music that made me think of college. My music choices reflected what I thought her music taste would be now. I learned on Facebook that she had a fondness for Justin Timberlake. I lamented making her CD so unhip and Grateful Dead laden. She sent me a postcard with familiar handwriting that I remembered from notes she left on my door in the dorms. She asked me to visit.</p>
<p>I was afraid that seeing Tara in person would bring up all of my memories of watching my mother die, memories that after three years I had finally been able to relegate to the background of my thoughts. I learned that a short film I wrote and produced would be screening in Seattle four months into the future. I told Tara I would visit her for a weekend then but told her to warn me if her health rapidly declined I&#8217;d find a way to visit earlier, knowing full well that I couldn&#8217;t get days off my television production job. Though Tara must have known she probably wouldn&#8217;t be healthy enough to see me by then (she was on Hospice) she emailed me that she was excited about the visit and said we could have a dorm reunion.</p>
<p>I&#8217;d had drama with almost all of the girls from my freshman dorm and the thought of seeing them made me feel nauseous. One had sent me an email that started, &#8220;Fuck you, fuck you, fuck you&#8230;&#8221; when I didn&#8217;t make time to visit her in L.A. 10 years ago. Another had been my roommate who went back and forth between our apartment and her boyfriend&#8217;s leaving messes in both locations then trading them out before cleaning either up. Another was a straight girl I had slept with Spring Trimester who broke my heart.</p>
<p>Worrying about myself in awkward social situations while Tara was dying made me feel selfish and petty. I went for a hike with my friend Cheryl and told her about the situation, that Tara wanted me to visit, that I had reservations about seeing her so ill, from seeing people from my past and revisiting the Pacific Northwest for the first time since college — a place I&#8217;d intentionally never returned to because college was such a hard time for me. But I had to somehow overlook these bad associations, I told her. Who was I to deny a dying friend&#8217;s wish? Cheryl asked, &#8220;Would you even have reconnected with this person if it hadn&#8217;t been for Facebook?&#8221; I admitted I probably wouldn&#8217;t have. Tara hadn&#8217;t been a close friend through most of college. We lost touch after our softmore year and before that we&#8217;d been mostly acquaintances. I had completely lost track of Tara after graduation and only lamented that fact after I realized she was sick.</p>
<p>Part of why we&#8217;d never been closer was that Tara was an extrovert who loved hanging out in groups, while I was more of a one-on-one person. Small talk with people tossing cigarette butts in rain-filled glasses was the only way I ever was around Tara, and even then I always felt like I never saw enough of her. &#8220;Not to discount your relationship to this person,&#8221; Cheryl said, &#8220;but there are probably a lot more people who are much closer to Tara vying for her attention right now.&#8221; Cheryl was right. I was seeing myself as the center of Tara&#8217;s universe, overrating my importance in her life like people are bound to do when someone they know is dying. I had watched this happen with my mother as acquaintance after acquaintance showed up at our door, preventing her from getting much needed rest. I knew the visits were more about their guilt, their feelings of helplessness than about them giving my mother what she needed.</p>
<p>I was going to visit Tara and yet in all of this time we hadn&#8217;t even talked on the phone. I emailed her to see if I could get her phone number but she didn&#8217;t respond. In our last correspondence, I suggested we Skype so we could see each other. In an email laden with spelling and typos so severe I could barely decipher it, Tara said it was a great idea but had no idea how to set it up. It was clear from her writing that she had gotten much sicker. Then she grew silent. I sent a few emails saying I hoped she was getting the alone time she needed and that she was in my thoughts, but received no response. Her Facebook account had gone silent as well. People posted photo after photo of Tara when she was healthy at parties, dinners, outdoor fairs. I didn&#8217;t have any photos of Tara to share.</p>
<p>I felt helpless and guilty, like I should have done more, like I should have gotten over my differences with those girls from the dorm and reconnected with them. If I had, I would have been able to stay connected to Tara in some human way off-line.</p>
<p>Then out of the blue I got an email from one of them — the girl who had broken my heart. She said she realized that Tara and I had reconnected in recent months and wanted to let me know Tara was now bed-ridden and losing her vision from the tumor. She could no longer swallow. It wouldn&#8217;t be long now. She said she was going to visit her that weekend and said she&#8217;d give Tara my love.</p>
<p>I was so grateful. A few days later, I heard back from my friend that she&#8217;d given Tara my sentiments and that Tara had said, &#8220;Tell Nicole I love her. She&#8217;s coming to Seattle soon, you know.&#8221; She had never received my email saying I had canceled my trip because I couldn&#8217;t get the days off work. I was relieved that disappointment wouldn&#8217;t be my last gift to Tara. The panic that had overtaken me while waiting for news had abated. I had gotten some form of a goodbye, some form of closure.</p>
<p>The girl who broke my heart promised to email me when Tara died, but she didn&#8217;t. I learned about Tara&#8217;s death on Facebook from a Community Page that had been created to keep people in the loop about Tara&#8217;s condition.</p>
<p>For weeks after her death, Tara was still listed as online on Facebook, the symbol of her mobile phone next to her photo and name in my IM contacts. I visited her page frequently to see her friends&#8217; comments about how much they missed her, about the little things that made them think of her. I had nothing to contribute, no memories to recount, because Tara hadn&#8217;t existed in real-time for me since 1995 when we both were 18 and considered our foreign language requirements and the Japanese exchange student&#8217;s cardboard box of hard liquor going dry &#8220;real problems.&#8221;</p>
<p>Last week, the icon of Tara&#8217;s cell phone disappeared from my online contacts. The relief of no longer seeing her name evaporates each time she shows up in my list of Facebook friends or when Facebook recommends pages she liked before she died. Whether she wants to or not, Tara no longer has a say as to whether she will exist on Facebook. Those disturbing photos of her when she was sick could be online for the next 30 years. Whether her continued online presence haunts us or comforts us, Facebook is indifferent. The social network has always functioned as a double-edged sword, bringing us closer together while accenting how far apart we really are. To the Facebook logorithm, Tara and I are just as close as she is to her other friends and she&#8217;s just as alive as when I accepted her friend request four years ago. The only difference now is she&#8217;s in my News Feed.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/183/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/183/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=183&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://grieftastic.wordpress.com/2012/11/27/watching-a-friend-die-on-facebook/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/3011cd63324956fcfbdd756909de2fa4?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">nicolekristal</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Le Saut</title>
		<link>http://lanomademoderne.wordpress.com/2012/11/27/le-saut/</link>
		<comments>http://lanomademoderne.wordpress.com/2012/11/27/le-saut/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2012 13:29:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sarah</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TAPIF]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Traveling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sky diving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tapif]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://lanomademoderne.wordpress.com/?p=4127</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Three days after stepping off the plane in Paris, I jumped out of one in rural Normandy.  Normal, quoi. My uncle (of sorts), who had furnished me a place to stay in Paris my first night vite fait, and with whom I was staying a week before heading south to where I&#8217;d be living for [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4127&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:left;"><span style="text-align:left;">Three days after stepping off the plane in Paris, I jumped out of one in rural Normandy.  Normal, quoi.</span></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">My uncle (of sorts), who had furnished me a place to stay in Paris my <a title="Je reprends le collier" href="http://lanomademoderne.wordpress.com/2012/10/29/je-reprends-le-collier/">first night</a> vite fait, and with whom I was staying a week before heading south to where I&#8217;d be living for the year, e-mailed me a few days before my departure, asking me a no-frills question: My son and I are going to do our first skydive on Sunday, would you care to join us?  And me, well, I said yes.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">So we drove out to the aérodrome in Saint-André-de-l&#8217;Eure for a &#8220;baptême de l&#8217;air&#8221; (France is a Catholic country, remember) and found a large group of people waiting equally for their chance to attain salvation.  We joined the line and my nervousness grew for the next three hours (worried to panicked and all the stages of denial in-between).</p>
<p>Once our names were called, there was a quick five-minute briefing about how to get in the airplane, how to jump, how to take over and release the emergency parachute in case your instructor became unconscious.  Or dead.  Ce du gâteau, hein?  Fastoche.</p>
<p>Visibly trembling, I suited up (snazzy), met my instructor (chatty &#8211; a shame since I had lost the ability to speak French about an hour before we left my uncle&#8217;s house) and was escorted out to the tarmac, waddling clumsily along in my straps.  Good thing this was all captured on video!</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/yopethop/8195185755"><img class="alignnone" alt="" src="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut01.jpeg?w=640&#038;h=427" height="427" width="640" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/yopethop/8195183187/"><img class="alignnone" alt="" src="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut02.jpeg?w=640&#038;h=427" height="427" width="640" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/yopethop/8196282100"><img class="alignnone" alt="" src="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut03.jpeg?w=640&#038;h=427" height="427" width="640" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/yopethop/8196583008"><img class="alignnone" alt="" src="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut04.jpeg?w=640&#038;h=427" height="427" width="640" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/yopethop/8196287396"><img class="alignnone" alt="" src="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut05.jpeg?w=640&#038;h=427" height="427" width="640" /></a></p>
<p>The pilot (a Belgian who flies like a madman, so said my instructor) hardly took a moment to stop before taking off again.  I was sat on the lap of my instructor, on the immediate right of the pilot, facing into the cabin.  Then up, up, to where the fields below were just blocks of color, and further still to where all traces of land were hidden behind a thick layer of clouds.  I can describe the ascent in quite a nice and flowery way now, though at the time, not much more than a string of profanities (both English and French) was going through my head.  Why, why, why.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/yopethop/8195195429"><img class="alignnone" alt="" src="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut06.jpeg?w=640&#038;h=427" height="427" width="640" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/yopethop/8195200483"><img class="alignnone" alt="" src="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut07.jpeg?w=640&#038;h=427" height="427" width="640" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/yopethop/8195203023"><img class="alignnone" alt="" src="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut08.jpeg?w=640&#038;h=427" height="427" width="640" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/yopethop/8195205563"><img class="alignnone" alt="" src="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut09.jpeg?w=640&#038;h=427" height="427" width="640" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/yopethop/8196598402"><img class="alignnone" alt="" src="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut10.jpeg?w=640&#038;h=427" height="427" width="640" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/yopethop/8205614390"><img class="alignnone" alt="" src="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut11.jpeg?w=640&#038;h=427" height="427" width="640" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Ah, the half-hearted grin of a girl convinced of her imminent death, interrupted by my instructor, who strapped us so closely together that it hurt, an annoying pain that I appreciated, as I was sure it would be the physical sensation I would experience before an eternity of lifelessness.  Spoiler alert: I live.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">When the door slid open, we scooted to the edge and my legs hung out, clicking against the underside of the plane.  Contrary to what every fiber of my being was telling me to do, my instructor made me lay my head back on his shoulder, rocked a couple of times, and we tumbled forward.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/yopethop/8196304672"><img class="alignnone" alt="" src="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut12.jpeg?w=640&#038;h=427" height="427" width="640" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/yopethop/8195212859"><img class="alignnone" alt="" src="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut13.jpeg?w=640&#038;h=427" height="427" width="640" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/yopethop/8196310710"><img class="alignnone" alt="" src="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut14.jpeg?w=640&#038;h=427" height="427" width="640" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/yopethop/8196317004/"><img class="alignnone" alt="" src="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut15.jpeg?w=640&#038;h=427" height="427" width="640" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/yopethop/8195225117"><img class="alignnone" alt="" src="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut16.jpeg?w=640&#038;h=427" height="427" width="640" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/yopethop/8196320940"><img class="alignnone" alt="" src="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut17.jpeg?w=640&#038;h=427" height="427" width="640" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/yopethop/8195228967"><img class="alignnone" alt="" src="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut18.jpeg?w=640&#038;h=427" height="427" width="640" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">In case it needs repeating or you stepped away for a moment, I jumped out of an airplane.  An airplane.  Eurgh, it&#8217;s scarier to think about even now.  Why did I do that?!</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/yopethop/8196590930"><img class="alignnone" alt="" src="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut19.jpeg?w=640&#038;h=427" height="427" width="640" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/yopethop/8196593048"><img class="alignnone" alt="" src="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut20.jpeg?w=640&#038;h=427" height="427" width="640" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/yopethop/8195501673"><img class="alignnone" alt="" src="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut21.jpeg?w=640&#038;h=427" height="427" width="640" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/yopethop/8195503667"><img class="alignnone" alt="" src="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut22.jpeg?w=640&#038;h=427" height="427" width="640" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">The free-fall was for a distance of about 3000 meters, and lasted around a minute.  Once the parachute was released &#8211; the best thing to ever happen in my life &#8211; we floated the remaining 1000 meters for six or seven minutes.  The scenery was as plain as it had been pre-jump, but it felt wonderful to slowly spiral down over it, knowing that I&#8217;d be living and breathing on it again soon.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/yopethop/8196325268"><img class="alignnone" alt="" src="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut23.jpeg?w=640&#038;h=427" height="427" width="640" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/yopethop/8195509861"><img class="alignnone" alt="" src="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut24.jpeg?w=640&#038;h=427" height="427" width="640" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/yopethop/8195234301"><img class="alignnone" alt="" src="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut25.jpeg?w=640&#038;h=427" height="427" width="640" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/yopethop/8196605546"><img class="alignnone" alt="" src="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut26.jpeg?w=640&#038;h=427" height="427" width="640" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/yopethop/8195236355/"><img class="alignnone" alt="" src="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut27.jpeg?w=640&#038;h=427" height="427" width="640" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/yopethop/8196332488"><img class="alignnone" alt="" src="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut28.jpeg?w=640&#038;h=427" height="427" width="640" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Phew!  Glad I&#8217;ve done it, but I&#8217;m glad it&#8217;s all over, too!  Jamais plus&#8230;At least I have the pictures to prove it!  Mes grands remerciements à l&#8217;équipe de <a href="http://www.flytandem.fr/">FlyTandem</a> for their in-flight photography and expertise as I flung myself out of a plane 4000 meters in the air.  I wouldn&#8217;t trust just anyone to catch me!</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><div class='embed-vimeo' style='text-align:center;'><iframe src='http://player.vimeo.com/video/52061665' width='640' height='352' frameborder='0'></iframe></div></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">Warning: Excessive nostril.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4127/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4127/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4127&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://lanomademoderne.wordpress.com/2012/11/27/le-saut/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/7969d4fa78e1de641b8169d22b033db0?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lanomademoderne</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut01.jpeg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut02.jpeg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut03.jpeg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut04.jpeg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut05.jpeg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut06.jpeg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut07.jpeg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut08.jpeg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut09.jpeg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut10.jpeg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut11.jpeg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut12.jpeg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut13.jpeg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut14.jpeg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut15.jpeg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut16.jpeg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut17.jpeg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut18.jpeg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut19.jpeg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut20.jpeg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut21.jpeg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut22.jpeg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut23.jpeg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut24.jpeg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut25.jpeg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut26.jpeg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut27.jpeg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://lanomademoderne.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/saut28.jpeg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mommy Power</title>
		<link>http://thisqueerfamilia.wordpress.com/2012/11/28/mommy-power/</link>
		<comments>http://thisqueerfamilia.wordpress.com/2012/11/28/mommy-power/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2012 18:45:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sarah V</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Decisions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics of parenting]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thisqueerfamilia.wordpress.com/?p=55</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[One reason to have a baby, in my mind, is to be able to register at Target and carry around that red scanning gun. It is almost better than a microphone at karaoke. And infinitely more satisfying than a label-making gun (though I remember, many years ago, thinking I might go into food service management [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=55&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://thisqueerfamilia.wordpress.com/2012/11/28/mommy-power/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/8c388c175603c73200d26ebee7c979b7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sfv2008</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thisqueerfamilia.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/registry.jpg?w=224" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">registry</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Natural Cure</title>
		<link>http://mikeallegra.com/2012/11/29/a-natural-cure/</link>
		<comments>http://mikeallegra.com/2012/11/29/a-natural-cure/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2012 16:30:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>heylookawriterfellow</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[On Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[procrastination]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inspiration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creativity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[squirrels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[feral cats]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mikeallegra.com/?p=1143</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I love the idea of sitting in an Adirondack chair on a sunny day with a pad and a pen. There’s something so romantic, so wonderful about writing in nature.  So, once in a while, I give it a try. And then the pollen goes up my nose. And the bugs bite. And the sun get [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1143&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_1144" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 594px"><a href="http://mikeallegra.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/squirrel.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1144" title="My pal" alt="" src="http://mikeallegra.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/squirrel.jpg?w=590"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">I saw what you did to that cat and, well, I just wanted to thank you. I also want a peanut.</p></div>
<p>I love the idea of sitting in an Adirondack chair on a sunny day with a pad and a pen. There’s something so romantic, so wonderful about writing in nature.  So, once in a while, I give it a try.</p>
<p>And then the pollen goes up my nose. And the bugs bite. And the sun get too hot and my hands get sweaty, and, since I’m a lefty, I smear the ink with my sweaty hand – which is not such a big deal because I’m not writing anything worth keeping anyway, because every time a leaf crinkles, I look up in eager anticipation of finding that feral cat that I oh, so wanna hit with a rock because NO ONE menaces my squirrels without hearing from me, buddy!</p>
<p>Ahem.</p>
<p>So I guess what I’m saying is that, when I try to write in it, nature distracts and annoys me.</p>
<p>Otherwise nature and I have no real problems. It often delights me. When the weather is right, I could stand around in nature all day interacting with it in the most genial and stupid ways. For example, the other day I caught myself waving at a squirrel. He didn’t wave back – that would be asking too much, I suppose – but he did seem to take the gesture in the spirit in which it was given and that pleased me no end.</p>
<p>Better still, I have discoverd that actions such as these improve my writing.</p>
<p>I have the bad habit of chaining myself to my desk. Even when my brain refuses to work, I stay put. In general this could be defined as good self-discipline. You can’t just sit around and wait for the muse, after all. It never shows up when you want it to. Since the words aren’t going to write themselves, I muscle through.</p>
<p>But every writer reaches a point when good self-discipline evolves into something that looks a whole lot more like masochism. Nothing’s gonna come no matter how hard you try.</p>
<p>So I pry myself away and tell myself it’s not procrastination if I deliver myself back to the desk eventually. Then I take a walk and wave at squirrels. Doing so restores my overall sense of well-being. It provides the second wind I need to get back to my awful, awful writing and make something that at least resembles progress.</p>
<p>Better yet, such a walk allows me to pursue my new hobby: feral cat chasing. In the grand scheme of things, saving a squirrel is always more important than a well-written paragraph.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1143/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1143/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1143&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://mikeallegra.com/2012/11/29/a-natural-cure/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>62</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/866cffe137fb80a19995f3514e09f2ea?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">heylookawriterfellow</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mikeallegra.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/squirrel.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">My pal</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Wild Thornberrys Revisited</title>
		<link>http://mittenskittens.wordpress.com/2012/11/14/the-wild-thornberrys-revisited/</link>
		<comments>http://mittenskittens.wordpress.com/2012/11/14/the-wild-thornberrys-revisited/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2012 01:24:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>jessmittens</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Humour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cartoons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the Wild Thornberrys]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mittenskittens.wordpress.com/?p=1567</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Going back to those favourite cartoons you watched as a child normally leads to a lot of strange and confused realisations about that show. You may pick out now-obvious sexual innuendo (I&#8217;ll never forget the moment in Bee Movie when the grandpa bee shouts &#8220;I did it with a grasshopper once, her crazy legs had [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1567&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Going back to those favourite cartoons you watched as a child normally leads to a lot of strange and confused realisations about that show. You may pick out now-obvious sexual innuendo (I&#8217;ll never forget the moment in <em>Bee Movie</em> when the grandpa bee shouts &#8220;I did it with a grasshopper once, her crazy legs had me up all night long!&#8221;), adult humour, jokes that reference something you&#8217;ve since seen / read / heard so can finally understand, and sometimes, the shows are downright creepy and you wonder how you ever sat through an episode at the age of 7 without crying.</p>
<p>Well, recently I went back to one of my old favourites,<em> The Wild Thornberrys, </em>because as far as my memory was concerned, that show was awesome. Or, in the words of Nigel, I thought it was &#8216;smashing!&#8217;</p>
<p><a href="http://mittenskittens.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/tumblr_md0aikh4zj1rie0uao1_500.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1572" title="tumblr_md0aikh4ZJ1rie0uao1_500" alt="" src="http://mittenskittens.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/tumblr_md0aikh4zj1rie0uao1_500.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>For the most part, it really is. I really like <em>The Wild Thornberrys</em>. It&#8217;s colourful, captivating, has talking animals (yes!) and you learn facts about said talking animals. No, my wonder at how I never noticed some things as a child began during an episode with a gas station man who had a captured hyena in a cage, that he then taunted with meat. His creepy line (grunt) was, &#8220;Wanna see him dance?&#8221;</p>
<div id="attachment_1576" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://mittenskittens.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/tumblr_mcsol5p5cp1rceklro1_500.gif"><img class="size-full wp-image-1576" title="tumblr_mcsol5P5Cp1rceklro1_500" alt="" src="http://mittenskittens.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/tumblr_mcsol5p5cp1rceklro1_500.gif?w=590"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Nigel was not impressed.</p></div>
<p>I was also annoyed when, for the 3rd episode in a row, Eliza mucked shit up again. I wanted to face palm<em> her</em> face. That girl thinks she is always right &#8211; and doesn&#8217;t just leave it at thinking she&#8217;s right, she acts on it. She&#8217;s freeing hyenas willynilly, ditching Donnie, running through wildebeest, canoeing in arctic water, playing with cheetahs dying of thirst and then wondering why they&#8217;ve turned on her with the plans of making her lunch&#8230; Eliza thinks mostly of herself and assumes every animal she meets will love her. She also<em> can&#8217;t stand it</em> when somebody likes Debbie. She&#8217;s a loose cannon, who nearly gets herself and the family killed multiple times, all while sighing, squeaking and complaining <em>nonstop</em>.</p>
<p><a href="http://mittenskittens.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/tumblr_m7mqburnb01qhnqajo1_5001.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-1574" title="tumblr_m7mqburNb01qhnqajo1_500" alt="" src="http://mittenskittens.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/tumblr_m7mqburnb01qhnqajo1_5001.jpg?w=300&#038;h=226" height="226" width="300" /></a>When I was a kid, I thought Debbie was an over-reacting, whiny teenage brat. Little did I realise that Debbie acts this way because she lives with a group of people who isolate her, ignore her, ridicule her, and force her to live in an environment devoid of any safety, comfort, education options, or anything she is interested in. Every time Debbie purchases a CD player or &#8216;boom box&#8217;, Donnie, Darwin or Eliza either break it or throw it in water. This goes for everything Debbie buys &#8211; and she buys these things in an attempt to feel a part of the world she so desperately misses. Besides, teenager living in a van with your family non-stop? We&#8217;d all go crazy.</p>
<p><a href="http://mittenskittens.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/char_40321.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-1575" title="char_40321" alt="" src="http://mittenskittens.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/char_40321.jpg?w=590"   /></a>When it comes to Donnie I only have questions. Yes, after his parents were killed he was raised by an Orangutan for a year or two, but why oh why, does that mean he is irreversibly insane? Perhaps it is to do with the fact that Donnie is never disciplined (aside from the occasional scream from Debbie) nor does he receive education (Honestly, the boy isn&#8217;t speaking English yet and you&#8217;ve had him with you for 2 years? I think it&#8217;s time to work on that, sign language?) And also because he has never left the wilderness. No wonder the boy can&#8217;t move on from the world of his dead parents and adoptive, Orangutan mother &#8211; he still lives in it!</p>
<p>The mother of the group, Marianne, is constantly depressed over whether or not she&#8217;s bonding correctly with her daughters, yet never does much to correct this due to the constraints of her job. She&#8217;s also insanely jealous of any woman who comes close to Nigel (going so far as to injure her back when competing with one English beauty) which makes me worry for her ability to trust. This inability to bond or trust possibly comes from her overly-critical mother who feels the need to make Marianne feel bad about well, everything. Except for at the very end of the show when they need to make everything happy again. You know.</p>
<p>There are a few things you could say about Nigel Thornberry, as far as shortcomings go, but after everything I&#8217;d just like to wrap his whole bit up with saying he&#8217;s still awesome.</p>
<p><a href="http://mittenskittens.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/tumblr_mdg4814p8w1ro8ysbo1_500.gif"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1571" title="tumblr_mdg4814p8w1ro8ysbo1_500" alt="" src="http://mittenskittens.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/tumblr_mdg4814p8w1ro8ysbo1_500.gif?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p><em>The Wild Thornberrys</em>. I thought things were normal until I was older, I liked Eliza until I realised how impossible she is to like, I worry for Donnie and I feel a sense of pity for Debbie. Who would have thought. My only question is, are these things really there? Or now that I&#8217;m older and more cynical, and worn, do I just see them?</p>
<p>It doesn&#8217;t really matter. What matters is that I&#8217;m writing a critical essay on a kid&#8217;s television program. What happened to my life?</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1567/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1567/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1567&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://mittenskittens.wordpress.com/2012/11/14/the-wild-thornberrys-revisited/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>43</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://mittenskittens.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/tumblr_md0aikh4zj1rie0uao1_500.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://mittenskittens.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/tumblr_md0aikh4zj1rie0uao1_500.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tumblr_md0aikh4ZJ1rie0uao1_500</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/fb23f6e342ed51997452bf51989cd153?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jessicamittens</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mittenskittens.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/tumblr_md0aikh4zj1rie0uao1_500.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tumblr_md0aikh4ZJ1rie0uao1_500</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mittenskittens.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/tumblr_mcsol5p5cp1rceklro1_500.gif" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tumblr_mcsol5P5Cp1rceklro1_500</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mittenskittens.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/tumblr_m7mqburnb01qhnqajo1_5001.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tumblr_m7mqburNb01qhnqajo1_500</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mittenskittens.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/char_40321.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">char_40321</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mittenskittens.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/tumblr_mdg4814p8w1ro8ysbo1_500.gif" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tumblr_mdg4814p8w1ro8ysbo1_500</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is Cursive Handwriting Dead?</title>
		<link>http://robincoyle.wordpress.com/2012/11/26/is-cursive-handwriting-dead/</link>
		<comments>http://robincoyle.wordpress.com/2012/11/26/is-cursive-handwriting-dead/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2012 19:53:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>robincoyle</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[In Search . . .]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cursive Handwriting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://robincoyle.wordpress.com/?p=3243</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[An article in today’s paper gave me pause. Cursive handwriting has one foot in the grave. A debate wages as 45 states adopt school curriculum guidelines for 2014 that exclude cursive handwriting, but do require keyboard proficiency by the time students exit elementary school. You can read the full article here, but some highlights are: [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3243&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://robincoyle.wordpress.com/2012/11/26/is-cursive-handwriting-dead/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>276</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/14283005e07cab680c3897d0a7d7cfb2?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">robincoyle</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/5/59/Cursive.png/300px-Cursive.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">English: I made it myself (Sotakeit)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://robincoyle.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/thank-you-note.jpg?w=225" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Thank you note</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://img.zemanta.com/zemified_e.png?x-id=ce4e2f5e-c977-4cf5-b00c-fc2df7c89bf9" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Enhanced by Zemanta</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Little Ones That Stole My Heart</title>
		<link>http://newmemories2012.wordpress.com/2012/11/29/the-little-ones-that-stole-my-heart/</link>
		<comments>http://newmemories2012.wordpress.com/2012/11/29/the-little-ones-that-stole-my-heart/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2012 13:25:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>robertoandnea</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mysore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yoga]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://newmemories2012.wordpress.com/?p=672</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The main reason I come to Mysore is to practice yoga with my teacher.  The couple of hours spent in the yoga shala in the wee hours of the morning are the highlight of the day. I’ve been coming here for seven years now. While it’s the yoga that keeps me coming back each year, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=672&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:justify;">The main reason I come to Mysore is to practice yoga with my teacher.  The couple of hours spent in the yoga shala in the wee hours of the morning are the highlight of the day. I’ve been coming here for seven years now. While it’s the yoga that keeps me coming back each year, there are other things that make my Mysore time special.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">In 2008, I arrived in Mysore with a broken heart. I had just said goodbye to someone I loved dearly. I knew my yoga practice and the community of friends here would help. But I also knew I needed to keep myself busy and resist the urge to wallow in self-pity. Over the previous two years I had spent more than 12 months in India. It was time to give back to the country that had given me so much.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">I started teaching English in the afternoons to some young children in a poor Muslim area of the city through an organisation called Pratham. One day my contact there, Mahesh, told me about a small children’s home that was very under resourced. I visited the home  &#8211; the space was tiny and the children were shy and sombre. Their ages ranged from 12 to 2 years and most had been rescued from the streets.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><a href="http://newmemories2012.wordpress.com/2012/11/29/the-little-ones-that-stole-my-heart/susmita/" rel="attachment wp-att-673"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-673" alt="" src="http://newmemories2012.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/susmita.jpg?w=604&#038;h=453" height="453" width="604" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><em>(After a few visits I wanted to learn their names so I took a series of these headshot photos. I didn&#8217;t realise then how fun it would be to look back and see how they have grown!)</em></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">I wasn’t sure what I could do to help. With the philosophy of something is better than nothing I started to visit them a couple of days a week in the afternoons. We sang songs, played games and anything else I could think of to entertain them (one day they even played musical statues to the accompaniment of my amateur flute playing &#8211; actually it was probably quite a few days!)</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><a href="http://newmemories2012.wordpress.com/2012/11/29/the-little-ones-that-stole-my-heart/kids-dancing/" rel="attachment wp-att-674"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-674" alt="" src="http://newmemories2012.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/kids-dancing.jpg?w=720&#038;h=540" height="540" width="720" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Other friends started to get involved and the support for the home snowballed. Funds were raised and donated. Activities became more ambitious from trips to the zoo, playtimes in the park to kirtans on the rooftop.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><a href="http://newmemories2012.wordpress.com/2012/11/29/the-little-ones-that-stole-my-heart/zoo/" rel="attachment wp-att-675"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-675" alt="" src="http://newmemories2012.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/zoo.jpg?w=604&#038;h=404" height="404" width="604" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><em>(I love this shot taken on a trip to the zoo!)</em></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://newmemories2012.wordpress.com/2012/11/29/the-little-ones-that-stole-my-heart/fund-raising-concert/" rel="attachment wp-att-676"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-676" alt="" src="http://newmemories2012.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/fund-raising-concert.jpg?w=720&#038;h=540" height="540" width="720" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><em>(The kids love it when Mark Robberds visits for kirtan. This was a particularly special night in 2010.)</em></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Support for the home really ramped up in early 2011 when a fellow yoga student Chris Ebbe relocated to Mysore fulltime. Thanks to the ongoing commitment of Chris, Warren and Flora, as well as other volunteers and donors. the kids now have regular yoga classes, English tutoring, fresh fruit and vegetables, dental and medical check-ups.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Some of the children I first met in 2008 have left the home but many are still there. It’s been lovely to see them grow and develop their personalities over the last five years. They are a special bunch. They steal the hearts of everyone they meet with their big eyes, wide smiles and non-stop antics. They are definitely more precocious than when I first met them. To be completely honest, sometimes in the afternoon when I am feeling a bit worn out, I don’t always feel like honouring my tutoring commitments. But no matter how tired I feel sitting in the rickshaw on the way there, I always feel energised and very happy on the way back.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">I once said to Chris, after he was telling me about some of the programs he had started for them, “Wow the kids are so lucky to have you here in Mysore.” He responded without a moment’s hesitation – “No I am lucky to have them.”</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">I couldn’t have said it better myself.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><a href="http://newmemories2012.wordpress.com/2012/11/29/the-little-ones-that-stole-my-heart/nea-and-sushmita/" rel="attachment wp-att-677"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-677" alt="" src="http://newmemories2012.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/nea-and-sushmita.jpg?w=300&#038;h=200" height="200" width="300" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><em>(Me with Sushmita just recently  - she has become quite the little madame since I first met her!)</em></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/672/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/672/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=672&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://newmemories2012.wordpress.com/2012/11/29/the-little-ones-that-stole-my-heart/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>36</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://newmemories2012.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/kids-dancing.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://newmemories2012.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/kids-dancing.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">kids dancing</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c32d23246669632760a2d29a2d5c31ff?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">robertoandnea</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://newmemories2012.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/susmita.jpg?w=604" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://newmemories2012.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/kids-dancing.jpg?w=720" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://newmemories2012.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/zoo.jpg?w=604" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://newmemories2012.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/fund-raising-concert.jpg?w=720" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://newmemories2012.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/nea-and-sushmita.jpg?w=300" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Economy</title>
		<link>http://conversationswithjapan.wordpress.com/2012/11/29/the-economy/</link>
		<comments>http://conversationswithjapan.wordpress.com/2012/11/29/the-economy/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2012 13:30:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>conversationswithjapan</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bubble]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[china]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[graphs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jobs]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://conversationswithjapan.wordpress.com/?p=144</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Me: Hi Japan. What’s going on with your economy? Japan: The usual. Why? Me: I keep hearing that it’s “stagnating” or “stagflating” or “sluggish” or a “train wreck”. Japan: It is. Me: And there’s a “lost generation” that can’t find really amazing jobs and earn buckets of cash every month. Japan: They can’t. Me: And [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=144&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><b>Me</b>: Hi Japan. What’s going on with your economy?</p>
<p><b>Japan</b>: The usual. Why?</p>
<p><b>Me</b>: I keep hearing that it’s “stagnating” or “stagflating” or “sluggish” or a “train wreck”.</p>
<p><b>Japan</b>: It is.</p>
<p><b>Me</b>: And there’s a “lost generation” that can’t find really amazing jobs and earn buckets of cash every month.</p>
<p><b>Japan</b>: They can’t.</p>
<p><b>Me</b>: And your GDP isn’t seventeen double digits above the baseline macro index for economic growth forecasts in the second half of the Dow Smith fiscal trimester.</p>
<p><b>Japan</b>: Something tells me you’re not an economist.</p>
<p><b>Me</b>: All of this must have had lots of very negative impacts on your society.</p>
<p><b>Japan</b>: Oh yes. Absolutely.</p>
<p><b>Me</b>: Such as?</p>
<p><b>Japan</b>: Well, as you said finding a decent job these days is tough.</p>
<p><b>Me</b>: Right<i>. </i>Finding a job isn’t easy. What else?</p>
<p><b>Japan</b>: People are earning less now. Wages have come down dramatically since the 90s.</p>
<p><b>Me</b>: How much were people earning before?</p>
<p><b>Japan</b>: Oh, shit loads. Business men got their bonuses delivered in wheel barrows.</p>
<p><b>Me</b>: And it’s subsequently come down to normal levels since the bubble burst?</p>
<p><b>Japan</b>: Yeah, i guess.</p>
<p><b>Me</b>: And what other major society-breaking, life-affecting problems have occurred since then?</p>
<p><b>Japan</b>: Well, erm, there&#8217;s the, er&#8230;let me think&#8230;</p>
<p><b>Me</b>: &#8230;</p>
<p><b>Japan</b>: &#8230;</p>
<p><b>Me</b>: Haven’t you still got one of the highest life expectancies in the world with some of the healthiest people even with your half-arsed smoking laws and steep suicide rates?</p>
<p><b>Japan</b>: Er&#8230;yeah. I think so.</p>
<p><b>Me</b>: And you’ve got one of the highest rates of literacy and numeracy and low rates or alcoholism and drug abuse.</p>
<p><b>Japan</b>: Yeah&#8230;but this year’s growth forecast isn’t looking great. Again.</p>
<p><b>Me</b>: Aren’t your crime and incarceration rates are really low? Don’t you have universal health care and an absence of obesity?</p>
<p><b>Japan</b>: Yeah, but last years’ numbers weren’t good at all. Just look at those graphs.</p>
<p><b>Me</b>: You’ve got low rates of teenage pregnancy and mental illness. You’ve got the best public transport infrastructure on earth that can take people to all corners of you quickly and cleanly.</p>
<p><b>Japan</b>: Yeah, look, you’re totally missing the point.</p>
<p><b>Me</b>: Sure, you’re not perfect and your financial system isn’t anywhere within driving distance of being in awesome tip-top shape, apparently, but all of the above has continued whilst your economy has “faltered” and “stuttered”. Daily life is still pretty comfortable isn’t it? Has any of this really changed? How have you suffered?</p>
<p><b>Japan</b>: Well, i’ve been left behind. China’s now the second biggest economy in the world. I’m number three.</p>
<p><b>Me</b>: And?</p>
<p><b>Japan</b>: Well, they’ve overtaken me.</p>
<p><b>Me</b>: So?</p>
<p><b>Japan</b>: So, well, erm, their economy is bigger than mine.</p>
<p><b>Me</b>: And that means it’s a better place to live?</p>
<p><b>Japan</b>: China? God no. Have you seen it? It’s a fantastic mess.</p>
<p><b>Me</b>: Right.</p>
<p><b>Japan</b>: But their graphs do look good. I mean, you can’t beat looking at an economic graph and statistics for finding out how nice a country is to live in, can you?</p>
<p><b>Me</b>: Have you ever thought of looking at some other graphs and statistics?</p>
<p><b>Japan</b>: Hell no. What would that tell me?</p>
<p><b>Me</b>: Well&#8230;who knows?</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/144/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/144/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=144&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://conversationswithjapan.wordpress.com/2012/11/29/the-economy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/9bad801c8345ceef5a881c253432e5a3?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">conversationswithjapan</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Beyond Fan Fiction, a Personal Account</title>
		<link>http://sillyverse.com/2012/11/26/beyond-fan-fiction-a-personal-account/</link>
		<comments>http://sillyverse.com/2012/11/26/beyond-fan-fiction-a-personal-account/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2012 19:45:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Brian Bixby</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Dragon Lady]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fan fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inspiration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Japanese dragon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[memoir]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://sillyverse.wordpress.com/?p=385</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As I mentioned in my post a week ago, my story telling was inspired by the example of my father reading to us kids and telling us his stories. However, inspiration is not enough. One has to take the initiative, and start working out stories of one&#8217;s own. I have had trouble falling asleep since [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=385&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As I mentioned in <a href="http://sillyverse.com/2012/11/19/teller-of-tales/">my post a week ago</a>, my story telling was inspired by the example of my father reading to us kids and telling us his stories. However, inspiration is not enough. One has to take the initiative, and start working out stories of one&#8217;s own.</p>
<p>I have had trouble falling asleep since as far back as I can remember. As a child, I slept in a bedroom that had a closet that contained other people&#8217;s clothes. So I rarely went into it, and its contents were unfamiliar to me. I would lie awake at night, and wonder just what might be lurking in the closet. Or maybe under the bed. It would take me forever to fall asleep.</p>
<p>I needed a way to distract myself. So, when I was in elementary school, I began thinking up stories as I lay there, trying to get to sleep.</p>
<p>I wasn&#8217;t original enough to make up my own stories from scratch. I needed something to get me started. So I did what millions of others have done. I engaged in dreaming up fan fiction, although I didn&#8217;t know that was what it was called. Give me a little credit for creativity, though. I didn&#8217;t just start with one source; I combined two. There was what I guess would be called a young adult novel by <a href="http://www.loisduncan.arquettes.com/index.htm">Lois Duncan</a> entitled <em>Ransom</em> that had just come out about children on a school bus being kidnapped. (I was nine when I read it, hardly a young adult, but I read well above my age level in those days.) And there was a television series, <em>The Green Hornet</em>, which was similar to the <em>Batman</em> series of the same era, but much, much less campy, more straightforward. (Here&#8217;s a <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uuoNLnrPlFM">link to its opening credits</a>, which gives you an idea of what it was about, and why it might inspire a nine-year-old. Don&#8217;t confuse this with the recent movie remake.) So I took the book and the TV series, recast myself as a Green Hornet clone, assigned the Kato role to the girl on whom I had a secret crush, and went out to foil the bad guys in <em>Ransom</em>. And imagining that story helped me to get to sleep.</p>
<p>Well, you can only tell yourself the same story so many times before it gets old and shopworn. I set out to solve other crimes, to right other wrongs. But I never got that far from being the Green Hornet. No, breaking away, becoming original, that took time. It also took yet another television series, the <em>Dark Shadows</em> gothic soap opera, for that step. The main protagonist in <em>Dark Shadows</em> was a vampire who was trying to do good, but compelled by his nature to do evil. It was a challenging concept for a subteen boy. That time around, I didn&#8217;t just borrow the stories and cast myself in the lead. I made up an entire universe. I was going to dream <em>my</em> dreams. In truth, my universe and characters were threadbare copies at first. They weren&#8217;t complete copies, though. I introduced differences. To start with, my lead character was not a vampire, even though he was a deeply conflicted individual who dealt with the supernatural. Over time, those differences built up. Eventually, they became my creations, with very little debt to the originals.</p>
<p>One of the engines for my original development of stories has been the age-old question, &#8220;How did it get that way?&#8221; I&#8217;d work out a story in my head, and once I had it worked out, I&#8217;d start wondering about what happened before. And there&#8217;s <em>always</em> something that happened before. Asking this question made me a historian by inclination long before I became a professionally-trained one. Trying to answer that question (and its counterpart, &#8220;What happened afterwards?&#8221;) meant I had to think about the motivations and social conditions that created any story I developed. For example, those of you reading my story <a href="http://sillyverse.wordpress.com/the-dragon-lady-of-stockbridge/dls-ch-1/"><em>The Dragon Lady of Stockbridge</em></a> as I post it, know it is set in the year 1886, and that Abigail Lane is one of its principal characters. Abigail was created to help explain elements in another story I have written, a story set in the year 2000!</p>
<p>That story set in the year 2000 represented the last crucial step I took in the transition from fan fiction in my head to original stories on the written page: writing. It doesn&#8217;t matter how lively your imagination is, you can&#8217;t write a good story unless you actually write it down. (Homer and Oscar Wilde are exceptions, I admit. If you&#8217;re in their league, don&#8217;t read my advice; send me yours!) Writing it down does three things for you. First, it forces you to actually define your story, set it in metaphorical concrete, make you translate your musings into something that has to have logic and coherence. Second, you have to consider how to tell the story, and what mechanics and strategies of writing you will use. To mention the most obvious example, because it is being written as a serial, <em>The Dragon Lady of Stockbridge</em> has to have some sort of climax at the end of every chapter, and I have had to try what for me are new strategies to create those. Third, you have to actually think about your audience. What you write has to be good enough to read, by someone. If it isn&#8217;t, you have to either revise, begin over, or admit you don&#8217;t really want to write. If it is, you then need to figure out how to reach your audience.</p>
<div id="attachment_386" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 170px"><a href="http://sillyverse.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/oscar_wilde_portrait.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-386" title="Oscar_Wilde_portrait" alt="" src="http://sillyverse.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/oscar_wilde_portrait.jpg?w=590"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">He&#8217;s an exception</p></div>
<p>The biggest day in my life as a writer was not creating that first story, back when I was a child. No, it was when I had the courage and desire to show my first written story to my girlfriend. That was the day I said I wanted to write something good enough for another reader, something good enough to be published. Writing in this blog has been another step. And if my protagonist, Rebecca Maxwell, carries a walking stick, just like the lead in <em>Dark Shadows</em>, I have the pleasure of knowing that it is only a resemblance, and that she and her story are entirely my creation, here for you to read.</p>
<div id="attachment_333" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 235px"><a href="http://sillyverse.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dragon-cane-ink2.png"><img class="size-medium wp-image-333" title="Dragon-cane-ink" alt="" src="http://sillyverse.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dragon-cane-ink2.png?w=225&#038;h=300" height="300" width="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Rebecca Farnsworth Maxwell&#8217;s walking stick &#8211; E.J. Barnes</p></div>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=385&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://sillyverse.com/2012/11/26/beyond-fan-fiction-a-personal-account/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>36</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/e0fa70f65f5676f04fa4198eeff03175?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sillyhughes</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://sillyverse.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/oscar_wilde_portrait.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Oscar_Wilde_portrait</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://sillyverse.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dragon-cane-ink2.png?w=225" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Dragon-cane-ink</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
