<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2012 22:02:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Paul Grist: Serious Funny Books</title>
		<link>http://timhayes.eu/2012/09/20/paul-grist-interview/</link>
		<comments>http://timhayes.eu/2012/09/20/paul-grist-interview/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2012 23:24:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tim</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DC Thomson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Image Comics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jack staff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kane]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[paul grist]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://timhayes.eu/?p=2794</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[An interview with Paul Grist about his career and most famous creations.<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2794&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2798" title="Let's put our bacon on the table. Paul Grist art from Kane." src="http://pentimento.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/nelson.jpg" alt="" width="550" height="381" /></p>
<p><em>(This interview with Paul Grist was originally destined for another venue and presented here as-is, house style and chronology intact. <a href="http://timhayes.eu/2012/09/19/paul-grist-review/" target="_blank">See also this companion post</a>.)</em></p>
<p>The first port of call for a lesson in why readers respond to simplified art and non-realistic drawings in comic strips is still Understanding Comics, in which Scott McCloud digs into the matter and ends up on his knees worshipping the power of cartoons.</p>
<p>Alternatively you can read Paul Grist comics.</p>
<p>Since 1986 Grist has produced a steady, if sometimes erratically scheduled, sequence of inventive and deceptively low-key British comics, developing his combination of expressive cartoon figure work, energetic layouts and dense plotting into a striking personal style.</p>
<p>&#8220;I wear my &#8216;I am a cartoonist&#8217; badge with pride,&#8221; Grist says. &#8220;I&#8217;ve never really understood why cartoony is used as a derogatory term by some comic readers. Are there people out there who think that the only thing that stopped Bill Watterson being successful was that he didn&#8217;t draw a realistic tiger? I just try to generate a readability, an immediacy, something that can be recognized and identified with.&#8221;</p>
<p>After a childhood following artists such as Mike Noble, Frank Bellamy and Gerry Haylock, Grist broke into comics via the UK&#8217;s small-press scene. His first effort, Short Stories, came to the attention of DC Thomson&#8217;s girls&#8217; comics group, and the publisher offered him work within a week – a contrast to his failure to catch the eye of Marvel and 2000AD, which were proving to be tougher nuts.</p>
<p>&#8220;Perhaps the lesson is that it&#8217;s a lot easier to get into those comics that not many other people are aiming for. DC Thompson were great and kept me busy for a couple of years, working primarily on Nikki. I did short humour strips, quiz illustrations, and drew the cover strip for a year or so.&#8221;</p>
<p>A higher profile arrived in 1989 when Grist illustrated Grant Morrison&#8217;s St. Swithin&#8217;s Day, originally for Trident and later reprinted by Oni Press. Morrison&#8217;s deliberately provocative mix of youthful unrest and anti-Thatcherite bile grabbed some headlines, but at least as much impact comes from the ink-heavy art and its unnerving high contrast. Grist&#8217;s cartooning does exactly what McCloud describes, turning the troubled protagonist into an ambiguous, queasy mirror.</p>
<p><strong>LIVING IN EDEN</strong><br />
Kane, the self-published story of New Eden&#8217;s 39th Precinct and its officers, is where everything clicked. A long-form police procedural, with constant flashbacks to trip up the unwary and sub-plots that looked all set to tumble on forever, the shadowy past of Detective Kane was a sprawling canvas for Grist&#8217;s imagination to work with.</p>
<p>When it appeared in 1993, the comparisons were with David Lapham&#8217;s Stray Bullets and Frank Miller&#8217;s Sin City &#8211; Grist affectionately ribbed Miller&#8217;s stories several times as he went along &#8211; but Kane was a chillier, more humane, and more effective strip. And for readers who found that New Eden&#8217;s moustachioed SWAT team leader and his taste for excessive violence rang a bell, the strongest influence was clearly from another medium altogether.</p>
<p>&#8220;Hill Street Blues is very much the template for Kane: multiple storylines with a wide-ranging cast, and a mix of drama and comedy,&#8221; agrees Grist. &#8220;I loved doing Kane. I think in general if you&#8217;re not working on your favourite comic then you&#8217;re probably doing it wrong, and it certainly helped get me noticed within the industry.&#8221;</p>
<p>Grist&#8217;s storytelling efforts in Kane were certainly noticeable, since he worked the page hard. One issue is told from a fixed vantage point on the rear seat of a patrol car; another makes do without speech or captions. A gangster speaks in a style on loan from Marlon Brando&#8217;s Don Corleone, via phonetic speech balloons to be unpicked at leisure; Kane himself often says hardly anything. Officer Kate Felix, ever the voice of reason, gets one of the great stand-alone issues of any comic, a childhood incident and present-day crisis running in parallel.</p>
<p>&#8220;I just try to make the page visually interesting,&#8221; comments Grist. &#8220;Comics are a visual medium, so when people just put one square panel after another, I think they&#8217;re really not using the medium to its full potential. To me that seems like dancing but not moving your feet.&#8221;</p>
<p>Kane was the definition of a cult hit, with vocal champions but not a huge readership. The book&#8217;s narrative became extended by publication delays and threatened to grind to a halt, and some felt that the flashback structure was too hard to follow. &#8220;Kane was very popular with the people who liked it, but sadly there weren&#8217;t that many of them,&#8221; says Grist looking back. &#8220;Ultimately it just wasn&#8217;t selling enough for me to be able to continue.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>THE PAST IS NEVER DEAD</strong><br />
As Kane showed signs of fatigue, Grist responded with Jack Staff, originally aiming to attract readers and then draw them over to Kane. Hence a change of tack: from an American cop to a British superhero. But the tone was recognisably from the same pen.</p>
<p>&#8220;I tend to see my comics as being a mix of the sombre and the humorous,&#8221; explains Grist. &#8220;Serious funny books. Or funny serious books. Jack Staff is all about cause and effect, rather than nostalgia, but it&#8217;s also about ageing and death. Jack Staff is someone who is alive forever; Becky Burdock, vampire girl reporter, is dead forever. And together they&#8217;re facing the End of Everything. But that doesn&#8217;t have to be a bad thing. You can still have a bit of fun along the road.&#8221;</p>
<p>If Kane was Americana, then Jack Staff is British to the core, loosely formatted in the style of past British action weeklies and seasoned with business from the UK&#8217;s collective memory. A flashback to 1940 allows for a walk-on by the Walmington-on-Sea Home Guard, while the ambiguously spectral Helen Morgan addresses the reader from limbo and views the world through the Play School windows.</p>
<p>&#8220;I just throw in things that amuse me, really,&#8221; comments her creator. &#8220;None of the in-jokes or references to old British comic characters are important in terms of the story, it&#8217;s just an extra layer for British readers of a certain age. I hope the story holds up in and of itself, and the fact that readers elsewhere can get it gives me some confidence that it does.&#8221;</p>
<p>The Americans at Image Comics got it, and picked up the book as a continuing series, leading not only to greater visibility for the strip, but also to a transition into colour.</p>
<p>As it turns out, colour transforms the effect of Grist&#8217;s art. The black-and-white Jack Staff is a contemplative, moody strip, sometimes given to introspection. The Image version is a full-colour Hellzapoppin&#8217;, in which anything goes, the layouts fizz, and the next figure around the corner may be demon, ghoul or giant talking goldfish.</p>
<p>&#8220;Eric Stephenson contacted me out of the blue and asked if I had ever thought about publishing Jack Staff at Image, to which the only honest answer was no. It  was only when they said that they wanted to publish it as a full-colour comic that it made sense to do it, since that gave me an opportunity to do something that I couldn&#8217;t do with my own resources. Image also allows me to have everything in print at the same time, which as a self-publisher was something that was proving a bit of a juggling act.&#8221;</p>
<p>Grist had always wanted to include colour in Jack Staff: &#8220;After all, it&#8217;s a superhero comic, and superhero comics are always in colour. I like to think of the original series as being a colour comic with a lot of black-and-white pages. But I do still find myself in the mindset of drawing black-and-white pages which are then coloured in. I don&#8217;t think a black-and-white page is simply a colour page without colour. That&#8217;s a common mistake in comics, I think.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>A PAPER MEDIUM</strong><br />
&#8220;In 1993 when I started doing Kane there were two big distributors plus several smaller ones, and there were less people actively making comics, so it was a bit easier to get noticed,&#8221; says Grist. &#8220;Now there is a single distributor which has tightened up a lot on what it will distribute, and which expects bar codes and all sorts of other professional malarkey that wasn&#8217;t asked for in my day. I&#8217;m not saying it is a bad thing that Diamond expects to approve the comics that they solicit for, but it makes it just a bit more difficult to get a new comic out there.&#8221;</p>
<p>On the other hand, the rise of the internet means it has become easier to get work seen by potential readers &#8211; whether or not the work is any good, or profitable. But fittingly for an artist with a taste for wrangling the fixed dimensions of a paper page, Grist feels no great urge to decamp onto the internet or create a web comic.</p>
<p>&#8220;As far as I&#8217;m concerned, comics are a paper medium,&#8221; he says. &#8220;This may well be an age thing. I don&#8217;t find reading comics on screen to be that interesting, so web comics are not something that I&#8217;m really planning on exploring in the near future. I did serialise a comic I published, The Eternal Conflicts of the Cosmic Warrior, in a blog, but that was more a case of putting a paper comic on-screen than actually doing a comic for the web.</p>
<p>&#8220;After years as an active self-publisher, I&#8217;ve now been published by Image for longer than I spent putting out my own books, so I’m really out of the loop as far as self-publishing goes nowadays. But one of the encouraging things about going to comic shows around the UK is that there are new, young people putting out their own comics. Twenty years ago you&#8217;d go to the London Convention and the small-press section would be in a corridor leading through to the main hall. Now they&#8217;ve become a main event in their own right. There&#8217;s a lot of creativity out there, which is very encouraging to see.&#8221;</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2810" title="In the mouth of madness. Paul Grist art from Jack Staff." src="http://pentimento.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/jackstaff41.jpg" alt="" width="535" height="807" /></p>
<p>(art by Paul Grist, scanned for review purposes. Copyright the respective publishers.)</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2794/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2794/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2794&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://timhayes.eu/2012/09/20/paul-grist-interview/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f23dce32a50bee06a3d8bebd698f5c0e?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tim</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://pentimento.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/nelson.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Let&#039;s put our bacon on the table. Paul Grist art from Kane.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://pentimento.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/jackstaff41.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">In the mouth of madness. Paul Grist art from Jack Staff.</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Universal Language</title>
		<link>http://raptorcoffee.wordpress.com/2012/09/19/the-universal-language/</link>
		<comments>http://raptorcoffee.wordpress.com/2012/09/19/the-universal-language/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2012 01:06:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Liz Rathbone</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Coffee Shop Chronicles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[barista]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coffee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coffee culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coffee shop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[seattle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[universal language]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://raptorcoffee.wordpress.com/?p=200</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[When I first started working at the District Coffee Shop, my boss told me “Coffee is a universal language. You can go anywhere in the world and find coffee and the culture that surrounds it.” I never for one moment doubted that statement. Coffee was something so personal to me, something that was more than [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=200&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When I first started working at the District Coffee Shop, my boss told me “Coffee is a universal language. You can go anywhere in the world and find coffee and the culture that surrounds it.”</p>
<p>I never for one moment doubted that statement. Coffee was something so personal to me, something that was more than just a warm cup; but rather an experience, emotional and physical, that I craved whether or not it was the caffeine driving it.</p>
<p>My friends at home were jealous when I told them I was moving to Seattle. I saw the barista faces of my friends long for the opportunity to be surrounded by so much good coffee. While I refrained from telling them just how many Starbucks there were in the city, I did share in their excitement and look forward to experiencing the coffee vibe of this city for myself.</p>
<p>Today when I woke up I knew that it was time to go to a coffee shop, alone, and see for myself what it felt like here. I know that buying coffee isn’t going to be something I can do on a regular basis, given the absurd price for a cup of joe in this city, but I was feeling lonely and I knew that something familiar would help me feel more at home in this city.</p>
<p>What would make a barista feel more at home than a coffee shop?</p>
<p>I opted for a coffee shop close to my aunt’s store called Zoka. As I walked through the large entrance I admired the beautiful woodwork and breathed in the familiar scent of coffee beans.  I noticed that the store was filled with other Seattle natives typing away on their computers or visiting with friends and smiled – this was a picture I was used to.</p>
<p>When I stepped up to the counter and looked at their menu I refrained from blurting out “You do Pour Over’s too? We’re the only shop in Boise that does that!” though I’m sure my friendly barista would have smiled and not thought I was too weird because of it.</p>
<p>I ordered my usual and scoped out a spot by the window where I could observe the people who came through the door. Young and old, students and couples, hippies and hipsters all walked through the door and looked like they belonged here. I wondered if I looked like I was supposed to be there too.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"> <a href="http://raptorcoffee.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_3690.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-201" title="IMG_3690" src="http://raptorcoffee.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_3690.jpg?w=300&h=397" alt="" width="300" height="397" /></a></p>
<p>My barista poured stunning latte art and I immediately sent a picture to my co-assistant manager back home, knowing he’d appreciate it. I felt another pang of loneliness knowing nobody was here to share this moment with me. But when I complimented my barista on her excellent pouring she smiled and we exchanged a few friendly words before I sat down to write.</p>
<p>I may not know anyone in this town yet, but I feel comfortable with one of the biggest parts of the culture: coffee. Maybe I haven’t made any friends, but the friendly smiles of others in the coffee shop reassure me that I’ve learned the language here – it’s only a matter of time before I get to speak it with someone.</p>
<p><a href="http://raptorcoffee.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_3692.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-202" title="IMG_3692" src="http://raptorcoffee.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_3692.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="373" /></a></p>
<p><strong><a href="http://www.zokacoffee.com/">Zoka Coffee</a></strong></p>
<p>2901 NE Blakeley Street<br />
Seattle, WA 98105<br />
206.527.0990<br />
Mon-Fri: 6am to 9pm<br />
Sat-Sun: 7am to 9pm</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/200/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/200/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=200&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://raptorcoffee.wordpress.com/2012/09/19/the-universal-language/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>34</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/6c45f8f50d2e451b712be911b0c477ef?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">rathbon</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://raptorcoffee.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_3690.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_3690</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://raptorcoffee.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_3692.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_3692</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>International Dot Day!</title>
		<link>http://soulstrikers.wordpress.com/2012/09/17/international-dot-day/</link>
		<comments>http://soulstrikers.wordpress.com/2012/09/17/international-dot-day/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2012 01:11:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>soul strikers</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exploring]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blc12]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dot Day]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://soulstrikers.wordpress.com/?p=523</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Monday was my first experience Skyping my class around the world!  This past summer at Building Learning Communities, word spread fast of an idea that students around the world could read and share the impact of a common book: The Dot, by Peter H.  Reynolds. It took no convincing for me to plan this for my [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=523&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://soulstrikers.wordpress.com/2012/09/17/international-dot-day/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>23</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://soulstrikers.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dotday.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://soulstrikers.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dotday.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">dotday</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/4af5c0fd13507a8103ea167b91a47a32?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">soulstrikers</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://www.peterhreynolds.com/dot/smDot.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://soulstrikers.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_0541.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0541</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://soulstrikers.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_0542.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0542</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://soulstrikers.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_0532.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0532</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://soulstrikers.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_0539.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0539</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://soulstrikers.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_0540.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0540</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>10 Years After Columbia: Balancing Life &amp; Work</title>
		<link>http://waynehale.wordpress.com/2012/09/19/ten-years-after-columbia-balancing-life-and-work/</link>
		<comments>http://waynehale.wordpress.com/2012/09/19/ten-years-after-columbia-balancing-life-and-work/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2012 12:42:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>waynehale</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Columbia Ac]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flight director]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[High Reliability Organizations]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://waynehale.wordpress.com/?p=248</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[When you are in a High Reliability Organization, you have to pay attention.  The more extreme the risk, the more difficult the environment, the more complex the technology, the more attention you must pay.  But life intrudes.  As the song says, there are planes to catch and bills to pay, and too there are little [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=248&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When you are in a High Reliability Organization, you have to pay attention.  The more extreme the risk, the more difficult the environment, the more complex the technology, the more attention you must pay.  But life intrudes.  As the song says, there are planes to catch and bills to pay, and too there are little children to play with.  You cannot work all the time, and if the balance gets too far either way, a price will be exacted.  Once upon a time I wrote:  “pay attention, do good work, have no regrets”.  True, but far too simplistic. </p>
<p>In 2002 I thought we were paying the right level of attention to the shuttle.  I thought<em> I</em> was paying the right level of attention to the shuttle.  I was a Flight Director.  I was also a husband and a father and active in my community.  I thought I could do it all. </p>
<p>I was wrong.</p>
<p>Later on, I will write about the MLK three day weekend that cost us a crew just because we took three days off.  But how can you know in advance where the proper balance is between work and life when you work at extreme risk?</p>
<p>This is my personal recollection of the events leading up to the Columbia accident nearly ten years ago, so let’s get personal. I will start with the work side; later I will visit the ‘life’ side.</p>
<p>In 2002 I was a Space Shuttle Flight Director at the Johnson Space Center.  Not only that, I was the Deputy Chief of the Flight Director’s Office for Space Shuttle Operations. That meant that I had managerial responsibilities; personnel responsibilities, budgetary responsibilities.  Oh, that last one, about budget – we will visit that again in a later post.  How I hated budget responsibilities in an era of cost cutting.</p>
<p>Life was a continuous round of meetings, teleconferences, and management decisions.  I regularly attended the Shuttle Program management meetings and had input into many of the decisions that were made in those days.  We evaluated in flight anomalies, provided recommendations on the budget, questioned technical issues, and tried to pay attention to everything.  Even though the organization chart showed I was in the Mission Operations organization, we were all part of “the Program”.</p>
<p>I had just come off a successful Lead Flight Director assignment in December 2001 for STS-108/ISS UF-1.  Being a lead flight director is a year long assignment; the Lead Flight Director is responsible for all aspects of mission planning, training, and execution for a shuttle flight.  It was a tremendous amount of pressure and a huge satisfaction when it was over.  ISS Utilization Flight-1, commanded by Dom Gorie, was a logistics flight with a Multi-Purpose Logistics Module full of supplies and a large quantity of scientific experiments for the ISS.  The most emotional part of the flight was the 9/11 remembrance which got punted to me.  The list of mission objectives was long.  We completed them all, just another 100% successful shuttle mission.  Except for the inflight anomalies on the shuttle system, nothing untoward occurred, and even those were nothing to worry about.  Or so we thought.</p>
<p>It was my third, and as it turned out, last assignment as a Lead Flight Director.</p>
<p>Every shuttle flight has three to five Flight Directors assigned.  One FD was the Ascent/Entry guy &#8211; my usual job.  The A/E FD worked shifts prelaunch, launch, went to in standby/monitor mode for the middle of the flight, and then worked one pre-deorbit shift (Flight Control System Checkout day) and the Entry shift.  Or Entry shifts, as weather caused frequently delays.  During most of the flight, while the on-orbit flight directors were in charge, the A/E FD could be found most often in the JSC Weather office kibitzing with the meteorologists, eating their food (they always had the best snack layout), hanging out in the back row of the MMT, and generally being a nuisance.  During the ‘on-orbit’ period, there were three shifts of roughly eight hours each, cleverly named the Orbit 1, Orbit 2, and Orbit 3 shift.  Sometimes we called the Orbit 3 shift (when the crew was asleep), the Planning shift because every “night” the plan would be reviewed, modified, and changes sent up to the astronauts.  If the flight was more than about 10 days long, an additional Orbit team would be assigned to allow the three primary shifts to have a day off.  Shift schedule planning could be complex.  Typically the Lead Flight Director worked the Orbit 1 shift.  But on every flight, because the FD had to stay in the Mission Control Room working the minute by minute details, a manager from the Mission Operations organization was assigned to be the go between from the flight control team and the on-console flight directors to the Mission Management Team, aka NASA senior management.  The Mission Operations Director had several formal duties, most important of which was as a member of the MMT.  The MOD did not work a specified shift but was always in the MCC during the most critical and dynamic times.  So when the on-console FD was under the most stress, that was the precise moment when the MOD, the FD “boss” would show up: to sit on the console directly behind the FD, and offer “advice” and “encouragement” and write up performance appraisals.  The MOD, along with the Lead Flight Director, also flew to KSC for the Flight Readiness Review about two weeks before launch where about a hundred of the NASA senior managers met face to face to ensure the shuttle was ready for launch. </p>
<p>I was assigned to be the MOD for the 4<sup>th</sup> Hubble Space Telescope servicing Mission, STS-109, which flew in March of 2002.  It was a hectic mission with lots of little issues, but no big ones that I recall.  I hope I wasn’t too much of a nuisance to the flight control team doing the real work!</p>
<p>Finally, for 2002, I was assigned as the STS-113 A/E Flight Director.   STS-113 or ISS Assembly Flight 11A carried a huge solar array – Port Array #1 – up to the ISS.  Jim Wetherbee was the commander.  We were all informed of the in flight anomalies from the previous flight, STS-112.  Among those anomalies was the loss of a large segment of insulating foam from the External Tank which fell and struck the left hand Solid Rocket Booster.  This strike left a large smudge on the steel case.  We Flight Directors speculated that if that piece of foam had struck a critical electronic box on the SRB not far from where the smudge was located, that BAD THINGS might have happened. But then, we Flight Directors were always worry warts.  At the FRR the foam loss was deemed “not a safety of flight issue”.  The A/E FD does not go to FRRs.  In retrospect, of course, I wish I had gone.  Maybe I could have gotten the captain to turn the Titanic away from the iceberg.  But that didn’t happen.  No significant foam loss occurred on STS-113, so we all shrugged and agreed it had been a one time thing. </p>
<p>We were wrong.  STS-113 was the last successful entry of a space shuttle flight for three years. </p>
<p>We all knew that Jim Wetherbee was slated to take over JSC’s office of Safety and Mission Assurance right after his flight; so for a humorous moment, I got on the Air to Ground radio after the landing and spoke with him.  It is not typical, but not all that unusual, for a Flight Director to pre-empt the CAPCOM and talk directly with the crew.  After the successful landing I was in a jocular mood so just before Wetherbee was to leave the cockpit, I called him up (you can probably find the recording somewhere) and congratulated him on a successful flight and told him “your desk in Building 1 [JSC’s management building] is waiting for you”.  Fate is funny;  it turned out that prophecy applied to me too, but I didn’t know it at the time.</p>
<p>It was my last time to sit at the Flight Director’s chair in Mission Control.  Best job of my life; I miss it every day; but it was over and I didn’t know it.</p>
<p>So work was a 60 hour a week job; it was always on my mind.  There were a thousand details to plan and decide and brief to management.  Even then I recognized that there were a million details in the shuttle business that I couldn’t participate in; there just wasn’t enough time or energy for any one person to do it all.  The folks in the shuttle program office, Ron Dittemore, Linda Ham, and the rest, they had a tough job.  Tougher than you know.  Tougher than I knew at the time.  Everybody played their part, everybody was highly motivated, everybody wanted the shuttle to succeed, and yet, within months, we were all to fail. </p>
<p>Why?  Listen and learn.  Maybe you will avoid failure.  But don’t count on it.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/248/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/248/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=248&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://waynehale.wordpress.com/2012/09/19/ten-years-after-columbia-balancing-life-and-work/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>17</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/ef05d62d6af79c04bda300eaafe489d2?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">waynehale</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>On Humility and Turds</title>
		<link>http://thebumplife.com/2012/09/18/humility_and_turds/</link>
		<comments>http://thebumplife.com/2012/09/18/humility_and_turds/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2012 18:28:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>The Bump Life</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pregnancy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[challenges for stay-at-home-moms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diapering mishaps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mommy wars]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thebumplife.com/?p=686</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A few mornings ago, I unzipped my son’s sleep sack and two perfectly round turds popped out, fell to the floor and rolled under the changing table. Thunk, thunk, rooollllll. I stood there, frozen, thinking, how did those turds escape?, only to proceed further and discover my son’s pajamas were unsnapped and up around his [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=686&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_697" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 620px"><a href="http://thebumplife.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/parentingreward.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-697" title="parentingreward" src="http://thebumplife.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/parentingreward.jpg" alt="Parenting's Reward" width="610" height="490" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">My sweet little slice of humble pie</p></div>
<p>A few mornings ago, I unzipped my son’s sleep sack and two perfectly round turds popped out, fell to the floor and rolled under the changing table.</p>
<p><em>Thunk, thunk, rooollllll. </em></p>
<p>I stood there, frozen, thinking, <em>how did those turds escape?, </em>only to proceed further and discover my son’s pajamas were unsnapped and up around his waist. His diaper, pee-stained but turd-free, was unfastened and resting at the bottom of the sleep sack. Poop was <em>everywhere</em>.</p>
<p>If there’s one thing I’ve learned in my time as a mom, it’s the importance of humility.</p>
<p>The funny thing was, I had just had lunch with a friend the day before the turd incident, and humility was the very thing we were discussing. I had recently been involved in quite a few conversations with other moms that had carried a pretty judgmental tone. Whenever I encounter moms bashing other moms for their parenting styles or decisions — or even just talking in a know-it-all fashion — I think about humility.</p>
<p>The most common fodder for the “Mommy Wars” that have gotten so much press lately is the decision to work a traditional job or stay home to raise kids. What those engaged in this silly battle seem to overlook is that there is no one-size-fits-all approach to life, and there are challenges no matter which road you choose to take.</p>
<p>Wendy Goffe writes in her article, “<a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/deborahljacobs/2012/04/15/a-working-mom-defends-the-lululemon-stay-at-home-mother/" target="_blank">A Working Mom Defends the &#8216;Lululemon Stay-at-Home Mother&#8217;</a>” that she’s thankful for her job and ability to pay for a nanny, because she doesn’t “have the skills to raise five children.”</p>
<p>There are days when I don’t believe I have those skills either. Especially on mornings when I find I’ve failed to perform the simple act of properly fastening a diaper so my son’s legs don’t wind up smeared in poop. When you’re a stay-at-home-mom and fastening diapers is a pretty prominent part of your job description, that’s a demoralizing feeling.</p>
<p>What gets me through the day is humility. I remind myself that I don’t have it all figured out, and that’s okay. It’s okay to be intimidated by the supreme responsibility of raising a human being from an infant to a man. Shouldn’t we all be?</p>
<p>Contrary to the fussy, colicky baby I prepared for throughout my pregnancy, my son sleeps through the night, eats well, plays independently and has a happy demeanor most of the time. I consider this nothing more than immensely good fortune, and I thank my lucky stars for him nearly every day.</p>
<p>If anything, this makes me <em>less</em> qualified to judge a mom whose baby cries incessantly, or wakes several times a night for months on end or refuses to eat healthy, well-balanced meals. What do I know about that mom’s struggle? What makes me think I would handle those challenges better?</p>
<p>And, also, there’s this one little thing about parenting that we all have to remember: <em>things change. </em></p>
<p>After months of sleeping beautifully, my son recently starting waking up crying in the middle of the night. At times I worried my parenting luck had run out. But we got through what turned out to be a simultaneous growth spurt and rough teething patch. Now, we’re dealing with a new challenge: his proclivity for biting. <em>Hard. </em></p>
<p>That three-week span when I found myself rocking a crying baby in the middle of the night, I thought about how fortunate I’ve been. I can’t imagine how much strength it would take to deal with that all the time. I don’t judge moms who have had a tough road with their babies; <em>I admire them. </em>I sympathize. I raise my fist in solidarity with them.</p>
<p>And I sure hope those moms who have never had to wipe up after a turd on the loose don’t judge me.</p>
<p>*       *       *       *       *</p>
<p>Welcome to those of you who found my blog via Freshly Pressed! Thanks so much for stopping by, and thanks to WordPress.com for &#8230; just, everything. Follow my blog to keep in touch!</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://thebumplife.com/category/children/'>Children</a>, <a href='http://thebumplife.com/category/life/'>Life</a>, <a href='http://thebumplife.com/category/parenting/'>Parenting</a>, <a href='http://thebumplife.com/category/pregnancy/'>Pregnancy</a> Tagged: <a href='http://thebumplife.com/tag/challenges-for-stay-at-home-moms/'>challenges for stay-at-home-moms</a>, <a href='http://thebumplife.com/tag/diapering-mishaps/'>diapering mishaps</a>, <a href='http://thebumplife.com/tag/humility/'>humility</a>, <a href='http://thebumplife.com/tag/mommy-wars/'>mommy wars</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/686/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/686/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=686&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thebumplife.com/2012/09/18/humility_and_turds/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>76</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/301498dbc6e3beab860a8fd12220be70?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">staceystradleyarnold</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thebumplife.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/parentingreward.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">parentingreward</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Swifts, Conflict, Decision Making &amp; Following Dreams</title>
		<link>http://theperpetualvagabond.com/2012/09/18/the-swifts-conflict-decision-making-and-following-my-dreams/</link>
		<comments>http://theperpetualvagabond.com/2012/09/18/the-swifts-conflict-decision-making-and-following-my-dreams/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2012 21:08:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>The Perpetual Vagabond</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[conflict]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[decision making]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fear]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[following your dreams]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life lessons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Portland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[swifts]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://theperpetualvagabond.com/?p=1141</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Last night I went to watch the swifts in Portland, who every September on their fall migration roost in the chimney of Chapman School in NW Portland. Watching the swifts is one of my favorite fall activities in this city, as hundreds of people come out with their families and friends and have picnic dinners [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1141&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://theperpetualvagabond.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/swifts-2.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1143" title="Swifts  2" src="http://theperpetualvagabond.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/swifts-2.jpg" alt="" width="525" height="347" /></a></p>
<p>Last night I went to watch the swifts in Portland, who every September on their fall migration roost in the chimney of Chapman School in NW Portland. Watching the swifts is one of my favorite fall activities in this city, as hundreds of people come out with their families and friends and have picnic dinners on the steeply sloped hill, while watching thousands of birds swirl into the chimney at sunset. It’s a beautiful community event and I try to go see it at least a few times during the season.</p>
<p>But, last night turned out to be more than just a nice night of watching the beauty of nature and the strength of community. I learned something about myself that took me by surprise and has left me a bit unsure of where to go next. It came about during a conversation about past relationships, in which I said to my friend, “we broke up because we fought too much…although I have never fought with anyone else I’ve dated…” and then it hit me; I haven’t fought with ANYONE else since we broke up, not boyfriends, not friends, not bosses, not my mother, not anyone. Suddenly I was slapped in the face with the realization that for the past 4 years I have been avoiding conflict at all costs.</p>
<p>I knew that I had changed quite a bit since the summer of 2008, and I often liked my new amicable self, but I also had slowing been losing my path, unable to make decisions, developing patterns of self isolation and becoming even more flighty than before. I had many potential explanations for my behavior; my most important long-term relationship had ended, I was in graduate school, the economic recession was making opportunity sparse, and I was dealing with issues of self worth and confidence. All normal things that happen in life, but for 4 years I had been trying to address these issues so that my life could be better and I could maybe discover some idea of how to live my dreams, but nothing ever worked.</p>
<p>So over the last 4 years I have looked at everything in this quest for clarity; my jobs, my living situations, my diet, my hobbies, my friends, my spirituality, everything. I have sought out therapy, Naturopaths, energy work, new friends, new adventures, new jobs and homes, but still nothing brought me to a place that felt right. It was like I forgot who I was and I was now just trying on different lives to see if they fit. I developed an inability to make real decisions instead opting for whatever presented itself to me in the moment. But, it never occurred to me that most of this might be the result of developing a pervasive avoidance of conflict.</p>
<p>Now I think it is reasonable to avoid unnecessary conflict, but when you avoid conflict at all costs you become willing to give up just about everything in order to keep the peace. You give up your hopes, desires, and the things that are most important to you. You isolate yourself from any situation that might evoke deep emotions. And you find ways to justify people’s bad behavior so as not to have to confront it. Avoiding conflict makes you begin to think that being nice is more important than being authentic.</p>
<p>Over the years I have started to feel successful in my interpersonal life because people began to perceive me as nice and pleasant to be around. I no longer got comments that I was “opinionated” and “bitchy”. People would talk about how kind and diplomatic I was. Which are all great things to be and it felt good to be this way, but it has all been at the expense of pursing my passions and dreams. I have not found a balance; I just swung from one extreme to the other.</p>
<p><a href="http://theperpetualvagabond.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/swifts-1.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1142" title="Swifts  1" src="http://theperpetualvagabond.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/swifts-1.jpg" alt="" width="525" height="792" /></a></p>
<p>And now I can see so clearly how it all started and it had nothing to do with my ex boyfriend that I did all the fighting with (it just occurred around the same time we broke up). It was during my second year serving in AmeriCorps, where I worked as an environmental educator in the mountains of Idaho. For the first three months everything was great, I loved my coworkers, my job and the town. As a group we worked well together and had a great dynamic. We did however avoid any real conflict which left things stewing under the surface, unaddressed. Then, just after winter break everything changed; the group finally let what was simmering come out and conflict erupted into an all out battle. And as an opinionated, stubborn, process oriented person I met it head on with dire consequences. I became the group’s scapegoat for all conflict; everything was my fault, which it sometimes was, but definitely not always.</p>
<p>For months every time the group had an issue I would be placed in the central point of blame and criticized for anything I said or did. It was horrible and I didn’t know what to do to fix it. I was in a constant state of anxiety and defensiveness. It wasn’t until I came down with a fortunate (yes I said fortunate) case of food-poisoning in which I was out of commission for a whole week and the group (in my absence) continued to have conflict and therefore had to acknowledge that maybe it wasn’t always my fault. A few of my coworkers decided to stand up for me and bring the issue of how I was being treated to the group. So, after months of dealing with conflict by making me the scapegoat, we finally had to address the real issues that were plaguing our group and I was finally allowed to move on with my life without constant harassment and negativity.</p>
<p>Unfortunately by this point, I had already completely shut down and must have subconsciously vowed never to do anything that would put me in that position again. I turned inward, began to avoid groups, and quickly lost my ability to make decisions. I became paralyzed with anxiety over doing anything that might upset someone or make someone think I was being contrary. I stopped speaking up or asking for what I wanted. And unfortunately, I was never able to make the connection that my sudden change in personality and behavior came from this very difficult experience and the resulting subconscious coping strategies.</p>
<p>And I now realize that my coping strategies have consumed my life. Being unable to make decisions, I stared to create predictable patterns that make my decisions for me. I go to the same restaurants, order the same foods, do the same things with the same people on a regular basis, wear the same clothes and generally leave the rest up to chance. I have learned to always be ok with whatever anyone else chooses, I no longer am a picky eater, I reserve my opinions for groups of people I know agree with me (and I can always see the opposition’s side and understand why they feel the way they do), I avoid people who I know have strong beliefs and tend to get worked up over them, and I spend more and more time alone.</p>
<p>I even recently decided that I wanted to live alone (even though I have a great, affordable house, with great roommates) because I feel like I’m always having to compromise, never acknowledging though that I never ask for what I want, never being willing to address my concerns or feelings with the people I live with. I would rather move out than discuss something that might not be pleasant. I’d rather run away than make things work.</p>
<p><a href="http://theperpetualvagabond.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/swifts-3.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1144" title="Swifts  3" src="http://theperpetualvagabond.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/swifts-3.jpg" alt="" width="525" height="349" /></a></p>
<p>So, that brings me to today. This whole realization just came crashing down in a torrent of insight and clarity, but now I don’t know what to do with it. Seeking out conflict doesn’t seem like the answer, but I clearly need to face my fear and maybe learn about strategies for effective conflict resolution instead of conflict avoidance. I know I don’t want to go through the rest of my life not authentically living with purpose because I am too afraid of being criticized or attacked for my choices. I want to have the courage to follow my dreams even if it may involve some unpleasantness. And I want to find a balance between being kind and diplomatic and being strong and living with conviction.</p>
<p>It’s gotten to the point where I don’t even know what I want anymore because it has just been easier to go with the flow and let things happen, than to risk being confronted for my choices. The problem is that this is incredibly uninspiring and leaves me feeling lost and confused most of the time as well as dependent on the spontaneity of others to keep my life interesting and fulfilled. And it makes my relationships unbalanced and inauthentic and leaves me feeling isolated from those I care about.</p>
<p>So, I guess my lesson is that sometimes going and watching the swifts is just a nice way to pass the time, but sometimes watching animals live out their purpose in life makes us question our own and helps us better understand our true nature. Fear is an amazingly powerful thing that can bury us under its weight if we don’t keep it in check. If the swifts were afraid of coming home to roost because of the peregrine falcons that prey on them each season, then the whole ecosystem would collapse. The swifts don’t avoid their journey because of the battle that awaits them at that chimney, they show up every year without fail and remind us that the journey is hard, but we have to go on it anyway.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1141/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1141/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1141&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://theperpetualvagabond.com/2012/09/18/the-swifts-conflict-decision-making-and-following-my-dreams/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>29</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/9aceb8eb433c56c4fba2eea0fc25b8c4?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">theperpetualvagabond</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theperpetualvagabond.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/swifts-2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Swifts  2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theperpetualvagabond.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/swifts-1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Swifts  1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theperpetualvagabond.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/swifts-3.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Swifts  3</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Poetry: Drafts of &#8216;Split My Thumb&#8217;</title>
		<link>http://monkeymoonmachine.com/2012/09/16/poetry-drafts-of-split-my-thumb/</link>
		<comments>http://monkeymoonmachine.com/2012/09/16/poetry-drafts-of-split-my-thumb/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2012 21:34:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>MonkeyMoonMachine</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Nonfiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Poems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[teaching writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[word play]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing process]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://monkeymoonmachine.com/?p=161</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Last week, in the creative writing classes I teach, we read Richard Hugo&#8217;s essay &#8220;Writing off the Subject,&#8221; and then I asked my students to write a poem in the way Hugo describes: starting from a particular idea, following the lead of one&#8217;s inner voice to end up at a new idea, a new place, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=161&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://monkeymoonmachine.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_6248.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-173" title="IMG_6248" src="http://monkeymoonmachine.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_6248.jpg?w=300&h=225" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a>Last week, in the creative writing classes I teach, we read Richard Hugo&#8217;s essay &#8220;<a href="http://ualr.edu/rmburns/RB/hugosubj.html" target="_blank">Writing off the Subject</a>,&#8221; and then I asked my students to write a poem in the way Hugo describes: starting from a particular idea, following the lead of one&#8217;s inner voice to end up at a new idea, a new place, something one hadn&#8217;t planned to say (Hugo implies a method like that in his discussion of &#8220;Autumn Leaves&#8221;). I followed the same instructions, and below are two free-writing drafts before the final (for now) draft.</p>
<p>But here&#8217;s the difficulty, of course: the real writing process is in my mind, and what&#8217;s in the drafts below is only the residue. Since my mind during freewrites tends to work associatively, I can&#8217;t explain why one thing led to another. And I can&#8217;t describe why I ended up with the poem I did, except to say that it felt right, it felt interesting. It might not even interest me later.</p>
<p>A student brought up a good question: when does an artist ever know when a poem is ready for publishing on a blog?  I don&#8217;t really know, I said, thinking out loud that the costs are low, which encourages publishing, but is the poem worth sharing? That answer requires thinking about what readers might appreciate, but also about being willing to send writing out that isn&#8217;t perfect. I guess my answer for these things below is  that the creative writing process is mysterious enough, and fascinating enough, that I want to discuss it, and these are at least a model, if a poor one.</p>
<p><strong>Freewrite 1</strong></p>
<p>(The two freewrites were hand-written, but the final poem was composed via word-processor. This freewrite started from the prompt word &#8220;surge,&#8221; given by a random word-lookup technique &#8212; picking shards of words out of newsprint that had been through a shredder &#8212; and an image/memory of a finger being jammed while playing basketball came to mind.)</p>
<p><em>Surge into the top joint, the basketball did, and rough skin slid back into my hand and pores spread open, air met body, lines decline to limit the me from the sky &#8212; the nearby sky the air-ocean we are pressed down by – impressed – tender is the light that strikes us – surge, the burst surges out from me and yet I stay the hand, the skin the sh!t box – swipe the keen face of the tandem bike rhizomes – strawberry marmalade takes tokens from toad </em></p>
<p><strong>Freewrite 2:</strong></p>
<p>(I took &#8220;rough skin&#8221; and &#8220;tandem bike rhizomes&#8221; from the previous freewrite, and then tried to let go, encourage words to come to mind without being too particular about which words got written down. It&#8217;s a process skill that has taken me a while to get good at doing.)</p>
<p><em>Rough skin slid back into my hand and pores spread open.  The world – the air confronts an enemy, the closed sealed entombed world of the blood – the inner sanctum where air is blocked – and tandem bike rhizomes – and air is the enemy, air is the enema, and toads kill the healing vice – the red rice bucks company plans – the rough skin slid again (over?) my hand – pores opened, veins poured open, the blood leaks like a radiator, like a brake line, and I push and no resistance – the blood leaks out – it’s under pressure inside, like a break line, like a family – the air is the enemy but the body pushes out the blood – the air-skin boundary – where I stop – leaks into air – where a r becom – I likes into a r to become “air” – where I becomes it</em></p>
<p><strong>Final &#8212; for now &#8212; draft:</strong></p>
<p>I liked the image of the air-ocean and the body-air boundary, but wanted to be more concrete, less philosophical here, and so I went with a description of an event that really had happened to me days earlier, which event-image had been in my mind as I had written earlier about the body-boundary. This poem is  blunt, which was an intentional &#8212; at this point in the process &#8211; choice of voice/mood, and so I was restricting my word choices to one-syllable ones where possible. When I am less self-restrictive, more automatically voiced, in my freewriting, longer words tend to come out (see my recent poem, written the same week, using a similar process, called &#8220;<a href="http://monkeymoonmachine.com/2012/09/16/poem-the-whistle-of-heat/" target="_blank">The Whistle of Heat</a>&#8220;).  I made a choice to use spare language here, to show as rawly, bluntly, physically as possible, the action &#8212; with my impulse to make interpretive associations held in check.</p>
<p><em>The stainless-steel paring knife </em><br />
<em>splits my thumb where it </em><br />
<em>backstopped </em><br />
<em>a tough tomato skin. </em><br />
<em>Blood comes to the air. </em><br />
<em>A paper towel </em><br />
<em>records</em><br />
<em>the blood drop </em><br />
<em>as a red dot. </em></p>
<p>This was where the poem stopped as the class period ended, but I was feeling like there could have been more added to it. I&#8217;m not sure more was needed, I&#8217;m not sure what the more would be, but I remind myself that poems don&#8217;t need to be long &#8212; I&#8217;m just not sure I&#8217;m entirely satisfied with this poem being short.</p>
<p>But I do like the simplicity of the images: skin being split by a knife, blood &#8220;comes&#8221; (&#8220;oozes&#8221; or &#8220;spurts&#8221; didn&#8217;t seem right, nor did the idea from earlier of blood under pressure seem interesting in the end) to air, and the implication of the verb &#8220;record&#8221; &#8212; that the body may not keep the record of the blood, blood being temporarily and not permanently liquid, but that the paper might &#8212; our bodies write themselves into their surroundings, the 3-D drop of blood becoming a 2-D stain, etc.  As I talk <span style="text-decoration:underline;">about</span> the poem, I could associate further, but this poem&#8217;s strength, such as it is, comes from being minimal.</p>
<p>Of course, this demonstration can&#8217;t really be a tutorial of how to write a poem &#8212; a new poem, at its most creative, has no model, and <a href="http://artsbeat.blogs.nytimes.com/2007/10/19/stray-questions-for-kay-ryan/" target="_blank">so is a new island</a>, so this  demonstration cannot be imitated the way other modeled skills can be. And writing about a process like this feels like that quote about how writing about music is like tap dancing about sculpture (or <a href="http://quoteinvestigator.com/2010/11/08/writing-about-music/" target="_blank">various other activities</a>).  A new poet must figure out her own process.  But as a teacher, I&#8217;d hope to give at least an idea of a path &#8212; those suggestions seemed to help me, I recall.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/161/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/161/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=161&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://monkeymoonmachine.com/2012/09/16/poetry-drafts-of-split-my-thumb/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>28</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f9815331c6e870a8b372510b74ac85f1?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">inschoolsuspension</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://monkeymoonmachine.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_6248.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_6248</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What Makes a Post Freshly Press-able: A Space For Learning</title>
		<link>http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2012/09/19/what-makes-a-post-freshly-press-able-a-space-for-learning/</link>
		<comments>http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2012/09/19/what-makes-a-post-freshly-press-able-a-space-for-learning/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2012 14:01:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Cheri Lucas</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Freshly Pressed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tactics/Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[better blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing tips]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dailypost.wordpress.com/?p=10193</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Every day, 19 WordPressers are featured on the Freshly Pressed section of WordPress.com. And every day, many more wonder, “What do I have to do to get Freshly Pressed?” Well, it’s time to reveal what the folks who push the launch button are thinking. Each week, a member of our editorial team will do a [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=10193&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Every day, 19 WordPressers are featured on the Freshly Pressed section of WordPress.com. And every day, many more wonder, “What do I have to do to get Freshly Pressed?”</em></p>
<p><em>Well, it’s time to reveal what the folks who push the launch button are thinking. Each week, a member of our editorial team will do a close-up on one post and why we thought it was Press-worthy. We hope we can provide insight into the process and give you tips and tools to make your blog the best it can be.</em></p>
<p>_________________________________________________________</p>
<p>Pamela Moran&#8217;s recent post, <a href="http://spacesforlearning.wordpress.com/2012/09/13/abandoning-the-space-shuttle-a-lesson-for-educators/">Abandoning the Space Shuttle&#8230;a Lesson for Educators</a>, resonated with me, and I&#8217;ve thought about it numerous times since I promoted it to Freshly Pressed last week. I&#8217;m enthusiastic about Pamela&#8217;s post not just because it&#8217;s original, but because it&#8217;s at once timely and reflective. She tackles something topical—NASA&#8217;s space exploration—but also uses personal experience to frame and shape the post. Through this lens, she weaves a unique and much larger discussion about the state of 21st-century education.</p>
<p>Here are three ways she does this:</p>
<p><span id="more-10193"></span></p>
<h2>She uses a metaphor to connect disparate topics in a natural way.</h2>
<p><a href="http://spacesforlearning.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/earths-orbit-the-silhouet-002.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-10204" title="A Space For Learning" src="http://dailypost.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/a-space-for-learning-2.jpeg?w=300&h=225" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a>In the introduction, Pamela grounds us by recounting a recent talk by retired space shuttle astronaut Kathy Thornton. Kathy said NASA abandoned the shuttle program—a tough decision—to dream up a new, bold human narrative of space exploration for the 21st century that moves beyond orbiting Earth. &#8220;Otherwise,&#8221; writes Pamela, &#8220;the current program doomed NASA’s astronauts to circling the globe in low space orbit, over and over and over again.&#8221;</p>
<p>After describing this evening with Kathy, Pamela states:</p>
<blockquote><p> I thought that night—just like kids doomed to sitting in rows, facing the same direction, doing 20th century test prep worksheets over and over and over again. When she finished speaking, I couldn’t help but think that <em>we educators </em><em>are caught in low orbit work, too.</em></p></blockquote>
<p>I felt that Pamela&#8217;s connection between the abandonment of the space shuttle program and the stunted state of education is natural and fitting, evoking visuals of shuttles in low orbit and apathetic students at desks. You don&#8217;t have to be a space enthusiast or educator to understand this metaphor. Through it, she weaves a fresh, intriguing discussion about two separate topics: space exploration and education.</p>
<p>If you want to experiment with metaphors in your own posts, consider different subjects that interest you. Can you find connections? Crafting a metaphor can be tricky, and you need to be sure the comparison you are drawing is not contrived. Furthermore, using a metaphor may not be appropriate for every post. Read your writing aloud to be sure it makes sense and doesn&#8217;t sound forced.</p>
<h2>The language is appropriate and accessible.</h2>
<p>A commenter on last week&#8217;s &#8220;What Makes a Post Freshly Press-able?&#8221; post talked about the <em>authority </em>of a blogger. Must a writer be an <em>expert</em> to write about a topic? Fellow bloggers commented that we don&#8217;t have to be seasoned journalists or established sources to share our thoughts; the blogosphere has room for many modes of writing.</p>
<p>That said, Pamela establishes credibility in both space exploration and education through her word choice. In the first paragraph, she writes:</p>
<blockquote><p>[Kathy's] earned that right, having been key to several major payload deployments into space including the first service work on the Hubble telescope. She’s a real-deal spacewalker.</p></blockquote>
<p><a href="http://spacesforlearning.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/curiosity.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-10208" title="Curiosity" src="http://dailypost.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/curiosity-2.jpeg?w=500" alt=""   /></a>Above, Pamela establishes her authority with insider speak such as &#8220;payload deployments.&#8221; But in the next sentence, she balances the jargon with more accessible language: &#8220;she&#8217;s a real-deal spacewalker.&#8221; She&#8217;s authoritative, but doesn&#8217;t distance herself from us.</p>
<p>She also strengthens her metaphor with precise (and evocative) word choice. She uses phrases like &#8220;shuttling test prep cargo&#8221; and plays with language:</p>
<blockquote><p>If NASA is doing it, shouldn’t we also “go boldly where no educators have gone before?”</p></blockquote>
<p>Reworking a well-known phrase, like this one from <em>Star Trek, </em>may help readers to identify with your topic and engage in your discussion.</p>
<p>In your own writing, pay attention to the words you use. Are you using the best adjective? Is there a more appropriate noun that matches your tone or the mood you want to create? Don&#8217;t worry too much about word choice when writing your first draft. Structure your post, do a round or two of editing, and <em>then</em> zoom in on revising specific phrases and words.</p>
<h2>Links support stats and information.</h2>
<p>Lastly, Pamela supports her post with links to external sources, but doesn&#8217;t overwhelm readers with <em>too many </em>links—it is possible to link too much! Many posts on WordPress.com—such as information-heavy pieces on science, politics, and history—include percentages, statistics, and monetary figures. Your discussions are stronger and more reliable when you cite and link to credible sources.</p>
<p>For more posts from Pamela, visit <a href="http://spacesforlearning.wordpress.com/">A Space for Learning</a>.</p>
<p>So, tell us: Do you think this is an appropriate selection for Freshly Pressed?</p>
<p><em>For more on our Freshly Pressed content, check out <a href="http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2012/09/12/what-makes-a-post-freshly-press-able-the-rise-of-ebooks-evil-or-essential/">last week’s Freshly Press-able post</a>, read our roundup of <a href="http://en.blog.wordpress.com/2012/09/04/freshly-pressed-editors-picks-for-august-2012/">Editors’ Picks for August</a>, or read <a href="http://en.support.wordpress.com/freshly-pressed/">So You Want to Be Freshly Pressed</a>.</em></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/10193/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/10193/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=10193&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2012/09/19/what-makes-a-post-freshly-press-able-a-space-for-learning/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>52</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/36207d4c7c014b0999b995ca3971d383?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">CL</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dailypost.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/a-space-for-learning-2.jpeg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">A Space For Learning</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dailypost.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/curiosity-2.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Curiosity</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>WordPress Powers Politics</title>
		<link>http://vip.wordpress.com/2012/09/13/wordpress-powers-politics/</link>
		<comments>http://vip.wordpress.com/2012/09/13/wordpress-powers-politics/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2012 19:52:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Peter Slutsky</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Case Studies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2012]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[campaign]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[candidate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[congress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[democrats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[election]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[republican]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vip.wordpress.com/?p=6656</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[WordPress is the most powerful content management system in the world &#8211; today it powers just under 17% of the top one million websites in the world. Millions of people from across the globe turn to WordPress to build websites of all shapes and sizes and across all different categories. Now that the political conventions [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=6656&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:left;"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-6661" title="infographic-header" src="http://vip.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/infographic-header.png?w=640&h=122" alt="" width="640" height="122" /></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">WordPress is the most powerful content management system in the world &#8211; today it powers just under 17% of the top one million websites in the world. Millions of people from across the globe turn to WordPress to build websites of all shapes and sizes and across all different categories.</p>
<p>Now that the political conventions are over and we have officially turned the corner towards the November election, WordPress.com VIP is proud to release this infographic which clearly shows that WordPress is now the backbone that powers websites from across the political spectrum.</p>
<p>Check it out!</p>
<p><a href="http://vip.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/wordpress-com-vip-politics-infographic-final-1.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-6663" title="WordPress Powers Politics - Infographic" src="http://vip.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/wordpress-com-vip-politics-infographic-final-1.png" alt="" width="759" height="1896" /></a></p>
<p>This research project started when we began to notice that more and more political websites were being built on WordPress. We focused on a couple of key categories: state parties, U.S. House races, U.S. Senate races, and Gubernatorial races. We looked at all of the major-party candidates across these categories and manually checked to see what content management system was being used. We were excited by the results and thus, they became the impetus for this lovely infographic.</p>
<p>If you want to learn more about WordPress for your political website, or any other purpose, get in touch with the WordPress.com VIP team <a href="http://vip.wordpress.com/contact/">here</a>.</p>
<h3>Spread the Word</h3>
<p>Copy the embed code below to share the infographic on your own site:</p>
<p><pre class="brush: xml; auto-links: false; gutter: false;">
&lt;a href=&quot;http://vip.wordpress.com/2012/09/13/wordpress-powers-politics/&quot;&gt;&lt;img title=&quot;WordPress Powers Politics -- compiled by WordPress.com VIP: Enterprise Hosting and Services for WordPress&quot; src=&quot;http://vip.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/wordpress-com-vip-politics-infographic-final-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;WordPress Powers Politics - Infographic&quot; width=&quot;759&quot; height=&quot;1896&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
</pre></p>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=6656&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://vip.wordpress.com/2012/09/13/wordpress-powers-politics/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a496fa3fc8dd609938802f54b9e96563?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">peterslutsky</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://vip.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/infographic-header.png?w=640" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">infographic-header</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://vip.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/wordpress-com-vip-politics-infographic-final-1.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">WordPress Powers Politics - Infographic</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The New Bizarre Online Security Questions</title>
		<link>http://kristenbrakeman.com/2012/09/17/the-new-bizarre-online-security-questions/</link>
		<comments>http://kristenbrakeman.com/2012/09/17/the-new-bizarre-online-security-questions/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2012 19:57:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>krisbrake</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[comedy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[websites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[passwords]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[website]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://kristenbrakeman.com/?p=337</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Blatant rip off of Jerry Seinfeld here, but what is the deal with those online security questions lately? They used to be so easy, so straightforward, like what’s your mother’s maiden name, high school mascot, or favorite pie? But now these questions have gotten strange.   Either the website designers are trying hard to foil the [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=337&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://kristenbrakeman.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_72261.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-341" title="IMG_7226" src="http://kristenbrakeman.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_72261.jpg?w=300&h=213" alt="" width="300" height="213" /></a></p>
<p>Blatant rip off of Jerry Seinfeld here, but what is the deal with those online security questions lately?</p>
<p>They used to be so easy, so straightforward, like what’s your mother’s maiden name, high school mascot, or favorite pie?</p>
<p>But now these questions have gotten strange.   Either the website designers are trying hard to foil the hackers or, as I suspect, they’re just really, really bored.  What else could account for these bizarre questions?<br />
ACTUAL SECURITY QUESTIONS:</p>
<p><strong>What was your favorite game to play as a child?</strong>  Good Lord, who on earth would remember such a thing?  And do they mean board game like Dream Date, or kickball or hide and seek?  I need some clarity here.</p>
<p><strong>What was your dream job as a child?</strong>  You mean when I was a five and wanted to be a princess – does that count as an actual job?</p>
<p><strong>What was your favorite place to visit as a child?</strong>  Okay really people, let’s think about this for a second &#8211; if I can’t remember my password, one I likely created only a month ago, why do you think I can remember what games I liked to play, or what I thought, or what I felt back when I was a child, so many eons ago?</p>
<p><strong>What was the name of your first pet?</strong>  Sandy.  Uh, oops, darn.  Now you all know.</p>
<p><strong>Where is your great grandmother buried? </strong> My great-grandmother.  Seriously?  Well, I never met her and don’t even know her first name so I’m gonna guess I don’t know where she’s buried either.  But I’ll take a stab at it &#8211; in a grave?</p>
<p><strong>What is your favorite food?</strong>  Easy:  shrimp and pasta.  Oh and hamburgers.  And that ahi tuna sandwich with avocado at that place on Third.  I like Sushi too.  Also steak and baked potato with sour cream.  And garlic bread with spaghetti.  God I’m so hungry now.</p>
<p><strong>What was your hair color as a child?</strong>  I don’t like what you’re implying there mister.</p>
<p><strong>Where were you when you heard about 9/11?</strong>  Huh?  Holy crap.  Here I was having a perfectly good day and now I’m thinking about that horrible morning and, jeez, people, come on.</p>
<p><strong>What is the coolest place you’ve ever visited?</strong>  Gosh, that seems really subjective.  Is there some hip meter I’m supposed to use to decide?  I’ll have you know I’ve been to lots of hip places because I’m pretty cool and . . . wait, oops I didn’t have my reading glasses on.  Apparently it’s “What’s the coldest place . . . ?”  Still, no idea.</p>
<p><strong>Who spoke at your high school graduation?</strong>   The valedictorian.  Hmm, what was her name again . . . brown hair . . . over-achiever . . . went to Berkeley and uh . . . ”</p>
<p><strong>What is the license plate (registration) of your dad&#8217;s first car? </strong> Let’s see, since my dad bought his first car about a decade before I was born I’m not sure I remember that.  Why stop there?  What was the thesis of my dad’s sophomore year history term paper?  What was he thinking back on July 18th, 1952?  How many hairs did he have on his head?</p>
<p><strong>What is the first name of the boy or girl that you first kissed? </strong> Why, that would be my husband of course.  Ahem.  That’s the story I’m sticking with.</p>
<p><strong>What is your dream vacation? </strong> Oh this is easy – Fiji.  Wait no, that takes too long to get to.  I know, Grand Cayman.  Yes I&#8217;ve always wanted to go there!  Oh, but I’ve also heard that the Bahamas are quite nice, and then there are a lot of wintery places I want to see.  The Alps, Banff, The Himalayas &#8211; how will I ever narrow this down?<br />
<strong> </strong><br />
<strong>What is the name of a college you applied to but didn&#8217;t attend? </strong> Gee, thanks for bringing up that old wound.</p>
<p><strong>What sports team do you love to see lose? </strong> That’s a very negative question.  These programmers must be a ton of fun to be around.  Frankly I don’t care who wins or loses as long as they’re serving cold beer.</p>
<p><strong>What is the name of your least favorite relative?</strong>  Whaaat?  I can’t believe that people have a least favorite relative and even if they did, wouldn’t they feel guilty actually typing their name?  Because what if you die and that is the one relative who is able to crack your password codes to access your accounts and then they see their name listed there as your least favorite relative?   That’s too much of a risk for me, and my backstabbing cousin Jennifer.</p>
<p>I’m mentally exhausted from answering all their questions.  I think this website knows more about me now than my therapist ever did.  I could use a cold beer . . . on Fiji . . . and that Ahi Sandwich from that place on Third.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/337/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/337/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=337&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://kristenbrakeman.com/2012/09/17/the-new-bizarre-online-security-questions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>97</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/ec3dec4ecebba632499276baec169dd7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">krisbrake</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://kristenbrakeman.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_72261.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_7226</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>