<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2011 14:56:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Volcano Sandboarding</title>
		<link>http://raxacollective.wordpress.com/2011/08/15/volcano-sandboarding/</link>
		<comments>http://raxacollective.wordpress.com/2011/08/15/volcano-sandboarding/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2011 00:57:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Seth Inman</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Eco-Tourism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cerro Negro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sandboarding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[volcanoes]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://raxacollective.wordpress.com/?p=1917</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Note: Many great images from Cerro Negro, including video, will be added with a future update. Volcán Cerro Negro, the youngest volcano in Central America, last erupted in 1999. Less than twenty miles from León, a city that I will be posting about soon, the volcano&#8217;s main attraction isn&#8217;t the crater itself, although the powerful [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=1917&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Note: Many great images from Cerro Negro, including video, will be added with a future update.</strong></p>
<p>Volcán Cerro Negro, the youngest volcano in Central America, last erupted in 1999. Less than twenty miles from León, a city that I will be posting about soon, the volcano&#8217;s main attraction isn&#8217;t the crater itself, although the powerful opening to the center of the Earth&#8211;which in the past three decades has spewed columns of ash and gas up to 24,000 feet high&#8211;is not unimpressive. Instead, most people climb Cerro Negro just to descend it. Why? Because its steep slopes, almost 2,400 feet high, consist of black volcanic stones, which are <a href="http://i1136.photobucket.com/albums/n498/raxacollective/SANY0016-3.jpg" target="_blank">finer</a> than normal gravel and heavily mixed with ash and dust. How do visitors get from top to bottom? Many locals do it by foot, running down in great leaps. Most tourists rent a wooden board with a metal underside: either a snowboard or sled design depending on their experience and daring.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://i1136.photobucket.com/albums/n498/raxacollective/SANY0001.jpg" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter" title="Cerro Negro" src="http://i1136.photobucket.com/albums/n498/raxacollective/SANY0001.jpg" alt="" width="491" height="369" /></a></p>
<p>The volcano and its surroundings, together known as the <a href="http://www.marena.gob.ni/index.php?option=com_content&amp;task=view&amp;id=211&amp;Itemid=542" target="_blank">Reserva Natural Complejo Volcánico Pilas El Hoyo</a>, amount to a protected area of 2,140 hectares that includes at least five different types of ecosystem. Entrance fees, as well as the rental of sleds and protective gear, somewhat help incentivize the conservation of the volcanic complex by surrounding communities, mostly farmers (cattle, peanuts, eucalyptus, corn, etc.).</p>
<p>Having only snowboarded once before, I opted for the sled, and Pierre did the same. We <a href="http://i1136.photobucket.com/albums/n498/raxacollective/SANY0004-3.jpg" target="_blank">hiked</a> up the volcano on the larger rocks (fist-sized to full boulders) for maybe fifty minutes, pausing to take photos of the beautiful hills that starkly contrasted with <span id="more-1917"></span>the black volcanic rocks. As we reached the <a href="http://i1136.photobucket.com/albums/n498/raxacollective/SANY0008-1.jpg" target="_blank">top</a>, the mix of natural colors grew even more amazing: red, white, black, and even <a href="http://i1136.photobucket.com/albums/n498/raxacollective/SANY0030-2.jpg" target="_blank">yellow</a> on the volcano alone, the variety of greens from the hills, the blue sky, and white clouds.</p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 501px"><a href="http://i1136.photobucket.com/albums/n498/raxacollective/SANY0023-3.jpg" target="_blank"><img title="volcano and hill slopes" src="http://i1136.photobucket.com/albums/n498/raxacollective/SANY0023-3.jpg" alt="" width="491" height="369" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">A palette of natural colors</p></div>
<p style="text-align:left;">Reaching the point of descent, we found a <a href="http://i1136.photobucket.com/albums/n498/raxacollective/SANY0020-1.jpg" target="_blank">group</a> of international <a href="http://i1136.photobucket.com/albums/n498/raxacollective/SANY0021-2.jpg" target="_blank">tourists</a> learning about the somewhat apocryphal development of volcano-boarding on Cerro Negro. Apparently an Australian who offered guided tours of the volcano got tired of walking back down the volcano after a tour, so one day he brought his surfboard to the top and tried sliding down on it. Needless to say, the surfboard was quickly destroyed. Next came a mattress, but it was too soft. Better luck was had with a wooden door, and from there the size of the wooden board decreased and materials were added to the bottom: metal on the whole surface, and a patch of very smooth vinyl-like plastic where the most pressure would be applied (in the case of the sleds, it is under the area one sits on).</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Leaving the group to themselves, we wandered <a href="http://i1136.photobucket.com/albums/n498/raxacollective/SANY0032-2.jpg" target="_blank">around</a> the summit and looked <a href="http://i1136.photobucket.com/albums/n498/raxacollective/SANY0033-1.jpg" target="_blank">down</a> into the <a href="http://i1136.photobucket.com/albums/n498/raxacollective/SANY0028-3.jpg" target="_blank">crater</a>, which had several &#8220;fumaroles&#8221; releasing sulphuric fumes, which may have been the gasses responsible for attracting <a href="http://i1136.photobucket.com/albums/n498/raxacollective/SANY0036.jpg" target="_blank">insects</a> to the top of the volcano. Those little bugs, as well as butterflies, grasshoppers, beetles, and these <a href="http://i1136.photobucket.com/albums/n498/raxacollective/SANY0035.jpg" target="_blank">bees</a>, were easily seen on the dark gravel and provoked much curiosity on my part, especially since most of these insects were found dead, apart from the butterflies and bees.</p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 501px"><a href="http://i1136.photobucket.com/albums/n498/raxacollective/SANY0017-2.jpg" target="_blank"><img title="view from above" src="http://i1136.photobucket.com/albums/n498/raxacollective/SANY0017-2.jpg" alt="" width="491" height="369" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Trees can&#039;t grow within a certain radius from the volcano due to Cerro Negro&#039;s youthful eruptions</p></div>
<p style="text-align:left;">We started putting on our elbow and knee pads and got behind the orange-jumpsuited tour group, who also sported strong-looking goggles. Pierre and I, each in shorts and a shirt, wearing sunglasses and the aforementioned protection, looked like we either knew exactly what we were doing or had no idea what we had gotten into. To make matters more amusing, a group came behind us wearing neon green jumpsuits and even more intense goggles, so that Pierre and I were sandwiched between two seemingly better prepared groups than our own.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Finally, we couldn&#8217;t put off sledding down the volcano any longer. We sat down a couple meters apart from each other (going two at a time is the recommended maximum in case of accidents) and got ready to reach speeds between thirty and fifty miles per hour, depending on how liberally we applied the brakes (how much we dug our feet into the gravel). We counted down from three and pushed ourselves downhill. Pierre sped ahead pretty quickly, leaning back and pulling on the rope tied to the front of the sled so that he would go faster. I, on the other hand, worried more about wiping out and taking gravel to tender areas of my body, so I leaned back, pulled very slightly on the rope (which I may have had in a death grip), and kept my feet lightly pressed into the gravel. Even with these precautions I was going enjoyably fast, and felt no danger of losing control, so I let up a bit on the brakes.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://i1136.photobucket.com/albums/n498/raxacollective/SANY0039-1.jpg" target="_blank"><img class="aligncenter" title="dusty slope" src="http://i1136.photobucket.com/albums/n498/raxacollective/SANY0039-1.jpg" alt="" width="491" height="369" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">However, as the slope <a href="http://i1136.photobucket.com/albums/n498/raxacollective/SANY0037-1.jpg" target="_blank">descends</a> it gets steeper, so I was soon going so fast that even when I dug my shoes completely into the gravel I didn&#8217;t seem to reduce my speed at all. The reason I was trying to brake so hard was that the slope doesn&#8217;t gradually get less steep as it meets ground level, so I feared a sudden crash into the base of the volcano when I reached the bottom. Gravel completely covered my sled in a huge pile, and it was accumulating in my shorts and shoes. Dust gathered around my head and mouth as I squinted past the shower of small black rocks flying into my sunglasses. But even with burning feet, blackening limbs, increasingly bumpy underwear, and grit in my nostrils, I was smiling. How often can you sled down an active volcano?</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1917/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1917/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1917/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1917/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1917/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1917/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1917/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1917/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1917/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1917/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1917/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1917/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1917/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1917/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=1917&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" /><div class="sharedaddy sd-like-enabled"></div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://raxacollective.wordpress.com/2011/08/15/volcano-sandboarding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/43c8be95aac01dde976ed7f35f46d0a6?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">setheinman</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://i1136.photobucket.com/albums/n498/raxacollective/SANY0001.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Cerro Negro</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://i1136.photobucket.com/albums/n498/raxacollective/SANY0023-3.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">volcano and hill slopes</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://i1136.photobucket.com/albums/n498/raxacollective/SANY0017-2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">view from above</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://i1136.photobucket.com/albums/n498/raxacollective/SANY0039-1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">dusty slope</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>I&#8217;m failing (and why that isn&#8217;t so bad)</title>
		<link>http://pindsha21.wordpress.com/2011/08/14/im-failing-and-why-that-isnt-so-bad/</link>
		<comments>http://pindsha21.wordpress.com/2011/08/14/im-failing-and-why-that-isnt-so-bad/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2011 23:53:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>pindsha21</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Graphic Design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Interest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Architecture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[postaweek2011]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[failure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[success]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[goals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[career]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[j. k. rowling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commencement speech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life change]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[career switch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[9 reasons why failure is not fatal]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://pindsha21.wordpress.com/?p=857</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[When I graduated from college in 2009, I had a dream. I was going to live in Chicago, get a job at an Architectural firm, and work toward my license. Then after 3 years (license acquired), I was going to move to Italy, Rome perhaps. Probably rent a nice little villa or apartment. Here&#8217;s what [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=857&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="size-medium wp-image-862 alignright" title="Big Fat Failure" src="http://pindsha21.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/a-big-fat-failure.gif?w=270&#038;h=238" alt="" width="270" height="238" />When I graduated from college in 2009, I had a dream. I was going to live in Chicago, get a job at an Architectural firm, and work toward my license. Then after 3 years (license acquired), I was going to move to Italy, Rome perhaps. Probably rent a nice little villa or apartment. Here&#8217;s what actually happened: the economy tanked, I couldn&#8217;t find an architectural position, and I moved to Florida. In terms of achieving &#8220;my dream&#8221; I failed, BIG TIME!  I received this article in my inbox titled <strong><a title="9 Reasons Why Failure Is Not Fatal" href="http://the99percent.com/articles/7057/9-Reasons-Why-Failure-Is-Not-Fatal" target="_blank">9 Reasons Why Failure is Not Fatal</a></strong> and the 9th example was a commencement speech given J.K Rowling (author of the Harry Potter series). Here&#8217;s an excerpt:</p>
<p>&#8220;&#8230;failure meant a stripping away of the inessential. I stopped pretending to myself that I was anything other than what I was and began to direct all my energy into finishing the only work that mattered to me. Had I really succeeded at anything else I might never have found the determination to succeed in the one arena where I believed I truly belonged. I was set free&#8230;&#8221;</p>
<p>Had I successfully made it to Rome with an architectural license in tow, here&#8217;s what I might never have done, at least not in the near future. I might not have made the decision to switch to graphic design. It just wouldn&#8217;t seem practical, after all that work towards becoming an architect. Granted, some people still think I&#8217;m crazy, I did complete 5 years in my college&#8217;s architectural program,  but this switch isn&#8217;t so strange. I&#8217;ve ALWAYS loved art. It was the class I lived for in high school. I excelled in my other classes because: 1. I don&#8217;t like to fail (oh the irony) 2. Great grades = great college + scholarships 3. If you don&#8217;t like the class,  why blow it off only to have to repeat it;  the list goes on&#8230;</p>
<p>So why become an architect, since I love art so much? Don&#8217;t get me wrong, I do love architecture as well and again it seemed practical. The impression I was given growing up was that to be an artist, you had to be struggling or starving (very cliché). Little did I know of graphic design. I do know though that if I had continued with architecture that I would have tried to put myself in the positions where I could work on the graphics (building renderings/illustrations) and interactive installations.</p>
<p>If I had a chance to do it all over again, would I do it differently? Probably not. I&#8217;m not saying life&#8217;s been a bed of roses since I made the switch. There&#8217;s a lot I need to teach myself and I&#8217;m still looking for more stable employment (anyone know of a paid graphic design internship please let me know or if you need some work done, <strong><a href="mailto:pinder.shav@gmail.com"> let&#8217;s talk </a></strong>). However, success extends beyond what you do. The relationships I&#8217;ve made at college are priceless. Some friends are more like family and my future children already have weekends booked at their future homes. I wouldn&#8217;t have met them if I had gone somewhere else and that would&#8217;ve been tragic. Also the people I&#8217;ve meet since moving to Florida have made a huge impact on my life and I&#8217;ve grown so much closer to my actual family here. You just can&#8217;t make the same connection in Italy through Skype.</p>
<p>So this is failure. I&#8217;m dealing with it, learning from it, and hopefully becoming a better person because of it.</p>
<p><strong>Please check out <a title="9 Reasons Why Failure Is Not Fatal" href="http://the99percent.com/articles/7057/9-Reasons-Why-Failure-Is-Not-Fatal" target="_blank">9 Reasons Why Failure is Not Fatal</a> and here is J.K Rowling&#8217;s full speech.</strong></p>
<div class='embed-vimeo' style='text-align:center;'><iframe src='http://player.vimeo.com/video/1711302' width='400' height='300' frameborder='0'></iframe></div>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://pindsha21.wordpress.com/category/architecture/'>Architecture</a>, <a href='http://pindsha21.wordpress.com/category/general-interest/'>General Interest</a>, <a href='http://pindsha21.wordpress.com/category/graphic-design/'>Graphic Design</a> Tagged: <a href='http://pindsha21.wordpress.com/tag/9-reasons-why-failure-is-not-fatal/'>9 reasons why failure is not fatal</a>, <a href='http://pindsha21.wordpress.com/tag/career/'>career</a>, <a href='http://pindsha21.wordpress.com/tag/career-switch/'>career switch</a>, <a href='http://pindsha21.wordpress.com/tag/commencement-speech/'>commencement speech</a>, <a href='http://pindsha21.wordpress.com/tag/failure/'>failure</a>, <a href='http://pindsha21.wordpress.com/tag/goals/'>goals</a>, <a href='http://pindsha21.wordpress.com/tag/j-k-rowling/'>j. k. rowling</a>, <a href='http://pindsha21.wordpress.com/tag/life-change/'>life change</a>, <a href='http://pindsha21.wordpress.com/tag/postaweek2011/'>postaweek2011</a>, <a href='http://pindsha21.wordpress.com/tag/success/'>success</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/857/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/857/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/857/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/857/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/857/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/857/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/857/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/857/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/857/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/857/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/857/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/857/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/857/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/857/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=857&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" /><div class="sharedaddy sd-like-enabled"></div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://pindsha21.wordpress.com/2011/08/14/im-failing-and-why-that-isnt-so-bad/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/7a6a86346e3653559ac83c23ba8b4a88?s=96&#38;d=monsterid&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">pindsha21</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://pindsha21.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/a-big-fat-failure.gif?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Big Fat Failure</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Snapshots from Italy</title>
		<link>http://christinepeh.wordpress.com/2011/07/01/snapshots-from-italy/</link>
		<comments>http://christinepeh.wordpress.com/2011/07/01/snapshots-from-italy/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 10:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Christine Peh</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Florence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Italy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Siena]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tuscany]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://christinepeh.wordpress.com/?p=438</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Am also posting on a Tumblr site that Angelyn and I created to chronicle our entire trip. Click on the image below for more pics and stories.<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=438&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone" src="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v510/christinepeh/Italy%202011/DSC_5850web.jpg" alt="" width="500" /><br />
<img class="alignnone" title="Italy 1" src="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v510/christinepeh/DSC_5597webnocaptions.jpg" alt="" width="500" /><br />
<img class="alignnone" src="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v510/christinepeh/Italy%202011/DSC_5718web.jpg" alt="" width="500" /><br />
<img class="alignnone" src="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v510/christinepeh/Italy%202011/Montepulciano5.jpg" alt="" width="500" /><br />
<img class="alignnone" src="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v510/christinepeh/Italy%202011/DSC_5877web.jpg" alt="" width="500" /><br />
<img class="alignnone" src="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v510/christinepeh/Italy%202011/DSC_5800web.jpg" alt="" width="500" /><br />
<img class="alignnone" src="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v510/christinepeh/Italy%202011/MontepulcianoDuomo1.jpg" alt="" width="500" /><br />
<img class="alignnone" src="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v510/christinepeh/Italy%202011/DSC_5818web700px.jpg" alt="" width="500" /><br />
<img class="alignnone" src="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v510/christinepeh/Italy%202011/Montepulciano2.jpg" alt="" width="500" /><br />
<img class="alignnone" src="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v510/christinepeh/Italy%202011/Montepulciano3.jpg" alt="" width="500" /><br />
Am also posting on a <a href="http://beatentrackish.tumblr.com" target="_blank">Tumblr site</a> that Angelyn and I created to chronicle our entire trip. Click on the image below for more pics and stories.</p>
<p><a href="http://beatentrackish.tumblr.com"><img class="alignnone" title="Notes from the Road Tumblr" src="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v510/christinepeh/travelogheader1web.jpg" alt="" width="500" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/438/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/438/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/438/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/438/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/438/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/438/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/438/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/438/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/438/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/438/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/438/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/438/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/438/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/438/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=438&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" /><div class="sharedaddy sd-like-enabled"></div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://christinepeh.wordpress.com/2011/07/01/snapshots-from-italy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/796844baa043f2544d24e1609be4e13d?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Christine Peh</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v510/christinepeh/Italy%202011/DSC_5850web.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v510/christinepeh/DSC_5597webnocaptions.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Italy 1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v510/christinepeh/Italy%202011/DSC_5718web.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v510/christinepeh/Italy%202011/Montepulciano5.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v510/christinepeh/Italy%202011/DSC_5877web.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v510/christinepeh/Italy%202011/DSC_5800web.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v510/christinepeh/Italy%202011/MontepulcianoDuomo1.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v510/christinepeh/Italy%202011/DSC_5818web700px.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v510/christinepeh/Italy%202011/Montepulciano2.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v510/christinepeh/Italy%202011/Montepulciano3.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v510/christinepeh/travelogheader1web.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Notes from the Road Tumblr</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Two zoo trips in one week?</title>
		<link>http://rufibrenta.wordpress.com/2011/08/12/two-zoo-trips-in-one-week/</link>
		<comments>http://rufibrenta.wordpress.com/2011/08/12/two-zoo-trips-in-one-week/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2011 09:53:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>astrojaxx</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zoo]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rufibrenta.wordpress.com/?p=1518</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Yes indeed. Yesterday we met up in London for a little family outing to the zoo! It&#8217;s been a few years since I went last, and Lou said she hadn&#8217;t been for a decade or so (!!) so we were clearly overdue. The weather was not ideal, but that didn&#8217;t stop us having an awesome [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=1518&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yes indeed. Yesterday we met up in London for a little family outing to the zoo! It&#8217;s been a few years since I went last, and Lou said she hadn&#8217;t been for a decade or so (!!) so we were clearly overdue. The weather was not ideal, but that didn&#8217;t stop us having an awesome time. Compared to Bristol it&#8217;s so huge, and they have a lot more big animals (although, as usual, the tigers and lions were being defiantly unphotogenic and sleeping deep in their hay).</p>
<p>After a fruitless search for the African wild dogs, and a while spent admiring a zebra who was either pregnant or had swallowed a barrel, we came to their rainforest exhibit which contains a number of little monkeys, sloths, tamanduas, a few exciting tropical birds, and, unintentionally, a whole load of mice. Fresh from seeing the new Goeldi&#8217;s monkeys at Bristol, we came across them again:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/astrojaxx/6034436683/" title="Goeldi's monkey by astrojazzy, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6203/6034436683_728937e53a.jpg" width="500" height="333" alt="Goeldi's monkey"></a></p>
<p>and mum spent a while watching some mischievous emperor tamarins, who were looking for food in the most unlikely places:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/astrojaxx/6034438507/" title="Mum with emperor tamarin by astrojazzy, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6086/6034438507_963cedb9dc.jpg" width="500" height="333" alt="Mum with emperor tamarin"></a></p>
<p>Next up were some grumpy meerkats, and then these otters, who I found completely captivating and could have watched all day. They moved as one from one side of their enclosure to the other, all the while keeping up a chorus of chittering and squeaking, and occasionally being enthusiastically wrestled by the others and overcome by all the excitement:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/astrojaxx/6034440707/" title="Oriental short-clawed otters by astrojazzy, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6182/6034440707_7c88141414.jpg" width="500" height="333" alt="Oriental short-clawed otters"></a></p>
<p>To the aquarium!</p>
<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/astrojaxx/6034442599/" title="Yellow fish by astrojazzy, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6127/6034442599_cfb256244b.jpg" width="500" height="333" alt="Yellow fish"></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/astrojaxx/6034996780/" title="Little shrimp by astrojazzy, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6207/6034996780_45cdca2412.jpg" width="500" height="333" alt="Little shrimp"></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/astrojaxx/6034445405/" title="Ray by astrojazzy, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6206/6034445405_fb63a91c0f.jpg" width="500" height="333" alt="Ray"></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/astrojaxx/6035006008/" title="Black and white fish by astrojazzy, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6184/6035006008_9ec70198f5.jpg" width="500" height="333" alt="Black and white fish"></a></p>
<p>The reptile house was super cool, and I actually saw some of the snakes in there moving, which is completely unheard of.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/astrojaxx/6034447127/" title="Yellow snake by astrojazzy, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6195/6034447127_35381e813d.jpg" width="500" height="333" alt="Yellow snake"></a></p>
<p>A sudden downpour necessitated taking cover, and we rushed into a building which housed an odd assortment of animals. It had the inside paddocks for bearded pigs and camels, and then some small enclosures for ferrets, a burrowing owl, armadillos, and Alaotran gentle lemurs. The pigs, like us, were sensibly sheltering from the rain (the camels, on the other hand, stoically sat outside, looking snobby as camels always do).</p>
<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/astrojaxx/6034449087/" title="Bearded pig by astrojazzy, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6089/6034449087_0f8d77253f.jpg" width="500" height="333" alt="Bearded pig"></a></p>
<p>The bug house didn&#8217;t actually contain huge numbers of bugs, but what there was looked cool:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/astrojaxx/6035004014/" title="Grasshopper by astrojazzy, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6080/6035004014_eb2595fbd9.jpg" width="500" height="333" alt="Grasshopper"></a></p>
<p>At half four we caught the penguin feed. They have four kinds of penguin: little African black-footed, like we have at Bristol, Humboldt&#8217;s penguins (the majority of the group), some Macaronis, and a single rockhopper called Ricky. They&#8217;ve just moved into a brand new enclosure which is amazing; they have a really large, deep pool, one side of which is held in by a clear perspex wall, and the view you get under the water is incredible.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/astrojaxx/6034454633/" title="Humboldt's penguin by astrojazzy, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6148/6034454633_eb08d65e0d.jpg" width="500" height="333" alt="Humboldt's penguin"></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/astrojaxx/6034456521/" title="Humboldt's penguin by astrojazzy, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6149/6034456521_8ac9c92994.jpg" width="500" height="333" alt="Humboldt's penguin"></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/astrojaxx/6034458323/" title="Humboldt's penguin by astrojazzy, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6085/6034458323_74be197a86.jpg" width="500" height="333" alt="Humboldt's penguin"></a></p>
<p>Watching them feed was really fun, and at the end when they were all full they stayed in the pool for ages, porpoising above the surface. They are obviously happy penguins, and it put the finishing touch on our day.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1518/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1518/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1518/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1518/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1518/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1518/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1518/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1518/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1518/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1518/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1518/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1518/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1518/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1518/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=1518&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" /><div class="sharedaddy sd-like-enabled"></div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://rufibrenta.wordpress.com/2011/08/12/two-zoo-trips-in-one-week/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">astrojaxx</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6203/6034436683_728937e53a.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Goeldi's monkey</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6086/6034438507_963cedb9dc.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mum with emperor tamarin</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6182/6034440707_7c88141414.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Oriental short-clawed otters</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6127/6034442599_cfb256244b.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Yellow fish</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6207/6034996780_45cdca2412.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Little shrimp</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6206/6034445405_fb63a91c0f.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ray</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6184/6035006008_9ec70198f5.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Black and white fish</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6195/6034447127_35381e813d.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Yellow snake</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6089/6034449087_0f8d77253f.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Bearded pig</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6080/6035004014_eb2595fbd9.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Grasshopper</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6148/6034454633_eb08d65e0d.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Humboldt's penguin</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6149/6034456521_8ac9c92994.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Humboldt's penguin</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm7.static.flickr.com/6085/6034458323_74be197a86.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Humboldt's penguin</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Facebook: A New Frontier in Social Awkwardness</title>
		<link>http://thejackieblog.com/2011/08/10/facebook-a-new-frontier-in-social-awkwardness/</link>
		<comments>http://thejackieblog.com/2011/08/10/facebook-a-new-frontier-in-social-awkwardness/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2011 13:00:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jackie</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[365 Project]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[musings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[postaday2011]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sociology]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thejackieblog.com/?p=1992</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Facebook is getting so awkward, isn&#8217;t it? Personally, I can&#8217;t take the pressure.   It was bad enough when our parents, aunts, and uncles began to join.  I don&#8217;t know about you, but sometimes I still manage to forget they&#8217;re in my contacts and I say something wildly inappropriate only to be scolded seconds later. [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=1992&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://thejackieblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/facebook.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1993" title="Facebook" src="http://thejackieblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/facebook.png?w=331&#038;h=246" alt="" width="331" height="246" /></a></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">Facebook is getting so awkward, isn&#8217;t it?</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">Personally, I can&#8217;t take the pressure.   It was bad enough when our parents, aunts, and uncles began to join.  I don&#8217;t know about you, but sometimes I still manage to forget they&#8217;re in my contacts and I say something wildly inappropriate only to be scolded seconds later.  Then all these apps and games and silly questionnaires came through and all the sudden I&#8217;m forced to virtually break up with my friend because she won&#8217;t stop telling me to water her virtual crops.  Sure, I could just weed through my privacy settings and try to block app invites, but if my friend is the kind of person that constantly bugs me to water her fake crops, <em>do I really want to be her friend anymore?</em></span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">These are the sorts of hard-hitting questions I&#8217;m faced with every time Facebook &#8216;upgrades&#8217;.</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">Things got even more intense when Facebook leveled-up to real-time updates so that when you stare at your mini-feed you can actually see someone&#8217;s comment post at the very moment they do it.   And now, the ultimate mega stresser: Facebook chat.</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">It could be the super awkward hermit in me, but the chat is where I draw the line.  The beauty of Facebook used to be that it was casual and cool.   People could post on each other&#8217;s walls at their leisure.   In a world where the weight of a cell phone text or an email is so heavy that people expect a response immediately, Facebook was the one place I could still go if I wanted to socialize at a relaxed pace.</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">Facebook relaxation is now dead to me.</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">When I log on, I have updates that need tended to.  I have people commenting on pictures or saying hello or writing on my wall to ask me to hang out that same day.  I have messages from friends who haven&#8217;t caught up in a while and think email is too impersonal.  And sometimes while I&#8217;m tending to those things, someone is online at the very same moment and responds immediately.  <em>Immediately! </em>Then there&#8217;s all this pressure.  Do I have to follow up? Can I go log off?  They&#8217;re on.  They see me.  They know I updated only 5 seconds ago; it&#8217;s stamped right there in cold, gray text. I can&#8217;t possibly just leave &#8211; I have to finish the conversation.</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">I also have to manage my status updates.  Because if I tell a friend I&#8217;m too busy to hang out one night but I update my status at 8:35pm saying how much I love Arrested Development, it&#8217;s voluntary incrimination.   It doesn&#8217;t matter if it&#8217;s on in the background while I&#8217;m working.  It doesn&#8217;t matter if I thought of a funny episode and it wasn&#8217;t even on television.  That friendship is doomed.  </span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">Doomed.</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">Don&#8217;t even get me started on birthdays and engagements.  Talk about stress! Seriously?! Every year on my birthday I have to be wished a happy birthday by hundreds of people I haven&#8217;t talked to in ages.  On one hand, it&#8217;s nice to feel loved.  On the other, you know that if any of those people really cared about your birthday they&#8217;d have called.  Or written.  Or emailed.  And now I feel inclined to follow up with them to see how they are, but I don&#8217;t know if they were really reaching out or if they just wanted to hop on the birthday bandwagon.</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">I don&#8217;t even recognize some of their names.</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">I&#8217;m not the only one who feels this pressure.  I know it.  Because not long ago, some dear friends of mine got engaged.  And while I was relishing in the happy moment with them, they admitted that they were quite exhausted because they had to be sure to call every single person that was even remotely close to them to let them know they were engaged before those people saw it on Facebook and got offended that they found out online and not from them.</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">You see? What are we doing to ourselves?!</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">So no, Facebook, I will not be utilizing your &#8216;Facebook Chat&#8217;.  The last thing I need in this too-accessible age is to log on and be immediately available to a thousand people, try to figure out how to end conversations with everyone because I don&#8217;t want to deal with them, and then worry about what to update my status to that will be amusing but also not indicate that I was having too much &#8216;not-too-busy-to-chat&#8217; fun.</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">Lord help us; Facebook will be the end of us all. <span style="color:#0000ff;">♣</span></span></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1992/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1992/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1992/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1992/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1992/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1992/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1992/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1992/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1992/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1992/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1992/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1992/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1992/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1992/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=1992&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" /><div class="sharedaddy sd-like-enabled"></div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thejackieblog.com/2011/08/10/facebook-a-new-frontier-in-social-awkwardness/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/8bceba58350ad75ac0585c27d2225419?s=96&#38;d=monsterid&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jacklynmarieb</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thejackieblog.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/facebook.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Facebook</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tips for New College Students – Round 8</title>
		<link>http://idrawsometimes.wordpress.com/2011/08/15/tips-for-new-college-students-%e2%80%93-round-8/</link>
		<comments>http://idrawsometimes.wordpress.com/2011/08/15/tips-for-new-college-students-%e2%80%93-round-8/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2011 05:27:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>ministerofpain</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adviser]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[college]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[first year]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[freshmen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[holiday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[internship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[major]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[school]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[study abroad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[university]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vacation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[year]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://idrawsometimes.wordpress.com/?p=2739</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Eight? This is getting out of hand. Today&#8217;s post is the last of the initial mega-batch of college advice that I came up with over the course of one day. Appropriately enough, the tips involve topics that are slightly more long-term, though that&#8217;s a pretty flexible phrase&#8211;it&#8217;s not like the classroom-related advice is something you&#8217;ll [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=2739&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Eight? This is getting out of hand. Today&#8217;s post is the last of the initial mega-batch of college advice that I came up with over the course of one day. Appropriately enough, the tips involve topics that are slightly more long-term, though that&#8217;s a pretty flexible phrase&#8211;it&#8217;s not like the classroom-related advice is something you&#8217;ll only think about for the first week of school or so. I still think that most of these suggestions are ones that you can wait to think about for a little while. They&#8217;re good things to keep in mind and reconsider in the next semester or year.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Book holiday flights early&#8211;and try to get a direct flight.</strong> If you&#8217;re going to school relatively far from home, chances are that your first trip back will be for Thanksgiving. Reserve that flight as soon as you have a solid idea of when you&#8217;ll be free. If you wait until November (or the week before), you will pay dearly for procrastinating. A flight that might only be about $200 if purchased in advance will be several times more expensive if you get it too late. That&#8217;s what happened to me during freshman year. A flight that would cost only $200-$250 in future years ended up being almost $700. It was also a flight with one connection. Due to delays, I missed my connecting flight, had to sleep in Atlanta&#8217;s airport overnight, and got home one day later than expected. It SUCKED. Thanksgiving weekend borders on pandemonium at airports, so reduce your chances of being screwed over by booking early and booking a flight to go home in one trip.</li>
</ul>
<div id="attachment_2740" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 410px"><a href="http://idrawsometimes.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/cimg3768.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-2740" title="CIMG3768" src="http://idrawsometimes.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/cimg3768.jpg?w=400&#038;h=300" alt="" width="400" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">My luxurious &quot;bedroom&quot; at Atlanta&#039;s airport; Thanksgiving 2006.</p></div>
<ul>
<li><strong>Really think about studying abroad in the future.</strong> One of the most common regrets you&#8217;ll hear from college students is not studying abroad. A semester abroad is often one of the most enriching experiences you&#8217;ll have as an undergrad. It&#8217;s also one of those things that your school will probably peddle endlessly, which almost makes you not want to go just out of spite. But really, they strongly suggest that you study abroad with good intentions. Living in a different country and absorbing its culture/language provides insight that no class could offer. If you&#8217;re learning a foreign language, going to a country where it&#8217;s the native tongue is incredibly intimidating but also extremely rewarding. You really feel like all your hard work is going to great use, and you feel powerful from being able to communicate in a totally different language. Even if you&#8217;re not focused on the language aspect, studying abroad is an unforgettable opportunity. Do everything in your power to make that time. You&#8217;ll thank yourself&#8211;possibly in a foreign language.</li>
</ul>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 382px"><img src="http://www.totallyduh.com/funny-images/redneck-spelling-b.jpg" alt="" width="372" height="326" /><p class="wp-caption-text">I&#039;m willing to guess that this man doesn&#039;t like getting advice from others.</p></div>
<ul>
<li><strong>Ask more people for advise than your advisor. </strong>The world of AP credits, liberal arts requirements, major requirements, and class registration is a sordid one that is hard/stupid to navigate all on your own. That&#8217;s why most every university will have an advising center where you can meet with an academic advisor and discuss your goals and options. College advisors work hard (most of them), they all mean well, and they want to help you walk out of the school with that fancy degree. Unfortunately, their good intentions don&#8217;t always translate into good advice, and you can&#8217;t really blame them too viciously for that. There are so many majors, minors, and pre-professional tracks to choose from, and each advisor has to keep up with a huge mass of students that all have their own aspirations and unique problems. How can they be completely informed about everything that the school has to offer? On the other hand, that&#8217;s no reason to be blindly forgiving of bad advice, and sometimes, the advice they give can be misguided, outdated, or outrageously wrong. If you don&#8217;t ask anyone else and just go with what they say, you could be losing out on a lot. My freshman year, I was taking an essay-writing class that was required of every student, no matter what. It was almost exclusively taken by freshmen, but there was one errant senior in my course. She looked incredibly unhappy to be there, and for good reason: Her old academic advisor had incorrectly told her that her AP English credit would exempt her from the class. In her last semester at school, she found out that she needed to take this course and was thrown in at the last second. It sucked for her, and you don&#8217;t want to suffer a similar fate. Go visit your advisor regularly and listen closely to their advice. Hopefully, it&#8217;ll be great! But there&#8217;s no reason to stop there. Speak with older students, other advisors, and the director of undergraduate studies (known as DUGS or DGS) in your department. Some of them might offer the most specific and correct advice, so don&#8217;t cheat yourself!</li>
</ul>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 382px"><img src="http://www.totallyduh.com/funny-images/redneck-spelling-b.jpg" alt="" width="372" height="326" /><p class="wp-caption-text">I&#039;m also willing to guess that this man did not study abroad.</p></div>
<ul>
<li><strong>Don&#8217;t get too caught up in the internship frenzy.</strong> This advice might not mean anything during the first semester, but rest assured that it will make more sense during the second. In the spring, students will begin to furiously pursue summer internships that can pad their resumes. In this stale economic climate, the internship race is even more frantic since there aren&#8217;t as many positions. (Yes, internships typically don&#8217;t pay anything, but more and more people who were laid off from real jobs are trying to nab these internships from students. Some companies also just don&#8217;t have the resources to support as many interns as they used to.) You might want a summer internship, too. That&#8217;s great; it&#8217;s nice to be productive during the summer and add to your credentials. However, it is really easy to get tunnel vision and start envisioning a summer internship as some make-or-break opportunity that could enable or totally cripple for future career prospects. That&#8217;s not true. Be happy if you get an internship, but don&#8217;t worry if you don&#8217;t&#8211;plenty of people will find perfectly great jobs even if they aren&#8217;t interns. And there&#8217;s always next year. Until then, keep yourself busy with other summer jobs or volunteer work. Just show people that you like to be active, and things will be fine.</li>
<li><strong>Don&#8217;t panic if you&#8217;re undecided about your major.</strong> One of those nagging questions you get as an incoming freshman, from both parents and fellow students, is: &#8220;So, what&#8217;s your major?&#8221; It gets irritating after a while, especially if you don&#8217;t have a concrete answer. Each time you&#8217;re asked, it&#8217;s a reminder of how tenuous your future seems. Don&#8217;t sweat it. You&#8217;re definitely not the only one to be undecided, and lots of students who confidently answer that question now will later face a small crisis when they contemplate changing their major later on. You have two years to decide your major(s). Be open-minded as you take some of those required courses. Explore your options, and you will most likely stumble across something that excites you. That&#8217;s what was behind my switch from math to political science. And by the way, enjoying reading doesn&#8217;t necessarily mean you&#8217;ll enjoy being an English major, nor does liking computers mean that you&#8217;d fit in as a Computer Science major. So if you think you know what you want to major in, take those classes and see whether the academic approaches to those fields actually interest you or not.</li>
</ul>
<p>I really want to stress that last one. You don&#8217;t want to totally ignore the question of what your major should be, but don&#8217;t do a disservice to yourself by agonizing over it. Keep an open mind and enjoy the ride, because it will lead you somewhere whether you expect it to or not.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ll (hopefully) close up shop next time.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2739/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2739/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2739/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2739/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2739/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2739/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2739/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2739/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2739/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2739/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2739/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2739/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2739/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2739/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=2739&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" /><div class="sharedaddy sd-like-enabled"></div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://idrawsometimes.wordpress.com/2011/08/15/tips-for-new-college-students-%e2%80%93-round-8/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/31a65afadb49ceb65db94358d5ec6cad?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ministerofpain</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://idrawsometimes.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/cimg3768.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">CIMG3768</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://www.totallyduh.com/funny-images/redneck-spelling-b.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://www.totallyduh.com/funny-images/redneck-spelling-b.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tereré: Paraguayan Cold Tea</title>
		<link>http://myargentineadventure.wordpress.com/2011/08/11/terere/</link>
		<comments>http://myargentineadventure.wordpress.com/2011/08/11/terere/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2011 02:37:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>VeeDub</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Belly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beverages]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Argentine culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cold brewed tea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[maté]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Paraguayan culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tereré]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://myargentineadventure.wordpress.com/?p=322</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Yerba mate, a brew of tea leaves reminiscent of foliage, packed into a gourd and slurped through a metal straw by the residents of the Cono Sur, continually mystifies and entertains unsuspecting yanquis new to this neck of woods. Mate is more than just a drink- it is a pastime, a daily ritual, and a [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=322&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://myargentineadventure.wordpress.com/2011/08/11/terere/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/009bed5330dc6f707c4104eb758ca094?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">veeceewillson</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://myargentineadventure.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/mate-blue-bgnd.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mate blue bgnd</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://myargentineadventure.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/100_2537.jpg?w=208" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Amanda brand</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://myargentineadventure.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/mate-top.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mate top</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://myargentineadventure.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/100_2582.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bombillas</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Properly stacked</title>
		<link>http://foto.dahlstroms.com/2011/08/12/properly-stacked/</link>
		<comments>http://foto.dahlstroms.com/2011/08/12/properly-stacked/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2011 11:04:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Håkan Dahlström</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2010]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chairs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cologne]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cyan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[floor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[germany]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[köln]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tables]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://hakansfotografi.wordpress.com/?p=3986</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Filed under: Photography Tagged: 2010, chairs, cologne, cyan, floor, germany, köln, photography, stack, tables<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=3986&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><img src="http://hakansfotografi.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/d160d3f.jpeg?w=950&#038;h=633" alt="Properly stacked" title="Properly stacked" width="950" height="633" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-2295" /></p>
</div>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://foto.dahlstroms.com/category/photography-2/'>Photography</a> Tagged: <a href='http://foto.dahlstroms.com/tag/2010/'>2010</a>, <a href='http://foto.dahlstroms.com/tag/chairs/'>chairs</a>, <a href='http://foto.dahlstroms.com/tag/cologne/'>cologne</a>, <a href='http://foto.dahlstroms.com/tag/cyan/'>cyan</a>, <a href='http://foto.dahlstroms.com/tag/floor/'>floor</a>, <a href='http://foto.dahlstroms.com/tag/germany/'>germany</a>, <a href='http://foto.dahlstroms.com/tag/koln/'>köln</a>, <a href='http://foto.dahlstroms.com/tag/photography/'>photography</a>, <a href='http://foto.dahlstroms.com/tag/stack/'>stack</a>, <a href='http://foto.dahlstroms.com/tag/tables/'>tables</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3986/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3986/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3986/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3986/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3986/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3986/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3986/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3986/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3986/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3986/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3986/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3986/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3986/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3986/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=3986&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" /><div class="sharedaddy sd-like-enabled"></div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://foto.dahlstroms.com/2011/08/12/properly-stacked/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		<georss:point>56.043875 12.695870</georss:point>
		<geo:lat>56.043875</geo:lat>
		<geo:long>12.695870</geo:long>
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/7521244303db89d571895b582651fc1e?s=96&#38;d=" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">hakandahlstrom</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hakansfotografi.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/d160d3f.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Properly stacked</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Deal with Stigma or Bias against Chronic Illness</title>
		<link>http://msmeans.wordpress.com/2011/08/15/how-to-deal-with-stigma-or-bias-against-chronic-illness/</link>
		<comments>http://msmeans.wordpress.com/2011/08/15/how-to-deal-with-stigma-or-bias-against-chronic-illness/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2011 12:13:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>msmeans</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[change]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cognitive issues]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[epilepsy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exercise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fitness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[happiness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Inspirations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life balance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[menopause]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MS treatments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[multiple sclerosis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[perimenopause]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[seizures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sexuality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Symptoms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[balance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inspiration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-esteem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yoga]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://msmeans.wordpress.com/?p=677</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[“Pain is inevitable. Suffering is optional.” ~Unknown Sometimes having a chronic illness can be like walking a lonely road&#8230;especially when people react to you in negative ways because they do not understand your illness. I find myself these days often between two extremes: some on one end, over-protective and treating me like I am a [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=677&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong><a href="http://msmeans.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0929.jpg"><br />
</a></strong><strong>“Pain is inevitable. Suffering is optional.” ~Unknown</strong></p>
<p><strong><a href="http://msmeans.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0929.jpg"><img title="IMG_0929" src="http://msmeans.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0929.jpg?w=584&#038;h=438" alt="" width="584" height="438" /></a></strong></p>
<p>Sometimes having a chronic illness can be like walking a lonely road&#8230;especially when people react to you in negative ways because they do not understand your illness.</p>
<p>I find myself these days often between two extremes: some on one end, over-protective and treating me like I am a helpless victim, ready to break and fail at any moment due to fragile health; and at the other end, some who are stressed by my very presence to some degree, because they fear what may happen if I have a medical emergency at some point while with them (read: seizure fear).</p>
<p>In the middle is me, just quietly plodding on and struggling to re-establish my personal balance, physically, spiritually, and mentally. The one end makes me feel suffocated, misread, and trapped, while the other end makes me feel like a burden, misunderstood, and something to be kept isolated for fear of causing stress. Both extremes create stress in me, and cause me personal emotional pain and frustration. The catch-22 is that this very stress reaction created in me can actually manifest the health crises these two ends of the spectrum fear they will see in me.</p>
<p>So &#8211; how do we deal with these extremes? Frankly, I wish I had a magic recipe for this. (Hmmm&#8230;I wonder if Hermione Granger is available to consult??? Maybe I should call up J.K.Rowling to ask.)</p>
<p>Here are the ways I have found that help me deal with the stigma and bias caused by chronic illness (especially seizure disorders):</p>
<p><strong>1. Cultivate your compassion.</strong></p>
<p>Be compassionate with yourself as well as the person creating the stress by their reactions. That person may not understand how their behaviour is affecting you. Choose to recognise that the person has a fear, and their fear is their issue &#8211; not yours.</p>
<p><strong>2. Remember, you are NOT your illness.</strong></p>
<p>Remind yourself that you are not defined by your illness, no matter what anyone may think, say, or feel. Only you can define who you are and what you are capable of achieving.</p>
<p><strong>3. Practice non-attachment.</strong></p>
<p>Keep a smile on your face and turn the other cheek. Do not allow your ego to become attached to anyone else&#8217;s fears or labels. Listen with an open heart where possible and remain true to yourself, non-attached to others&#8217; issues.</p>
<p><strong>4. Walk away if need be.</strong></p>
<p>If the situation persists and creates increasing stress in you, you can walk away. You are not defined by other&#8217;s fears &#8211; don&#8217;t allow them to take hold. Choose to walk away.</p>
<p><strong>“Believe nothing no matter where you read it, or who said it, no matter if I have said it, unless it agrees with your own reason and common sense.” ~Buddha</strong></p>
<p>Namaste.</p>
<p>Carolyne</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://msmeans.wordpress.com/category/change/'>change</a>, <a href='http://msmeans.wordpress.com/category/cognitive-issues/'>cognitive issues</a>, <a href='http://msmeans.wordpress.com/category/epilepsy/'>epilepsy</a>, <a href='http://msmeans.wordpress.com/category/exercise/'>exercise</a>, <a href='http://msmeans.wordpress.com/category/fitness/'>fitness</a>, <a href='http://msmeans.wordpress.com/category/happiness/'>happiness</a>, <a href='http://msmeans.wordpress.com/category/health/'>health</a>, <a href='http://msmeans.wordpress.com/category/humor/'>humor</a>, <a href='http://msmeans.wordpress.com/category/inspirations/'>Inspirations</a>, <a href='http://msmeans.wordpress.com/category/life/'>life</a>, <a href='http://msmeans.wordpress.com/category/life-balance/'>life balance</a>, <a href='http://msmeans.wordpress.com/category/menopause/'>menopause</a>, <a href='http://msmeans.wordpress.com/category/ms-treatments/'>MS treatments</a>, <a href='http://msmeans.wordpress.com/category/multiple-sclerosis/'>multiple sclerosis</a>, <a href='http://msmeans.wordpress.com/category/perimenopause/'>perimenopause</a>, <a href='http://msmeans.wordpress.com/category/personal/'>personal</a>, <a href='http://msmeans.wordpress.com/category/seizures/'>seizures</a>, <a href='http://msmeans.wordpress.com/category/sexuality/'>Sexuality</a>, <a href='http://msmeans.wordpress.com/category/symptoms/'>Symptoms</a> Tagged: <a href='http://msmeans.wordpress.com/tag/balance/'>balance</a>, <a href='http://msmeans.wordpress.com/tag/cognitive-issues/'>cognitive issues</a>, <a href='http://msmeans.wordpress.com/tag/coping/'>coping</a>, <a href='http://msmeans.wordpress.com/tag/epilepsy/'>epilepsy</a>, <a href='http://msmeans.wordpress.com/tag/happiness/'>happiness</a>, <a href='http://msmeans.wordpress.com/tag/health/'>health</a>, <a href='http://msmeans.wordpress.com/tag/humor/'>humor</a>, <a href='http://msmeans.wordpress.com/tag/inspiration/'>inspiration</a>, <a href='http://msmeans.wordpress.com/tag/life/'>life</a>, <a href='http://msmeans.wordpress.com/tag/multiple-sclerosis/'>multiple sclerosis</a>, <a href='http://msmeans.wordpress.com/tag/personal/'>personal</a>, <a href='http://msmeans.wordpress.com/tag/seizures/'>seizures</a>, <a href='http://msmeans.wordpress.com/tag/self-esteem/'>self-esteem</a>, <a href='http://msmeans.wordpress.com/tag/symptoms/'>Symptoms</a>, <a href='http://msmeans.wordpress.com/tag/work/'>work</a>, <a href='http://msmeans.wordpress.com/tag/yoga/'>yoga</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/677/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/677/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/677/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/677/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/677/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/677/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/677/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/677/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/677/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/677/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/677/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/677/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/677/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/677/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=677&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" /><div class="sharedaddy sd-like-enabled"></div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://msmeans.wordpress.com/2011/08/15/how-to-deal-with-stigma-or-bias-against-chronic-illness/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/8eba3ccb185e5fc181a53753804e50fd?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F0.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">msmeans</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://msmeans.files.wordpress.com/2011/08/img_0929.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0929</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Economics of Dry Cleaning</title>
		<link>http://melonbloggers.wordpress.com/2011/07/05/the-economics-of-dry-cleaning/</link>
		<comments>http://melonbloggers.wordpress.com/2011/07/05/the-economics-of-dry-cleaning/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2011 16:46:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>melonbloggers</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dry cleaning]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://melonbloggers.wordpress.com/?p=381</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Jerry Seinfeld has a funny bit about dry cleaning and lately I&#8217;ve been dubious myself. Besides not knowing how something could possibly be cleaned without water, when does dry cleaning become more expensive than it&#8217;s worth? In our home we have a strict do-not-buy dry-clean-only policy for frequently used items. But there are a couple [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=381&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://melonbloggers.files.wordpress.com/2011/07/dry-cleaning.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-383" title="dry cleaning" src="http://melonbloggers.files.wordpress.com/2011/07/dry-cleaning.jpg?w=218&#038;h=128" alt="" width="218" height="128" /></a>Jerry Seinfeld has a funny <a title="bit" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bCGHtUOx20I" target="_blank">bit</a> about dry cleaning and lately I&#8217;ve been dubious myself. Besides not knowing how something could possibly be cleaned without water, when does dry cleaning become more expensive than it&#8217;s worth?</p>
<p>In our home we have a strict do-not-buy dry-clean-only policy for frequently used items. But there are a couple of DCO renegades in the closet from earlier days.</p>
<p>So back to my question: When does the cost of dry cleaning outweigh the worth of the item of clothing? Surely some lonely economics blogger has come up with an equation involving initial item cost, expected lifetime of item, frequency and cost of cleaning, etc, right? But my Google search was fruitless. Boo blogosphere!</p>
<p>Any thoughts?</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://melonbloggers.wordpress.com/category/science/'>Science</a> Tagged: <a href='http://melonbloggers.wordpress.com/tag/dry-cleaning/'>dry cleaning</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/381/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/381/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/381/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/381/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/381/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/381/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/381/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/381/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/381/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/381/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/381/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/381/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/381/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/381/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=381&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" /><div class="sharedaddy sd-like-enabled"></div>]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://melonbloggers.wordpress.com/2011/07/05/the-economics-of-dry-cleaning/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/e28b29bebd25b4c123ac5842e5304b38?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F0.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">melonbloggers</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://melonbloggers.files.wordpress.com/2011/07/dry-cleaning.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">dry cleaning</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>