<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 20:14:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>&#8216;Dry Holi&#8217; Campaign: Is Digital Activism Slacktivism?</title>
		<link>http://gettingloquacious.wordpress.com/2013/03/27/dry-holi-campaign-is-digital-activism-slacktivism/</link>
		<comments>http://gettingloquacious.wordpress.com/2013/03/27/dry-holi-campaign-is-digital-activism-slacktivism/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 14:14:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Tejas Harad</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Digital Activism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Drought In Maharashtra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Save Water]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Slacktivism]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://gettingloquacious.wordpress.com/?p=589</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Maharashtra is worst hit with drought this year since 1972 as 13 out of 35 districts are facing acute shortage of water. The situation in Vidarbha and Marathwada is dire. People don&#8217;t have enough water to drink. Every village is not lucky enough to get water tankers on time. It won&#8217;t be long before we [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=589&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://xomariee.files.wordpress.com/2012/03/cropped-social-media-activism.jpg" width="100%" class="alignnone" /></p>
<p>Maharashtra is worst hit with <a href="http://blogs.wsj.com/indiarealtime/2013/03/25/western-india-hopes-for-rain/" target="_blank">drought</a> this year since 1972 as 13 out of 35 districts are facing acute shortage of water. The situation in Vidarbha and Marathwada is dire. People don&#8217;t have enough water to drink. Every village is not lucky enough to get water tankers on time. It won&#8217;t be long before we start hearing reports of cattle and even people dying due to lack of water.</p>
<p>This has created ripples in the urban areas of Maharashtra, such as Mumbai and Pune, especially in the digital arena. People have decided to show solidarity with the drought-hit region by not wasting water in the festival of Holi. They are urging other people to play &#8216;dry Holi&#8217; through Facebook statuses, tweets and WhatsApp messages. Even celebrities have <a href="http://blogs.wsj.com/indiarealtime/2013/03/26/celebrities-call-for-dry-holi-amid-drought/" target="_blank">joined the chorus</a>. This has generated a fair amount discussion about the issue on various social media forums and even off these platforms; and most of the people have agreed to the pledge of not wasting water.</p>
<p>But there are some dissenting voices too, who like to call this whole exercise tokenism. According to them, this digital activism farce is not going to change anything. It doesn&#8217;t take much efforts to post a comment or share or like a post (a post can be a text message, an image, a link to an article, a video, etc.) and most of these clicks are half-hearted. According to them, this is not activism, but <a href="http://www.cracked.com/funny-6978-slacktivism/" target="_blank">slacktivism</a>. (Read this New Yorker <a href="http://www.newyorker.com/reporting/2010/10/04/101004fa_fact_gladwell?currentPage=all" target="_blank">piece</a> by celebrated author Malcolm Gladwell, which made this argument famous).</p>
<p>I disagree. Participants in digital activism are mostly students and young professionals. If they did not have an outlet like social media, what other options would they have? Rallies, protest marches, hunger  strikes, public gatherings or distributing pamphlets on the railway platforms? How many of the participants could give either their time or efforts for such activities, balancing college or workplace commitments? Is it fair to expect them to become full-fledged activists? Social activists have their own commitments and resources and they are fighting their own battles somewhere else. But does that mean, we, normal citizens can&#8217;t play any role in changing our society?</p>
<p>Calling digital activism slacktivism is outright derogatory. Though it basically tries to ridicule netizens who participate in such campaigns as lazy, it also unconsciously assumes that digital sphere is a separate entity. Nathan Jurgenson terms this argument digital dualism (you can read his critique on digital dualism <a href="http://thesocietypages.org/cyborgology/2011/02/24/digital-dualism-versus-augmented-reality/" target="_blank">here</a>). I am a staunch opponent of digital dualism, as it bifurcates digital and physical into two different worlds. It makes us believe that there is no interplay between the two, while I believe that they are enmeshed and affect each other&#8217;s behaviour.</p>
<p>People who participate in digital campaigns are not serious activists, but that does not mean they do not care about the society. They may not have studied the issues they are talking about thoroughly. Their solutions to the problems may be half-baked. But their intentions and the desire to do something meaningful is very genuine. And I believe, some of these very people are going to be tomorrow&#8217;s Medha Patkars, Arundhati Roys and Harsh Manders.</p>
<p>The major benefit of digital campaigns is that they create awareness about the issues they are espousing. The movement that emerged after Delhi Gang Rape is a case in point. Now we are at a better understanding as a society as far as women rights, violence against women and sexism is concerned than before and internet played a major role in this. Even the dry Holi campaign will not give water to the people suffering from drought, but it has at least brought their plight in limelight. I consider it a valuable contribution to the cause. (Here is an <a href="http://www.meta-activism.org/2012/02/digital-activism-101-the-5-activist-functions-of-technology/" target="_blank">article</a> which lists five other functions new technology plays in activism).</p>
<p>Internet offers a lot of resources to study a particular issue. Everybody who likes a post on Facebook about saving water on Holi will not go and read about <a href="http://www.thehindu.com/opinion/columns/sainath/how-the-other-half-dries/article4456130.ece" target="_blank">drought in Maharshtra</a> in another tab, but there will be a small bunch of people who will. This small bunch mostly consists of people who are influencers and leaders in their own way, as they shape the opinions and lead the debates in their own circles. And I am banking on these people.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/589/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/589/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=589&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://gettingloquacious.wordpress.com/2013/03/27/dry-holi-campaign-is-digital-activism-slacktivism/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		<georss:point>19.075984 72.877656</georss:point>
		<geo:lat>19.075984</geo:lat>
		<geo:long>72.877656</geo:long>
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/6bab71d32e2bde262bee1fd1a5484cb2?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tejas12</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://xomariee.files.wordpress.com/2012/03/cropped-social-media-activism.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Drawing the Line on Government Intervention</title>
		<link>http://historyandwine.com/2013/03/25/drawing-the-line-on-government-intervention/</link>
		<comments>http://historyandwine.com/2013/03/25/drawing-the-line-on-government-intervention/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 18:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>historywino</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[DP Challenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Political Commentary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPChallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lifestyle intervention]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NYC Soda Ban]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://historyandwine.com/?p=517</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I’m writing in response to Word Press’ Daily Post Writing Challenge about “The State of the State.” The question was posted today, March 25th, “Where do you draw the line between a reasonable government attempt to maintain stability or solve a problem and an unnecessary infringement on your decisions?” Interesting question; this is right up my alley. NYC [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=517&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I’m writing in response to Word Press’ Daily Post Writing Challenge about “<a href="http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2013/03/25/writing-challenge-government/">The State of the State.</a>” The question was posted today, March 25th, “Where do <em>you</em> draw the line between a reasonable government attempt to maintain stability or solve a problem and an unnecessary infringement on your decisions?”</p>
<p>Interesting question; this is right up my alley.</p>
<p>NYC Soda Ban: preposterous. I cannot and will not support a nanny state mentality.</p>
<p>When you look at ordinances like the large soda ban in New York City, what do you think? Do you honestly think that the government cares about you individually, or do you think that perhaps there is an exertion of power beyond the limits of the functionality of a successful government? I think the latter. If the NYC government, with bologna Bloomberg at its helm, honestly cared about the health of each citizen of the city of New York, it/he would not focus on the menial task of banning sodas. That’s child’s play. It is so condescending and offensive to assume that people do not have enough self-control to regulate the amount of sugary beverage they intake in any given setting. Maybe some people cannot exercise that self-control as well as others, but it is not the role of the government to go around telling those with health issues how much they can or cannot consume at any given time&#8211; just as your parents no longer have control over minor decisions such as these in your life once you are over a certain age. Did Bloomberg just adopt 9 million children? Sure seems like he wants to.</p>
<p><i>Please</i> give the people education. That is far more important. Nutritional education would go a lot farther than banning a large soda. Lifestyle modification is what a lot of people need, not a quick fix substance ban. People who struggle with obesity or food and beverage self-control do not need someone breathing down their neck and demanding that they take measures to change. These people need encouragement and support, and a system to guide them to choose better options on their own. Rarely do people adhere to regulations forced upon them, but those who decide for themselves to make healthier choices are more likely to succeed.</p>
<p>Do I think that the government should play a role in education? Yes, to a certain extent. I think that Bloomberg’s efforts to curb the obesity epidemic in his small corner of the world would see better results if he were able to offer some kind of city-funded nutritional program, or some kind of reimbursement for a lifestyle modification program such as the YMCA’s Diabetes Prevention Program, which is hosted at local YMCAs or other community centers throughout the city. Not only are programs such as these proven to better the health status of individuals who commit to them, but individuals enter these programs as a matter of personal choice. You see, people must make their own decision to change; Michael Bloomberg (or any government) cannot make that decision for them by punishing them like foolish schoolchildren.</p>
<p>Is the government overstepping boundaries by taking away a person’s choice in beverage? Absolutely, unequivocally, resounding YES. Would society be better off if the government offered the choice of education, which provides resources for people who need to make lifestyle changes? Oh yes. Please do not undermine the ability of a human being to make an educated decision when he is given the tools to do so. And do not underestimate the power of the resources that are already available and underutilized to help those in need make the decisions for a healthier life.</p>
<p>Mr. Bloomberg, back off of the rights of the people of New York City.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/517/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/517/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/517/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/517/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/517/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/517/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/517/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/517/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/517/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/517/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/517/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/517/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/517/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/517/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=517&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://historyandwine.com/2013/03/25/drawing-the-line-on-government-intervention/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/34549e17c94711ffb3650f6c801e1d34?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">historywino</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Message to Parents From Your Child’s Teacher</title>
		<link>http://christinemccartney.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/a-message-to-parents-from-your-childs-teacher/</link>
		<comments>http://christinemccartney.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/a-message-to-parents-from-your-childs-teacher/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 17:17:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>christine mccartney</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[activism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPchallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Finland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[schools]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://christinemccartney.wordpress.com/?p=140</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Dear Parent/Guardian, I am your child’s teacher.  My role as educator extends far beyond the walls of my classroom.  It is my profession, what I practice.   I have chosen to devote the better part of what will be the years that make up my life to educating your child. I take it very seriously and [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=140&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>
<p dir="ltr"><span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='640' height='390' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/IQ-OtEdFAKI?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span></p>
<p dir="ltr">Dear Parent/Guardian,</p>
<p dir="ltr">I am your child’s teacher.  My role as educator extends far beyond the walls of my classroom.  It is my profession, what I practice.   I have chosen to devote the better part of what will be <em>the years that make up my life </em>to educating your child. I take it very seriously and I should; I am a stakeholder in <em>your</em> child’s future.</p>
<p dir="ltr">And so are you. You take it seriously also.  You take your role in your child’s life more seriously than probably anyone else ever will.  You have spent countless hours modeling empathy and kindness, teaching right from wrong, helping your child learn how to navigate through an increasingly complicated world and spending time to understand who your child is and where he/she is coming from.   You do this in order to help guide your child down the path to who he/she will become.  So I ask you, taking all of this into consideration, how willing would you be to allow some other parent to take over this role for you &#8211;someone who claimed to know “better” than you about what was right for your child?</p>
<p dir="ltr">Think about it.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Because that is what is happening in my classroom.  And it isn’t because they know “better” than I do how to educate your child &#8211;<em>the undertaking I have chosen to devote my life’s work to becoming better at doing.</em>  It certainly isn’t because they have spent months getting to know the individual you have raised in an effort to better understand what your student needs to thrive in a responsive learning environment.  It has nothing to do with the relationship they have formed with your child in order to show respect and care for him/her as a person and as a learner.  It doesn’t, for a second, reflect the passion I have for the subject I teach &#8211;passion that I pass on to your student in every way I can and at every chance I get.</p>
<p dir="ltr">It simply has to do with money.</p>
<p dir="ltr">It has to do with the $500 billion dollars allocated by the United States government to children like yours.  Your money.  Tax-payer money intended to directly benefit students. Money that is being hijacked by for-profit educational management companies.  The same people who are using their voices to belittle me and my colleagues, and our schools, and <em>your</em> child’s performance, in order to rationalize their hidden agenda: making money.</p>
<p dir="ltr">They are spending their own money too.  They are using it to pay lobbyists who help manipulate educational policy and dictate allocation of resources towards private companies&#8230; and it is working.  The $13 million dollars they had their hands on in 2005 had already risen to $389 million by 2011.  Don&#8217;t mistake it: there exists big profit potential in your child.  Three hundred and eighty-nine million dollars&#8230;and that was two years ago.</p>
<p dir="ltr">So <em>today</em> I ask you this:</p>
<p dir="ltr"><em>My life’s work.</em>  The countless hours I spend with your child presenting new material, creating on-going formative assessments that are authentic and based on your student’s individual needs at a given moment in time, the active learning and knowledge-construction happening in my classroom on a daily basis, the time I spend creating lessons which require students to build upon and re-evaluate prior knowledge and the work that reflects the relationship that I have worked diligently to foster with your student:  is it worth putting all of this hard-won expertise on the back-burner so that someone can divert money intended for <em>your</em> child?</p>
<p>The person your child is and how he/she learns and grows cannot be gauged by an answer bubbled onto a sheet of paper.  Your student deserves my full expertise, not a narrowed curriculum and hours devoted to my teaching to the test.  My colleagues and I deserve to be freed from the negative impact that the calculated teacher-bashing and union-bashing is having on our profession&#8230;because it is calculated, and by this point I don&#8217;t think I need to tell you by whom.</p>
<p>So please, educate yourself.  Have a voice in this issue.  Talk to teachers and administrators about what is happening in your child&#8217;s school as a result of America&#8217;s education reform; support teachers you know are there for your student; question media reports that claim there is a simple answer to so-called underperformance; and be aware of what is happening on a local and national level.  It is affecting <em>your</em> student . . . and it isn&#8217;t going away any time soon.</p>
<p>Sincerely,</p>
<p>Christine McCartney</p>
<p>To learn more:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/networkforpubliceducation" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">https://www.facebook.com/networkforpubliceducation</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.alecexposed.org/wiki/Privatizing_Public_Education,_Higher_Ed_Policy,_and_Teachers" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">http://www.alecexposed.org/wiki/Privatizing_Public_Education,_Higher_Ed_Policy,_and_Teachers</a></p>
<p><a href="http://dianeravitch.net/2013/01/03/get-title/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">http://dianeravitch.net/2013/01/03/get-title/</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/08/02/private-firms-eyeing-prof_n_1732856.html" rel="nofollow">http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/08/02/private-firms-eyeing-prof_n_1732856.html</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/alan-singer/pearson-education-profits_b_2902642.html?utm_hp_ref=fb&#038;src=sp&#038;comm_ref=false" rel="nofollow">http://www.huffingtonpost.com/alan-singer/pearson-education-profits_b_2902642.html?utm_hp_ref=fb&#038;src=sp&#038;comm_ref=false</a></p>
</div>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/140/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/140/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=140&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://christinemccartney.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/a-message-to-parents-from-your-childs-teacher/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>48</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/0205bb39853de61d0a7419ab0e3b6d50?s=96&#38;d=&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">christinemccartney</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Autistic Awareness, Accommodation, and Understanding</title>
		<link>http://eyesthroughtheglass.com/2013/03/26/the-role-of-government-autistic-awareness-accommodation-and-understanding/</link>
		<comments>http://eyesthroughtheglass.com/2013/03/26/the-role-of-government-autistic-awareness-accommodation-and-understanding/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 14:15:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dylan</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ableism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPChallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Prejudice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://eyesthroughtheglass.com/?p=6012</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This week&#8217;s writing challenge was so delightfully juicy that I couldn&#8217;t afford to pass it up. I could write pages upon pages about this topic, including my flirtation with libertarianism and then my subsequent falling out. But if any topic made the most sense it would be about the government&#8217;s role in autistic rights. Ableism [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=6012&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This week&#8217;s writing challenge was so delightfully juicy that I couldn&#8217;t afford to pass it up. I could write pages upon pages about this topic, including my flirtation with libertarianism and then my subsequent falling out.</p>
<p>But if any topic made the most sense it would be about the government&#8217;s role in autistic rights.</p>
<p><span id="more-6012"></span></p>
<p><strong>Ableism Lives</strong></p>
<p>It may be surprising, but autistic people don&#8217;t have large groups that will vouch for them. Many of the groups that are purported to be advocates of those with autism are more interested in curing autism than accepting those who have it.</p>
<p>Autism Speaks for example, views autism as a disease and has focused a large amount on researching the former notion of vaccines having a connection. This was discredited in what was known as the &#8220;autism omnibus trial&#8221;.</p>
<p>The prejudice I spoke of in earlier posts, ableism, still exists. In some ways, it is has grown. I was strolling around Facebook when one of my friends sent me this image:</p>
<p><a href="http://eyesthroughtheglass.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/disability-rights.png"><img class="size-full wp-image" id="i-6040" alt="Image" src="http://eyesthroughtheglass.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/disability-rights.png?w=350" /></a></p>
<p>Recently, a gay teen with Asperger&#8217;s was<a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/03/23/steven-simpson-gay-teen-burned-birthday-_n_2939092.html"> burned to death</a> at his own birthday party after being covered with tanning oil.  Anti-gay messages such as &#8220;I love dick&#8221; and &#8220;gay boy&#8221; were scrawled all over his body.</p>
<p>This also highlights a chilling intersection between the prejudices between those with Asperger&#8217;s and homosexuals.</p>
<p>And as in my case, I have not only been marginalized by my peers, but by my <a href="http://eyesthroughtheglass.com/2013/02/24/exodus-part-one/">own</a> <a href="http://eyesthroughtheglass.com/2013/02/25/exodus-part-two/">family</a>.</p>
<p><strong>A Source of Relief</strong></p>
<p>But of course, one may wonder what relevance this has to the government. That relevance lies in the fact that the government is really the only consistent form of assistance for us. It&#8217;s not perfect, but it&#8217;s certainly preferable to our treatment elsewhere.</p>
<p>In high school, it was not the benevolence of my private high school that allowed me success. It was the accommodation of my public high school.</p>
<p>In college, I was equally left to sink or swim in a system built for the mainstream. I had no anchors, and I came out miserably. Rest assured, I&#8217;m going to a school that takes much greater steps to accommodate.</p>
<p><strong>On Our Behalf</strong></p>
<p>It is heavily embedded in the American consciousness that the government exists primarily as an obstacle to greater individual success. I disagree with this notion.</p>
<p>I am not naive. I understand the shortcomings and problems within our government. However, I&#8217;d like to call attention to the fact that it is often forgotten that government has acted and can act on behalf of the compromised.</p>
<p> </p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/6012/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/6012/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=6012&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://eyesthroughtheglass.com/2013/03/26/the-role-of-government-autistic-awareness-accommodation-and-understanding/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/fe813491e9febac6ee9e00fdbee8215a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">arenejo</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://eyesthroughtheglass.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/disability-rights.png?w=350" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Everyone is Dancing Their Best Dance</title>
		<link>http://writeproject.wordpress.com/2013/03/08/one-of-the-most-valuable-lessons-i-ever-learned/</link>
		<comments>http://writeproject.wordpress.com/2013/03/08/one-of-the-most-valuable-lessons-i-ever-learned/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 13:33:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>blakehiemstra</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[school]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[acceptance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dancing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grace]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[teaching]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tolerance]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://writeproject.wordpress.com/?p=1126</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In order to become a teacher a college student is subjected to many well-meaning professors of education who fill the prospective instructor with all types of theorems and philosophies, ways of writing objectives and best-practice research.   And while I felt equipped by my education program to navigate the world of adolescents in the classroom, no [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1126&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In order to become a teacher a college student is subjected to many well-meaning professors of education who fill the prospective instructor with all types of theorems and philosophies, ways of writing objectives and best-practice research.   And while I felt equipped by my education program to navigate the world of adolescents in the classroom, no classroom teacher ever taught me more about kids than what I learned from a free-spirited, ex-hippie professor I had in grad school named Nancy Spejcher.</p>
<p>As far as professors go, she was about as far away from the wire-rimmed-glasses/leather-patch-on-the-blazer stereotype as one end of the rainbow is from the other.  She often eschewed the status quo, especially if toeing the company ever got in the way of caring for kids.  Quite simply she loved on kids in a way that sure inspired and challenged teachers.  One nugget of wisdom from her mouth has stuck with me, some eleven years later:</p>
<p><strong>&#8220;<em>Everyone is dancing the best dance that he or she can.&#8221;</em></strong></p>
<p>To buy in to this philosophy is to choose to think the best of kids, to extend grace in a way that they are not used to getting.  It means to drop the rocks of condemnation and use those arms to embrace. It means to refuse to snidely  pass judgment on the boy whose missing assignments are more routine than the morning newspaper.   To believe that the girl with the chip on her shoulder <em>is</em> truly dancing her best dance, instead of simply trying to bait me into the ring every day. To understand that maybe there&#8217;s a reason behind someone&#8217;s lack of productivity, and it&#8217;s not just pure laziness;  it&#8217;s because navigating a harrowing home-life requires just about every ounce of energy he can muster.</p>
<div id="attachment_1130" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 539px"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/cdunitz/5103378512/"><img class="size-full wp-image-1130" alt="Photo by Claudia Crane, Creative Commons" src="http://writeproject.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/tap-shoes-2.jpg?w=529&#038;h=705" width="529" height="705" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Photo by Claudia Crane, Creative Commons</p></div>
<p>It&#8217;s pretty easy to like the kids who are perfect, the kids whose educational pirouettes look sublime. What about the kid whose face comes to class with a permanent scowl?  Understanding that he&#8217;s dancing the best dance that he can might mean seeing that even his silent brooding in class is a lot better rumba than a spew of vitriol from his lips.</p>
<p>Granted, such an approach doesn&#8217;t merely tolerate everyone&#8217;s shortcomings with a pursed-lips pout of resignation.  No matter how spirited the waltz, improvement is always possible, especially if someone notices the dance and is willing to lead.  To believe in that possibility, to imagine the possibility of change, is to be fully human.  To join a student in the dance of life and lead him or her towards a new tomorrow is why teaching is a priceless endeavor.</p>
<div id="attachment_169" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 539px"><a href="http://writeproject.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/girls-dancing1.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-169" alt="Even with my own kids, I need to realize they're dancing with everything they've got. " src="http://writeproject.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/girls-dancing1.jpg?w=529&#038;h=350" width="529" height="350" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Even with my own kids, I need to realize they&#8217;re dancing with everything they&#8217;ve got.</p></div>
<p>Imagine what would happen if you approached everyone in your family or your office the same way.  Remember, it&#8217;s not about just summoning super-human levels of patience to deal with all the difficult people in your life.  It&#8217;s about giving the benefit of the doubt daily.  Maybe Janice from accounting&#8217;s constant negativity is enough to make you scratch the veneer off your desk . . . with your teeth.  Realizing that there&#8217;s more below the surface and that she&#8217;s dancing the best dance that she can might just give you the grace to lend a hand instead of throwing a stone.</p>
<p>Doing so might just make your change your own cha-cha.</p>
<p><em><strong>How could realizing this truth about people change your life today?  Who do you need to show a little more grace towards?</strong></em></p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://writeproject.wordpress.com/category/school/'>school</a>, <a href='http://writeproject.wordpress.com/category/tips/'>Tips</a>  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1126&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://writeproject.wordpress.com/2013/03/08/one-of-the-most-valuable-lessons-i-ever-learned/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/5d77eb18f8c785e17bb04653aaa165ca?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">blakehiemstra</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://writeproject.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/tap-shoes-2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Photo by Claudia Crane, Creative Commons</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://writeproject.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/girls-dancing1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Even with my own kids, I need to realize they&#039;re dancing with everything they&#039;ve got. </media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Displaying the Famous Political Dead</title>
		<link>http://bonesdontlie.wordpress.com/2013/03/28/displaying-the-famous-political-dead/</link>
		<comments>http://bonesdontlie.wordpress.com/2013/03/28/displaying-the-famous-political-dead/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 14:56:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Katy Meyers</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Funeral Practices]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[embalming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[funeral]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://bonesdontlie.wordpress.com/?p=2154</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Preservation of a body is an interesting phenomenon, whether it be the evanescent embalming at a funeral home to prevent the body from decaying at the wake, or preservation for hundreds of years as is the case with Rosalia Lombardo in the Palermo catacombs. Embalming is a three-fold process of sanitation, presentation and presentation. While the process [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2154&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://bonesdontlie.wordpress.com/2013/03/28/displaying-the-famous-political-dead/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://bonesdontlie.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/800px-embalming_fluid-e1364482574290.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://bonesdontlie.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/800px-embalming_fluid-e1364482574290.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">800px-Embalming_fluid</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/5b3585faa447df0bbcbda49d2e4199e7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bonesdontlie</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://bonesdontlie.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/800px-embalming_fluid-e1364482574290.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Embalming Chemicals, via Wikimedia</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://bonesdontlie.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/440996a-i1-0.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Lenin Preserved with his Embalmers, via Nature</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Sky Is Socked In with \&#8221;Shock and Awe\&#8221;</title>
		<link>http://carryingthegun.wordpress.com/2013/03/27/the-sky-is-socked-in-with-shock-and-awe-no-jump-tonight-mar-27-2003/</link>
		<comments>http://carryingthegun.wordpress.com/2013/03/27/the-sky-is-socked-in-with-shock-and-awe-no-jump-tonight-mar-27-2003/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 00:15:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Don</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[iraq ten years ago]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[82nd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[band of brothers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[combat jump device]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cruise missiles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fedayeen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fedayeen saddam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iraq]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iraq war]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kuwait]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mustard stain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shock and awe]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://carryingthegun.wordpress.com/?p=1467</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#160; Listen up! The channel coast is socked in with rain and fog. High winds in the drop zone. NO JUMP TONIGHT. The invasion has been postponed. We&#8217;re on a 24-hour stand-down. Scratch. The mission we had been rehearsing for over a month just got scratched. To get &#8220;scratched&#8221; is airborne parlance for cancelled. Our [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1467&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<blockquote><p>Listen up! The channel coast is socked in with rain and fog. High winds in the drop zone. NO JUMP TONIGHT. The invasion has been postponed. We&#8217;re on a 24-hour stand-down.</p></blockquote>
<p>Scratch.</p>
<p>The mission we had been rehearsing for over a month just got scratched. To get &#8220;scratched&#8221; is airborne parlance for cancelled. Our entire mission was cancelled. Hearts were broken, especially mine. I wanted that rarest of awards, the tiny yellow star, the infamous &#8216;mustard stain&#8217; &#8211; the combat jump device &#8211; affixed to my parachutist badge. That award required just about no talent or work. You simply had to be at the right place at the right time, like World War II, Grenada, or Panama.</p>
<p>With our mission cancelled, we waited in Kuwait, dodging scuds, playing dodgeball, sitting on cots listening to the BBC while the rest of military stormed towards Baghdad. Things were moving quickly, and the fear shifted from going to war to missing it completely.</p>
<p>Then, finally, we received a new mission. We would parachute into an open field outside of a small city called Samawah and secure the city to allow supplies to move forward to support the main elements pushing towards Baghdad. Elements of the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fedayeen_Saddam" target="_blank">Fedayeen Saddam </a>were conducting ambushes along Highway 8 which passed through Samawah.</p>
<p>When my squad leader pointed out the city and tentative drop zone I beamed. The Baghdad jump was seeming like it&#8217;d be a bloodbath. Plus, it would probably be a hard pavement landing &#8211; ouch. Now we were looking at a landing in the desert and an assault on a much smaller city &#8216;garrisoned&#8217; by a rag tag militia of fake ninjas.</p>
<p>We spent the 27th tearing down our camp and packing up our bags neatly on palettes. We got into lines and did a lot of sitting. Some of the guys in our platoon started writing quotes, prayers, missives, and plain nonsense on their t-shirts. Eventually someone from BN headquarters saw it and yelled at them, putting an end to it.</p>
<p>We waited for nightfall.</p>
<p>When it came, we sat and waited more.</p>
<p>Eventually we were told that we were on a 24 hour stand down. The skies were saturated with cruise missiles and someone was afraid we&#8217;d be knocked out of the air.</p>
<p>We scurried back into empty tents and found spots on the floor and slept. Our war wouldn&#8217;t start today.</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://carryingthegun.wordpress.com/category/iraq-ten-years-ago/'>iraq ten years ago</a> Tagged: <a href='http://carryingthegun.wordpress.com/tag/82nd/'>82nd</a>, <a href='http://carryingthegun.wordpress.com/tag/band-of-brothers/'>band of brothers</a>, <a href='http://carryingthegun.wordpress.com/tag/combat-jump-device/'>combat jump device</a>, <a href='http://carryingthegun.wordpress.com/tag/cruise-missiles/'>cruise missiles</a>, <a href='http://carryingthegun.wordpress.com/tag/fedayeen/'>fedayeen</a>, <a href='http://carryingthegun.wordpress.com/tag/fedayeen-saddam/'>fedayeen saddam</a>, <a href='http://carryingthegun.wordpress.com/tag/iraq/'>iraq</a>, <a href='http://carryingthegun.wordpress.com/tag/iraq-war/'>iraq war</a>, <a href='http://carryingthegun.wordpress.com/tag/kuwait/'>kuwait</a>, <a href='http://carryingthegun.wordpress.com/tag/mustard-stain/'>mustard stain</a>, <a href='http://carryingthegun.wordpress.com/tag/shock-and-awe/'>shock and awe</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1467/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1467/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1467&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://carryingthegun.wordpress.com/2013/03/27/the-sky-is-socked-in-with-shock-and-awe-no-jump-tonight-mar-27-2003/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/9e413dce97a6a11e6a436e1d6aa84ba9?s=96&#38;d=retro&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">dongomezjr</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Playing Fields</title>
		<link>http://litwist.wordpress.com/2013/02/13/playing-fields/</link>
		<comments>http://litwist.wordpress.com/2013/02/13/playing-fields/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2013 22:19:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lila</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Going Back to Innocence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Poetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bipolar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[February 11 2013]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[feminists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[literature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moving on]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[postaweek]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[singing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[suicides]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sylvia plath]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://litwist.wordpress.com/?p=1684</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I looked at the calendar last night and someone reminded me that the anniversary of your death had just passed. I thought anniversaries were supposed to be festive and jolly but there&#8217;s nothing to celebrate about you killing yourself. To tell you the truth, I think it&#8217;s just a way to test whether or not we&#8217;re [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1684&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://litwist.wordpress.com/2013/02/13/playing-fields/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>49</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/4520c477814957a8b058a6fb3fd67cf0?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">litwist</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://litwist.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/stop-by_large.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Playing Fields</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>68 Teams, 1 Dream: Why March Madness is Sheer Happiness</title>
		<link>http://sheridansshorts.com/2013/03/26/68-teams-1-dream-why-march-madness-is-sheer-happiness/</link>
		<comments>http://sheridansshorts.com/2013/03/26/68-teams-1-dream-why-march-madness-is-sheer-happiness/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 01:34:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>sheridad69</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Basketball]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[March Madness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NCAAM]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://sheridansshorts.com/?p=522</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[10 seconds left on the clock.  Tie ball game. 20,000 nervous fans, all on their feet, tensely await the start of the next play.  Hearts are pounding, palms are sweating, knees are shaking… this is the moment of truth.  After a long, hard-fought 39 minutes and 50 seconds of playing time, the game hangs in [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=522&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://sheridansshorts.com/2013/03/26/68-teams-1-dream-why-march-madness-is-sheer-happiness/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f3e5d90f98c62d304005dd1688e460d5?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sheridad69</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Love&#8217;s Leaver&#8217;s Lost</title>
		<link>http://boozeforthought.net/2013/03/19/loves-leavers-lost-2/</link>
		<comments>http://boozeforthought.net/2013/03/19/loves-leavers-lost-2/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 01:24:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Charles Hardwick</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Non-Fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cocktails]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lost and Found]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shakespeare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spirits]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://boozeforthought.net/?p=39</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Losing things can be a tremendous nuisance. There are the tangible losses that sting: a scarf, an umbrella or a cell phone. And the abstract losses: your innocence, your inhibitions, and perhaps, your self-respect as a result of several booze-induced bad decisions. Alone or accompanied, you wake up and wonder, “What was I thinking?” The [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=39&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Losing things can be a tremendous nuisance. There are the tangible losses that sting: a scarf, an umbrella or a cell phone. And the abstract losses: your innocence, your inhibitions, and perhaps, your self-respect as a result of several booze-induced bad decisions. Alone or accompanied, you wake up and wonder, “What was I thinking?” The bar is a place where you willfully go hoping to lose something intangible and perhaps unmentionable, while praying that your belongings and daily mentionables don’t tumble out of your purse or pocket along the way. After all, a hat or scarf can be replaced, but that favorite hat or scarf that you bought during that trip to Ireland, and all the memories associated with it, cannot. You walk through the door courting a kind of self-inflicted amnesia, and you do so at your peril. You wager on your future and the quality of your evening . Win big, lose small, and most of all, know when it’s time to go home.</p>
<p>The best bartenders know a lot about losses and gains. They recognize that the bar is a kind of casino where bets are placed; often by people who don’t even know what game they are playing.  In the abstract, you can win big in the form of closing a big business deal, or you can meet the love of your life. You can also come so painfully close to success with either that you will want to cry like a baby when it is suddenly snatched away from you.  We are the Croupier, the Pit Boss and Casino Manager all rolled into one. Things get lost or left behind, people spend far more than they intended to, and we dispassionately bear witness to all the comings and goings. When the item is something material, we store it, label it like an archivist and (usually) hope it gets back to it&#8217;s rightful owner. When it is something we covet however, this becomes more of a challenge. The woman whose shameless flirting seems to grow in direct proportion to her date’s lateness or dull conversation. The new iPad or digital camera someone left behind. These things can inspire no small amount of temptation. But I feel pretty secure in saying that our guilt at keeping an item from the lost and found directly corresponds to its material value. It is the cheap and mundane, the crass or comical things, neglected and easy to replace, that we consider fair game.</p>
<p>Take umbrellas for example. I haven’t bought an umbrella in twenty years. I’ve had all sorts come into my possession. At one point I counted an accumulated two dozen umbrellas in my apartment. I eventually gave most of them away and all but two I don’t have anymore. Why? Because I left them in a bar somewhere. Believe me, I am more likely to buy an Aston-Martin than I am to buy an umbrella.</p>
<p>I don’t smoke, but I have dozens of cigarette lighters. Bics and butanes, large, small, plastic, aluminum, I even have a $500 DuPont lighter that I probably should have sold on Ebay long ago. Scarves and jackets, a couple of amazing raincoats courtesy of the unclaimed lost and found bin; I could build a façade of accessories that would make Ian Fleming proud. But please don’t think me a thief or cold-blooded opportunist. In every one of these cases I have at least waited the requisite 2-4 weeks before taking possession of the orphaned items. I confess to being a bit of a calendar watcher on occasion, but at least as often, I have gone on the internet, or Facebook, and called credit card companies and told them to inform the card holder of their lost item.  Certainly, that lambs wool sweater feels far less itchy with a clear conscience.</p>
<p>Some things that get left behind are just plain weird. Opening a stranger&#8217;s bag can be akin to opening the prize packet inside a depraved box of Cracker Jacks. Someone once left a beautiful leather golf bag behind and upon opening it I discovered, among other things, a nice, but weathered dop kit that, along with the usual toiletries, contained a diabetics insulin testing kit and several syringes and medications. Worrying about the persons safety should they not get their meds, I scoured the bag for anything that might identify the owner, but to no avail. I was once haunted for months by a woman’s lost Korean passport with all sorts of difficult and complicated stamps and visas stapled in it. Try as I might, I couldn’t find her via the internet or any other source and she never called or returned for it. The documents are probably still in that office right now.</p>
<p>But it is the birthday parties that yield the most colorful left behinds. The half-consumed customized cakes, and tons of delicious designer pastries. Kooky balloons withering on their strings, the thoughtfully chosen oversized cards with scores of signatures that the drunken birthday celebrant completely forgot about. I once had a guy celebrate his birthday at my bar. Kinda hip looking in a Maroon 5 sort of way, he intended to move to a table but wound up having such a blast at the bar that he just stayed and reveled the night away as his friends continued to give him all sorts of various and sundry gifts. When he left, many of them were left behind in a bag (they were unwrapped) and a partial list included: an iPod Charger, a bottle of 1999 Dom Perignon, a bottle of K-Y warming lubricant, and an enormous 12” black dildo called “The Emperor.” I suspect the last item  may have explained his hesitancy in calling to retrieve them. We kept everything for quite a while until one day, the dildo mysteriously vanished along with a never-been-kissed Jehovah’s Witness cocktail waitress of ours. The timing may have been a coincidence, but at the end of the day, I’ll never know. I can only view it as the detritus of a night well enjoyed, that in some mysterious way, rippled outward and made a few lives better.</p>
<p>When the evening ends, the inventory of things lost and found can begin, and one hopes that they are only vague and ethereal. A few cares and inhibitions, perhaps a forgotten stop or two during your bar crawl.  This along with a few dollars and you can happily declare that you’ve at least broken even. If it’s a tooth or a pair of underwear, well, it still could’ve been worse. William Shakespeare must have just awakened after a long night out when he wrote, “Praising what is lost, makes the remembrance dear.”  Indeed. And if you’re lucky, we may just be holding on to it for you.</p>
<p><b>Cocktail Epilogue</b></p>
<p>The Casino Cocktail</p>
<p>2 parts Old Tom Gin</p>
<p>¼ part Maraschino liqueur</p>
<p>¼ part fresh lemon juice</p>
<p>2 dashes Orange bitters</p>
<p>Combine all ingredients along with ice in a cocktail shaker, shake vigorously and strain into a chilled cocktail glass. Garnish with a brandied Maraschino cherry.</p>
<p><i>Source: New Diners Club Drink Book, 1968, by Matty Simmons</i></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/39/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/39/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=39&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://boozeforthought.net/2013/03/19/loves-leavers-lost-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>21</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://boozeforthoughtdotnet.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/n503400088_1753798_3873.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://boozeforthoughtdotnet.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/n503400088_1753798_3873.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">n503400088_1753798_3873</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/3428b7315dc49b167a8e7ed2c464c988?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">charhard</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
