<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2012 01:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>What Happens When You Send Your Parents a Photo Scanner</title>
		<link>http://40isthenew13.wordpress.com/2012/08/22/to-view-this-image-from-1982-protective-eyewear-is-recommended/</link>
		<comments>http://40isthenew13.wordpress.com/2012/08/22/to-view-this-image-from-1982-protective-eyewear-is-recommended/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2012 10:37:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>40 is the new 13</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[40s]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nostalgia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[style and beauty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[teens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[1980s]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[roller skates]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adolescence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[puberty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Facts of Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[genetics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parents]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://40isthenew13.wordpress.com/?p=1413</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s 1982. Some visionary has just invented sneaker roller skates. We&#8217;re finally over disco. All the seventh grade girls are carrying battered copies of Flowers in the Attic or The Amityville Horror in their backpacks at school. Everybody&#8217;s saying, &#8220;They&#8217;re heeeerrre&#8230;&#8221; because Spielberg has just scared the pants off us with greedy developers building expensive [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1413&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em><strong>It&#8217;s 1982.</strong></em></p>
<p>Some visionary has just invented sneaker roller skates.</p>
<p>We&#8217;re finally over disco.</p>
<p>All the seventh grade girls are carrying battered copies of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flowers_in_the_Attic"><em>Flowers in the Attic</em></a> or <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kathy_Lutz"><em>The Amityville Horror</em></a> in their backpacks at school.</p>
<p>Everybody&#8217;s saying, <em>&#8220;They&#8217;re heeeerrre&#8230;&#8221;</em> because Spielberg has just scared the pants off us with greedy developers building expensive new houses on a cemetery. &#8220;<em>You only moved the headstones!&#8221;</em></p>
<p>This is also the year a theater manager tossed me out of a showing of <em>Dead Men Don&#8217;t Wear Plaid</em> for throwing popcorn into the projector beam<em>.  </em>(This was possibly due to anger at my mother, who wouldn&#8217;t let me attend the midnight screening of <em>The Rocky Horror Picture Show</em>.)</p>
<p>Although they claim to want the best for me, my parents allow me to wear fashions provided by my orthodontist. (My shirt has a cartoon beauty queen in braces with the slogan <em>Born to Smile</em>.  It came with another that says, <em>Kiss Me You Fool!</em>)</p>
<p>In addition, the front pieces of my hair have turned orange from flopping into the Clearasil on my forehead. Did you know it doubles as a hair lightener?</p>
<p>Before we proceed, let me offer one more piece of relevant information.  The man in the picture is my lovely dad.  He&#8217;s the one who sent me this jpeg.  He&#8217;s a brilliant research scientist and has never looked or behaved in a completely normal manner.  But he&#8217;s spent 40-years studying the actions of carbonic anhydrase and its inhibitors&#8230; so he&#8217;s entitled.</p>
<p>Let me just preface this with a warning.  You should probably shield your eyes in some way before viewing this image more closely.  Get a pair of very dark sunglasses. Or maybe turn your back to the monitor and, using a hand mirror, view <em>only the reflection</em>.  That way it won&#8217;t permanently damage your eyes.  Your emotional health is another matter.</p>
<p>So let&#8217;s don our protective gear and take a deep breath&#8230;</p>
<p><a href="http://40isthenew13.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/jen-and-dad-on-roller-skates-small-31.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-1415" title="Jen and Dad on roller skates SMALL-3" src="http://40isthenew13.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/jen-and-dad-on-roller-skates-small-31.jpg?w=702&h=1024" alt="" width="702" height="1024" /></a></p>
<p>Are you still conscious?  Are your corneas intact?  Can you see and interpret the following message?</p>
<p>I AM VERY VERY VERY SORRY FOR SUBJECTING YOU TO THIS.</p>
<ul>
<li>If you can both decipher and understand the previous line, please continue.</li>
<li>If damage to your optic nerve and/or left brain make comprehension impossible, please delete this post and seek immediate medical attention.</li>
</ul>
<p>There are a number of possible interpretations of what you&#8217;ve just seen.</p>
<ul>
<li>Again (and I beat a dead horse)&#8230; but 1982.</li>
<li>&#8220;That awkward stage&#8221; was something I considered a personal style choice.</li>
<li>My life was actually a social experiment conducted by the creators of every teen movie, sitcom or dramedy to come. Seen &#8220;The Middle&#8221; on ABC?  I think this is how they came up with <a href="http://abc.go.com/shows/the-middle/bio/sue-heck/274017">Sue Heck.</a></li>
</ul>
<p><a href="http://40isthenew13.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/screen-shot-2012-08-21-at-6-47-22-pm1.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1418" title="Screen shot 2012-08-21 at 6.47.22 PM" src="http://40isthenew13.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/screen-shot-2012-08-21-at-6-47-22-pm1.jpg" alt="" width="91" height="108" /></a>     <a href="http://40isthenew13.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/screen-shot-2012-08-21-at-6-49-27-pm.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1421" title="Screen shot 2012-08-21 at 6.49.27 PM" src="http://40isthenew13.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/screen-shot-2012-08-21-at-6-49-27-pm.jpg" alt="" width="82" height="109" /></a></p>
<p>Fortunately, even a Sue Heck can turn out relatively alright.</p>
<p>This is where I need to commend my husband for not meeting me until 1994 (by which time I&#8217;d completed a long, intense reinvention process), and for diluting the geek DNA that my progenitors passed down like a family bible.</p>
<p>Thanks to him, the kids seem completely normal.</p>
<ul>
<li>Their hair would not look inappropriate at a social event.</li>
<li>Their faces are shiny in the non-Clearasil way.</li>
<li>They appear to understand clothing has an aesthetic aspect.</li>
<li>They frequently pat my shoulder and say, &#8220;Poor Mommy.&#8221;</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="http://40isthenew13.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_8855.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1424" title="DSC_8855" src="http://40isthenew13.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_8855.jpg" alt="" width="440" height="294" /></a></p>
<p>There&#8217;s more to discuss.</p>
<p>Just because the universe gets a kick out of messing with us, this particular jpeg from my dad arrived the same morning that I purchased a DVD set of the first two seasons of <em>The Facts of Life</em> at Best Buy.  (The Geek Squad was repairing my laptop and it was a long wait.  I also purchased <em>Home Alone 2</em>.)</p>
<p>Popping a disc into the player was like time travel. Not just the earworm theme song.  But Mr. Bradley! Remember him?  The Headmaster of Eastland School?</p>
<p><a href="http://40isthenew13.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/thumbnail-aspx7.jpeg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1430" title="thumbnail.aspx" src="http://40isthenew13.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/thumbnail-aspx7.jpeg" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a></p>
<p>I couldn&#8217;t tell you what Jonas Salk looked like, or James Madison or even Robert Reich.  But this man&#8230; like the back of my hand.</p>
<p>After thirty years I could close my eyes and conjure an exact mental image of the dude who tried to make it with Blair&#8217;s mother.  (Who was <em>divorced</em>! Shhhhh&#8230;. controversy!)</p>
<p>So though I inherited a lot from my father, you now see I didn&#8217;t get the full brilliance.  My dad passed along the nerdy TV sitcom punchline chromosomes but not the equally nerdy <em>Manhattan Project</em> ones.  This is the equivalent of having Groucho Marx as your father, and inheriting the moustache and eyebrows without the wit and comic timing.</p>
<ul>
<li>So I watched <em>The Facts of Life</em> instead of doing my algebra homework.</li>
<li>I thought skates with jeans looked totally bitchin&#8217; to the max.</li>
<li>I&#8217;ve still got this place inside my head where it&#8217;s always 1982 and I&#8217;m wheeling around the driveway thinking what a great movie <em>Grease 2 </em>was.  (I have it on DVD, also.)</li>
</ul>
<p>If I ever get a concussion, I&#8217;ll probably come to as a 13-year-old with a crush on Troy MacArthur.  (Who didn&#8217;t know I existed until I screwed up the courage to call him on the phone <em><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VFZrmUnWYzM">during the 1983 Superbowl. </a>  </em>I didn&#8217;t know it was on. My parents were unaware of football.  He didn&#8217;t like me back.)</p>
<p>But I&#8217;ve finally accepted that all this defines the kid I was and the person I am.  Don&#8217;t you think our identities are forged in childhood? Isn&#8217;t that the consensus these days? Isn&#8217;t there a child still inside of you?</p>
<p>If I live to be a hundred years old, I&#8217;ll still have a Sue Heck fighting to get out.</p>
<p>But with some coaching, fashion advice and a little plastic surgery&#8230; she has definitely improved.  She&#8217;s got a good role model.  My dad got rid of that shirt, bought new glasses, and hardly ever wears that hat anymore.  Better yet, he&#8217;s got an incredibly good heart.  He sent this jpeg with the warning, &#8220;Don&#8217;t show this to anyone.&#8221;  Which I suppose suggests he&#8217;s brilliant in more areas than just carbonic anhydrase&#8230; and my missteps (fashion, algebra or otherwise) are probably my own.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s why my lovely, affectionate kids just keep patting my arm and saying, &#8220;Poor Mommy.&#8221;</p>
<p>And I love them all for being so forgiving.  I mean, really.</p>
<p>Just take one more look at that picture.</p>
<p>Remember to close this page before removing your protective goggles.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1413/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1413/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1413&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://40isthenew13.wordpress.com/2012/08/22/to-view-this-image-from-1982-protective-eyewear-is-recommended/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/2ded95bd2e1c092634a19eb38ff3e314?s=96&#38;d=&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">40isthenew13</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://40isthenew13.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/jen-and-dad-on-roller-skates-small-31.jpg?w=702" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Jen and Dad on roller skates SMALL-3</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://40isthenew13.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/screen-shot-2012-08-21-at-6-47-22-pm1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen shot 2012-08-21 at 6.47.22 PM</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://40isthenew13.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/screen-shot-2012-08-21-at-6-49-27-pm.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen shot 2012-08-21 at 6.49.27 PM</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://40isthenew13.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_8855.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_8855</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://40isthenew13.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/thumbnail-aspx7.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">thumbnail.aspx</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Post Challenge: Needles</title>
		<link>http://menomama3.wordpress.com/2012/08/22/needles/</link>
		<comments>http://menomama3.wordpress.com/2012/08/22/needles/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2012 01:34:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>menomama3</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[DPchallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[knitting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parenting]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://menomama3.wordpress.com/?p=203</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[At first it wasn’t about the needles. I wanted to be productive while sitting with my daughter as she did her homework. She didn’t really need me there but my presence was wanted for moral support so how could I say no? The difficulty is that I am a fidgeter. I find it impossible to [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=203&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At first it wasn’t about the needles. I wanted to be productive while sitting with my daughter as she did her homework. She didn’t really need me there but my presence was wanted for moral support so how could I say no? The difficulty is that I am a fidgeter. I find it impossible to sit still and moral support no matter how vociferously provided is an inactive, passive role. My legs would twitch, my toes tap, my butt shift in the chair and I would exude irritability with every movement. I needed something to do in between the regular dishing up of “You’re doing great, kiddo!”</p>
<p>So I learned to knit. I didn’t give a stitch about the tools and thus the first needles I chose were cheap, ugly, cheap, grey plastic. Did I mention cheap? <a href="http://menomama3.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/greyneedles2.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-211" title="Greyneedles" src="http://menomama3.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/greyneedles2.jpg" alt="" width="225" height="225" /></a>I was trying to be frugal. It seemed fitting that the frugality was embodied in utilitarian, grey, straight needles. They were slippery, long, unwieldy beasts, too. The Ford-150 of needles. They caught under my arms, my elbows pointed straight to the side like I was about to start the “chicken dance” and my shoulders bunched up. I couldn’t sit close to my daughter because I took up too much space. The real kicker though was the yarn would slide off the needles too easily and as a beginning knitter I was frequently dropping stitches, causing me to cuss under my breath. But that’s another story.</p>
<p>The knitting intelligentsia at my local wool store suggested circular needles. These are petite versions of their gawky straight cousins, joined by a cable so you never lose one and have to buy a new set. Next I discovered bamboo needles.<a href="http://menomama3.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/clover_takumi_bamboo_circular_needles2800201011.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-212" title="Clover_Takumi_Bamboo_Circular_Needles28002010[1]" src="http://menomama3.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/clover_takumi_bamboo_circular_needles2800201011.jpg?w=300&h=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" /></a> I was working on a shrug using soft, chunky, pure wool in a luscious deep maroon; it stuck to the wooden implement like sap to a tree trunk. I had to shove the work so forcefully along that the joint in my pointer finger became sore. It was my first knitting repetitive strain injury.<a href="http://menomama3.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/sueshrug1.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-213" title="SueShrug" src="http://menomama3.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/sueshrug1.jpg?w=224&h=300" alt="" width="224" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>I made a sweet discovery on my last project. Standing in front of the vast array of needles in my local wool dealer I turned to the left and there on a smaller wall was a display of exquisite, highly polished, delicate wooden sticks. These were circulars with class, the Donatella Versace of knitting implements. Style, elegance, pizzaz formed into glossy, elegant accessories. The stitches float along these beauties and I am hypnotized by the sensuous flash of polished wood winking underneath the slowly growing garment almost longing for decreasing stitches so that more of the dainty wood is exposed. My hands softly finger the tool feeling the slip and glide that urges me forward in the project. The sweater seems to assemble itself using these delights. The only problem now is I need to find a yarn worthy of the tool. I yearn for the right yarn.<a href="http://menomama3.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/circular20knitting20needles2080cm-2012-500x50011.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-214" title="circular%20knitting%20needles%2080cm.2012-500x500[1]" src="http://menomama3.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/circular20knitting20needles2080cm-2012-500x50011.jpg?w=300&h=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>As for my daughter and her homework, well, she has moved on and become quite successfully independent and responsible in tackling her school work. And I? I have a new obsession. Needles.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/203/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/203/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=203&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://menomama3.wordpress.com/2012/08/22/needles/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/23aa4b152bd43a35fd9b418597312d2f?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">menomama3</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://menomama3.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/greyneedles2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Greyneedles</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://menomama3.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/clover_takumi_bamboo_circular_needles2800201011.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Clover_Takumi_Bamboo_Circular_Needles28002010[1]</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://menomama3.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/sueshrug1.jpg?w=224" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">SueShrug</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://menomama3.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/circular20knitting20needles2080cm-2012-500x50011.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">circular%20knitting%20needles%2080cm.2012-500x500[1]</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Tribute to Julia Child</title>
		<link>http://laughcooklove.wordpress.com/2012/08/22/a-tribute-to-julia/</link>
		<comments>http://laughcooklove.wordpress.com/2012/08/22/a-tribute-to-julia/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2012 01:54:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>stellacarolyn</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[dessert]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Grandma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Grandpa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[history]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Julia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[someone else's idea]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://laughcooklove.wordpress.com/?p=2299</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As mentioned here, August 15, 2012 would have been Julia Child&#8217;s 100th birthday.  I&#8217;ve mentioned this before, my grandparents were friendly with the Childs.  They bought wine from my grandfather in his store and my grandmother and Julia knew each other through a few gourmet cooking groups. One of my prize possessions is framed and [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2299&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As mentioned <a href="http://laughcooklove.wordpress.com/2012/08/15/happy-birthday-julia/">here</a>, August 15, 2012 would have been Julia Child&#8217;s 100th birthday.  I&#8217;ve mentioned this before, my grandparents were friendly with the Childs.  They bought wine from my grandfather in his store and my grandmother and Julia knew each other through a few gourmet cooking groups.</p>
<p>One of my prize possessions is framed and hanging in my kitchen.  It&#8217;s a letter written to my grandmother a few months before her death.  My grandfather had reached out to Julia to let her know that Grandma was sick so she wrote to her in response.</p>
<p><a href="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/photo-51.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-2336" title="photo 5" src="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/photo-51.jpg?w=225&h=300" alt="" width="225" height="300" /></a>It&#8217;s a bit hard to read so I&#8217;ll re-type it here:  &#8220;Dear Grace, Just a little note to wish you well.  Myron tells me that you have been having a mean rotten time.  No fun!  Things have been going well with me, thank heaven, and we&#8217;ve a new television series on Public TV starting in October- hope you&#8217;ll see it.  On baking this time- breads, brioches, gooey chocolate cakes and all kind of good things.  Not fattening if you keep to small helpings.  Here&#8217;s wishing you all the best, and sending you my love- Julia Child.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sadly, my grandmother died almost exactly a month later so she never saw the baking series (it was Baking With Julia).  I found that letter years later when I was going through stuff at our house.  My grandfather had saved it, along with this bill of sale from his store:</p>
<div id="attachment_2335" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 240px"><a href="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/photo-31.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-2335" title="photo 3" src="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/photo-31.jpg?w=230&h=300" alt="" width="230" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Julia and Paul loved their wine!</p></div>
<p>You&#8217;d think with these letters and the connections that I&#8217;d remember Julia Child.  I do not.  I recall <em>tall</em> and that&#8217;s about it.  I feel connected to her, nonetheless.</p>
<p>As a tribute to Julia and her 100th birthday, a friend and I planned a dinner party composed of her dishes.  My friend made her Beouf Bourguignon, roasted brussel sprouts and potatoes with parsley.  It was all delicious and when we were done, there were no leftovers.  My friend will guest blog that one soon.  It was a meal worthy of Julia- several bottles of wine, lots of laughter and so much good food.</p>
<p>I was in charge of dessert so I made Julia&#8217;s Bombe aux Trois Chocolats.  It&#8217;s a large chocolate cake filled with chocolate mousse and topped with chocolate ganache.  Incredibly rich and decadent.</p>
<p>While the recipes themselves aren&#8217;t complicated, they are a bit time-consuming due to all the steps.  I did mine over the course of two days.  I suppose you could do it all in one day but I think you&#8217;d need the whole day.  The recipes are really three separate things plus one set of instructions for putting it all together.  As usual, I ended up putting my own twist on this for reasons I&#8217;ll explain as we go.  Rather than making one whole cake, I made individual ones.  Either way, it&#8217;s a delicious way to end a meal.</p>
<p><strong>Kate&#8217;s Great Chocolate Fudge Cake</strong></p>
<p><strong>Ingredients</strong></p>
<p>1 stick (4oz) of unsalted butter</p>
<p>4 ounces of unsweetened chocolate</p>
<p>1 more stick of unsalted butter</p>
<p>2 cups white sugar</p>
<p>3 large eggs</p>
<p>1 teaspoon vanilla extract</p>
<p>1/2 teaspoon salt</p>
<p>1 cup of white, all purpose flour</p>
<p>*For this you will need a jelly-roll (sheet) pan, 11 x 17 inches</p>
<p><strong>Instructions:</strong></p>
<p>Pre-heat your oven to 350 degrees.  Butter (or spray) your jelly roll pan and line it with parchment paper.  Leave about two inches hanging over the edge of the pan.  Then butter and flour your parchment. I actually just sprayed mine with baking spray.  It worked just fine.</p>
<p>Make sure to use good quality chocolate.</p>
<p><a href="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3683.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-2302" title="IMG_3683" src="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3683.jpg?w=300&h=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" /></a>Melt it with the butter in a double boiler.  Julia says to have about 2-3 inches of water in the bottom of the double boiler and to let it simmer (over low heat).  This will let the chocolate in the top part melt slowly, without scorching.</p>
<p><a href="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3685.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-2304" title="IMG_3685" src="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3685.jpg?w=300&h=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" /></a>Combine the butter and the sugar.  Julia actually offers three different ways to do this in her book- by hand, in a mixer or in a food processor.  I chose to use the mixer.</p>
<p><a href="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3684.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-2303" title="IMG_3684" src="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3684.jpg?w=300&h=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" /></a>Once the butter and sugar is sort of light and fluffy, add the eggs one by one and mix well.  <a href="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3686.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-2305" title="IMG_3686" src="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3686.jpg?w=300&h=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" /></a>Add the vanilla and salt.  Then stir in the yummy melted chocolate/butter mixture.</p>
<p><a href="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3688.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-2306" title="IMG_3688" src="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3688.jpg?w=300&h=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" /></a>Don&#8217;t taste the chocolate mixture- remember that it&#8217;s unsweetened chocolate.  Mix it well.</p>
<p><a href="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3689.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-2307" title="IMG_3689" src="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3689.jpg?w=300&h=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" /></a>Add the flour (Julia says to do it in thirds but I will admit that I just dumped it all in, lazy cook that I am) and mix well.</p>
<p><a href="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3690.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-2308" title="IMG_3690" src="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3690.jpg?w=300&h=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" /></a>Pour it into the sheet pan and spread it evenly.</p>
<p><a href="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3691.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-2309" title="IMG_3691" src="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3691.jpg?w=300&h=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" /></a>Bake for 25 minutes on the middle rack of the oven.  It should be set but the top should be spongy.  A toothpick inserted in the middle should come out with a few crumbs on it.  It&#8217;s important that it not overcook- you need it to be chewy for texture in the dessert and you need it to be bendy in order to assemble it.</p>
<p>When you take it out to cool, let it sit in the pan for 10 minutes.  Then turn the pan upside down over a cake rack and unmold the cake, gently.  Peel off the parchment and let it cool at least 10 more minutes.  Since I&#8217;d made mine the day before, I wrapped it tightly in plastic wrap and kept it in the fridge overnight.  Before I used it the next day, I let it come to room temperature.</p>
<p><strong>Chocolate Mousse (Chocolate Mougins)</strong></p>
<p><strong>Ingredients</strong></p>
<p>12 ounces semisweet chocolate</p>
<p>1 1/2 ounces unsweetened chocolate</p>
<p>2 1/2 teaspoons plain unflavored gelatin (this was about a packet and a half of the kind I bought)</p>
<p>3 Tablespoons Dark rum, cognac or bourbon whiskey (I used Godiva chocolate liquor)</p>
<p>3 large eggs</p>
<p>2 egg whites (about 4 Tablespoons)</p>
<p>1 1/2 cups heavy cream</p>
<p>1 1/2 Tablespoons vanilla extract</p>
<p>large pinch of salt</p>
<p>3 Tablespoons white sugar</p>
<p><strong>Directions</strong></p>
<p>Break up the two chocolates and place them in the top of a double boiler.</p>
<p><a href="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3693.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-2310" title="IMG_3693" src="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3693.jpg?w=300&h=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" /></a>Meanwhile, pour the gelatin into a small bowl and pour the liquor over it.  Let it sit while you do the rest and it will soften.  Soften means it will start looking like this:</p>
<p><a href="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3697.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-2314" title="IMG_3697" src="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3697.jpg?w=300&h=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>and end looking like this:</p>
<p><a href="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3701.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-2318" title="IMG_3701" src="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3701.jpg?w=300&h=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>So the chocolate is melting, the gelatin is setting.  Time to get the rest of the mousse going.  Separate the eggs, putting the whites into a mixing bowl and the yolks into a saucepan.</p>
<p><a href="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3694.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-2311" title="IMG_3694" src="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3694.jpg?w=300&h=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" /></a>Beat the yolks with a whisk until they are thick and sticky.</p>
<p><a href="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3695.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-2312" title="IMG_3695" src="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3695.jpg?w=300&h=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" /></a>Then add the cream and stir it slowly over low heat.  It is important not to let come to a boil or else it will curdle.  If this happens to you, according to <a href="http://carrietracy.blogspot.com/">the hippo</a>, you can strain it and no one will be the wiser.  (I think that Julia would have liked that tip.)<a href="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3700.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-2317" title="IMG_3700" src="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3700.jpg?w=300&h=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" /></a>Julia has all kinds of tips to know when the custard is ready.  None of them have worked for me in general.  The only one that sort of works for me is to let it coat the back of the spoon.  Or to let it heat to 156-185 degrees Farenheit.  Either way, immediately remove it from the heat and stir it for a minute so that it stops cooking.</p>
<p>Stir the gelatin into the custard.  It will be in one big lump (actually one big shape of whatever it was in) but keep stirring and it will melt into the custard.  Once it has dissolved into the custard, add vanilla and then the melted chocolate.</p>
<p><a href="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3704.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-2319" title="IMG_3704" src="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3704.jpg?w=300&h=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>Beat the eggs whites (remember them from earlier?) with a mixer at slow speed until they get foamy.  Then add the salt and increase the speed to fast.  Keep beating until the egg whites form soft peaks.  Add the sugar and beat more, until the egg whites are forming stiff, shiny peaks.</p>
<div id="attachment_2320" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3705.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-2320" title="IMG_3705" src="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3705.jpg?w=300&h=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The magic of egg whites, they go from this&#8230;.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_2321" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3706.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-2321" title="IMG_3706" src="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3706.jpg?w=300&h=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">&#8230;.to this. Cooking magic!</p></div>
<p>Fold these egg whites into the chocolate mixture.  Gently, so as to keep as much of the air as possible. Cover the mousse and put it in the fridge to set.  It should be soft but not runny.</p>
<p><a href="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3714.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-2329" title="IMG_3714" src="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3714.jpg?w=300&h=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" /></a><strong>Chocolate Ganache for topping</strong></p>
<p>I improvised a bit here.  Julia uses the same chocolate as the mousse, recipe, melted and drizzled over.  I made a ganache, using the ratio of 3 parts chocolate to 1 part cream.  This means I heated 1 cup of cream over low heat to just under the boiling point and then added 3 cups of milk chocolate (good quality please) chips.  I let it sit off the heat and then whisked it together until smooth.</p>
<p><strong>Putting it all together</strong></p>
<p>Ok so this is where I drove myself a little bit nuts.  Julia calls for a 6 cup bowl, about 8 inches in top diameter.  She says that you could use a charlotte mold &#8220;or even a flowerpot could be used, of course, and either is fine because they are both tall enough for drama.&#8221;  I found a bowl that fit the requirements and lined it with plastic wrap as Julia instructed.</p>
<div id="attachment_2322" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3707.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-2322" title="IMG_3707" src="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3707.jpg?w=300&h=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">One of my favorite bowls, given to me at my wedding by a dear Irish friend.</p></div>
<p>Then it was time to cut out the template.  Julia suggests that you cut out a template using parchment paper so that you know how to cut the cake to line the bowl.  I am  not exaggerating when I tell you that I worked on this for a solid half an hour.  Let&#8217;s just say that I am not spatially gifted.</p>
<div id="attachment_2323" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3708.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-2323" title="IMG_3708" src="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3708.jpg?w=300&h=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">This was the aftermath after a half hour of working on the template. Again, not spatially gifted.</p></div>
<p>I did finally end up with a template that fit the bowl.</p>
<p><a href="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3709.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-2324" title="IMG_3709" src="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3709.jpg?w=300&h=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" /></a>But when I tried it on the cake, I couldn&#8217;t see how I was going to have enough cake.  At all.  Aside from the pieces pictured above, I also needed one to &#8220;cap&#8221; the cake- a round piece the same diameter as the bowl.  I thought for a bit and then decided that I could make individual ones in ramekins.  The best part about that?  I didn&#8217;t really need a template.  Though, I did make one- it was slightly easier than the large bowl.  Not much but slightly.</p>
<p><a href="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3710.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-2325" title="IMG_3710" src="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3710-e1345686095720.jpg?w=300&h=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" /></a>So, this is where Julia and I diverged.  If you want to make one big cake, I hardily recommend you consult her recipe because her instructions for the template are good.  Unless you&#8217;re me.  The steps are sort of the same, small or big.</p>
<p>Line each ramekin with plastic wrap.  Place a circular piece of cake on the bottom, good side out (it&#8217;s going to be the top of the cake so make it pretty).</p>
<p><a href="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3711.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-2326" title="IMG_3711" src="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3711.jpg?w=300&h=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" /></a>Then line the sides.  The cake will sort of squish together, kind of like making pie dough.  Keep the edges of the cake at or just below the edge of the container.</p>
<p><a href="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3712.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-2327" title="IMG_3712" src="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3712.jpg?w=300&h=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>Fill with mousse.</p>
<p><a href="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3716.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-2331" title="IMG_3716" src="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3716.jpg?w=300&h=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>Top with another circle of cake, sort of pushing down in order to keep the mousse inside.</p>
<p><a href="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3713.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-2328" title="IMG_3713" src="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3713.jpg?w=300&h=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>Wrap in plastic wrap (I just pulled up the sides that were overhanging) and put into the fridge to set.  Let them set for six hours or overnight.</p>
<p>When you&#8217;re ready to serve, whip up some cream, make or heat up your ganache and then get ready to unmold.  Unwrap the plastic from the top and then place a plate over the opening.  Flip the ramekin over and tap it.  It should come out- you may have to wiggle the plastic wrap a bit.  Peel the plastic wrap off and you should be left with a little chocolate bomb.</p>
<p>Top with the ganache, chopped nuts or sliced strawberries.</p>
<p><a href="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3721.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-2333" title="IMG_3721" src="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3721.jpg?w=300&h=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>There you have it!</p>
<p>Happy birthday Julia.  You are missed.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2299/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2299/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2299&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://laughcooklove.wordpress.com/2012/08/22/a-tribute-to-julia/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f702cf0780d7fa95db3a86588ea2ce8e?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">stellacarolyn</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/photo-51.jpg?w=225" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">photo 5</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/photo-31.jpg?w=230" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">photo 3</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3683.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_3683</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3685.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_3685</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3684.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_3684</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3686.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_3686</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3688.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_3688</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3689.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_3689</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3690.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_3690</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3691.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_3691</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3693.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_3693</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3697.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_3697</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3701.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_3701</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3694.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_3694</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3695.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_3695</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3700.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_3700</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3704.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_3704</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3705.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_3705</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3706.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_3706</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3714.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_3714</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3707.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_3707</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3708.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_3708</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3709.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_3709</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3710-e1345686095720.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_3710</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3711.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_3711</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3712.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_3712</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3716.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_3716</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3713.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_3713</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://laughcooklove.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3721.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_3721</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Post Challenge: The Life and Death of a Chocolate Bar</title>
		<link>http://zenscribbles.wordpress.com/2012/08/23/the-life-and-death-of-a-chocolate-bar/</link>
		<comments>http://zenscribbles.wordpress.com/2012/08/23/the-life-and-death-of-a-chocolate-bar/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2012 08:20:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Zen</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Inanity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chocolate bar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPchallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[white chocolate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing challenge]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://zenscribbles.wordpress.com/?p=737</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I see her prowling the aisles, trying to decide what her pick of the day. She comes in here three or four times a week for a sugar fix, usually after she returns from her job. She looks tired, but her eyes gleam as they run over the shiny wrappers. She takes her sweet time [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=737&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I see her prowling the aisles, trying to decide what her pick of the day. She comes in here three or four times a week for a sugar fix, usually after she returns from her job. She looks tired, but her eyes gleam as they run over the shiny wrappers. She takes her sweet time deciding what to buy. You can almost see her calculating and weighing the options in her head.</p>
<p>&#8220;Pick me! Look at me!&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;No, pick me! I&#8217;m nougat and caramel and peanuts!&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Pft. Who likes peanuts? She wants walnuts and raisins!&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Oh, you guys, you know she wants a piece of lil&#8217; white me.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Oh <em>shut up</em>. Everyone knows white chocolate isn&#8217;t really chocolate.&#8221;*</p>
<p><span id="more-737"></span></p>
<p>The candy bars do this every day, even though they know that she can&#8217;t really hear them. I, however, maintain my silence. I know she&#8217;s not going to pick me. It&#8217;s been months since she spared a look in my direction, so there&#8217;s no reason why she should start noticing me now. I&#8217;m but a boring old Twix.</p>
<p>She reaches out for a Mars bar (&#8220;Yay!&#8221;). Her hand hovers over the box for a moment before she lets it drop back to her side, amidst groans from the Mars bar and cheers from the other candy bars. She sighs and  scrutinizes the shelves some more as she walks up and down the length of the aisle. Suddenly she stops and frowns&#8230; at<em> me</em>. Then her eyes light up in recognition, as if she&#8217;d been reunited with a long-lost friend. Her fingers close around me without a second thought.</p>
<p>Mars is highly affronted. &#8220;<em>Seriously? </em>You ditch <em>me</em> for <em>Twix</em>?&#8221;</p>
<p>I personally can&#8217;t believe it myself. I don&#8217;t believe it even after she pays for me and leaves the store. I keep thinking she&#8217;ll have a change of heart and go back to return me, but she only sticks me in her hand bag and takes me home. It&#8217;s dark and crowded and stuffy in the bag, and I worry that I may become bruised &#8211; or worse, melted &#8211; and she&#8217;ll never want to eat me. I don&#8217;t know how long I stay in there, but eventually she opens it and takes me out.</p>
<p>She slowly tears my golden wrapping and pushes up one of my fingers. I feel a shiver of excitement. This is it. I&#8217;m finally going to achieve my purpose in life. I feel no pain as she sinks her teeth into me; <em>au contraire</em>, I feel absolute bliss. This is only heightened when she says, &#8220;Oh wow, I&#8217;ve forgotten how good Twix tastes.&#8221;</p>
<p>I can now die happy.</p>
<p>&#8212;-</p>
<p><em><strong>* For the record, I do believe white chocolate is chocolate. The views of the chocolate bars are in no way related to my own.<br />
</strong></em></p>
<p><em><strong>This is my response to the Weekly Writing Challenge on WP, which you can find <a href="http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2012/08/20/passive-voice-challenge/">here</a>. It&#8217;s been a while since I did any writing challenges, but I&#8217;ve always loved writing about inanimate objects! Let me know what you think. <img src='http://s0.wp.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif' alt=':D' class='wp-smiley' /><br />
</strong></em></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/737/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/737/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=737&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://zenscribbles.wordpress.com/2012/08/23/the-life-and-death-of-a-chocolate-bar/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>19</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/04a2739f2c9d1450ed885541d40230ca?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">zenscribbles</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8220;Best&#8221; vs. &#8220;Favorite&#8221; &#8211; or, Apples vs. Oranges</title>
		<link>http://cheezblog.com/2012/08/23/best-vs-favorite-or-apples-vs-oranges/</link>
		<comments>http://cheezblog.com/2012/08/23/best-vs-favorite-or-apples-vs-oranges/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2012 02:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ziggy</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Movies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rants]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[AFI]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Best]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Citizen Kane]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Favorite]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sight & Sound]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Ten]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vertigo]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cheezblog.com/?p=51</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Recently, “Sight &#38; Sound” revised its list of the Top Ten Movies of All Time, with Alfred Hitchcock’s Vertigo ousting the venerable Orson Welles classic Citizen Kane from the top spot.  (A spot that Kane still holds in the most recent American Film Institute poll, for now.)  To some, this is blasphemy (for to them, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=51&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Recently, “Sight &amp; Sound” revised its list of the Top Ten Movies of All Time, with Alfred Hitchcock’s <em>Vertigo</em> ousting the venerable Orson Welles classic <em>Citizen Kane</em> from the top spot.  (A spot that <em>Kane</em> still holds in the most recent American Film Institute poll, for now.)  To some, this is blasphemy (for to them, nothing can best <em>Kane,</em> ever), whereas to others, it’s about time.</p>
<p>To me, it just signifies a conversation starter.</p>
<p>See, I simply don’t believe that it’s possible to objectively call any film “The Best of All Time.”  A group of films, perhaps; I think it’s possible to come up with a list of a few dozen essentials (ten is simply not enough) that exemplify the art of filmmaking, but an ordered list where each is better than the last and the top spot can only be occupied by one film?  No.</p>
<p>The first problem with this idea is that filmmaking is an <em>art,</em> not a science.  It’s not like (most) math where there’s only one perfect answer and it can be arrived at through objective reasoning; it is, instead, a very subjective thing about which an infinite number of opinions can be correct, for beauty truly is in the eye of the beholder.  Yes, there are technical elements that go into making a motion picture that can be judged by a generally agreed upon set of standards, but when it comes to the <em>heart</em> of the thing… again, no.</p>
<p>Humphrey Bogart once dismissed the idea of an Oscar for “Best Actor” because every actor nominated played a different role; the only way to really judge, he said, would be to have every actor read the same scene from “Hamlet” and then make an apples-to-apples comparison based on that.  However, much as I deeply admire Humphrey Bogart, his argument is no less flawed than the original proposition is in the first place.  Different acting “muscles” go into a comedic performance than go into a deeply dramatic one than go into a terrifying one; and so just as it’s an apples-to-oranges comparison to ask whether Bogart’s performance in <em>The African Queen</em> beats Jack Lemmon’s in <em>Some Like It Hot,</em> it’s also an apples-to-oranges comparison to say that Sir Laurence Olivier is a better actor than John Candy or Boris Karloff based on how well he reads “Hamlet.”  Sure, he may be a wonderful Shakespearean dramatist, but I’m pretty certain he’d have stunk playing the lead in <em>Uncle Buck</em> or wearing the makeup in <em>Frankenstein.</em>  Objectivity?  Single sets of standards?  You can try, and maybe you can even build a ballpark or two, but at the end of the day, it’s still going to be apples-to-oranges and/or subjective.</p>
<p>And then there’s the problem I mentioned in my previous post about <a href="http://wp.me/p2s0FI-E">why I don’t use numeric ratings</a>.  Often times, a movie can do absolutely everything right on a technical level but do absolutely nothing for some people as a piece of entertainment, even if those people are perfectly capable of recognizing that movie’s technical excellence.  For me, one of these films is <em>The Shawshank Redemption.</em>  Wonderfully made; I never want to see it again.  On the other hand, <a href="http://doomcheez.com/reviews/gymkata.html" target="_blank"><em>Gymkata</em></a> is crap by any reasonable person’s definition, and I <em>know</em> it’s crap, but I’d pick <a href="http://doomcheez.com/reviews/gymkata.html" target="_blank"><em>Gymkata</em></a> over <em>The Shawshank Redemption</em> as a movie to watch any day of the week.  Why?  Because I think it&#8217;s entertaining, and <em>Shawshank</em> isn&#8217;t.</p>
<p>This, in turn, brings up what to me is a key point: can any movie really be “The Best” if one doesn’t want to watch it over and over again?  <em>Citizen Kane</em> is great, and I love it… but only once or maybe twice in a year love it.  To be honest, it’s been six years, I think, and I feel no urge to rush out and reset the clock.  Doesn’t mean that it’s not great, or even that I don’t find it entertaining, but…</p>
<p>Do I have a list of critical “Bests”?  Sure I do, but nothing’s numbered (or even written down), and honestly, I don’t put a lot of weight on it.  Yes, such a list is useful in an academic sense or as a matter of breaking down the technical aspects of filmmaking, but outside of what I would call an academic or “professional inner circle” environment, I think the primary value of such an exercise is exactly what I suggested above: it’s a conversation starter.</p>
<p>But you know what?  Every critic has that conversation.</p>
<p>More interesting to me is the “Favorites” list; movies that a person goes back to again and again, whether they’re “quality” or “crap.”  The kind of list that starts from the question: if you were placed [in an isolated location; you decide if it’s in a spaceship, on a desert island, etc.] for [a length of time; at least a year, maybe more] and could only watch from a library of X number of movies, what movies would be in that library?</p>
<p>I don’t know a single honest person whose list would conform to the AFI “Best”; that’s for damn sure.</p>
<p>At the end of the day, yes, there is a place for “Best” lists, and no, it isn’t the trash.  They&#8217;ve got legitimate value to them.  But even there, once you get to the top… it’s a game of microns, people.  Which is better: <em>Citizen Kane</em> or <em>Vertigo?</em>  Personally, I say <em>Vertigo,</em> but I recognize my subjective point of view.  Speaking on a technical level, each is realistically just as good as the other, and when the “Sight &amp; Sound” people put it to a vote… don’t tell anyone, but slide rules and mathematical algorithms weren’t involved: <em>the voters just picked their favorites.</em></p>
<p>Just sayin’.</p>
<p>PS – Keep watching this space.  I may post a Favorites List sometime soon.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/51/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/51/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=51&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://cheezblog.com/2012/08/23/best-vs-favorite-or-apples-vs-oranges/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/23dda7d92391794fc553955b3f3a7a4e?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cheezblog</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Daily Post Challenge: Sandals Schmandals, a Song</title>
		<link>http://sotheresthisthing.wordpress.com/2012/08/24/sandalsschmandals/</link>
		<comments>http://sotheresthisthing.wordpress.com/2012/08/24/sandalsschmandals/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2012 12:12:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>alexically</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Quest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPchallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[listen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[passive and active voice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[passive voice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sandals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[singing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[song]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weekly writing challenge]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://sotheresthisthing.wordpress.com/?p=300</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Here&#8217;s my contribution to The Daily Post&#8217;s Weekly Writing Challenge: Passive Voice. It was a challenge of recognizing, understanding, and properly using Passive Voice in a creative piece that focuses on an object (object as subject). I obviously used a mix of passive and active voice, allowing the passive voice to emphasize the tragedy done to my [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=300&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://sotheresthisthing.wordpress.com/2012/08/24/sandalsschmandals/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>12</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/1aaeb1abc139cbaca01db07187088a7d?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">alexically</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What/Who is Anonymous?</title>
		<link>http://cybernid.wordpress.com/2012/08/22/whatwho-is-anonymous/</link>
		<comments>http://cybernid.wordpress.com/2012/08/22/whatwho-is-anonymous/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2012 02:06:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Rebecca Hardesty</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Big Ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Philosophy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Julian Assange]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Anonymous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wikileaks]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cybernid.wordpress.com/?p=149</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The standoff between Britain and Ecuador over Julian Assange’s bid for political asylum has been making headlines around the world. For the past two months, Julian Assange, the founder of the whistleblower website Wikileaks, has been taking refuge in the Ecuadorean Embassy in London. The U.K. courts ruled to extradite him to Sweden where he [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=149&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_155" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 348px"><a href="http://cybernid.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/5400848923_c5708bd6751.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-155 " title="We are legion" src="http://cybernid.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/5400848923_c5708bd6751.jpg?w=338&h=450" alt="" width="338" height="450" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Photo by Enrique Dans (http://www.flickr.com/photos/edans/)</p></div>
<p>The standoff between Britain and Ecuador over Julian Assange’s bid for political asylum has been making headlines around the world. For the past two months, Julian Assange, the founder of the whistleblower website Wikileaks, has been taking refuge in the Ecuadorean Embassy in London. The U.K. courts ruled to extradite him to Sweden where he faces possible sexual assault and misconduct charges. This story has caught the attention of the public because it is more than just news; it is a drama. Assange is a controversial figure because of his role in publishing classified diplomatic cables on Wikileaks (for more about “Cablegate,” see <a href="http://www.smh.com.au/technology/technology-news/us-redfaced-as-cablegate-sparks-global-diplomatic-crisis-courtesy-of-wikileaks-20101128-18ccl.html">here</a>), but he is not the only one involved in this spectacle. Although the U.S. is not directly involved, it casts a shadow over this standoff. Assange and his supporters fear that if the UK extradited him to Sweden, it would not be long before he would be delivered to the U.S. where he would be charged with espionage stemming from when his website published a trove of American secrets.</p>
<p>Another controversial player in this drama is the “hacktivist” group Anonymous. Anonymous has used Wikileaks to distribute information it acquired from its hacking endeavors. It has also supported the ideals of free information, freedom of expression and freedom of the press that Assange espoused. The question people have been asking is, &#8220;who or what is Anonymous?&#8221; People have asked if members of this  hacktivist group are freedom fighters, vigilantes or terrorists. However asking about members is not the way to get at the meaning of this group. The real question is, on a metaphysical level, what is Anonymous? Or in other words, on a fundamental level, what kind of entity or being is it?</p>
<p>Anonymous is a loosely affiliated international collective, composed of tech-savvy activists, which originated online on imageboards and forums. In its early days, Anonymous was not an identifiable Internet entity, but was a large subculture of people who posted anonymously and played “pranks” on websites, popularized memes and defined aspects of Internet culture. The creativity and outrageous content on these boards attracted the media, which described this community as brilliant and insane. In 2008, this boundless creativity developed a more focused shape and perspective on the world. It adopted the name “Anonymous” and often used the image of a suit without a head or a Guy Fawkes mask to symbolize that it had no leader and was the embodiment of an idea. Since then, Anonymous has become known for its strong opposition to Internet censorship, human rights violations, privacy violations, government opacity, and big corporations. It has become a recognizable presence at protests because its members wear the symbolic masks to show that they are part of this international group.</p>
<div id="attachment_157" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://cybernid.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/7799105128_4beb9cb510.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-157" title="Ecuadorian Embassy Standoff - Front Entrance" src="http://cybernid.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/7799105128_4beb9cb510.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="281" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Photo by Trowbridge Estate (http://www.flickr.com/photos/jaggers/)</p></div>
<p>On August 15<sup>th</sup>, I became aware that Anonymous was following, and invested in, this standoff when Britain threatened to remove the Ecuadorian embassy’s diplomatic privileges and storm the building to arrest Assange. I was up late enough to see several Anonymous groups on Facebook post urgent messages in the early hours of the 16<sup>th</sup>. According to the posts, police officers were entering the embassy. The messages were brief and conveyed a sense of anxiety that is rare on such pages. Although separate individuals maintain the various Facebook pages and Twitter accounts, within several minutes of each other, all were calling for available “Anons” to convene at the embassy and see what was going on. More specifically, the administrators and people online who were not in London were asking others to take pictures and transmit a live video of what was happening.</p>
<p>Soon enough a protester had a “livestream” feed up and others were taking photos and uploading them to Anonymous pages. In addition, several Anons were able to coordinate a demonstration where they wore Guy Fawkes masks and held signs proclaiming, “I am Julian” as an expression of solidarity. This was not a risk-free endeavor on the part of the protesters. Police threatened to arrest the man who was filming and they arrested at least one person outside the embassy including a legal observer who was then “released” under the condition that he stay in a designated “protest pen.” (See <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4xavIyLEqsI">here</a>)</p>
<p>This remarkable display of efficient collaboration, communication and willingness to act for the good of the group is a large part of what makes Anonymous so remarkable. Anonymous describes itself as a “hive mind” and this could not be a more accurate description. Just as in a hive, each member contributes to the whole and brings his or her talents, abilities, and insights that benefits the community. Although there are people within Anonymous who have skills in planning operations and working with technology, there is no leader. Each person who participates and contributes has the liberty to take the initiative and start a project on behalf of the collective. There is no official way to become a “member,” so it is odd to speak of those who consider themselves to be part of Anonymous as such. It is more accurate to say that Anonymous is made up of people who have connected online over shared goals, interests and ideals, and also individually identify with whatever they perceive Anonymous as. (Check out this <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-FkvfNMnjjo">video</a>)</p>
<p>On a fundamental level, Anonymous is an actualized idea of the potential for freedom, creativity and personal responsibility. It is an idea to which individuals can, and do, attribute their actions that they believe are in-line with the sentiments of the hive mind.  One can see those who actively participate in Anonymous, or related groups, as parts of a giant brain or fragments of a self-aware collective consciousness. This loosely connected group acts on issues about which the majority of people participating on the Internet feel strongly. Shared ideas evolve the way an individual’s thoughts evolve and this collective thought process directs the trend of Anonymous&#8217; activity in the physical world. However, this entity does not have specific longterm goals that could potentially stifle the creative and organic way it interacts with the world.</p>
<p>Anonymous’ response to Britain’s threat to the Ecuadorian embassy was an example of this hive mind’s ability to focus on and respond to a specific situation in the physical world. Although the vast majority of Anonymous activity occurs online, this entity has the ability to manifest in the physical world with people acting as eyes or mouths. The protesters who uploaded photos on the 16<sup>th</sup> potentially put themselves in harm&#8217;s way in order to serve as the eyes of the group. Perhaps one of the reasons people are willing to risk their safety is because no one told them that it was their duty to do so. Instead, it seems that this willingness originates authentically and organically within the individuals, which results in these people having a strong personal investment in their choice of actions, and therefore are willing to do more. In these moments when someone chooses to act under the banner of Anonymous, the person not only acts for the benefit of everyone creating the hive mind; the individual surrenders his or her own personal identity and assumes that of the whole, becoming Anonymous &#8211; both one and many.</p>
<p>What do you think of Anonymous?</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Sources</span></p>
<p><a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2012/08/19/world/europe/julian-assange-under-watch-at-ecuadorean-embassy.html">http://www.nytimes.com/2012/08/19/world/europe/julian-assange-under-watch-at-ecuadorean-embassy.html</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.google.com/hostednews/ap/article/ALeqM5gqJKCxCWL5LOFr35MFQNkgnx_jzg?docId=0419da513cb346dd9625cf29e41e8729">http://www.google.com/hostednews/ap/article/ALeqM5gqJKCxCWL5LOFr35MFQNkgnx_jzg?docId=0419da513cb346dd9625cf29e41e8729</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.abc.net.au/news/2012-08-18/carr-denies-us-seeking-assange-extradition/4207426">http://www.abc.net.au/news/2012-08-18/carr-denies-us-seeking-assange-extradition/4207426</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.smh.com.au/national/us-intends-to-chase-assange-cables-show-20120817-24e1l.html">http://www.smh.com.au/national/us-intends-to-chase-assange-cables-show-20120817-24e1l.html</a></p>
<p><a href="http://articles.chicagotribune.com/2012-08-15/business/sns-rt-us-wikileaks-assange-ecuadorbre87e16n-20120815_1_foreign-minister-ricardo-patino-ecuadorean-embassy-wikileaks-founder-julian-assange">http://articles.chicagotribune.com/2012-08-15/business/sns-rt-us-wikileaks-assange-ecuadorbre87e16n-20120815_1_foreign-minister-ricardo-patino-ecuadorean-embassy-wikileaks-founder-julian-assange</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.ajc.com/news/nation-world/assange-urges-us-to-1500379.html">http://www.ajc.com/news/nation-world/assange-urges-us-to-1500379.html</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-2188946/Julian-Assange-granted-asylum-Ecuador-scuffles-break-out.html">http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-2188946/Julian-Assange-granted-asylum-Ecuador-scuffles-break-out.html</a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/149/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/149/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=149&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://cybernid.wordpress.com/2012/08/22/whatwho-is-anonymous/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>29</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/3be1245e23445edca2741401b5f8c6b8?s=96&#38;d=wavatar&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">rahardesty</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cybernid.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/5400848923_c5708bd6751.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">We are legion</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cybernid.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/7799105128_4beb9cb510.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ecuadorian Embassy Standoff - Front Entrance</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Brussels: We’re Ugly and We Like It</title>
		<link>http://loveelizabethtravels.com/2012/08/22/brussels-were-ugly-and-we-like-it/</link>
		<comments>http://loveelizabethtravels.com/2012/08/22/brussels-were-ugly-and-we-like-it/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2012 15:45:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>loveelizabethtravels</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[architecture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Belgium]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brussels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comic book]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flea market]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[graffiti]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Manneken Pis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[market]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[street art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UNESCO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[World Heritage Site]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://loveelizabethtravels.com/?p=92</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There’s no other way of saying this: Brussels is a weird city. It’s not a place that is on every traveler’s to-go list when spending time in Europe, but it is in a country that I wanted to spend a little time in, so I made a quick stop there during my spring break Euro [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=92&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://loveelizabethtravels.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/293093_10150628997845976_196866230_n.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-113" title="Brussels, Belgium" src="http://loveelizabethtravels.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/293093_10150628997845976_196866230_n.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="377" /></a></p>
<p><em>There’s no other way of saying this: Brussels is a weird city. It’s not a place that is on every traveler’s to-go list when spending time in Europe, but it is in a country that I wanted to spend a little time in, so I made a quick stop there during my spring break Euro trip, and I’m glad I did!</em></p>
<p>After arriving in the city, I checked into my hostel. I don’t often plan out a lot of my trips in advance, so usually I’ll pick up a few city guides from the front desk to see what the must-see things are.</p>
<p><strong>I knew right away that I was going to enjoy my day in Brussels when I looked at the city guide and saw the motto “We’re ugly and we like it.”</strong> Brussels isn’t a breathtakingly beautiful city like many other places in Europe; it always seems to fall just short of “pretty,” but it never fails to satisfy the qualifications of “interesting.”</p>
<p>One barely has to look further than the main attraction of the city: Manneken Pis. This fountain, which can be found in the side streets close to the main plaza, is a small boy doing exactly what his name suggests. Nobody knows the actual significance of the statue, but I think that’s what makes him so interesting. <strong>He certainly won’t win any beauty awards, but he will remind you of the “irreverent spirit” that Brussels is so proud of.</strong></p>
<p><a href="http://loveelizabethtravels.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/292990_10150629000485976_1396830402_n.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-112" title="Manneken Pis" src="http://loveelizabethtravels.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/292990_10150629000485976_1396830402_n.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="663" /></a></p>
<p>Always full of contradictions, Brussels’ other main point of interest is the impressive Grand Plaza. This brick square is surrounded by tall historic buildings that certainly could win awards. (In fact, it is named by UNESCO as a World Heritage Site.)</p>
<p><a href="http://loveelizabethtravels.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/389751_10150628903160976_188972813_n.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-109" title="Grand Place Architecture" src="http://loveelizabethtravels.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/389751_10150628903160976_188972813_n.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="377" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://loveelizabethtravels.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/551541_10150628996915976_732461681_n.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-110" title="Grand Place Architecture" src="http://loveelizabethtravels.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/551541_10150628996915976_732461681_n.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="663" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://loveelizabethtravels.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/532733_10150628902550976_575366580_n.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-111" title="Grand Place Architecture" src="http://loveelizabethtravels.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/532733_10150628902550976_575366580_n.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="661" /></a></p>
<p>Informally called “the comic book capital of the world,” Brussels is filled with many murals and paintings from some of the world’s most beloved comics.</p>
<p><a href="http://loveelizabethtravels.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/528942_10150629027625976_1218030727_n.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-106" title="Comic Book Art" src="http://loveelizabethtravels.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/528942_10150629027625976_1218030727_n.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="663" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://loveelizabethtravels.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/529000_10150629046325976_1480723480_n.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-107" title="Comic Book Art" src="http://loveelizabethtravels.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/529000_10150629046325976_1480723480_n.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="663" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://loveelizabethtravels.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/538382_10150629056670976_1722072172_n.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-108" title="Comic Book Art" src="http://loveelizabethtravels.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/538382_10150629056670976_1722072172_n.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="662" /></a></p>
<p>Even so, graffiti abounds all throughout the city and can be just as interesting as the rest of the street art.</p>
<p><a href="http://loveelizabethtravels.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/557960_10150629027970976_1972307160_n.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-105" title="Graffiti" src="http://loveelizabethtravels.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/557960_10150629027970976_1972307160_n.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="663" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://loveelizabethtravels.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/538714_10150628898200976_340277191_n.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-104" title="&quot;It's a Good Day&quot; Graffiti" src="http://loveelizabethtravels.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/538714_10150628898200976_340277191_n.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="663" /></a></p>
<p><strong>The contrasts continue in the architecture of the city.</strong> With so many different styles, pretty buildings aren’t hard to come by.</p>
<p><a href="http://loveelizabethtravels.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/547666_10150628895525976_1331418793_n.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-102" title="Ship at Sea Building" src="http://loveelizabethtravels.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/547666_10150628895525976_1331418793_n.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="663" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://loveelizabethtravels.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/522513_10150629047380976_2053222816_n.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-101" title="Animal-print Building" src="http://loveelizabethtravels.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/522513_10150629047380976_2053222816_n.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="663" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://loveelizabethtravels.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/564560_10150628891960976_1584097465_n.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-103" title="Hexagon Building" src="http://loveelizabethtravels.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/564560_10150628891960976_1584097465_n.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="662" /></a></p>
<p>But at the same time, everything seems to be under construction.</p>
<p><a href="http://loveelizabethtravels.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/306584_10150628897380976_313989283_n.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-100" title="Canal Construction" src="http://loveelizabethtravels.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/306584_10150628897380976_313989283_n.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="378" /></a></p>
<p>As a testament to the diversity of the people who live in Brussels, shoppers can satisfy themselves at an elaborate shopping arcade.</p>
<p><a href="http://loveelizabethtravels.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/293083_10150629059880976_1204326924_n.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-99" title="Galeries Royales St Hubert" src="http://loveelizabethtravels.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/293083_10150629059880976_1204326924_n.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="376" /></a></p>
<p>Or they can pick around piles of antiques (and junk) at the flea market at Jeu de Balle Plaza.</p>
<p><a href="http://loveelizabethtravels.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/526101_10150629041815976_173319004_n.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-98" title="Jeu de Balle Market" src="http://loveelizabethtravels.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/526101_10150629041815976_173319004_n.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="377" /></a></p>
<p>Looking through my photos of Brussels, I’ve found one in particular that I think summarizes the entire city quite well: a statue of the Manneken Pis standing atop a metallic hot air balloon sculpture and poised to do what he does best.</p>
<p><a href="http://loveelizabethtravels.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/557774_10150629030015976_1469301922_n1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-97" title="Manneken Pis on Hot Air Balloon" src="http://loveelizabethtravels.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/557774_10150629030015976_1469301922_n1.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="663" /></a></p>
<p><strong>Even the shiniest of exteriors doesn’t hide how truly offbeat Brussels can be.</strong> But why should that be hidden? Brussels is shameless, eccentric, and different. What it lacks in beauty, it makes up for in personality. <strong>Brussels is ugly, and I like it.</strong></p>
<p><strong>Love, Elizabeth</strong></p>
<p><em>Would you ever consider going to Brussels?</em></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/92/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/92/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=92&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://loveelizabethtravels.com/2012/08/22/brussels-were-ugly-and-we-like-it/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>29</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/bacbbcb33caf56b236d3d93f0c1ccd2e?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">loveelizabethtravels</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://loveelizabethtravels.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/293093_10150628997845976_196866230_n.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Brussels, Belgium</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://loveelizabethtravels.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/292990_10150629000485976_1396830402_n.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Manneken Pis</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://loveelizabethtravels.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/389751_10150628903160976_188972813_n.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Grand Place Architecture</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://loveelizabethtravels.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/551541_10150628996915976_732461681_n.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Grand Place Architecture</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://loveelizabethtravels.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/532733_10150628902550976_575366580_n.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Grand Place Architecture</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://loveelizabethtravels.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/528942_10150629027625976_1218030727_n.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Comic Book Art</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://loveelizabethtravels.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/529000_10150629046325976_1480723480_n.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Comic Book Art</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://loveelizabethtravels.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/538382_10150629056670976_1722072172_n.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Comic Book Art</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://loveelizabethtravels.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/557960_10150629027970976_1972307160_n.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Graffiti</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://loveelizabethtravels.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/538714_10150628898200976_340277191_n.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">&#34;It&#039;s a Good Day&#34; Graffiti</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://loveelizabethtravels.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/547666_10150628895525976_1331418793_n.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ship at Sea Building</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://loveelizabethtravels.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/522513_10150629047380976_2053222816_n.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Animal-print Building</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://loveelizabethtravels.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/564560_10150628891960976_1584097465_n.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Hexagon Building</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://loveelizabethtravels.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/306584_10150628897380976_313989283_n.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Canal Construction</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://loveelizabethtravels.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/293083_10150629059880976_1204326924_n.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Galeries Royales St Hubert</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://loveelizabethtravels.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/526101_10150629041815976_173319004_n.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Jeu de Balle Market</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://loveelizabethtravels.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/557774_10150629030015976_1469301922_n1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Manneken Pis on Hot Air Balloon</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Parental Winning: You\&#8217;re Not As Awful As You Think</title>
		<link>http://partoftheplan.com/2012/08/22/parental-winning-wednesday-august-22/</link>
		<comments>http://partoftheplan.com/2012/08/22/parental-winning-wednesday-august-22/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2012 21:08:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>mamaschinsky</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Being a Grown-Up]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parental Winning Wednesday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[There's a baby in my tummy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kids]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pregnancy]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://partoftheplan.com/?p=1131</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[If we would all just be honest about how we really parent our children, I truly believe we&#8217;d all feel like much better (or at least less crappy) parents. Face it, you&#8217;ve felt like a terrible parent in at least one instance every day since your child was born. Today I&#8217;m here to tell you you&#8217;re not [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1131&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://partoftheplan.com/2012/08/22/parental-winning-wednesday-august-22/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>26</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/1ff870427968f4bffdcba965d23d937e?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mamaschinsky</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://partoftheplandotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/imagejpeg_3-2.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">imagejpeg_3-2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://partoftheplandotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/imagejpeg_2-15.jpg?w=279" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">imagejpeg_2-15</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>\&#8221;All Have Sinned\&#8221;: The U.S.-Dakota War of 1862</title>
		<link>http://pietistschoolman.com/2012/08/20/all-have-sinned-the-u-s-dakota-war-of-1862/</link>
		<comments>http://pietistschoolman.com/2012/08/20/all-have-sinned-the-u-s-dakota-war-of-1862/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2012 18:21:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Chris Gehrz</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Current Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Museums]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Abraham Lincoln]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Civil War]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elden Lawrence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[James Calvin Schaap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Minnesota History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Native Americans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Public History]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://pietistschoolman.com/?p=9093</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Last Friday I decided to put syllabus revision on hold and spend an afternoon continuing my tour of World War I commemoration in the Twin Cities by visiting Fort Snelling, the nearly 200-year old former military installation at the convergence of the Mississippi and Minnesota rivers that trained officers, processed recruits and draftees, and housed [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=9093&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last Friday I decided to put syllabus revision on hold and spend an afternoon continuing my tour of <a title="Commemorating WWI in Minnesota (part 1)" href="/2012/08/13/commemorating-wwi-in-minnesota-part-1/" target="_blank">World War I commemoration</a> in the Twin Cities by visiting Fort Snelling, the nearly 200-year old former military installation at the convergence of the Mississippi and Minnesota rivers that trained officers, processed recruits and draftees, and housed a hospital in 1917-1918. As you&#8217;ll see when that WWI commemoration series continues, the visit proved to be a bit of a bust, WWI-wise. But I&#8217;m still glad I went that particular day&#8230;</p>
<div id="attachment_9105" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://collections.mnhs.org/visualresources/image.cfm?imageid=73134"><img class="size-medium wp-image-9105" title="Battle at New Ulm" src="http://pietistschoolman.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/battle-at-new-ulm.jpg?w=300&h=185" alt="Battle at New Ulm, Minnesota" width="300" height="185" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Depiction of fighting at New Ulm, Minnesota, one of the earliest battles in the 1862 war &#8211; Minnesota Historical Society</p></div>
<p>Since last Friday also marked the 150th anniversary of the beginning of a war that few Americans noticed at the time and few remember today, and Fort Snelling played an important role in it. On August 17, 1862, four Wahpeton Dakota warriors killed five white settlers in rural Meeker County, Minnesota, sparking a wave of attacks in succeeding days elsewhere in the Minnesota River Valley. Eventually, the violence spread to northern Minnesota and what was then still the Dakota Territory.</p>
<p>While the Civil War continued with Robert E. Lee&#8217;s successful campaign against the Union armies of John Pope in Northern Virginia (Second Bull Run started on the 28th), what&#8217;s now generally called the U.S.-Dakota War (or simply the Dakota War) was fought by much smaller forces, but perhaps greater brutality, in the middle of one of the states of the Union. A mark of the relative insignificance (for most Americans) of what was happening in Minnesota is that Pres. Abraham Lincoln chose the disgraced Pope to lead government forces against the Dakota.</p>
<p>In the end, the Dakota were defeated on September 23 in Yellow Medicine County, in a battle that featured no more than 2000 white soldiers and 1200 Dakota warriors. Most of the war party moved to the Great Plains for the winter (and Pope lacked cavalry with which to pursue), but about four hundred were arrested and put on trial for murder, rape, and other charges.</p>
<p>Military courts found over three hundred guilty, often trying the Dakota in groups and taking as few as five minutes to reach a decision. Minnesota&#8217;s Episcopal bishop, Henry Whipple, traveled to Washington to meet with Lincoln; he explained to the president that Dakota grievances stemmed in large part from the greed, corruption, and deceit of government agents, traders, and other whites. Lincoln took what he called &#8220;the rascality of this Indian business&#8221; into consideration and granted clemency to most of those sentenced to die. But thirty-eight Dakota were hanged the day after Christmas, the largest mass execution in American history. (Two more Dakota leaders who had fled to Canada were kidnapped by British agents, turned over to the U.S. government, and hanged at Fort Snelling in 1865.)</p>
<p><em>(The </em>New York Times<em>&#8216; Civil War blog, </em>Disunion<em>, has a post today on <a href="http://opinionator.blogs.nytimes.com/2012/08/20/lincoln-and-the-sioux/" target="_blank">Lincoln&#8217;s role in the Dakota War</a>.)</em></p>
<div id="attachment_9100" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 225px"><a href="http://pietistschoolman.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dakota-prisoners-at-fort-snelling.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-9100" title="Dakota Prisoners at Fort Snelling" src="http://pietistschoolman.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dakota-prisoners-at-fort-snelling.jpg?w=215&h=300" alt="Dakota Internees at Fort Snelling" width="215" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Some of the Dakota interned at Fort Snelling &#8211; Minnesota Historical Society</p></div>
<p>Meanwhile, about 1600 more Dakota (mostly women, children, and the elderly) who surrendered were held at an internment camp at what&#8217;s now Fort Snelling State Park. Perhaps as many as 300 died of malnutrition or measles, and others suffered abuse at the hands of white soldiers and civilians. Amid calls from some white Minnesotans for extermination, 1300 Dakota were expelled from Minnesota; relatively few remain today, the most visible in the Twin Cities being the Mdewakanton (just over 300 people).</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a significant moment in Minnesota history, and Fort Snelling (because of its symbolic prominence as the center of white military power in Minnesota in the mid-19th century, the site of the concentration camp, and the scene of the final two executions) seemed like the appropriate place to be for the commemoration of the 150th anniversary. Yet you would barely have known what was happening during my visit: there&#8217;s a nice public history display inside the visitor center, but more people were paying attention to the neighboring exhibit about the Fort during World War II; on the grounds themselves, most of the trickle of visitors headed inside to interact with the historical interpreters enacting nineteenth-century life, passing by the information stands outside the fort&#8217;s walls that marked the sites of the concentration camp and the 1865 executions.</p>
<p>But for those willing to give it their attention, the anniversary has generated some excellent, nuanced coverage. Last week the state&#8217;s largest newspaper, the <em>Star Tribune</em> ran a multi-part profile of the <a href="http://www.startribune.com/local/164577856.html" target="_blank">Dakota leader Little Crow</a>, who was famously conflicted about going to war (while he did fight, many other Dakota refused to take up arms and actually protected white friends) and ended being killed in 1863 while picking raspberries. (His corpse was decapitated, his scalp turned in for a bounty.) In association with that series, Twin Cities Public Television aired documentaries on the <a href="http://www.tpt.org/?a=programs&amp;id=2097" target="_blank">1862 war</a> and the <a href="http://www.tpt.org/?a=programs&amp;id=5281" target="_blank">scattering of the Dakota</a> that ensued. The Minnesota Historical Society (MHS) has worked closely with historians and activists to commemorate the anniversary, developing everything from an <a href="http://www.usdakotawar.org/stories" target="_blank">oral history project</a> to an <a href="http://minnesotahistorycenter.org/exhibits/us-dakota-war-of-1862" target="_blank">exhibit at the Minnesota History Center</a> to a <a href="http://www.allmyrelationsarts.com/?p=629" target="_blank">gallery of paintings</a> by Native American artists inspired by the legacy of the war. And while the anniversary has not been free from controversy (including whether or not to display one of the nooses used to hang the thirty-eight Dakota in December 1863), MHS staff have <a href="http://bethelhistory.wordpress.com/2012/01/30/the-us-dakota-war-150-years-later/" target="_blank">been forthcoming</a> about the challenge of commemorating this particular event.</p>
<div id="attachment_9104" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://collections.mnhs.org/visualresources/details.cfm?imageid=60107"><img class="size-medium wp-image-9104" title="Attack on Dakota Prisoners" src="http://pietistschoolman.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/attack-on-dakota-prisoner.jpg?w=300&h=179" alt="Attacks on Dakota Prisoners" width="300" height="179" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">A crowd attacks Dakota prisoners as they pass through New Ulm, Minnesota in 1862 &#8211; Minnesota Historical Society</p></div>
<p>Just to write a 500-word summary of the war is difficult: How much background needs to be included to give context for the killings on August 17, 1862 and what followed? Were the 1600 Dakota civilians held at an &#8220;internment&#8221; or &#8220;concentration&#8221; camp? (Following the MHS&#8217; lead, I used both terms.) There was ample brutality on both sides, but how much detail belongs in a brief summary?</p>
<p>One of the best pieces that I&#8217;ve read on the Dakota War comes from writer and recently retired Dordt College professor James Calvin Schaap, whose essay published at the <em>Books and Culture </em>website (and also at his <a href="http://siouxlander.blogspot.com/" target="_blank">personal blog</a>) brings those bloody weeks in August-September 1862 to life. (Here&#8217;s <a href="http://www.booksandculture.com/articles/webexclusives/2012/august/dakota-war.html" target="_blank">part one</a> and <a href="http://www.booksandculture.com/articles/webexclusives/2012/august/dakota-war-of-1862.html" target="_blank">part two</a>.) In the opening paragraphs, he sketches the events that initiated the war, concluding:</p>
<blockquote><p>Robinson Jones [the settler at whose homestead the violence began] didn&#8217;t ask to be murdered, nor did his adopted daughter. They were victims of what was to them totally unforeseen Dakota lawlessness and brutality.</p>
<p>Or were they? Who of the Dakota had asked white people to take over their land? Who of the Dakota had written up treaties that were sheer lies? Who of the Dakota had asked Europeans to come in and destroy their culture?</p>
<p>The violent opening foray of the Dakota War of 1862 was the vicious, cold-blooded murder of three white men, a white woman, and a white child.</p>
<p>Now, 150 years later, telling the story remains immensely painful, not simply because of hundreds of deaths, but because what happened that August afternoon was the opening round of the Sioux Indian wars across the Upper Midwest, a story of which it can be said that there is no one righteous, no not one. All have sinned.</p></blockquote>
<p>It&#8217;s unlikely to show up in a public history project that caters to a plural society, but I appreciate Schaap&#8217;s allusion to <a href="http://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=Romans%203&amp;version=NIV" target="_blank">Romans 3</a>. There is heroism (Dakota who protected white friends; Bishop Whipple&#8217;s desperate attempts to save life) and pathos (the reluctant, honorable Little Crow) here, but we should resist the temptation to shape this history to conform to simplistic narratives of white supremacy (late 19th century memorials erected by white Minnesotans treated the settlers as martyrs and made no reference to whites&#8217; treatment of the indigenous population — <em>for an interesting reflection on what to do with such monuments, see <a href="http://www.usdakotawar.org/stories/contributors/dr-elden-lawrence/1285" target="_blank">this segment</a> of the oral history interview with Elden Lawrence, a Dakota historian and author of a <a href="http://shop.mnhs.org/moreinfo.cfm?product_id=2947" target="_blank">book on Dakota converts to Christianity</a> and their peacemaking efforts in 1862)</em> or of Dakota victimhood. Truly, &#8220;all have sinned.&#8221;</p>
<p>At the same time, Schaap warns against the resulting temptation: to treat this history as irreducibly complex and better left unaddressed:</p>
<blockquote><p>Perhaps the story should simply be forgotten, like some of the old war monuments one can still find throughout the Minnesota River valley. Perhaps some history is better left to crumble into dust, as the bodies of the dead, red and white.</p>
<p>But the 1862 Dakota War is our story—all of ours, and not remembering simply means forgetting.</p></blockquote>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=9093&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://pietistschoolman.com/2012/08/20/all-have-sinned-the-u-s-dakota-war-of-1862/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://pietistschoolman.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dakota-prisoners-at-fort-snelling.jpg?w=107" />
		<media:content url="http://pietistschoolman.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dakota-prisoners-at-fort-snelling.jpg?w=107" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Dakota Prisoners at Fort Snelling</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/b0ea20f4111076e72b3a2a0beeccbf31?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cgehrz</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://pietistschoolman.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/battle-at-new-ulm.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Battle at New Ulm</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://pietistschoolman.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dakota-prisoners-at-fort-snelling.jpg?w=215" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Dakota Prisoners at Fort Snelling</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://pietistschoolman.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/attack-on-dakota-prisoner.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Attack on Dakota Prisoners</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>