<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2011 22:59:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>How I Use Visualization To Drive Creativity</title>
		<link>http://techcrunch.com/2011/01/17/how-i-use-visualization-to-drive-creativity/</link>
		<comments>http://techcrunch.com/2011/01/17/how-i-use-visualization-to-drive-creativity/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2011 16:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Guest Author</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[TC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mark Suster]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://techcrunch.com/?p=264323</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.bothsidesofthetable.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/visualization-brainstorming.jpg" /><em>This is a guest post by Mark Suster, a 2x entrepreneur turned VC.  He sold his second company to Salesforce.com, becoming VP of Product Management. He joined GRP Partners in 2007 as a General Partner focusing on early-stage technology companies. Read more about Suster on his blog at <a href="http://www.bothsidesofthetable.com/"><strong>Bothsidesofthetable</strong></a> and on Twitter at <a href="http://twitter.com/msuster"><strong>@msuster.</strong></a></em><img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=264323&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>This is a guest post by <a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/person/mark-suster">Mark Suster</a>, a 2x entrepreneur turned VC.  He sold his second company to Salesforce.com, becoming VP of Product Management. He joined GRP Partners in 2007 as a General Partner focusing on early-stage technology companies. Read more about Suster on his blog at <a href="http://www.bothsidesofthetable.com/"><strong>Bothsidesofthetable</strong></a> and on Twitter at <a href="http://twitter.com/msuster"><strong>@msuster.</strong></a></em></p>
<p>Creativity.  I&#8217;ve always believed it&#8217;s been one of the most important attributes of business success yet something very few business leaders talk about.  So I thought I&#8217;d write a post about how I drive my personal creativity.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter" src="http://www.bothsidesofthetable.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/visualization-brainstorming.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<p>As a practitioner of creativity rather than as an instructor of it I&#8217;m certain that there are many ways to get the creative juices flowing and how to release more creativity.  The one that works best for me is visualization coupled with self talk.</p>
<p>Visualization is so important to help yourself &amp; others conceptualize ideas.  It&#8217;s why I always work hard to find images for my blog posts &amp; why all of my keynote presentations are visual rather than bullet points with words.</p>
<p><strong>EXECUTIVE SUMMARY: </strong>This is a long post, so I put an executive summary here if you want to get the point without reading all the detail. If you plan to read the post you can skip the summary if you want.</p>
<ul>
<li>Almost all business success relies on creativity. This applies equally to VCs, startups &amp; big company executives</li>
<li>Despite the importance of creativity, there seems to be almost no focus on teaching it, encouraging it, training at it &amp; incorporating it into our daily routines. The need for creativity extends well beyond product design.</li>
<li>Many people are visual thinkers. Therefore to drive creativity people need to do visual brainstorming</li>
<li>You need to find what works for you to put yourself in that environment and learn how to do &#8220;self talk,&#8221; learn how to create visual charts, learn how to test &amp; iterate ideas and the learn how to effectively communicate results.</li>
<li>For me I can only do this by myself. I think team sessions are better for testing ideas than for original thought, but that&#8217;s me. Solitude &amp; creativity go hand-in-hand.</li>
<li>I use tools to invoke my creatieve self.  One example is driving, which has an actual physiological reason it makes you creative. The key is channeling what you learn when you drive onto paper for retention purposes so you have to write it down soon afterward</li>
<li>One of the books that first made me aware of the &#8220;creative brain&#8221; was &#8220;<a href="http://www.drawright.com/">Drawing on the Right Side of the Brain</a>&#8221; by Betty Edwards.  It&#8217;s a book about creating art but shows how an artist&#8217;s mind gets &#8220;into the zone,&#8221; how creativity can be invoked, and why looking at what you create in a different way than the rational mind would conceive is an important part of creativity.  She literally encourages you to draw things upside down.</li>
<li>Other ways I drive creativity are time pressure, showers &amp; occasionally wine. All are known creativity drivers and are covered in the book mentioned above.  For others they swear by music.  I personally find music more distracting than helpful.</li>
<li>Adding structure to creativity is not an oxymoron. It&#8217;s how you codify your ideas</li>
<li>Like anything, creativity takes practice.  There&#8217;s no such thing as &#8220;not being a creative person.&#8221;  Some people are more creative than others but it&#8217;s within us all.  You just have to dedicate yourself to a wanting to tap your creative juices.</li>
<li>I apply visual thinking for nearly everything I do: preparing for important phone calls (I imagine my opening lines, I imagine the responses), writing keynote presentations, deciding whether or not to invest in a company, preparing for board meetings &#8211; you name it.  These are all creative processes.</li>
<li>Visualization is a well known technique in professional sports where the difference between winning &amp; losing is often psychological more than physical.  If it can work for them, it can work for you.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>THE DETAILS</strong></p>
<p><strong>What exactly is visualization?</strong> &#8211; It is exactly as it sounds.  The process of visualization is literally imagining or seeing things in your mind.  When I need to give a speech and I&#8217;m writing a slide for my deck, I think up the story in my mind that I&#8217;m going to tell for this slide.  I literally imagine myself on stage saying the words.  I think about how the audience might react and whether if I were in the audience I would be intrigued.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s why before every speech I call the organizer and drill them about who will be in the audience.  I want to know how many people, their level of tech sophistication, their age and their interests.  I look carefully at who is speaking before me.  In order to visualize how an audience will receive my presentation I have to be able to imagine the whole situation.</p>
<p>When I write a blog post I often see the words before I write them.  If I know I have a topic I&#8217;m interested in writing about many times I&#8217;ll literally think whole sentences in my mind as a test drive before I ever sit at the computer and type.</p>
<p>Strange, I know.  But for many people the most important driver of innovation is this kind of visualization &amp; self talk.  Yet it almost sounds too strange or mystical and as a result I seldom hear leaders talk about it.  So I thought I would.</p>
<p><strong>Creativity in our business lives</strong> &#8211; The average tech startup these days spends time talking with colleagues &amp; investors about a multitude of things: customer acquisition, viral adoption, raising capital, hiring / firing employees, product features, technology trends, marketing / branding, and on and on.  I hear very little discussion ever about how to be more creative.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s ironic because I believe creativity is the most important success criterion for a startup.  And if we&#8217;re reflective, it&#8217;s also one of the most important success criteria for investors, senior executives, tech writers and virtually anybody involved in business leadership.  Yet most startups seem to constrain creativity to product design.  That&#8217;s a shame.</p>
<p>Creativity is what helps us think of our ideas in the first place.  It&#8217;s what helps us imagine what feature sets would be most appealing.  It&#8217;s how we package our company story and drive our press coverage.  As a VC it&#8217;s how I think through which markets will be attractive in the future, which ones I want to be in now and how the technology &amp; business world will likely evolve.  Without creativity I&#8217;d simply invest in the trends I&#8217;m seeing on TechCrunch which I inherently believe means I would be investing in what has already happend rather than imagining what could be.</p>
<p>When I make important phone calls I literally play out the start of the call in my mind&#8217;s eye before I ever pick up the phone.  I imagine myself saying my opening line and put myself in the shoes of the receiver to think about how they&#8217;ll react.</p>
<p>There is not a single important business function I do that doesn&#8217;t involve creativity.  And whether I&#8217;m preparing to attend a board meeting, I&#8217;m planning to lead a strategic discussion with an executive team, or whether I&#8217;m preparing for a TV interview &#8211; I use the same process.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.bothsidesofthetable.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/shapes-and-lines.jpg"><strong> </strong></a></p>
<p><strong>The creative process </strong>- Whenever I need to do any task that requires insight I have to be able to visualize &#8211; to literally SEE the decision framework.  Many people are visual thinkers.  I often start with a blank piece of paper &amp; a pen and start doodling. I try to visually deconstruct the problem with boxes, arrows, circles &amp; other shapes.  I add words &amp; ideas.  I try to figure out the structure of the component parts.  I start to build in metaphors for what I&#8217;m thinking about.  I roll up metaphors into a narrative or theme that has coherence.</p>
<p>I know this sounds abstract so let me give you an example from this week.</p>
<p>I recently invested in a company in the media &amp; entertainment sector (this will be announced in a couple of months) so I&#8217;ve been thinking a lot about how the industry works, why the structure has evolved the way it did, why the company I invested in has had so much success and what this all implies for the future.  I had to do all of this in order to get comfortable that the company had a scalable &amp; sustainable advantage and to think through the threats I thought they would encounter.</p>
<p>I started to build this into a media &amp; entertainment value chain that broke down the components of the industry into discrete parts.  I put my definitions on them because I didn&#8217;t want my thinking to be constrained by industry-defined boundaries or definitions.  From left to right I wrote in boxes: talent discovery, content development, production, post-production, distribution, &amp; marketing.  Underpinning it all I wrote: sales, asset management, analytics &amp; talent management.</p>
<p>I used these boxes to imagine what existing film, tv, radio &amp; print media companies did in each of these areas.  Were they <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vertical_integration">vertically integrated</a>?  If so, why?  Did they dominate one or two areas?  How did they come to do so?  Why do cable &amp; satellite companies force us to take content &#8220;bundles&#8221; that cost more than we want and have content we don&#8217;t watch.  Why?  Who else is complicit and equally bound by <a href="http://www.bothsidesofthetable.com/2010/11/04/understanding-how-the-innovators-dilemma-affects-you/">The Innovator&#8217;s Dilemma</a>?  Will this hold in the future?</p>
<p>Where do the new entrants like YouTube, Pandora, iTunes, Huffington Post, Boxee, Netflix, Demand Media and other disruptive offerings fit into that equation and how is it changing?  How much power does Google have due to search? How does social media on Facebook &amp; Twitter change things?</p>
<p>If the past required us to watch in a linear, time-based TV show that favored a grid-like TV Guide or electronic programming guides (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Electronic_program_guide">EPG</a>s), how will we find &amp; discover content in the world of over-abundance? Can the market support new entrants like Clicker or will it favor the old guard like Rovi?  If this appointment television had a 22-minute structure, is there a reason to expect that time allotment in the future? Why?</p>
<p>I wrote my initial conclusions in a post on <a href="http://www.bothsidesofthetable.com/2010/10/19/the-future-of-television-the-digital-living-room/">The Future of Television &amp; The Digital Living Room</a>.  If you read the post you&#8217;ll literally see the dissection of the topic in the way I saw it in my head.</p>
<p>But as I contemplate the future world I asked myself this new set of questions and I literally thought about each topic in my head and I scribbled notes onto my page.  I moved the boxes around, I changed where the arrows went, I drew bullet points underneath each box.  I rewrote the page 7-10 times.  Writing it &amp; re-writing it is not a problem &#8211; it is part of the creative process for me.</p>
<p>By having thought through the issues I can now begin the process of talking with industry people about this topic and why it works how it works.  I can ask for feedback in a focused way rather than a vague way.  &#8221;In which situations do you start with talent and built content that matches their talents and in which situation do you write the storyline first?&#8221; My framework gives me a deeper understanding of the sector.</p>
<p><strong>Creativity &amp; structure are not mutually exclusive</strong> &#8211; We associate creativity with the right side of our brain and logic or structure with the left side of our brains.  So having structure with creativity sounds like an oxymoron.  It is not.  In every brainstorming session I have (with myself) I start by scribbling down ideas in a rapid, free form way and then I look for structure.  As I already spoke about, when I do it with paper I often draw shapes, words, lines &amp; bullet points and then think out loud in my head with self talk to think about how they&#8217;re connected.</p>
<p>I have a process I use for blog posts, too.  The ideas themselves almost always come from an idea I had in discussions with others as part of my daily working life.  I then mull them over in my head when I&#8217;m jogging, when I&#8217;m driving or when I&#8217;m laying in bed.  I visualize the blog title and think about whether it will be impactful.  I often start thinking about sentences and constructing them in my head.  I think about what the key points are.</p>
<p>From there I add the title into WordPress. I probably have about 30 blog titles tee&#8217;d up to write for any day that I sit down.  I never really come to WordPress and think, &#8220;what should I write about today?&#8221;  Either it&#8217;s a thought I&#8217;ve had and have to get out of my head, or something I&#8217;m reacting to because I read a post that I want to respond to or &#8211; as is usually the case &#8211; I look through my titles and think, &#8220;which one am I passionate about today?&#8221;</p>
<p>And here&#8217;s where the formal structure comes in.  I almost always break up my post into sections before I write.  Just as in this post, I thought about the structure before letting the words flow out of my head and on to the screen. I organize the components of the topic, I write the section headings, I think about them each as individual titles, I think about whether the order flows and whether the overall narrative holds.</p>
<p>In a way, I&#8217;ve written the whole thing before a detailed word comes out of my head.  Then it&#8217;s just a function of writing each section, re-reading to test for flow, attempting to edit a bit and then hit publish.</p>
<p>I then think visually about the post.  I imagine people reading it.  I wonder whether it will make an impact.  If I think I&#8217;ve missed the mark I either delay publishing it or I rewrite sections.  Or &#8211; like today &#8211; I decide it&#8217;s too long for most readers but I still want to get all my thoughts out so I decide to add an executive summary for those with less time or interest.</p>
<p>But to be clear &#8211; it is structure that underpins my creative process.  Always.  Free form, then aggregation, then organization, then structure, then words, then metaphors, then narrative, then publish.  I becomes predictable and repeatable.</p>
<p><strong>The importance of solitude</strong> &#8211; I don&#8217;t believe in group creativity.  I understand that some people do.  They work well with a facilitator and they learn from hearing other people&#8217;s ideas.  Not me.  I really need a quite space, a blank canvass, a pen or keyboard, an objective, and enough time for ideas to flow.  In a group if I have a creative spark I have no time for it to marinate as other people begin speaking.</p>
<p>To be clear &#8211; V1 of my ideas are never the best I can do.  Once I have my ideas I then like to bring them to a public setting and take them for a test drive.  Debate is one of the most important ingredients in innovation.  But I like to show up to the debate with my &#8220;strawman&#8221; ideas rather than thinking about a topic for the first time.  It all starts on my own.</p>
<p><strong>Time pressure &amp; creativity </strong>- I&#8217;ve written about &#8220;<a href="http://www.bothsidesofthetable.com/2010/08/18/do-you-suffer-from-the-urgency-addiction-its-more-common-than-you-think/">The Urgency Addiction</a>&#8221; before.  The premise is that many people focus on stuff that&#8217;s urgent &amp; important when we should really focus on what&#8217;s not urgent &amp; important.  But people like me thrive on urgency.  For whatever reason it&#8217;s what gets my creative juices going.  I think that without a deadline my mind wanders too much on other tasks.  Knowing that I&#8217;m doing a speech in the morning in front of 200 people has a funny way of focusing my mind the night before if I haven&#8217;t finished my deck.  I have a high fear of failure that acts as my safety net.</p>
<p>In the urgency post I talked about creating artificial deadlines that get you to dig into the same creative urgency while giving yourself a buffer to refine your ideas.  I spoke at the <a href="http://nextgenconf.com/">NextGen conference</a> last week to a large audience.  It was on a Wednesday and I was traveling to be there.  I knew I&#8217;d have 7 other meetings the day before so I told myself that I HAD to finish the deck on Sunday night to avoid pulling an all-nighter on Tuesday and getting myself sick.  And that did the trick.</p>
<p>I decided the topic &#8211; &#8220;All the things I effed up at my first company.&#8221;  It was a conference for mostly college undergraduate students or recent graduates.  First time wantrepreneurs.  So I thought this would be a good topic.  I then took 20 blank Powerpoint pages.  I brainstormed the things I had messed up and wrote a title for each: raised too much money, wasn&#8217;t passionate about the industry, hired too senior of people, built too many products &amp; over spec&#8217;d them, internationalized too early, etc.</p>
<p>Next, I imagined a story I would tell for each topic and what image would represent that story.  I spent time on istockphoto and Google Images getting the images just right.  And in 2 hours I was done.  I woke up early the day of the presentation and I practiced the stories in my head.  I did self talk.  I visualized whether the story would be well received.  I tweaked a couple of titles and changed 2 pictures that didn&#8217;t sit right with me.  And then done.  If you&#8217;re interested the deck is <a href="http://www.docstoc.com/docs/document-preview.aspx?doc_id=69286554">here.</a></p>
<p>[tc_docstoc docid=69286554 width= 525 height=450 mid=29713]</p>
<p><a href="http://www.docstoc.com/docs/69286554/Things-I-Effed-Up-at-my-First-Company">Things I Effed Up at my First Company</a></p>
<p><strong>Invoking the creative brain</strong> &#8211; Have you ever noticed that you have more creative thoughts when you&#8217;re on a long drive?  For years I felt this and never understood why until I read &#8220;<a href="http://www.drawright.com/">Drawing on the Right Side of the Brain</a>&#8221; a book by Betty Edwards that talks about the creative process in art.  When you drive you&#8217;re forced to deal with 3D visual stimulation coming at you in a continual stream.  Your brain has to process this information and the process of dealing with all of this visual stimulus forces you into &#8220;right brain thinking&#8221; and when you&#8217;re in that zone you&#8217;re tapping into your creative potential.</p>
<p>Apparently what artists do when they sit at their canvass or when they record songs is get into this right-brain creative zone.  Artists often have more right-brain thinkings skills and so it comes more naturally.  For us left-brain thinkers we need to find ways to get into the zone.  When I&#8217;m in a creative zone I literally feel like an artist at work.</p>
<p>When I start scribbling on paper and am able to &#8220;see&#8221; solutions to problems or outline industry structures I feel &#8220;in the zone&#8221; and what I&#8217;ve learned over the years is that I need to have the right environment and stimuli.  That&#8217;s why I talk about the importance of being alone, my need for silence, having blank paper for scribbling notes furiously, applying time pressure and forcing myself to do unconstrained writing, which can be organized into patterns when I have a chance to read it later.</p>
<p>In addition to driving Ms. Edwards talks about the other natural activity that invokes creativity &#8211; taking a shower.  I&#8217;m sure you&#8217;ve noticed you&#8217;ve had creative thoughts in the shower before.  Be open to it.  I also get into the zone when I&#8217;m running and occasionally after a glass of wine.</p>
<p>One of the most interesting more recent things I&#8217;ve noticed lately is that Guitar Hero has the same impact on me as driving.  I&#8217;m forced to look at colors dropping rapidly on my TV and I have to hit the keys on my plastic guitar in rapid sequence.  There&#8217;s no way to deal with the falling colors logically so you literally start to &#8220;feel&#8221; the notes dropping and your fingers start to respond to your visual stimulus without rational thought.  This is the best way I can describe &#8220;the zone&#8221; to anyone who doesn&#8217;t regularly experience it.</p>
<p><strong>Reworking human interactions back into your creative design</strong> &#8211; I&#8217;ve talked a lot about my need to be creative on my own but as we all know it&#8217;s the power of human interactions that improves our thinking.  For me it&#8217;s just a question of when I bring other people into my process.  My first ideas never survive contact with others.  I&#8217;ll walk my model around several smart &amp; informed people on any topic.  I&#8217;ll practice my arguments and hear how they respond.</p>
<p>Sometimes it is by presenting to my colleagues and debating.  Sometimes it is by speaking at a conference in the way that comedians test drive their material at small venues before taking their shows on the road.  They use audience reactions to refine their craft.  I also feed off of the energy of others.  My ideas morph the way your products do when you test them with customers and watch how they use them.</p>
<p><strong>Being creative in an ADD world </strong>- Sitting at your computer can often detract from creativity, which is why I often do it with paper &amp; pen and in a room with no computer.  The problem I have on the computer is that there are always distractions to pull me away from my brainstorming.  I look up at the tabs in Chrome and see that there are two new @ messages to me in Twitter.  Somebody IM&#8217;s me in Gmail.  I feel like looking at the headlines on NYTimes.  I hear a bell ring in Outlook telling me, &#8220;you&#8217;ve got mail!&#8221;</p>
<p>I handle this in three ways.  Really important innovative thinking I do with pen &amp; paper.  If I need to innovate on my computer I try to turn off all my external stimuli (e.g. close email) so I can stay focused. Or if I&#8217;m struggling to get into the flow I take an ADD distraction break over on email or Twitter and come back to my brainstorming session 20 minutes later.</p>
<p><strong>Summary / Putting it Into Action:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Allocate enough time in your weekly routine for &#8220;being creative&#8221;</li>
<li>Find ways to invoke your creativity (driving, shower, wine, music) and learn what your best environment is (quite vs. music, alone vs. group)</li>
<li>Develop &amp; refine a process. It might be similar to mine: write, organize, shape, move objects, add bullet points, develop stories, etc. Or your process might be different.  But you need a process for innovation.  It doesn&#8217;t just happen.</li>
<li>Test your ideas with others, seek feedback, refine.</li>
<li>Have fun.  That&#8217;s what the creative process is supposed to be.</li>
<p>[crunchbase url="http://www.crunchbase.com/person/mark-suster" name="Mark Suster"]</ul>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/264323/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/264323/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/264323/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/264323/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/264323/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/264323/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/264323/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/264323/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/264323/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/264323/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/264323/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/264323/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/264323/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/264323/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=264323&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://techcrunch.com/2011/01/17/how-i-use-visualization-to-drive-creativity/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/e12f7aa1bd665c6be022576c0b8ebe9a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">guestauthor</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://www.bothsidesofthetable.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/visualization-brainstorming.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Regis Philbin Ruined My Brain</title>
		<link>http://thejackieblog.com/2011/01/17/regis-philbin-ruined-my-brain/</link>
		<comments>http://thejackieblog.com/2011/01/17/regis-philbin-ruined-my-brain/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2011 20:36:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jackie</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[365 Project]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[game shows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[postaday2011]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[regis philbin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trivia]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thejackieblog.com/?p=273</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I have wasted an incredible amount of brain storage for useless pop culture trivia and I fear I will never get it back. As I approach my quarter-of-a-century life celebration, I&#8217;m forced to again wonder how much I can possibly fit inside my brain before other material is pushed out. Of course, I wondered the [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=273&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 262px"><a href="http://buzzerblog.flashgameshows.com/who-wants-to-be-a-millionaire-eligibility-calls-now-going-out/"><img src="http://flashgameshows.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/100117_087_ful.jpg" alt="" width="252" height="189" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Regis Philbin, Ruiner of Brains and Dreams.</p></div>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">I have wasted an incredible amount of brain storage for useless pop culture trivia and I fear I will never get it back.</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">As I approach my quarter-of-a-century life celebration, I&#8217;m forced to again wonder how much I can possibly fit inside my brain before other material is pushed out.</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">Of course, I wondered the same thing in 4th grade and I&#8217;ve managed to make room for a decent amount of information since then.</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">But I can&#8217;t help but consider the useless knowledge I&#8217;ve racked up in the dusty attic of my cerebrum.  2nd edition rules for Dungeons and Dragons, the proper execution of raids in World of Warcraft, the names, titles, and prior affiliations of bands and artists from the 60&#8242;s, 70&#8242;s and 80&#8242;s, the entire plotline of Battlestar Galactica&#8230;  these are all fine details that have proven to be of absolutely no worth in real life.</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">Unless we are attacked by cylons.  Or wizards.  Then I&#8217;m President, no question.</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">The unfortunate reality of the situation is that these are all areas of study that were self-chosen.  And I&#8217;ve decided that there is only one thing to blame: Who Wants to Be a Millionaire.  Well, my incredible affinity for geeky hobbies and Who Wants to Be a Millionaire.</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">Long before people were just <em>handed</em> a million dollars at the beginning of the show only to waste it away, people actually had to work their way up a frightening ladder of trivia in order to have that beautiful, dirty money rain from the sky like confetti.  </span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">Regis would pull the check out after every ladder rung was successfully climbed, just to show the contestant a taste of what could be theirs if only they would walk away.</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">I watched at home on the edge of my seat.  All the answers up to the $32,000 mark were pop culture questions!  I only had to watch the most recent shows, listen to the most popular music, and watch the most popular videos to successfully work my way up the ladder to being a millionaire.  I spent time committing strange and random facts to memory, like who invented the lava lamp (for your information, it was Edward Craven Walker).  I even prepared for the possibility that a friend would need me when they were in the hot seat and practiced strategies for looking up the answer to a random question in less than 30 seconds.  </span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">My 8th grade math teacher compounded the problem, by reviewing homework and approaching critical thinking questions with the same rules as the popular game show.  He had actually entered to be a contestant and in anticipation of winning a place in the hot seat, he practiced strategies in the classroom.  If I didn&#8217;t know something, I could phone a friend,  try 50/50, or poll the entire class.</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">That turned out to be a policy other teachers were really not okay with.</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">Somewhere within the deep, dark crawlspaces of my subconcious, I truly believed that someday I would be called upon to represent the human race and be tested with a vast array of pop culture trivia, after which I would undoubtedly win and sprinkle my friends and family with greasy one dollar bills.  </span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">No one ever called.</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">The popularity of Millionaire began to decline and Regis Philbin bid adeiu.  New game shows were introduced that had nothing to do with knowledge.  America didn&#8217;t want to learn things, it wanted to watch people do ridiculous, degrading tasks for money in one minute or less.  They wanted to see beautiful women open suitcases full of cash.  They wanted to hook people up to lie detectors and see how much they can be humiliated before their friends and family before they step off the stage.</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">The Internet boasted information overload, Americans became dumber, and I became obselete.</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">I have no idea who is on the top 10 list for music or videos right now.  I don&#8217;t know even <em>one</em> song by Justin Bieber, and I had to google his last name just now to make sure I spelled it correctly.   I&#8217;m not entirely sure what&#8217;s on T.V. these days and I only browse Netflix&#8217;s Instant Queu long after popular shows have gone to DVD.</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">I have become old and oblivious.</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">If Meredith Viera called me today and asked me if I wanted to be a millionaire, I would admit in the affirmative and then immediately tell her I&#8217;m unworthy out of humiliation.   I am no match for today&#8217;s game show quizzes.</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">I wish I could do something with that space in my brain.  I wish I could go back and fill it with another language or Calc 3 or origami, but I can&#8217;t.</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">I can, however, embrace the new path of T.V. game shows.  I can attempt to move three eggs across my kitchen floor only by fanning them with an empty pizza box.  I can practice pulling tissues out of a box one by one as fast as possible and by only using one hand.   I can speed sort M&amp;Ms by color and place them into separate cups one at a time until I am the grand master of the world at M&amp;M speed sorting.</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">And so I shall.</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">Guy Fieri and the producers of Minute to Win It: I&#8217;ll be expecting your call.<span style="color:#3366ff;"> ♣</span></span></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/273/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/273/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/273/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/273/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/273/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/273/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/273/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/273/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/273/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/273/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/273/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/273/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/273/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/273/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=273&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thejackieblog.com/2011/01/17/regis-philbin-ruined-my-brain/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>43</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/8bceba58350ad75ac0585c27d2225419?s=96&#38;d=monsterid&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jacklynmarieb</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://flashgameshows.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/100117_087_ful.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Haven for Elephants and Rhinos (and my heart!)</title>
		<link>http://wandaswords.wordpress.com/2011/01/19/a-haven-for-elephants-and-rhinos-and-my-heart/</link>
		<comments>http://wandaswords.wordpress.com/2011/01/19/a-haven-for-elephants-and-rhinos-and-my-heart/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2011 21:50:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Wanda O'Brien</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Kenya]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[animals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David Sheldrick Wildlife Trust]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://wandaswords.wordpress.com/?p=440</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Within a month of being in Nairobi I went to visit the David Sheldrick Wildlife Trust: A Haven for Elephants and Rhinos. Located just outside Nairobi, the trust fosters orphaned elephants and rhinos, providing the nurture and care they need to grow into strong, independent adults. Become a temporary parent! Foster an ellie! Filed under: Kenya Tagged: [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=440&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://wandaswords.wordpress.com/2011/01/19/a-haven-for-elephants-and-rhinos-and-my-heart/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/8377f999aec5a97110376cea83202685?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">wobrien</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>My Friends Have Baggage</title>
		<link>http://thenestinggame.wordpress.com/2011/01/18/my-friends-have-baggage/</link>
		<comments>http://thenestinggame.wordpress.com/2011/01/18/my-friends-have-baggage/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2011 20:08:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Molly</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DIY]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Every Nest Needs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fabric]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Guest Room]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thenestinggame.wordpress.com/?p=702</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Since moving into the Nest, we have had a good amount of guests/visitors. Of course, Taylor&#8217;s kids come about once a month, but we&#8217;ve also had other friends and family popping in frequently. Which we love! One of my favorite travel finds is a luggage rack. If I stay at a hotel that doesn&#8217;t have [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=702&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Since moving into the Nest, we have had a good amount of guests/visitors. Of course, Taylor&#8217;s kids come about once a month, but we&#8217;ve also had other friends and family popping in frequently. Which we love! One of my favorite travel finds is a luggage rack. If I stay at a hotel that doesn&#8217;t have one in the room, I always call and they&#8217;ll bring one up to me. It&#8217;s just more civilized than throwing the suitcase on the desk or on the floor. And I&#8217;m all about civilized.</p>
<p>I snagged this from my grandparent&#8217;s house a few years ago. It&#8217;s pretty standard issue. In fact I think I&#8217;ve seen the exact same one out and about somewhere. <a onclick="return mugicPopWin(this,event);" oncontextmenu="mugicRightClick(this);" href="http://www.luggagepros.com/gate-house-furniture-luggage-rack-with-tapestry-straps.shtml?cm_mmc=cse-_-NexTag-_-GateHouseFurniture-_-PID648">Here</a> is a link to a similar one. P.S. and by the way, I would likely not spend $65 on this if I didn&#8217;t already own it&#8230;</p>
<p><a href="http://thenestinggame.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3571.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-704" title="IMG_3571" src="http://thenestinggame.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3571.jpg?w=600&#038;h=800" alt="" width="600" height="800" /></a></p>
<p>Anyhoozit, I&#8217;ve never been exactly wild about the ribbon straps and they were fraying, so while Taylor and I were at the insane <a href="http://www.gailkfabricsinc.com/">Gail K Fabrics </a>this weekend on a wedding-related outing, I peeked at the trim they have there and found this Greek Key goodness.</p>
<p><a href="http://thenestinggame.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3592.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-706" title="IMG_3592" src="http://thenestinggame.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3592.jpg?w=600&#038;h=800" alt="" width="600" height="800" /></a></p>
<p>Me likey.</p>
<p>So, I bought 2 yards of it for about 12 bucks. Sunday morning, I pulled out my handy dandy flat head screwdriver and staple gun and got to work removing the old ribbon and attaching the new stuff.</p>
<p>It took all of 15 minutes to get it done.</p>
<p>And here&#8217;s the new and improved luggage stand:</p>
<p><a href="http://thenestinggame.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3595.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-707" title="IMG_3595" src="http://thenestinggame.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3595.jpg?w=600&#038;h=800" alt="" width="600" height="800" /></a></p>
<p>Even though the room is on the warm side, I really love the black and white of the ribbon against the black stand. And we have a few black accents in the room, such as the framed artwork above the stand and on the etagere and a black and white enamel barber&#8217;s chest for a nightstand. (And I guess the crummy television set.)</p>
<p><a href="http://thenestinggame.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3596.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-708" title="IMG_3596" src="http://thenestinggame.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3596.jpg?w=600&#038;h=800" alt="" width="600" height="800" /></a></p>
<p>It&#8217;s the little things like this that keep me sane while doing wedding stuff.</p>
<p>You and your baggage are welcome anytime.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/702/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/702/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/702/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/702/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/702/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/702/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/702/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/702/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/702/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/702/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/702/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/702/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/702/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/702/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=702&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thenestinggame.wordpress.com/2011/01/18/my-friends-have-baggage/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/174ec4b2a4b981fda649cc80dffffccc?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Molly</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thenestinggame.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3571.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_3571</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thenestinggame.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3592.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_3592</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thenestinggame.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3595.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_3595</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thenestinggame.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3596.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_3596</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Blurbondency: how do you react to bamboozling book blurbs?</title>
		<link>http://lynseymay.wordpress.com/2011/01/18/blurbondency-how-do-you-react-to-bamboozling-book-blurbs/</link>
		<comments>http://lynseymay.wordpress.com/2011/01/18/blurbondency-how-do-you-react-to-bamboozling-book-blurbs/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2011 13:06:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lynsey May</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ranting in general]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bad blurbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blurbs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[favourite authors]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://lynseymay.wordpress.com/?p=811</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Blurbondency - The feeling of let down and confusion that follows reading a book because it has a blurb from one of your favourite authors, only to find the book disappointing and unreadable. Self doubt and a re-examination of bookshelves is also to be expected. Blurbs are powerful things. They act as the same kind [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=811&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote><p><strong>Blurbondency</strong> -<em> The feeling of let down and confusion that follows reading a book because it has a blurb from one of your favourite authors, only to find the book disappointing and unreadable. Self doubt and a re-examination of bookshelves is also to be expected. </em></p></blockquote>
<p>Blurbs are powerful things. They act as the same kind of seal of approval you&#8217;re looking for when you&#8217;re eyeing up a potential date. I&#8217;ve picked up and taken home plenty of books thanks to a few words of praise from one of my favourite authors &#8211; but you can&#8217;t always count on a blurb when you&#8217;re choosing what to snuggle up with at night.</p>
<p>Recently I read a book I just couldn&#8217;t get into. I could see it wasn&#8217;t awful, I could see it had some merit, but there were parts of it that really stuck in my craw. I sat contemplating the cover, and noticed it had blurbs from no fewer than three of my favourite authors. A strange mixture of feelings quickly arose. Confusion &#8211; were they talking about the same book? Self doubt &#8211; can&#8217;t I even tell a good book when I look at it? Shaken faith &#8211; are my favourite writers not the all-knowing beings I hoped they were?</p>
<p>Ultimately, I know that when judging books &#8211; as with all other art forms &#8211; there&#8217;s a great deal of subjectivity involved. You say tomato, I say pulpy, soppy trash. But that won&#8217;t stop me from suffering a good dose of blurbondency when the book and the blurb just don&#8217;t seem to fit.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/811/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/811/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/811/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/811/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/811/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/811/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/811/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/811/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/811/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/811/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/811/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/811/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/811/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/811/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=811&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://lynseymay.wordpress.com/2011/01/18/blurbondency-how-do-you-react-to-bamboozling-book-blurbs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>65</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/ed0284af60cb0603c2ac84e7f91ed227?s=96&#38;d=monsterid&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lynseymay</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Art of Preserves</title>
		<link>http://itiablog.wordpress.com/2011/01/18/the-art-of-preserves/</link>
		<comments>http://itiablog.wordpress.com/2011/01/18/the-art-of-preserves/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2011 08:45:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Anna</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Craft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Theology]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://itiablog.wordpress.com/?p=1988</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Sounds, tastes, and smells have the ability to transform a moment into a kind of transportation device into our memories. We can be transported to places of warmth, hope, and consolation, as much as moments of disappointment and grief. I remember it well: the evening we finished the last of the plum sauce. This was [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=1988&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://itiablog.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/dsc_0083.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-1989" title="ma's kitchen" src="http://itiablog.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/dsc_0083.jpg?w=230&#038;h=373" alt="" width="230" height="373" /></a>Sounds, tastes, and smells have the ability to transform a moment into a kind of transportation device into our memories. We can be transported to places of warmth, hope, and consolation, as much as moments of disappointment and grief.</p>
<p>I remember it well: the evening we finished the last of the plum sauce. This was not just any plum sauce; this was the last of the plum sauce made from the fruit of the orchard at &#8220;Rosedale,&#8221; a property that had been sold years before.</p>
<p>The Orchard and garden at Rosedale had provided many years of marmalade, apple sauce, chutneys and pickles, preserved peaches and apricots, and, of course, the plum sauce, years of preserves made in the kitchen of my mother&#8217;s mother.</p>
<p>The proliferation of colour and the smells of preserving are unmistakable: Vacola Bottles and lids with pressed lettering, sugar, vinegar, spices, and buckets and containers overflowing with fruits and vegetables. After preparation, and much boiling, the preserved fruit and vegetables are placed in sterilised glass jars and stored in the cool  of the pantry until they are needed, or given away to family and  friends.</p>
<p>The making of chutneys, relishes, jams, and preserved fruit and  vegetables is an art. The art of preserving food is not just utilitarian, though its most  important function is to preserve the fruits of the harvest for the  leaner winter months. Preserved food often provides variety in the diet. After all, when the fruits of the harvest have been collected, and you have tomatoes and apples filling every bowl, bucket and box you own, a little variety offered by the act and art of preserving becomes a way, in itself, of preserving the vestiges of thankfulness of that harvest when you are sick to death of tomato sandwiches. As my grandmother often says, &#8220;there&#8217;s only so many ways you  can eat zucchini.&#8221;</p>
<p><a href="http://itiablog.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/fruitcolourpalette.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-2037" title="fruitcolourpalette" src="http://itiablog.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/fruitcolourpalette.jpg?w=288&#038;h=191" alt="" width="288" height="191" /></a>The value of place and the ritual of preserves  has a richness greater  than simply the outcome of food for the winter. Preserving food in this way is rarely done alone. From the cultivation of the fruit and vegetables, to the preparation, peeling, cutting, and boiling of the ingredients in bulk, the work lends itself towards groups working together under the direction of a leader. In my case my grandmother, who uses the recipes of her mother and grandmother.</p>
<p>This domestic art is  worth celebrating and cultivating. In the very least, the cost effectiveness of growing your own vegetables and using them in nutritionally healthy ways, is a wonderful use of the fruits of the earth, and something satisfying for the hands and the heart.</p>
<p><a href="http://itiablog.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/lomotomatoes.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-2033" title="lomotomatoes" src="http://itiablog.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/lomotomatoes.jpg?w=378&#038;h=251" alt="" width="378" height="251" /></a>Aesthetically, the way the massed  jars look on the pantry shelves has always fascinated me. The beauty of  repetition of a simple pattern is the design principle, but nonetheless  there&#8217;s a satisfaction about seeing the stacked bottles with their rounded shapes suspended in viscous liquid.</p>
<p>So why is it that the last of the &#8220;Rosedale&#8221; batch looms so large in my mind? It may be this: the recipes and process for preserving food is relatively simple, but like all art the true richness must begin with the quality of materials. Those plums were just something else. There has been other plum sauce, but it has never been, nor will be    quite the same.</p>
<p>As I walked into her kitchen the other day,<a href="http://itiablog.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/smallplumsauce.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-2036 alignright" title="plumsauce" src="http://itiablog.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/smallplumsauce.jpg?w=200&#038;h=310" alt="" width="200" height="310" /></a> the smell of vinegar wafted  through the air as the apple cucumbers were  pickling on my  grandmother&#8217;s stove. There were bowls overflowing with tomatoes on the counter, the stove, and in the fridge. And there was a bottle of plum sauce on the island bench.</p>
<p>Now let&#8217;s talk: <em>Is this a domestic art you grew up with, still practise and cultivate? Why? Where do you source your fruit and vegetables? Do you think of it as a creative process? If you&#8217;ve never preserved food in this way before, have you ever considered doing so?</em></p>
<p><strong>Images</strong>: Author</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1988/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1988/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1988/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1988/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1988/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1988/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1988/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1988/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1988/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1988/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1988/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1988/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1988/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1988/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=1988&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://itiablog.wordpress.com/2011/01/18/the-art-of-preserves/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>20</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Goannatree</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://itiablog.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/dsc_0083.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ma's kitchen</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://itiablog.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/fruitcolourpalette.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">fruitcolourpalette</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://itiablog.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/lomotomatoes.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lomotomatoes</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://itiablog.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/smallplumsauce.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">plumsauce</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Many Spaces Should You Put After a Period?</title>
		<link>http://westerntradition.wordpress.com/2011/01/18/how-many-spaces-should-you-put-after-a-period/</link>
		<comments>http://westerntradition.wordpress.com/2011/01/18/how-many-spaces-should-you-put-after-a-period/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2011 14:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dr. J</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Academia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://westerntradition.wordpress.com/?p=823</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I know you have all lost many hours of sleep over this question, so I&#8217;m here to relieve your stress. For a journal editor, few tasks are more tedious than going through a document and fixing all the incorrect spacing at the ends of sentences, so please, if you ever decide to send me anything, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=823&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://westerntradition.wordpress.com/2011/01/18/how-many-spaces-should-you-put-after-a-period/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>91</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/e03e46b800a6029f1181d18885d946ff?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">profjej</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://westerntradition.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/typewriter_1_md.gif?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">typewriter_1_md</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Day 48 &#8211; Tiago, Valpo &amp; Viña</title>
		<link>http://monotonundminimal.wordpress.com/2011/01/17/day-48-tiago-valpo-vina/</link>
		<comments>http://monotonundminimal.wordpress.com/2011/01/17/day-48-tiago-valpo-vina/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2011 20:48:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>minimal</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[South America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drinks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[friends & relatives]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[santiago]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[south america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[valparaiso]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[viña del mar]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://monotonundminimal.wordpress.com/?p=302</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[We arrived in Santiago on day 43 and were warmly received by our extended family in Chile. The next day we headed early in the morning to Valpo (Valparaiso) and Viña (Viña del Mar), two adjacent cities on the Chilean coast that are each other&#8217;s opposite. We found Valpo to be charming and enchanting with [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=302&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://monotonundminimal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3331.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-303" title="Breakfast" src="http://monotonundminimal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3331.jpg?w=700&#038;h=525" alt="" width="700" height="525" /></a></p>
<p>We arrived in Santiago on day 43 and were warmly received by our extended family in Chile.</p>
<p><a href="http://monotonundminimal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3256.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-304" title="Valpo" src="http://monotonundminimal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3256.jpg?w=700&#038;h=525" alt="" width="700" height="525" /></a></p>
<p>The next day we headed early in the morning to Valpo (Valparaiso) and Viña (Viña del Mar), two adjacent cities on the Chilean coast that are each other&#8217;s opposite. We found Valpo to be charming and enchanting with lots of character, and thanks to our lovely guides, Paloma and Kote, we had a great time.</p>
<p><a href="http://monotonundminimal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3251.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-306" title="Valpo" src="http://monotonundminimal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3251.jpg?w=700&#038;h=525" alt="" width="700" height="525" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://monotonundminimal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3251.jpg"></a><a href="http://monotonundminimal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3278.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-305" title="Mural" src="http://monotonundminimal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3278.jpg?w=700&#038;h=525" alt="" width="700" height="525" /></a></p>
<p>Valpo is home to many artists and bohemians, we visited <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pablo_Neruda">Pablo Neruda</a>&#8216;s home that was both charming, crazy and inspiring, unfortunately we weren&#8217;t allowed to take any photos so you&#8217;ll have to visit it for yourself.</p>
<p><a href="http://monotonundminimal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3272.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-307" title="Chorrillana" src="http://monotonundminimal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3272.jpg?w=700&#038;h=525" alt="" width="700" height="525" /></a></p>
<p>We tasted several Chilean specialities, here is one typical of Valpo, the Chorrillana, which is supposed to be  great hang-over food.</p>
<p><a href="http://monotonundminimal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3291.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-308" title="Abandoned Train" src="http://monotonundminimal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3291.jpg?w=700&#038;h=525" alt="" width="700" height="525" /></a></p>
<p>This abandoned train was scaring passers-by with its ghost piano.</p>
<p><a href="http://monotonundminimal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3288.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-309" title="Ghost Café" src="http://monotonundminimal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3288.jpg?w=490&#038;h=653" alt="" width="490" height="653" /></a></p>
<p>Fortunately we were courageous enough to take a look inside and found a lovely café called, El Tren Mas Lento Del Mundo, we had home-made pastries and a cup of coffee.</p>
<p><a href="http://monotonundminimal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3293.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-310" title="Viña Beach" src="http://monotonundminimal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3293.jpg?w=700&#038;h=525" alt="" width="700" height="525" /></a></p>
<p>We walked over to Viña to find it crowded and somewhat polished, pretty enough but not as interesting as Valpo, according to our taste. The shoreline was beautiful but all beaches had signs saying that they were not suitable for bathing. Hard to tell if people had missed the sign or just didn&#8217;t care.</p>
<p><a href="http://monotonundminimal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3299.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-311" title="In Case Of A Tsunami" src="http://monotonundminimal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3299.jpg?w=490&#038;h=653" alt="" width="490" height="653" /></a></p>
<p>Today there was no tsunami, but it is good to know in which direction to run.</p>
<p><a href="http://monotonundminimal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3301.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-312" title="AFS Reunion II" src="http://monotonundminimal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3301.jpg?w=700&#038;h=525" alt="" width="700" height="525" /></a></p>
<p>Back in Santiago we met up with an old friend, Alejandra and I did an exchange year in the United States 13 years ago. She took us to a lovely Peruvian restaurant and we had a great night, tasting local wine and talking about old times.</p>
<p><a href="http://monotonundminimal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3307.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-313" title="Mapuche Ponchos" src="http://monotonundminimal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3307.jpg?w=700&#038;h=525" alt="" width="700" height="525" /></a></p>
<p>Day 45 we walked around Santiago and visited the Centro Cultural de la Moneda.</p>
<p><a href="http://monotonundminimal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3310.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-314" title="Udder" src="http://monotonundminimal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3310.jpg?w=700&#038;h=525" alt="" width="700" height="525" /></a></p>
<p>Yes, it comes from a cow.</p>
<p><a href="http://monotonundminimal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3317.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-315" title="Salvador Allende" src="http://monotonundminimal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3317.jpg?w=490&#038;h=653" alt="" width="490" height="653" /></a></p>
<p>Santiago is full of history, a statue of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Salvador_Allende">Salvador Allende</a> reminds us of his murder here in El Palacio de la Moneda on the 11th of September 1973, the day of the Chilean military coup.</p>
<p><a href="http://monotonundminimal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3320.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-316" title="Completo" src="http://monotonundminimal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3320.jpg?w=490&#038;h=653" alt="" width="490" height="653" /></a></p>
<p>Completo is this tasty Chilean speciality, you just pop by one of these bars and eat it standing, yummy.</p>
<p><a href="http://monotonundminimal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3322.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-317" title="Mote con Huesillo" src="http://monotonundminimal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3322.jpg?w=490&#038;h=653" alt="" width="490" height="653" /></a></p>
<p>A dessert speciality, Mote con Huesillo, I wouldn&#8217;t be able to tell you what it is by its name, the only word I understand in that name is <em>con</em> which means <em>with</em>, but it is great for any sweet-tooth looking for a refreshment.</p>
<p><a href="http://monotonundminimal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3324.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-318" title="Plaza de Armas" src="http://monotonundminimal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3324.jpg?w=700&#038;h=525" alt="" width="700" height="525" /></a></p>
<p>Tribute to the indigenous community.</p>
<p><a href="http://monotonundminimal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3325.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-319" title="Caressing The Moon" src="http://monotonundminimal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3325.jpg?w=490&#038;h=653" alt="" width="490" height="653" /></a></p>
<p>Johan found this sculpture particularly interesting since this must have been the first square we visited in South America that didn&#8217;t have a monument with some old hero standing or riding a horse. And look at that, the moon!</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/302/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/302/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/302/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/302/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/302/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/302/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/302/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/302/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/302/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/302/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/302/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/302/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/302/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/302/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=302&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://monotonundminimal.wordpress.com/2011/01/17/day-48-tiago-valpo-vina/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/a8fba9c1e9ca1afca7b7f74063d4b404?s=96&#38;d=wavatar&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2talmente</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://monotonundminimal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3331.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Breakfast</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://monotonundminimal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3256.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Valpo</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://monotonundminimal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3251.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Valpo</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://monotonundminimal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3278.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mural</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://monotonundminimal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3272.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Chorrillana</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://monotonundminimal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3291.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Abandoned Train</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://monotonundminimal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3288.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ghost Café</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://monotonundminimal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3293.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Viña Beach</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://monotonundminimal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3299.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">In Case Of A Tsunami</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://monotonundminimal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3301.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">AFS Reunion II</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://monotonundminimal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3307.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mapuche Ponchos</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://monotonundminimal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3310.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Udder</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://monotonundminimal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3317.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Salvador Allende</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://monotonundminimal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3320.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Completo</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://monotonundminimal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3322.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mote con Huesillo</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://monotonundminimal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3324.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Plaza de Armas</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://monotonundminimal.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/img_3325.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Caressing The Moon</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Jobs 2.0: Data-centric Jobs for Generation Y</title>
		<link>http://gigaom.com/2011/01/17/jobs-2-0-data-centric-jobs-for-generation-y/</link>
		<comments>http://gigaom.com/2011/01/17/jobs-2-0-data-centric-jobs-for-generation-y/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2011 15:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Guest Column</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Career]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jobs]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://gigaom.com/?p=286744</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[While some may say that Generation Y are slackers, I think they’re just waiting around for the next crop of interesting jobs. Well, good news, 20-somethings, the new fall line of jobs is here! You’ll note that most of these jobs center around one thing: data. <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=286744&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://gigaom2.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/helpwanted.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-286855" title="helpwanted" src="http://gigaom2.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/helpwanted.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a>While some may say that Generation Y are slackers, I think they’re just waiting around for the next crop of interesting jobs. Well, good news, 20-somethings, the new fall line of jobs is here! You’ll note that most of these jobs center around one thing: data. Gen Y (which I prefer to call Gen A, for &#8220;Analysis&#8221;) will be the first generation entering the workforce that have the skills to apply measurement and analysis to everything. They’ve been counting calories on their iPhones (s aapl), anxiously trying to raise their <a href="http://klout.com/">Klout</a> scores and driving their follow counts on Twitter. Data is the new black.</p>
<h3>Content Monetization Manager (Department: Production)</h3>
<p>There are an incredible number of ways to monetize content coming onto the horizon. The days of CPM being the only game in town are over. Affiliate links, daily deals, in-text ads, sponsorships, promoted on-site Twitter feeds and remnant inventory optimization: It’s all coming your way if you make money from content. How to best utilize these monetization strategies for your users, your content, your site design and your bottom line is a tricky thing. The content monetization manager will make use of all of the content monetization tools available, the underlying usage analytics, and the CMS, and will constantly A/B test monetization strategies and page layouts to maximize revenue, while preserving the user experience.</p>
<h3>Webmaster 2.0 (Department: Marketing)</h3>
<p>Pretty much no one has the title of &#8220;Webmaster&#8221; any more. But like all things retro, it&#8217;s coming back. The new webmaster, much like the content monetization manager, will be responsible for fine-tuning every detail of the corporate website to produce the desired result (sales or leads). Websites are becoming much more dynamic, more content-heavy (including text, images and video), and blurring with corporate blogs. Tools of the webmaster 2.0 include <a href="http://www.google.com/analytics/">Google Analytics</a> (s goog), SEO, <a href="http://www.salesforce.com/">Salesforce</a> (s crm) integration (for closed-loop data), and the CMS. The job will include lots of A/B testing of landing pages, <a href="http://52weeksofux.com/post/646711369/cohort-analysis-measuring-engagement-over-time">cohort analysis</a> and a healthy dose of keyword and inbound linking SEO.</p>
<h3>Amplification Manager (Department: Marketing)</h3>
<p>As social media evolves and expands, it also becomes more diluted. Many social media vanguards have now pushed Tweeting and Facebooking down to the internship level (partly because it is so time-consuming). What is emerging is a radical new philosophy of amplification: the ability to use social media, SEO, virality, and sharing as a powerful mechanism for promotion. While most social media managers would sum up the first five years of social media as “engagement,” the next five will be about “amplifying.” Like having sharing buttons in all the right places, cross-posting, SEO, targeted retweets and Klout scores (amplification being a big part of this score). If you’re not amplifying, you’re dying.</p>
<h3>Game Mechanics Designer (Department: Engineering/Product Management)</h3>
<p>Just like almost every website has a sharing feature, every application in the next few years will have game mechanics. Easy to understand, but harder than you think to design, game mechanics will become a full-fledged job. Just like any application development company worth its salt has a studied and knowledgeable UX person on the team, the game mechanics designer role will become just as important and prevalent.</p>
<h3>Employee Mechanics Designer (Department: HR)</h3>
<p>The future of the employee experience will be much like <a href="http://foursquare.com/">Foursquare</a>. You’re in sales and made 50 phone calls in a day? Great, you just got the “Heavy Dialer” badge. You’re in QA? Well how many bugs did you close out today? Check the company QA leaderboard. It’s all coming; Marc Benioff is already talking about integrating these kind of features into Salesforce.com.</p>
<p>Much like the game mechanics designer designs the incentive and engagement structure in your application, the employee mechanics designer will design the internal game that is your business, which will include an ever-evolving set of rules that must be aligned with the current goals of the company.</p>
<h3>Metrics Manager (Department: Finance)</h3>
<p>The metric manager&#8217;s job is to extract data from every nook and cranny of the company. Once the stream of data is flowing, it’s then time to put it in a data warehouse and do interesting things with it. Pretty charts and pictures usually are the most engaging place to start, but departmental dashboards and daily metrics emails will be more useful. Metrics managers will love statistics and <a href="http://www.edwardtufte.com/tufte/">Tufte</a>.</p>
<h3>Crowd Manager (Department: Crowd and Community – A New Department)</h3>
<p>In the next 10 years, every company will leverage the crowd in some shape or form. Whether it’s directly through building applications in <a href="https://www.mturk.com/">Mechanical Turk</a> or sponsoring designs in <a onclick="return mugicPopWin(this,event);" oncontextmenu="mugicRightClick(this);" href="http://99designs.com/">99Designs</a>, or indirectly by managing a sub-crowd in a marketplaces like <a href="http://www.trada.com/">Trada</a> (for advertising) or <a href="http://www.napkinlabs.com/">Napkin Labs</a> (for design). How you interface with the crowd, how you incentivize them (payment, praise, virtual currency, rewards), and, more importantly, how you teach your own company to work with them correctly is key.</p>
<p>In case you don’t want to work for anyone (how very Gen-Y of you) &#8212; there are also some amazing self-employment opportunities arising as well:</p>
<h3>Crowd Worker (Self-Employed)</h3>
<p>Having a boss is so 2010. The next generation of workers will be gainfully self-employed working in the crowd whenever and wherever they want. As crowdsourcing marketplaces (such as Trada’s performance-based advertising marketplace) reach critical mass and generate real dollars for their workers, full-time livings are being made by a few. Soon the few shall be the masses. 2011 will be the year that crowdsourcing as a viable business <em>and</em> a viable job becomes a reality.</p>
<p>Expect the increase in the self-service workforce to drive the need for new regulation (and opportunity) around individual and group-buying healthcare. It would also be a good time to invest in Starbucks (s sbux), the primary office-space of the crowd-crowd.</p>
<h3>Life Coach 2.0 (Self-Employed)</h3>
<p>It used to be the good old days where you could just pack your old self in a box, move to another town, and start over. Unfortunately, with everything in the cloud, your former self is destined to keep following you. What you need is some expertise.</p>
<p>The new life coach will be versed in online reputation building and PR. They’ll know about services like <a href="https://about.me/">About.me</a> before you do. They’ll be monitoring your Klout scores and crowd reputation. Breach some etiquette on Twitter or make some public <em>faux pas</em> – no problem – your life coach can just SEO that away for you in a few weeks.</p>
<p>As the future become about reputation, engagement and online social profile, we’ll all need a little help smoothing out the edges. Life coaches will need to know about building reputation, scoring algorithms, and how to be a better you (at least statistically speaking).</p>
<h3>Personal Trainer 2.0 (Self-Employed)</h3>
<p>The future of the self is measurement. How many footsteps did I take today (<a href="http://www.fitbit.com/">FitBit</a>)? How many calls at work did I make (employee game mechanics)? How did my Klout score go up or down? Am I meeting my workout goals on <a href="http://www.dailymile.com/">DailyMile</a>?  The old personal trainer/nutritionist role will morph into a digital age version of itself, focused on measuring first, optimizing second. Skills will include technology (measurement), data management (storage), analysis, and medical and privacy law.</p>
<p><em>Niel Robertson is a three-time entrepreneur and CEO of <a href="http://www.trada.com/">Trada Paid Search</a>, a crowdsourced paid search marketplace. You can find Niel on Twitter at <a href="http://twitter.com/nielr1">@nielr1</a>. </em></p>
<p><strong>Related content from GigaOM Pro (sub. req.):</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a title="Report: The Real-Time Enterprise" href="http://pro.gigaom.com/2010/05/are-you-empowering-your-mobile-workforce/?utm_source=webworkerdaily&amp;utm_medium=editorial&amp;utm_content=simonmackie&amp;utm_campaign=related3">Are You Empowering Your Mobile Workforce?</a></li>
<li><a title="Report: The Real-Time Enterprise" href="http://pro.gigaom.com/2010/01/report-the-real-time-enterprise/?utm_source=webworkerdaily&amp;utm_medium=editorial&amp;utm_content=simonmackie&amp;utm_campaign=related3">Report: The Real-Time Enterprise</a></li>
<li><a href="http://pro.gigaom.com/2010/01/who-owns-your-data-in-the-cloud/?utm_source=webworkerdaily&amp;utm_medium=editorial&amp;utm_content=simonmackie&amp;utm_campaign=related3">Who Owns Your Data in the Cloud?</a></li>
</ul>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/286744/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/286744/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/286744/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/286744/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/286744/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/286744/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/286744/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/286744/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/286744/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/286744/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/286744/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/286744/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/286744/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/286744/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=286744&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://gigaom.com/2011/01/17/jobs-2-0-data-centric-jobs-for-generation-y/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/4411542bbd7a2a9a2fc2a1b38809e45c?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F0.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gigaguest</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://gigaom2.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/helpwanted.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">helpwanted</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>January, 18</title>
		<link>http://onebreakfastaday.wordpress.com/2011/01/18/january-18/</link>
		<comments>http://onebreakfastaday.wordpress.com/2011/01/18/january-18/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2011 14:45:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sere</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Breakfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blueberries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Speculaas]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onebreakfastaday.wordpress.com/?p=60</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Oyez, oyez, oyez! Non-Belgian world meet Pâte de Speculaas! Whole wheat toast with Pâte de Speculaas, blueberries (plus an orange and caffèlatte) Here people are so obsessed with Speculaas that they even made a kind of spread with them. It actually tastes quite good. Coming soon&#8230; more Belgian breakfast food, guess what?<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=60&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Oyez, oyez, oyez! Non-Belgian world meet <span style="font-size:15px;font-weight:bold;">Pâte de Speculaas!</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size:15px;font-weight:bold;"><a href="http://onebreakfastaday.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/dsc_0208.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-61" title="Pate de Speculoos" src="http://onebreakfastaday.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/dsc_0208.jpg?w=490&#038;h=325" alt="" width="490" height="325" /></a></span></p>
<div>
<div>
<div>
<div>
<div>
<p style="text-align:center;"><em>Whole wheat toast with Pâte de Speculaas, blueberries </em></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><em>(plus an orange and caffèlatte)</em></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Here people are so obsessed with <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Speculaas">Speculaas</a> that they even made a kind of spread with them. It actually tastes quite good.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Coming soon&#8230; more Belgian breakfast food, guess what?</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/60/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/60/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/60/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/60/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/60/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/60/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/60/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/60/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/60/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/60/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/60/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/60/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/60/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/60/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=60&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://onebreakfastaday.wordpress.com/2011/01/18/january-18/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>28</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/bb4975903d26a5716ef30fe7a642e26b?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">seremm</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://onebreakfastaday.files.wordpress.com/2011/01/dsc_0208.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Pate de Speculoos</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>