<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2013 20:02:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>The Other Iraq (Part 2)</title>
		<link>http://samnorthcote.wordpress.com/2013/02/03/the-other-iraq-part-2/</link>
		<comments>http://samnorthcote.wordpress.com/2013/02/03/the-other-iraq-part-2/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2013 22:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Mystery Tramp</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Iraq]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bazaar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[current affairs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Iraq War]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kurdistan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Middle East]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mosul]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[post-war Iraq]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Saddam Hussein]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sulaymaniyah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://samnorthcote.wordpress.com/?p=332</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The Department of State warns U.S. citizens against all but essential travel to Iraq given the security situation. Travel within Iraq remains dangerous. This Travel Warning replaces the Travel Warning dated January 19, 2012, to update information on security incidents and to remind U.S. citizens of ongoing security concerns for U.S. citizens in Iraq, including [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=332&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://samnorthcote.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/img_0824-002.jpg"><img style="background-image:none;padding-left:0;padding-right:0;display:inline;padding-top:0;border-width:0;" title="IMG_0824-002" alt="IMG_0824-002" src="http://samnorthcote.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/img_0824-002_thumb.jpg?w=640&#038;h=460" width="640" height="460" border="0" /></a></p>
<blockquote><p><span style="color:#666666;">The Department of State warns U.S. citizens against all but essential travel to Iraq given the security situation. Travel within Iraq remains dangerous. This Travel Warning replaces the Travel Warning dated January 19, 2012, to update information on security incidents and to remind U.S. citizens of ongoing security concerns for U.S. citizens in Iraq, including kidnapping and terrorist violence. The United States completed its withdrawal of military forces from Iraq as of December 31, 2011. The ability of the Embassy to respond to situations where U.S. citizens face difficulty, including arrests, is extremely limited.</span></p></blockquote>
<p>If you follow the international news you’ll know that Iraq is still being torn apart by sectarian violence more than a year after the US Army and its allies pulled out of the country. The coalition forces have brought some kind of democracy to the place but they failed to put an end to the mass slaughter which is indiscriminately laying waste to the population. The Angel of Death works overtime in this land, visiting pain on household after household. And a spirit of enmity continues to divide religious sects and ethnic groups. Unsurprisingly emotions are strongest in the oil-rich areas.</p>
<p>That being said I can say with hand on heart that the Kurdish-majority northern part of Iraq felt to me as safe as anywhere else I’ve been. Several times I roamed freely on my own without feeling threatened at all. In all honesty I have felt more at risk in parts of New York or London than I did in downtown Sulaymaniyah. When I walked in the bazaar the locals barely paid any attention to me even though I was the only white face in the crowd. And when they did interact with me they were invariably charming and friendly.</p>
<p>Perhaps I am a little reckless. Or just stupid. My friend Ciprian, who has been living there for around three months now, was more nervous about me going out on my own than I was. He advised me not to take taxis on my own, fearing I’d be an easy target for kidnappers. One time I told him I was going outside to take some photos but when he saw me fish my brand new Canon EOS 550D out of my bag an ashen look came over him. ‘I don’t think that’s a good idea,’ he said, ‘it’ll attract too much attention.’ Nonetheless I ventured into the thronging bazaar shooting away with my DSLR and all I got by way of a reaction was a friendly salute from this kid.</p>
<p><a href="http://samnorthcote.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/img_0799.jpg"><img style="background-image:none;padding-left:0;padding-right:0;display:inline;padding-top:0;border-width:0;" title="IMG_0799" alt="IMG_0799" src="http://samnorthcote.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/img_0799_thumb.jpg?w=640&#038;h=435" width="640" height="435" border="0" /></a></p>
<p>However, I do not wish to deny the disturbances which do sometimes take place in Sulaymaniyah. In March of last year an American teacher was shot dead in front of his class by one of his students. The reason for his horrific fate may be that he was an outspoken Christian. At an international church which congregates in a rented room of a shopping mall I spoke to several people who knew him. They all agreed that this teacher had been too forward in his attempts to evangelise the Kurdish people, who are predominantly Muslim. The student who shot him had not responded well to having his worldview challenged. Exposure to Christian teaching left him confused – some days he embraced it eagerly, other days he reacted angrily to it.</p>
<p>There was also a consensus in the international church that the American teacher had been an extremely kind-hearted and approachable individual. Even Kak Amanj knew him and claimed that he was a close friend.</p>
<p>Such shootings are relatively rare in Sulaymaniyah. But, as I said in my previous <a href="http://samnorthcote.wordpress.com/2013/01/28/the-other-iraq-part-1">post</a>, political demonstrations are common and sometimes things can get ugly. If you want to read about some of these protests from the perspective of a Kurdish blogger who has been under fire from the government’s riot squads I recommend you check out <a href="http://themovingsilent.wordpress.com/2011/02/17/sulaymaniyah-iraqi-kurdistan-they-killed-the-protesters-they-killed-the-people/">The Moving Silent</a>.</p>
<p>I had arrived in Iraqi Kurdistan at around 5am on Saturday, the 12th of January 2013. And after a bumpy ride from the airport in Kak Amanj’s battered car we arrived at Ciprian’s dorm. His living conditions are Spartan, like a cell in a hermitage or something. A stripped-down type of life. There is no inbuilt heating and Ciprian hates the smell of the bulky kerosene heaters which are normally used to heat interiors in Sulaymaniyah, not to mention the twofold danger of fire and carbon-monoxide poisoning which they pose. So he instead uses a small electric fan-heater. The only problem with that is the power-cuts which happen several times daily. You see, Sulaymaniyah’s power-grid was not built to handle modern-day levels of electricity consumption. As wealth grows in the city more and more people can afford to run air-conditioning and other power-hungry appliances and the electrical system can’t cope. Most businesses have back-up generators, and their insistent humming is part of the sonic background of the city. Some shrewd entrepreneurs have bought large generators and earn a tidy profit from providing back-up power to residential neighbourhoods for a fee.</p>
<p><a href="http://samnorthcote.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/img_0769.jpg"><img style="background-image:none;padding-left:0;padding-right:0;display:inline;padding-top:0;border-width:0;" title="IMG_0769" alt="IMG_0769" src="http://samnorthcote.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/img_0769_thumb.jpg?w=639&#038;h=431" width="639" height="431" border="0" /></a></p>
<p>Ciprian says he can handle the primitive conditions of the dorm. Having spent his childhood in communist-era Romania when food and other basic necessities were in short supply he is familiar with extreme deprivation. But one thing he can’t stand is the cold. Even with the electric heater on he goes to bed nearly fully clothed and still complains that he’s not warm enough. It doesn’t help that his balcony door doesn’t close properly and is only secured with an elastic band tied to the bunk-bed. One night there was a sandstorm raging outside and this door was constantly being yanked open by the fierce wind. Funnily enough I didn’t feel cold at all in the room. I guess all those bitter winters I spent in Beijing count for something.</p>
<p>Ciprian’s neighbour, a slightly eccentric maths teacher called Kak Salim, was pleased to see his Romanian friend. ‘I thought you were never coming back!’ he exclaimed. (Ciprian had been traveling around Europe for a month or so, visiting his scattered family and doing musical performances). Kak Salim welcomed us with a plateful of dried figs, raisins and assorted nuts which had apparently come from Iran. Then he went back to his room to Skype his fiancée.</p>
<p>We also met the guy who was Ciprian’s roommate when he first arrived in the dorm, before he moved into a room of his own. I don’t recall his name but he was a Catholic from Mosul, a city about four hours drive north of Sulaymaniyah. Mosul is said to be a hub of al-Qaeda activity and is regularly buffeted by violence. The city’s Christians in particular are being forced out by targeted attacks. Just three days before I arrived in the country a Chaldean Christian teacher had her throat cut in Mosul and the following day a car bomb claimed the life of a Christian final-year medical student.</p>
<p>Ciprian’s ex-roommate is doing a PhD in family medicine. The ongoing violence in Mosul made it impossible for him to complete his course there. So, to pursue an uninterrupted education and to escape the brutal attacks on Christians in his hometown, he moved to the comparatively peaceful Sulaymaniyah where, amazingly, schools were only stopped once during the Iraq War. He is now in his final year of study and when he finishes he will apply for refugee status and move to the USA. His sisters are already living over there.</p>
<p>The three of us sat down to a simple breakfast in Ciprian’s room – freshly baked naan, cream cheese, jam, a salty yoghurt drink called <em>ayran</em>, and mandarins.</p>
<p>Then we hit the bazaar – Ciprian and myself – to drink sweet cardamom tea and buy a guitar. I would frequent the bazaar in the coming days after developing a strong attachment to the sweet tea, savouring its delectable comfort on cold mornings. The teashop owners for the most part were exceptionally friendly and sometimes would refuse to accept payment from us for the tea.</p>
<p><a href="http://samnorthcote.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/img_0550.jpg"><img style="background-image:none;padding-left:0;padding-right:0;display:inline;padding-top:0;border-width:0;" title="IMG_0550" alt="IMG_0550" src="http://samnorthcote.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/img_0550_thumb.jpg?w=640&#038;h=435" width="640" height="435" border="0" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://samnorthcote.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/img_0562.jpg"><img style="background-image:none;padding-left:0;padding-right:0;display:inline;padding-top:0;border-width:0;" title="IMG_0562" alt="IMG_0562" src="http://samnorthcote.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/img_0562_thumb.jpg?w=640&#038;h=434" width="640" height="434" border="0" /></a></p>
<p>As I already said I never once felt in danger when walking around the bazaar. Strangely I didn’t even feel out of place there. Although I was the only white person around I was barely conscious of my foreignness. People mostly paid me no attention. I was not overwhelmed by hawkers or dogged by pickpockets. I was not trailed by beggars. And the shopkeepers didn’t try to exploit my lack of local knowledge by charging me over the odds for things.</p>
<p>One time when I was looking for my sweet-tea fix a shop-owner hailed me over and struck up conversation with me. ‘Sprechen sie deutsche?’ he enquired.</p>
<p>I told him I couldn’t speak German.</p>
<p>‘Kurdi?’</p>
<p>I shook my head: ‘Inglise.’</p>
<p>‘Pity, my English is not so good.’</p>
<p>But his English was good enough for basic conversation. He told me he lived in Nuremburg, Germany as a refugee for about a decade. I asked him if he liked it there. He shook his head. ‘Too many racists.’</p>
<p>I experienced many variations of this conversation during my time in Iraqi Kurdistan. Pretty much everyone I met there had lived for some time in Europe or America. It’s only really since the fall of Saddam Hussein and the Baathist government that the Kurds have been able to feel safe in their homeland.</p>
<p><a href="http://samnorthcote.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/img_0806.jpg"><img style="background-image:none;padding-left:0;padding-right:0;display:inline;padding-top:0;border-width:0;" title="IMG_0806" alt="IMG_0806" src="http://samnorthcote.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/img_0806_thumb.jpg?w=640&#038;h=433" width="640" height="433" border="0" /></a></p>
<p>This caused me to re-examine my own views on the Iraq War. I have always been a pacifist and was staunchly opposed to the deployment of coalition forces in Iraq and Afghanistan. I have long felt that foreign wars are a counter-productive way to combat terrorism. And yet I cannot deny that the US-led invasion of Iraq was, for the Kurdish people at least, a good thing insofar as it took Saddam out of the picture.</p>
<p>Saddam was a ruthless dictator who sought to impose Arabic culture on the Kurdish region of Iraq. When the Kurds resisted this process of ‘Arabization’ he implemented Operation Anfal, a long, bloody campaign to wipe them and their culture off the map. I will come back to Anfal in a later post but for now suffice to say that Kurdish life was cheap under this reign of terror. Hundreds of thousands were killed and many more displaced. But ever since American troops spearheaded the overthrow of Saddam and the Baathists the fortunes of the Kurdish people have changed dramatically. Their cities are, for the most part, thriving; their markets are buzzing with activity; their children play freely in the streets; their villages have been rebuilt; their culture and language is intact; and hope is alive and well.</p>
<p>Whatever ulterior motives the allied forces may have had for entering Iraq – and I’m still convinced oil was the main motivator rather than empathy for suffering civilians – I’m glad that their actions at least gave the Iraqi Kurds the chance to live at peace in their homeland.</p>
<p><a href="http://samnorthcote.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/img_0809.jpg"><img style="background-image:none;padding-left:0;padding-right:0;display:inline;padding-top:0;border-width:0;" title="IMG_0809" alt="IMG_0809" src="http://samnorthcote.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/img_0809_thumb.jpg?w=640&#038;h=431" width="640" height="431" border="0" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://samnorthcote.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/img_0811.jpg"><img style="background-image:none;padding-left:0;padding-right:0;display:inline;padding-top:0;border-width:0;" title="IMG_0811" alt="IMG_0811" src="http://samnorthcote.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/img_0811_thumb.jpg?w=640&#038;h=431" width="640" height="431" border="0" /></a></p>
<p>In the evening Ciprian and I went to the Saturday service at the international church. The congregation was small but several nationalities were represented. I spoke to a Swiss man who had come to Kurdistan with his family to do business and a Mexican businessman who had likewise come with his family. Because of the lack of international schools the children of these families were being home-schooled.</p>
<p>There was also a bunch of American girls in their early twenties. They had come to Kurdistan as volunteers with humanitarian organisations to teach English. They too said they feel perfectly safe walking around in Sulaymaniyah. One of them had started out teaching in a village out in the mountains surrounding the city.</p>
<p>There were only two Kurdish guys at the church. One – Kak Saber – gave me his business card and said he worked for the International Bible Society. He was also a freelance journalist for various Kurdish newspapers. The other was a softly-spoken young guy with long hair and a Michael Jackson T-shirt. His name was Kak Shorsh. He couldn’t speak much English but he was pleased to see Ciprian. I learned later that this guy had lost both of his parents. In fact there wasn’t much left of his family at all. I’m not sure what his day-job is but, according to Ciprian, he is a gifted preacher.</p>
<p>After church Kak Shorsh took a taxi with Ciprian and myself because he lives near the dorm. He could barely speak a word of English and Ciprian’s Kurdish is very limited so there wasn’t much verbal communication between us. But this Kak Shorsh radiated some kind of inner peace which baffled me. His family had been wiped out – decimated. But if he harboured any bitterness there was no sign of it.</p>
<p>Back at the dorm Kak Amanj invited me to eat popcorn with him. In no time he had a saucepan rattling on the stove in the communal kitchen. A guy from the Turkish part of Kurdistan came in and I greeted him with the Arabic phrase which is always used in Iraqi Kurdistan: ‘Salaam alaikum’ (peace be upon you). But he laughed and said ‘I&#8217;m not an Arab! Don’t speak Arabic to me, I hate it.’</p>
<p>The following day I would visit an old prison where the Baathists detained and tortured their political opponents. And later in the week I would talk to a class of high-school students and take the bus to the ancient city of Erbil which is crowned with an 8,000-year-old citadel.</p>
<p>***</p>
<p>More posts on Iraqi Kurdistan coming soon.</p>
<p><a href="http://samnorthcote.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/img_0766.jpg"><img style="background-image:none;padding-left:0;padding-right:0;display:inline;padding-top:0;border:0;" title="IMG_0766" alt="IMG_0766" src="http://samnorthcote.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/img_0766_thumb.jpg?w=640&#038;h=431" width="640" height="431" border="0" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://samnorthcote.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/img_0765.jpg"><img style="background-image:none;padding-left:0;padding-right:0;display:inline;padding-top:0;border:0;" title="IMG_0765" alt="IMG_0765" src="http://samnorthcote.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/img_0765_thumb.jpg?w=640&#038;h=431" width="640" height="431" border="0" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://samnorthcote.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/img_0815.jpg"><img style="background-image:none;padding-left:0;padding-right:0;display:inline;padding-top:0;border:0;" title="IMG_0815" alt="IMG_0815" src="http://samnorthcote.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/img_0815_thumb.jpg?w=640&#038;h=431" width="640" height="431" border="0" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/332/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/332/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=332&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://samnorthcote.wordpress.com/2013/02/03/the-other-iraq-part-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://samnorthcote.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/img_0766_thumb.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://samnorthcote.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/img_0766_thumb.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0766_thumb.jpg</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/4f9886716902884e1eb842b046ef62d6?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">samnorthcote</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://samnorthcote.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/img_0824-002_thumb.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0824-002</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://samnorthcote.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/img_0799_thumb.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0799</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://samnorthcote.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/img_0769_thumb.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0769</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://samnorthcote.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/img_0550_thumb.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0550</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://samnorthcote.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/img_0562_thumb.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0562</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://samnorthcote.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/img_0806_thumb.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0806</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://samnorthcote.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/img_0809_thumb.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0809</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://samnorthcote.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/img_0811_thumb.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0811</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://samnorthcote.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/img_0766_thumb.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0766</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://samnorthcote.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/img_0765_thumb.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0765</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://samnorthcote.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/img_0815_thumb.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0815</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Moral Quandary Got You? Lie About It!</title>
		<link>http://unorthodoxepicure.com/2012/02/20/confession-no-34-moral-quandary-got-you-down-lie-about-it/</link>
		<comments>http://unorthodoxepicure.com/2012/02/20/confession-no-34-moral-quandary-got-you-down-lie-about-it/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2012 18:46:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Adam J. Holland</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cajun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mardi Gras]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Seafood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shrimp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Soup]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cajun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crab]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creole]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gumbo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mardi gras]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[okra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://unorthodoxepicure.wordpress.com/?p=973</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Where I come from, lying is a sin only most of the time. You can never lie to your parents, pastor, teacher or Scoutmaster. You are, however, allowed to stretch the truth when it comes to complimenting someone – especially a woman. In the South, we call those &#8216;white lies.&#8217; &#8216;White lies&#8217; work quite well [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=973&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Where I come from, lying is a sin only most of the time.</p>
<p>You can never lie to your parents, pastor, teacher or Scoutmaster. You are, however, allowed to stretch the truth when it comes to complimenting someone – especially a woman. In the South, we call those &#8216;white lies.&#8217; &#8216;White lies&#8217; work quite well when complimenting someone&#8217;s hair, clothing or blackberry cobbler – so long as you don&#8217;t get caught up in the web you&#8217;re weaving.</p>
<p>I was first busted in a &#8216;white lie&#8217; by none other than my wife, a Jersey girl who was unacquainted with Southern customs.</p>
<p><strong>The sauerbraten incident</strong><br />
It was some time in 1995, and we newlyweds were getting into the groove of going to Sunday dinner with her family. Though the meal and the company were always comfortable, I was elated to learn that my mother in-law this time would be preparing a legit festgelage — complete with kartoffelpuffer (potato pancakes), rotkohl (red cabbage) and sauerbraten, a traditional Deutschland-style beef roast. I&#8217;m a German, through and through. But I&#8217;d never had the main dish prior to that meal.</p>
<p>Whether it&#8217;s something reasonably simple – like eggplant parmesan – or painstakingly time-consuming – like sauerbraten – my wife&#8217;s mother is a cook. Period. Knowing her, she probably learned how to make an authentic sauerbraten from a German neighbor or family member. Instead of trying to make adjustments through the years (like most of us do), her efforts go into buying the best beef shoulder roast, and using exact measurements of allspice, gingerbread crumbs, red wine, and so on. The result is always a thing of beauty. And it&#8217;s absolutely delicious — if you like sauerbraten.</p>
<p>I learned – during the first bite – that sauerbraten is not my taste.</p>
<p>But, like any southern gentleman who is taught that lies told when complimenting someone don&#8217;t count against you, I chewed and swallowed, then took another bite.</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8216;Wow,&#8217; I told my mother in-law as she looked my way for a reaction. &#8216;This is really delicious sauerbraten. It&#8217;s really rich.&#8217;</p>
<p>&#8216;Thank you,&#8217; she replied. &#8216;I marinated it for three days.&#8217;</p>
<p>&#8216;I can tell,&#8217; I said. &#8216;I can really taste the allspice. Nice.&#8217;</p></blockquote>
<p>My new wife smiled. I could tell she was proud of her mom. She might have even been considering learning to make the dish, like her mother had done for her father. But, the conversation we had a couple of months later probably streichened those thoughts.</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8216;I have a surprise for you,&#8217; my wife said. &#8216;You&#8217;re going to love it.&#8217;</p>
<p>&#8216;Really? Are we going to Papaya Dog and to a Yankees game?&#8217;</p>
<p>&#8216;No, silly,&#8217; she responded. &#8216;My mom is making sauerbraten again, just for you!&#8217;</p></blockquote>
<p>I was in trouble. I couldn&#8217;t fake it twice. Besides, I&#8217;d just worked up a hankering for some cheap New York City hot dogs.</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8216;Look, Catherine … I don&#8217;t really like sauerbraten. So, please tell your mom I&#8217;m sick, or something.&#8217;</p>
<p>&#8216;What? Are you kidding me?&#8217;</p>
<p>&#8216;No. It&#8217;s just tha—&#8217;</p>
<p>&#8216;I can&#8217;t believe you!&#8217; she shouted, cutting me off. &#8216;Mom works on this dish for days? You tell her how great it is? Now, all-of-a-sudden you don&#8217;t like sauerbraten? Do you lie just for the hell of it, Adam?&#8217;</p>
<p>&#8216;I wasn&#8217;t lying,&#8217; I said, in a feeble attempt to escape her wrath. &#8216;Your mom&#8217;s sauerbraten is fantastic … for sauerbraten.&#8217;</p></blockquote>
<p>As the verbal beat-down continued, I learned that &#8216;white lies&#8217; in New Jersey are apparently just lies, and that the proper thing to do is to just flat-out tell someone you don&#8217;t like something. So, we went to Mom&#8217;s for a wonderful German dinner.</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8216;Let me tell you, Lillian, this sauerbraten is even better than the last one,&#8217; I said. &#8216;I really want to learn how to make this dish.&#8217;</p></blockquote>
<p>Even as my wife shot me various looks of disgust, I continued to pour it on. And eat more sauerbraten. I think she became an honorary Southern woman soon following that incident. And it&#8217;s not just because her hair became bigger, and lipstick much brighter. Her palate also seems to have dramatically changed.</p>
<p>Just about every dish that I&#8217;ve made and served since then has been her absolute favorite … ever.</p>
<p><em>If you like what you read here, please help me spread the word. I&#8217;d also love for you to join me on <a href="http://www.facebook.com/UnorthodoxEpicure">Facebook</a> (click the &#8216;like&#8217; button) and <a href="http://pinterest.com/unorthodxepicur/">Pinterest</a>.</em></p>
<hr />
<p>Mardi Gras in my part of the country is just part of life. Some people take it very seriously, and plan for months ahead their jaunt to New Orleans, while others (like myself) prefer to partake in the food and spirits from the comfort of our homes — or at least at a local themed fundraiser (and there are many). There is no wrong way to make gumbo, in my opinion, unless you omit okra. Though gumbo has roots all over the world, okra is the true namesake for this thickened soup. According to various horticultural historians, okra arrived in North America on slave ships from West Africa, where the pod was known as <em>ki ngombo</em> or <em>quingombo</em>. The other ingredients really depend on whether you are making the Cajun or Creole version, but any purist will also tell you that filé is also necessary to call it &#8216;gumbo.&#8217; My recipe combines the dark roux, seafood and spice of the Cajun version; and the savory tomatoes and other vegetables of the Creole dish.</p>
<div id="attachment_977" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 540px"><a href="http://unorthodoxepicure.files.wordpress.com/2012/02/gumbo.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-977" title="gumbo" alt="" src="http://unorthodoxepicure.files.wordpress.com/2012/02/gumbo.jpg?w=720"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">This gumbo has all the traditional vegetables, but they are strained to produce a smoother broth. With this dish, you can fool people who don&#8217;t think they like Louisiana-style cooking. And that&#8217;s no &#8216;white lie.&#8217;</p></div>
<h2>Louisiana Gumbo</h2>
<p>2 – Tablespoons butter<br />
3 cloves – garlic, minced<br />
1 medium – onion, chopped<br />
3 – celery stalks, chopped<br />
1 lb. – okra, chopped<br />
½ cup – butter<br />
½ cup – all-purpose flour<br />
2 quarts – chicken or vegetable stock<br />
1 Tablespoon – sugar<br />
1 – 16 oz. can chopped tomatoes, with liquid<br />
1 Tablespoon – fresh parsley, chopped<br />
1 sprig – fresh thyme<br />
2 bay leaves<br />
½ teaspoon – ground cayenne pepper<br />
1 teaspoon – ground black pepper<br />
½ teaspoon – Louisiana-style hot pepper sauce<br />
⅛ cup – Worcestershire sauce<br />
Juice from ½ lemon<br />
Filé powder*</p>
<p>2 lbs. – Raw seafood (peeled &amp; deveined shrimp; scallops; flaked crab; oysters; clams; lobster chunks; etc.)<br />
1 lb – andouille sausage, cut into ½ inch pieces</p>
<p>Melt (2 TB) butter in large skillet over medium heat. Cook garlic, onions, celery and okra until crisp tender, and browning around edges. Set aside.<br />
<strong> The Roux</strong><br />
In a large stock pot over medium-high heat, melt ( ½ cup) butter. Add flour. Stir constantly.<br />
When the roux is a rich, dark brown (milk-to-dark chocolate), add reserved vegetables and stir. Add stock and tomatoes. Stir well. Add dry seasonings: parsley, bay leaves, cayenne pepper, black pepper and thyme. Bring to a boil; reduce heat; and simmer for about 1 ½ hours, stirring occasionally.<br />
Through a wire mesh sieve (into a large pan), strain vegetables. Pour stock back into large stock pot. Add andouille sausage, Worcestershire sauce, hot sauce and lemon juice. Simmer for about an hour, stirring and skimming occasionally. Stock will thicken slightly. (If it thickens too much for your liking, add more stock and turn heat down slightly.) Add seafood. Simmer for another 10-15 minutes. Sprinkle with file powder and serve with rice. Garnish with fresh parsley or scallions, if desired. Allow guests to salt their own gumbo. This recipe makes about 8-10 servings.</p>
<p>*Filé (pronounced fee-lay) powder is the ground leaves of the sassafras tree, and is available in grocery stores across the South. It has a very light tea-like flavor and thickens the soup slightly. It should always be added after cooking.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/973/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/973/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=973&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://unorthodoxepicure.com/2012/02/20/confession-no-34-moral-quandary-got-you-down-lie-about-it/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>75</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/9d0b5753a211733e623bd21083223bac?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">adamjholland</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://unorthodoxepicure.files.wordpress.com/2012/02/gumbo.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gumbo</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why I Write</title>
		<link>http://rtewrite.wordpress.com/2013/02/05/why-i-write/</link>
		<comments>http://rtewrite.wordpress.com/2013/02/05/why-i-write/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2013 15:17:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>harperfaulkner</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Anne Frank]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Diary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[history]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Literature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Random]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WW II]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rtewrite.wordpress.com/?p=2205</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I have neglected my duties in responding to so many well-deserved accolades from my fellow bloggers. By my count, I owe you a list of 47,332 things about myself. I had filled five, yellow, legal pads and was up to 41,765 things when I decided that maybe I should just tell you one thing about [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2205&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I have neglected my duties in responding to so many well-deserved accolades from my fellow bloggers. By my count, I owe you a list of 47,332 things about myself. I had filled five, yellow, legal pads and was up to 41,765 things when I decided that maybe I should just tell you one thing about me that might give you some true insight, comprehensive insight, into what makes Harper Faulkner tick.</p>
<p>I have just painted my study/den/writer’s workroom and have returned pictures, posters and photos to my walls. The first two items I placed back and that hold the most prominent place in the room and in my visual sphere are a portrait of Anne Frank and a framed poster of the attic where she lived and wrote.</p>
<p>I write for Anne Frank.</p>
<p>Anne Frank’s diary has no ending.  We are always on that last page with her, August 1, 1944. We are left with promise unfulfilled.</p>
<p>I hate with a gut-burning, soul-searing never ending hatred, the strong trampling the weak. I hate the arrogance of those who place themselves in god-like positions over others. I hate that insidious nature of mankind that says because I am stronger; I can control you, use you, and even kill you.  And, if possible, I hate even more the people who can, but don’t stand up and say, “I will not let that happen!”</p>
<p>Anne Frank was a teenage girl on the cusp of womanhood and her diary reflects that.  In itself, it is not great literature. But it does reveal that with growth and maturity, wonderful inspiring words of greatness were to come. She was denied that. We were denied that.</p>
<p>I write because Anne Frank cannot. She would have turn 84 this year. What would we have if she would have been allowed to write for 70 more years? Would she lean over her computer keys and each time she tapped out a word, would she think of that precious paper diary and dull pencils and a cold attic and Nazis in the streets?</p>
<p>I write for Anne Frank. I do not have an ounce of the greatness she had inside her. I am a coward compared to her courage. But I can write and she can’t and I will never, ever take that for granted.</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://rtewrite.wordpress.com/category/uncategorized/'>Uncategorized</a> Tagged: <a href='http://rtewrite.wordpress.com/tag/anne-frank/'>Anne Frank</a>, <a href='http://rtewrite.wordpress.com/tag/diary/'>Diary</a>, <a href='http://rtewrite.wordpress.com/tag/history/'>history</a>, <a href='http://rtewrite.wordpress.com/tag/life/'>Life</a>, <a href='http://rtewrite.wordpress.com/tag/literature/'>Literature</a>, <a href='http://rtewrite.wordpress.com/tag/miscellaneous/'>Miscellaneous</a>, <a href='http://rtewrite.wordpress.com/tag/random/'>Random</a>, <a href='http://rtewrite.wordpress.com/tag/writers/'>Writers</a>, <a href='http://rtewrite.wordpress.com/tag/writing/'>Writing</a>, <a href='http://rtewrite.wordpress.com/tag/ww-ii/'>WW II</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2205/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2205/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2205/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2205/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2205/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2205/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2205/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2205/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2205/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2205/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2205/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2205/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2205/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2205/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2205&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://rtewrite.wordpress.com/2013/02/05/why-i-write/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>100</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/22e36424fe1e2edc89db94c3f03071dc?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">harperfaulkner</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Should Historians &#8220;Mind&#8221; What&#8217;s Been Said?</title>
		<link>http://hist291.wordpress.com/2013/02/03/should-historians-mind-whats-been-said/</link>
		<comments>http://hist291.wordpress.com/2013/02/03/should-historians-mind-whats-been-said/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2013 23:29:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>mcheesaker</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Digital History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Don Cherry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hockey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[language]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[n-gram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[student]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[twitter]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://hist291.wordpress.com/?p=572</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[According to Google’s new n-gram tool, when researching history, words count. Literally. By analyzing over 500 billion words from 5.2 million books in Chinese, English, French, German, Russian, and Spanish, the n-gram tool allows users to track the usage of words from 1500AD onwards. The implications of this tool in terms of historical and cultural [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=572&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>According to Google’s new n-gram tool, when researching history, words count.</p>
<p><strong>Literally.</strong></p>
<p>By analyzing over 500 billion words from 5.2 million books in Chinese, English, French, German, Russian, and Spanish, the n-gram tool allows users to track the usage of words from 1500AD onwards.</p>
<div id="attachment_573" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://hist291.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/screen-shot-2013-02-03-at-4-25-55-pm.png"><img class="size-medium wp-image-573" alt="Were they talking about the Renaissance in the 1500s? Apparently they were." src="http://hist291.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/screen-shot-2013-02-03-at-4-25-55-pm.png?w=300&#038;h=187" width="300" height="187" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Were they talking about the Renaissance in the 1500s? Apparently they were.</p></div>
<p>The implications of this tool in terms of historical and cultural research are just beginning to come to light. In the article  “<a href="http://www.sciencemag.org/content/331/6014/176.abstract">Quantitative Analysis of Culture Using Millions of Digitized Books</a>,” Jean-Baptiste Michel and his fellow researchers suggest that Google’s n-gram can be used to track the emergence of diseases, state censorship and the relative “celebrity” of a given person.</p>
<div id="attachment_574" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://hist291.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/screen-shot-2013-02-03-at-4-42-18-pm.png"><img class="size-medium wp-image-574" alt="Contrary to popular belief, I am not in fact famous." src="http://hist291.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/screen-shot-2013-02-03-at-4-42-18-pm.png?w=300&#038;h=187" width="300" height="187" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Contrary to popular belief, I am not in fact famous.</p></div>
<p>There is no doubt that the n-gram is, and will continue to be, an extremely useful tool in historical inquiry. However, there are some limitations that need to be addressed.</p>
<p>Firstly, the Google n-gram is limited in regards to language. Most of the collected works are written in English. Although this is helpful for me (an Anglophone student from Canada), some of the world’s most spoken languages, like Arabic and Hindi, are not even present in the database.</p>
<p>Furthermore, as Jean-Baptiste Michel notes, the Google n-gram tool simply measures the frequency of words within books, and books alone. Therefore, other publications like newspapers, and academic journal articles are marginalized from each search. The impact of this becomes quite clear when you compare n-gram searches on Google, and an n-gram search that browses through local newspaper clippings like the site, <a href="http://dsl.richmond.edu/dispatch/">Mining the Dispatch</a>. On Mining the Dispatch, users are able to see the relative frequency of fugitive slave ads that made it into the local Richmond newspaper during the Civil War. Because of its larger scope, and inability to browse through newspapers, this kind of historical deduction cannot be made through Google’s n-gram.</p>
<p>I think it’s also important to note that language, although an important (and often forgotten) indication of culture is certainly not the only one. As historians know, geography, religion and class, all play a critical role in shaping the thoughts, actions and mindsets of a given people. Language is only one small piece of what makes us who we are.</p>
<p>Indeed, Canada, the United States, and the UK, may all be English speaking nations, but we have very different cultures.</p>
<p>Just to prove this point, I decided to gauge the relative frequencies of three major sports: baseball, hockey, and football. From 1900-2008, the frequency of hockey was dismal compared to football and baseball. However, this was a search that took into account <i>all</i> English books written during the designated period. I imagine if I were to search a corpus containing only Canadian books, hockey would be mentioned far more frequently.</p>
<div id="attachment_575" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://hist291.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/screen-shot-2013-02-03-at-6-09-29-pm.png"><img class="size-medium wp-image-575   " alt="" src="http://hist291.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/screen-shot-2013-02-03-at-6-09-29-pm.png?w=300&#038;h=187" width="300" height="187" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Don Cherry would not be pleased.</p></div>
<p>But more than that, words themselves are limited.</p>
<p>Think about Twitter. Depending on the words we choose to use in our hashtags, our statuses are more searchable. Similarly, if we tweet about a topic that’s trending, what we say is viewed by a larger audience. But what if we don’t use the right words to categorize what we’re saying? What if we type in an extra &#8220;s&#8221; or add an apostrophe where it doesn&#8217;t belong? But more pertinent than that, what if we say one thing, and mean another?</p>
<p>My previous example with sports provides an interesting example. In English, the word “football” can either mean soccer, or American football. In my search, this discrepancy wasn’t accounted for. Therefore, any mention of the word “football,” whether that book was actually talking about soccer or American football, was nonetheless counted. And therein lies another problem with Google’s n-gram: the tool gives us no sense of context.</p>
<p><strong>And for the historian, context is king.</strong></p>
<p>An old Chinese proverb claims that, “If you wish to know the mind of a man, listen to his words.”</p>
<p>After playing around with the Google n-gram, and uncovering its uses, I think this is extremely accurate. However, words are only one investigative tool in the proverbial historical tool-belt that can be used to understand history and culture.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/572/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/572/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=572&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://hist291.wordpress.com/2013/02/03/should-historians-mind-whats-been-said/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/89d70db88c3d76813504b7f93bd42f3a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mcheesaker</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hist291.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/screen-shot-2013-02-03-at-4-25-55-pm.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Were they talking about the Renaissance in the 1500s? Apparently they were.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hist291.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/screen-shot-2013-02-03-at-4-42-18-pm.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Contrary to popular belief, I am not in fact famous.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hist291.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/screen-shot-2013-02-03-at-6-09-29-pm.png?w=300" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Back to the Front</title>
		<link>http://tragicocomedia.com/2013/02/04/back-to-the-front/</link>
		<comments>http://tragicocomedia.com/2013/02/04/back-to-the-front/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2013 02:52:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Professor Rollmops</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Memoir]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travelogues]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tragicocomedia.com/?p=2891</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This piece was written just prior to my arrival in India on December 24, 2012, but remained incomplete. After a quick edit and polish, I present it here in its original tense, despite just having returned from India. I got the shakes just before leaving Singapore. It was two and a half years since my [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2891&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>This piece was written just prior to my arrival in India on December 24, 2012, but remained incomplete. After a quick edit and polish, I present it here in its original tense, despite just having returned from India.</em></p>
<p>I got the shakes just before leaving Singapore. It was two and a half years since my last visit to India and I had forgotten how hardcore it can be. On the whole, India is a pretty safe place to travel – it’s not exactly a warzone and whilst violence and crime certainly occur, most foreigners get away with being ripped off a few times and suffering some health issues. Yet, travelling in India takes a lot of effort and can be at times quite harrowing. It is not, despite its reputation as a centre for meditation and religious retreat, a very relaxing country.</p>
<p><a href="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/9935-jodphur-bw.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2897" title="Everybody wants you in their photograph" alt="Jodphur B&amp;W" src="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/9935-jodphur-bw.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>I’ve written several stories about my first trip to India and some of the various experiences I had there. Some fictionalised, others as memoir, and it is not an easy place to which to do justice. It can be breathtaking and amazing, restful and beautiful, yet it can also be utterly exhausting and very frustrating. It also has its attendant, inherent difficulties – such as the heat and dust, the discomfort, the chaos, the noise, the touts, the lying and cheating that goes hand in hand with incredible hospitality, and the inconvenience of not being able to drink the tap water in a country that is often unrelentingly hot and humid.</p>
<p><a href="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/7984-taj-from-agra-fort.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2893" title="The Taj from Agra Fort" alt="Taj from Agra Fort" src="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/7984-taj-from-agra-fort.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>In my first few days in India in March 2010 I struggled to make sense of the place and learn to negotiate it. Rather like being thrown in at the deep end, I learned to swim soon enough, yet not before having a number of difficult and challenging experiences and getting sick. The illness in itself wasn&#8217;t so bad &#8211; stomach cramps and diarrhoea &#8211; but after a few days it made me feel very weak. For two days in Pushkar I did almost nothing but lie in my hotel room and read, with occasional ventures outside.</p>
<p><a href="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/1218-bikaner.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2898" title="Woman in muddy street in Bikaner" alt="Bikaner" src="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/1218-bikaner.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>After four days, travelling further into Rajasthan, I arrived in Udaipur dehydrated and exhausted. The weakness of not eating much for three days made me paranoid and, sitting alone in my hotel room watching the cricket that night I got the crazy idea that I might genuinely die. I force-fed myself a vegetable biriani and fruit salad and the following morning went straight to the chemist to get some antibiotics. Within twelve hours of taking them, the illness vanished and I cursed myself for not having done so sooner. Take my advice – most gastric illness in India is bacterial and over-the-counter antibiotics are readily available at any medical shop.</p>
<p><a href="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/9031-udaipur.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2894" title="Not a bad place to fear death" alt="Udaipur" src="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/9031-udaipur.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>As soon as I got better, that first trip in India really got underway. With my strength returned, I was able to put in the hard yards and see and do the things I wanted to. The more I saw of India, the more I loved it – but this love came with serious reservations about why I felt the way I did. It was all very well to see charm and romance and the exotic, yet alongside that was terrible poverty, failing infrastructure, appalling hygiene in public places, rubbish dumped and burned everywhere on the streets, including plastics and excrement, and such a harrowing welter of noise pollution, overcrowding and almost non-stop inquisitions from people I passed that it was equally depressing and demoralising. It was, of course, a photographers&#8217; paradise, but my joy at the subject matter was tainted by a feeling of intrusion and exploitation and terms like “poverty porn” lingered in my mind. I tried very hard on that trip to remain friendly and positive. For the first few weeks I answered every query, shook hands with a hundred strangers and stopped for the ubiquitous “just one photo, sir”, but after a time India’s constant assault forced me to retreat inside myself. I turned to my headphones and sunglasses and started ignoring people.</p>
<p><a href="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/5925-onkar.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2902" title="Onkar! a very nice tea man in McLeod Ganj" alt="Onkar!" src="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/5925-onkar.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>A better solution, however, came when I arrived in Darjeeling. Perhaps it was the prevalence of Buddhism, the cool calm of the mountains or just the friendly, peaceful nature of the Ghorka people, but in Darjeeling people left me alone. When people did greet me or make an inquiry, it was not merely preliminary to an attempted transaction.</p>
<p><a href="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/3986-darjeeling.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2899" title="Darjeeling, chilled" alt="Darjeeling" src="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/3986-darjeeling.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>In the rest of India there seems to be an automatic reflex whereupon, seeing a tourist, if staring is insufficient, then belting out the question “which country?” is the next step. This was sometimes done in the nicest possible way, but often it was thrown at me with such urgency that it felt impolite. What really surprised me was how often the inquirers accepted the answer without further ado, at times seeming almost uninterested, which left me wondering why they had needed to ask in the first place. It was like being a display, which, to be fair, was probably not much different from how people felt when I was photographing them – though I do try to shoot as surreptitiously as possible.</p>
<p>The solution, it seemed, to avoiding the hustle of India, was to be in the mountains, which wasn&#8217;t exactly India after all. Once I’d discovered the relative calm of the mountains, I did my best to stay there.</p>
<p><a href="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/5641-amritsar.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2900" title="The Golden Temple, Amritsar" alt="Amritsar" src="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/5641-amritsar.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>From Darjeeling I flew across to Amritsar where I lasted one day before taking a bus across Punjab into the mountains around Dharamsala.</p>
<p><a href="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/6949-vashisht.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2903" title="Mountains around Vashisht" alt="Vashisht" src="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/6949-vashisht.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>I was so reluctant to return to the heat, dust and general hubbub hat I stayed another three weeks in Himachal Pradesh before finally venturing down again via Shimla.</p>
<p><a href="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/5830-mcleod-ganj.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2901" title="Twin Rainbows, McLeod Ganj" alt="McLeod Ganj" src="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/5830-mcleod-ganj.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>By the end of that journey, just shy of two months, I felt like an old veteran after a long campaign. Yet my energy was also pretty well spent and I had fallen into a state of relative dissipation. Tired and world-weary, I wandered around Varanasi in a daze, wiped out by heat and hash. I made sure I took the photographs I wanted to get, yet the subject that had so fascinated me for the first two months – namely India – had become a little less appealing.</p>
<p><a href="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/9129-varanasi.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2895" title="So many people, Varanasi" alt="Varanasi" src="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/9129-varanasi.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>I could no longer stomach the scent of excrement, urine and decomposition. I had no more patience for beggars, priests, touts or even genuinely curious Indians. I literally just wanted to shoot the place and avoid any interactions. When anyone spoke to me I shook my head, pointed to the headphones, raised my hands as though to say, “Sorry, dude, I can’t hear you,” and walked away. It was not how I wanted to be at all, and I hid out in my hotel room at times, simply indulging in privacy and regretting the feelings of displeasure I had with the world at large. I guess introverts should travel in Scandinavia instead.</p>
<p><a href="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/9412-varanasi.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2896" title="Man with tea, Varanasi" alt="Varanasi" src="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/9412-varanasi.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>It was for these reasons that, just prior to my flight into Thiruvananthapuram for a second visit to India, I started to have reservations about where I was going. I should be looking forward to the challenge, but perhaps I am too effete and western for the grit and grime of it all.  Still, despite the above introduction, my last trip was one of the greatest experiences of my life and I came away from it feeling very inspired. This time is also bound to be different for a number of reasons. Firstly, I&#8217;ll be starting in the south instead of the north and travelling in regions I&#8217;ve not visited before. Secondly, I&#8217;m not travelling alone this time around. V is coming with me, or I with her if you will, and the dynamic will be very different indeed. It will certainly be a lot easier with someone to share the highs and lows, and I hope it will be more enjoyable as a consequence. Hopefully I will come away both appreciating what I have discovered anew and having been reminded of what is important and good in life. I also hope to shoot a hell of a lot of good photographs. Wish me luck.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2891/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2891/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2891&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tragicocomedia.com/2013/02/04/back-to-the-front/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>19</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/131f1980849d4768f8e3ee6882a5b019?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Professor Rollmops</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/9935-jodphur-bw.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Everybody wants you in their photograph</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/7984-taj-from-agra-fort.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The Taj from Agra Fort</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/1218-bikaner.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Woman in muddy street in Bikaner</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/9031-udaipur.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Not a bad place to fear death</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/5925-onkar.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Onkar! a very nice tea man in McLeod Ganj</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/3986-darjeeling.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Darjeeling, chilled</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/5641-amritsar.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The Golden Temple, Amritsar</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/6949-vashisht.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mountains around Vashisht</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/5830-mcleod-ganj.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Twin Rainbows, McLeod Ganj</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/9129-varanasi.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">So many people, Varanasi</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tragicocomedia.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/9412-varanasi.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Man with tea, Varanasi</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Land Before Hype</title>
		<link>http://mostlybrightideas.wordpress.com/2013/02/01/the-land-before-hype/</link>
		<comments>http://mostlybrightideas.wordpress.com/2013/02/01/the-land-before-hype/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 16:59:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bronxboy55</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Still Human After All These Years]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[baseball]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[basketball]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commercials]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[football]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Super Bowl]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[World Series]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yankees]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mostlybrightideas.wordpress.com/?p=5345</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It’s that time again: Super Bowl week. I know this, not because I follow football in even the slightest way, but because I’ve noticed the potato chip and Coca-Cola displays at the grocery store. Built like shrines to the gods, these stockpiles of snacks will be inhaled by a hundred million people in six hours. [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=5345&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It’s that time again: Super Bowl week. I know this, not because I follow football in even the slightest way, but because I’ve noticed the potato chip and Coca-Cola displays at the grocery store. Built like shrines to the gods, these stockpiles of snacks will be inhaled by a hundred million people in six hours. This is just enough time to complete the pre-game and post-game shows, four fifteen-minute quarters of actual football competition, a forty-five-minute halftime extravaganza, and a lot of expensive commercials created to get you to eat potato chips and drink Coca-Cola.</p>
<div id="attachment_5346" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 366px"><a href="http://mostlybrightideas.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/electric.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-5346" alt="Electric" src="http://mostlybrightideas.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/electric.jpg?w=356&#038;h=198" width="356" height="198" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">From <a href="http://www.kshs.org" rel="nofollow">http://www.kshs.org</a></p></div>
<p>I don’t have many positive memories related to the sport. When I was about eleven, my best friend got one of those electric football games that had plastic players and a metal field that would vibrate when you flipped the switch. We’d line up our teams with great care, and then sit there for a long time listening to this thing buzz and staring at our little men as they wandered around in all directions, quivering like mad and eventually getting stuck against a side wall or clustering in bunches in the corner like tiny bumper cars. It was, I imagine, not much different from putting on show tunes and watching termites attempt to perform <i>Guys and Dolls</i>. Every now and then my friend would announce that he’d gotten a first down, a development that always escaped my attention but that he never failed to see. Touchdowns and field goals would follow, along with other assorted scoring opportunities based on obscure rules that I was pretty sure he was making up on the spot.<a href="http://mostlybrightideas.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/football.png"><img class="alignright  wp-image-5349" style="margin-top:8px;margin-bottom:8px;" alt="Football" src="http://mostlybrightideas.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/football.png?w=416&#038;h=300" width="416" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>Sometimes, when the older boys had a thirst for human blood, we played real football on an empty lot riddled with small rocks and shards of broken glass. We had only the ball, and no other equipment whatsoever. Helmets were for sissies, we decided, and complaining of pain after being slammed to the ground and crushed under a pile of snarling teenagers would just mean you’d be picked last the next time we played. If we didn’t call it the Stupid Bowl, we should have. We were a bunch of morons.</p>
<p>I preferred baseball. For one thing, in other sports the opposing team spent most of its time trying to take something away from you, inflicting physical harm and verbal abuse in the process. It was too much like real life. Football, for example, was nothing more than the offense bulling its way through, while the defense did whatever it could to knock you down and get you to fumble the ball.</p>
<p>Basketball was the same, except you wore shorts and were required to dribble and avoid committing a three-second violation. No one ever explained the three-second rule to me, or how the referees could possibly keep track of where everyone was and for how long. I got called on it a lot in gym class, usually because I had to stop and re-tie my sneakers in the middle of play.</p>
<p><a href="http://mostlybrightideas.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/soccer.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-5351" alt="Soccer" src="http://mostlybrightideas.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/soccer.png?w=720"   /></a>In both hockey and soccer, there was an infraction referred to as <i>off-sides</i>. Again, I’ve never been able to understand this rule, beyond the simple conclusion that it’s designed to keep you from wanting to score a goal too much. The result, often, was an unbearably long game that ended in a tie. Frequently, a <i>scoreless</i> tie. This was like going to a restaurant, ordering a meal, waiting for your dinner to be served, then leaving without eating anything.</p>
<p>I found myself playing lacrosse once, and like hockey, its bizarre regulations included something called a <i>crease</i>, which I think is an invisible fourth dimension that players either must stay inside of or avoid entering at all costs. I’m still not sure.</p>
<p>These sports seemed to have a common element: they all had commentators and coaches who rattled on and on about intricate strategies and match-ups, deep explanations of what worked and didn’t work, how they needed to go back to the fundamentals, and what they intended to accomplish next game or next season. The only thing I ever saw was a bunch of lunatics chasing after a loose ball or puck, unsure of where it was headed and knocking each other around to relieve their frustration.<a href="http://mostlybrightideas.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/baseball.png"><img class="alignright  wp-image-5352" style="margin-top:10px;margin-bottom:10px;" alt="Baseball" src="http://mostlybrightideas.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/baseball.png?w=342&#038;h=352" width="342" height="352" /></a></p>
<p>But baseball was different. Baseball involved thinking, rather than reptilian-brain reflex responses. There was time to plan ahead. And there was room for real strategy, because there were just so many things that could happen, and each thing had a correct reaction.</p>
<p>My younger brother and I played baseball every chance we got. We played in the street, using flattened beer cans and manhole covers for bases. We played on concrete playgrounds, and on any available stretch of grass. We pitched to a rectangle we’d drawn with yellow chalk on a brick wall. In the winter, we played in the house, arranging the living room furniture like an infield and using a rolled-up sock for a ball.</p>
<p>We watched professional games on television. And once or twice a year, our father took us to see the Yankees or the Mets play in person. One summer, we went to the Mayor’s Trophy Game, an annual fundraiser in which the Yankees and Mets played <i>against</i> each other. My brain nearly exploded with excitement, but I’d also been backed into the corner of team loyalty, and chose to focus instead on eating as many hot dogs as I could. This was in the early 1960s, when you could sit in a box seat for three dollars, or the bleachers for seventy-five cents. When players had names like Ernie and Vic, Roberto and Duke, Sandy and Moose, and the very best of them made less than a hundred thousand dollars.</p>
<p>Of course, I had no idea about players’ salaries when I was a kid. I doubt I’d ever even considered the fact that they were paid at all. Baseball was a game, not a job, and I’d have paid <i>them</i> just for a chance to step onto that field and touch the bases. I dreamed of someday getting a close look at the three monuments in centerfield at Yankee Stadium, vertical granite slabs that looked exactly like the headstones I’d seen when visiting my grandparents’ graves at the cemetery in Queens. I wasn’t certain, but I thought the players might have been buried right there in the outfield.</p>
<p>At one game, Mickey Mantle hit a five-hundred-foot shot over the black screen in dead center. I may have seen it, but more likely I was looking around for a food vendor. Still, I was there. I remember standing and cheering about something; it had to be either the home run or the guy selling Dixie Cups – cardboard containers filled with half vanilla and half chocolate ice cream that you ate with a flat wooden spoon.</p>
<p>World Series games were played in the afternoons back then, in the first week of October, when you could tell the inning by how close the shadows were to the pitcher’s mound. There were two leagues, as there are now, but each had just ten teams. The best record at the end of the season got you into the World Series. No playoffs or division championships. No slipping into a side entrance off Wild Card Alley. You either won the pennant or you didn’t. It was pure, and it was fair. I remember running home from school to catch the last couple of innings. And sometimes, on days when I loved the world more than anything, the nuns would turn on the television and let us watch the game right there in our classroom.</p>
<p>The Super Bowl had not yet been born. The highlights of the year were Easter, summer vacation, the World Series, my birthday, and Christmas. It was the anticipation of each event that helped sustain me from one to the next. People say it was a simpler time, and I guess it was. Potato chips came in two flavors, and there was Coca-Cola and whatever it was other people drank. There was vanilla and chocolate, the Yankees and the Mets, baseball and all those strange, inferior sports.</p>
<p style="padding-bottom:30px;">And there was time to think.</p>
<hr />
<p style="padding-top:30px;"><span style="color:#0000ff;"><em>On second thought, <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qmXacL0Uny0">he</a> explains it better.</em></span></p>
<p style="padding-bottom:34px;">
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5345/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5345/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=5345&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://mostlybrightideas.wordpress.com/2013/02/01/the-land-before-hype/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>100</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/985f77a6e63f66b1719d766801a886e7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bronxboy55</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mostlybrightideas.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/electric.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Electric</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mostlybrightideas.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/football.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Football</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mostlybrightideas.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/soccer.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Soccer</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mostlybrightideas.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/baseball.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Baseball</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fire and Ice: The Rise of the Snow Weber</title>
		<link>http://patronsofthepit.wordpress.com/2013/02/02/fire-and-ice-the-rise-of-the-snow-weber/</link>
		<comments>http://patronsofthepit.wordpress.com/2013/02/02/fire-and-ice-the-rise-of-the-snow-weber/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2013 14:25:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Patrons of the Pit</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[barbecue]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[barbeque]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bbq]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[camping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cooking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[extreme]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faithful remnant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fire and Ice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fishing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[foodie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[huntung]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outdoors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robert Frost]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[snow weber]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[winter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[winter grilling]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://patronsofthepit.wordpress.com/?p=933</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Over a steaming cup of tea, I glance out the window at the pit, watching spindrift swirl off the house in a fashion suitable maybe, for the weathered,  icy,  flanks of Everest. The mercury gauge read a sporty 5 degrees F, but the weather man said it felt more like minus 15, and I guess [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=933&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Over a steaming cup of tea</strong>, I glance out the window at the pit, watching spindrift swirl off the house in a fashion suitable maybe, for the weathered,  icy,  flanks of Everest. The mercury gauge read a sporty 5 degrees F, but the weather man said it felt more like minus 15, and I guess believed him. You kind of have to believe him I concluded, when it feels like your parking brake is engaged when you back down the driveway in the morning, only it isn&#8217;t  Yeah, it was cold out there alright. A vintage January day in Minnesota. The kind of day where you put on two or three shirts in the morning, and then you go about the business of getting dressed. I curled my toes in my warm socks, fingers cradling the hot, porcelain cup , and after a dash of consideration, I decided to do the only sensible thing I could think of &#8211; to go outside naturally, and ignite the Snow Weber!</p>
<p><a href="http://patronsofthepit.wordpress.com/2013/02/02/fire-and-ice-the-rise-of-the-snow-weber/afterfocus_1359675847092_edit0/" rel="attachment wp-att-928"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-928" alt="afterfocus_1359675847092_edit0" src="http://patronsofthepit.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/afterfocus_1359675847092_edit0.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<div id="mp0_ctr">
<div id="mp0_msgPartBody">
<div id="mpf0_readMsgBodyContainer">
<div id="mpf0_MsgContainer">
<div>The Snow Weber, that’s what I’m calling it at least, is the tactile end result of our latest BBQ brain thrust. A frozen monument if you will, erected in a semi-stately homage, symbolic to all the keepers of the grill out there, who do not, and will not, save for a trip somewhere with a blue tag on their big toe,  take the winter off.  The faithful remnant possessing the macaroni to lay meat to flame whence the jaws of winter hath conspired against them. Carry the flame proudly brethren, for this is our story. A tale of fire and ice.</div>
<div></div>
<div><a href="http://patronsofthepit.wordpress.com/2013/02/02/fire-and-ice-the-rise-of-the-snow-weber/afterfocus_1359694383277_edit0/" rel="attachment wp-att-932"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-932" alt="afterfocus_1359694383277_edit0" src="http://patronsofthepit.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/afterfocus_1359694383277_edit0.jpg?w=720"   /></a></div>
<p>Robert Frost postulates in his poem the virtues of world destruction either by the fire or by ice, figuring either, if we had to, would be pretty nice.  I wonder tho if he ever grilled in winter, or knew that the two forces could harmonize together for the betterment of his tummy. Because they can. And so it was, with pork chops in hand, I stepped out onto the wind-swept patio, and at once my left eye lid seared tight from the keen northern wind. I love it! Tenderly I placed the two chops on the hot grate, and admired them there for a spell.  The previous owners of which I&#8217;m sure knew each other back on their farm. Perhaps routinely getting together for morning slop, to discuss their lives, their hopes, and their dreams. Maybe they even aspired to make it on to this blog one day. Hmm. I shook off the thought, and dusted the chops with some <a href="http://louisianafishfry.elsstore.com/view/product/?id=18723&amp;cid=2062">Louisiana Fish Fry Cajun Seasoning</a> instead.</p>
<p><a href="http://patronsofthepit.wordpress.com/2013/02/02/fire-and-ice-the-rise-of-the-snow-weber/afterfocus_1359693630086_edit0/" rel="attachment wp-att-931"><img class="size-full wp-image-931 aligncenter" alt="           " src="http://patronsofthepit.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/afterfocus_1359693630086_edit0.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>After a while, and maybe even longer than that, I felt the compulsion to put the lid on, and go think about my life. Nothing quite so fine as repairing out in the yard with a 15 below cross-wind, whilst two pork chops sizzle on the snow grill. Glory! <a href="http://patronsofthepit.wordpress.com/2012/12/09/to-grill-or-not-to-grill/" target="_blank">The art of winter grilling</a>, if your wondering, is not to fight it. But to embrace it. To make the proverbial glass of lemon aid out of it. To meet it on it&#8217;s terms and not your own. That, and a degree of lunacy doesn&#8217;t hurt none either.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div></div>
<div>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://patronsofthepit.wordpress.com/2013/02/02/fire-and-ice-the-rise-of-the-snow-weber/20130131_172504_edit0/" rel="attachment wp-att-929"><img class="size-full wp-image-929 aligncenter" alt="" src="http://patronsofthepit.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/20130131_172504_edit0.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
</div>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>And supper is served, courtesy of, and inspired by:</strong></p>
<h3 style="text-align:center;">Fire and Ice</h3>
<p style="text-align:center;"><em>Some say the world will end in fire,</em><br />
<em>Some say in ice.</em><br />
<em>From what I&#8217;ve tasted of desire</em><br />
<em>I hold with those who favor fire.</em><br />
<em>But if it had to perish twice,</em><br />
<em>I think I know enough of hate</em><br />
<em>To say that for destruction ice</em><br />
<em>Is also great</em><br />
<em>And would suffice</em>.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">-Robert Frost</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/933/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/933/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=933&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://patronsofthepit.wordpress.com/2013/02/02/fire-and-ice-the-rise-of-the-snow-weber/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>62</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://patronsofthepit.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/afterfocus_1359675847092_edit0.jpg?w=112" />
		<media:content url="http://patronsofthepit.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/afterfocus_1359675847092_edit0.jpg?w=112" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Fire and Ice</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/b358cc0808635b00957805d083fe96e8?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">patronsofthepit</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://patronsofthepit.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/afterfocus_1359675847092_edit0.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">afterfocus_1359675847092_edit0</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://patronsofthepit.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/afterfocus_1359694383277_edit0.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">afterfocus_1359694383277_edit0</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://patronsofthepit.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/afterfocus_1359693630086_edit0.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">           </media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://patronsofthepit.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/20130131_172504_edit0.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Are They Really So Different?</title>
		<link>http://thenorth666.wordpress.com/2013/01/28/thought-of-the-week-are-they-really-so-different/</link>
		<comments>http://thenorth666.wordpress.com/2013/01/28/thought-of-the-week-are-they-really-so-different/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 02:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Satis</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Thought of the Week]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Behaviors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Calvin and Hobbes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kids]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pluto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thenorth666.wordpress.com/?p=2082</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s a funny business, living with a child. It&#8217;s a little bit like living with a mooching flatmate who is quite a bit smarter than you. (And shorter, which sort of makes up for it.) You see, when you&#8217;re talking about children in the hypothetical (as in, &#8220;we might want kids some day&#8221;, or &#8220;aren&#8217;t your [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2082&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://thenorth666.wordpress.com/2013/01/28/thought-of-the-week-are-they-really-so-different/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>76</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://thenorth666.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/dsc_0181.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://thenorth666.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/dsc_0181.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0181</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/d88970831fd574590dd147783c59dc8b?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F1.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">thenorth666</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thenorth666.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/dsc_0181.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">A child and a grownup…but which is which?</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thenorth666.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/pluto-a.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">-Pluto-a</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thenorth666.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/daysarejustpacked.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">daysarejustpacked</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apple\&#8217;s Nine Definitions Since 1995</title>
		<link>http://alex4d.wordpress.com/2013/02/05/apple-is/</link>
		<comments>http://alex4d.wordpress.com/2013/02/05/apple-is/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2013 16:10:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Alex</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://alex4d.wordpress.com/?p=4004</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Looking back, it&#8217;s interesting to see how the way Apple has described itself has changed over the years. Luckily for us, press releases usually include a definition of the company issuing them. I&#8217;ve been back through Apple&#8217;s site and used The Wayback Machine at Archive.org to research the evolution of the way Apple sees itself. [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4004&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Looking back, it&#8217;s interesting to see how the way Apple has described itself has changed over the years. Luckily for us, press releases usually include a definition of the company issuing them. I&#8217;ve been back through Apple&#8217;s site and used <a href="http://Archive.org/web/web.php" target="_blank">The Wayback Machine at Archive.org</a> to research the evolution of the way Apple sees itself.</p>
<h4>April 1995 &#8211; A standard mid-nineties computer company</h4>
<p>The only distinction being a mention of &#8216;personal digital assistants&#8217;:</p>
<blockquote><p>Apple Computer, Inc., a recognized pioneer and innovator in the information industry, creates powerful solutions based on easy to use personal computers, servers peripherals, software, online services and personal digital assistants. Headquartered in Cupertino, California, Apple Computer, Inc. (NASDAQ: AAPL) develops, manufactures, licenses, and markets products, technologies, and services for the business, education, consumer, scientific &amp; engineering and government markets in over 140 countries.</p></blockquote>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://web.archive.org/web/19990922045328/http://product.info.apple.com/pr/press.releases/1995/q3/950403.pr.rel.education2.html"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-4013" alt="press-release-1995" src="http://alex4d.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/press-release-1995.jpg?w=308&#038;h=442" width="308" height="442" /></a></p>
<p><span id="more-4004"></span></p>
<h4><strong>January 1996 &#8211; Apple&#8217;s only asset?</strong></h4>
<p>In 1996, Apple decided to define QuickTime as one of its major assets:</p>
<blockquote><p>Apple Computer, Inc., a recognized innovator in the information industry<span style="color:#000000;"> <em>and leader in multimedia technologies</em></span>, creates powerful solutions based on easy-to-use personal computers, servers, peripherals, software, online services, and personal digital assistants. Headquartered in Cupertino, California, Apple (NASDAQ: AAPL) develops, manufactures, licenses and markets solutions, products, technologies and services for business, education, consumer, entertainment, scientific &amp; engineering and government customers in over 140 countries.</p></blockquote>
<h4><strong>April 1997 &#8211; The Newton declines</strong></h4>
<p>As less complex PDAs started to gain market share, &#8216;online services, and personal digital assistants&#8217; became &#8216;handheld computers and Internet content<em>&#8216;:<br />
</em></p>
<blockquote><p>Apple Computer, Inc., a recognized innovator in the information industry and leader in multimedia technologies, creates powerful solutions based on easy-to-use personal computers, servers, peripherals, software, <em><span style="color:#000000;">handheld computers and Internet content</span>.</em> Headquartered in Cupertino, California, Apple develops, manufactures, licenses and markets solutions, products, technologies and services for business, education, consumer, entertainment, scientific and engineering and government customers in more than 140 countries.</p></blockquote>
<h4><span class="Apple-style-span" style="font-size:14px;font-weight:bold;line-height:14px;"><strong>September 1997 &#8211; Steve Jobs changes everything</strong></span></h4>
<p>10 months after Steve Jobs returned to Apple, four days before <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20010816130723/http://product.info.apple.com/pr/press.releases/1997/q4/970916.pr.rel.jobs.html" target="_blank">his appointment as Interim CEO</a>, the definition <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20010816130723/http://product.info.apple.com/pr/press.releases/1997/q4/970912.pr.rel.quicktime.html" target="_blank">almost completely changed</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>Apple Computer<span style="color:#000000;">, Inc. ignited the personal computer revolution in the 1970s with the Apple II, and reinvented the personal computer in the 1980s with the Macintosh. Apple is now recommitted to its original mission-to bring the best personal computing products and support to students, educators, designers, scientists, engineers, businesspersons and consumers in over 140 countries around the world.</span></p></blockquote>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20010816130723/http://product.info.apple.com/pr/press.releases/1997/q4/970912.pr.rel.quicktime.html"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-4014" alt="press-release-1997" src="http://alex4d.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/press-release-1997.jpg?w=206&#038;h=270" width="206" height="270" /></a></p>
<h4><strong>July 2004 &#8211; &#8216;Original mission&#8217; achieved</strong></h4>
<p>It took almost seven years for the definition to <a href="http://www.apple.com/pr/library/2004/07/07Apple-iPod-mini-International-Availability-Set-for-July-24.html" target="_blank">change again</a>. Steve&#8217;s 1997 mission achieved, the definition includes specific products and what they do.</p>
<blockquote><p>Apple ignited the personal computer revolution in the 1970s with the Apple II and reinvented the personal computer in the 1980s with the Macintosh. <em><span style="color:#000000;">Today, Apple continues to lead the industry in innovation with its award-winning desktop and notebook computers, OS X operating system, and iLife and professional applications. Apple is also spearheading the digital music revolution with its iPod portable music players and iTunes online music store.</span><br />
</em></p></blockquote>
<h4><strong>March 2007 &#8211; Next market disruption announced</strong></h4>
<p>Almost three years later, the distinction between desktop and notebook computers was dropped and <a href="http://www.apple.com/pr/library/2007/03/21Apple-TV-Now-Shipping.html" target="_blank">the iPhone was included</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>Apple ignited the personal computer revolution in the 1970s with the Apple II and reinvented the personal computer in the 1980s with the Macintosh. Today, Apple continues to lead the industry in innovation with its award-winning computers, OS X operating system and iLife and professional applications. Apple is also spearheading the digital media revolution with its iPod portable music and video players and iTunes online store,<em><span style="color:#000000;"> and will enter the mobile phone market this year with its revolutionary iPhone.</span><br />
</em></p></blockquote>
<h4><strong>April 2010 &#8211; Three revolutions joined by a fourth</strong></h4>
<p>A small <a href="http://www.apple.com/pr/library/2010/04/05Apple-Sells-Over-300-000-iPads-First-Day.html" target="_blank">addition for the iPad</a>, Apple&#8217;s fourth market revolution<a href="http://www.apple.com/pr/library/2010/04/05Apple-Sells-Over-300-000-iPads-First-Day.html" target="_blank"><br />
</a></p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Apple ignited the personal computer revolution with the Apple II, then reinvented the personal computer with the Macintosh. Apple continues to lead the industry with its award-winning computers, OS X operating system, and iLife, iWork and professional applications. Apple leads the digital music revolution with its iPods and iTunes online store, has reinvented the mobile phone with its revolutionary iPhone and App Store,<em><span style="color:#000000;"> and has recently introduced its magical iPad which is defining the future of mobile media and computing devices.&#8221;</span><br />
</em></p></blockquote>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://www.apple.com/pr/library/2010/04/05Apple-Sells-Over-300-000-iPads-First-Day.html"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-4015" alt="press-release-2010" src="http://alex4d.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/press-release-2010.jpg?w=327&#038;h=254" width="327" height="254" /></a></p>
<h4><strong>June 2010 &#8211; Computers, yes, also…</strong></h4>
<p>The Apple II is dropped and the amount of text on the Mac <a href="http://www.apple.com/pr/library/2010/06/28iPhone-4-Sales-Top-1-7-Million.html" target="_blank">is reduced</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p><span style="color:#000000;"><em>Apple designs Macs, the best personal computers in the world, along with</em></span> OS X, iLife, iWork, and professional software. Apple leads the digital music revolution with its iPods and iTunes online store. Apple reinvented the mobile phone with its revolutionary iPhone and App Store, and has recently introduced its magical iPad which is defining the future of mobile media and computing devices.</p></blockquote>
<h4>January 2012 &#8211; iPad mission achieved</h4>
<p><span class="Apple-style-span" style="color:#000000;font-size:12px;line-height:18px;">The current definition </span><span class="Apple-style-span" style="color:#000000;font-size:12px;line-height:18px;"><a href="http://www.apple.com/pr/library/2012/01/19Apple-Unveils-All-New-iTunes-U-App-for-iPad-iPhone-iPod-touch.html" target="_blank">is a year old</a></span><span class="Apple-style-span" style="color:#000000;font-size:12px;line-height:18px;">:</span></p>
<blockquote><p>Apple designs Macs, the best personal computers in the world, along with OS X, iLife, iWork and professional software. Apple leads the digital music revolution with its iPods and iTunes online store. Apple has reinvented the mobile phone with its revolutionary iPhone and App Store, and is defining the future of mobile media and computing devices with iPad.</p></blockquote>
<h4>January 2013 &#8211; Something MacPro users will love?</h4>
<p>Writing as a long-term user of Apple&#8217;s professional software, I find it interesting that despite predictions of Apple abandoning pro users, pro software has been part of the way Apple identifies itself since July 2004. However given that iLife and iWork haven&#8217;t changed very often over the last few years, they&#8217;ll either be updated soon, or dropped from Apple&#8217;s corporate definition.</p>
<p>Given that an email from Tim Cook reassured that later this year Apple will introduce a product that MacPro users will love, how could that redefine Apple? Here&#8217;s a possible definition from me:</p>
<blockquote><p>Apple leads the digital music revolution with its iPods and iTunes online store. Apple reinvented the mobile phone with its revolutionary iPhone and App Store, and is defining the future of mobile media and computing devices with iPad. <span style="color:#000000;"><em>Apple helps people organise their lives with iLife, iWork and iCloud. Apple makes Macs, OS X and professional software: the best content creation tools in the world.</em></span></p></blockquote>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4004/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4004/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4004&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://alex4d.wordpress.com/2013/02/05/apple-is/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>36</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/9957eee2771a6071c439194f4d97fe99?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Aladar</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://alex4d.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/press-release-1995.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">press-release-1995</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://alex4d.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/press-release-1997.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">press-release-1997</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://alex4d.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/press-release-2010.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">press-release-2010</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Beating the Drum for Metaphor</title>
		<link>http://blog.lexiconbranding.com/2013/01/30/beating-the-drum-for-metaphor/</link>
		<comments>http://blog.lexiconbranding.com/2013/01/30/beating-the-drum-for-metaphor/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2013 11:00:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lexicon® Blog</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Brand Name Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brand Naming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Branding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate naming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Linguistics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Naming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trademarks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David Placek]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ithkuil]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[language]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lexicon Branding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[metaphor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Will Leben]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://lexiconblog.com/?p=286</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[An engaging recent New Yorker article* describes the constructed language Ithkuil, which aims to be “maximally precise” by “eliminating the ambiguity, vagueness, illogic, redundancy, polysemy (multiple meanings) and overall arbitrariness that [are] seemingly ubiquitous in natural human language.” Our first response was that the creator of this constructed language had likely not seen our recent [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=286&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:left;">An engaging recent <em>New Yorker</em> article* describes the constructed language Ithkuil, which aims to be “maximally precise” by “eliminating the ambiguity, vagueness, illogic, redundancy, polysemy (multiple meanings) and overall arbitrariness that [are] seemingly ubiquitous in natural human language.”</p>
<p><a href="http://lexiconblog.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ninja.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-292" alt="ninja" src="http://lexiconblog.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ninja.jpg?w=720"   /></a>Our first response was that the creator of this constructed language had likely not seen <a title="the Unbearable Lightness of Meaning" href="http://lexiconblog.com/2013/01/03/the-unbearable-lightness-of-meaning/" target="_blank">our recent blog post</a> about connotation vs. denotation in brand names. The post notes that connotation is often more important than denotation in brand names. An example is <em>gazelle</em>. For the many who have never actually seen one of these animals, the literal meaning may be a bit blurry, yet to them the gazelle is still likely to connote swiftness and grace.</p>
<p>Our second reaction to Ithkuil was to ask why, as its creator noted, overall arbitrariness is so widespread in human language. The answer’s pretty easy if we picture what occurs in ordinary conversation: as communicators, we incline more toward verbal artistry than toward explicit programming. We <strong>launch</strong> plans as if they were rockets, <strong>face</strong> problems as if they were adversaries, and <strong>target</strong> opportunities as if&#8211;well, no need to flog a metaphorical horse.</p>
<p>Consider what language would be like without metaphor. Rather than launching plans, we’d simply make them, or start them. Metaphor is so intrinsic to the way we use words, it’s even difficult to find literal verbs to substitute for <em>face</em> in “face problems” or <em>target</em> in “target opportunities.” It’s much easier to find other metaphors: <em>attack problems</em>, <em>meet problems head on</em>, <em>embrace change</em>, <em>aim for opportunities</em>…</p>
<p>That gives good reason to suppose that even if a precise language&#8211;be it Ithkuil or C++&#8211;should ever be spoken, it wouldn’t take a day for a ninja band of metaphors to start creeping in.</p>
<p>No wonder, then, that metaphor should be a staple of brand names. Metaphor helps us to see something new in everyday objects. It enables brands like <strong>Tide</strong>, <strong>BlackBerry</strong>, and <strong>Volt</strong> to stand out from the competition by endowing them with a unique, attractive message.</p>
<p>Metaphors do lose their force over time. Our verb <em>reveal</em> goes back to a Latin verb meaning ‘pull back the veil,’ yet that image no longer pops up when we encounter the word. Metaphor weakening explains how we get unwitting blends of metaphor like:</p>
<blockquote>
<p style="text-align:left;">Over all, many experts conclude, advanced climate research in the United States is fragmented among an alphabet soup of agencies, strained by inadequate computing power and starved for the basic measurements of real-world conditions that are needed to improve simulations.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;padding-left:360px;"><em>New York Times</em>, June 11, 2001</p>
</blockquote>
<p style="text-align:left;">The images in brand names subside over time as well. While the newcomer <strong>Volt</strong> immediately brings to mind an electric charge, the <strong>BlackBerry</strong>, introduced in 1999, now offers models&#8211;the Porsche and the Pearl&#8211;in colors other than black. <strong>Tide</strong>, introduced in 1946, hardly conjures the image of waves in the sea anymore.</p>
<p>But in branding, that’s OK, because a brand name’s heaviest lifting happens up front, when the name is new. A colorful name attracts attention, ties a unique message to a product, and is more likely to spread virally (if you’ll pardon the metaphor) when it’s first introduced.</p>
<p>Therefore, for those – like the inventor of Ithkuil – that wish to make language more efficient, we recommend metaphor, which in a single word can turn a caterpillar into a butterfly.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">— Will Leben, Chair of Linguistics</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">* Joshua Foer, <a href="http://www.newyorker.com/reporting/2012/12/24/121224fa_fact_foer" target="_blank">“Utopian for Beginners: An Amateur Linguist Loses Control of the Language He Invented.”</a> The New Yorker, December 24 &amp; 31, 2012.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/286/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/286/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=286&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://blog.lexiconbranding.com/2013/01/30/beating-the-drum-for-metaphor/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>28</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/bb7241ca6a25c3359d36324be21b773d?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lexiconblog</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lexiconblog.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/ninja.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ninja</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
