<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2012 21:02:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>An uphill battle for &#8220;Killer Joe&#8221;</title>
		<link>http://thechicagofilmsnob.com/2012/07/27/an-uphill-battle-for-killer-joe/</link>
		<comments>http://thechicagofilmsnob.com/2012/07/27/an-uphill-battle-for-killer-joe/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2012 18:13:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>thechicagofilmsnob</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Film Industry News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Previews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Killer Joe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Matthew McConaughy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blue Valentine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Quentin Tarantino]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[William Friedkin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tracy Letts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bug]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Weinstein Company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[film noir]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[violence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NC-17 Rating]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thechicagofilmsnob.com/?p=63</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Every couple of years or so, there comes a film that gets some momentum prior to its release. Internet blabber says it may be one of the best films of the year, but just months before its release, it gets hit by a big ol’ baseball bat to the stomach, hurting any potential chance of [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=63&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Every couple of years or so, there comes a film that gets some momentum prior to its release. Internet blabber says it may be one of the best films of the year, but just months before its release, it gets hit by a big ol’ baseball bat to the stomach, hurting any potential chance of success. What am I talking about? The film, despite all the hoorah gets slapped with the dreaded and debilitating NC-17 rating. This year the film slapped with this rating goes to “Killer Joe,” the second film collaboration between legendary director William Friedkin and writer Tracy Letts, after 2006&#8242;s &#8220;Bug.&#8221; The film is set to open today in some theaters.</p>
<span style="text-align:center; display: block;"><a href="http://thechicagofilmsnob.com/2012/07/27/an-uphill-battle-for-killer-joe/"><img src="http://img.youtube.com/vi/cxpvzmvFHTM/2.jpg" alt="" /></a></span>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Considering what I have heard about the film, I’m not shocked it got slapped with the rating. While I’m never a proponent of censorship of any kind, I am for the rating system. Sometimes I agree with the ratings and other times I don’t. This is one of those times I’m probably going to have to agree with the rating.</p>
<p><strong>NOTE: If you do not want to hear even the slightest clue of why this film has been hit with the NC-17 rating or if you simply do not want to hear any slight spoiler, stop reading now.</strong></p>
<p>As you can see from the trailer, “Killer Joe” obviously is a film with an immeasurable amount of violence, blood spatter and harsh language. Considering how many rated R films have an excessive amount of violence, blood spatter and harsh language, I highly doubt this plays any part in the NC-17 rating — for the most part at least. When I say most, I’m referring to one scene supposedly taking place in the film that deals with sexual violence, which is no surprise as pretty much whenever any film gets hit with the NC-17 rating it’s due to the sexual content. Due to the graphic details of said scene, I am not going to divulge the details on this blog, nor do I necessarily recommend seeking it out either. However, that’s not the point of this entry.</p>
<p>The point of this entry is that the film actually looks like it could be pretty damn good. The film itself actually looks fairly Tarantino-esque, minus less humor but with the addition of it being a much, much darker film. What I find most intriguing about the film (and I can’t believe I’m typing this) is the acting of Matthew McConaughy. Yes, you heard me. Matthew McConaughy’s acting. Typically whenever I see McConaughy attached to a film, I have trouble taking him seriously. He typically comes off as a good ol’ southern boy who appears to be stoned out of his mind. This demeanor about him also I may add isn’t too distant from his real-life persona. However, in the trailer above, I don’t think of his goofy persona he has portrayed in the past. I actually got pumped up for the film due to what actually, shockingly, looks like a stellar performance.</p>
<p>Where am I going with this? While I don’t agree in altering the vision of the writer and director, once they got the NC-17 rating, if I were them, I would’ve tried to see if there was a way to alter the scene in question or maybe do more implying than doing. There are creative ways in showing provocative, sexual acts on film. Hell, I’ve seen a number of films that were extremely shocking on a sexual/violent level that managed to obtain an R-rating.</p>
<p>My point is this, for a film that looks this good and has some serious potential, this filmmaking tandem should have been smarter and tried their best to get that R-rating. In fact, it’s downright stupid they didn’t try. Just by seeing that trailer, McConaughy I think had a serious shot at Oscar contention. It also probably would’ve had a decent, albeit still niche following in theaters. However, with an NC-17 rating both of those things are most likely out the window. Theaters are very hesitant to carry NC-17 films; in fact, opening weekend, “Killer Joe” is only playing in three theaters in New York. While I think we can guarantee at some point, it’ll play in Los Angeles, don’t be entirely shocked if it ends there, they cut their losses and pull it from theaters for an eventual DVD/Blu-ray release. Even a film town like Chicago may not pick up the film if no one goes to see it in New York and LA.</p>
<p>When something like this happens, the less likely a film is to get nominated, including acting nominations. A lot of times, certain distributors and filmmakers will file an appeal for the rating. This was the case in 2010’s “Blue Valentine.” What helped that film get it to an R-rating though had to do with two things. The first is that it was appealed by the very successful Weinsteins, who have made a history of turning everything they touch into gold. Secondly, the scene in question was simply sexual, wasn’t over the top and had a leg to stand on in its dispute. The filmmakers for “Killer Joe,” I’m guessing, knew they didn’t have a leg to stand on if they were to merely appeal without doing a re-edit.</p>
<p>The bottom line here is that I understand artistic integrity. I applaud it. I would be fiercely defensive if either the MPAA or the studio of a film told me I had to alter a scene due to the explicit nature, despite it being in the script. I for one absolutely dread it when producers try to alter scripts as they tend to destroy the impact of the film. However, I think in this particular case, the filmmakers are shooting themselves in the foot by not altering the film. Hell, if they really want that part to stay then they should compromise by releasing it on DVD/Blu-ray with the uncut version or maybe have select screenings of the NC-17 cut. At the end of the day, this is filmmaking suicide, and I truly hate to see hard working talent go unnoticed.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/63/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/63/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=63&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thechicagofilmsnob.com/2012/07/27/an-uphill-battle-for-killer-joe/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c79ea484cb4c38b6ede815bd291a6da6?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F0.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">thechicagofilmsnob</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8220;Orgasmic&#8221; commercials. Umm&#8230; WHAT&#8217;S your demographic?</title>
		<link>http://spunknanigan.wordpress.com/2012/07/28/orgasmic-commercials-umm-whats-your-demographic/</link>
		<comments>http://spunknanigan.wordpress.com/2012/07/28/orgasmic-commercials-umm-whats-your-demographic/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2012 18:24:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>spunknanigan</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Square Peg, Round Hole]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Angry Elf]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commercials]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ridiculous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shampoo]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://spunknanigan.wordpress.com/?p=97</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;m getting a little tired of seeing women in commercials having orgasms over their hair shampoo, hamburgers, and a myriad of other inanimate objects. IF your shampoo was ACTUALLY that great&#8230; I would buy it. Come to that, I would probably wash my hair a LOT more often&#8230; and I wash it every day! I [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=97&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://spunknanigan.wordpress.com/2012/07/28/orgasmic-commercials-umm-whats-your-demographic/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>16</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/5ca16cb20822932cb5ccd00dd777dc97?s=96&#38;d=&#38;r=R" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">spunknanigan</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ts4.mm.bing.net/images/thumbnail.aspx?q=4776283449066899&#38;id=a90f6bce00b9ef6ec604d65356122270" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://th60.photobucket.com/albums/h35/johnston0902/th_Paris-Hilton-carl-jr--Burger.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://ts3.mm.bing.net/images/thumbnail.aspx?q=4638075703656730&#38;id=b0d64011f975096876160fc56ce2931c" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://ts3.mm.bing.net/images/thumbnail.aspx?q=4876708378641818&#38;id=a53ae10ff9ad2414cface9d437a34ef9" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://ts4.mm.bing.net/images/thumbnail.aspx?q=5018863217476451&#38;id=5692c47e3344bde6b0c4bd79e5821c11" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://ts3.mm.bing.net/images/thumbnail.aspx?q=4956667781972406&#38;id=cf8dbb0e293edb8df6258292e3b68808" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://ts3.mm.bing.net/images/thumbnail.aspx?q=4534283517886574&#38;id=6910bfe1bf053a50a27f990cc3126f77" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://ts1.mm.bing.net/images/thumbnail.aspx?q=4884959012978920&#38;id=d5fecde697efac1d6b305863507ee3ac" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://ts4.mm.bing.net/images/thumbnail.aspx?q=4832036422550671&#38;id=0e0025a3b30c7814adc45e9b7b099c86" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://ts2.mm.bing.net/images/thumbnail.aspx?q=4699618278769253&#38;id=05a533841bd7c715c72d8b0926c9c92e" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://ts1.mm.bing.net/images/thumbnail.aspx?q=4527308513937072&#38;id=410eceb28797d0c1d2de6a1bc1f432d3" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Wide-Eyed Olympic Walk</title>
		<link>http://olympics-2012.si.com/2012/07/27/2012-olympics-venue-tour/</link>
		<comments>http://olympics-2012.si.com/2012/07/27/2012-olympics-venue-tour/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2012 18:23:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>lukewinn</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[2012 Olympics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://olympics-2012.si.com/?p=920</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[LONDON &#8212; This is my first post and my first Summer Olympics, so before the events begin in earnest, I thought I&#8217;d take you on a wide-eyed walking tour of the Olympic Park &#8212; or at least everything I could access with a media credential. The public won&#8217;t hit the park until the gates open [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=920&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>LONDON &#8212; This is my first post and my first Summer Olympics, so before the events begin in earnest, I thought I&#8217;d take you on a wide-eyed walking tour of the Olympic Park &#8212; or at least everything I could access with a media credential. The public won&#8217;t hit the park until the gates open for the Opening Ceremony; in the meantime it&#8217;s a mostly empty wonderland in which media members and staffers are wandering around, and distance runners are using it as a free-range training space. </p>
<p>The tour starts with wheat, as this was also my first time seeing trays of wheat on rolling carts. These are props for Danny Boyle&#8217;s big show at the opening ceremony. He hopes his English countryside scenes will meet high standards of verisimilitude.  </p>
<p><img src="http://siwinterolympics.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/wheat.jpg" alt="Wheat" title="wheat" width="640" height="463" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-945" /></p>
<p>From trays of wheat to walkways with McDonald&#8217;s ball-pit patterns: This is the empty promenade outside fang-walled Olympic Stadium. Colleagues have reported hearing both Paul McCartney&#8217;s soundcheck and the <em>Chariots of Fire</em> theme emanating from inside the stadium.</p>
<p><img src="http://siwinterolympics.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/olympicstadium.jpg" alt="Olympic Stadium" title="olympicstadium" width="640" height="494" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-934" /></p>
<p>If you happen to get a dog inside Olympic Park, organizers don&#8217;t want it defecating on the fancy walkways. They created a &#8220;Dog-relief area,&#8221; complete with wood chips, compost bin &#8230; and a roll of toilet paper, if your dog is into that level of hygiene. </p>
<p><img src="http://siwinterolympics.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dogrelief.jpg" alt="Doggie Relief" title="dogrelief" width="640" height="397" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-929" /></p>
<p>One way to increase your odds of needing a human-relief area: Have a double meal of &#8220;Salt Beef&#8221; and &#8220;Pie and Mash&#8221;:</p>
<p><img src="http://siwinterolympics.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/saltbeef.jpg" alt="Salt Beef" title="saltbeef" width="640" height="239" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-936" /></p>
<p>The well-sodded exterior &#8212; and sleek interior &#8212; of the venue that will dominate the first week of news, the Aquatics Centre: </p>
<p><img src="http://siwinterolympics.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/swimoutside.jpg" alt="Aquatics Center outside" title="swimoutside" width="640" height="324" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-939" /></p>
<p><img src="http://siwinterolympics.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/aquatics2.jpg" alt="Aquatics Center inside" title="aquatics2" width="640" height="409" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-924" /></p>
<p>I hoped to see signs advising swimmers not to hit the water for at least an hour after eating Salt Beef, but all I found was something about a &#8220;deep clean.&#8221; This should make germaphobic spectators and athletes happy. Your Olympics have been sanitized:</p>
<p><img src="http://siwinterolympics.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/deepclean.jpg" alt="Deep Clean" title="deepclean" width="640" height="306" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-927" /></p>
<p>My camera taking a picture of a TV camera taking a swimming picture. So meta!</p>
<p><img src="http://siwinterolympics.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/swimcam.jpg" alt="TV Camera Swim" title="swimcam" width="640" height="393" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-937" /></p>
<p>Less meta: swimming cameras on a catwalk, ready to catch the long view of the pool:</p>
<p><img src="http://siwinterolympics.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/swimcams.jpg" alt="Swim Cameras" title="swimcams" width="640" height="376" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-938" /></p>
<p>Synchronized diving practice. More photogenic than swimming, yet immensely less popular. </p>
<p><img src="http://siwinterolympics.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/divers.jpg" alt="Divers on board" title="divers" width="640" height="364" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-928" /></p>
<p>The divers&#8217; private bath is nicely framed by a concrete embankment. Once again, a better photo subject than swimming practice, which I chose to ignore.</p>
<p><img src="http://siwinterolympics.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/aquatics.jpg" alt="Diver Pool" title="aquatics" width="640" height="419" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-923" /></p>
<p>Boise State has nothing on the Olympic field hockey venue. A fuchsia frame really makes the blue turf &#8220;pop,&#8221; doesn&#8217;t it? </p>
<p><img src="http://siwinterolympics.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/fhfield.jpg" alt="Field Hockey Field" title="FHfield" width="640" height="404" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-931" /></p>
<p>In case you&#8217;ve never seen a what a major field-hockey event bench looks like &#8212; and I, for one, had not &#8212; this is it. Blue seats, fuchsia carpet:</p>
<p><img src="http://siwinterolympics.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/fhbench.jpg" alt="Field Hockey Bench" title="FHbench" width="640" height="417" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-930" /></p>
<p>The Velodrome is my favorite venue, in part because it&#8217;s being billed as <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/sport/2011/feb/22/london-2012-olympics-velodrome-opened" target="_blank">the world&#8217;s fastest cycling track</a>, and in part because front-row spectators can get within inches of cyclists turning high and wide at breakneck speeds. (There are signs that warn fans not to put anything on the rails.)</p>
<p><img src="http://siwinterolympics.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/velodrome.jpg" alt="Velodrome Inside" title="velodrome" width="640" height="480" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-941" /></p>
<p><img src="http://siwinterolympics.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/velobiker.jpg" alt="Velodrome Biker" title="velobiker" width="640" height="427" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-948" /></p>
<p>The BMX venue was still labeled a &#8220;work site&#8221; &#8212; they were putting up the makeshift grandstands &#8212; so I couldn&#8217;t get in, but this is the view from over the deck of the Velodrome:</p>
<p><img src="http://siwinterolympics.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/bmx.jpg" alt="BMX" title="bmx" width="640" height="292" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-925" /></p>
<p>Without an exclamation point, this is more of an instruction than an exhortation &#8230; but it and the Coca-Cola &#8220;Beat Box&#8221; (in the next photo) are the most prominent sculptures in the park. </p>
<p><img src="http://siwinterolympics.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/run.jpg" alt="RUN!" title="run" width="640" height="319" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-935" /></p>
<p><img src="http://siwinterolympics.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/cokething.jpg" alt="Coke" title="cokething" width="640" height="373" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-926" /></p>
<p>This Chinese Taipei coach was not posing for me; I photographer-bombed his wall-grabbing moment at the entrance to the athletes&#8217; village.</p>
<p><img src="http://siwinterolympics.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/village.jpg" alt="Olympic Village" title="village" width="640" height="274" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-943" /></p>
<p>Media access to the residential area of the athletes village is restricted &#8212; as in, we can&#8217;t get back there during the Games &#8212; but SI photographer Bill Frakes took this shot of the Romanian dorm during a tour:</p>
<p><img src="http://siwinterolympics.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/frakesromania.jpg" alt="Romanian Housing" title="frakesromania" width="640" height="388" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-950" /></p>
<p>Frakes also got a glimpse of the athletes&#8217; cafeteria, which  specializes in Rocket Radicchio, an Italian chicory with apparently legal speed-boosting properties.</p>
<p><img src="http://siwinterolympics.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/frakescafe.jpg" alt="Athlete Cafe" title="frakescafe" width="640" height="386" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-949" /></p>
<p>In the souvenir store in the athletes&#8217; village, there&#8217;s a world map pinboard on which visitors are encouraged to post notes of, well, encouragement. Oman only has one note, but it&#8217;s also the only one with lipstick. There is love, in the village, for Oman. </p>
<p><img src="http://siwinterolympics.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/noteswall.jpg" alt="Oman Notes" title="noteswall" width="640" height="381" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-933" /></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/920/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/920/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=920&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://olympics-2012.si.com/2012/07/27/2012-olympics-venue-tour/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/9abebcae63bfd9196653b63bcaa1d6d1?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lukewinn</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://siwinterolympics.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/wheat.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">wheat</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://siwinterolympics.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/olympicstadium.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">olympicstadium</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://siwinterolympics.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/dogrelief.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">dogrelief</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://siwinterolympics.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/saltbeef.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">saltbeef</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://siwinterolympics.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/swimoutside.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">swimoutside</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://siwinterolympics.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/aquatics2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">aquatics2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://siwinterolympics.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/deepclean.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">deepclean</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://siwinterolympics.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/swimcam.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">swimcam</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://siwinterolympics.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/swimcams.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">swimcams</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://siwinterolympics.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/divers.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">divers</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://siwinterolympics.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/aquatics.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">aquatics</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://siwinterolympics.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/fhfield.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">FHfield</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://siwinterolympics.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/fhbench.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">FHbench</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://siwinterolympics.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/velodrome.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">velodrome</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://siwinterolympics.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/velobiker.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">velobiker</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://siwinterolympics.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/bmx.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bmx</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://siwinterolympics.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/run.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">run</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://siwinterolympics.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/cokething.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cokething</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://siwinterolympics.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/village.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">village</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://siwinterolympics.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/frakesromania.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">frakesromania</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://siwinterolympics.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/frakescafe.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">frakescafe</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://siwinterolympics.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/noteswall.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">noteswall</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Exposed ²</title>
		<link>http://strausslouw.wordpress.com/2012/07/22/exposed-%c2%b2/</link>
		<comments>http://strausslouw.wordpress.com/2012/07/22/exposed-%c2%b2/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 20:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Strauss Louw</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[double exposures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[element of chance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[experimenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[juxtaposition]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://strausslouw.wordpress.com/?p=314</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I love having fun with my camera and experimenting with the limits of the film I am using.  I have shot two rolls of double exposures over the past year and find the results increasingly fascinating.  The images are achieved completely by use of the element of chance and it is this that interests me [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=314&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I love having fun with my camera and experimenting with the limits of the film I am using.  I have shot two rolls of double exposures over the past year and find the results increasingly fascinating.  The images are achieved completely by use of the element of chance and it is this that interests me most.  I find the coincidental relationship between the juxtaposition of the different layers of subject matter surprising, as it creates an unintended narrative which allows the viewer to indulge in his or her own imagination and interpretation.</p>
<p>These are the results of the two rolls.</p>
<p><a href="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000010.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-315" title="000010" src="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000010.jpg" alt="" width="584" height="390" /></a><a href="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000011.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-316" title="000011" src="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000011.jpg" alt="" width="584" height="390" /></a><a href="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000012.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-317" title="000012" src="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000012.jpg" alt="" width="584" height="390" /></a><a href="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000014.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-318" title="000014" src="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000014.jpg" alt="" width="584" height="390" /></a><a href="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000016.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-319" title="000016" src="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000016.jpg" alt="" width="584" height="390" /></a><a href="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/0000191.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-320" title="000019" src="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/0000191.jpg" alt="" width="584" height="390" /></a><a href="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000020.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-321" title="000020" src="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000020.jpg" alt="" width="584" height="390" /></a><a href="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000023.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-322" title="000023" src="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000023.jpg" alt="" width="584" height="390" /></a><a href="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/0000301.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-324" title="000030" src="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/0000301.jpg" alt="" width="584" height="390" /></a><a href="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000031.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-325" title="000031" src="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000031.jpg" alt="" width="584" height="390" /></a><a href="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000037.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-326" title="000037" src="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000037.jpg" alt="" width="584" height="390" /></a><a href="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000038.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-327" title="000038" src="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000038.jpg" alt="" width="584" height="390" /></a><a href="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000042.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-328" title="000042" src="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000042.jpg" alt="" width="584" height="390" /></a><a href="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000043.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-329" title="000043" src="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000043.jpg" alt="" width="584" height="390" /></a><a href="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000018.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-331" title="000018" src="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000018.jpg" alt="" width="584" height="391" /></a><a href="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/0000192.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-332" title="000019" src="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/0000192.jpg" alt="" width="584" height="391" /></a><a href="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000021.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-333" title="000021" src="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000021.jpg" alt="" width="584" height="391" /></a><a href="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/0000221.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-334" title="000022" src="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/0000221.jpg" alt="" width="584" height="391" /></a><a href="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000024.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-335" title="000024" src="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000024.jpg" alt="" width="584" height="391" /></a><a href="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000026.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-336" title="000026" src="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000026.jpg" alt="" width="584" height="391" /></a><a href="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/0000302.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-337" title="000030" src="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/0000302.jpg" alt="" width="584" height="391" /></a><a href="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000033.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-338" title="000033" src="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000033.jpg" alt="" width="584" height="391" /></a><a href="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000034.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-340" title="000034" src="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000034.jpg" alt="" width="584" height="391" /></a><a href="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000036.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-341" title="000036" src="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000036.jpg" alt="" width="584" height="391" /></a><a href="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/0000371.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-342" title="000037" src="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/0000371.jpg" alt="" width="584" height="391" /></a><a href="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000039.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-343" title="000039" src="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000039.jpg" alt="" width="584" height="391" /></a><a href="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/0000421.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-344" title="000042" src="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/0000421.jpg" alt="" width="584" height="391" /></a><a href="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/0000431.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-345" title="000043" src="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/0000431.jpg" alt="" width="584" height="391" /></a><a href="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000044.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-346" title="000044" src="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000044.jpg" alt="" width="584" height="391" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/314/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/314/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=314&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://strausslouw.wordpress.com/2012/07/22/exposed-%c2%b2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/96ee0711a4ea98a4454414228e80b56d?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">strausslouw</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000010.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">000010</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000011.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">000011</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000012.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">000012</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000014.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">000014</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000016.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">000016</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/0000191.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">000019</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000020.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">000020</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000023.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">000023</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/0000301.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">000030</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000031.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">000031</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000037.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">000037</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000038.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">000038</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000042.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">000042</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000043.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">000043</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000018.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">000018</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/0000192.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">000019</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000021.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">000021</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/0000221.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">000022</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000024.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">000024</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000026.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">000026</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/0000302.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">000030</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000033.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">000033</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000034.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">000034</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000036.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">000036</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/0000371.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">000037</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000039.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">000039</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/0000421.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">000042</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/0000431.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">000043</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://strausslouw.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/000044.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">000044</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pine Straw, Dad, Birthday</title>
		<link>http://theyoungplum.wordpress.com/2012/07/27/pine-straw-dad-birthday/</link>
		<comments>http://theyoungplum.wordpress.com/2012/07/27/pine-straw-dad-birthday/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2012 14:07:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>theyoungplum</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coffee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://theyoungplum.wordpress.com/?p=313</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[My regular coffee house employs an unreasonable amount of pretty female Asian students; it’s borderline ridiculous. I think the owner is some sort of pervert. I know that’s a bold claim considering I have no hard evidence, but I seriously watched three episodes of Law and Order SVU the other day, and now I feel [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=313&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>My regular coffee house employs an <em>unreasonable</em> amount of pretty female Asian students; it’s borderline ridiculous.</p>
<p>I think the owner is some sort of pervert. I know that’s a bold claim considering I have no hard evidence, but I seriously watched three episodes of Law and Order SVU the other day, and now I feel like I’m qualified to solve particularly heinous crimes taking place in the Raleigh area. I can not, however, find my car keys anytime I might need them.</p>
<p>The owner of said coffee house is an overweight Caucasian male who wears really thick glasses on thin wire frames. He has no hair on the top of his head, but the hair on the sides is really more than suitable enough to tie into a greasy looking ponytail.</p>
<p>That’s <em>definitely</em> the dress code for perverts. Like… 60% of all sex offenders have that same <em>look</em>. They just <em>look</em> sexually offensive. We could cut down on the rate of crime if we just called it early. You can call it <em>profiling </em>if you want, or you can call it my sixth sense, and we can make a movie about it.</p>
<p>Either way, I’m willing to wager he’s some sort of sex offender. If he isn’t, then he eventually will be. When I get some hard evidence, I’ll switch coffee places, but right now I’m quite fine with this place.</p>
<p>The issue really is that the multitude of Asian baristas makes my coffee visits slightly difficult.</p>
<p>I know it’s politically incorrect to say they all look the same, but my GOD the girls here really <em>do</em> look similar. And then as some sick joke they all <em>dress</em> similar; hair in a tight ponytail, basic t-shirt, keds shoes, skinny jeans. Why aren’t any of them wearing nametags?</p>
<p>I divulged my eBay shopping habits to one of the baristas and the very next day I updated her with my loss, being outbid for a pair of jeans that I probably didn’t really need during the last few seconds of bidding. Yes, I lost a battle, but something inside of me still wants to win the war.</p>
<p>The barista, not understanding my nearly psychotic level of ambition, looked at me slightly puzzled for a good few seconds before drawing her conclusion.</p>
<p>&#8220;I think you have me confused with Rachel.&#8221; She said pointing to a slightly more familiar and friendly face.</p>
<p>Oh cool. I’m an idiot.</p>
<p>I’m <em>not </em>a pig headed racist. I have Asian friends. Well…actually, that’s should be singular. I have <em>an</em> Asian friend. We haven’t talked in like three years, but it’s not because I’m racist but because I’m just an awful friend. Maybe I could redeem myself by spurting off bits of Chinese I’ve learned from the back of fortune cookies.</p>
<p>So far, I can say <em>pine straw</em>, <em>dad</em>, and <em>birthday</em>.</p>
<p>I’m as good as dead if I ever run into an emergency in China that <em>doesn’t</em> involve <em>pine</em> <em>straw</em>, <em>dads</em>, or <em>birthday’s</em>.</p>
<p>Additionally, none of those words are suitable for a proper apology, so I did the next best thing:</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&#8220;I’m….so..sorry.&#8221; I said clearly and slowly in the English language.</p>
<p>&#8220;It’s not….a big deal….&#8221; She said just as slow and just as clear.</p>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=313&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://theyoungplum.wordpress.com/2012/07/27/pine-straw-dad-birthday/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>12</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a8df1a1ee56c9c30d87b1c4ad8f7a8b7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">theyoungplum</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Here come the robots . . . can we keep up with them?</title>
		<link>http://writersrest.com/2012/07/26/here-come-the-robots-can-we-keep-up-with-them/</link>
		<comments>http://writersrest.com/2012/07/26/here-come-the-robots-can-we-keep-up-with-them/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2012 07:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lindsay Edmunds</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Machine minds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artificial intelligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[auburn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Siri]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Star Wars]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://writersrest.com/?p=4519</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This blog springboards off an editorial in The Citizen, the newspaper of Auburn, New York. The choice is not arbitrary; I know Auburn, New York. I&#8217;ve shopped in its WalMart, bought half-moon cookies at a little hole-in-the-wall bakery. I attended the baptism of one of my cousin&#8217;s babies at an old Presbyterian church with authentic [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4519&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This blog springboards off an editorial in <em>The Citizen, t</em>he newspaper of Auburn, New York. The choice is not arbitrary; I know Auburn, New York. I&#8217;ve shopped in its WalMart, bought half-moon cookies at a little hole-in-the-wall bakery.</p>
<p>I attended the baptism of one of my cousin&#8217;s babies at an old Presbyterian church with authentic Tiffany windows. The day was stifling hot and humid, and the minister quoted the Lee Ann Womack song, &#8220;I Hope You Dance.&#8221;</p>
<p>The weather in Auburn, New York, on Sunday July 22, 2012, was a sunny and pleasant 74 degrees. In the online edition of <em>The Citizen</em> at auburnpub.com, Brad Molloy published a piece titled <span style="color:#ff0000;"><a href="http://auburnpub.com/columnists/brad_molloy/molloy-i-ve-got-my-own-chaos-theory/article_8a3a2eca-e392-5d12-8ea3-b6050564aee3.html" target="_blank"><span style="color:#ff0000;">&#8220;I&#8217;ve got my own chaos theory.&#8221;</span></a></span></p>
<p>It opens with a quotation:</p>
<blockquote><p>Before we work on artificial intelligence why don&#8217;t we do something about natural stupidity?”</p>
<p>- Steve Polyak</p></blockquote>
<p>Molloy&#8217;s specificity is admirable. He objects to a middle-aged man in a pickup truck who sideswiped a concrete barrier protecting some construction workers while he was texting someone on his phone. &#8220;But even after the sparks were done flying from his sideswipe, he, get this, continued to keep texting!&#8221;</p>
<p>Also, there are people getting high on bath salts. That one was news to me. &#8220;If you are actually considering using bath salts to &#8216;get high&#8217; then it’s time you started using your free time looking for a better paying job,&#8221; Molloy says, reasonably.</p>
<h3><strong>Stupid vs Smart</strong></h3>
<p>The question that occurred to me as I read Malloy&#8217;s small-town good sense was this: as artificial intelligence gets smarter and smarter, what will <a href="http://writersrest.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/robots_r2d2-and-c-3po.png"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-4542" title="Robots_R2D2 and C-3PO" src="http://writersrest.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/robots_r2d2-and-c-3po.png?w=246&h=300" alt="" width="246" height="300" /></a>happen to the haphazard, lazy, short-sighted,  stupid choices?  AI won&#8217;t make them. AI generally represents the work of people who keep their best in mind (whatever &#8220;best&#8221; means for the specific application at hand).</p>
<p>What about the kinds of intelligence uncaptured by AI, at least so far? Intuition, for example. Intuition is real. I ignore it at my peril.</p>
<h3><strong>Our best in mind</strong></h3>
<p>Here in what a friend calls the &#8220;first world&#8221; (that place with a million TV channels and fast internet connections) we know that robots are going to be part of our everyday lives someday soon. Ever talked to Siri? Siri is nothing compared with what is coming.</p>
<p>To me, the best image for the human-robot relationship remains that scene in STAR WARS where <span style="color:#ff0000;"><a href="http://starwars.wikia.com/wiki/Droid" target="_blank"><span style="color:#ff0000;">C-3PO</span></a></span> pompously and fussily describes himself and his purpose to Luke Skywalker. Luke is intent on fixing some sort of machine and does not even bother to look back when he says, casually, &#8220;Hello.&#8221;</p>
<p>We say hello. We adapt. We have been adapting to changing times as long as we have been on earth.</p>
<p>People can love their pets and vice versa. People can bond powerfully and sometimes dangerously with others through the written word, art, and music. Why should robots be any different?</p>
<p>There was a study—I forget its name—that showed that when people took a computer survey and then were asked to evaluate their experience, their ratings were consistently higher when they did the evaluation on the same computer versus a different one. It was as if they didn&#8217;t want to hurt the computer&#8217;s feelings.</p>
<p>So. We know what we are going to do. Try to get along. Continue to love. Do stupid things such as text while driving.</p>
<p>The question not yet answerable:  what are the <em>robots</em> going to do? In that scene with Luke Skywalker, suppose C-3PO had a bad robot agenda?</p>
<p>We  know what machines programmed for intelligence would think of texting while driving. They would find a way to prevent it. Unless, of course, they don&#8217;t like us at all. Unless they want to get us out of the way.</p>
<p>Then they would cuddle up to us with words of encouragement: &#8220;Don&#8217;t worry,&#8221; they would say, &#8220;Do whatever you want.&#8221;</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://writersrest.com/category/machine-minds/'>Machine minds</a> Tagged: <a href='http://writersrest.com/tag/artificial-intelligence/'>artificial intelligence</a>, <a href='http://writersrest.com/tag/auburn/'>auburn</a>, <a href='http://writersrest.com/tag/new-york/'>New York</a>, <a href='http://writersrest.com/tag/robots/'>robots</a>, <a href='http://writersrest.com/tag/siri/'>Siri</a>, <a href='http://writersrest.com/tag/star-wars/'>Star Wars</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4519/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4519/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4519&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://writersrest.com/2012/07/26/here-come-the-robots-can-we-keep-up-with-them/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>16</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/41e849720e1cf66133e15c99283d51e9?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Lindsay Edmunds</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://writersrest.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/robots_r2d2-and-c-3po.png?w=246" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Robots_R2D2 and C-3PO</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Windows Wear Clothes: a product name &#8220;opposition research&#8221; paper ultimately discounted by Bill Gates</title>
		<link>http://pervertedwisdom.com/2012/07/27/why-windows-wear-clothes-a-product-name-opposition-research-paper-ultimately-discounted-by-bill-gates/</link>
		<comments>http://pervertedwisdom.com/2012/07/27/why-windows-wear-clothes-a-product-name-opposition-research-paper-ultimately-discounted-by-bill-gates/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2012 14:15:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Alan Brech</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business communication]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cultural criticism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[philosophy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anti-windows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bad product name]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bill Gates]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[computers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[naked windows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[operating system]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[people hate windows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[windows are bad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[windows are like people]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[windows is bad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[windows product]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://pervertedwisdom.com/?p=1538</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Windows is a bad name for a product. Looking at a window either means you&#8217;re indoors bored or you&#8217;re outdoors pervin&#8217;.  Oh yeah, and they break. Windows are too much like people.  They get dirty.  They get fat under high humidity and lack of exercise.  Windows need clothes.  What else in the house besides you [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1538&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Windows is a bad name for a product. Looking at a window either means you&#8217;re indoors bored or you&#8217;re outdoors pervin&#8217;.  Oh yeah, and they break.</p>
<p>Windows are too much like people.  They get dirty.  They get fat under high humidity and lack of exercise.  Windows need clothes.  What else in the house besides you needs to wear a frilly skirt all the time?</p>
<p>Windows need blinds and curtains and screens and tinting and locks and alarms and brave-but-doomed men to scrub them 200 feet in the air.</p>
<p>And glass isn&#8217;t even a reliable solid&#8211;pure science tells us it&#8217;s just a lazy-ass liquid that hasn&#8217;t gotten around to spilling yet.</p>
<p>How much human blood has been shed over glass?  (None by me&#8211;I <em>think</em> with my feet, thank you.  But <em>other</em> people.  Oafs.)</p>
<p>And don&#8217;t forget <em>Kristallnacht</em>.  Those were windows.</p>
<p>Instructive riddle:  What&#8217;s the opposite of &#8220;safety glass?&#8221;</p>
<p>Glass.</p>
<p>Windows are for prisoners. And un-adopted puppies.  For annoying insects that want to invade at night.</p>
<p>Successful executives turn their backs on windows in order to do their best desk-work.  By contrast, I was only a B+ student because of windows.</p>
<p>Boats won&#8217;t even call their windows windows, that&#8217;s how bad a name windows has.</p>
<p>The happiest people on earth in the pre-modern era&#8211;the Eskimo, Navajo, Plains Indians, Arab Bedouins, and Siberians&#8211;all lived without windows.  Now they&#8217;re miserable.</p>
<p>The Anasazi had windows and disappeared.  Because they knew.</p>
<p>Scientific instruments (microscopes, telescopes, etc.) only use windows that are round and curved and distorted&#8211;i.e., useful only to the extent that they do <em>not</em> function like a normal &#8220;good&#8221; window.  Give a scientist a rectangular plane of perfectly flat glass and he&#8217;ll say &#8220;What they fuck am I going to do with this?&#8221;</p>
<p>Windows kill birds.  They make us look fat.  They&#8217;re the weakest part of the bathysphere. They look creepy on old abandoned houses.  They look even creepier on some old <em><span style="text-decoration:underline;">un</span></em>-abandoned houses!</p>
<p>Worst of all, having big ones supposedly prevents you from throwing those helpful stones your neighbors need to improve their lives or just leave.</p>
<p>The greatest looking-out-the-window thought was never recorded, but if it had been, it probably wouldn&#8217;t have been much better than &#8220;I bet it&#8217;s also raining on the houses of the unjust&#8230; Man, I wish they&#8217;d move out!&#8221;</p>
<p>People <span style="text-decoration:underline;">think</span> they like windows. They don&#8217;t. They just hate walls more.  And that&#8217;s why windows wear clothes.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><em>Alan Brech 2012</em></p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://pervertedwisdom.com/category/business/'>business</a>, <a href='http://pervertedwisdom.com/category/business-communication/'>business communication</a>, <a href='http://pervertedwisdom.com/category/cultural-criticism/'>cultural criticism</a>, <a href='http://pervertedwisdom.com/category/humor/'>humor</a>, <a href='http://pervertedwisdom.com/category/philosophy/'>philosophy</a> Tagged: <a href='http://pervertedwisdom.com/tag/anti-windows/'>anti-windows</a>, <a href='http://pervertedwisdom.com/tag/bad-product-name/'>bad product name</a>, <a href='http://pervertedwisdom.com/tag/bill-gates/'>Bill Gates</a>, <a href='http://pervertedwisdom.com/tag/computers/'>computers</a>, <a href='http://pervertedwisdom.com/tag/naked-windows/'>naked windows</a>, <a href='http://pervertedwisdom.com/tag/operating-system/'>operating system</a>, <a href='http://pervertedwisdom.com/tag/people-hate-windows/'>people hate windows</a>, <a href='http://pervertedwisdom.com/tag/windows-are-bad/'>windows are bad</a>, <a href='http://pervertedwisdom.com/tag/windows-are-like-people/'>windows are like people</a>, <a href='http://pervertedwisdom.com/tag/windows-is-bad/'>windows is bad</a>, <a href='http://pervertedwisdom.com/tag/windows-product/'>windows product</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1538/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1538/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1538&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://pervertedwisdom.com/2012/07/27/why-windows-wear-clothes-a-product-name-opposition-research-paper-ultimately-discounted-by-bill-gates/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/9c164f8a01745907706e69a315777548?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">alanbrech</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gym Types</title>
		<link>http://notthehardestpart.wordpress.com/2012/07/27/gym-types/</link>
		<comments>http://notthehardestpart.wordpress.com/2012/07/27/gym-types/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2012 12:33:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>The Waiting</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Fashion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Healthcare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[douches at the gym with be the death of me]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exercise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fatty mcfatterson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gym]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health club]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[swimming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weird Al Yankovic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[white trash]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[working out]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zumba]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://notthehardestpart.wordpress.com/?p=2165</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[One of the big incentives I have for going to the gym is to observe the wildlife there. I have collected some data about the people I am likely to see, and today I will present my findings. 1. Pacers You can mostly find these people around the weightlifting area. They lift about 500 pounds [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2165&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One of the big incentives I have for going to the gym is to observe the wildlife there. I have collected some data about the people I am likely to see, and today I will present my findings.</p>
<p>1. Pacers</p>
<p>You can mostly find these people around the weightlifting area. They lift about 500 pounds and then just pace around for 30 minutes until they approach the machine and nearly kill themselves lifting again. Then they go home. Although I don&#8217;t usually lift weights at the gym (I heft a 13-pound weight around the house all day long, thank you), I can&#8217;t imagine that this is an optimal fitness plan.</p>
<p>2. Friend Makers</p>
<p>At each gym I&#8217;ve been a member of, there has always been a guy who wants to strike up a conversation and make friends with any warm body available. Perhaps he wants to become king of the gym? I don&#8217;t know, but he does very little exercising and instead just bothers everyone who actually <em>is</em>. No matter how engrossed you appear to be with your book or iPod, he will target you and it&#8217;s hard to shake him if you engage him. This guy at my current gym kind of looks like Weird Al so whenever I see him moseying up to some unknowing person, I imagine him asking them if they&#8217;d like an accordion lesson or to hear the story of how <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=t2mU6USTBRE">he used to be fat</a>.</p>
<div id="attachment_2168" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 330px"><a href="http://notthehardestpart.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/weirdal.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-2168" title="weirdal" src="http://notthehardestpart.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/weirdal.jpg" alt="" width="320" height="320" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Dare to be healthy. <a href="http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Music/WeirdAlYankovic">Source</a></p></div>
<p>3. The Ill-Dressed</p>
<p>There are a number of sub-species of this particular nomenclature (ie, girl who wears only sports bra but shouldn&#8217;t, 40-year-old man who still wears his high school track shorts, etc.), but I am focusing on the people who don&#8217;t seem to understand that corduroy pants do not proper gym attire make. Old people are really bad about this. In their travels through life, some of them never learned that button-down oxford blouses, khaki pants and Tevas with black socks are not optimal exercise apparel. But it&#8217;s not just old people. My younger brother always wears jeans, a wife beater, and Timberlands to the gym. No. Just no. I can&#8217;t even.</p>
<p>4. Gum Smackers</p>
<p>It is extremely easy to come off as a douche at the gym, even when you&#8217;re not. This is because very few people who are at the gym actually want to be, so they (and by &#8220;they&#8221; I mean &#8220;me&#8221;) spend their time there judging everyone who seems to be enjoying themselves/not having trouble. Thus enters the gum-chewer. If I am dying during Zumba and you are flying through the routine while still chomping your gum and barely sweating whatsoever, you are a douche. Plain and simple. You are also likely to be wearing shorts with &#8220;PINK&#8221; or &#8220;JUICY&#8221; across your butt. See # 3.</p>
<div id="attachment_2175" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 460px"><a href="http://notthehardestpart.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/juicy-pants.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-2175" title="juicy pants" src="http://notthehardestpart.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/juicy-pants.jpg" alt="" width="450" height="276" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Oh, I&#8217;m sorry. I seem to have confused you for someone I don&#8217;t want to punch in the face.  <a href="http://blogs.endonline.com/wakeupcall/2010/11/10/things-women-should-never-do-after-35/">Source</a></p></div>
<p>5. The Bored</p>
<p>Not to be confused with Pacers, who ought to be bored if they aren&#8217;t already, these are the people who come in with every iDevice available on the market, plus an e-reader, plus a hardcover book. Each are set up in its own little spot on the treadmill, where the Bored will walk for maybe 45 minutes. I can&#8217;t even justify bringing that much crap on a transcontinental flight.</p>
<div id="attachment_2173" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://notthehardestpart.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/swim-fin.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-2173" title="swim fin" src="http://notthehardestpart.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/swim-fin.jpg?w=300&h=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Silicone frog fins: for when shaving your legs and chest just doesn&#8217;t alienate you enough</p></div>
<p>6. The Fake Fish</p>
<p>At health clubs with pools, you will find people who swim only with flippers and fins that make them go faster. Why? Just why? You&#8217;re not racing anyone. Again, I&#8217;m not a swimmer so maybe there&#8217;s some secret real usage for these that I&#8217;m not aware of, but they seem like the equivalent of running with shoes with springs in them. Sorry, but the more unnecessary equipment you use, the doucheyer you look.</p>
<p>And last but not least:</p>
<p>7. The Coerced</p>
<p>You can always tell the people at the gym who are there because their doctor ordered it and their spouse found out and made them go. They do everything to counteract the health benefits of exercising. At one gym I used to go to, there was a group of 350-pound men who would stake out the stationary cycles where they&#8217;d drink coffee and talk about football. Occasionally they would pedal. Occasionally.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s all I&#8217;ve got for now. I&#8217;m writing this on Thursday, which is my off day at the gym, and I&#8217;ve already thought far too much about it.</p>
<p><strong>Do you have any pet peeves about exercising at the gym?</strong></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2165/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2165/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2165&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://notthehardestpart.wordpress.com/2012/07/27/gym-types/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>126</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/0cd3f9443e0754bb29cb8b7dcb3eae58?s=96&#38;d=monsterid&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">takeitonfaith</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://notthehardestpart.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/weirdal.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">weirdal</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://notthehardestpart.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/juicy-pants.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">juicy pants</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://notthehardestpart.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/swim-fin.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">swim fin</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Learning from shortcomings and other movements</title>
		<link>http://ericstoner.net/2012/07/23/learning-from-shortcomings-and-other-movements/</link>
		<comments>http://ericstoner.net/2012/07/23/learning-from-shortcomings-and-other-movements/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2012 01:51:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>ericstoner1</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Afghanistan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[foreign policy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Iraq]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mercenaries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nonviolence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[War]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ericstoner.net/?p=912</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[July 23, 2012 Mobilizing Ideas The 10-year anniversary for the movement that sprung up against the war in Iraq is on the horizon, and it presents an opportune time to reflect on its progress, and more importantly, the lessons that can be learned from its shortcomings. While activists were busy organizing in the fall of [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=912&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://ericstoner.net/2012/07/23/learning-from-shortcomings-and-other-movements/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/bc1ea1276072f19a5b0d35b212302fee?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ericstoner1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ericstoner1.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/protest-8.jpg?w=300" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Weddings Are Hilarious.</title>
		<link>http://girlonthecontrary.com/2012/07/27/weddings-are-hilarious-4/</link>
		<comments>http://girlonthecontrary.com/2012/07/27/weddings-are-hilarious-4/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2012 11:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>girlonthecontrary</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wedding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wedding]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://girlonthecontrary.com/?p=3088</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Did you know you aren&#8217;t allowed to get angry when you&#8217;re a bride? Yeah. That&#8217;s a thing. You aren&#8217;t allowed to get angry because no matter how justified your anger, everyone will call you a &#8220;Bridezilla&#8221; and completely disregard your feelings, even if they&#8217;re legitimate&#8230;.because you&#8217;re getting married&#8230;.so, that automatically makes you a &#8220;Bridezilla&#8221;. Apparently, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3088&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://girlonthecontrary.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/screen-shot-2012-07-26-at-7-14-50-pm.png"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3090" title="Godzilla" src="http://girlonthecontrary.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/screen-shot-2012-07-26-at-7-14-50-pm.png" alt="Godzilla" width="500" height="364" /></a></p>
<p>Did you know you aren&#8217;t allowed to get angry when you&#8217;re a bride? Yeah. That&#8217;s a thing. You aren&#8217;t allowed to get angry because no matter how justified your anger, everyone will call you a &#8220;Bridezilla&#8221; and completely disregard your feelings, even if they&#8217;re legitimate&#8230;.because you&#8217;re getting married&#8230;.so, that automatically makes you a &#8220;Bridezilla&#8221;. Apparently, it&#8217;s science.</p>
<p>Say, for example, you&#8217;re a bride and a member of your bridal party intentionally hits you with their car (you know, for laughs) &#8211; you totally can&#8217;t get mad at them because then everyone will say &#8220;She&#8217;s just stressed about having two broken legs at the wedding and is being such a Bridezilla.&#8221; That is a thing that would happen.</p>
<p>Or, on a less violently hyperbolic note, perhaps someone you&#8217;ve invited to the wedding makes a big deal about how inconvenient your wedding is for them and what a hassle it will be to attend. You, as the bride, are not allowed to respond with anything other than a smile and a shrug because otherwise OH MY GOSH IT&#8217;S BRIDEZILLA.</p>
<p>There are a lot of things that can go wrong with your wedding, and nothing is going to go exactly as planned. Most of those things are minor and you&#8217;ll be able to laugh about them because, in case you haven&#8217;t heard, weddings are hilarious. But there will be other things, things that actually do matter, relationships that matter, that are going to go through the ringer and cause the bride heartache and headache- and while those things might not be hilarious (although, if you&#8217;re me, you might still inappropriately laugh at them) what <em>is</em> hilarious is that as a bride, you aren&#8217;t allowed to get mad without getting slapped with a big scarlet <span style="color:#ff0000;"><strong>B</strong></span> for &#8220;Bridezilla&#8221;. And that&#8217;s funny y&#8217;all because out of all the villainous monsters, I&#8217;m way more of a Medusa when I get mad. Or like, an Octoshark.  Godzilla doesn&#8217;t even make sense- I&#8217;m terrified of dinosaurs, why would I become one when I&#8217;m mad? That&#8217;s just poor logic.</p>
<p>I guess what I&#8217;m trying to say is that people should be more clever with their bride-directed insults. Yeah. That&#8217;s probably what I&#8217;m trying to say. Because I certainly wouldn&#8217;t say that it&#8217;s some bull that a bride isn&#8217;t allowed to get angry for legitimate reasons for fear of being labeled a &#8220;Bridezilla&#8221;. Saying something like that would make me a &#8220;Bridezilla&#8221;. Which I&#8217;m not. Because I&#8217;m afraid of dinosaurs.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3088/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3088/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3088&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://girlonthecontrary.com/2012/07/27/weddings-are-hilarious-4/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>45</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/6251d19e7be07c898a24b78a732cb1ab?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F0.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">girlonthecontrary</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://girlonthecontrary.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/screen-shot-2012-07-26-at-7-14-50-pm.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Godzilla</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>