<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2013 21:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Downton Abbey Power Rankings</title>
		<link>http://bluestockingsmag.com/2013/01/07/downton-abbey-power-rankings/</link>
		<comments>http://bluestockingsmag.com/2013/01/07/downton-abbey-power-rankings/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2013 00:47:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bluestockings</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[downton abbey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[issue 1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[television]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://bluestockingsmag.com/?p=544</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As the new Mad Men season aired last spring, Grantland writer Mark Lisanti wrote &#8220;Power Rankings&#8221; for each weekly episode, ranking the top ten most powerful characters that really held their own, characters that had the nerve do something bold and unprecedented. I set out to do the same with America&#8217;s new favorite period piece [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=544&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_545" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><img class="size-medium wp-image-545" alt="Downton Abbey Women, Clothes, Jewelry" src="http://bluestockingsmagazine.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/downton-abbey-women-clothes-jewelry.png?w=300&#038;h=197" width="300" height="197" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Edith, Sybil, and Mary Crawley from Downton Abbey</p></div>
<p>As the new <i>Mad Men </i>season aired last spring, <i>Grantland</i> writer Mark Lisanti wrote &#8220;Power Rankings&#8221; for each weekly episode, ranking the top ten most powerful characters that really held their own, characters that had the nerve do something bold and unprecedented. I set out to do the same with America&#8217;s new favorite period piece television obsession <i>Downton Abbey</i>, a Masterpiece Theater series created by Julian Fellowes. The series depicts the lives of the British aristocratic Crawley family and their servants at their country estate, Downton Abbey. Seasons one and two are set between April 1912 and December 1919, during which great world events shape the lives of the people at Downton and the British social hierarchy in general. These events include the sinking of the Titanic, WWI and the Spanish influenza epidemic.</p>
<p>The series begins with Lord Robert Crawley, head of the Downton estate, receiving news of the death of his heir aboard the Titanic. Lord Crawley sees the preservation of the Downton estate as his mission in life<b>, </b>and feels strongly about the necessity to marry off one of his daughters to the heir of Downton in order to maintain the estate&#8217;s line of heritage. In turn, he bringS a distant cousin, Matthew Crawley, to the estate to act as his new heir. Matthew and his mother, Isobel, are very progressive and socially engaged, and clash at first with Lady Mary Crawley, eldest daughter of Lord Crawley, and the Dowager Countess Violet Crawley, Lord Crawley&#8217;s mother. Meanwhile, the staff members of Downton have intriguing storylines amongst themselves, storylines of dedication, heartbreak, and inner strength, even as they lead most of their entire lives within Downton’s servants quarters.</p>
<p>Only a total of seventeen episodes in, this television import from the UK has captured the undivided attention of over fourteen million Americans—but why? Is it because everyone loves watching the Earl of Grantham stomp around the estate in his old military uniform? Probably not. How about watching Carson the Butler all puffed up in a rage, spurting out ridiculous phrases like &#8220;hobbledehoy?&#8221; Definitely not. It&#8217;s really all about the women when it comes to <i>Downton Abbey.</i></p>
<p>The ladies of <i>Downton Abbey </i>are the backbone and the soul of the show, and when it comes down to it, they are the ones who hold all the cards. In a time where most period piece television shows revolve around males (think <i>Mad Men</i>, <i>Boardwalk Empire</i>, <i>Vegas</i>) or if there are female storylines, they&#8217;re always dependent upon the storylines of their male counterparts. No period television drama currently on the air really explores female issues of the time, other than as a secondary or tertiary storyline. Even though <i>Downton Abbey</i> is an ensemble show, it does a fantastic job of showing the nuances of womanhood in post-Edwardian British society, from many generational and socioeconomic viewpoints. If there&#8217;s any women&#8217;s issue taken up in an episode, such as employment for an aristocratic woman or the women&#8217;s vote, you&#8217;ll see the it from all sides, from the perspective of an elderly countess to the perspective of a teenage kitchen maid. Moreover, even issues that aren&#8217;t as gendered as &#8220;women&#8217;s&#8221; issues, such as the First World War, the changing significance of the aristocracy in British society or adapting to new inventions like the telephone or increasingly modern automobile models, you can bet that elderly countess, that teenage kitchen maid, and every female in-between will have something distinct and poignant to say about it, something that will resonate with you even after the episode&#8217;s over.</p>
<p>So, here it is, the Top Ten Key Female Players on the Downton estate:</p>
<p>1) <b>The Right Honorable Violet Crawley, Dowager Countess of Grantham (<i>played by Maggie Smith</i></b>)</p>
<p>If you have ever watched even a single episode of <i>Downton Abbey</i>, you know that Violet is the head bitch in charge. The Dowager Countess is always a step ahead of everyone else. Nothing gets by without her knowledge of it, and she has the final word on every decision that is made in the Downton Abbey village and estate—and with good reason! No matter what the moment is, she&#8217;s always got the perfect retort:</p>
<p>-Exhibit A: <i>(on Mr. Pamuk, the Turkish visitor to Downton Abbey, and his sudden death at Downton) </i>&#8220;Of course it would happen to a foreigner.  It&#8217;s typical…No Englishman would dream of dying in someone else&#8217;s house.&#8221;</p>
<p>-Exhibit B: <i>(on Lady Edith lamenting her probable future as a spinster) </i>&#8220;Don&#8217;t be defeatist, dear. It&#8217;s very middle-class.&#8221;</p>
<p>-Exhibit C: <i>(on dealing with the blackmailing Sir Richard Carlisle) </i>&#8220;We can&#8217;t have him assassinated, I suppose.&#8221;</p>
<p>And there you have it—the head bitch in charge.</p>
<p>2) <b>Lady Sybil Crawley/Branson <i>(played by Jessica Brown Findlay)</i></b></p>
<p>Between her one-piece silk and tulle genie-like dinner party outfit, her desire to work as a nurse, and running off with the socialist Irish chauffeur, Lady Sybil is always challenging the norm. She is not someone who wants to split her time between social engagements and sitting around an estate all day; instead she would rather have a long, frustrating day in a hospital, probably followed by heading to the pub to grab a pint with her co-workers. She is definitively marching to the beat of her own drum, but what is even greater about Lady Sybil is that she wants everyone else to do the same—there&#8217;s no criticism of her sister, Lady Mary, who wants her whole life to revolve around Downton Abbey (more on her shortly), nor of someone like Carson the Butler, who lives and breathes to serve the Crawley family in the most traditional fashion. Lady Sybil is, unashamedly, pro-choice (which may or may not come into conflict with her new Irish Roman Catholic husband, whom she marries at the end of season two. To be determined…).</p>
<p><b>3) Lady Mary Crawley <i>(played by Michelle Dockery)</i></b></p>
<p>Ah, the ever so practical Lady Mary. She is without a doubt the product of her grandmother Violet—everything has to play out in a business-like manner. Lady Mary has no time to worry about others&#8217; feelings, much less others&#8217; problems of the heart—unless of course, they&#8217;re her own (oh, to love your third cousin, Matthew Crawley!) But Lady Mary is quite virtuous in her loyalty, to Downton Abbey, to her family, and most importantly, to herself. As Sir Richard Carlisle, a newspaper man, tries to blackmail Mary into marrying him by threatening to release information about her out-of-marriage sexual trysts with the Turkish visitor to Downton, Mr. Pamuk, she ultimately decides that it is better to live with a scandalized name than marry a man that already does and will continue to treat her without dignity and without respect. This is something huge for a woman of that time with her status, given the standards for women in the 1910s (no sex before marriage, especially with a foreigner!) and especially the standards for aristocratic women, who were the celebrities of Britain at the time. When it comes down to it, Lady Mary is a principled woman, and nothing can sway her from the rules of life she has set out for herself.</p>
<p><b>4) Gwen Dawson <i>(played by Rose Leslie)</i></b></p>
<p>Gwen is not the typical dreaming housemaid, who spends her spare moments wondering what a life outside of serving an estate would be like—she makes things happen! It takes real <i>chutzpah</i> and bravery to decide you&#8217;re going to secretly hide a typewriter in the estate you&#8217;re working in and spend any free time you have learning how to type so that you can ever so slightly move up in the rigid British class system and make a better life for yourself. But Gwen doesn&#8217;t care, because she knows if she sets her mind to it, she will get exactly what she dreams of, some life that is more fulfilling than a life of solely serving others. And look!—at the end of the first season this girl of poor country farming origins secures herself (with a bit of help from Lady Sybil) a position as a secretary for the new telephone installation company. It was a shame to see her leave the show after this happened, because her determination was really something inspirational to us all.</p>
<p><b>5) Mrs. Isobel Crawley <i>(played by Penelope Wilton)</i></b></p>
<p>Isobel is probably the most headstrong character on this show. At one time married to a doctor with whom she sometimes worked, she knows she is just as capable as any man and is always out to prove it. At times her very modern views may come into conflict with Violet&#8217;s (let&#8217;s be real, they <i>always</i> come into conflict) but somebody has to be there to convert Downton Abbey into a very much needed WWI convalescent hospital, or tell Violet that shorter skirts and looser cut dresses are the way of the future for women. That someone is always going to be Isobel.</p>
<p><b>6) Anna Smith/Bates <i>(played by Joanna Froggatt)</i></b></p>
<p>Very much like Lady Mary, whom she attends to as a ladymaid, Anna knows what she thinks is right and what she thinks is wrong, and nothing will cause her to waver. She knows that Mr. Bates is a good man, and refuses to let any naysayers (ahem ahem, O&#8217;Brien and Thomas) say any different. Even when Mr. Bates is indicted for the murder of his ex-wife, Anna sees it only as a moment to stick even closer to him, doing everything in her power to clear his name. Yes, it is because she loves him, but I think it is even more because she knows he is an innocent man who is accused of a crime he did not commit—she seeks justice to no end, and for that kind of righteous persistence, she is an obvious female favorite on <i>Downton Abbey</i>.</p>
<p><b>7) Mrs. Beryl Patamore <i>(played by Lesley Nicol)</i></b></p>
<p>Mrs. Patamore is the best cook out there, and she will never let you forget it. She runs that kitchen with an iron fist, and I pity the fool that tries to get in her way. It truly is an amazing feat to cook three square meals daily for a family of five, plus their frequent and occasional guests, plus the entire staff of the Downton Abbey estate, and she knows that there&#8217;s no one out there better for the job than her, which is why she leaves Downton Abbey kicking and screaming (metaphorically) when Lord Grantham sends her to a London hospital for eye surgery so that she can regain her sight. Mrs. Patamore is a straight-up lion (she&#8217;s got the hair for it, after all)—proceed with caution.</p>
<p><b>8) Miss Sarah O&#8217;Brien <i>(played by Siobhan Finneran)</i></b><b><i> </i></b></p>
<p>Also proceed with caution with O&#8217;Brien: she is the vengeful type and believe you me, you will feel it if and when you cross her. For every kindness she does not forget it, that goes doubly for anyone that does this ladymaid wrong. She is distrustful and obviously a believer in survival of the fittest, which would explain all the horrible tricks she plays on Mr. Bates. But, she carries with her a dignity and respect that, rather than becoming apparent only at certain times, is with her and on display at all times. There is a never-ending list of awful things one could call O&#8217;Brien, but weak is certainly not one of them.</p>
<p><b>9) Mrs. Elsie Hughes <i>(played by Phyllis Logan)</i></b></p>
<p>Yes, Mrs. Hughes is the head housekeeper, and yes, she does a very good job at being housekeeper, but Julian Fellowes has not given his viewers much on Mrs. Hughes to keep us interested—except for the fourth episode of season one, in which a former suitor of Mrs. Hughes&#8217; youth returns to court her and ask her to marry him. As Mrs. Hughes relates the history of herself and this man to Carson the Butler, it becomes clear that her choice between the suitor and continuing to work at Downton was really a question of choosing dependence on another or self-reliance, and Mrs. Hughes, before and then again, could not bring herself to give up her independence. For that, I tip my nonexistent hat to Mrs. Hughes.</p>
<p><b>10) The Right Honorable Cora Crawley, Countess of Grantham <i>(played by Elizabeth McGovern)</i></b></p>
<p>Last but not least we have Lady Cora, who, like Mrs. Hughes, usually is not the center of attention of any episode. But she is the wife of the Earl of Grantham, and her family&#8217;s fortune did save the Downton estate, so she&#8217;s got both money and power on her side. More interesting, though, is that her maiden name is Levinson—is she a part of the tribe? A member of the chosen people? If so, there must be some wild backstory in which she had to square off with Violet in order to get her permission to marry her son, Lord Grantham (I would think the Dowager Countess would want pure Anglo-Saxon blood for her son and her grandchildren). Maybe one day Julian Fellowes will make use of the classic flashback but until then, we can only speculate on the strength and willpower of this Jewish-American countess.</p>
<p>Not ranked: Lady Edith Crawley, Daisy Robinson the kitchen maid, the evil ex-wife Vera Bates, Jane and Ethel the housemaids, Mrs. Bird the other cook, Ms. Lavinia Swire the deceased fiancée of Matthew Crawley, Lady Rosamund Painswick the sister of the Earl of Grantham, Lady Rosamund&#8217;s ladymaid, the farmer&#8217;s wife from that one time Edith drove a tractor, other miscellaneous maids on the estate, women of the village. Some of these ladies don&#8217;t have enough of a storyline to ever warrant a power ranking (c&#8217;mon, the farmer&#8217;s wife from that one time Edith drove a tractor?). But the real difference between them and the Top Ten Ladies of Downton is that they have not quite found their voice, unlike the most powerful females of the show. The most powerful women of <i>Downton Abbey</i> are the ones that have worked out the extent of their agency over their lives in a strict male-dominated British society—and are constantly striving for even greater agency over their lives that they know they deserve.</p>
<p><em>-Kate Holguin, Features Editor</em></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/544/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/544/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=544&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://bluestockingsmag.com/2013/01/07/downton-abbey-power-rankings/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://bluestockingsmagazine.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/downton-abbey-women-clothes-jewelry.png?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://bluestockingsmagazine.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/downton-abbey-women-clothes-jewelry.png?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Downton Abbey Women, Clothes, Jewelry</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/7cf32fee294fd02ae4c8cec3585315e8?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bluestockingsmagazine</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://bluestockingsmagazine.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/downton-abbey-women-clothes-jewelry.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Downton Abbey Women, Clothes, Jewelry</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Test Scores Over Touchdowns</title>
		<link>http://thequietvoice18.wordpress.com/2013/01/06/test-scores-over-touchdowns-when-sports-soil-our-education-system/</link>
		<comments>http://thequietvoice18.wordpress.com/2013/01/06/test-scores-over-touchdowns-when-sports-soil-our-education-system/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2013 14:10:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Thomas</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Society]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[academics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[achievement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[athletics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rape]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[steubenville]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[success]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thequietvoice18.wordpress.com/?p=2567</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I have attended every book club meeting at my school. I&#8217;ve never missed a National Honor Society meeting, a Math Honor Society meeting, a Social Studies Honor Society meeting, or a Latin Honor Society meeting. But when I tell people that I&#8217;ve never attended a high school football game, I am always asked the same [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2567&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_2576" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://thequietvoice18.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/football-players-picture.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-2576 " style="border:1px solid grey;" alt="High School Football/slapstix55/CC/flickr" src="http://thequietvoice18.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/football-players-picture.jpg?w=300&#038;h=199" width="300" height="199" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">High School Football/slapstix55/CC/flickr</p></div>
<p>I have attended every book club meeting at my school. I&#8217;ve never missed a National Honor Society meeting, a Math Honor Society meeting, a Social Studies Honor Society meeting, or a Latin Honor Society meeting. But when I tell people that I&#8217;ve never attended a high school football game, I am always asked the same question: <em>what&#8217;s wrong with you?</em></p>
<p>What&#8217;s wrong with me? Let&#8217;s take a look at what&#8217;s wrong with America&#8217;s schools first. <span id="more-2567"></span>China, Korea, Finland, and numerous other countries are <a href="http://www.pbs.org/newshour/extra/features/us/july-dec10/education_12-10.html">crushing us</a> in terms of test scores &#8211; especially in subjects like math and science. One out of every three fourth graders is at a below basic reading level, while more than 67% of fourth graders <a href="http://www.studentsfirst.org/pages/the-stats">are not reading at grade level at all</a>. <a href="http://www.fldcu.org/">Athletic scholarships</a> abound while hardworking Honor Roll students earning perfect SAT scores have to work at Walmart and McDonald&#8217;s just to make ends meet.</p>
<p>Tell me how throwing a football will help solve our country&#8217;s financial problems and save us from going over the fiscal cliff. Tell me how kicking a soccer ball will ameliorate our country&#8217;s failing mental health system. Tell me how slamming a tennis serve will solve our country&#8217;s foreign face offs in the Middle East. Tell me how anything related to pure physical achievement will allow our society to make great strides, or how it will propel our country to prosperity.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m not anti-athletics. I understand the value of sports in that they encourage exercise, promote teamwork, and provide entertainment. As a member of the tennis team and a proponent of several professional tennis players, I see that sports are not inherently evil. But why do we need sports in our education system? As one commenter noted in <a href="http://news.yahoo.com/ohio-sheriff-confronts-protesters-football-rape-case-212214094.html">this</a> Yahoo! article, why can we not have Little League teams or Minor League teams to train athletes for professional teams? Why should the star football player be the &#8220;big man on campus&#8221; while the gifted intellectual struggles day and night for successes that could save our country?</p>
<p>I hope this post doesn&#8217;t sound too caustic. I&#8217;m just upset over the<a href="http://localleaks.blogs.ru/"> recent rape case</a> that has overtaken the town of Steubenville, Ohio, where members of their community have tried to cover up for the suspected rapists involved &#8211; beloved football players who have now been labeled the &#8220;Rape Crew&#8221;. Maybe if those guys had read <em>Speak</em> by Laurie Halse Anderson or learned about human dignity after a discussion of <em>To Kill a Mockingbird</em>, things would have gone down differently.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2567/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2567/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2567&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thequietvoice18.wordpress.com/2013/01/06/test-scores-over-touchdowns-when-sports-soil-our-education-system/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>26</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a6f14f2cceace2ef19b834cf41d8f8ef?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">thequietvoice18</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thequietvoice18.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/football-players-picture.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">High School Football/slapstix55/CC/flickr</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Proxies for Reality: Fact-Based Films and Their Mythmaking Potential</title>
		<link>http://mediamythalert.wordpress.com/2013/01/07/proxies-for-reality-fact-based-films-and-their-mythmaking-potential/</link>
		<comments>http://mediamythalert.wordpress.com/2013/01/07/proxies-for-reality-fact-based-films-and-their-mythmaking-potential/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2013 17:03:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>W. Joseph Campbell</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cinematic treatments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Debunking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Murrow-McCarthy myth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Washington Post]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Watergate myth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[All the President's Men]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cinema]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fact-checking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Getting It Wrong]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media-driven myths]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Watergate]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mediamythalert.wordpress.com/?p=12795</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Carefully researched, yet with enough fictional or imaginative elements so that it's no documentary: Those have been ingredients of mythmaking by the cinema. Take "All the President's Men," as an example.<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=12795&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Sunday &#8220;Outlook&#8221; section of the <em><a title="No ‘rock-em,’ no ‘sock-em’: What ails WaPo" href="http://mediamythalert.wordpress.com/2011/08/07/no-rock-em-no-sock-em-what-ails-wapo/">Washington Post</a></em> usually is such a <a href="http://www.zerodarkthirty-movie.com/"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-12817" alt="ZeroDarkThirty_poster" src="http://mediamythalert.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/zerodarkthirty_poster.jpg?w=202&#038;h=300" width="202" height="300" /></a>jumble of <a title="‘Spiegel’ thumbsucker invokes Watergate myth" href="http://mediamythalert.wordpress.com/2010/12/14/spiegel-thumbsucker-invokes-watergate-myth/">thumbsucker </a>essays and middling book reviews that it deserves just passing attention.</p>
<p>What made yesterday&#8217;s &#8220;Outlook&#8221; an exception was an engaging <a title="Critique of 'Zero Dark Thirty'" href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/a-cia-veteran-on-what-zero-dark-thirty-gets-wrong-about-the-bin-laden-manhunt/2013/01/03/4a76f1b8-52cc-11e2-a613-ec8d394535c6_print.html" target="_blank">critique</a> of <a title="Zero Dark Thirty description" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1790885/" target="_blank"><em>Zero Dark Thirty</em></a>, the <a title="'Atlantic' on 'Zero Dark Thirty'" href="http://www.theatlantic.com/entertainment/archive/2012/12/dont-trust-zero-dark-thirty/266253/" target="_blank">controversial new movie</a> about the CIA&#8217;s years-long hunt for terror leader <a title="False parallels: bin Laden slaying and bogus tale about Jessica Lynch" href="http://mediamythalert.wordpress.com/2011/05/05/false-parallels-bin-laden-slaying-and-bogus-tale-about-jessica-lynch/">Osama bin-Laden</a>.</p>
<p>The critique, written by former CIA official Jose A. Rodriguez Jr., suggests anew the mythmaking capacity of fact-based films. &#8220;Inevitably,&#8221; Rodriguez writes of <em>Zero Dark Thirty</em>, &#8220;films like this come to be seen by the public as a sort of proxy for reality.&#8221;</p>
<p>And that&#8217;s especially troubling because, as Rodriguez also points out:</p>
<p>&#8220;One of the advantages of inhabiting the world of Hollywood is that you can have things both ways.&#8221; Publicity for <em>Zero Dark Thirty</em> emphasizes that it rests upon careful research, Rodriguez notes; at the same time, the film&#8217;s screenwriter, Mark Boal, has insisted it&#8217;s &#8220;not a documentary.&#8221;</p>
<p>Carefully researched, yet with enough fictional or imaginative elements so that it&#8217;s no documentary: Such have been the ingredients of mythmaking by the cinema.</p>
<p><a title="WaPo on ‘historically faulty’ films: Ignoring ATPM" href="http://mediamythalert.wordpress.com/2011/02/27/wapo-on-historically-faulty-films-ignoring-atpm/"><em>All the President&#8217;s Men</em></a> offers a compelling example.</p>
<p>The <a title="The hero-journalist myth of Watergate" href="http://mediamythalert.wordpress.com/2010/02/07/the-hero-journalist-myth-of-watergate/">hero-journalist myth of Watergate</a> &#8212; the notion that the dogged investigative journalism of <em>Washington </em><em>Post</em> reporters Bob Woodward and Carl Bernstein <a title="On bringing down Nixon" href="http://mediamythalert.wordpress.com/2010/04/12/on-bringing-down-nixon/">brought down</a> Richard Nixon&#8217;s corrupt presidency &#8212; was propelled and <a title="Pumping up Watergate’s heroic-journalist myth" href="http://mediamythalert.wordpress.com/2011/03/10/pumping-up-watergates-heroic-journalist-myth/">solidified </a>by the cinematic treatment of <a title="Only superstars newspapers even produced?" href="http://mediamythalert.wordpress.com/2012/04/16/woodward-and-bernstein-the-only-superstars-newspapers-ever-produced/" target="_blank">Woodward and Bernstein</a>&#8216;s 1974 book, <em>All the President&#8217;s Men</em>.</p>
<p>The movie version was fact-based, but certainly no documentary treatment of Watergate (even though the<em> Post</em> once referred to the film as journalism&#8217;s &#8220;<a title="WaPo on ATPM" href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-srv/national/longterm/watergate/stories/ringle.htm" target="_blank">finest 2 hours and 16 minutes</a>&#8220;).<br />
<em></em></p>
<p>As I note in my media-mythbusting book, <a title="Getting It Wrong_Amazon.com" href="http://www.amazon.com/Getting-Wrong-Greatest-Misreported-Journalism/dp/0520262093/ref=sr_1_2?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1315662496&amp;sr=1-2" target="_blank"><strong><em>Getting It Wrong</em></strong></a>, <em>All the President&#8217;s Men</em> the movie offers &#8220;a neat, tidy, and vastly simplified account of the Watergate scandal, one that allowed viewers to sidestep the scandal’s complexity while engaging in an entertaining storyline.”</p>
<p>The movie dramatized the reporting of <a title="Woodward, Bernstein toppled Nixon? Think again" href="http://mediamythalert.wordpress.com/2011/08/27/woodward-bernstein-toppled-nixon-think-again/" target="_blank">Woodward and Bernstein</a> while ignoring the <a title="What was decisive in Watergate’s outcome?" href="http://mediamythalert.wordpress.com/2010/07/25/what-was-decisive-in-watergates-outcome/" target="_blank">far more decisive contributions</a> of federal investigators, special prosecutors, and Congressional investigative panels.</p>
<p>The omissions made for a cleaner storyline &#8212; and promoted a media-centric myth that not even <a title="Woodward bemoans celebrity journalism" href="http://mediamythalert.wordpress.com/2011/04/24/thats-rich-woodward-bemoans-celebrity-journalism/" target="_blank">Woodward</a> embraces.</p>
<p>&#8220;To say that the press brought down Nixon,&#8221; <a title="AJR article with Woodward quote" href="http://www.ajr.org/article.asp?id=3735" target="_blank">Woodward once told <em>American Journalism Review</em></a>, &#8220;that’s horseshit.&#8221;</p>
<p><em><a href="http://mediamythalert.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/wordpress_freshlypressed-logo.png"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-12820" alt="WordPress_FreshlyPressed logo" src="http://mediamythalert.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/wordpress_freshlypressed-logo.png?w=590"   /></a>All the President&#8217;s Men</em> was made in 1976 and remains the most-viewed cinematic treatment of Watergate &#8211;  a &#8220;proxy for reality&#8221; about how America&#8217;s greatest political scandal was rolled up. It&#8217;s <a title="WaPo ‘broke the Watergate scandal’? No way" href="http://mediamythalert.wordpress.com/2011/03/17/wapo-broke-the-watergate-scandal-no-way/" target="_blank">Watergate simplified</a>.</p>
<p>Rodriguez says in his commentary that the makers of <em>Zero Dark Thirty </em>get a lot right: Notably, they &#8220;portray the hunt for bin Laden as a 10-year marathon, rather than a sprint ordered by a new president.&#8221;</p>
<p>His principal concern is the movie&#8217;s depiction of the interrogation of captured al-Qaeda operatives. The interrogation scenes early in the movie &#8220;torture the truth,&#8221; he writes, adding:</p>
<p>&#8220;The film shows CIA officers brutalizing detainees &#8212; beating them mercilessly, suspending them from the ceiling with chains, leading them around in dog collars and, on the spur of the moment, throwing them on the floor, grabbing a large bucket and administering a vicious ad hoc waterboarding. The movie implies that such treatment went on for years.</p>
<p>&#8220;The truth is that no one was bloodied or beaten in the enhanced interrogation program which I supervised from 2002 to 2007. Most detainees received no enhanced interrogation techniques, and the relative few who did faced harsh measures for only a few days or weeks at the start of their detention.&#8221;</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve not seen <em>Zero Dark Thirty</em>. But Rodriguez&#8217;s critique seems well-reasoned. He advises theatergoers to recognize &#8220;that <em>Zero Dark Thirty</em> is more than a movie and less than the literal truth.&#8221;</p>
<p>I&#8217;d shift the obligation somewhat, away from moviegoers: It behooves the makers of fact-based movies to stipulate that &#8220;fact-based&#8221; doesn&#8217;t mean factual, that even high-quality cinematic treatments simplify and distort.</p>
<p>Fact-based movies ought not be <a title="Shafer on Murrow-McCarthy movie" href="http://www.slate.com/articles/news_and_politics/press_box/2005/10/edward_r_movie_2.html" target="_blank">served up in effect as history lessons</a> for the public.</p>
<p>These are <a title="Pocahontas movie myth" href="http://www.nytimes.com/2005/11/27/movies/27chago.html?pagewanted=all&amp;_r=0" target="_blank">hardly new concerns</a>, of course. &#8220;Is it possible,&#8221; Richard Bernstein wrote in 1989 in an <a title="NYT essay: Can movies teach history" href="http://www.nytimes.com/1989/11/26/movies/can-movies-teach-history.html?pagewanted=print&amp;src=pm" target="_blank">essay</a> in the <em>New York Times</em>, &#8220;to have successful cinema and good history at the same time?&#8221;</p>
<p>Perhaps, Bernstein added, &#8220;the rule of thumb is this: When artists, intentionally or not, distort the known facts to get an effect, either political or commercial, they are on the wrong side of the line between poetic truth and historical falsification. Artists who present as fact things that never happened, who refuse to allow the truth to interfere with a good story, are betraying their art and history as well.&#8221;</p>
<p>Ideally, fact-based movies would be so compelling as to stimulate interest and curiosity, to encourage passive theatergoers to find out more about the subject, to conduct some research on their own.</p>
<p>Doing so isn&#8217;t always easy; but it can be an antidote to cinematic mythmaking.</p>
<p><a title="WJC" href="http://www.wjosephcampbell.com" target="_blank"><strong>WJC</strong></a></p>
<p><span style="text-decoration:underline;"><em>More from Media Myth Alert</em></span>:</p>
<ul>
<li><a title="Taking stock: Top mythbusting posts of 2012" href="http://mediamythalert.wordpress.com/2012/12/30/taking-stock-top-mythbusting-posts-of-2012/"><strong>Taking stock: Top mythbusting posts of 2012</strong></a></li>
<li><a title="Mythmaking in the movies" href="http://mediamythalert.wordpress.com/2010/12/08/woah-wapo-mythmaking-in-the-movies/" target="_blank"><strong>Woah, WaPo: Mythmaking in the movies</strong></a></li>
<li><a title="The power of cinema" href="http://mediamythalert.wordpress.com/2012/01/08/follow-the-money-and-the-power-of-cinema/" target="_blank"><strong>&#8216;Follow the money&#8217; and the power of cinema</strong></a></li>
<li><a title="Cinema and the tenacity of media myths" href="http://mediamythalert.wordpress.com/2010/01/17/cinema-and-the-tenacity-of-media-myths/" target="_blank"><strong>Cinema and the tenacity of media myths</strong></a></li>
<li><a title="That's a myth" href="http://mediamythalert.wordpress.com/2010/01/24/the-post-took-down-a-president-what-a-myth/" target="_blank"><strong>The Post &#8216;took down a president&#8217;? That&#8217;s a myth</strong></a></li>
<li><a title="Watergate and its hardy myths" href="http://mediamythalert.wordpress.com/2010/12/16/watergate-and-its-hardy-myths/" target="_blank"><strong>Watergate and its hardy myths</strong></a></li>
<li><a title="Historian dismisses as ‘self-promotion’ the heroic-journalist interpretation of Watergate" href="http://mediamythalert.wordpress.com/2011/10/25/historian-dismisses-as-self-promotion-the-heroic-journalist-interpretation-of-watergate/"><strong>Historian dismisses as ‘self-promotion’ the heroic-journalist interpretation of Watergate</strong></a></li>
<li><strong><a title="Mythmaking in Moscow" href="http://mediamythalert.wordpress.com/2011/03/12/mythmaking-in-moscow-biden-says-wapo-brought-down-nixon/" target="_blank"><strong>Mythmaking in Moscow: Biden says WaPo brought down Nixon</strong></a></strong></li>
<li><strong><a title="Little sustained media reflection two weeks after botched massacre coverage" href="http://mediamythalert.wordpress.com/2012/12/28/little-sustained-media-reflection-two-weeks-after-botched-massacre-coverage/" target="_blank">Little sustained media reflection two weeks after botched massacre coverage</a></strong></li>
<li><a title="‘A debunker’s work is never done’" href="http://mediamythalert.wordpress.com/2010/05/21/a-debunkers-work-is-never-done/" target="_blank"><strong>‘A debunker’s work is never done’</strong></a></li>
<li><a title="‘Getting It Wrong’ goes on Q-and-A" href="http://mediamythalert.wordpress.com/2010/08/04/getting-it-wrong-goes-on-q-and-a/" target="_blank"><strong>‘Getting It Wrong’ goes on Q-and-A</strong></a></li>
</ul>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://mediamythalert.wordpress.com/category/cinematic-treatments/'>Cinematic treatments</a>, <a href='http://mediamythalert.wordpress.com/category/debunking/'>Debunking</a>, <a href='http://mediamythalert.wordpress.com/category/murrow-mccarthy-myth/'>Murrow-McCarthy myth</a>, <a href='http://mediamythalert.wordpress.com/category/washington-post/'>Washington Post</a>, <a href='http://mediamythalert.wordpress.com/category/watergate-myth/'>Watergate myth</a> Tagged: <a href='http://mediamythalert.wordpress.com/tag/all-the-presidents-men/'>All the President's Men</a>, <a href='http://mediamythalert.wordpress.com/tag/cinema/'>Cinema</a>, <a href='http://mediamythalert.wordpress.com/tag/fact-checking/'>Fact-checking</a>, <a href='http://mediamythalert.wordpress.com/tag/getting-it-wrong/'>Getting It Wrong</a>, <a href='http://mediamythalert.wordpress.com/tag/history/'>History</a>, <a href='http://mediamythalert.wordpress.com/tag/media-driven-myths/'>Media-driven myths</a>, <a href='http://mediamythalert.wordpress.com/tag/washington-post/'>Washington Post</a>, <a href='http://mediamythalert.wordpress.com/tag/watergate/'>Watergate</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/12795/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/12795/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=12795&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://mediamythalert.wordpress.com/2013/01/07/proxies-for-reality-fact-based-films-and-their-mythmaking-potential/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/ab01b23c211e0278274d1b19d26c73a7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mediamythalert</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mediamythalert.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/zerodarkthirty_poster.jpg?w=202" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ZeroDarkThirty_poster</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mediamythalert.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/wordpress_freshlypressed-logo.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">WordPress_FreshlyPressed logo</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Along With the Right Amount of Support</title>
		<link>http://bringmetheheadofdaviddixon.com/2013/01/06/along-with-the-right-amount-of-support/</link>
		<comments>http://bringmetheheadofdaviddixon.com/2013/01/06/along-with-the-right-amount-of-support/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2013 20:59:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bringmetheheadofdaviddixon</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[comic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comic strip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[webcomic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bring me the head of david dixon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[webcomics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://bringmetheheadofdaviddixon.com/?p=1027973105</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1027973105&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8467/8354338905_0eca501d0e_b_d.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<p>
<img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8364/8354338975_754f74dbfc_b_d.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<p>
<img src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8054/8354339071_5b46ea228f_b_d.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1027973105/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1027973105/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1027973105&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://bringmetheheadofdaviddixon.com/2013/01/06/along-with-the-right-amount-of-support/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>20</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f9214a8ed913f66c27dbf1e9ddbf4fee?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bringmetheheadofdaviddixon</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8467/8354338905_0eca501d0e_b_d.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8364/8354338975_754f74dbfc_b_d.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8054/8354339071_5b46ea228f_b_d.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Growing Up Seventh-Day Adventist: Being a &#8220;Preacher&#8217;s Kid&#8221;</title>
		<link>http://samsonlinejournal.wordpress.com/2013/01/05/growing-up-sda-being-pk/</link>
		<comments>http://samsonlinejournal.wordpress.com/2013/01/05/growing-up-sda-being-pk/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2013 12:42:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sam McManus</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Religion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Revelations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SDA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[preacher]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[preacher's kid]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[religion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sermon]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://samsonlinejournal.wordpress.com/?p=328</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I was in the unenviable position of having a father who was a traveling minister (he still is). This meant that he was away for long stretches of time, on the road, traveling, going to church after church, in conference after conference, spending so much time away from his family. Don&#8217;t think I didn&#8217;t notice, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=328&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I was in the unenviable position of having a father who was a traveling minister (he still is). <img class="alignleft" alt="" src="http://www.hieropraxis.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/01/praying-hands-in-pew-300x199.jpg" width="290" height="201" />This meant that he was away for long stretches of time, on the road, traveling, going to church after church, in conference after conference, spending so much time away from his family. Don&#8217;t think I didn&#8217;t notice, dad. But that&#8217;s just the way it was, and he is quite an inspirational speaker, don&#8217;t get me wrong. I&#8217;ve seen his process, how he goes about preparing sermons, and it&#8217;s a wonder to behold. I&#8217;ve also seen those same sermons delivered, in churches, in tents, in prisons, and in fields and pavilions throughout this country, and it&#8217;s also something special. But being him, and being his son are two completely different things, something too many people failed to remember.</p>
<p>When I would travel with my dad, which happened more and more as I got a bit older, I would always be introduced to everyone and their mothers as the next big preacher. I would shake their hands, they would pat me on the head (which I detested), and they would proclaim me the second coming of Jehosophat. I would nod along, laugh when instructed, and proceed to sit in my place of honor at the front of the church so I could listen to another one of my dad&#8217;s sermons while everyone around me looked at me to see my reactions. It was so strange, such a surreal time anytime I went with him. And I wore my special suit for the occasion. It was bright white, the better to call attention to myself, but also easier for people to recognize me. When we would go &#8220;on tour&#8221; I think they honestly passed on this knowledge from church to church. It was almost like we were celebrities, and while I liked it, I did not like the expectations that came with it.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s where the disconnect really began. At first I found it interesting and was even honored by the attention, but once they all started saying I was going to be a great preacher too I started to honestly think about it. And I realized I didn&#8217;t want to be a preacher. I didn&#8217;t want to stand in that pulpit and speak the words of God from on high. I wasn&#8217;t that guy, but how can one person stand against legions who are certain of that fact? I couldn&#8217;t, or at least I felt like I couldn&#8217;t. So I let myself get swept along with the tide, I let them believe I was the second coming, and I got tangled up in youth church, in theology courses, until I finally said &#8220;enough!&#8221; It took me long enough, and while I realized that being a preacher was a noble profession, it was also a calling, and I wasn&#8217;t called that way, even though so many people believed it to be the case. When I finally shut it down, I know I disappointed so many people, but I realized by then I am not my father, nor do I want to be, so it was okay.</p>
<p>And amazingly enough, the church still has some solid young preachers who really know how to sermonize. I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;m missed.</p>
<p><em><strong>Sam</strong></em></p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://samsonlinejournal.wordpress.com/category/religion-2/'>Religion</a>, <a href='http://samsonlinejournal.wordpress.com/category/revelations/'>Revelations</a>, <a href='http://samsonlinejournal.wordpress.com/category/sda/'>SDA</a> Tagged: <a href='http://samsonlinejournal.wordpress.com/tag/preacher/'>preacher</a>, <a href='http://samsonlinejournal.wordpress.com/tag/preachers-kid/'>preacher's kid</a>, <a href='http://samsonlinejournal.wordpress.com/tag/religion/'>religion</a>, <a href='http://samsonlinejournal.wordpress.com/tag/sda/'>SDA</a>, <a href='http://samsonlinejournal.wordpress.com/tag/sermon/'>sermon</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/328/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/328/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/328/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/328/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/328/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/328/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/328/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/328/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/328/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/328/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/328/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/328/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/328/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/328/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=328&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://samsonlinejournal.wordpress.com/2013/01/05/growing-up-sda-being-pk/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>28</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/6c3705df252f8251a0f9a3afe714e97a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mr. M</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://www.hieropraxis.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/01/praying-hands-in-pew-300x199.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Agency is Agency, No Matter What It Wears</title>
		<link>http://smokeandstir.org/2013/01/06/agency-is-agency-no-matter-what-it-wears/</link>
		<comments>http://smokeandstir.org/2013/01/06/agency-is-agency-no-matter-what-it-wears/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2013 01:07:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>taylormarvin</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[E.J. Graff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Islam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rape]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rape Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reza Aslan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Veil]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://smokeandstir.org/?p=4589</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[By Taylor Marvin At The American Prospect E.J, Graff has a thought-provoking piece on rape culture in the US and abroad. If Americans are tempted to view the horrific torture, rape, and murder of a New Delhi woman as evidence that rape culture is endemic only to foreign societies, they&#8217;re wrong; in Graff&#8217;s words, rape culture &#8220;lives anywhere that has [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4589&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>By Taylor Marvin</em></p>
<p>At <em>The American Prospect </em><a href="https://prospect.org/article/purity-culture-rape-culture#.UOdLnJ5T9F4.twitter">E.J, Graff has a thought-provoking piece</a> on rape culture in the US and abroad. If Americans are tempted to view the horrific torture, rape, and murder of a New Delhi woman as evidence that rape culture is endemic only to foreign societies, they&#8217;re wrong; in Graff&#8217;s words, rape culture &#8220;lives anywhere that has a &#8216;traditional&#8217; vision of women’s sexuality.&#8221; This, of course, includes the US, where slut-shaming is epidemic, politicians restrict their sympathy for survivors of &#8220;legitimate&#8221; rape, and all too many people continue to blame rape survivors for being the victim of crimes.</p>
<p>Graff makes her argument in graphic detail, and her piece is well worth reading. However, one troubling line jumps out:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;A culture in which women must cover up or be threatened is a rape culture. You&#8217;re thinking of hijab and burquas, right? Think also of the now well-known SlutWalks, which were launched after a Toronto police officer told young women that they could avoid rape by not dressing like &#8216;sluts.&#8217;&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Graff&#8217;s point is that the coerced covering of female bodies in the West is just as indicative of rape culture as in the Muslim world. The reference to hijabs and burquas is evoked to emphasize this point: if Canadian police telling women not to dress like &#8220;sluts&#8221; is comparable to Muslim head and body coverings it <em>must</em> be oppressive, because the veil is a perfect synonym for patriarchy. Here the Muslim world is the alien other, identified only by definitional oppression. There&#8217;s the threat &#8212; if we, the West, don&#8217;t change our ways we&#8217;ll be <em>like them.</em></p>
<p>This is a troublingly Orientalist view of the female experience in the Muslim world. This isn&#8217;t to say that Muslim societies are not crippled by widespread misogyny and sexual violence; they clearly are, and the costs of patriarchy are arguably higher in these societies than anywhere else. This also doesn&#8217;t suggest that hijabs and other female religious garments are not a product of patriarchy. In an alternative reality where Islam &#8212; and of course Christianity &#8212; arose in egalitarian, rather than patriarchal, societies, it&#8217;s difficult to believe that these religious traditions would stress concealing clothing for women and not men. But assuming that the veil always represents a denial of female freedom is a condescending and simplistic dismissal of a complex tradition, and denies agency to the millions of Muslim women who chose to wear the garment.</p>
<div id="attachment_4596" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 410px"><a href="http://smokeandstir.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/veil_cartoon.png"><img class=" wp-image-4596 " alt="Artist unknown; please contact me if you know." src="http://smokeandstir.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/veil_cartoon.png?w=400&#038;h=477" width="400" height="477" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Artist unknown; please contact me if you know.</p></div>
<p>Are many women forced to wear clothing they otherwise would not, on the justification of religious tradition? Of course. But assuming that <em>all </em>women wear the hijab because they are forced to compresses millions of Muslim women&#8217;s varied experiences into a single condemnation of their culture. In this view, Western women&#8217;s choices are valid, while Muslim women&#8217;s are not. It is difficult to imagine a more condescending narrative, because this story of oppressed, subservient Muslim women denies them the agency to <em>choose. </em>Reza Aslan ably explains this distinction in his history of Islam, <em><a href="http://www.amazon.com/god-but-God-Updated-Edition/dp/0812982444/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1357515355&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=no+god+but+god">No god but God</a>:</em></p>
<blockquote><p>&#8216;The fact is that the traditional colonial image of the veiled Muslim woman as the sheltered, docile sexual property of her husband is just as misleading and simpleminded as the postmodernist image of the veil as the emblem of female freedom and empowerment from Western cultural hegemony. The veil may be neither or both of these things, but that is up to Muslim women to decide for themselves. [p. 73]&#8220;</p></blockquote>
<p>To Westerners, the narrative of the veil as a tool of oppression is both satisfying and comforting: satisfying because it reaffirms the West&#8217;s cultural superiority, and comforting because it simplifies a bewildering variety of religious and cultural traditions into a simple narrative of backwardness. Again, this does not mean that patriarchy is absent from the practice &#8212; as Aslan notes, reading the veil as empowering freedom from the male gaze is just as simplistic as understanding it solely as patriarchal barbarism. But lumping <em>all </em>women who wear the veil into the category of pitied victims reflects an inherent narrative of cultural superiority. It is up to individual Muslim women, not non-Muslim observers, to decide whether the practice is oppressive. The veil is not incompatible with feminism; only the lack of female agency is.</p>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4589&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://smokeandstir.org/2013/01/06/agency-is-agency-no-matter-what-it-wears/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/8fcceb0a083e1ddfb3730e514a7cb173?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">taylormarvin</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://smokeandstir.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/veil_cartoon.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Artist unknown; please contact me if you know.</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Little Black Books Instead of Phones and Computers</title>
		<link>http://jseliger.wordpress.com/2013/01/04/why-little-black-books-instead-of-phones-and-computers/</link>
		<comments>http://jseliger.wordpress.com/2013/01/04/why-little-black-books-instead-of-phones-and-computers/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2013 02:59:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jake Seliger</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Essays]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Moleskine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[notebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pretension]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rhodia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rhodia webbie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technologies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[webbie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[webnotebook]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://jseliger.wordpress.com/?p=3100</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;Despite being a denizen of the digital world, or maybe because he knew too well its isolating potential, Jobs was a strong believer in face-to-face meetings.&#8221; That&#8217;s from Walter Isaacson&#8217;s biography of Steve Jobs. It&#8217;s a strange way to begin a post about notebooks, but Jobs&#8217; views on the power of a potentially anachronistic practice [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3100&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;Despite being a denizen of the digital world, or maybe because he knew too well its isolating potential, Jobs was a strong believer in face-to-face meetings.&#8221; That&#8217;s from <a href="https://jseliger.wordpress.com/2011/10/24/the-steve-jobs-biography/">Walter Isaacson&#8217;s biography of Steve Jobs</a>. It&#8217;s a strange way to begin a post about notebooks, but Jobs&#8217; views on the power of a potentially anachronistic practice applies to other seemingly anachronistic practices. I&#8217;m a believer in notebooks, though I&#8217;m hardly a luddite and use a computer too much.</p>
<p>The notebook has an immediate tactile advantage over phones: they <em>aren&#8217;t</em> connected to the Internet. It&#8217;s intimate in a way computers aren&#8217;t. A notebook has never interrupted me with a screen that says, &#8220;Wuz up?&#8221; Notebooks are easy to use without thinking. I know where I have everything I&#8217;ve written on-the-go over the last eight years: in the same stack. It&#8217;s easy to draw on paper. I don&#8217;t have to manage files and have yet to delete something important. The only way to &#8220;accidentally delete&#8221; something is to leave the notebook submerged in water.<a href="http://jseliger.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/notebook-stack.jpg"><img class="alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-2546" alt="Notebook stack" src="http://jseliger.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/notebook-stack.jpg?w=123&#038;h=150" width="123" height="150" /></a></p>
<p>A notebook is the written equivalent of a face-to-face meeting. It has no distractions, no pop-up icons, and no software upgrades. For a notebook, fewer features are better and fewer options are more. If you take a notebook out of your pocket to record an idea, you won&#8217;t see nude photos of your significant other. You&#8217;re going to see the page where you left off. Maybe you&#8217;ll see another idea that reminds you of the one you&#8217;re working on, and you&#8217;ll combine the two in a novel way. If you want to flip back to an earlier page, it&#8217;s easy.</p>
<p>The lack of editability is a feature, not a bug, and the notebook is an enigma of stopped time. Similar writing in a computer <em>can</em> function this way but doesn&#8217;t for me: the text is too open and too malleable. Which is wonderful in its own way, and that way opens many new possibilities. But those possibilities are different from the notebook&#8217;s. It&#8217;s become a cliche to argue that the technologies we use affect the thoughts we have and the way we express those thoughts, but despite being cliche the basic power of that observation remains. I have complete confidence that, unless I misplace them, I&#8217;ll still be able to read my notebooks in 20 years, regardless of changes in technology.</p>
<p>In <em>Distrust That Particular Flavor</em>, William Gibson says, &#8220;Once perfected, communication technologies rarely die out entirely; rather, they shrink to fit particular niches in the global info-structure.&#8221; The notebook&#8217;s niche is perfect. I don&#8217;t think it&#8217;s a coincidence that Moleskine racks have proliferated in stores at the same time everyone has acquired cell phones, laptops, and now tablets.</p>
<p>In <em>The Shallows</em>, Nicholas Carr says: &#8220;The intellectual ethic is the message that a medium or other tool transmits into the minds and culture of its users.&#8221; Cell phones subtly change our relationship with time. Notebooks subtly change our relationship with words and drawings. I&#8217;m not entirely sure how, and if I were struggling for tenure in industrial design or psychology I might start examining the relationship. For now, it&#8217;s enough to feel the relationship. <a href="http://www.slate.com/articles/technology/technology/2012/01/ipad_stylus_steve_jobs_hated_it_but_apple_s_touchscreen_gadgets_could_use_a_pseudo_pen_.single.html">Farhad Manjoo</a> even cites someone who studies these things:</p>
<blockquote><p>“The research shows that the type of content you produce is different whether you handwrite or type,” says Ken Hinckley, an interface expert at Microsoft Research who’s long studied pen-based electronic devices. “Typing tends to be for complete sentences and thoughts—you go deeper into each line of thought. Handwriting is for short phrases, for jotting ideas. It’s a different mode of thought for most people.” This makes intuitive sense: It’s why people like to brainstorm using whiteboards rather than Word documents.</p></blockquote>
<p><a href="http://jseliger.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_2100.jpg"><img class="alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-3102" alt="IMG_2100" src="http://jseliger.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_2100.jpg?w=150&#038;h=71" width="150" height="71" /></a>I like to write in notebooks despite carrying around a smartphone. Some of this might be indicative of the technology I grew up with—would someone familiar with smartphone touchscreens from age seven have sufficiently dexterous fingers to be faster than they would be with paper?—but I think the obvious answer to &#8220;handwriting or computer?&#8221; is &#8220;both, depending.&#8221; As I write this sentence, I have a printout of a novel called ASKING ANNA in front of me, covered with blue pen, because editing on the printed page feels different to me than editing on the screen. I write long-form on computers, though. The plural of anecdote is not data. Still, I have to notice that using different mediums appears to improve the final work product (insert joke about low quality here).</p>
<p>There&#8217;s also a shallow and yet compelling reason to like notebooks: a disproportionate number of writers, artists, scientists, and thinkers like using them too, and I suspect that even contemporary writers, artists, scientists, and thinkers realize that sometimes silence and <em>not</em> being connected is useful, <a href="http://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=4802581">like quiet</a> and <a href="http://theamericanscholar.org/solitude-and-leadership/">solitude</a>.</p>
<p><strong>In &#8220;<a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2010/11/a-new-wrinkle-in-time/8249/">With the decline of the wristwatch</a></strong>, will time become just another app?&#8221;, Matthew Battles says:</p>
<blockquote><p>Westerners have long been keenly interested in horology, as David Landes, an economic historian, points out in <em>Revolution in Time</em>, his landmark study of the development of timekeeping technology. It wasn’t the advent of clocks that forced us to fret over the hours; our obsession with time was fully in force when monks first began to say their matins, keeping track of the hours out of strict religious obligation. By the 18th century, secular time had acquired the pressure of routine that would rule its modern mode. Tristram Shandy’s father, waiting interminably for the birth of his son, bemoans the “computations of time” that segment life into “minutes, hours, weeks, and months” and despairs “of clocks (I wish there were not a clock in the kingdom).” Shandy’s father fretted that, by their constant tolling of the hours, clocks would overshadow the personal, innate sense of time—ever flexible, ever dependent upon mood and sociability.</p></blockquote>
<p>The revolution in electronic technology is wonderful in many ways, but its downsides—distraction, most obviously—are present too. The notebook combats them. Notebooks are an organizing or disorganizing principle: organizing because one keeps one&#8217;s thoughts, but disorganizing because one cannot rearrange, tag, and structure thoughts in a notebook as one can on a screen (Devonthink Pro is impossible in the real world, and Scrivener can be done but only with a great deal of friction).</p>
<p>Once you try a notebook, you may realize that you&#8217;re a notebook person. You might realize it without trying. If you&#8217;re obsessed with this sort of thing, see Michael Loper / Rands&#8217; <a href="http://www.randsinrepose.com/archives/2008/06/01/sweet_decay.html">Sweet Decay</a>, which is better on validating why a notebook is important than evaluating the notebooks at hand. It was also written in 2008, before Rhodia updated its Webbie.</p>
<p>Like Rands, I&#8217;ve never had a sewn binding catastrophically fail. As a result, notebooks without sewn bindings are invisible to me. I find it telling that so many people are willing to write at length about their notebooks and use a nominally obsolete technology.</p>
<p>Once you decide that you like notebooks, you have to decide which one you want. I used to like Moleskines, <a href="http://jseliger.wordpress.com/2011/05/11/eight-years-of-writing-and-the-first-busted-moleskine/">until one broke</a>, and I began reading other stories online about the highly variable quality level.</p>
<p>So I&#8217;ve begun ranging further afield.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve tested about a dozen notebooks. Most haven&#8217;t been worth writing about. But by now I&#8217;ve found the best reasonably available notebooks, and I can say this: you probably don&#8217;t actually want a <a href="http://jseliger.wordpress.com/2012/01/17/product-review-guildhall-pocket-notebook/">Guildhall Pocket Notebook</a>, which is number two. You want a Rhodia Webnotebook.</p>
<p>Like many notebooks, the Guildhall starts off with promise: the pages do lie flat more easily than alternatives. Lines are closely spaced, maximizing writable area, which is important in an expensive notebook that shouldn&#8217;t be replaced frequently.</p>
<p><a href="http://jseliger.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_3900.jpg"><img class="alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-3101" alt="IMG_3900" src="http://jseliger.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_3900.jpg?w=124&#038;h=150" width="124" height="150" /></a>I like the Guildhall, but it&#8217;s too flimsy and has a binding that appears unlikely to withstand daily carry. Mine is already bending, and I haven&#8217;t even hauled it around that much. The Rhodia is somewhat stiffer. Its pages don&#8217;t lie flat quite as easily. The lines should go to the end of each page. But its great paper quality and durability advantage make it better than the alternatives.</p>
<p>The Rhodia is not perfect. <a href="http://www.thepaperie.co.uk/rhodia-a7-black-webnotebook-ruled.html">The A7 version</a>, which I like better than the 3.5 x 5.5 American version, is only available in Europe and Australia, which entails high shipping costs. The Webbie&#8217;s lines should stretch to the bottom of the page and be spaced slightly closer together. The name is stupid; perhaps it sounds better in French. The notebook&#8217;s cover extends slightly over its paper instead of aligning perfectly. Steve Jobs would demand perfect alignment. To return to Isaacson&#8217;s biography:</p>
<blockquote><p>The connection between the design of a product, its essence, and its manufacturing was illustrated for Jobs and Ive when they were traveling in France and went into a kitchen supply store. Ive picked up a knife he admired, but then put it down in disappointment. Jobs did the same. &#8216;We both noticed the tiny bit of glue between the handle and the blade,&#8217; Ive recalled. They talked about how the knife&#8217;s good design had been ruined by the way it was being manufactured. &#8216;We don&#8217;t like to think of our knives as being glued together,&#8217; Ive said. &#8216;Steve and I care about things like that, which ruin the purity and detract from the essence of something like a utensil, and we think alike about how products should be made to look pure and seamless.</p></blockquote>
<p>I wish the Rhodia were that good. But the Rhodia&#8217;s virtues are more important than its flaws: the paper quality is the highest I&#8217;ve seen, and none of the Rhodias I&#8217;ve bought have broken. If anyone knows of a notebook that combines the Rhodia&#8217;s durability with the qualities it lacks, by all means send me an e-mail.</p>
<hr />
<p>More on the subject: <a href="http://artofmanliness.com/2010/09/13/the-pocket-notebooks-of-20-famous-men/">The Pocket Notebooks of 20 Famous Men</a>.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3100/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3100/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3100&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://jseliger.wordpress.com/2013/01/04/why-little-black-books-instead-of-phones-and-computers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>40</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/146ec8e007295ff273a9e28ddeb2a963?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F1.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Jake Seliger</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jseliger.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/notebook-stack.jpg?w=123" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Notebook stack</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jseliger.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_2100.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_2100</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jseliger.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/img_3900.jpg?w=124" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_3900</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Future According to Google’s Larry Page</title>
		<link>http://tech.fortune.cnn.com/2013/01/03/google-larry-page/</link>
		<comments>http://tech.fortune.cnn.com/2013/01/03/google-larry-page/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2013 10:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Miguel Helft, senior writer</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[The Future Issue]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Android]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eric Schmidt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Maps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Mobile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google Search]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Larry Page]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Motorola Mobility]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sergey Brin]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tech.fortune.cnn.com/?p=104199</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Google CEO Larry Page envisions a future in which computers plan your vacations, drive your cars, and anticipate your whims. Audacious? Maybe. But Page’s dreams have a way of coming true. Note: On Jan 3, as Fortune published this article, the Federal Trade Commission ended its investigation of Google&#8217;s search practices saying it found no [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=104199&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://tech.fortune.cnn.com/2013/01/03/google-larry-page/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f54f6b36d20a6e2e0c869f52f928ab5b?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mhelft</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://fortunebrainstormtech.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/larry_page.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">larry_page</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://fortunebrainstormtech.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/google_charts.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">google_charts</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Top 40 Albums of 2012</title>
		<link>http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.wordpress.com/2013/01/04/top-40-albums-of-2012-20-1/</link>
		<comments>http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.wordpress.com/2013/01/04/top-40-albums-of-2012-20-1/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2013 23:34:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>android50</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Top Albums Lists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2012]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[a sleep & a forgetting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[action bronson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ariel pink's haunted graffit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ascent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beach house]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bend beyond]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best albums of 2012]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[best of 2012]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[black breath]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bloom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blue chips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bob dylan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[celebration rock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[channel orange]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[favorite albums]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fiona apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[frank ocean]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[harmonicraft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[heaven]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[islands]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Japandroids]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[killer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[killer mike]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lonerism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lotus plaza]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mature themes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pallbearer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[r.a.p. music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sentenced to life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[six organs of admittance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[slaughterhouse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sorrow and extinction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[southern lord]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spiritualized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spooky action at a distance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[swans the seer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sweet heart sweet light]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tame impala]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the idler wheel...]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the ilder wheel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the seer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the walkmen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[top albums of 2012]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[torche]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ty Segall]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Woods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zammuto]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.wordpress.com/?p=2756</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A few days ago I posted the first 20 in my Top 40 Albums of 2012 (check it out here).  The first half of the list is always easier to compile than the final 20.  With this, the top half of the list, I find myself swapping albums from one spot to the next, trying [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2756&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.wordpress.com/2013/01/04/top-40-albums-of-2012-20-1/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>28</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/08-visions-from-io.mp3" length="5880042" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/08-visions-from-io.mp3" length="5880042" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/05-tell-me-whats-inside-your-heart.mp3" length="8980318" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/05-tell-me-whats-inside-your-heart.mp3" length="8980318" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/08-ron-simmons.mp3" length="6582411" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/05-tell-me-whats-inside-your-heart.mp3" length="8980318" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/08-ron-simmons.mp3" length="6582411" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/08-ron-simmons.mp3" length="6582411" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/01-kinski-assassin.mp3" length="8206039" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/01-kinski-assassin.mp3" length="8206039" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/01-in-a-dream-it-seemed-real.mp3" length="3223730" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/01-fiona-apple-every-single-night.mp3" length="8530083" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/01-in-a-dream-it-seemed-real.mp3" length="3223730" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/01-fiona-apple-every-single-night.mp3" length="8530083" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/01-fiona-apple-every-single-night.mp3" length="8530083" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/02-kicking.mp3" length="6209043" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/01-fiona-apple-every-single-night.mp3" length="8530083" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/03-is-it-honest.mp3" length="6409344" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/03-is-it-honest.mp3" length="6409344" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/01-yay.mp3" length="5270320" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/05-endless-corpse1.mp3" length="6724218" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/05-endless-corpse1.mp3" length="6724218" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/05-endless-corpse1.mp3" length="6724218" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/11-heaven.mp3" length="8397322" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/11-heaven.mp3" length="8397322" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/killer-mike-06-reagan.mp3" length="6148882" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/killer-mike-06-reagan.mp3" length="6148882" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/05-tell-me-whats-inside-your-heart.mp3" length="8980318" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/03-apocalypse-dreams-1.mp3" length="11887636" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/killer-mike-06-reagan.mp3" length="6148882" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/killer-mike-06-reagan.mp3" length="6148882" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/05-white-galactic-one1.mp3" length="9844258" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/05-white-galactic-one1.mp3" length="9844258" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/05-white-galactic-one1.mp3" length="9844258" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/03-lazuli.mp3" length="12251249" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/03-lazuli.mp3" length="12251249" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/02-devoid-of-redemption.mp3" length="20338458" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/02-devoid-of-redemption.mp3" length="20338458" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/03-lazuli.mp3" length="12251249" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/05-too-late.mp3" length="9054632" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/05-too-late.mp3" length="9054632" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/03-lazuli.mp3" length="12251249" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/05-white-galactic-one1.mp3" length="9844258" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/14-bad-religion.mp3" length="7043255" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/14-bad-religion.mp3" length="7043255" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/07-the-house-that-heaven-built.mp3" length="5786277" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/1-01-lunacy.mp3" length="14976877" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/1-01-lunacy.mp3" length="14976877" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/07-the-house-that-heaven-built.mp3" length="5786277" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/03-apocalypse-dreams-1.mp3" length="11887636" type="audio/mpeg" />
<enclosure url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/03-apocalypse-dreams-1.mp3" length="11887636" type="audio/mpeg" />
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/d6531bd93bd03aa84c53d0283f5e5f05?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">android50</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cdn4.pitchfork.com/albums/18369/homepage_large.3794146f.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://cdn3.pitchfork.com/albums/17905/homepage_large.51efdc41.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://cdn.pitchfork.com/albums/17588/homepage_large.0d8b3163.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://cdn2.pitchfork.com/albums/18112/homepage_large.e6f1f25a.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://cdn3.pitchfork.com/albums/17446/homepage_large.2d60bb4c.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://cdn3.pitchfork.com/albums/17892/homepage_large.762bfaa8.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://cdn3.pitchfork.com/albums/17697/homepage_large.56460df4.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://cdn3.pitchfork.com/albums/18221/homepage_large.3639c2e7.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://cdn.pitchfork.com/albums/17597/homepage_large.8724f499.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://cdn4.pitchfork.com/albums/17710/homepage_large.cf0da1c0.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://cdn2.pitchfork.com/albums/17803/homepage_large.c5b2f354.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://cdn2.pitchfork.com/albums/17701/homepage_large.a269b51a.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://cdn.pitchfork.com/albums/18319/homepage_large.140bf2a7.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://cdn.pitchfork.com/albums/17596/homepage_large.28cc3f68.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://cdn.pitchfork.com/albums/17774/homepage_large.f251d544.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://cdn2.pitchfork.com/albums/17508/homepage_large.d64212bb.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://cdn3.pitchfork.com/albums/17663/homepage_large.0838d06a.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://cdn2.pitchfork.com/albums/18028/homepage_large.45e3c196.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://cdn2.pitchfork.com/albums/17735/homepage_large.6cc98599.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://cdn3.pitchfork.com/albums/18141/homepage_large.07924400.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/08-visions-from-io.mp3" medium="audio">
			<media:player url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.wordpress.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf?soundFile=http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/08-visions-from-io.mp3" />
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/05-tell-me-whats-inside-your-heart.mp3" medium="audio">
			<media:player url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.wordpress.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf?soundFile=http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/07/05-tell-me-whats-inside-your-heart.mp3" />
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/08-ron-simmons.mp3" medium="audio">
			<media:player url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.wordpress.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf?soundFile=http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/08-ron-simmons.mp3" />
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/01-kinski-assassin.mp3" medium="audio">
			<media:player url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.wordpress.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf?soundFile=http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/01-kinski-assassin.mp3" />
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/01-in-a-dream-it-seemed-real.mp3" medium="audio">
			<media:player url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.wordpress.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf?soundFile=http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/01-in-a-dream-it-seemed-real.mp3" />
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/01-fiona-apple-every-single-night.mp3" medium="audio">
			<media:player url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.wordpress.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf?soundFile=http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/01-fiona-apple-every-single-night.mp3" />
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/02-kicking.mp3" medium="audio">
			<media:player url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.wordpress.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf?soundFile=http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/02-kicking.mp3" />
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/03-is-it-honest.mp3" medium="audio">
			<media:player url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.wordpress.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf?soundFile=http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/03-is-it-honest.mp3" />
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/01-yay.mp3" medium="audio">
			<media:player url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.wordpress.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf?soundFile=http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/01-yay.mp3" />
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/05-endless-corpse1.mp3" medium="audio">
			<media:player url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.wordpress.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf?soundFile=http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/05-endless-corpse1.mp3" />
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/11-heaven.mp3" medium="audio">
			<media:player url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.wordpress.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf?soundFile=http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/11-heaven.mp3" />
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/killer-mike-06-reagan.mp3" medium="audio">
			<media:player url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.wordpress.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf?soundFile=http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/killer-mike-06-reagan.mp3" />
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/03-apocalypse-dreams-1.mp3" medium="audio">
			<media:player url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.wordpress.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf?soundFile=http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/03-apocalypse-dreams-1.mp3" />
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/05-white-galactic-one1.mp3" medium="audio">
			<media:player url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.wordpress.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf?soundFile=http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/05-white-galactic-one1.mp3" />
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/03-lazuli.mp3" medium="audio">
			<media:player url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.wordpress.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf?soundFile=http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/03-lazuli.mp3" />
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/02-devoid-of-redemption.mp3" medium="audio">
			<media:player url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.wordpress.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf?soundFile=http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/02-devoid-of-redemption.mp3" />
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/05-too-late.mp3" medium="audio">
			<media:player url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.wordpress.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf?soundFile=http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/06/05-too-late.mp3" />
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/14-bad-religion.mp3" medium="audio">
			<media:player url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.wordpress.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf?soundFile=http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/14-bad-religion.mp3" />
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/07-the-house-that-heaven-built.mp3" medium="audio">
			<media:player url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.wordpress.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf?soundFile=http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/07-the-house-that-heaven-built.mp3" />
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/1-01-lunacy.mp3" medium="audio">
			<media:player url="http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.wordpress.com/wp-content/plugins/audio-player/player.swf?soundFile=http://bobdylanwrotepropagandasongs.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/1-01-lunacy.mp3" />
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bullying and Building a Better Web</title>
		<link>http://stearns.wordpress.com/2013/01/06/bullying-and-building-a-better-web/</link>
		<comments>http://stearns.wordpress.com/2013/01/06/bullying-and-building-a-better-web/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2013 05:19:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Josh Stearns</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Amanda Palmer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bullying]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[civic engagement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hate speech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Internet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jeff Jarvis]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://stearns.wordpress.com/?p=1265</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As a parent, I think a lot about the world we are creating for our children. As an advocate for press freedom and digital rights I think a lot about the web we are creating for our children too. A lot of my work centers around creating more democratic structures and policies that shape our [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1265&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As a parent, I think a lot about the world we are creating for our children. As an advocate for press freedom and digital rights I think a lot about the web we are creating for our children too.</p>
<p>A lot of my <a href="http://www.freepress.net">work</a> centers around creating more democratic structures and policies that shape our media, and pushing back on the companies that want to assert more and more control over the Internet. But I also think a lot about how the Internet changes the ways we communicate with each other, and thus the ways we relate to each other. When I get sucked into a Twitter fight, see a particularly ugly comment thread, or hear about bullying and <a href="http://www.dailydot.com/culture/anita-sarkeesian-ted-talk-misogynist-comments/">harassment online</a>, I wonder what kind of web my kids will inherit from us.</p>
<p>That’s why I was so struck when I read Jeff Jarvis’ blog post “<a href="http://buzzmachine.com/2013/01/05/we-get-the-net-and-society-we-build/">We get the net—and society—we build</a>.” Jarvis’ post (a response to <a href="http://www.amandapalmer.net/blog/2013010/">this post</a> from Amanda Palmer on &#8220;Internet hate&#8221; – also a must read) puts into words a few things I have been feeling in my gut for sometime. He writes:</p>
<blockquote><p>“We are building the norms of our new net society. It can go either way; there’s nothing, absolutely nothing to say that technology will lead to a better or worse world. It only provides us choices and the opportunity to show our own nature in what we choose. Will you support the fights, the attacks, the hate? Or will you stand up for the victims and against the bullies and trolls and their cheering mobs who gleefully tweet, ‘Fight! Fight!’?”</p></blockquote>
<p>Jarvis’s post is a profound reminder that each of us is making the web as we go along. Our tweets, our Facebook posts, our Instagram photos, our Reddit comments are both literally and figuratively the links that hold the web together. Online our actions don’t speak louder than words, our words are our actions, and we should make them count.<span id="more-1265"></span></p>
<p>In her blog post Amanda Palmer talks about <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;v=vOHXGNx-E7E">Amanda Todd</a>, a 15-year-old who committed suicide after being bullied on and off line. I live just up the road from South Hadley, a town that was put on the map in 2010 when a 15-year-old student there, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Suicide_of_Phoebe_Prince">Phoebe Prince</a>, committed suicide after being bullied relentlessly.  These stories resonate for me in part because when I was in high school a friend of mine committed suicide when he was about 15.</p>
<p>Today, we access the web via our phones, our laptops, our TVs. We connect to the Internet via WiFi routers and Ethernet cables and phone lines. Given all of that, it is easy to forget that at its most basic, the web is us.</p>
<p>In 2011 Jim Gilliam gave a <a href="http://www.internetismyreligion.com/">speech</a> at the Personal Democracy Forum that spoke to this point. He said, “We are all connected, we are all in debt to each other, we all owe every moment of our lives to countless people we will never meet. The internet gives us the opportunity to pay back a small part of that debt.” How we treat those people that we may never meet, those people on the other side of all those connections, will necessarily shape those connections for years to come.</p>
<p>Gilliam’s talk was so full of hope that when he said at the end, “We have faith that people connected can create a new world,” it was easy to ignore the double-edged nature of that promise.  There is, of course, the threat that without some compassion, accountability and care, we might not like the world we create.</p>
<p>A few months before my first son was born I asked my father how to raise a good, caring and compassionate son in a world so full of mixed messages for men and boys alike. There is a lot we can’t control, he said, but what we can do is try to be the kind of men we want our sons to aspire to. Our example is the best compass we can provide to our sons and our daughters.</p>
<p>Creating a new world, or in Jarvis’ words “building the norms of our new net society,” isn’t that much different. “This is our problem. Your problem. My problem,” Jarvis writes. “When argument over an idea turns to attack against a person, then it crosses the line. When disliking a person becomes public ridicule of that person, it is hate. Dealing with that isn’t the responsibility of government. It is our responsibility.”</p>
<p>As a parent, it is not enough to wring my hands about bullying or hate online. It’s not enough to wonder how to protect my kids. As a parent, it is incumbent on me to engage in the hard work of building a better web by being a better citizen of the web.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1265/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1265/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1265&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://stearns.wordpress.com/2013/01/06/bullying-and-building-a-better-web/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>44</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/52c3347c7ef28682fd7345976a66e569?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F2.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Josh</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
