<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 May 2012 18:57:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>PandoMonthly NYC with Matt Mullenweg Is Next Week. Tickets on Sale Now!</title>
		<link>http://pandodaily.com/2012/05/17/pandomonthly-nyc-with-matt-mullenweg-is-next-week-tickets-on-sale-now/</link>
		<comments>http://pandodaily.com/2012/05/17/pandomonthly-nyc-with-matt-mullenweg-is-next-week-tickets-on-sale-now/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2012 16:46:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Sarah Lacy</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[People]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tech]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://pandodaily.com/?p=18783</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-18799" title="matt-mullenweg-2" src="http://pandodaily.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/matt-mullenweg-2.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="199" />We <a href="http://pandodaily.com/2012/04/24/pandomonthly-with-dustin-moskovitz-is-next-week-plus-our-line-up-and-a-new-city/">announced</a> a few weeks ago that we decided to bring our amazing event series <a href="http://pandodaily.com/events/">PandoMonthly</a> to New York. And I'm thrilled to announce that our first guest is a man whose company we rely on pretty heavily here at PandoDaily: Matt Mullenweg.

Tickets are on sale <a href="http://pandomonthlymattmullenweg.eventbrite.com/">here</a> now!<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=18783&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-18799" title="matt-mullenweg-2" src="http://pandodaily.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/matt-mullenweg-2.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="199" />We <a href="http://pandodaily.com/2012/04/24/pandomonthly-with-dustin-moskovitz-is-next-week-plus-our-line-up-and-a-new-city/">announced</a> a few weeks ago that we decided to bring our amazing event series <a href="http://pandodaily.com/events/">PandoMonthly</a> to New York. And I&#8217;m thrilled to announce that our first guest is a man whose company we rely on pretty heavily here at PandoDaily: Matt Mullenweg.</p>
<p>Tickets are on sale <a href="http://pandomonthlymattmullenweg.eventbrite.com/">here</a> now!</p>
<p>Mullenweg started WordPress as a project in 2004, and its road has been anything but conventional. It has a bizarre structure, as Mullenweg is one of those rare guys whose sole focus isn&#8217;t building a $1 billion company. He&#8217;s turned down acquisition offers that could have made him rich, and has historically had a Craigslist-like resistance to maximizing revenues. That&#8217;s starting to change revenue is doubling annually, and WordPress has bulked up on &#8220;grown ups&#8221; including a new CFO and chief counsel.</p>
<p>Will a new more businessy WordPress retain its street cred? The company&#8217;s hippy past created sort of a cult around WordPress throughout the world. There is on average one WordCamp somewhere in the world every week. Mullenweg travels to many of them where he&#8217;s frequently greeted like a rosy-cheeked, wavy-haired deity.</p>
<p>The company powers more than 15% of the Web and more than seventy million blogs, including nearly half of the top 100 blogs in the world. And yet, as a company, it&#8217;s fairly modest in size. It&#8217;s raised just $30 million or so in venture capital, brings in a reported $50 million or so in annual revenues and employs just over 100 people. A lot of companies claim to be motivated purely by mission&#8211; WordPress actually lives that rhetoric.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ll talk about how a 19-year-old Texas boy wound up creating the default content management system for old media and new media alike, and whether he&#8217;s under threat from new, sexier systems like New York&#8217;s own SquareSpace.</p>
<p>Mullenweg splits his time between San Francisco and New York these days, so we thought he&#8217;d be an ideal first guest as we start to branch out to the Big Apple. I&#8217;ll be curious to hear what he has to say about the cultural differences between the two scenes and which one he feels more at home in. Mullenweg is quirky and funny, and I&#8217;m sure this will be a great conversation.</p>
<p>The event will be held at the School of the Visual Arts Beatrice Theatre located at 333 West 23rd Street. We had a last minute scramble for a venue, and appreciate the School of Visual Arts being so accommodating.</p>
<p>In addition to Matt, we&#8217;ve got a great lineup of guests planned for the next few months in New York, which we&#8217;ll be telling you more about in the future. I&#8217;m really excited to have an excuse to fly to the world&#8217;s second largest tech ecosystem every month. It&#8217;s obvious that something major is happening in New York&#8217;s tech scene, and I believe over the next year we will start to see some big exits back up all the hype.</p>
<p>The goal of PandoMonthly is to give first time entrepreneurs a place to go every month and get beer, pizza, meet other entrepreneurs and hear a great conversation with someone fascinating from the industry. They&#8217;ve been hugely popular in San Francisco, and as a media property we get a lot out of it too. We get to meet up and coming entrepreneurs, and we get a candid, intimate conversation with a thought leader that makes amazing video content. I&#8217;m excited to showcase the talent in New York to the world via live stream, the way we have with Dave Morin, Peter Thiel, and Dustin Mokovitz from San Francisco.</p>
<p>But I have to confess, I&#8217;m a little nervous about expanding PandoMonthly to New York. Not because we can&#8217;t find amazing guests and not because there aren&#8217;t plenty of entrepreneurs who may want to attend. But because we&#8217;re primarily known as a Silicon Valley blog. I know there are a lot of events that go on in New York tech scene every month, and I hope you will find some time in your calendar for us. I promise to make it worth the $20 cost of admission!</p>
<p>A note on tickets: We&#8217;ll continue to offer our dual prices of $20 for single tickets and $1000 for a 2012 annual pass. The idea is people with expense accounts subsidize the series so we can keep the price point really low for the entrepreneurs. The annual pass is popular in San Francisco because the general admission tickets tend to sell out in a few hours, and the pass is transferable. At last count, more than fifty companies and venture firms had bought passes to rotate them around to employees or portfolio companies.</p>
<p>I have no idea if the New York event will sell out (I hope so!), so annual passes may make no sense there. <strong>But as added inducement, we are allowing all existing annual pass holders to attend the New York events as part of their existing subscription, and we will allow any new annual pass members to get a free monthly ticket to the San Francisco events.</strong> You just need to claim your ticket by emailing Oni at PandoDaily dot com. In other words, if you support us with your $1,000 investment, we&#8217;ll give you a free ticket in 2012 to any PandoMonthly event <em>anywhere</em> we do one. And since the ticket is transferable, you can gift it to a friend or colleague. It&#8217;s just our way of saying thanks for making the event possible and helping us keep the single ticket prices insanely low.</p>
<p>Sponsors help too. If you are interested in sponsoring PandoMonthly, please email Jeanne Logozzo at jlogo (at) earthlink (dot) net.</p>
<p>See you next week New York!</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/18783/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/18783/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/18783/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/18783/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/18783/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/18783/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/18783/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/18783/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/18783/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/18783/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/18783/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/18783/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/18783/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/18783/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=18783&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://pandodaily.com/2012/05/17/pandomonthly-nyc-with-matt-mullenweg-is-next-week-tickets-on-sale-now/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://pandodaily.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/matt-mullenweg-2.jpg?w=100" />
		<media:content url="http://pandodaily.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/matt-mullenweg-2.jpg?w=100" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">matt-mullenweg-2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/2e197a9560dd191a6039c8c650f7f98f?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">pandosarahlacy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://pandodaily.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/matt-mullenweg-2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">matt-mullenweg-2</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>It&#8217;s a Mommy&#8217;s World &#8211; Exposing Dadscrimination</title>
		<link>http://jerry-mahoney.com/2012/05/07/its-a-mommys-world-exposing-dadscrimination/</link>
		<comments>http://jerry-mahoney.com/2012/05/07/its-a-mommys-world-exposing-dadscrimination/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2012 12:59:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jerry Mahoney</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Super Parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dora The Explorer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay dad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Home]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Katherine Heigl]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kids]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lifestyle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marisa Tomei]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mommy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SAHD]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stay-at-home dad]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://jerry-mahoney.com/?p=1366</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Nice try, New Yorker cover.  Hey, can you tell me where to find that park where there are so many cool dads that moms feel left out, because I have a feeling you need to live in a cartoon in order to get there.  I&#8217;ve been doing the stay-home dad thing for going on three [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1366&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://jerrymahoney.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/newyorkercover.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1368" title="newyorkercover" src="http://jerrymahoney.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/newyorkercover.jpg" alt="" width="465" height="633" /></a>Nice try, New Yorker cover.  Hey, can you tell me where to find that park where there are so many cool dads that moms feel left out, because I have a feeling you need to live in a cartoon in order to get there.  I&#8217;ve been doing the stay-home dad thing for going on three years now, and I still feel like Marisa Tomei at Hillman College, if you know what I mean.</p>
<p>According to the <a href="http://www.census.gov/newsroom/releases/archives/facts_for_features_special_editions/cb11-ff11.html" target="_blank">2010 census</a>, there are 154,000 stay-home dads in the U.S.</p>
<p>154,000?  That&#8217;s not even a lot of people <em>in Delaware</em>.  Isn&#8217;t that exactly the number of Wayans brothers?  We couldn&#8217;t take over Lichtenstein with those numbers.  You really think we&#8217;re taking over parks?</p>
<p><a href="http://jerrymahoney.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/adifferentworld-2.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-1370" title="adifferentworld-2" src="http://jerrymahoney.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/adifferentworld-2.jpg?w=211&h=300" alt="" width="211" height="300" /></a>Look, I&#8217;m not one to cry &#8220;oppression&#8221;.  I&#8217;m a middle-class white male, after all.  My kind have had it pretty good for the last few millennia or so.  Yes, I&#8217;m also gay, but let&#8217;s put that aside for a minute.  Other than that, I&#8217;m fairly demographically charmed.</p>
<p>Still, I&#8217;m in a minority group because of what I do for a living, and as a result I face a particular kind of prejudice on a daily basis.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s right.  I&#8217;m talking about &#8220;Dadscrimination&#8221;.  There may be more of us than there used to be, but in a lot of ways, the world still doesn&#8217;t get us.  We&#8217;re second-class parents, a joke or an afterthought.  Yo, it&#8217;s hard out here for a Daddy.</p>
<p>From the serious to the semantic, here are just a few of the ways dads get the shaft:</p>
<p>- <strong>The Mommification of Everything Parent-Related</strong></p>
<p>You never see &#8220;Men at Work&#8221; signs anymore.  It&#8217;s always &#8220;Crew Working In Trees&#8221;.  We don&#8217;t call them &#8220;Policemen&#8221; or &#8220;Mailmen&#8221;, they&#8217;re &#8220;Officers&#8221; and &#8220;Postal workers.&#8221;  But when it comes to parenting, everything&#8217;s &#8220;Mommy&#8221;.  &#8220;Mommy movies&#8221;, &#8220;Mommy &amp; Me&#8221; classes, &#8220;Mommy wars&#8221;, &#8220;Mommy Zumba&#8221;.  It&#8217;s as if <a href="http://jerry-mahoney.com/2011/11/02/the-m-word/" target="_blank">the M-word</a> is synonymous with &#8220;parent&#8221;.  No matter what barriers we break down in terms of gender inequality, inclusiveness goes out the window once you have kids.</p>
<p><a href="http://jerrymahoney.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/newmotherssign.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-1371" title="h" src="http://jerrymahoney.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/newmotherssign.jpg?w=240&h=300" alt="" width="240" height="300" /></a>I&#8217;ll admit I&#8217;ve never been to a Mommy movie, mostly because neither my kids nor I are interested in a film whose title is preceded by the words &#8220;Katherine Heigl in&#8230;&#8221;.</p>
<p>I did take a Mommy &amp; Me class when my kids were young, although I think the kids and I all snuck in through the &#8220;Me&#8221; loophole.  Some parenting groups won&#8217;t even allow men.  I get it.  Ladies want to talk about breastfeeding (and do it) in privacy.  But until there are enough stay-home dads to sustain a decent-sized get-together, we don&#8217;t have a lot of places to turn for information.  I&#8217;m going to vouch for straight dads, too.  They&#8217;re not trying to look at your boobs.  We&#8217;re all just doing it for our kids, so please let us crash your party.</p>
<p>- <strong>The Boob Tube.</strong></p>
<div id="attachment_1372" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 300px"><a href="http://jerrymahoney.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/brawny.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-1372 " title="brawny" src="http://jerrymahoney.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/brawny.jpg?w=290&h=300" alt="" width="290" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">My only role model</p></div>
<p>If you&#8217;ve ever turned on TV between when school starts and the work day ends, you know it&#8217;s slim pickins for anyone with a moderate amount of testosterone in their system.  Good thing we have Tivo, On Demand and Netflix Instant or we&#8217;d be stuck with nothing but endless infotainment featuring doctors, judges and chattering coffee-sippers sitting on stools.  You know what I&#8217;m talking about .  The &#8220;The&#8221; shows.  &#8220;The View&#8221;, &#8220;The Talk&#8221;, &#8220;The Chew.&#8221;  Yes, there&#8217;s really a show called &#8220;The Chew&#8221;, and if I didn&#8217;t love my kids so much, that alone would be reason enough to go back to work and throw them in day care.</p>
<div id="attachment_1373" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://jerrymahoney.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/jif.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1373" title="jif" src="http://jerrymahoney.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/jif.jpg?w=300&h=280" alt="" width="300" height="280" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">And what about choosy dads? I&#8217;m all ears, Madison Avenue!</p></div>
<p>Of course, no one is blinder to the existence of stay-home dads than advertisers.  Check the commercial breaks during those aforementioned shows, and you&#8217;ll see what I mean.  Look, I buy the Lemon Pledge in my family.  Would it kill you to show a dude dusting his fine wooden surfaces now and then?</p>
<p>- <strong>The Great Potty Disparity.</strong></p>
<p>Nowhere is the disparity between dads and moms more obvious or extreme than in public restrooms.  I&#8217;ve already written about <a href="http://jerry-mahoney.com/2011/12/05/washing-my-hands-of-my-germophobia/" target="_blank">one bad experience</a> I had at a children&#8217;s play center, but it&#8217;s an ongoing concern.  Too many businesses only put changing tables in the women&#8217;s bathrooms, which is not just dadscrimination but sexist, too.  Who says wiping poopy tushies is just a woman&#8217;s job?  If dads aren&#8217;t changing their kids, they should be.</p>
<p><a href="http://jerrymahoney.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/familyrestroom.gif"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-1375" title="familyrestroom" src="http://jerrymahoney.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/familyrestroom.gif?w=300&h=300" alt="" width="300" height="300" /></a>There&#8217;ve been times I&#8217;ve had to wait outside a women&#8217;s bathroom until the coast was clear so I could go in and change a diaper.  Other times, I&#8217;ve had to lay my kid down on a scummy men&#8217;s room floor in the shadow of a urinal or take them back to my car just to get the job done.</p>
<p>Nothing makes me happier than seeing a Family Bathroom, because I know it&#8217;s well-equipped and Dad-friendly.  I know a lot of small businesses don&#8217;t have the funds or the square footage to add a third bathroom, let alone one with curtain-shielded rocking chairs for discreet feeding.  But at any public establishment that welcomes families, Koala Kares in the men&#8217;s room are a must, or personally, I&#8217;m going to find somewhere else to pump my kids full of chicken fingers.</p>
<p>- <strong>Perv stares at the park.</strong></p>
<p>I don&#8217;t hover over my kids at the park, but I&#8217;m always watching them closely from afar, for two very important reasons: 1, so they don&#8217;t get seriously hurt and 2, so they&#8217;re not snatched up by a perv.</p>
<p>We all know public recreation areas are pedophile smorgasbords, but here&#8217;s the irony: While I&#8217;m standing there by myself, eyes narrowly focused on a child who&#8217;s frolicking far off, then turning occasionally in a different direction to eyeball my other kid, what do I look like?  That&#8217;s right&#8230;</p>
<p>A LOUSY, STINKING PERV.</p>
<p>Ask any dad, and he&#8217;ll tell you: In a Mommy&#8217;s world, you are assumed creepy until proven otherwise.</p>
<p>Stay-home dads often fit the perv profile &#8212; middle-aged guys who look tired and unshaven, wearing yesterday&#8217;s Spaghetti-O-stained t-shirt and seeming as if they didn&#8217;t have time to take a shower that morning.  We spend a lot of time at playgrounds and toy stores.  And if you catch us in a moment when our kids aren&#8217;t eagerly tugging at our pant legs and begging us for some Dora the Explorer fruit snacks, we might look like we&#8217;re just there to case the joint.</p>
<p>In researching this piece, I came across <a href="http://daddy-dialectic.blogspot.com/2011/01/parenting-while-male-74-fathers-talk.html" target="_blank">this post</a> from Daddy Dialectic, who faced the ultimate indignity.  Someone actually asked him to leave a park because she assumed he was a predator.  He did a survey and found out it was more common than he thought.  Having read that, I consider myself lucky that that&#8217;s never happened to me.</p>
<p>When I get a perv stare, I&#8217;m always quick to establish contact with my kids, just to prove my credibility.  Of course, that only works when your kids back you up.  One time, while my daughter was throwing a tantrum at Target, she yelled out, &#8220;Where&#8217;s my Mommy?&#8221;  That&#8217;s the only time that&#8217;s ever happened, but if the wrong person had been listening, I could&#8217;ve ended up in a one-on-one with store security.  Thanks, kid.</p>
<p>- <strong>Mommy cliquishness.</strong></p>
<p>I thought my days of feeling hopelessly uncool ended with high school, but that was before I tried striking up conversations with stay-home moms.  Anywhere moms gather, dads are outcasts.</p>
<p><a href="http://jerrymahoney.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/littlechildren.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-1377" title="littlechildren" src="http://jerrymahoney.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/littlechildren.jpg?w=300&h=177" alt="" width="300" height="177" /></a>At least this is one area where gay dads have an edge.  Once I out myself, moms tend to get friendlier.  Maybe their real fear is that I&#8217;ll be some suave male homewrecker like Patrick Wilson in Little Children.</p>
<p>I suspect it&#8217;s something deeper and darker.  Most women just don&#8217;t respect men who stay home with their kids.  They see other women raising kids and think, sure, she&#8217;s a traditionalist or a post-modern feminist proving she doesn&#8217;t need a career to be a strong woman.  Go, sister!</p>
<p>When they see a man raising kids, they think he&#8217;s lazy.  They can&#8217;t help imagining his poor wife busting her ass trying to make partner while he stays home wearing flip-flops and eating Fritos on the couch.</p>
<p>- <strong>The presumption of cluelessness.  </strong></p>
<p>When Drew and I were exploring our parenting options, we saw a counselor to help us sort things out.  She was smart, supportive and extremely helpful.  She quickly became one of my favorite people I&#8217;ve ever met.</p>
<p>Then, after the kids were born, I lamented how hard it was sometimes to soothe them when they were crying.  Our counselor just shrugged and said, &#8220;Well, you&#8217;re a dude.&#8221;</p>
<p>I was stunned, but I&#8217;ve since realized that&#8217;s how a lot of people think.  &#8220;That poor guy, alone with his kids.  He must be in over his head.&#8221;</p>
<p>Thanks, I&#8217;m doing fine, and you can spare me your advice, strangers.  I prefer to screw my kids up <em>my</em> way, not yours.</p>
<p>OK, fair enough.  Moms get unsolicited advice, too, and they hate it just as much.  Maybe this is one area where dads are catching up to moms faster than we&#8217;d like.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>I know dadscrimination isn&#8217;t the worst form of bias.  Nobody&#8217;s making us sit in the back of any buses or denying us the right to vote.  I won&#8217;t be leading any marches on Washington or trying to become daddyhood&#8217;s Malcolm X.  Mostly, I just wanted a chance to vent.</p>
<p>Aren&#8217;t dads allowed to complain once in a while, too?</p>
<p>OK, gotta go.  My kids are waking up.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1366/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1366/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1366/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1366/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1366/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1366/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1366/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1366/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1366/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1366/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1366/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1366/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1366/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1366/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1366&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://jerry-mahoney.com/2012/05/07/its-a-mommys-world-exposing-dadscrimination/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>45</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c881efce8e6aa990ee6fa76b4e9fd2b0?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jerrymahoney</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jerrymahoney.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/newyorkercover.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">newyorkercover</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jerrymahoney.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/adifferentworld-2.jpg?w=211" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">adifferentworld-2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jerrymahoney.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/newmotherssign.jpg?w=240" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">h</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jerrymahoney.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/brawny.jpg?w=290" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">brawny</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jerrymahoney.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/jif.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jif</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jerrymahoney.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/familyrestroom.gif?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">familyrestroom</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jerrymahoney.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/littlechildren.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">littlechildren</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Spain</title>
		<link>http://ryanmg.wordpress.com/2012/05/17/spain/</link>
		<comments>http://ryanmg.wordpress.com/2012/05/17/spain/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2012 15:56:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>ryanmg</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ryanmg.wordpress.com/?p=421</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Its been a few weeks since we came home from spain but life has been so busy so have not had time to go through the photos. In this entry I&#8217;m going to skip writing so much and instead just share some photos from our trip.<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=421&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-64.jpg"><img title="2012-4-spaintravel-64" src="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-64.jpg?w=400&h=600" alt="" width="400" height="600" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-59.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-422" title="2012-4-spaintravel-59" src="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-59.jpg" alt="" width="590" height="393" /></a></p>
<p>Its been a few weeks since we came home from spain but life has been so busy so have not had time to go through the photos. In this entry I&#8217;m going to skip writing so much and instead just share some photos from our trip. <img src='http://s0.wp.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif' alt=':)' class='wp-smiley' /> </p>
<p><a href="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-14.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-423" title="2012-4-spaintravel-14" src="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-14.jpg" alt="" width="590" height="393" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-12.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-426" title="2012-4-spaintravel-12" src="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-12.jpg" alt="" width="590" height="393" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-67.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-427" title="2012-4-spaintravel-67" src="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-67.jpg" alt="" width="400" height="600" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-28.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-428" title="2012-4-spaintravel-28" src="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-28.jpg" alt="" width="590" height="393" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-21.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-429" title="2012-4-spaintravel-21" src="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-21.jpg" alt="" width="590" height="393" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-4.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-430" title="2012-4-spaintravel-4" src="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-4.jpg" alt="" width="400" height="600" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-61.jpg"><img title="2012-4-spaintravel-6" src="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-61.jpg?w=590&h=393" alt="" width="590" height="393" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-15.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-431" title="2012-4-spaintravel-15" src="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-15.jpg" alt="" width="590" height="393" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-72.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-433" title="2012-4-spaintravel-72" src="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-72.jpg" alt="" width="590" height="393" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-43.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-434" title="2012-4-spaintravel-43" src="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-43.jpg" alt="" width="400" height="600" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-56.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-435" title="2012-4-spaintravel-56" src="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-56.jpg" alt="" width="590" height="393" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-22.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-436" title="2012-4-spaintravel-22" src="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-22.jpg" alt="" width="590" height="393" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-42.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-437" title="2012-4-spaintravel-42" src="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-42.jpg" alt="" width="590" height="393" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-37.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-438" title="2012-4-spaintravel-37" src="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-37.jpg" alt="" width="590" height="393" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-68.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-439" title="2012-4-spaintravel-68" src="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-68.jpg" alt="" width="400" height="600" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-44.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-440" title="2012-4-spaintravel-44" src="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-44.jpg" alt="" width="590" height="393" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-55.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-441" title="2012-4-spaintravel-55" src="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-55.jpg" alt="" width="590" height="393" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-7.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-442" title="2012-4-spaintravel-7" src="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-7.jpg" alt="" width="400" height="600" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-34.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-443" title="2012-4-spaintravel-34" src="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-34.jpg" alt="" width="590" height="393" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-33.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-444" title="2012-4-spaintravel-33" src="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-33.jpg" alt="" width="590" height="393" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-65.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-445" title="2012-4-spaintravel-65" src="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-65.jpg" alt="" width="590" height="393" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-63.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-446" title="2012-4-spaintravel-63" src="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-63.jpg" alt="" width="400" height="600" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/421/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/421/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/421/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/421/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/421/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/421/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/421/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/421/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/421/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/421/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/421/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/421/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/421/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/421/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=421&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://ryanmg.wordpress.com/2012/05/17/spain/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/5a901204c5d55e47763619b005be2cbe?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ryanmg</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-64.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2012-4-spaintravel-64</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-59.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2012-4-spaintravel-59</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-14.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2012-4-spaintravel-14</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-12.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2012-4-spaintravel-12</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-67.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2012-4-spaintravel-67</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-28.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2012-4-spaintravel-28</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-21.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2012-4-spaintravel-21</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-4.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2012-4-spaintravel-4</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-61.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2012-4-spaintravel-6</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-15.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2012-4-spaintravel-15</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-72.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2012-4-spaintravel-72</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-43.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2012-4-spaintravel-43</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-56.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2012-4-spaintravel-56</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-22.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2012-4-spaintravel-22</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-42.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2012-4-spaintravel-42</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-37.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2012-4-spaintravel-37</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-68.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2012-4-spaintravel-68</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-44.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2012-4-spaintravel-44</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-55.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2012-4-spaintravel-55</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-7.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2012-4-spaintravel-7</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-34.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2012-4-spaintravel-34</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-33.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2012-4-spaintravel-33</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-65.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2012-4-spaintravel-65</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ryanmg.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/2012-4-spaintravel-63.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2012-4-spaintravel-63</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Gracious Guide to Benevolent Blogging &#8212; Five Tips</title>
		<link>http://brigittebanter.com/2012/04/06/a-gracious-guide-to-benevolent-blogging-five-tips/</link>
		<comments>http://brigittebanter.com/2012/04/06/a-gracious-guide-to-benevolent-blogging-five-tips/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2012 14:26:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Brigitte</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Just Because]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Literary Ramblings and Thoughts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News Worthy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Non-Fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Other Musings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social networking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brigittebanter.com/?p=524</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I’ve been in the blogging world for almost four months now, so I don’t claim to be an expert at this way we find ourselves communicating in the 21st century.  I do, however, consider myself a gracious and nice human being and try to extend courtesies when someone takes the time to acknowledge my work. [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=524&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I’ve been in the blogging world for almost four months now, so I don’t claim to be an expert at this way we find ourselves communicating in the 21st century.  I do, however, consider myself a gracious and nice human being and try to extend courtesies when someone takes the time to acknowledge my work.</p>
<p>With that in mind, I’ve come up with a few tips that I believe all bloggers should keep in mind when they have something to say, whether that be from their own writing or when they comment on others.</p>
<p><strong>1.  <span style="text-decoration:underline;">Find other blogs that you like and comment</span></strong></p>
<p><a href="http://brigittebanter.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/socialnet-sujin-jetkasettakorn.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-526" title="SocialNet.Sujin Jetkasettakorn" src="http://brigittebanter.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/socialnet-sujin-jetkasettakorn-e1333720122431.jpg?w=250&h=166" alt="" width="250" height="166" /></a>I’ve found those blogs by exploring, sometimes through Freshly Pressed blogs, friends’ blogs or just by accident.  If I find one that I think is interesting, funny or inspiring, I make a comment.  I figure if they’ve taken the time to write something, I can do the same.  If someone decides to follow me, I follow them.  With the way in which we can control those alerts/comments, I don’t see a reason why one shouldn’t.</p>
<p>BTW, if you’ve got thousands of followers &#8212; congrats, I know it&#8217;s hard work &#8212; but some of your blog&#8217;s success stems from other bloggers paying homage to yours.  Please take the time to visit your supporters&#8217; blogs every once in awhile to leave a comment, share the love please!</p>
<p><a href="http://brigittebanter.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/socialnetworking-nutdanai-apikhomboonwaroot.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-529 alignright" title="SocialNetworking.Nutdanai Apikhomboonwaroot" src="http://brigittebanter.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/socialnetworking-nutdanai-apikhomboonwaroot-e1333721219195.jpg?w=275&h=182" alt="" width="275" height="182" /></a>&#8220;Likes” are great, but if possible leave a comment <em>and</em> a “Like,” why not? Yes, I’m guilty of the same thing &#8212; just leaving a “Like” (I WELCOME all “Likes” and thank you so much to all who have taken the time to like my posts) but a comment, now that’s good stuff.</p>
<p><strong>2.  <span style="text-decoration:underline;">Be nice/positive when leaving a comment</span></strong></p>
<p>This should be a given and we do have the opportunity to ignore or disapprove comments, but they still hurt (negative comments) the one who receives them.  I’ve not received any mean-spirited comments; everyone in the blogging community has been wonderful, but I’ve visited other blogs where I’ve seen rather unkind comments.  Even if you critique someone’s work or disagree, start out with what you liked about a post and then cite what you may not agree with &#8211; in a constructive, kind manner.  Judith Martin (Miss Manners) says:  <em>When virtues are pointed out first, flaws seem less insurmountable.  </em></p>
<p><strong>3.  <span style="text-decoration:underline;">Reply back to those who take the time to comment</span></strong></p>
<p>Another thing that I think should be a given, but alas, it doesn’t always happen.  If someone comments on my blog, I reply back with a thank you and a few words of encouragement to them.  It’s just good manners.  From Emily Post:  <em>Manner is personality—the outward manifestation of one’s innate character and attitude toward life.  </em>You get back what you give.</p>
<p>P.S. (If I’ve inadvertently not done so to anyone who may be reading this, then my heartfelt apologies).</p>
<p><strong>4.  <span style="text-decoration:underline;">Give credit if someone inspires a blog you write&#8211;help a blogger out<a href="http://brigittebanter.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/thankyou-felixco-inc.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-527" title="ThankYou.Felixco, Inc" src="http://brigittebanter.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/thankyou-felixco-inc.jpg?w=260&h=300" alt="" width="260" height="300" /></a></span></strong></p>
<p>We get ideas from current trends and from reading fellow bloggers’ posts. Someone’s musings help us create our own &#8212; say <a href="http://brigittebanter.com/2012/04/05/dancing-with-words/" target="_blank">thank you</a>, it only takes a sentence or two.  If you find yourself writing a blog that was prompted by reading someone else’s, then mention who inspired you with a link back to their blog.  From Anne Lamott:  <em>Here are the two best prayers I know:  Help, help me, help and Thank you, thank you, thank you.</em></p>
<p>BTW, read the <a href="http://en.blog.wordpress.com/2012/03/15/build-your-audience/" target="_blank">excerpt</a> from blogger Rachel Bertsche and best-selling author of <em>MWF Seeking BFF: My Yearlong Search for a New Best Friend </em>who was the inspiration for my post.  She gleaned inspiration from another blogger to share her tips.</p>
<p><strong>5.  <span style="text-decoration:underline;">Share your wisdom</span></strong></p>
<p><a href="http://brigittebanter.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/the_thinker_rodin.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-528" title="Digital StillCamera" src="http://brigittebanter.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/the_thinker_rodin.jpg?w=165&h=300" alt="" width="165" height="300" /></a>There are so many talented people out there!  Great writers, poets, photographers, musicians, satirists, comedians, spiritual souls and hobbyists who share their time and talents.  A couple of bloggers have asked me for advice and I replied back to them &#8212; quickly.  I was flattered that they valued my opinion and hopefully, I helped them in some small way.  Share what you know; you never know when you may need a little help to inspire you.</p>
<p>That’s my five tips for courteous blogging.  Do you have any to share?</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><em>A candle loses nothing by lighting another candle</em>.  &#8212; Erin Majors<a href="http://brigittebanter.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/candleburningrock-simon-howden1.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-532 aligncenter" title="candleburningrock.Simon Howden" src="http://brigittebanter.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/candleburningrock-simon-howden1.jpg" alt="" width="173" height="186" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/524/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/524/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/524/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/524/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/524/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/524/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/524/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/524/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/524/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/524/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/524/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/524/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/524/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/524/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=524&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://brigittebanter.com/2012/04/06/a-gracious-guide-to-benevolent-blogging-five-tips/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>60</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://brigittebanter.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/smilinghalo-digitalart.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://brigittebanter.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/smilinghalo-digitalart.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">SmilingHalo.digitalart</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/673c0b8d0f8443cf1ba451650aad9658?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">brigitte622</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://brigittebanter.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/socialnet-sujin-jetkasettakorn-e1333720122431.jpg?w=250" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">SocialNet.Sujin Jetkasettakorn</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://brigittebanter.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/socialnetworking-nutdanai-apikhomboonwaroot-e1333721219195.jpg?w=275" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">SocialNetworking.Nutdanai Apikhomboonwaroot</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://brigittebanter.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/thankyou-felixco-inc.jpg?w=260" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ThankYou.Felixco, Inc</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://brigittebanter.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/the_thinker_rodin.jpg?w=165" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Digital StillCamera</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://brigittebanter.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/candleburningrock-simon-howden1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">candleburningrock.Simon Howden</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Puerto Rican Adventure</title>
		<link>http://kansaslovebird.wordpress.com/2012/05/15/puerto-rican-adventure/</link>
		<comments>http://kansaslovebird.wordpress.com/2012/05/15/puerto-rican-adventure/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2012 20:04:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Kansas Love Bird</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adventure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bioluminescent bays]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Caribbean]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fajardo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Guanica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mofongo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Old San Juan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ponce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Puerto Rico]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://kansaslovebird.wordpress.com/?p=188</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I tell you what! This Midwestern gal loves a good adventure. And I&#8217;ve seen a LOT of places and have had a LOT of adventures. Anyone who wants an amazing Caribbean adventure should definitely go to Puerto Rico. Not only are there amazing winding backwood mountain roads, there are beaches: lush and beautiful, on each [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=188&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone size-full" src="http://kansaslovebird.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/20120515-150202.jpg" alt="20120515-150202.jpg" />    <img class="alignnone size-full" src="http://kansaslovebird.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/20120515-150209.jpg" alt="20120515-150209.jpg" /></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full" src="http://kansaslovebird.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/20120515-150151.jpg" alt="20120515-150151.jpg" />    <img class="alignnone size-full" style="border-style:initial;border-color:initial;cursor:default;border-width:0;" src="http://kansaslovebird.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/20120515-150227.jpg" alt="20120515-150227.jpg" /></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full" src="http://kansaslovebird.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/20120515-150220.jpg" alt="20120515-150220.jpg" /></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full" src="http://kansaslovebird.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/20120515-150234.jpg" alt="20120515-150234.jpg" /></p>
<p>I tell you what! This Midwestern gal loves a good adventure. And I&#8217;ve seen a LOT of places and have had a LOT of adventures. Anyone who wants an amazing Caribbean adventure should definitely go to Puerto Rico. Not only are there amazing winding backwood mountain roads, there are beaches: lush and beautiful, on each side of the island. On the north eastern side you see the Atlantic Ocean with huge crashing waves carving the rock and stone. To the southwest you have the beautiful calm turquoise waters of the Caribbean Sea in Guanica and Ponce.</p>
<p>Forget your GPS. Our paper maps didn&#8217;t even work consistently. But isn&#8217;t getting lost half of the fun? It was for my rainforest mountain beach adventure in Puerto Rico. The first day we counted 14 rainbows. I knew I was in paradise.</p>
<p>Downtown Old San Juan is so beautiful with its hundreds-of-years-old brightly colored buildings and homes. The cobblestone streets covered in moss and the gorgeous patios are such a treat. Other than Old Town Alexandria (Virginia, that is, where I spent much of my childhood wandering and dreaming) Old Town San Juan might just be my new favorite place to take architectural photogs.</p>
<p>Mofongo is the national dish made with plantain and all kinds of other ingredients like crab or pork. I hadn&#8217;t eaten pork in nearly 15 years and I <em>had</em> to try the pork mofongo. Holy cow (pig?) it was good! Back in the States, I still don&#8217;t eat pork but I do dream about that mofongo.</p>
<p>Perhaps the most memorable part of my adventure in Puerto Rico was the midnight kayaking: under a new moon, through a mangrove forest. If that&#8217;s not magical enough for you, read on!</p>
<p>I drove into what seemed like uncharted areas (uncharted on <em>our</em> maps) east of El Yunque Rainforest.  Into the twisty winding roads past tons of roadside food stands (coconut water is a must!) going deeper and deeper into a little mountain town near Fajardo to see the <em>bioluminescent bays of Puerto Rico. </em>These waters were so magical! If you ever wanted to believe in magic, the bioluminescent bays of PR is where you will see it. When you touch the water, it glows like blue fire. If you splash your body, you are suddenly covered in blue diamonds! This is all from little single-celled organisms (algae) that bioluminese when touched. Think of fireflies in the summer. Except blue. Gorgeous deep blue fire light. No exaggeration. It&#8217;s science. In fact, our kayak tour was led by marine biologists who study the organisms. It was so amazing. What&#8217;s more, my Spanish came back to me! Now that&#8217;s real magic!!</p>
<p>Have you ever been to Puerto Rico? What was your favorite place?</p>
<p><a href="http://kansaslovebird.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/20120515-150244.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full" src="http://kansaslovebird.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/20120515-150244.jpg" alt="20120515-150244.jpg" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/188/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/188/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/188/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/188/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/188/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/188/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/188/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/188/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/188/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/188/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/188/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/188/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/188/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/188/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=188&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://kansaslovebird.wordpress.com/2012/05/15/puerto-rican-adventure/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/3a56d1b4d42fdd63e7134e3a35535aa5?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lovebirdphotoblog</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://kansaslovebird.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/20120515-150202.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">20120515-150202.jpg</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://kansaslovebird.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/20120515-150209.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">20120515-150209.jpg</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://kansaslovebird.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/20120515-150151.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">20120515-150151.jpg</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://kansaslovebird.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/20120515-150227.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">20120515-150227.jpg</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://kansaslovebird.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/20120515-150220.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">20120515-150220.jpg</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://kansaslovebird.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/20120515-150234.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">20120515-150234.jpg</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://kansaslovebird.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/20120515-150244.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">20120515-150244.jpg</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The End of The Sangria Pitcher</title>
		<link>http://orangespicedrop.wordpress.com/2012/05/14/the-end-of-the-sangria-pitcher/</link>
		<comments>http://orangespicedrop.wordpress.com/2012/05/14/the-end-of-the-sangria-pitcher/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2012 13:42:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>mkultra76</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[home]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[random]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[summer]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://orangespicedrop.wordpress.com/?p=1167</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;The beauty of things must be that they end.&#8221;  &#8212; Jack Kerouac All that remained in the pitcher was a fine coating of artificial sweetener sludge.  The fingerprints of the children covered the pitcher&#8217;s surface after many glasses of lemonade were poured.  It was not a particularly practical pitcher, as its bulbous shape was reminiscent [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1167&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>&#8220;The beauty of things must be that they end.&#8221;  &#8212; Jack Kerouac</em></p>
<p>All that remained in the pitcher was a fine coating of artificial sweetener sludge.  The fingerprints of the children covered the pitcher&#8217;s surface after many glasses of lemonade were poured.  It was not a particularly practical pitcher, as its bulbous shape was reminiscent of the Kool Aid Man, and it required entirely too much space in the refrigerator, crowding out the more important jugs of milk and orange juice.  It was made of glass.  It was rather heavy.  This was especially true when it was full.</p>
<p><a href="http://orangespicedrop.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/pitcher.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1168" title="pitcher" src="http://orangespicedrop.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/pitcher.jpg" alt="" width="225" height="225" /></a></p>
<p>The pitcher was never meant to hold lemonade.   Something about it&#8217;s shape, and the way it was perched on the department store shelf and complimented by perfect lighting conditions, whispered not, &#8220;Hey, Kool Aid!&#8221; but, &#8220;Summer&#8230;sunshine&#8230;sangria!&#8221; to the lady who walked past it and ultimately purchased the clean and shining vessel.  However, when items are purchased by a person who lives in a home containing children, that item somehow takes on a different role than the one that was originally envisioned.</p>
<p>As of yet, the pitcher has contained absolutely no sangria.  After its inaugural use, in which it held an abundant amount of fluorescent green Appletinis for a St. Patrick&#8217;s Day party, it sat on top of the refrigerator, with nothing but travel mugs and metal water bottles for company.  Eventually, cool temperatures and the requisite drinking of cup after cup of Irish Breakfast Tea and Hot Chocolate gave way to more balmy conditions.  But alas, the sticker on the bottom of the pitcher when purchased warned against the dangers of pouring hot liquid into it, making the pitcher an unsuitable container for even freshly brewed iced tea.</p>
<p>Nobody wants a steaming cup of tea after mowing the lawn, and no kid wants a mug of hot chocolate after riding his bike all afternoon as far as Mom will allow him to venture, with the blazing sun beating down on the top of his head.  (Just a wee bit further than mom will allow him to venture, actually.  Never underestimate the allure of rebellion fueled adrenaline to an 11 year old boy.)</p>
<p>It was a day such as this, when the sun did what the sun does best&#8211;heating the world below, without even a wisp of cloud to impede its rays&#8211;when the Sangria Pitcher was hastily grabbed off the top of the refrigerator for its new life as a decanter for innocent, thirst quenching beverages, suitable adults and kids alike.</p>
<p>It was weeks later, when the pitcher was reduced to total humiliation.  One evening, when the last glass of lemonade was poured by a child who was eager to return to the picnic table outside where the family was devouring a Mother&#8217;s Day dinner that Dad had carefully and lovingly barbequed to juicy, succulent perfection.  Unwilling to take the three steps necessary to deposit the empty pitcher into the kitchen sink, where it would later be washed, dried, and refilled with lemonade, the child returned the empty pitcher back into the refrigerator, devoid of all contents except for a haze of undissolved aspartame.</p>
<p>&#8220;Wow,&#8221; opined the Mother Figure.  &#8220;I&#8217;ve heard of taking the last Pop Tart and not throwing the box away before.  But this&#8211;this takes laziness to a whole new level, doesn’t it?&#8221;</p>
<p>And it was thus, that the pitcher whose original purpose was to offer refreshments to one woman and her lady friends on a balmy summer evening, came to symbolize the hasty, eager, and gloriously lazy summer days of childhood.  No longer would it be known as &#8220;The Sangria Pitcher.&#8221;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1167/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1167/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1167/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1167/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1167/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1167/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1167/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1167/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1167/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1167/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1167/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1167/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1167/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1167/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1167&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://orangespicedrop.wordpress.com/2012/05/14/the-end-of-the-sangria-pitcher/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>22</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c3cc44ee5879cefc536edc3eb659289b?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mkultra76</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://orangespicedrop.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/pitcher.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">pitcher</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A little bit of Chicago</title>
		<link>http://lyndabphotography.wordpress.com/2012/05/17/a-little-bit-of-chicago/</link>
		<comments>http://lyndabphotography.wordpress.com/2012/05/17/a-little-bit-of-chicago/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2012 16:49:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>lyndabphotography</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cityscapes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bridge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[buildings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chicago]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[city]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://lyndabphotography.wordpress.com/?p=112</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=112&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://lyndabphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/dsc_0100.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-120" title="DSC_0100" src="http://lyndabphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/dsc_0100.jpg" alt="" width="590" height="391" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://lyndabphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/dsc_0093.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-119" title="DSC_0093" src="http://lyndabphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/dsc_0093.jpg" alt="" width="590" height="391" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://lyndabphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/dsc_0092.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-118" title="DSC_0092" src="http://lyndabphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/dsc_0092.jpg" alt="" width="590" height="391" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://lyndabphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/dsc_0091.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-117" title="DSC_0091" src="http://lyndabphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/dsc_0091.jpg" alt="" width="590" height="391" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://lyndabphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/dsc_0088.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-116" title="DSC_0088" src="http://lyndabphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/dsc_0088.jpg" alt="" width="590" height="391" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://lyndabphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/dsc_0076.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-114" title="DSC_0076" src="http://lyndabphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/dsc_0076.jpg" alt="" width="590" height="391" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://lyndabphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/dsc_0085.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-115" title="DSC_0085" src="http://lyndabphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/dsc_0085.jpg?w=354&h=533" alt="" width="354" height="533" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://lyndabphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/dsc_0032.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-113" title="DSC_0032" src="http://lyndabphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/dsc_0032.jpg?w=354&h=533" alt="" width="354" height="533" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/112/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/112/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/112/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/112/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/112/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/112/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/112/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/112/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/112/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/112/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/112/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/112/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/112/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/112/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=112&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://lyndabphotography.wordpress.com/2012/05/17/a-little-bit-of-chicago/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/6125fa4fb47d3f55865b551d210ccf21?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lyndabphotography</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lyndabphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/dsc_0100.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0100</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lyndabphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/dsc_0093.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0093</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lyndabphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/dsc_0092.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0092</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lyndabphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/dsc_0091.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0091</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lyndabphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/dsc_0088.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0088</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lyndabphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/dsc_0076.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0076</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lyndabphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/dsc_0085.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0085</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://lyndabphotography.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/dsc_0032.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0032</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>You&#8217;re never too old for a temporary tattoo (?)</title>
		<link>http://cindspectus.wordpress.com/2012/05/17/youre-never-too-old-for-a-temporary-tattoo/</link>
		<comments>http://cindspectus.wordpress.com/2012/05/17/youre-never-too-old-for-a-temporary-tattoo/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2012 14:31:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Cindie</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Good Eats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adventures in libations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beer]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cindspectus.wordpress.com/?p=50</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Last night I went out to a brewery night at one of my favorite bars with a few friends. These friends happen to be very beer savvy. When I say beer savvy, I don&#8217;t just mean that they choose Bud instead of Bud Light, I mean they stand on line for rare release bottles, and [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=50&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last night I went out to a brewery night at one of my favorite bars with a few friends. These friends happen to be very beer savvy. When I say beer savvy, I don&#8217;t just mean that they choose Bud instead of Bud Light, I mean they stand on line for rare release bottles, and in one case, brew their own [if you're wondering, the home-brew is quite good]. After handing in my last assignment of the semester earlier in the day, I was absolutely ready to just sit back, sip on a few delicious beers and enjoy the company.</p>
<div id="attachment_53" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 522px"><a href="http://cindspectus.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/founders.jpeg"><img class=" wp-image-53 " title="Founders" src="http://cindspectus.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/founders.jpeg?w=512&h=377" alt="" width="512" height="377" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">One of yesterday&#8217;s brews, mmm.</p></div>
<p>Let me set the scene: A half-dozen twentysomethings, in a range of business, business casual, and straight-up casual clothes. A no-frills bar with a good craft beer selection. We&#8217;re sitting at our table, nibbling at fries and hamburgers [inevitably made with farm-fresh ingredients and fancy cheese]. Why is this important? I just wanted to establish that this isn&#8217;t a dive bar, we&#8217;re not coeds looking for the beer pong table. I like to think that we&#8217;re a bunch of moderately sophisticated adults, swapping work war stories and general conversation over some good food and drinks.</p>
<p>There. I think you can picture it, right? I&#8217;d provide a picture of the bar itself for some additional visuals, but their website is lacking and I don&#8217;t want to steal from others.</p>
<p>So I leave the table briefly, and when I return, everyone has a small sticker in front of them. Not just any small sticker: a <em>temporary tattoo. </em>It&#8217;s nothing all that revolutionary, just a miniature version of the brewery&#8217;s logo. But for some reason, I needed to have one. I looked hopefully at my beau to see if my sad eyes would make him relinquish his. They did, but as he was handing it over, I was given my very own. I felt like a five-year old again, for just a few seconds. It was slightly embarrassing, but I think I hid my sheer joy well enough [until I spilled my true feelings all over this post, of course].</p>
<p>So in short: you&#8217;re never too old for a temporary tattoo, right? Assuming I won&#8217;t actually use it, and if I do, it won&#8217;t be visible to anyone who sees me as remotely professional anyway.</p>
<p>P.S. I consider this a &#8220;food post&#8221;, so I suppose I should address the beer itself. Yum. Founders is one of those breweries that I never would have discovered if I didn&#8217;t have said beer-savvy friends. Last night&#8217;s lineup [for me, anyway, I'm sure amongst all of us we tried each of the Founders' beers on tap] was the Breakfast Stout and Centennial IPA. Both were delicious. I can&#8217;t tell you what kind of barrels they ferment in or what the prominent tasting notes are, but just know that they&#8217;re good, and if you find yourself at a bar where they&#8217;ve got some on tap, I recommend it.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/50/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/50/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/50/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/50/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/50/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/50/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/50/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/50/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/50/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/50/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/50/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/50/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/50/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/50/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=50&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://cindspectus.wordpress.com/2012/05/17/youre-never-too-old-for-a-temporary-tattoo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://cindspectus.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/founders.jpeg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://cindspectus.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/founders.jpeg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Founders</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Cindie</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cindspectus.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/founders.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Founders</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Match point</title>
		<link>http://emmamiranda.com/2012/04/16/match-poin/</link>
		<comments>http://emmamiranda.com/2012/04/16/match-poin/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2012 07:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>emmamiranda</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Photo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[as seen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[couples]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[London]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[on the street]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stories]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://emmamiranda.com/?p=1225</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[So I&#8217;ve been mulling over this whole thing about couples that has been on my mind lately. For me, part of the interest is the way that people start to merge their individual styles together to create a look that sets them apart as a pair. I love it when you see people who clearly [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1225&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://emmamiranda.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/couples-match-1.jpg"><img src="http://emmamiranda.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/couples-match-1.jpg" alt="" title="couples match-1" width="667" height="1000" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1226" /></a><br />
So I&#8217;ve been mulling over this whole thing about couples that has been on my mind <a href="http://emmamiranda.com/2012/04/14/the-real-deal/" title="The real deal" target="_blank">lately</a>. For me, part of the interest is the way that people start to merge their individual styles together to create a look that sets them apart as a pair. I love it when you see people who clearly just belong together. I&#8217;ve been observing this recently on the street and I&#8217;m going to post a few examples up here of what I mean over the next couple of days.<br />
I wonder, do we seek out people who look like us or do we blend together once we&#8217;re an item? I&#8217;m not sure, maybe a bit of both, but either way, I&#8217;m loving the way these guys look together.</p>
<p><a href="http://emmamiranda.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/couples-match-3.jpg"><img src="http://emmamiranda.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/couples-match-3.jpg" alt="" title="couples match-3" width="667" height="1000" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1228" /></a></p>
<br /> Tagged: <a href='http://emmamiranda.com/tag/as-seen/'>as seen</a>, <a href='http://emmamiranda.com/tag/couples/'>couples</a>, <a href='http://emmamiranda.com/tag/london/'>London</a>, <a href='http://emmamiranda.com/tag/on-the-street/'>on the street</a>, <a href='http://emmamiranda.com/tag/photography/'>photography</a>, <a href='http://emmamiranda.com/tag/stories/'>stories</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1225/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1225/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1225/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1225/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1225/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1225/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1225/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1225/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1225/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1225/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1225/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1225/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1225/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1225/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1225&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://emmamiranda.com/2012/04/16/match-poin/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">emmamiranda</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://emmamiranda.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/couples-match-1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">couples match-1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://emmamiranda.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/couples-match-3.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">couples match-3</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Summer Reading List 2012</title>
		<link>http://adashofcinema.com/2012/05/16/summer-reading-list-2012/</link>
		<comments>http://adashofcinema.com/2012/05/16/summer-reading-list-2012/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2012 08:00:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lauren</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[authors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[foodies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[summer reading]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://adashofcinema.com/?p=3459</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Blood, Bones, and Butter by Gabrielle Hamilton &#124; Best Food Writing 2011 by Holly Hughes &#124; An Economist Gets Lunch: New Rules for Everyday Foodies by Tyler Cowen &#124; The Film That Changed My Life by Robert K. Elder Summer is the perfect time to finally read all those books you&#8217;ve been neglecting during the year. I currently [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3459&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://adashofcinema.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/books-summer.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-3460" title="books summer" src="http://adashofcinema.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/books-summer.jpg?w=600&h=972" alt="" width="600" height="972" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://www.amazon.com/Blood-Bones-Butter-Inadvertent-Education/dp/0812980883/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1337143303&amp;sr=8-1" target="_blank"><em>Blood, Bones, and Butter</em></a> by Gabrielle Hamilton |<em> <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Best-Food-Writing-Holly-Hughes/dp/073821518X/ref=sr_1_2?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1337143303&amp;sr=8-2" target="_blank">Best Food Writing 2011 </a></em>by Holly Hughes | <a href="http://www.amazon.com/An-Economist-Gets-Lunch-Everyday/dp/0525952667/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1337143487&amp;sr=1-1" target="_blank"><em>An Economist Gets Lunch: New Rules for Everyday Foodies</em> </a>by Tyler Cowen | <a href="http://www.amazon.com/The-Film-That-Changed-Life/dp/1556528256/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1337143538&amp;sr=1-1" target="_blank"><em>The Film That Changed My Life</em> </a>by Robert K. Elder</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Summer is the perfect time to finally read all those books you&#8217;ve been neglecting during the year. I currently have a list of 11 books that I am hoping to get through in the next few months. I&#8217;m sure I will find more books as the weeks go on, but my goal this season is to finish my list &#8211; no excuses! These are the first four books on my &#8220;To Read&#8221; list. What are you reading this summer?</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3459/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3459/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3459/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3459/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3459/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3459/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3459/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3459/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3459/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3459/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3459/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3459/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3459/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3459/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3459&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://adashofcinema.com/2012/05/16/summer-reading-list-2012/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/4009cb5688b9a9a2faa808b6896ae3ea?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">laurjess</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://adashofcinema.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/books-summer.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">books summer</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>