<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Dec 2012 20:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>The Debt Bias: Or, how good reforms do bad things to good people</title>
		<link>http://yourbrainonecon.wordpress.com/2012/12/07/the-debt-bias-or-how-good-reforms-do-bad-things-to-good-people/</link>
		<comments>http://yourbrainonecon.wordpress.com/2012/12/07/the-debt-bias-or-how-good-reforms-do-bad-things-to-good-people/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2012 02:09:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>mdsy10</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corporate finance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[debt bias]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Econ for Poets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[financial reform]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tax coded]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://yourbrainonecon.wordpress.com/?p=999</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve been reading a lot of economic commentary and analysis around two things lately: (1) is, naturally, the negotiations surrounding the &#8220;fiscal cliff,&#8221; and (2) is Prof. Anas Admati&#8217;s argument that the best financial reform we could undertake would be to require banks to have a higher equity ratio (that is, to finance more of [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=999&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve been reading a lot of economic commentary and analysis around two things lately: (1) is, naturally, the negotiations surrounding the &#8220;fiscal cliff,&#8221; and (2) is Prof. Anas Admati&#8217;s <a href="https://gsbapps.stanford.edu/researchpapers/library/BankEquityNotExpensive.pdf">argument</a> that the best financial reform we could undertake would be to require banks to have a higher equity ratio (that is, to finance more of their assets through stock and less through debt, reducing their leverage). I hope to write at greater length about (2) in the future, but, for now, suffice it to say that both of these things center on the &#8220;debt bias&#8221; in the U.S. tax-code, a bias which piqued my interest and so which, after a little research, I should like to tell you about.</p>
<p>Let me start out with some econ for poets. Suppose you&#8217;re a business and you want to make a big expansion&#8211;setting up lots of new stores, opening a new R&amp;D facility, etc.&#8211;that will cost you $1 billion.  Unless you have a lot of cash on hand (which you probably shouldn&#8217;t&#8211;it would have been wasteful to have just accumulated it) there are two ways you could fund this expansion. One, you could issue more shares in your company (that is, sell more stock to the public)&#8211;this is equity. Or, two, you could get a loan from a bank to do this&#8211;this is debt. Which option should you choose? Well, naturally, you should choose whichever one is cheaper&#8211;technically, whichever funding option&#8217;s obligations have a lower net present discounted value (the debt&#8217;s obligations being interest and principle, and the equity&#8217;s obligation being a share of profits and ownership). In reality, which one will be cheaper? Well, theoretically, since these two instruments are both providing the same good&#8211;financing&#8211;they should be about equally expensive. Think about it: if interest rates were relatively high, meaning that debt was more expensive than equity, firms would rush to issue more shares, which would reduce stock prices by increasing their supply, and eschew bank loans, which would force banks to lower their &#8216;prices&#8217; (their interest rates), until the two became equally expensive. So in a perfect market, equity and debt should be about equally expensive for companies, and companies would make their financing decisions as follows:  they would fund their activities through equity if they thought that their shares were slightly overpriced, and through debt if they thought their shares were relatively underpriced.</p>
<p>Now, we&#8217;ve just done some typical Econ 101 theory above, about an ideal market. But in the real world corporate financing decisions are distorted. One major distortion is the U.S. tax code, which includes a deduction for interest payments on debt. The tax code does not include a deduction from dividend payments to shareholders. To the contrary, corporate profits returned to shareholders are taxed twice: once as corporate profits (just before they have been returned to shareholders), and again as capital gains (once they are in the shareholders&#8217; hands). What does this do? Well, it gives companies a strong &#8220;debt bias&#8221; relative to the ideal market we laid out above. Because the obligations they incur from debt-financing in fact reduce their tax burdens, corporations are incentivized to rely relatively more heavily on debt, and less on equity.</p>
<p>Why is this a problem? Well, it isn&#8217;t always, necessarily, a problem for everyone. Indeed, if you&#8217;re a shareholder of a firm that has really great growth prospects for the future, you should be happy with debt-financing&#8211;this &#8220;leverage&#8221; means that you will get a higher share of whatever is left over once debt-obligations are paid off, than if your share had been diluted by the issuance of more equity. But the problems are twofold. First, in general, we as a society want companies to devote their analysis to trying figure out, and their energies to trying to meet, our needs as we express them in the marketplace&#8211;not make their decisions based on how best to game the tax code.  But, second, debt becomes a very big, very tangible problem during an economic downturn, when it can cause a credit crunch, a massive financial crisis, and thence a recession/depression, as you may have heard. We often hear debt analogized to &#8220;leverage,&#8221; because it makes the good times better for companies&#8217; owners (shareholders) and the bad times worse. Consider this super simplified model of a firm buying one asset in one year, with a 2% interest rate: If you&#8217;ve financed a $100 million asset through $50m of equity and $50m of debt (a debt-equity ratio of 1 to 1), if the value of that asset suddenly declines to $85m, you&#8217;re still easily okay&#8211;you can pay back your creditors their $51m, and still have $34m left, which is now the value of your shareholders&#8217; stake, a loss of $16m for them. But if you financed that through $10m of equity and $90m of debt (a debt-equity ratio/leverage of 9 to 1), the same decline in the asset&#8217;s value will bankrupt you: You owe creditors more than you have, and so your shares are worth less than nothing, and you have to enter bankruptcy. If you get the conceptual gist here, you can probably also see how, in good times, when firms are making high profits, &#8220;leverage&#8221; (a high debt-equity ratio) can increase the profits that are returned to shareholders. (But, and this is a bit technical, it does not technically increase shareholder <em>value</em>, because the leverage makes the expected return-on-equity <em>riskier</em>.) It also makes it much easier for firms to slip into bankruptcy when the times are not as good as they had predicted.</p>
<p>So what, then, is the problem with leverage if it just helps shareholders on the upside, and hurts them or causes bankruptcy on the downside? Why should I care if I&#8217;m not a major shareholder, or involved in any way with a highly-levered firm? Or if I am a shareholder, shouldn&#8217;t I be okay with this as long as I have a diversified portfolio that is collectively non-risky? The problem is that, during a credit crunch and financial crisis, bankruptcy is contagious. That is, when a highly-levered firm (which could itself be a bank&#8211;see my upcoming post on Admati) can no longer meet its obligations and enters bankruptcy, it is failing to pay out a cash flow that a bank had been depending on to finance its own activities. So that can send that bank into bankruptcy, or leave it unable to roll over the debt of another firm, sending <em>that</em> firm into bankruptcy. This is basically what a &#8220;credit crunch&#8221; is&#8211;everybody being so indebted to everyone else, that a small economic downturn can cause a string of interlocking insolvencies&#8211;and this is pretty much the story of what has happened in the economy from 2007-present. If companies had had less debt, and financed more of their activities with equity, an economic downturn would have caused their shareholders to take an unpleasant hit, but it would not cause this contagious domino-effect of insolvency.</p>
<p>A lot of what I&#8217;ve written about firms is also true of people, except for the fact that we people don&#8217;t really have the option (yet) of getting outside equity-financing (though some are proposing to equity-finance college loans&#8211;more on this later). For example, we humans have a mortgage-interest deduction, which provides us an incentive to take out relatively larger mortgages on our homes. There are a couple of problems with this. First, since the real-estate market is in reality largely an arms-race to get into the best school district possible, people generally buy the most expensive house they can afford, and so, according to many economists, the economic value of the mortgage-interest deduction is simply capitalized in higher home prices&#8211;i.e., in the aggregate, it doesn&#8217;t provide any easing of financial burdens to homeowners at all. Second, it distorts the market for buying vs. renting property&#8211;and there&#8217;s no particularly compelling reason to do that. And third, and most importantly, as we, again, saw in the financial crisis, more debt makes it easier for you to get wiped out by even small changes in the value of your assets. Suppose bad employment prospects have made it difficult for you to make your mortgage payments&#8211;if, in addition, the value of your house has declined, leaving you &#8220;underwater,&#8221; you won&#8217;t be able to refinance your house, and so you&#8217;ll default. That will reduce the cash flow to the bank that is entitled to them which, in turn, can cause Lehman&#8230; You get the picture. So personal bankruptcies, just like company bankruptcies, are contagious, and they become likelier and more harmful the more debt we all have.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">***</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">I hope that you, gentle reader, do not spend as much time reading economics commentary as I do (because then what use would I be to you?), but one thing I&#8217;ve noticed is that almost all econ-theory minded people want to get rid of all of these distortions. Everyone seems to agree that the ideal tax reform involve lower rates, while getting rid of loopholes and deductions, such that we can actually raise more revenue, while imposing fewer distortions on the marketplace. There&#8217;s a consensus among them. But if there&#8217;s a consensus, why can&#8217;t we get some policy and legal changes done? The answer, of course, is &#8220;vested interests.&#8221; But that term sounds mean, and derogatory, and, more importantly, it understates the difficulty of our challenge.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Because, in this case, the term &#8216;vested interests&#8217; doesn&#8217;t just mean super-rich super-evil tobacco lobbyists, or some such fun-to-hate villain, but actually literally means your mom and dad. Even if your mom and dad have already finished paying off the mortgage on your house, getting rid of the mortgage-interest deduction would hurt them, because it would reduce the sale-value of their house, because it would hurt the real-estate market as a whole (since new buyers won&#8217;t get such large mortgages if they can&#8217;t write them off). And the same goes for the corporate interest deduction&#8211;if we eliminated it, a lot of medium-size firms would  lose a lot of money when they can no longer write off the interest on bonds they issued a decade or two ago. And the same goes for a lot of other loopholes:  if we get rid of the federal deduction of state income taxes, medium-high-income people in high-tax states are going to get badly hurt. All of these people were, when they made these decisions, responding rationally to the incentives our public polices had put in place. They formed rational expectations for the future based off of those expectations. They were good people doing the right thing, in the circumstances and policy landscape that they were presented with, and now the policy changes that we are proposing are going to hurt them and disrupt the life path that the old policies had led them to expect. These people are, quite justly, going to be very upset if their representatives do it.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><strong>This is why reform is hard. </strong></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Nonetheless, I&#8217;ll reiterate that we really should do the right thing and eliminate these distortions and tax loopholes if we can. It would obviously be wrong to leave bad policies in place forever. But the longer we leave them in place, the more and more good, rational, reasonable people build their lives around those policies, making them even more costly to be rid of in the future. So the very best time to take the plunge is right away.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/999/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/999/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=999&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://yourbrainonecon.wordpress.com/2012/12/07/the-debt-bias-or-how-good-reforms-do-bad-things-to-good-people/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/2cc98e89f06c4b83c183bee84df8d647?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mdsy10</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Expedia: Bad for the Traveler, Bad for the Hotel</title>
		<link>http://playazone.wordpress.com/2012/12/04/expedia-bad-for-the-traveler-bad-for-the-hotel/</link>
		<comments>http://playazone.wordpress.com/2012/12/04/expedia-bad-for-the-traveler-bad-for-the-hotel/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2012 16:25:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Tony &#38; Cheri</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Recommendations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Hotel & Bar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[expedia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fraud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hotels.com]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mexico]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://playazone.wordpress.com/?p=4158</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There is a lot of talk in the news these days about the difficulties facing small business owners around the world. Nowhere are these difficulties felt as deeply as in the travel industry. The rapid growth of the control of travel by big business with its multi-billion-dollar internet and advertising power has caused many small [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4158&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://playazone.wordpress.com/2012/12/04/expedia-bad-for-the-traveler-bad-for-the-hotel/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>79</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/59d5b4fb266a1d27d32979d9621607ac?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">playazone</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://playazone.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/fightexpediablog1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Tony &#38; Cheri owners of Luna Blue Hotel in Playa del Carmen Mexico</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://playazone.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/fightexpediablog3.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">fightexpediablog3</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://playazone.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/fightexpediablog2.jpg?w=400" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">fightexpediablog2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://playazone.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/fightexpediablog4.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">fightexpediablog4</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://playazone.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/fightexpediablog5.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">fightexpediablog5</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="https://badge.facebook.com/badge/133786885870.1732.610301680.png" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A &#8220;Predatory Teenage Girl&#8221; Speaks Out</title>
		<link>http://weekwoman.wordpress.com/2012/12/18/a-predatory-teenage-girl-speaks-out/</link>
		<comments>http://weekwoman.wordpress.com/2012/12/18/a-predatory-teenage-girl-speaks-out/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2012 19:37:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Week Woman</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Features]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Abuse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Feminism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Feminist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gender]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rape]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sexism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stereotypes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VAWG]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Victim-blaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Violence Against Women]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://weekwoman.wordpress.com/?p=1116</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The author of this post has asked to remain anonymous; she wrote it in response to Nikki McWatters&#8217;s piece, &#8220;Predatory Teenage Girls&#8220;, in the Huffington Post  When I was 15, like many teenage girls I had crushes. Not just sexual urges toward people, but platonic or intellectual ones as well. There were several girls in my school [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1116&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://weekwoman.wordpress.com/2012/12/18/a-predatory-teenage-girl-speaks-out/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>22</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/06140c8800ca238a62926d026c31333b?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">weekwoman</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://weekwoman.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/lolita.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lolita</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>On Gifts</title>
		<link>http://afrankangle.wordpress.com/2012/12/23/on-gifts-2012/</link>
		<comments>http://afrankangle.wordpress.com/2012/12/23/on-gifts-2012/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2012 01:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>aFrankAngle</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Holidays]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bloggers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christmas gifts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christmas presents]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Holiday gifts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Merry Christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Presents]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Santa Claus]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://afrankangle.wordpress.com/?p=8007</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Yes, I believe in Santa Claus, and the reason is simple – Santa Claus is a spirit of giving and kindness that transcends all cultures. This post is for Christians, Jews, Muslims, Hindus, Buddhists, secular humanists, Atheists, agnostics, and all other belief systems because this my way of saying thank you with hopes that it [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=8007&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://afrankangle.wordpress.com/2012/12/23/on-gifts-2012/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>165</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/70793a759d6de06b6be55d2f9b599ee1?s=96&#38;d=identicon" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">A Frank Angle</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://afrankangle.files.wordpress.com/2011/09/interfaithlogo.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">interfaithlogo</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://afrankangle.files.wordpress.com/2011/12/christmas-tree2.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">christmas-tree2</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Santa: Man or Woman?</title>
		<link>http://logosconcarne.com/2012/12/18/santa-man-or-woman/</link>
		<comments>http://logosconcarne.com/2012/12/18/santa-man-or-woman/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2012 23:14:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Wyrd Smythe</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[From My Collection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[men]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mr Santa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mrs Santa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ms Santa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Santa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Santa Claus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Santa female]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Santa gender]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Santa male]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://logosconcarne.com/?p=2764</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Having previously established that Santa has to be magical (because the laws of physics prohibit a real Santa accomplishing successful toy delivery), we can turn to the question of Santa&#8217;s gender. One might question this on the grounds of Santa&#8217;s apparent historic maleness, but in counter I offer George Sand, Mulan and any number of [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2764&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-2779" alt="Santas both" src="http://logosconcarne.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/santas-both.png?w=590"   /><span style="color:#000000;">Having <a style="color:#ff0000;" title="Santa Claus: Fact or Fiction?" href="http://logosconcarne.com/2012/12/16/santa-claus-fact-or-fiction/" target="_blank">previously established</a> that Santa <em>has</em> to be magical (because the laws of physics prohibit a real Santa accomplishing successful toy delivery), we can turn to the question of Santa&#8217;s gender. One might question this on the grounds of Santa&#8217;s apparent historic maleness, but in counter I offer <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/George_Sand" target="_blank">George Sand</a>, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mulan" target="_blank"><em>Mulan</em></a> and any number of Shakespeare plays.</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">One might also question this on the grounds of gender perhaps not applying to magical creatures, to which I reply that Hobbits, Elves and Dwarves seem pretty clear on the matter (although one can never really tell with Dwarves—all that hair and battle armor are quite concealing, and it&#8217;s poor form to actually <em>ask</em>).</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">In any event, like all &#8220;news&#8221; programs these days, I give you now, two opposing views on the matter of Santa&#8217;s gender. You decide.</span></p>
<p><span id="more-2764"></span></p>
<h3>Santa is a man!</h3>
<p><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-2758" alt="Santa making toys" src="http://logosconcarne.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/santa-2.png?w=590"   /><span style="color:#000000;">It is precisely because Christmas is an <em>&#8220;organized, warm, fuzzy, nurturing social deal&#8221;</em> that Santa has to be a man. Delegation… that&#8217;s the key. Just imagine if a woman was trying to delegate all of those tasks and obligations to her underlings. Christmas would be as ambiguous as the spring equinox. Nobody would know what day of the year we were going to celebrate it on.</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">It takes a man to organize a commercial event as huge as Christmas. What with the ads, the parades, the football, and the basketball, the sheer immensity of the task would overwhelm most females. We&#8217;d have to plan football schedules around lunch instead of the other way around. Or worse yet… there might not be any football at all.  [<em>shudder</em>] That&#8217;s a scary thought.</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">If Santa was a female, the toys might never be delivered. It would take a she Santa until New Year&#8217;s Eve to get dressed (for the third time) and out of the bathroom. And just try harnessing those reindeer with freshly painted nails. Never happen. Once she got underway, she&#8217;d be too busy talking on the cell phone to her girl friends to get all the way around the world to every girl and boy&#8217;s house in a single year, let alone a single night.</span></p>
<p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-2757" alt="Santa has a secret!" src="http://logosconcarne.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/santa-1.png?w=590"   /><span style="color:#000000;">If Santa was female, the whole idea of gift giving would be unrecognizable. Everybody would get socks, or ties, or aftershave, or fuzzy slippers every year. There would be none of the noise-making, shoot &#8216;em up, battery-operated windfalls that kids love. Bicycles would all come complete with helmets and knee pads. And training wheels so nobody could get hurt. Toy soldiers would be replaced by books on improving one&#8217;s self-esteem. Christmas just wouldn&#8217;t be the same.</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">I&#8217;ll tell you another reason why Santa has to be a man (<em>and</em> a football fan). Look at the names of his reindeer: Dasher, Comet, <em>Blitzen</em>… If those aren&#8217;t male names for football players, then I&#8217;m an elf!</span></p>
<hr style="color:#ff0000;height:1px;" />
<h3>Santa is a Woman!</h3>
<p><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-2781" alt="Ms Santa 1" src="http://logosconcarne.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/ms-santa-1.png?w=590"   /><span style="color:#000000;">I think Santa Claus is a woman… I hate to be the one to defy a sacred myth, but I believe he&#8217;s a she. Think about it. Christmas is a big, organized, warm, fuzzy, nurturing social deal, and I have a tough time believing a guy could possibly pull it all off!</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">For starters, the vast majority of men don&#8217;t even think about selecting gifts until Christmas Eve. Once at the mall, they always seem surprised to find only Ronco products, socket wrench sets, and mood rings left on the shelves. On this count alone, I&#8217;m convinced Santa is a woman.</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">Surely, if he were a man, everyone in the universe would wake up Christmas morning to find a rotating musical Chia Pet under the tree, still in the bag.</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">Another problem for a he-Santa would be getting there. First of all, there would be no reindeer because they would all be dead, gutted and strapped to the rear bumper of the sleigh amid wide-eyed, desperate claims that buck season had been extended. Blitzen&#8217;s rack would already be on the way to the taxidermist.</span></p>
<p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-2782" alt="Ms Santa 2" src="http://logosconcarne.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/ms-santa-2.png?w=590"   /><span style="color:#000000;">Even if the male Santa <em>did</em> have reindeer, he&#8217;d still have transportation problems because he would inevitably get lost up there in the snow and clouds and then refuse to stop and ask for directions.</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">Other reasons why Santa can&#8217;t possibly be a man:</span></p>
<ul style="color:#000000;">
<li>Men can&#8217;t pack a bag.</li>
<li>Men would rather be dead than caught wearing red</li>
<li>Men would feel their masculinity is threatened having to be seen with all those elves.</li>
<li>Men don&#8217;t answer their mail.</li>
<li>Men would refuse to allow their physique to be described even in jest as anything remotely resembling a &#8220;bowlful of jelly.&#8221;</li>
<li>Men aren&#8217;t interested in stockings unless somebody&#8217;s wearing them.</li>
<li>Having to do the Ho Ho Ho thing would seriously inhibit their ability to pick up women.</li>
<li>Finally, being responsible for Christmas would require a commitment.</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="color:#000000;"> I can buy the fact that other mythical holiday characters are men:</span></p>
<ul style="color:#000000;">
<li>Father Time shows up once a year unshaven and looking ominous; definite guy.</li>
<li>Cupid flies around carrying weapons.</li>
<li>Uncle Sam is a politician who likes to point fingers.</li>
</ul>
<p><span style="color:#000000;"> Any one of these individuals could pass the testosterone screening test. But not St. Nick. Not a chance.</span></p>
<hr style="color:#ff0000;height:1px;" />
<p><span style="color:#000000;">As with the <a style="color:#ff0000;" title="Santa Claus: Fact or Fiction?" href="http://logosconcarne.com/2012/12/16/santa-claus-fact-or-fiction/" target="_blank">previous attempt</a> to bind Santa to mere physics, I think the attempt to bind Santa to mere gender is doomed to fail.  Santa is more likely quantum and therefore both (and neither) man <em>and</em> woman!</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#000000;">And more importantly… isn&#8217;t there a little Santa in all of us?  Well, there should be. Embrace your inner Santa and be a Santa!  We&#8217;re not turning Japanese; we&#8217;re turning Santa Claus!</span><br />
<img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2784" alt="Santas many 1" src="http://logosconcarne.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/santas-many-1.png?w=590"   /><br />
<img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2785" alt="Santas many 2" src="http://logosconcarne.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/santas-many-2.png?w=590"   /></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2764/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2764/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2764&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://logosconcarne.com/2012/12/18/santa-man-or-woman/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>51</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/fe0da1ca8ba569811f1805fd4bab9f1e?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">wyrdsmythe</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://logosconcarne.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/santas-both.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Santas both</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://logosconcarne.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/santa-2.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Santa making toys</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://logosconcarne.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/santa-1.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Santa has a secret!</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://logosconcarne.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/ms-santa-1.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ms Santa 1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://logosconcarne.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/ms-santa-2.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ms Santa 2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://logosconcarne.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/santas-many-1.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Santas many 1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://logosconcarne.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/santas-many-2.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Santas many 2</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Paris Street Art: A Final Round-Up / Un Assortiment Finale</title>
		<link>http://maratinage.wordpress.com/2012/12/19/paris-street-art-a-final-round-up-un-assortiment-finale/</link>
		<comments>http://maratinage.wordpress.com/2012/12/19/paris-street-art-a-final-round-up-un-assortiment-finale/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2012 03:46:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>maratinage</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[street art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel / tourism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[art de la rue]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[paris itself]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://maratinage.wordpress.com/?p=613</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Sadly, I am leaving Paris tomorrow, and I very much doubt I&#8217;ll have time today for one of my street art seeking walks, so this will be my last post showing pictures on the subject &#8211; at least until I come back, whenever that may be. (In the meantime I may do posts on the [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=613&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_614" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 1034px"><a href="http://maratinage.wordpress.com/2012/12/19/paris-street-art-a-final-round-up-un-assortiment-finale/img_6751/" rel="attachment wp-att-614"><img src="http://maratinage.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_6751.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=764" alt="Pacman vs Tetris, by BauBô. Rue de la Main D'Or, 11ème. Dec 12, 2012." width="1024" height="764" class="size-large wp-image-614" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Pacman vs Tetris, by BauBô. Rue de la Main D&#8217;or. Dec 12, 2012.</p></div>
<p>Sadly, I am leaving Paris tomorrow, and I very much doubt I&#8217;ll have time today for one of my street art seeking walks, so this will be my last post showing pictures on the subject &#8211; at least until I come back, whenever that may be. (In the meantime I may do posts on the art in general, or on the artists I&#8217;m most interested in, but it&#8217;s less fun if I&#8217;m not taking the pictures, and it&#8217;s less fun if the pictures are dated.)</p>
<p>The news today is that, as noted in the opening ETA section of my last post, I&#8217;ve discovered &#8211; to my great delight &#8211; the artist behind the elaborate masks gracing the 11ème (after she graciously answered a query I put out about it on facebook). The artist in question is <a href="http://humanbaubo.blogspot.fr/">BauBô</a>, whose very interesting website (which incorporates essays and slam poetry among photos of her visual work) seems to indicate that she intends through her work to explore the feminine &#8211; or perhaps, more precisely, perceptions of the feminine, the tyranny of gender roles, et cetera. She&#8217;s got a particularly interesting project going on right now called <a href="http://humanbaubo.blogspot.fr/2012/11/street-art-pacman-vs-feminin-tetris.html">Pacman vs Tetris</a>, an example of which I came across in the 11ème a week or so ago (pictured above).</p>
<p>I only wish I had come across more of these, as, judging by the one pictured above and the photos on her website, they are really awesome. For one thing, from what I understand based on the site, the idea seems to be to comment on the ways girls are socialized to play &#8211; or not to play. As a life-long (female) lover of video games, I am a big, big fan of commentary along these lines (don&#8217;t get me started on the way girls in the West have been discouraged from playing video/computer games). </p>
<p>In any case, BauBô&#8217;s masks series also continues in the general vicinity of my soon-to-be-ex apartment:</p>
<div id="attachment_615" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 1034px"><a href="http://maratinage.wordpress.com/2012/12/19/paris-street-art-a-final-round-up-un-assortiment-finale/img_6707/" rel="attachment wp-att-615"><img src="http://maratinage.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_6707.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=764" alt="Masks arrangement by BauBô. Passage Saint Bernard, 11ème. Dec 11, 2012." width="1024" height="764" class="size-large wp-image-615" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Masks arrangement by BauBô. Passage Saint Bernard, 11ème. Dec 11, 2012.</p></div>
<p>As you can see, by the time I came across and photographed this grouping, it had clearly lost some of its masks in a way similar to the loss (or removal) of masks from the mandala I discussed <a href="https://maratinage.wordpress.com/2012/12/11/street-art-lacunae/">in my last post</a>. As of this afternoon it had lost yet a few more&#8230; I&#8217;ll forego putting up a picture, as I have nothing particularly new to say (or ask) on the subject, though I continue being fascinated by the ephemeral quality present here (as in all street art), the role of lack / removal, etc. I find it interesting, as well, that despite my great curiosity on the subject of what exactly is going on with the removal of these masks, I&#8217;ve avoided asking the artist what she thinks on the subject. So perhaps the mystery, the opening up of possibilities, is part of the appeal?</p>
<p>Speaking of la Rue de la Main D&#8217;Or (the place where I found the Pacman vs Tetris), I only discovered last week that it, and the neighboring Passage de la Main D&#8217;Or (former home of the &#8220;place au peuple&#8221; grouping I&#8217;ve talked about so often now) are goldmines of street art&#8230; and only a couple of blocks from my house. I <i>would</i> figure this out immediately before leaving and despite having found &#8220;place au peuple&#8221; in it *facepalm*. In any case it yielded a bunch of interesting stuff. Today, for instance, I found 3 &#8220;new&#8221; <a href="http://www.missticinparis.com/">miss.tic</a> oeuvres, all at street level and thus easy to miss:</p>
<div id="attachment_617" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 1034px"><a href="http://maratinage.wordpress.com/2012/12/19/paris-street-art-a-final-round-up-un-assortiment-finale/img_6982/" rel="attachment wp-att-617"><img src="http://maratinage.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_6982.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=764" alt="&quot;Par quel bout le prendre,&quot; miss.tic. Basically untranslatable idiom indicating an uncertainty about how to take something or someone, how to handle something, how to view it. Rue de la Main D&#039;Or, 11ème. Dec 18 2012." width="1024" height="764" class="size-large wp-image-617" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">&#8220;Par quel bout le prendre,&#8221; miss.tic. Basically untranslatable idiom indicating an uncertainty about how to take something or someone, how to handle something, how to view it. Rue de la Main D&#8217;Or, 11ème. Dec 18 2012.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_618" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 1034px"><a href="http://maratinage.wordpress.com/2012/12/19/paris-street-art-a-final-round-up-un-assortiment-finale/img_6985/" rel="attachment wp-att-618"><img src="http://maratinage.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_6985.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=764" alt="&quot;La nuit tous les chants sont cris,&quot; miss.tic [&quot;at night all songs are screams&quot;]. Rue de la Main D&#039;Or, 11ème. Dec 18 2012. Miss.tic seems to like cats. " width="1024" height="764" class="size-large wp-image-618" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">&#8220;La nuit tous les chants sont cris,&#8221; miss.tic ["at night all songs are screams"]. Rue de la Main D&#8217;Or, 11ème. Dec 18 2012. Miss.tic seems to like cats.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_619" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 774px"><a href="http://maratinage.wordpress.com/2012/12/19/paris-street-art-a-final-round-up-un-assortiment-finale/img_7033/" rel="attachment wp-att-619"><img src="http://maratinage.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_7033.jpg?w=764&#038;h=1024" alt="&quot;Bricole moi un été,&quot; miss.tic. [&quot;Bricoler&quot; is very hard to translate. Sentence roughly means &quot;Build me a summer.&quot;] Passage de la Main D&#039;Or, 11ème. Dec 18 2012." width="764" height="1024" class="size-large wp-image-619" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">&#8220;Bricole moi un été,&#8221; miss.tic. ["Bricoler" is very hard to translate. Sentence roughly means "Build me a summer."] Passage de la Main D&#8217;Or, 11ème. Dec 18 2012.</p></div>
<p>I&#8217;m intrigued by the fact that every miss.tic piece I&#8217;ve seen has been at or very near street level &#8211; I had to kneel to take all three of those photos. Why? A fair bit of street art is very low down (and even more is very high up), but the stuff I see low to the ground isn&#8217;t usually this elaborate. Miss.tic&#8217;s pieces also seem to always be sprayed on the walls of businesses &#8211; nearly always under the front windows &#8211; and I have a hunch a few are there with the owners&#8217; permission; certainly I have a sense of their being more permanent in some way than most of the street art I see. What&#8217;s the story here? Miss.tic has been around since the mid-80s; is it a form of respectability?</p>
<p>The Passage is currently sporting a massive mash-up by many artists &#8211; it&#8217;s clearly a place, like the little square on my street, where this is commonly the case. The mash-up (which has changed since last week) was impossible to photograph all at once, but here&#8217;re my best attempts. First, the east wall, which seems to consist largely of one (&#8220;one&#8221;) work with multiple authors, &#8220;Mustafukaz tribute&#8221;:</p>
<div id="attachment_622" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 1034px"><a href="http://maratinage.wordpress.com/2012/12/19/paris-street-art-a-final-round-up-un-assortiment-finale/img_6759/" rel="attachment wp-att-622"><img src="http://maratinage.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_6759.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=764" alt="&quot;Mustafukaz tribute,&quot; as was written to the left (and is called as much on multiple sites with photos of this). It seems to have been executed by Codex Urbanus and Bastek, with a notable contribution by toctoc in the recessed area. Dec 12 &#039;12. " width="1024" height="764" class="size-large wp-image-622" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">&#8220;Mustafukaz tribute,&#8221; as was written to the left (and is called as much on multiple sites with photos of this). It seems to have been executed by Codex Urbanus and Bastek, with a notable contribution by toctoc in the recessed area. Dec 12 &#8217;12.</p></div>
<p><a href="http://www.mutafukaz.com/"><i>Mustafukaz</i></a> seems to be a bande déssinée, but I&#8217;m not familiar with it and thus don&#8217;t understand the references. I do know that the diamond-shaped pieces up at the top (the alien for instance) are signature <a href="https://www.facebook.com/Bastek.Artist">Bastek</a> works (check out that link for, among other things, pictures of the tribute new and in better shape). <a href="http://codexurbanus.tumblr.com/">Codex Urbanus</a> seems to do a lot of animal figures and is, I assume, responsible for the cockroaches. (On a side note, my appalling cockroach phobia, normally set off even by depictions of them, is not triggered if they&#8217;re multicolored. Who knew?)</p>
<p>I was pleased to find, inside the tribute, the remains of <a href="https://www.facebook.com/toctoc.streetart">toctoc</a>&#8216;s Frankenstein figure, created in honor of Hallowe&#8217;en along with his Chucky figure and the figure from Scream that I&#8217;ve already posted:</p>
<div id="attachment_623" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 774px"><a href="http://maratinage.wordpress.com/2012/12/19/paris-street-art-a-final-round-up-un-assortiment-finale/img_6807/" rel="attachment wp-att-623"><img src="http://maratinage.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_6807.jpg?w=764&#038;h=1024" alt="Frankenstein by toctoc, Passage de la Main D&#039;Or. Created in October; photographed Dec 12 &#039;12." width="764" height="1024" class="size-large wp-image-623" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Frankenstein by toctoc, Passage de la Main D&#8217;Or. Created in October; photographed Dec 12 &#8217;12.</p></div>
<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/hogreman/">Hogre</a> (who it turns out is mostly based in Rome) had weighed in at some point, turning the tribute into a mash-up:</p>
<div id="attachment_625" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 774px"><a href="http://maratinage.wordpress.com/2012/12/19/paris-street-art-a-final-round-up-un-assortiment-finale/img_6803/" rel="attachment wp-att-625"><img src="http://maratinage.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_6803.jpg?w=764&#038;h=1024" alt="&quot;In music we trust.&quot; Hogre. Passage de la Main D&#039;Or. Dec 12 &#039;12." width="764" height="1024" class="size-large wp-image-625" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">&#8220;In music we trust.&#8221; Hogre. Passage de la Main D&#8217;Or. Dec 12 &#8217;12.</p></div>
<p>High up on the wall was (and still is) a figure by a mosaicist (I don&#8217;t know who it is &#8211; yet) who has put up several very cool works of this kind in that intersection:</p>
<div id="attachment_627" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 774px"><a href="http://maratinage.wordpress.com/2012/12/19/paris-street-art-a-final-round-up-un-assortiment-finale/img_6813/" rel="attachment wp-att-627"><img src="http://maratinage.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_6813.jpg?w=764&#038;h=1024" alt="Mosaic figure, artist unknown. Passage de la Main D&#039;Or. Dec 12 &#039;12." width="764" height="1024" class="size-large wp-image-627" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Mosaic figure, artist unknown. Passage de la Main D&#8217;Or. Dec 12 &#8217;12.</p></div>
<p>Other figures by the same artist are scattered nearby, often difficult to see because they&#8217;re fairly small and usually high up:</p>
<p><a href="http://maratinage.wordpress.com/2012/12/19/paris-street-art-a-final-round-up-un-assortiment-finale/img_6824/" rel="attachment wp-att-628"><img src="http://maratinage.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_6824.jpg?w=764&#038;h=1024" alt="IMG_6824" width="764" height="1024" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-628" /></a></p>
<div id="attachment_629" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 774px"><a href="http://maratinage.wordpress.com/2012/12/19/paris-street-art-a-final-round-up-un-assortiment-finale/img_6992/" rel="attachment wp-att-629"><img src="http://maratinage.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_6992.jpg?w=764&#038;h=1024" alt="Mosaic figure, artist unknown. Rue de la Main D&#039;Or. Dec 18 &#039;12." width="764" height="1024" class="size-large wp-image-629" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Mosaic figure, artist unknown. Rue de la Main D&#8217;Or. Dec 18 &#8217;12.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_630" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 774px"><a href="http://maratinage.wordpress.com/2012/12/19/paris-street-art-a-final-round-up-un-assortiment-finale/img_6999/" rel="attachment wp-att-630"><img src="http://maratinage.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_6999.jpg?w=764&#038;h=1024" alt="Another mosaic figure, this one either more abstract or partially destroyed, artist unknown. Rue de la Main D&#039;Or. Dec 18 &#039;12." width="764" height="1024" class="size-large wp-image-630" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Another mosaic figure, this one either more abstract or partially destroyed, artist unknown. Rue de la Main D&#8217;Or. Dec 18 &#8217;12.</p></div>
<p>Then there&#8217;s the south wall of the tiny square, which is, if possible, even more covered in graffiti/art, some of it reaching all the way up the building (I&#8217;m always impressed when they manage to cover such broad surfaces so high up). Space Invader and a Gzup octopus feature in the mash-up:</p>
<div id="attachment_631" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 774px"><a href="http://maratinage.wordpress.com/2012/12/19/paris-street-art-a-final-round-up-un-assortiment-finale/img_6773/" rel="attachment wp-att-631"><img src="http://maratinage.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_6773.jpg?w=764&#038;h=1024" alt="Space Invader; crowned octopus by Gzup; rest by unknown artist(s). Dec 12 &#039;12." width="764" height="1024" class="size-large wp-image-631" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Space Invader; crowned octopus by Gzup; rest by unknown artist(s). Dec 12 &#8217;12.</p></div>
<p>On the 12th, sign language was featured underneath the above mash-up (I have no idea who the artist is for this either, or what the message is, if there is one):</p>
<div id="attachment_632" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 1034px"><a href="http://maratinage.wordpress.com/2012/12/19/paris-street-art-a-final-round-up-un-assortiment-finale/img_6777/" rel="attachment wp-att-632"><img src="http://maratinage.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_6777.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=764" alt="Artist unknown. Rue de la Main D&#039;Or. Dec 12 &#039;12." width="1024" height="764" class="size-large wp-image-632" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Artist unknown. Rue de la Main D&#8217;Or. Dec 12 &#8217;12.</p></div>
<p>There was also this rather unusual artifact (gone as of the 18th), painted on a piece of newspaper glued to a torn-off piece of cardboard attached to a pole:</p>
<p><a href="http://maratinage.wordpress.com/2012/12/19/paris-street-art-a-final-round-up-un-assortiment-finale/img_6821/" rel="attachment wp-att-633"><img src="http://maratinage.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_6821.jpg?w=764&#038;h=1024" alt="IMG_6821" width="764" height="1024" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-633" /></a></p>
<p>I&#8217;ve also discovered, thanks to his papering of the square near my apartment, the graffitist <a href="http://jpmgraffiti.e-monsite.com/">JPM</a> (JP Morvan), whose work seems to be concentrated around celebrating graffiti itself. As a huge comics geek I was delighted to see this tribute (unfortunately already gone) to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Becassine">Becassine,</a> the first female comic strip heroine (of one of the first comic strips):</p>
<div id="attachment_634" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 774px"><a href="http://maratinage.wordpress.com/2012/12/19/paris-street-art-a-final-round-up-un-assortiment-finale/img_6562/" rel="attachment wp-att-634"><img src="http://maratinage.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_6562.jpg?w=764&#038;h=1024" alt="&quot;Bk&#039;sin la graffeuse,&quot; JPM (who to my delight has included a shout-out to Pinchon, her creator). Rue de la Forge Royale, Dec 2 &#039;12." width="764" height="1024" class="size-large wp-image-634" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">&#8220;Bk&#8217;sin la graffeuse,&#8221; JPM (who to my delight has included a shout-out to Pinchon, her creator). Rue de la Forge Royale, Dec 2 &#8217;12.</p></div>
<p>Other JPM works gracing the wall, some of which are still there:</p>
<div id="attachment_635" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 1034px"><a href="http://maratinage.wordpress.com/2012/12/19/paris-street-art-a-final-round-up-un-assortiment-finale/img_6647/" rel="attachment wp-att-635"><img src="http://maratinage.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_6647.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=764" alt="&quot;Les couleurs explosent sur les murs&quot; [colors explode on the walls], JPM. Rue de la Forge Royale, Dec 11 &#039;12." width="1024" height="764" class="size-large wp-image-635" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">&#8220;Les couleurs explosent sur les murs&#8221; [colors explode on the walls], JPM. Rue de la Forge Royale, Dec 11 &#8217;12.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_636" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 774px"><a href="http://maratinage.wordpress.com/2012/12/19/paris-street-art-a-final-round-up-un-assortiment-finale/img_6651/" rel="attachment wp-att-636"><img src="http://maratinage.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_6651.jpg?w=764&#038;h=1024" alt="&quot;Coutellier,&quot; JPM (a play on someone&#039;s name and the word for &quot;knife-grinder&quot;). Rue de la Forge Royale, Dec 11 &#039;12." width="764" height="1024" class="size-large wp-image-636" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">&#8220;Coutellier,&#8221; JPM (a play on someone&#8217;s name and the word for &#8220;knife-grinder&#8221;). Rue de la Forge Royale, Dec 11 &#8217;12.</p></div>
<p>(The above is rather confusing &#8211; it appears to be a reference to someone named Philippe Coutellier, who appears to be a friend of JPM&#8217;s but may or may not be a street artist himself. The internet is not always very helpful, is it?)</p>
<p>Then there was a really rather awesome, if quite busy, mash-up on the same wall, some of which has been taken down in the week since:</p>
<div id="attachment_638" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 1034px"><a href="http://maratinage.wordpress.com/2012/12/19/paris-street-art-a-final-round-up-un-assortiment-finale/img_6642/" rel="attachment wp-att-638"><img src="http://maratinage.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_6642.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=764" alt="Mash-up by Paddy, JPM, toctoc, Lomozano, and the unknown exclamation point artist. Dec 11 &#039;12." width="1024" height="764" class="size-large wp-image-638" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Mash-up by Paddy, JPM, toctoc, Lomozano, and Maxime Aum. Rue de la Forge Royale, Dec 11 &#8217;12.</p></div>
<p>Here I give Paddy props for the woman with the machine gun; I may not be a fan of his figures taking selfies, but this image kinda rocks. And something about the mash-up, busy as it is, works for me. It&#8217;s vibrant. I do wish I knew who was putting up all the cartoons featuring exclamation points &#8211; the internet isn&#8217;t helping me with that either.</p>
<p>[ETA 12/22/12: The "Exclamation point artist" has turned out to be <a href="http://www.onewalltoanother.com/index.php?p=thumbs&amp;cat=maxime-aum">Maxime Aum</a>. Hooray for the internet after all!]</p>
<p>Here we have two of the six or seven of the Maxime Aum works on my block hanging out with the pink bear by K I mentioned in <a href="https://maratinage.wordpress.com/2012/11/29/paris-street-art-nouveautes-new-stuff/">my last smorgasbord post</a>:</p>
<div id="attachment_639" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 1034px"><a href="http://maratinage.wordpress.com/2012/12/19/paris-street-art-a-final-round-up-un-assortiment-finale/img_6675/" rel="attachment wp-att-639"><img src="http://maratinage.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_6675.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=764" alt="Two exclamation points hanging out with one of K&#039;s teddy bears. Rue de la Forge Royale, Dec 11 &#039;12." width="1024" height="764" class="size-large wp-image-639" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Two exclamation points hanging out with one of K&#8217;s teddy bears. Rue de la Forge Royale, Dec 11 &#8217;12.</p></div>
<p>[edited 12/21/12] (I won&#8217;t post now all the pictures I have of the exclamation points cartoons, which I see more and more, but I may do later posts on specific artists, including Maxime Aum.) [/edited]</p>
<p>Back to Passage Saint-Bernard. Currently there&#8217;s this, unsigned. It&#8217;s one of 2-3 pieces I&#8217;ve spotted lately that look like miss.tic&#8217;s style but which I either can tell (due to the signature) or strongly suspect are not by her:</p>
<div id="attachment_641" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 1034px"><a href="http://maratinage.wordpress.com/2012/12/19/paris-street-art-a-final-round-up-un-assortiment-finale/img_6693/" rel="attachment wp-att-641"><img src="http://maratinage.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_6693.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=764" alt="&quot;Vendez moi du rêve!&quot; [sell me dreams!] Artist unknown, Passage Saint Bernard, Dec 11 &#039;12." width="1024" height="764" class="size-large wp-image-641" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">&#8220;Vendez moi du rêve!&#8221; [sell me dreams!] Artist unknown, Passage Saint Bernard, Dec 11 &#8217;12.</p></div>
<p>There&#8217;s also this small tile installation up on one wall, which seems to have been written on by several different people and which I can&#8217;t make heads or tails of:</p>
<div id="attachment_642" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 1034px"><a href="http://maratinage.wordpress.com/2012/12/19/paris-street-art-a-final-round-up-un-assortiment-finale/img_6697/" rel="attachment wp-att-642"><img src="http://maratinage.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_6697.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=764" alt="Colored tiles, artist unknown. Passage Saint Bernard, Dec 11 &#039;12." width="1024" height="764" class="size-large wp-image-642" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Colored tiles, artist unknown. Passage Saint Bernard, Dec 11 &#8217;12.</p></div>
<p>In other news, a feminist (and apparently lesbian) graffitist likes to spray-paint political statements on the sidewalk Rue de Charonne. For example:</p>
<div id="attachment_643" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 1034px"><a href="http://maratinage.wordpress.com/2012/12/19/paris-street-art-a-final-round-up-un-assortiment-finale/img_6737/" rel="attachment wp-att-643"><img src="http://maratinage.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_6737.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=764" alt="&quot;Gouine banale,&quot; graffitist unknown. Rue de Charonne. Dec 12 &#039;12." width="1024" height="764" class="size-large wp-image-643" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">&#8220;Gouine banale,&#8221; graffitist unknown. Rue de Charonne. Dec 12 &#8217;12.</p></div>
<p>I&#8217;m not sure that fits into the category of street art &#8211; whatever &#8220;street art&#8221; means &#8211; but I rather like seeing these around.</p>
<p>Finally, for now (as I said, I may post on this again even once I&#8217;m back in the states), I&#8217;ll end with FatCat, whose whimsical little drawings/tags cheer me up (though they never seem to last more than a couple of days):</p>
<div id="attachment_644" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 1034px"><a href="http://maratinage.wordpress.com/2012/12/19/paris-street-art-a-final-round-up-un-assortiment-finale/img_6731/" rel="attachment wp-att-644"><img src="http://maratinage.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_6731.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=764" alt="&quot;FatCat wishes you a good day,&quot; signed ACBS. Rue de Charonne, Dec 12 &#039;12." width="1024" height="764" class="size-large wp-image-644" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">&#8220;FatCat wishes you a good day,&#8221; signed ACBS. Rue de Charonne, Dec 12 &#8217;12.</p></div>
<p>And that&#8217;s it (again, at least for now). I leave Paris in less than 36 hours, to go back to a place with no street art beyond some tagging (and tagging tends to profoundly bore me). I have to admit that losing the street art scene &#8211; its ever-changing-ness, its providing jolts of interest or joy in otherwise tiring or dull days, its freshness, its changing the face of the city day to day &#8211; losing it, I was saying, is a major part of my current distress around leaving. I just discovered that I love this stuff, and I live on a street with galleries devoted to street art that I never even had time to check out (I just found out I missed a showing this very Saturday)&#8230; eh, I suppose c&#8217;est la vie. I am a French citizen; I can come back, if I find a way to live. And maybe there&#8217;s a way to stay involved in the scene from afar, if only by enviously trolling other websites. But still&#8230; I&#8217;ll miss taking my walks and spotting new Space Invaders and toctocs and Gzups and miss.tics and BauBôs and Ks and Soldats Inconnus and all the work by all the amazing artists combing this city. Goodbye for now, Paris street art.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/613/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/613/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=613&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://maratinage.wordpress.com/2012/12/19/paris-street-art-a-final-round-up-un-assortiment-finale/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>12</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/8c73eccd0cb2edc64540c9a9ffd0fb7a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">maratinage</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://maratinage.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_6751.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Pacman vs Tetris, by BauBô. Rue de la Main D&#039;Or, 11ème. Dec 12, 2012.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://maratinage.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_6707.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Masks arrangement by BauBô. Passage Saint Bernard, 11ème. Dec 11, 2012.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://maratinage.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_6982.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">&#34;Par quel bout le prendre,&#34; miss.tic. Basically untranslatable idiom indicating an uncertainty about how to take something or someone, how to handle something, how to view it. Rue de la Main D&#039;Or, 11ème. Dec 18 2012.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://maratinage.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_6985.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">&#34;La nuit tous les chants sont cris,&#34; miss.tic [&#34;at night all songs are screams&#34;]. Rue de la Main D&#039;Or, 11ème. Dec 18 2012. Miss.tic seems to like cats. </media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://maratinage.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_7033.jpg?w=764" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">&#34;Bricole moi un été,&#34; miss.tic. [&#34;Bricoler&#34; is very hard to translate. Sentence roughly means &#34;Build me a summer.&#34;] Passage de la Main D&#039;Or, 11ème. Dec 18 2012.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://maratinage.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_6759.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">&#34;Mustafukaz tribute,&#34; as was written to the left (and is called as much on multiple sites with photos of this). It seems to have been executed by Codex Urbanus and Bastek, with a notable contribution by toctoc in the recessed area. Dec 12 &#039;12. </media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://maratinage.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_6807.jpg?w=764" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Frankenstein by toctoc, Passage de la Main D&#039;Or. Created in October; photographed Dec 12 &#039;12.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://maratinage.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_6803.jpg?w=764" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">&#34;In music we trust.&#34; Hogre. Passage de la Main D&#039;Or. Dec 12 &#039;12.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://maratinage.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_6813.jpg?w=764" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mosaic figure, artist unknown. Passage de la Main D&#039;Or. Dec 12 &#039;12.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://maratinage.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_6824.jpg?w=764" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_6824</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://maratinage.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_6992.jpg?w=764" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mosaic figure, artist unknown. Rue de la Main D&#039;Or. Dec 18 &#039;12.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://maratinage.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_6999.jpg?w=764" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Another mosaic figure, this one either more abstract or partially destroyed, artist unknown. Rue de la Main D&#039;Or. Dec 18 &#039;12.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://maratinage.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_6773.jpg?w=764" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Space Invader; crowned octopus by Gzup; rest by unknown artist(s). Dec 12 &#039;12.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://maratinage.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_6777.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Artist unknown. Rue de la Main D&#039;Or. Dec 12 &#039;12.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://maratinage.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_6821.jpg?w=764" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_6821</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://maratinage.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_6562.jpg?w=764" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">&#34;Bk&#039;sin la graffeuse,&#34; JPM (who to my delight has included a shout-out to Pinchon, her creator). Rue de la Forge Royale, Dec 2 &#039;12.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://maratinage.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_6647.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">&#34;Les couleurs explosent sur les murs&#34; [colors explode on the walls], JPM. Rue de la Forge Royale, Dec 11 &#039;12.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://maratinage.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_6651.jpg?w=764" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">&#34;Coutellier,&#34; JPM (a play on someone&#039;s name and the word for &#34;knife-grinder&#34;). Rue de la Forge Royale, Dec 11 &#039;12.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://maratinage.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_6642.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mash-up by Paddy, JPM, toctoc, Lomozano, and the unknown exclamation point artist. Dec 11 &#039;12.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://maratinage.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_6675.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Two exclamation points hanging out with one of K&#039;s teddy bears. Rue de la Forge Royale, Dec 11 &#039;12.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://maratinage.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_6693.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">&#34;Vendez moi du rêve!&#34; [sell me dreams!] Artist unknown, Passage Saint Bernard, Dec 11 &#039;12.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://maratinage.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_6697.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Colored tiles, artist unknown. Passage Saint Bernard, Dec 11 &#039;12.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://maratinage.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_6737.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">&#34;Gouine banale,&#34; graffitist unknown. Rue de Charonne. Dec 12 &#039;12.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://maratinage.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/img_6731.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">&#34;FatCat wishes you a good day,&#34; signed ACBS. Rue de Charonne, Dec 12 &#039;12.</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Subculture Responds to ‘Goth Loner’ Accusation Over Adam Lanza Tragedy</title>
		<link>http://theblogginggoth.wordpress.com/2012/12/18/subculture-responds-to-goth-loner-accusation-over-adam-lanza-tragedy/</link>
		<comments>http://theblogginggoth.wordpress.com/2012/12/18/subculture-responds-to-goth-loner-accusation-over-adam-lanza-tragedy/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2012 18:07:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tychoanomaly</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[interview]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[response]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[subculture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[violence]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://theblogginggoth.wordpress.com/?p=19</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The Mail on Sunday&#8217;s front page from 16th December 2012 There are three factors which define my response this story. I am a human being, a Goth, and a Journalist. As a human being, I abhor and reject the horrific violence committed in Newton, Connecticut. As a Goth, I abhor and reject any association with [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=19&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://theblogginggoth.wordpress.com/2012/12/18/subculture-responds-to-goth-loner-accusation-over-adam-lanza-tragedy/18253_453152691411151_490996263_n/" rel="attachment wp-att-20"><img class="size-medium wp-image-20 aligncenter" alt="18253_453152691411151_490996263_n" src="http://theblogginggoth.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/18253_453152691411151_490996263_n.png?w=225&#038;h=300" width="225" height="300" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><em>The Mail on Sunday&#8217;s front page from 16th December 2012</em></p>
<p>There are three factors which define my response this story. I am a human being, a Goth, and a Journalist.<br />
As a human being, I abhor and reject the horrific violence committed in Newton, Connecticut. As a Goth, I abhor and reject any association with my subculture, and fear the demonizing effect of headlines like this. As a journalist, I abhor and reject the kind of &#8216;journalism&#8217; that has led the Daily Mail to such knee-jerk reactionary headline writing. The Goth tag has been attached to <a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-2248645/Nancy-Lanza-Mother-murderer-Adam-Lanza-avid-gun-collector-taught-sons-use-firearms.html#ixzz2FQ8yifA7" target="_blank">this story</a> because of the following quote:</p>
<blockquote><p>Catherine Urso, who was attending a vigil Friday evening in Newtown said her college-age son knew the killer and remembered him for his alternative style.</p>
<p>&#8216;He just said he was very thin, very remote and was one of the goths,&#8217; she said.</p></blockquote>
<p>A second-hand recollection from someone not even involved. The implication is that the world is struggling to try and understand what could motivate such a crime, and the Daily Mail &#8211; with characteristic unfeeling insensitivity &#8211; has chosen a marginalized and misunderstood group to &#8216;take the blame&#8217;. Ironically, the Mail has previously written about <a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-2063122/Attacked-goth-Thugs-stamped-Melodys-face-times--looked.html" target="_blank">attacks on Goths</a> in a supportive light, especially the tragic case of <a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-1017121/Jailed-life-Binge-drinking-feral-thugs-kicked-death-gap-year-student-dressed-Goth.html" target="_blank">Sophie Lancaster</a> who was killed in an unprovoked assault in 2007. Since then her mother and others have worked tirelessly to promote diversity and tolerance; the S.O.P.H.I.E. charity <a href="https://www.facebook.com/thesophielancasterfoundation/posts/10151200655853871" target="_blank">released a statement</a> in response on Sunday:</p>
<blockquote>
<div></div>
<div>The demonisation of subcultures, in this case goth/gamer/alternative does nothing to help anyone understand why Adam Lanza woke up on Thursday and killed 20 people including his own Mother. Our frustration at this lazy journalism, where they are quoting distraught ex pupils and neighbours because they have no facts is made worse by the fact that the readers of the articles may well believe what they see and not challenge it, leading to yet more prejudice and fear.</div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="http://tychoanomaly.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/978-1-86189-301-7-frontcover.jpg"><img class="alignleft" id="i-98" alt="Image" src="http://tychoanomaly.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/978-1-86189-301-7-frontcover.jpg?w=268&#038;h=377" width="268" height="377" /></a>Crucially, the Daily Mail failed to interview any representatives from the Goth subculture about their reactions. All responses, including what you are reading now, have been self-motivated &#8211; because for some reason, the majority of the mainstream media of the <a href="http://www.thesun.co.uk/sol/homepage/article4700544.ece" target="_blank">United Kingdom</a> and<a href="http://www.foxnews.com/us/2012/12/15/conn-gunman-recalled-as-intelligent-but-remote/" target="_blank"> the United States</a> will not give us a voice.<a href="http://www.lancashiretelegraph.co.uk/news/10112091.Mum_of_murdered_teenager_Sophie_Lancaster_slams_US_killer_s__goth__label/" target="_blank"> Notable exceptions exist</a> amongst unbiased, regional media but the large part the Goth culture is sorely unrepresented in the press. When we are portrayed, observes <a href="http://www.lancs.ac.uk/fass/english/profiles/Catherine-Spooner/" target="_blank">Dr Catherine Spooner</a> of Lancaster University (author of several social studies of the Goth culture), it is through a veil of journalistic interpretation.</p>
<blockquote>
<div>‘Goth’ is sometimes used in high school slang as an insult or as shorthand for kids perceived as outsiders or weirdos, regardless of whether or not they self-identify as Goths or have any affiliations with the Goth scene. By labelling Lanza as a Goth on the basis of hearsay, apparently objective journalism ‘fixes’ this loose, slang use of the term, converting it into a firm evocation of a specific subculture and identity.<br />
Many readers will not discern that this process of fixing has taken place, and therefore this loose term takes on the status of ‘official’ knowledge: Lanza was a Goth and Goths are weirdos and outsiders.</div>
<div></div>
<div>It goes without saying that the evidence for the former is flimsy and the latter becomes self-fulfilling for those doing the labelling. This may seem a minor detail beside the larger fact of the tragedy. But scapegoating Goths is not going to help matters and may, in fact, cause further harm.</div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
</blockquote>
<p>This view is concurred by <a href="http://www.surrey.ac.uk/sociology/people/paul_hodkinson/" target="_blank">Dr Paul Hodkinson</a> of Surrey University &#8211; another social scientist &#8211; who expands on the newspaper relationship with the<a href="http://tychoanomaly.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/51ycnavhctl-_sl500_aa300_.jpg"><img class="alignright" id="i-93" alt="Image" src="http://tychoanomaly.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/51ycnavhctl-_sl500_aa300_.jpg?w=312&#038;h=312" width="312" height="312" /></a> Goth Culture.</p>
<blockquote><p>Newspapers like to develop familiar stories with familiar characters and will sometimes filter the information available in order to do so. So the reason they have picked up on use of the word ‘goth’ here is that, for them, it acts as the perfect narrative device to render the killer as deviant, different, other – external to normal society and not one of ‘us’ – and imagined ‘normal society’.</p>
<div></div>
<div>Paradoxically, however, the reference to things like goth may also serve to enable the development of a different angle of engagement, based on engaging the fears of parents  and others over the possible links between dark subcultures their own children may have contact with and this sort of violence.</div>
<div></div>
</blockquote>
<p>In our discussion, I asked Dr Hodkinson if he could expand on this &#8216;different angle&#8217;, in terms of the fears being developed by parents of Goths now faced with the possibility of association between this crime, and their own children. He responded:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8230;there is  little evidence of any link to the goth scene and, even if there were, there’s certainly no evidence that the goth scene would encourage anyone to behave in such a way. In this article the term goth really has been put into the headline here purely as a means of drawing in more readers for the reasons I previously gave. They don’t even purport to be presenting a serious article about the dangers of the goth scene – they’ve just mentioned the term because it embellishes the profile and makes good copy.</p>
<p>Overall, it seems clear that the labelling of him as a goth is based on minimal evidence. More importantly, the issue of whether he identified as a goth, a gamer, a nerd or anything similar is almost certainly irrelevant to determining the cause of the horrible events that took place.</p></blockquote>
<p>I questioned Dr Hodkinson&#8217;s conviction that, in the face of the beliefs broadcast by the Daily Mail, The Sun and the FOX Network, any motivation for Lanza&#8217;s murder-spree could not include his subcultural associations.</p>
<blockquote><p>I think what I’d briefly say is that there is no evidence that they have a negative influence of the kind discussed. Millions of people are goths, gamers, ‘geeks’ etc across the world. Aside from anecdotal speculation in relation to the occasional isolated incident such as this, I’m not aware of any evidence that, amongst these millions of people, there is any substantial problem with violence. In the case of goths, evidence points towards an emphasis in the values of the group towards non-violence and, as I’m sure you know, goths are much more likely to be the subject of violent attack than the perpetrators of violence.</p></blockquote>
<p><a href="http://tychoanomaly.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bwr2.jpg"><img class="alignleft" id="i-111" alt="Image" src="http://tychoanomaly.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bwr2.jpg?w=230&#038;h=303" width="230" height="303" /></a>As mentioned above this has been the case, with the stories of assaults on Goths as reported by both the Daily Mail and <a href="http://www.thesun.co.uk/sol/homepage/news/justice/1098999/Teenagers-to-face-sentence-for-murder-of-goth-Sophie-Lancaster-in-Bacup-Lancashire.html" target="_blank">The Sun</a>. This time however, the reporting of these two papers has been met with disbelief, sadness and hostility by the culture. Well-known DJ and promoter <a href="http://www.martinoldgoth.co.uk/" target="_blank">Martin &#8216;Oldgoth&#8217; Coles</a> responded:</p>
<blockquote><p>One passing comment about him being a loner &#8216;like the goths&#8217;, has been seized upon and used, in my opinion, maliciously by two of the UK biggest &#8216;news&#8217; papers (The Sun and Mail) purely in order to create a shock headline.</p></blockquote>
<p>Martin observes some of the underlying issues that have surrounded other tragic shootings which have lacked any &#8216;Goth&#8217; angle.</p>
<blockquote><p>If you read about his background, and in particular his day to day behaviour it just points to the fact that what the US [needs] is not only tighter gun control &#8211; to prevent things like assault rifles being obtained so easily (who really needs one to &#8216;defend&#8217; themselves or their property?) &#8211; but better mental health care. I firmly believe that had this guy been given proper treatment then this would never have happened, and it helps to highlight that so people get the help they need.</p></blockquote>
<p>He firmly believes that the media&#8217;s performance is crucial to understanding crimes like these.</p>
<blockquote><p>The media has fueled this kind of thing, 100%, and I feel is totally to blame for sensationalising the idea that doing this will have you going out in a &#8216;blaze of glory&#8217;, with all the worldwide fame that comes with it.</p></blockquote>
<p>Concluding firmly, Martin states:</p>
<blockquote><p>This guy did not attack anyone because of the music he listened to, he resorted to murder as never got the help he needed and had easy access to lethal weapons in a world where violence of this kind makes you famous, gets you noticed in a world that I&#8217;m sure he thought didn&#8217;t care.</p></blockquote>
<p><a href="http://tychoanomaly.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/photo-credit-holly-fairclough.jpg"><img class="aligncenter" id="i-133" alt="Image" src="http://tychoanomaly.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/photo-credit-holly-fairclough.jpg?w=301&#038;h=443" width="301" height="443" /></a></p>
<p>I also e-mailed Rosie Garland, better known as<a href="http://www.rosielugosi.com/wp/" target="_blank"> Rosie Lugosi</a> &#8211; singer with legendary Eighties dark rock band <a href="http://www.marchviolets.co.uk/" target="_blank">The March Violets</a>, as well as an award-winning poet, author, and sought-after compère. Her prompt response to my questions about her feelings on the reporting simply said:</p>
<blockquote><p>So &#8211; the Leveson Enquiry into improving press standards is clearly having a massive effect on the tabloids.</p></blockquote>
<p>The <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.ca/liisa-ladouceur/adam-lanza-goth_b_2316144.html" target="_blank">Goth community online has united</a> to <a href="http://louderthanwar.com/why-is-connecticut-killer-adam-lanza-being-called-the-goth-killer/" target="_blank">condemn the portrayal of the culture</a> by headlines like this. The quotes used above were taken from responses gained within hours of publication by the Daily Mail and other outlets, none of whom had researched the scene or interviewed any relevant commentators. An <a href="http://db.tt/Cd54L8kh" target="_blank">e-mail to the Daily Mail asking for comment</a> to be used in this article remains unanswered after a day, in comparison. Should a response be received, this article will be updated accordingly.</p>
<p>The Goth culture so rarely hits the headlines for the best reasons. In this case, blame has been laid at a subculture&#8217;s door when no proof has been obtained &#8211; an act that goes beyond &#8216;lazy&#8217; journalism and into the realms of downright dangerous.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/19/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/19/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=19&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://theblogginggoth.wordpress.com/2012/12/18/subculture-responds-to-goth-loner-accusation-over-adam-lanza-tragedy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>45</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/5d77cba8909b28572f554fa2fbc293d3?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tychoanomaly</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theblogginggoth.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/18253_453152691411151_490996263_n.png?w=225" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">18253_453152691411151_490996263_n</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tychoanomaly.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/978-1-86189-301-7-frontcover.jpg?w=404" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tychoanomaly.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/51ycnavhctl-_sl500_aa300_.jpg?w=290" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tychoanomaly.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bwr2.jpg?w=490" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tychoanomaly.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/photo-credit-holly-fairclough.jpg?w=580" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Day Two in Bhutan: This is Life</title>
		<link>http://compassandcamera.wordpress.com/2012/12/18/day-2-in-bhutan-this-is-life/</link>
		<comments>http://compassandcamera.wordpress.com/2012/12/18/day-2-in-bhutan-this-is-life/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2012 23:12:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Compass&#38;Camera</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Experience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beauty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vacation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bhutan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adventure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photo Essay]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://compassandcamera.wordpress.com/?p=2233</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Our second day in Bhutan began with breakfast at the hotel and a drive up the mountainside near Thimphu. Fin was taking us to see Bhutan&#8217;s sitting Buddha &#8212; what will soon be the largest sitting Buddha in the world at nearly 170 feet tall. Bhutan is so small, and yet this Buddha is SO [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2233&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0121.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-2286 aligncenter" title="The Sitting Buddha" alt="The Sitting Buddha" src="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0121.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Our second day in Bhutan began with breakfast at the hotel and a drive up the mountainside near Thimphu. Fin was taking us to see Bhutan&#8217;s sitting Buddha &#8212; what will soon be the largest sitting Buddha in the world at nearly 170 feet tall. Bhutan is so small, and yet this Buddha is SO big &#8212; facing east, overlooking the valley and enormous in scale as you begin to approach it. The mountainside has been carved away and flattened out, with a massive expanse of concrete where the Buddha sits at the west side. The Buddha emanates good energy and happiness to everything in the vicinity.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan013.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2235" alt="The Sitting Buddha" src="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan013.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>Construction of the sitting Buddha is an exercise in international cooperation &#8212; funded by a Singaporean, constructed by Indians, with metal work completed by Chinese and land supplied by Bhutan. The project was started about six years ago and is nearing completion, although quite a bit later than expected. The Buddha was created in China and shipped to Bhutan in pieces, where it has been welded together on site.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0141.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-2300 aligncenter" title="The Sitting Buddha" alt="The Sitting Buddha" src="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0141.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>The cone-shaped third eye at the forehead is five feet across and encrusted with diamonds. The hair is deep sapphire blue, the face with well-defined features and a gaze that looks past you toward the edge of the mountain. In the Bhutanese sun, the entire Buddha glows brightly against the sky.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan015.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2237" alt="The Sitting Buddha" src="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan015.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0161.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2304" alt="Thimphu" src="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0161.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>From the site of the sitting Buddha there&#8217;s a terrific view of Thimphu, the capital of Bhutan. From here, we were headed across town to the hillside on the north side of the city to do a morning hike at Sangaygang.</p>
<p><a href="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0171.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2306" alt="Sangaygang" src="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0171.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>The hillside at Sangaygang has been joyfully overtaken with prayer flags strewn in every direction. From here, the trail climbs steeply up and leads to several monasteries and meditation sites in the hills.</p>
<p><a href="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0181.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2307" alt="Sangaygang" src="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0181.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>The current king&#8217;s residence, Samtenling Palace, isn&#8217;t far from here &#8212; we were able to get a glimpse through the trees. According to Fin, the fourth and former king (Jigme Singye Wangchuck or K4, as he&#8217;s known) is 57 years old and enjoys mountain biking on this trail. No wonder &#8212; it&#8217;s great single track with wide open views of the valley. Bhutan definitely has the terrain to become a world-class mountain biking destination of the future.</p>
<p><a href="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0191.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2308" alt="Wangditse Goemba" src="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0191.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>At the top of the hill we reached Wangditse Goemba, founded around 1750. A large prayer wheel stands at the south side, with prayer flags staked along the edge of the site.</p>
<p><a href="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0201.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2309" alt="Wangditse Goemba" src="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0201.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan021.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2243" alt="Sangaygang" src="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan021.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>All over Bhutan, groups of 108 tall white prayer flags mark significant locations and memorialize people who have passed away. In Mahayana Buddhism, 108 is an auspicious number referencing 108 volumes of the Kangyur &#8212; a collection of the words of the Buddha. White prayer flags symbolize air, while blue, red, green and yellow symbolize space, fire, water and earth. Traditionally, mantras were printed on prayer flags with wood blocks. Wind spreads the peace, goodwill and blessings of prayer flags to everyone and everything around them.</p>
<p><a href="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0221.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2310" alt="Sangaygang" src="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0221.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan023.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2245" alt="The Takin" src="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan023.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>From Sangaygang, we drove down the hill and stopped to see Bhutan&#8217;s national animal &#8212; the takin. Thimphu has a takin preserve (free admission), with fenced acreage on which they can roam with barking deer. Takins are strange looking animals. Legend has it they were created when Bhutan&#8217;s Divine Madman put the head of a goat on the body of a cow and brought his new creation to life.</p>
<p><a href="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0451.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2311" alt="Bhutanese architecture" src="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0451.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>A new building at the takin preserve will open someday as a museum and visitors center. It was amazing to see such beautiful new architecture, with ornamental spirit and exquisite hand-painted detail. Traditional artistry is very clearly valued, preserved and passed on throughout Bhutan.</p>
<p><a href="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0461.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2312" alt="Handpainted exterior" src="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0461.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0471.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2313" alt="Land of the Thunder Dragon" src="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0471.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0241.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2314" alt="Weaving scarves at the Takin Preserve" src="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0241.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>Departing the takin preserve, we stopped to watch this young woman weaving on a loom. She displayed stacks and stacks of colorful raw silk and cotton scarves she had created while overseeing the entrance to the preserve. I picked up a little souvenir for myself.</p>
<p><a href="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0251.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2315" alt="Thimphu Royal Golf Club" src="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0251.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>Back on the road, we drove into downtown Thimphu for lunch, passing the Royal Thimphu Golf Club along the way. Quite a few golfers were out on the course enjoying the sunshine amidst a few deep water hazards.</p>
<p>We ate lunch on the top floor of a building downtown &#8212; fried dumplings, buckwheat noodles, potatoes, vegetables and the usual Bhutanese chili-cheese combo. Fin, owner of <a title="Bridge to Bhutan" href="http://www.bridgetobhutan.com/" target="_blank">Bridge to Bhutan</a> who had accompanied us for our first 24 hours in Bhutan, introduced us to our official guide and driver who would take us from there. We were sad to see Fin go, but Kinga and Kumar were fun, well-educated companions from whom we would learn even more about life in Bhutan.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan026.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2248" alt="Thimphu Post Office" src="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan026.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>After lunch, Kinga and Kumar escorted us to the bank and the post office &#8212; the latter being well worth a stop on anyone&#8217;s itinerary. Bhutan has a rich history of stamp production, with elaborate and beautiful stamps from the past several decades celebrating everything from Olympic sports to aviation to Bhutanese folk lore to butterflies of Bhutan. Best of all, you can have your photo taken and printed on Bhutanese stamps you can use on the post cards you send home! So cool! Check the mail, mom, but it might take a few weeks.</p>
<p><a href="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0271.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2317" alt="Jungshi Handmade Paper Factory" src="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0271.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>After the post office, we were off on an afternoon tour of Thimphu which started with the Jungshi Handmade Paper Factory. Housed in a one-story white building, the operation begins outside where fibers are soaked, boiled and cooled, then dumped in a heap on a table inside.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan028.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2250" alt="Jungshi Handmade Paper Factory" src="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan028.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan029.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2251" alt="Jungshi Handmade Paper Factory" src="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan029.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan030.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2252" alt="Jungshi Handmade Paper Factory" src="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan030.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan030a1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2318" alt="The grinder" src="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan030a1.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>The fibers are processed into pulp using an old grinder. The pulp is poured into a sink where it&#8217;s spread onto a screen, then the screen is lifted out and the paper is placed in a stack where it releases water and dries into sheets.</p>
<p><a href="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0311.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2319" alt="Spreading the pulp" src="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0311.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0321.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2320" alt="Lifting the sheet" src="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0321.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0331.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2321" alt="Aligning the edge" src="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0331.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0341.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2322" alt="Laying the paper" src="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0341.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan035.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2257" alt="Jungshi Handmade Paper Factory" src="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan035.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>When dry, the paper is hung up one piece at a time, brushed off and stamped with a logo. Jungshi has a small paper shop on site where you can buy the paper, posters and journals they produce.</p>
<p><a href="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0371.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2323" alt="Archery competition" src="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0371.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>Leaving the paper factory, we made an impromptu stop at an archery range where an afternoon competition was taking place. In retrospect, the 20 minutes we spent here is one of my favorite memories from the entire trip. Archery is Bhutan&#8217;s national sport, practiced with great enthusiasm all over the country.</p>
<p>About two dozen archers were at the north and south ends of the archery range which was 140 meters long. (What a VAST distance to cover with a traditional bow and arrow, not to mention the tiny target which is about the size of a dinner plate.) Archers at the south end of the range took turns shooting while archers at the north end stood behind concrete walls, out of danger, waiting to see if their arrows hit the target. When the archers at the south end had finished, the archers at the north end similarly took their shots.</p>
<p>When we arrived, an archer at the south end had just hit the target near us which brought about a synchronized &#8220;dance&#8221; with singing and shouting by all the archers at the north end of the field. Quite a production, no doubt steeped in years and years of tradition.</p>
<p><a href="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0381.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2324" alt="Archery competition" src="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0381.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>After the dance, the archers at the north end took turns shooting their arrows. Ready, aim, fire&#8230; then they each waited for shouts and hollers to see if they scored.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan039.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2261" alt="Archery Competition" src="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan039.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan040.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2262" alt="Archery Competition" src="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan040.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0411.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2325" alt="Archery competition" src="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0411.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>If I ever return to Bhutan, I hope to spend more time watching archery. It&#8217;s fun, spirited and pretty incredible to see these sharp shooters in action, even as an occasional dog wanders in front of the target. Just two Bhutanese athletes competed in the 2012 Olympic games &#8212; both female, and one of them in archery. It&#8217;s a sport loved by men and women alike.</p>
<p><a href="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0421.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2327" alt="Trashi Chhoe Dzong" src="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0421.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>The sun was setting and that was our cue to get to the Trashi Chhoe Dzong for the changing of the guard &#8212; newly implemented since last year&#8217;s wedding of King and Queen Wangchuck. We walked to the far end of the dzong where soldiers were assembling to march out and lower Bhutan&#8217;s flag.</p>
<p><a href="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0431.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2328" alt="Trashi Chhoe Dzong" src="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0431.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0441.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2329" alt="Changing of the Guard" src="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0441.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>In a ceremony that lasted about 15 minutes (I&#8217;m hoping to get video up soon!), a monk led the procession from the dzong to the flag, then the flag was lowered, rolled, carried inside and stowed until the next morning.</p>
<p>I reflected on the day&#8217;s events over dinner at the hotel. We had canvassed Thimphu from morning to dusk, capturing many moments of daily life in Bhutan that didn&#8217;t seem all that different from my own life: hiking, golf, archery, paper making, the post office and bank, a dzong, the takins and one big, giant Buddha (okay, that part was very different). It was all foreign, yet not unfamiliar. Fascinating, yet similar. Strangers, yet people who are just like me and you. It was a day of adventure for sure, yet just an ordinary day in the life of Bhutan.</p>
<p><a title="Day One in Bhutan: Surprise, Surprise" href="http://compassandcamera.wordpress.com/2012/12/12/day-1-in-bhutan-surprise-surprise/"><em>Click here to read Day One in Bhutan: Surprise, Surprise</em></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2233/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2233/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2233&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://compassandcamera.wordpress.com/2012/12/18/day-2-in-bhutan-this-is-life/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>87</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0341.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0341.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Laying the paper</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/e67f1ff39ecff54b6008045f7aae9337?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">compassandcamera</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0121.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The Sitting Buddha</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan013.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The Sitting Buddha</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0141.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The Sitting Buddha</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan015.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The Sitting Buddha</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0161.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Thimphu</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0171.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Sangaygang</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0181.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Sangaygang</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0191.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Wangditse Goemba</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0201.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Wangditse Goemba</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan021.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Sangaygang</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0221.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Sangaygang</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan023.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The Takin</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0451.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Bhutanese architecture</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0461.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Handpainted exterior</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0471.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Land of the Thunder Dragon</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0241.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Weaving scarves at the Takin Preserve</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0251.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Thimphu Royal Golf Club</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan026.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Thimphu Post Office</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0271.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Jungshi Handmade Paper Factory</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan028.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Jungshi Handmade Paper Factory</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan029.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Jungshi Handmade Paper Factory</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan030.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Jungshi Handmade Paper Factory</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan030a1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The grinder</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0311.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Spreading the pulp</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0321.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Lifting the sheet</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0331.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Aligning the edge</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0341.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Laying the paper</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan035.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Jungshi Handmade Paper Factory</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0371.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Archery competition</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0381.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Archery competition</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan039.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Archery Competition</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan040.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Archery Competition</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0411.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Archery competition</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0421.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Trashi Chhoe Dzong</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0431.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Trashi Chhoe Dzong</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://compassandcamera.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bhutan0441.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Changing of the Guard</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Challenge of Eating ‘Less’ But \&#8217;Better’</title>
		<link>http://madeinkachchh.wordpress.com/2012/12/18/the-challenge-of-eating-less-but-better/</link>
		<comments>http://madeinkachchh.wordpress.com/2012/12/18/the-challenge-of-eating-less-but-better/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2012 12:28:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jérémie</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Kachchh]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kutch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photo blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photo Essay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Storytelling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bhujodi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Handloom Weaving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tradition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Weaving]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://madeinkachchh.wordpress.com/?p=325</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A visit to a village of weavers, this sunny sunday morning, made me think a lot and I want to share this experience with you. Bhujodi, a small village about ten kilometers east of Bhuj is inhabited by several craftsmen who specialize in hand-loom weaving. Besides the fact that artisans welcomed us to their homes as [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=325&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A visit to a village of weavers, this sunny sunday morning, made me think a lot and I want to share this experience with you. Bhujodi, a small village about ten kilometers east of Bhuj is inhabited by several craftsmen who specialize in hand-loom weaving. Besides the fact that artisans welcomed us to their homes as if we were family, they shared their knowledge with passion and without a second thought about selling anything to us.</p>
<p><a href="http://madeinkachchh.wordpress.com/2012/12/18/312/weaving05/" rel="attachment wp-att-317"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-317" alt="weaving05" src="http://madeinkachchh.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/weaving05.jpg?w=590"   /></a>First we meet Narayan-bhai and his son. They specialize in the manufacture of woollen carpets. Today it is a bit special, they are preparing for Diwali, the Indian New Year, so are coating the walls of their home with a mixture of mud, lime and cow-dung.</p>
<p><a href="http://madeinkachchh.wordpress.com/2012/12/18/312/weaving08/" rel="attachment wp-att-320"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-320" alt="weaving08" src="http://madeinkachchh.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/weaving08.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>However seeing our excitement to watch the looms work, they settle down at their looms and start weaving a carpet. Although I&#8217;ve seen weaving work before, I am fascinated! Beyond the technical moves that are impressive, the complexity and beauty of the machine leaves me speechless. All these lines, these regular movements, these colors &#8230; create an atmosphere that is truly mesmerizing!</p>
<p>They have 2 looms, fully manual. The one that Naryanbhai uses</p>
<p><a href="http://madeinkachchh.wordpress.com/2012/12/18/312/weaving01/" rel="attachment wp-att-313"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-313" alt="weaving01" src="http://madeinkachchh.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/weaving01.jpg?w=590"   /></a>and the other handled by his son:</p>
<p><a href="http://madeinkachchh.wordpress.com/2012/12/18/312/weaving02/" rel="attachment wp-att-314"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-314" alt="weaving02" src="http://madeinkachchh.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/weaving02.jpg?w=590"   /></a>My wife and I sit there for a long time just watching them work. Most of their production is for a client from Finland! They take about 1 day to make 1 carpet.</p>
<p><a href="http://madeinkachchh.wordpress.com/2012/12/18/312/weaving03/" rel="attachment wp-att-315"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-315" alt="weaving03" src="http://madeinkachchh.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/weaving03.jpg?w=590"   /></a>They are proud to show that they have designed a carpet with three different types of wool: camel, black sheep and white sheep.</p>
<p><a href="http://madeinkachchh.wordpress.com/2012/12/18/312/weaving04/" rel="attachment wp-att-316"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-316" alt="weaving04" src="http://madeinkachchh.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/weaving04.jpg?w=590"   /></a>They say they love the creative side of their craft, but do not have enough time to truly experiment since they need to produce carpets for the Finnish which are large orders and are always the same : gray and white&#8230;&#8221;european tastes!&#8221; they say.</p>
<p>And then there is Purushothambhai. If you can read the name correctly the first time you win a silk shawl <img src='http://s0.wp.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif' alt=':)' class='wp-smiley' />  We had not even planned to visit his home, he catches us on the streets and says &#8220;come and see, I have something to show you.&#8221;</p>
<p><a href="http://madeinkachchh.wordpress.com/2012/12/18/312/weaving10/" rel="attachment wp-att-322"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-322" alt="weaving10" src="http://madeinkachchh.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/weaving10.jpg?w=590"   /></a>He begins by showing us a series of very finely woven shawls with a mixture of silk and cotton, then take us to his loom. It is much narrower than Naryanbhai because it is used to make scarves and shawls but it is equally impressive.</p>
<p><a href="http://madeinkachchh.wordpress.com/2012/12/18/312/weaving07/" rel="attachment wp-att-319"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-319" alt="weaving07" src="http://madeinkachchh.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/weaving07.jpg?w=590"   /></a> The thread is much thinner, and the weaving takes longer. Depending on the type of pattern, a piece can take up to 1 month. The method for doing this kind of pattern is inexplicable in writing, it has been a good half an hour to figure out how he is doing it! Purushothambhai is first and foremost an artist, he creates his own designs, his own forms &#8230; He sells his works everywhere in India, at exhibitions and events related to crafts.</p>
<p><a href="http://madeinkachchh.wordpress.com/2012/12/18/312/weaving09/" rel="attachment wp-att-321"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-321" alt="weaving09" src="http://madeinkachchh.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/weaving09.jpg?w=590"   /></a>He tells us this moving story of how he once set off to create his &#8220;best&#8221; piece, he had already given three months of hardwork into it and while it was still on the loom and nearly complete, an insect ate into it. This piece hence will never get sold. But will remain with him to tell his story.</p>
<p><a href="http://madeinkachchh.wordpress.com/2012/12/18/the-challenge-of-eating-less-but-better/weaving11/" rel="attachment wp-att-327"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-327" alt="weaving11" src="http://madeinkachchh.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/weaving11.jpg?w=590"   /></a>To be able to feel the connection between knowledge and the product is really a unique experience, it gives a new perspective on the value of things.</p>
<p>&#8220;The industrial era&#8221; helped us make a bunch of objects accessible in large numbers and at a price much more affordable than products that are &#8220;handmade&#8221;. This is what allows us to not have to save for two months to buy a pair of trousers, that I personally find quite handy &#8230; However, this &#8220;progress&#8221; has totally engulfed our concept of the &#8220;value&#8221; of things.</p>
<p>There is little or no information on the conditions under which the products we use are made, by whom, with what, with what impact on the environment and on society more generally. Take the time to take this step to &#8220;understand&#8221; a product, to look at it differently and go back again to the challenge of <i>eating &#8220;less&#8221; but &#8220;better&#8221;.</i></p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://madeinkachchh.wordpress.com/category/kachchh/'>Kachchh</a>, <a href='http://madeinkachchh.wordpress.com/category/kutch/'>Kutch</a>, <a href='http://madeinkachchh.wordpress.com/category/photo-blog/'>Photo blog</a>, <a href='http://madeinkachchh.wordpress.com/category/photo-essay/'>Photo Essay</a>, <a href='http://madeinkachchh.wordpress.com/category/photography/'>Photography</a>, <a href='http://madeinkachchh.wordpress.com/category/storytelling/'>Storytelling</a>, <a href='http://madeinkachchh.wordpress.com/category/travel/'>Travel</a> Tagged: <a href='http://madeinkachchh.wordpress.com/tag/bhujodi/'>Bhujodi</a>, <a href='http://madeinkachchh.wordpress.com/tag/handloom-weaving/'>Handloom Weaving</a>, <a href='http://madeinkachchh.wordpress.com/tag/kachchh/'>Kachchh</a>, <a href='http://madeinkachchh.wordpress.com/tag/kutch/'>Kutch</a>, <a href='http://madeinkachchh.wordpress.com/tag/photo-blog/'>Photo blog</a>, <a href='http://madeinkachchh.wordpress.com/tag/tradition/'>Tradition</a>, <a href='http://madeinkachchh.wordpress.com/tag/travel/'>Travel</a>, <a href='http://madeinkachchh.wordpress.com/tag/weaving/'>Weaving</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/325/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/325/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/325/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/325/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/325/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/325/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/325/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/325/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/325/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/325/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/325/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/325/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/325/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/325/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=325&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://madeinkachchh.wordpress.com/2012/12/18/the-challenge-of-eating-less-but-better/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>50</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c213be0d7aa917e78756358e23034c00?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F0.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jegaudin</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://madeinkachchh.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/weaving05.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">weaving05</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://madeinkachchh.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/weaving08.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">weaving08</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://madeinkachchh.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/weaving01.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">weaving01</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://madeinkachchh.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/weaving02.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">weaving02</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://madeinkachchh.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/weaving03.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">weaving03</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://madeinkachchh.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/weaving04.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">weaving04</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://madeinkachchh.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/weaving10.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">weaving10</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://madeinkachchh.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/weaving07.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">weaving07</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://madeinkachchh.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/weaving09.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">weaving09</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://madeinkachchh.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/weaving11.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">weaving11</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>I Can Write.</title>
		<link>http://andsmilestogobeforeiweep.wordpress.com/2012/12/11/i-can-write/</link>
		<comments>http://andsmilestogobeforeiweep.wordpress.com/2012/12/11/i-can-write/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2012 11:12:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>notadamselindistress</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[On the patience of paper.]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stars I Have Fathomed Into Constellations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[endorphin high]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[epiphany]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[literary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[literature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[memoir]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[memoirs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nanowrimo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[national novel writing month]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[novel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[paper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thoughts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://andsmilestogobeforeiweep.wordpress.com/?p=504</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[So, as you may know (if you&#8217;ve been keeping up with my previous posts), just last month, I finished writing a novel. And by finished writing a novel, I mean that I spend a bit under thirty days haphazardly dashing down almost 60 thousand words vaguely forming a plot that could be considered a cohesive [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=504&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://andsmilestogobeforeiweep.wordpress.com/2012/12/11/i-can-write/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>148</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/2f1034740ff6a4d21bbe4c12b6acda10?s=96&#38;d=retro&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">notadamselindistress</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
