<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2013 21:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>My Fountain of Youth</title>
		<link>http://javaj240.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/my-fountain-of-youth/</link>
		<comments>http://javaj240.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/my-fountain-of-youth/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 21:47:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>javaj240</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Aging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aging gracefully]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ambling & Rambling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bullshit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cleaning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[funny]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gray hair]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[middle age]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[midlife bloggers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Fountain of Youth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[absurd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[appearance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bullshit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Clairol]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Emmylou Harris]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Florida]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[getting old]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gray hair]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grey hair]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hair dye]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jamie Leigh Curtis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[L'Oreal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[midlife]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nice 'n Easy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pepe LePew]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ponce de Leon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Roseanne Roseannadanna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Grim Reaper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[youth]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://javaj240.wordpress.com/?p=2404</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Ponce de Leon thought, upon arriving in St. Augustine, Florida, that he had discovered the &#8220;Fountain of Youth&#8221;. Senor de Leon would undoubtedly be shocked to discover that Florida has become NOT the place to maintain one&#8217;s youth but, instead and for many, the final destination before the grave. It&#8217;s a veritable &#8220;hot spot&#8221; for [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2404&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><div id="attachment_2397" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 290px"><a href="http://javaj240.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/fountainofyouth.jpg"><img src="http://javaj240.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/fountainofyouth.jpg?w=280&#038;h=180" alt="Ponce de Leon and The Fountain of Youth" width="280" height="180" class="size-full wp-image-2397" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Ponce de Leon and The Fountain of Youth</p></div>Ponce de Leon thought, upon arriving in St. Augustine, Florida, that he had discovered the &#8220;Fountain of Youth&#8221;. Senor de Leon would undoubtedly be shocked to discover that Florida has become NOT the place to maintain one&#8217;s youth but, instead and for many, the final destination before the grave. It&#8217;s a veritable &#8220;hot spot&#8221; for The Grim Reaper! Why should he haul that heavy scythe all over creation when he can knock off, in a manner of speaking, most of his &#8220;to-do&#8221; list with a short jaunt to sunny Florida? I have no personal experience with The GR myself, but one would think that, having made his career in the business of death throughout the whole history of humankind, he would appreciate the kind of one-stop shopping and increased productivity that a place like Florida would afforded him.</p>
<p>I have been giving this whole idea of a more youthful appearance a great deal of thought lately. I have been toying with the idea of disposing of the boxes of hair dye that are currently taking up space in my closet. These boxes are my own version of &#8220;The Fountain of Youth&#8221;. You didn&#8217;t really think I was going to write about Ponce de Leon and The Grim Reaper, did you? </p>
<p>I&#8217;ve been graying since my twenties. It&#8217;s hereditary. My father had a full head of gray hair by the time he was forty. He likes to blame it on having four daughters, but we know better now. Studies have shown that gray hair, like baldness, hirsuteness, and most other physical (and mental) characteristics, are marked on our DNA. In other words, many of us are just plain doomed by our faulty genetics.</p>
<p>No one wants to be &#8220;marked&#8221; as old at the age of twenty-five. And, let&#8217;s be honest, gray hair is synonymous with old age. Nothing, and I mean nothing, screams &#8220;you&#8217;re aging!&#8221; quite like gray hair. Unlike losing one&#8217;s hair or having so much body hair that one could be mistaken in the dark for a Sasquatch, those of us who suffer from premature graying can just throw a box of hair dye into our shopping carts and painlessly (unless you get it in your eye!) and fairly quickly, solve the problem. Unlike our hairless or our excessively hairy friends, we don&#8217;t need daily doses of expensive prescription salves to halt our hair loss; we don&#8217;t need to subject our bodies to painful waxes or electrolysis treatments to rid ourselves of the extra coat of fur that our prehistoric ancestors needed for warmth but that is now, here in the 21st Century, just plain unsightly. I suppose, put in perspective, those of us whose afflictions can be solved with a six-dollar box of hair dye have it relatively easy.</p>
<p>At some point, usually by the time we reach our forties, graying ceases to be &#8220;premature&#8221; and gives way to just plain graying. Our friends and coworkers catch up to those of us who have suffered long and, usually, in silence. I knew this was the case when, beginning a few years ago, I could not run into one of my cohorts in the grocery store, the drug store, or, even the local Target, without spying the box of hair dye in their shopping cart. If I looked closely, (and I did!) I could almost always find it &#8212; usually hidden amongst other necessities like eggs, anti-perspirant, or that cute pair of trendy flats! (Why they thought they needed to engage in shopping cart subterfuge, I&#8217;ll never know.) </p>
<p>Sure, there are always a few women who don&#8217;t buy into covering up their graying locks. These women, generally speaking, tend to fall into two categories. They are either the bland and dowdy types who shop for the few cosmetics that they carelessly apply (only on special occasions!) at the dollar store (even I don&#8217;t buy make-up at the dollar store!) or they are the environmentally-conscious health food nuts who wouldn&#8217;t dream of putting chemicals on their heads (so close to their brains!). Either way, they&#8217;re not &#8220;my peeps&#8221;. These women are definitely NOT the ones with the leopard-print flats in their Target cart. More likely, they&#8217;re hiding things like support hose or flax seed oil in those bright red baskets. I&#8217;m no statistician, but I would, based on my own vast experience, go out on a limb and make the claim that these fortyish hair dye eschewing/support hose wearing/flax seed ingesting consumers are the exception, not the rule! </p>
<p>Lately, though, I have been thinking more and more about joining them. No. I haven&#8217;t taken up granola-crunching, but I did, just recently, begin a flax seed regimen (because of my dry eyes!). You won&#8217;t find me shopping for outdated Maybelline at the dollar store anytime soon and I think I&#8217;ll hold off on the support hose, at least for a few more years, but it may be time to throw in the towel where the hair dye is concerned. It&#8217;s become, quite frankly, a very time, energy, and money sucking battle with the bottle &#8212; one that I am, by the way, losing. (Already having lost one battle with the bottle, I simply may not have it in me to lose another!)  </p>
<p>Part of the reason I haven&#8217;t, thus far, just done it already is because I am, and I&#8217;m not ashamed to admit this, vain. I don&#8217;t want to look older than I already am. I don&#8217;t consider forty-seven to be all that old, but it&#8217;s not all that young either. While I certainly understand that age is relative, I also work in a very youthful environment. At the end of a long shift I have a tendency to grow tired and lose my patience. On some level we all do, regardless of our ages, but my fear is that IF I stop dying my hair I will be perceived NOT just as fatigued and exasperated, but as old and cranky. I&#8217;m not saying that I&#8217;m NOT old and cranky. I&#8217;m saying that I don&#8217;t want OTHER people, YOUNGER people (who, by the way, I can still run circles around) to perceive me as such. </p>
<p>The other decision that I must make, IF I decide to stop dyeing my hair, is whether to dye my whole prodigious head of hair gray or to cut off the rather large and very long portion of my hair that is still brownish (as a result of various bottles of Miss Clairol, L&#8217;Oreal, or whatever brand was on sale). I know that the &#8220;ombre&#8221; look is &#8220;in&#8221;, but the gray on the top, brown on the bottom variation that I am currently sporting is more &#8220;two-tone&#8221; than it is &#8220;ombre&#8221;. I love Pepe LePew as much as the next gal. I do not, however, want to LOOK like him. (Nor would I want to smell like him, but that&#8217;s a whole other subject!) In order to avoid this &#8212; the looking like Pepe, NOT the smelling like Pepe &#8212; I must choose between two styles: The Jamie Leigh Curtis or The Emmylou Harris. </p>
<p>Jamie Leigh manages her style because she has such fine bone structure and because, let&#8217;s face it, she&#8217;s thin. Thin, successful actresses can wear almost any hairstyle. Emmylou pulls it off because she&#8217;s a musician. Those musicians can get away with almost anything. Also, she&#8217;s got the aging hippie thing going on. That doesn&#8217;t hurt. I am neither thin nor successful. I&#8217;m not Hollywood royalty, nor am I a world-renowned singer-songwriter. While I like to think of myself as a free spirit, it&#8217;s safe to say that no one would ever describe me as a hippie (or, come to think of it, hip). </p>
<p><div id="attachment_2394" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 210px"><a href="http://javaj240.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/jackiegray1-e1363727732656.jpg"><img src="http://javaj240.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/jackiegray1-e1363727732656.jpg?w=200&#038;h=280" alt="Me! Or, Pepe --- you decide!" width="200" height="280" class="size-full wp-image-2394" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Me! Or, Pepe &#8212; you decide!</p></div><br />
<div id="attachment_2393" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 210px"><a href="http://javaj240.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/jaimeleighcurtis-e1363727531758.jpg"><img src="http://javaj240.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/jaimeleighcurtis-e1363727531758.jpg?w=200&#038;h=278" alt="Jamie Leigh --- look at that chin! I&#039;d kill for that chin!" width="200" height="278" class="size-full wp-image-2393" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Jamie Leigh &#8212; look at that chin! I&#8217;d kill for that chin!</p></div><br />
<div id="attachment_2392" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 210px"><a href="http://javaj240.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/emmylouharris1.jpg"><img src="http://javaj240.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/emmylouharris1.jpg?w=200&#038;h=133" alt="Emmylou --- she&#039;s not dowdy at all!" width="200" height="133" class="size-full wp-image-2392" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Emmylou &#8212; she&#8217;s not dowdy at all!</p></div></p>
<p>So, it&#8217;s a dilemma. To dye or not to dye. To cut or not to cut. Maybe I should just move to Florida now. I could shave my head and invest in a couple of wigs. Because I don&#8217;t even want to get into with you what tropic-like humidity does to my hair. I know. I know. Florida is not &#8220;technically&#8221; the tropics, but still &#8212; two words spring to mind: Roseanne Roseannadanna.  </p>
<div id="attachment_2402" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 210px"><a href="http://javaj240.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/roseanneroseannadanna-e1363728929495.jpg"><img src="http://javaj240.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/roseanneroseannadanna-e1363728929495.jpg?w=200&#038;h=150" alt="My hair + humidity = Roseanne Roseannadanna" width="200" height="150" class="size-full wp-image-2402" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">My hair + humidity = Roseanne Roseannadanna</p></div>
<p>photo credits:<br />
<a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=the+fountain+of+youth&amp;hl=en&amp;source=lnms&amp;tbm=isch&amp;sa=X&amp;ei=ydVIUY-YO6Hi4APx8IC4Cg&amp;sqi=2&amp;ved=0CAcQ_AUoAQ&amp;biw=1600&amp;bih=775#imgrc=NNO4KHyiVnunIM%3A%3BcnrtXknYLL37QM%3Bhttp%253A%252F%252Famericancountryside.com%252Fwp-content%252Fgems%252F2011%252F04%252Fponcedeleon.jpg%3Bhttp%253A%252F%252Famericancountryside.com%252F2011%252F04%252F08%252Fin-search-of-the-fountain-of-youth%252F%3B528%3B340" target="_blank">The Fountain of Youth</a><br />
Me<br />
<a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=emmylou+harris&amp;hl=en&amp;biw=1600&amp;bih=775&amp;source=lnms&amp;tbm=isch&amp;sa=X&amp;ei=JdNIUcCQMOS30gGHpIHIAQ&amp;sqi=2&amp;ved=0CAcQ_AUoAQ#imgrc=sXgYbrBAH6gH_M%3A%3BVLCJfwua_WQqMM%3Bhttp%253A%252F%252Fcps-static.rovicorp.com%252F3%252FJPG_250%252FMI0003%252F423%252FMI0003423465.jpg%253Fpartner%253Dallrovi.com%3Bhttp%253A%252F%252Fwww.allmusic.com%252Fartist%252Femmylou-harris-mn0000159699%3B250%3B167" target="_blank">Emmylou</a><br />
<a href="http://inyourface.blog.ocregister.com/2008/06/23/jamie-lee-curtis-reveals-her-struggles-with-plastic-surgery-drugs-aging/" target="_blank">Jamie Leigh</a><br />
<a href="http://www.tumblr.com/tagged/roseanne%20roseannadanna?before=45" target="_blank">Roseanne Roseannadanna</a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2404/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2404/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2404&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://javaj240.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/my-fountain-of-youth/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>21</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/526726815989c03bd896ecebb496719e?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">javaj240</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://javaj240.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/fountainofyouth.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ponce de Leon and The Fountain of Youth</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://javaj240.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/jackiegray1-e1363727732656.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Me! Or, Pepe --- you decide!</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://javaj240.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/jaimeleighcurtis-e1363727531758.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Jamie Leigh --- look at that chin! I&#039;d kill for that chin!</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://javaj240.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/emmylouharris1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Emmylou --- she&#039;s not dowdy at all!</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://javaj240.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/roseanneroseannadanna-e1363728929495.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">My hair + humidity = Roseanne Roseannadanna</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why the Higgs Matters, In A Few Sentences</title>
		<link>http://profmattstrassler.com/2013/03/20/why-the-higgs-matters-in-a-few-sentences/</link>
		<comments>http://profmattstrassler.com/2013/03/20/why-the-higgs-matters-in-a-few-sentences/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 12:38:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Matt Strassler</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Higgs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Public Outreach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LHC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[press]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PublicPerception]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://profmattstrassler.com/?p=5686</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[One of the big challenges facing journalists writing about science is to summarize a scientific subject accurately, clearly and succinctly. Sometimes one of the three requirements is sacrificed, and sadly, it is often the first one. So here is my latest (but surely not last) attempt at an accurate, succinct, and maybe even clear summary [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=5686&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One of the big challenges facing journalists writing about science is to summarize a scientific subject accurately, clearly and succinctly. Sometimes one of the three requirements is sacrificed, and sadly, it is often the first one.</p>
<p>So here is my latest (but surely not last) attempt at an accurate, succinct, and maybe even clear summary of why the Higgs business matters so much.</p>
<p><strong>`True&#8217; Statements about the Higgs</strong></p>
<p>True means &#8220;as true as anything compressed into four sentences can possibly be&#8221; &#8212; i.e., very close to true.  For those who want to know where I&#8217;m cutting important corners, a list of caveats will follow at the end of the article.</p>
<ul>
<li>Our very existence depends upon the Higgs field, which pervades the universe and gives elementary particles, including electrons, their masses.  Without mass, electrons could not form atoms, the building blocks of our bodies and of all ordinary matter.</li>
<li>Last July&#8217;s discovery of the Higgs particle is exciting because it confirms that the Higgs field really exists.  Scientists hope to learn much more about this still-mysterious field through further study of the Higgs particle.</li>
</ul>
<p>Is that so bad? These lines are almost 100% accurate&#8230; I&#8217;m sure an experienced journalist can cut and adjust and amend them to make them sound better and more exciting, but are they really too long and unclear to be useable?</p>
<p><strong>Some False Statements about the Higgs<span id="more-5686"></span></strong></p>
<p>Meanwhile I would like to suggest we avoid the following statements, or anything like them.</p>
<ul>
<li>The Higgs field and/or the Higgs particle were crucial to the Big Bang. <em>[On the contrary, there's no evidence that the Big Bang would have been stymied in the absence of the Higgs field and particle, or of anything directly related to them... despite <a title="Why, Professor Kaku? Why?" href="http://profmattstrassler.com/2013/03/19/why-professor-kaku-why/">what Professor Michio Kaku said earlier in the week on CBS news, to the embarrassment and annoyance of the physics community</a>.]</em></li>
<li>All mass in the universe comes from the Higgs field and/or Higgs particle. <em>[<a title="Why the Higgs and Gravity are Unrelated" href="http://profmattstrassler.com/2012/10/15/why-the-higgs-and-gravity-are-unrelated/" target="_blank">There are many things in the universe which don't get their mass from the Higgs field</a>, including atomic nuclei, the black holes at the centers of galaxies, and (probably) dark matter.  <em><em></em>Meanwhile, the Higgs particle cannot give mass to <strong>anything</strong>.</em>]</em></li>
<li><em></em>The Higgs field and/or Higgs particle gives ordinary matter its mass.  <em>[Nope; although the Higgs field, by giving the electron its mass, makes ordinary matter possible, it doesn't provide most of ordinary matter's mass.  Most of an atom's mass is in its nucleus, and thus in protons and in neutrons, particles which are not elementary and do <strong>not</strong> get most of their mass from the Higgs field.  Protons and neutrons get the<em>ir masses from effects involving the strong nuclear force; they'd still have mass if there were no Higgs field.  And again, <strong>nothing </strong>gets its mass from the Higgs particle.</em>]</em></li>
<li>The existence of the Higgs particle confirms Einstein&#8217;s theories. <em>[Einstein had nothing to do with these ideas, which were developed after his death.]</em></li>
</ul>
<p>Oh, and please let&#8217;s stop using &#8220;God Particle&#8221;.  Aside from the fact that it is the <em>field</em>, not the particle, that&#8217;s so important, the term makes it sound as though important religious questions can be answered by science, using experiments. Science is a powerful tool, but it has its limitations, and it cannot address questions of this sort.  No one benefits when scientists and/or the media confuse non-scientists into thinking that it can.</p>
<p><strong>Addenda, Subtleties and Caveats</strong></p>
<p>Now, in the interest of accuracy and precision, and so that any journalists and other non-scientists reading this understand exactly where I&#8217;m taking short cuts, here are some caveats and addenda to the two nearly-accurate statements that I gave above.</p>
<p>A first small caveat: I said the Higgs field &#8220;gives elementary particles&#8221; mass; I avoided saying &#8220;gives all elementary particles their mass&#8221; because it is likely that there are elementary particles that we haven&#8217;t yet discovered that don&#8217;t get their mass from the Higgs field.  This is probably true of the particles of dark matter, assuming that dark matter really is made from particles in the first place.  (In fact it is arguably <a title="Does the Higgs Field Give the Higgs Particle Its Mass, or Not?" href="http://profmattstrassler.com/2012/10/23/does-the-higgs-field-give-the-higgs-particle-its-mass-or-not/">true of the Higgs particle itself, but I don&#8217;t want to argue about this,</a> because semantic issues immediately come up.)</p>
<p>The most important subtlety left out of the two statements above is that not only does the Higgs field <strong>exist</strong>, it is &#8220;<strong>on</strong>&#8221;, in a sense. If you could measure the Higgs field at any point in space (which we can&#8217;t actually do directly), you&#8217;d find it isn&#8217;t zero, because it is &#8220;on&#8221;; in fact it has just about the same value everywhere throughout the universe (at least in that part that we can observe.) By contrast, if the Higgs field were &#8220;off&#8221;, you&#8217;d measure it to be zero in most places. This is similar (though different in a couple of key ways) to another field you may know about, the electric field; it too can be &#8220;on&#8221; or &#8220;off&#8221; on average. If it were &#8220;on&#8221; in your vicinity then your hair would stand on end, just as when lightning is about to strike nearby, or when you&#8217;ve just taken off a wool hat in winter and static electricity is at work. On the other hand, the electric field exists (i.e., it is something real that can be measured) even when it is &#8220;off&#8221;, as it probably is where you&#8217;re sitting right now, with nicely behaved hair.</p>
<p>And so an important addendum to the second statement is that discovery of a <a title="From “Higgs-like Particle” to “Standard Model-like Higgs”" href="http://profmattstrassler.com/2013/03/15/from-higgs-like-particle-to-standard-model-like-higgs/" target="_blank">Standard Model-like Higgs particle</a> doesn&#8217;t just confirm the Higgs field exists; it confirms that the field is &#8220;on&#8221; &#8212; which is crucial, since if it were off, it wouldn&#8217;t be able to provide masses for elementary particles.</p>
<p>We must also now add an asterisk to the statement that electrons would be massless if there were no Higgs field.<em> If the Higgs field did not exist at all, the statement is correct</em>: electrons would be massless. However, if the Higgs field existed but were simply <em>turned off</em> somehow, and nothing else were changed, electrons would still have a very, very tiny mass, due to a funny quantum interplay of the strong nuclear force and small interactions between electrons and the (off) Higgs field. <em>(Thanks to George Fleming for reminding me of this some time ago.)</em> But this is really a small asterisk, because it remains true that atoms could not form at the current epoch of the universe; the warmth left over from the Big Bang would blow them apart. The correct statement in this case would be that electrons would have tiny, tiny masses compared to what they do in nature, and this would cause atoms to become extremely fragile and easily fall apart. So the basic idea is still right.</p>
<p>Another addendum: if the Higgs field were off, not just the electron&#8217;s mass but many other aspects of the world would be very, very different. It isn&#8217;t clear exactly what would happen, actually&#8230; it turns out that, for subtle reasons, it is rather hard to calculate the impact. <em>(Professor Chris Quigg recently mentioned to me that he and his colleagues tried to compute the main effects, but found some important issues are too close to call.)</em> It appears likely that there would be no atomic nuclei,  and/or the proton would be unstable, and/or stars couldn&#8217;t shine. What is certain is that the world would be unrecognizable, even if electrons managed through some alternative magic to keep their masses. So the electron&#8217;s mass is only a part of the story &#8212; the part that is easiest to understand, but not the only part &#8212; of why the Higgs field is crucial.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s important because there is yet one more asterisk about the electron and the Higgs. In the so-called Standard Model (the equations that we use to describe <a title="The Known (Apparently-) Elementary Particles" href="http://profmattstrassler.com/articles-and-posts/particle-physics-basics/the-known-apparently-elementary-particles/" target="_blank">the known particles and forces</a>) there is only one Higgs field and one Higgs particle, of <a title="The Standard Model Higgs" href="http://profmattstrassler.com/articles-and-posts/the-higgs-particle/the-standard-model-higgs/" target="_blank">the simplest possible type</a>, and in that case my statements about the electron mass are true (still with the previous asterisk). But if the Standard Model isn&#8217;t quite right, there might be more than one Higgs field and more than one Higgs particle. If this turns out to be the case (and the experimentalists at the <a title="Introduction to the LHC" href="http://profmattstrassler.com/articles-and-posts/largehadroncolliderfaq/introduction-to-the-large-hadron-collider/" target="_blank">Large Hadron Collider</a> are trying to find out), then we do not actually know yet that the Higgs field associated to the recently discovered Higgs particle &#8212; the field which definitely gives the W and Z particles much or all of their rather large masses &#8212; is truly the <em>same</em> as the Higgs field that gives the electron its relatively small mass. So the caveat here is that although at least <em>one</em> of the Higgs fields in nature must be responsible for the electron&#8217;s mass, we don&#8217;t yet know that the Higgs particle we&#8217;ve just discovered is associated to <em>that</em> particular field. (The field associated to the newly-discovered Higgs particle would still be crucial to our lives, however, because of its other important roles mentioned in the previous paragraph. Moreover, evidence is already rising that this field interacts with the heaviest cousin of the electron, a particle called the &#8220;tau&#8221;, which for technical reasons makes it more likely that it interacts with the electron too.  Still, strictly speaking the jury is out, and will be for a while.)</p>
<p>Despite these caveats and addenda (and maybe there are more I should add), I still think the above two statements are about as accurate as you can get without becoming technical and long-winded. And again, they are far more accurate than what often appears in print!</p>
<p>&#8212;-</p>
<p>Colleagues: please feel free to suggest further improvements, and please point out further addenda, subtleties and caveats that I&#8217;ve overlooked; I&#8217;ll add them to this page.</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://profmattstrassler.com/category/higgs/'>Higgs</a>, <a href='http://profmattstrassler.com/category/public-outreach/'>Public Outreach</a> Tagged: <a href='http://profmattstrassler.com/tag/higgs/'>Higgs</a>, <a href='http://profmattstrassler.com/tag/lhc/'>LHC</a>, <a href='http://profmattstrassler.com/tag/press/'>press</a>, <a href='http://profmattstrassler.com/tag/publicperception/'>PublicPerception</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5686/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5686/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=5686&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://profmattstrassler.com/2013/03/20/why-the-higgs-matters-in-a-few-sentences/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>55</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/adeb244d3a56730027286aae9204ecc5?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">profmattstrassler</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Tin Anniversary of the Iraq War</title>
		<link>http://bobmschwartz.com/2013/03/19/the-tin-anniversary-of-the-iraq-war/</link>
		<comments>http://bobmschwartz.com/2013/03/19/the-tin-anniversary-of-the-iraq-war/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 19:48:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bob Schwartz</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[War]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Iraq War]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vietnam War]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://bobmschwartz.com/?p=1827</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Tin is the traditional gift to mark a 10th wedding anniversary, just as it is silver for the 25th and gold for the 50th. There is no tradition about the anniversaries of wars, so tin will have to do. All wars are controversial, whatever the split in support (80/20, 20/80, 50/50, rarely true 100% support), [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1827&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1828" alt="Tin Cup" src="http://bmschwartz.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/udb_tin_cup.jpg?w=500&#038;h=375" width="500" height="375" />Tin is the traditional gift to mark a 10th wedding anniversary, just as it is silver for the 25th and gold for the 50th. There is no tradition about the anniversaries of wars, so tin will have to do.</p>
<p>All wars are controversial, whatever the split in support (80/20, 20/80, 50/50, rarely true 100% support), whatever the rationale, whatever the price. Every American war has had its naysayers, contemporary with combat and in the rear view mirror of history. World War II came close to consensus, although even there questions are still raised about whether we were late getting in and whether the unprecedented brutal way we got out was necessary.</p>
<p>This paragraph was going to include a bunch of numbers about the Iraq War. But you are going to find those numbers everywhere: how many of our personnel served, how many were killed and wounded, how many civilians were killed and wounded, how much it cost in dollars. Those numbers are meant to demonstrate the price paid, in, as they say, blood and treasure. Here it is in brief: the price was staggeringly high.</p>
<p>And next is something surprisingly good to say about the Vietnam War. If we learned nothing else from that nation-dividing conflict, we learned this: whatever we believe about a war, we can never, ever, ever take anything away from the service of those who fight.</p>
<p>Some people miss an important point when they argue that we have to justify a war after the fact so that those who suffered won’t have suffered “in vain”. It is the exact opposite. When a war turns out in hindsight to present real questions about why, those who fought are maybe more our most loyal heroes, especially in a volunteer army. They didn’t answer a call to defeat some cosmic embodiment of evil (e.g., Hitler); they just loyally answered a call to serve. They deserve all we can give them (which, by the way, includes world-class medical care).</p>
<p>In August 2002 I sent an e-mail to some U.S. Senators, including Bob Graham of Florida and Robert Byrd of West Virginia. Both of them were skeptical about the rush to war, and both—particularly Byrd—believed that the role of Congress was being ignored.</p>
<p>This is an excerpt from that e-mail It is not here to reveal some astute analysis or prescience. Lots of people knew or suspected that something was wrong. It is just here as an artifact of a moment that led us to the anniversary today.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">Sent August 29, 2002</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">Congress has the constitutional power to make war, which includes careful deliberation and action if necessary.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">In the case of Iraq, you and Congress should assert that power immediately and clearly. Congress has previously allowed that power to erode in the face of political pressure, and now faces an administration that is using an atmosphere of fear (that it has intentionally or inadvertently helped create) to dare Congress to defy its claimed authority.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">When you do exercise that power, as I hope you will, it should be more than a rubber stamp. The President seems to have a simplistic and maybe, with all due respect, a simple-minded view of world affairs. The role he is carving out for the U.S. as the world&#8217;s sheriff may be right in a moral sense, but is possibly disastrous in the world of the 21st century. Which evildoer is next on the list; which town is he planning to clean up?</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">This isn&#8217;t <em>High Noon</em> or <em>The Magnificent Seven</em>. We have been lucky in Afghanistan, though I expect things will fall apart there within the next year or so. The destabilization of Iraq, especially in the face of global disdain for our actions, could be much more costly.</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;">Finally, I believe that the President&#8217;s strange game of hide-the-ball regarding his plans for Iraq (in the guise of not telegraphing our strategy) is wreaking havoc with our economic confidence. Anybody with any economic insight knows that things are <em>much</em> worse than anyone is willing to talk about, restraining such talk in the hope that consumers and businesses will regain lost faith in the future. There is no way that an attack on Iraq can help that situation, and a thousand ways it can and will hurt.</p>
<p>For the record, when the Iraq War Resolution did pass Congress in October 2002, Byrd, Graham and a total of 23 Senators (21 Democrats, 1 Republican, 1 Independent) voted against it. Of those, only a handful are still in the Senate: Barbara Boxer, Dick Durbin, Carl Levin, Barbara Mikulski, Patty Murray, Jack Reed, Debbie Stabenow and Ron Wyden. It has been more than ten years, so choice and death have taken the rest of them. One who did vote for it who is no longer in the Senate is John Kerry, who became Secretary of State after the &#8220;official&#8221; end of the Iraq War, and who, between the vote for the war and the end of it, ran for President.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a funny old world.</p>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1827&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://bobmschwartz.com/2013/03/19/the-tin-anniversary-of-the-iraq-war/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/6db52e9761487e4efa398120ffeb1e8c?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bmschwartz</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://bmschwartz.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/udb_tin_cup.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Tin Cup</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Edible Art: Cylon Raider Crescents</title>
		<link>http://kitchenoverlord.com/2013/03/04/edible-art-cylon-raider-crescents/</link>
		<comments>http://kitchenoverlord.com/2013/03/04/edible-art-cylon-raider-crescents/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2013 20:03:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Chris-Rachael Oseland</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Illustrated Geek Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science Fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Battlestar Galactica]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bread]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Breakfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crescent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cylon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cylon raider]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Geek]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[geek food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Illustrated Geek Recipe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nerd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Starbuck]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://kitchenoverlord.com/?p=430</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[By your command, this week we bring you a simple breakfast recipe that&#8217;s equally good for soaking up whiskey at a 4 a.m. poker match or keeping your stomach calm after a cocktail of vision inducing herbs and cancer drugs. You can find edible silver spray paint at craft stores like Hobby Lobby and Michael&#8217;s, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=430&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://kitchenoverlord.com/2013/03/04/edible-art-cylon-raider-crescents/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://kitchenoverlord.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/ko_cylonraider-header.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://kitchenoverlord.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/ko_cylonraider-header.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Kitchen Overlord Cylon Raider Header</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/ff6816c96eeeca44879622780927b7de?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">chrisrachael</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://kitchenoverlord.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/ko_cylonraider.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Kitchen Overlord Cylon Raider Crescents</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is black beautiful?</title>
		<link>http://feministssa.com/2013/03/20/is-black-beautiful/</link>
		<comments>http://feministssa.com/2013/03/20/is-black-beautiful/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 07:08:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jen Thorpe</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[CULTURE]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[GENDER POLITICS]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SEX AND SEXUALITY]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://feministssa.com/?p=2952</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Athambile Masola describes the representation of black women in magazines. "The lack of positive representations of black women in popular culture doesn’t mean black women are not beautiful, but we still have a long way to go in convincing the world, and particularly black women too, that black is beautiful."<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2952&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_1977" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 160px"><a href="http://feministssa.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/athambilemasola-claremonthighschool_dh_0806.jpg"><img class="size-thumbnail wp-image-1977" alt="Athambile Masola" src="http://feministssa.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/athambilemasola-claremonthighschool_dh_0806.jpg?w=150&#038;h=99" width="150" height="99" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Athambile Masola</p></div>
<p><a title="Contributors" href="http://feministssa.com/contributors/" target="_blank"><em>By Athambile Masola</em></a></p>
<p><span style="line-height:1.625;">I&#8217;m not a fan of glossy magazines. I often buy one when I&#8217;m mentally exhausted and I&#8217;m looking for something frivolous to peruse and perhaps bitch over— &#8220;why does their skin look like plastic?&#8221; or I&#8217;m trying to build up a stock of magazines I will need for a classroom activity. Recently I purchased a copy of </span><a style="line-height:1.625;" href="http://www.truelove.co.za/">True Love Magazine</a><span style="line-height:1.625;">. It seems I&#8217;m only ever drawn to buying this magazine when Lira is the front cover girl.</span></p>
<p><span style="line-height:1.625;">While trying to make a choice of which magazine would be the object of my scorn, I had a Biko</span><a style="line-height:1.625;" title="" href="/Users/jthorpe/Downloads/Is%20black%20is%20beautiful.doc#_ftn1">[1]</a><span style="line-height:1.625;"> moment. This is the moment when the racism alert button goes off in my brain and I have to question myself: are you imagining the problem in this situation? While scanning the magazines on display (lets say more than 10 women&#8217;s magazines) only three magazines had black women as their cover girl: </span><a style="line-height:1.625;" href="http://www.oprahmag.co.za/">O mag</a><span style="line-height:1.625;">, </span><a style="line-height:1.625;" href="http://www.destinyconnect.com/">Destiny</a><span style="line-height:1.625;"> and True love magazine.</span></p>
<p><span style="line-height:1.625;">I recognise that the magazine industry is fraught with complexities about the representation of women and in particular, black women. When a black woman is lucky enough to be featured on the cover of a glossy magazine I am often struck by how &#8220;yellow&#8221; she looks (unless she&#8217;s </span><a style="line-height:1.625;" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alek_Wek">Alek Wek</a><span style="line-height:1.625;">). This conversation in my head relates to what Alice Walker refers to as </span><a style="line-height:1.625;" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/ernest-owens/beyonce-colorism-and-why-_b_2687029.html">colorism</a><span style="line-height:1.625;">: the stigma of skin complexion. Amongst black women, there is a desired shade of blackness that allows one to be seen as beautiful. The skin lightening industry is still booming thanks to many black women who have been duped into the idea that beauty is about having lighter skin; to be as white as possible. As a child, I remember watching my own mother obsessing with creams that would alter (and ruin) her skin. My mother is also the person who will comment on my skin colour whenever she hasn’t seen me for a long time (often comparing me to my sisters who are considered yellow). The lighter one&#8217;s skin (and the longer one&#8217;s weave or braids) the closer they are to reaching the norms about beauty which require (amongst many things) that a women be light-skinned with wavy hair.</span></p>
<p><span style="line-height:1.625;">The challenge with being a consumer of glossy magazines is that I am constantly confronted with images of beauty which do not represent what I look like. The representation of black women in the media is controlled and requires black women to resemble whiteness as much as possible. Gone are the days of </span><a style="line-height:1.625;" href="http://www.sahistory.org.za/topic/drum-magazine">DRUM</a><span style="line-height:1.625;"> magazine which portrayed black women who were darker, shorter hair, wider hips and had not undergone the snipping and editing of photoshop. The “Drum decade” allowed Black women on the darker side of the continuum of blackness to be seen as the norm in the black community. Granted, this was also a time when declarations such as &#8220;black is beautiful&#8221; or &#8220;I&#8217;m black and I&#8217;m proud&#8221; meant something.</span></p>
<p><span style="line-height:1.625;">In our rush to be post-racism, the dominant media&#8217;s representation of black women (and perhaps broadly black people) is in a precarious position. For many years black women were invisible in glossy magazines. Hair products and make up tips were targeted at white people because the models were all white. Criticism of glossy magazines often considers how sexism is promoted because of the prototype that is displayed every month in each magazine, but racism needs to be considered too. When </span><a style="line-height:1.625;" href="http://fhm.co.za/in-the-mag/fhm-june-2011-issue-covergirl-bonang-matheba/7078/">Bonang</a><a style="line-height:1.625;" href="http://entertainment.howzit.msn.com/sa-celeb/the-rise-of-bonang-matheba">Matheba</a><span style="line-height:1.625;"> was on the cover of South Afria&#8217;s FHM cover, she was applauded for finally being the first sister to &#8220;take one for the team&#8221;. The truth is, Bonang suits the mould that FHM works within: thin, long hair and yellow skin. To celeberate Bonang’s victory of climbing the white slopes of beauty, her accomplishment was referred to as “the rise of Bonang.” Really?</span></p>
<p><span style="line-height:1.625;">This led me to consider what Oprah Winfrey has done with her magazine. It&#8217;s easy to criticise her for being so vain that she would have her face on every single issue of her magazine, but she&#8217;s making a political statement and destabilising the dominant discourse of glossy magazine industry beauty. With a lack of positive representations of black women in the media we will be accosted by Oprah&#8217;s face on the cover of O mag as a reminder of the limitations we have about beauty and what kind of representation black women have in popular culture. She is a reminder of what it means to be a successful black woman as well as what it means not to be seen as a black person.</span></p>
<p><span style="line-height:1.625;">Magazines create illusions about who we are as women and mostly what women should look like. I haven’t discussed the “Beyonce question” and what she’s done for the representation of black women, nor what it means for America to have a First Lady who scores high on colorism’s scale of blackness. In South Africa we have many black women in the public eye and the truth is, many emulate the trends of African-American women: the weave and the yellow skin being the ideal. We forget about Toni Morrison’s book </span><i style="line-height:1.625;">The bluest eye</i><span style="line-height:1.625;">, a story about Pecola and her unfortunate blackness in a sea of other black girls who victimized her for her blackness. This book highlights the complexity of beauty and colorism which is taken for granted in pop culture when forming representation of black women.</span></p>
<p><span style="line-height:1.625;">I’m still going to buy glossy magazines, but with misgivings. The slogan, “Black is beautiful” is not any easier to say now than it was in the 1950s. The lack of positive representations of black women in popular culture doesn’t mean black women are not beautiful, but we still have a long way to go in convincing the world, and particularly black women too, that black is beautiful.</span></p>
<div></p>
<hr align="left" size="1" width="33%" />
<div>
<p><a title="" href="/Users/jthorpe/Downloads/Is%20black%20is%20beautiful.doc#_ftnref1">[1]</a> Inspired by Steve Bantu Biko’s writing about Black Consciousness, <i>I write what I like.</i></p>
</div>
</div>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://feministssa.com/category/culture/'>CULTURE</a>, <a href='http://feministssa.com/category/gender-politics/'>GENDER POLITICS</a>, <a href='http://feministssa.com/category/sex-and-sexuality/'>SEX AND SEXUALITY</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2952/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2952/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2952/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2952/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2952/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2952/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2952/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2952/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2952/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2952/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2952/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2952/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2952/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2952/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2952&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://feministssa.com/2013/03/20/is-black-beautiful/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>17</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/9c71da81acfbc37e5b2ee774450d7fe9?s=96&#38;d=monsterid&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">1sttime2010</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://feministssa.files.wordpress.com/2011/10/athambilemasola-claremonthighschool_dh_0806.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Athambile Masola</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>In Zoo City, it’s impolite to ask.</title>
		<link>http://pechorinsjournal.wordpress.com/2013/03/18/zoo-city-by-lauren-beukes/</link>
		<comments>http://pechorinsjournal.wordpress.com/2013/03/18/zoo-city-by-lauren-beukes/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 13:55:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Max Cairnduff</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Beukes, Lauren]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science Fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[South African Literature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lauren Beukes]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://pechorinsjournal.wordpress.com/?p=5458</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Zoo City, by Lauren Beukes The Arthur C. Clarke Award for Science Fiction Literature is one of the very few literary prizes I pay any attention to. In part that&#8217;s because I don&#8217;t read enough science fiction to otherwise be on top of what&#8217;s coming out, but it&#8217;s also because it&#8217;s a well curated prize [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=5458&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Zoo City, by Lauren Beukes</strong></p>
<p>The Arthur C. Clarke Award for Science Fiction Literature is one of the very few literary prizes I pay any attention to. In part that&#8217;s because I don&#8217;t read enough science fiction to otherwise be on top of what&#8217;s coming out, but it&#8217;s also because it&#8217;s a well curated prize that really does tend to catch much of what&#8217;s most exciting in the field.</p>
<p>Lauren Beukes&#8217; second novel, Zoo City, won the prize back in 2011. That caused some controversy, with many arguing that it wasn&#8217;t science fiction at all but rather a fantasy novel which shouldn&#8217;t even have been shortlisted (hardcore genre fans can get very bullish about defending genre boundaries). For me the better view is that the boundaries aren&#8217;t the point. The point is that the Clarke Award did its job, by finding a bloody good book and shouting to the world about it.</p>
<p><a href="http://pechorinsjournal.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/zoo-city-sa-cover-final.jpg"><img alt="Zoo-City-SA-cover-final" src="http://pechorinsjournal.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/zoo-city-sa-cover-final.jpg?w=500&#038;h=778" width="500" height="778" /></a></p>
<p>Zoo City is the Johannesburg ghetto where the &#8220;animalled&#8221; live. The animalled are people <span style="line-height:1.7;">who carry the guilt of another human being&#8217;s death in an unusually literal way, manifested in the form of animals which they must keep near them at all times. Zinzi December, the protagonist, used to be a Johannesburg lifestyle journalist until she fell into addiction and got her brother killed. Now she has a sloth which goes with her wherever she goes &#8211; a living reminder of her sense of responsibility for her brother&#8217;s death.</span></p>
<p>The animalled are stigmatised. In China, the novel mentions at one point in passing, they&#8217;re executed on the assumption that whatever they did to end up with an animal must necessarily be a crime worthy of execution. They&#8217;re outcasts, and since few people want to employ a presumed killer who is accompanied everywhere by some bizarre creature (examples in the book include a sparrow, a bear, a mongoose, a vulture and much more) they can&#8217;t get regular employment.</p>
<p>Other than the presence of the animalled the world of Zoo City is our world. People started being animalled in the 1980s, the first being an Afghan warlord who manifested a penguin which he promptly issued with a custom-made bullet-proof vest. The phenomenon then quickly spread worldwide (the timeline is similar to the spread of Aids in real life). Some seek explanations in religion, others by reference to dodgy sounding quantum physics, but nobody really knows and from the point of view of the animalled it doesn&#8217;t really matter.</p>
<p>Being apart from your animal causes profound psychic stress. If your animal dies, you do too (and in a particularly eerie fashion). The only upside, and it&#8217;s not much of one, is that each animalled person gains a small magical power.</p>
<p>Zinzi December&#8217;s magical gift is the ability to find lost possessions. That&#8217;s a talent you can charge people for, that and her writing ability which makes her particularly good at crafting email scams to lure in unsuspecting first world retirees. The emails apparently come from:</p>
<blockquote><p><span style="line-height:1.7;">&#8230;an old lady with a flooded mansion, desperate to sell her priceless antiques cheap-cheap. A Chechnyan refugee fleeing the latest Russian pogroms with her family&#8217;s diamonds in tow. A Somali pirate who has found Jesus and wants to trade in his rocket launcher and ransom millions for absolution&#8221; and to make some money while they do so. </span></p></blockquote>
<p><span style="line-height:1.7;">What each of them has in common is the need to get a large amount of money out of South Africa, the promise of rich rewards for the kindly stranger who helps with that, and some unfortunate up-front administrative fees that can&#8217;t be paid from in-country&#8230;</span></p>
<p>We&#8217;re in noir territory then, with Zinzi a down at heels and distinctly morally ambiguous PI. Soon a pair of hired thugs (with poodle and vulture in tow) are pressuring Zinzi to take on a job for a reclusive music producer who&#8217;s lost one half of his latest boy-girl pop sensation. Zinzi doesn&#8217;t do missing people, but when the money&#8217;s right how hard can it be to find one lost teenager? Besides, there are some people it&#8217;s very hard to say no to.</p>
<p>The cover for my copy of Zoo City comes with a William Gibson quote, which makes sense because Beukes has a lot in common with Gibson. Neither has any real interest in the how of their world, whether the animalled or Gibson&#8217;s Cyberspace could actually happen. What each focuses on instead is the experience, the personal and social impact of change.</p>
<p>Beukes&#8217; first novel, Moxyland (which I reviewed <a href="http://pechorinsjournal.wordpress.com/2011/08/05/moxyland-by-lauren-beukes/">here</a>), was outright cyberpunk in the classic Gibsonian mould. Here she&#8217;s writing what could be termed urban fantasy, but with the same outlook. Modern Africa is a mix of the high tech and traditional beliefs (the same could be said of modern Singapore, modern Britain). The animals and the magical gifts they bring allow her to explore the world of <em>muti</em>, African folk beliefs which continue in a world of email scams and disposable mobile phones.</p>
<blockquote><p>Nyangas and sangomas and faith healers with varying degrees of skill or talent, broadcasting their services on posters stuck up on telephone poles and walls. Some of them are charlatans and shysters, advertising cures for anything from money woes to love-sickness and Aids with muti made from crushed lizard balls and aspirin. Guess which ingredient does all the hard work?</p></blockquote>
<p>To South Africans the animals are another form of <em>muti</em>, as are the abilities they give their humans. December&#8217;s view of the world is a modern South African view, influenced in part by animist tradition surviving into a Christian and increasingly secular age. In truth she doesn&#8217;t particularly understand how magic works, but then she probably doesn&#8217;t understand how her car works either (since car control systems went largely electronic, few people do).</p>
<blockquote><p>Object muti is easy, particularly when it&#8217;s based on a simple binary. Locked or unlocked. Lost or found. Objects want to have a purpose. They&#8217;re happy to be told what to do. People less so. [...] Most magic is more abstract. Capricious. It has a tendency to backfire. And the big stuff they promise, the Aids cures, bigger penises or death spells, are all placebo and nocebo, blessings and curses conjured up in your head. Not unlike glossy magazines, which also promise a better sex life, a better job, a better you. Trust me, I used to write those articles. And just look at me now.</p></blockquote>
<p>The worldbuilding here is done to an extent by stealth - characters don&#8217;t spend time explaining their everyday world to each other (a common fault in much other SF). The result is that you pick up the details as you go along, and Beukes is good enough at her craft to ensure this doesn&#8217;t become confusing.</p>
<p>Beukes&#8217; world convinces on its terms then, but that isn&#8217;t of itself enough to make a good novel. For me, where Beukes&#8217; fiction really shines is her evocation of contemporary urban South Africa. She&#8217;s tremendous at capturing noise, smells, the clash of colours and the sheer energy and chaos of it.</p>
<blockquote><p>Everything takes on a muted quality fifteen floors up. The traffic is reduced to a flow and stutter, the car horns like the calls of mechanical ducks. The skyline is in crisp focus, the city graded in rusts and coppers by the sinking sun that has streaked the wispy clouds the colour of blood. It&#8217;s the dust in the air that makes the Highveld sunsets so spectacular, the fine yellow mineral deposits kicked up from the mine dumps, the carbon-dioxide choke of the traffic. Who says bad things can&#8217;t be beautiful?</p></blockquote>
<p>Though this next quote reminded me more of when I used to live in Earl&#8217;s Court, showing perhaps that in some ways major cities are the same the world over.</p>
<blockquote><p>I catch a taxi into Auckland Park with the late-night cleaners, the nurses and the restaurant dish-washers: the invisible tribe of behind-the-scenes. I get off after Media Park and walk up to 7th Street with its scramble of restaurants, bars and Internet cafés. Outside the Mozambican deli-cum-Internet café, a hawker tries to sell me a star lantern made of wire and paper and, when I decline, offers me marijuana instead.</p></blockquote>
<p>Beukes also often shows a nice turn of phrase. I liked an email-scam mark having his good sense overwhelmed by the smell of money which &#8220;<span style="line-height:1.7;">bellows like a vuvuzela, drowning out the whisper of doubt.&#8221; Similarly I enjoyed a teenaged boy &#8220;</span><span style="line-height:1.7;">pouting like he ordered strippers for his birthday and got clowns instead&#8221;, and in terms of imagery when a fatally wounded man &#8220;</span>screams like a slaughterhouse pig in a Peta video&#8221; it&#8217;s vivid and unpleasantly easy to imagine.</p>
<p>What makes Zoo City such an enjoyable read then isn&#8217;t the concept itself, clever (and capable of so many allegorical readings) as it is. It&#8217;s the writing, the noirish characters, and perhaps most of all that remarkable sense of place. I&#8217;ve not read most of the novels Zoo City was up against in 2011, so I can&#8217;t say whether it deserved to beat them or not. I&#8217;m not at all surprised though that it got shortlisted, because if science fiction (or fantasy if you prefer) was producing many books like this back in 2011 it must have been an exceptionally good year.</p>
<p><span style="line-height:1.7;">Zoo City has been widely reviewed. There&#8217;s an excellent (and spoiler free) example at David H&#8217;s blog, </span><a style="line-height:1.7;" href="http://davidhblog.wordpress.com/2010/12/08/lauren-beukes-zoo-city-2010/">here</a><span style="line-height:1.7;"> (I only just realised David&#8217;s blog wasn&#8217;t on my blogroll, so I&#8217;ve promptly corrected that) and he links in turn to fine reviews from John Clute and Niall Harrison each of which is definitely worth reading. I was happier with the ending than David was as for me the book always had that crime heritage overlapping with the SF and I was therefore expecting a fairly plot-driven ending.</span></p>
<p><em>Postscript: Some issues with the Kindle edition</em></p>
<p>Finally, a note of caution for those who don&#8217;t have this and might be thinking of picking it up. Beukes uses different fonts in places, to indicate emails or internet chats, and all that inevitably gets lost in the kindle version. Much worse though the kindle version, in the UK at least, has some truly appalling formatting errors which were so frequent and so bad that they started to genuinely spoil the book for me.</p>
<p>Since I knew the author was on twitter I dropped her a line there asking if there was some way to get the ebook version fixed (the paperback doesn&#8217;t have these problems). She put me in touch with her publishers, who asked me to email through the details of the problems I&#8217;d found (since they apparently weren&#8217;t in all e-editions in all countries).</p>
<p>The publishers offered to send me a cleaned up version, but before they could Lauren Beukes herself very kindly emailed me a word version of the book which was entirely error free (and which was apparently a later version of the book, fixing a plot problem I&#8217;d already read past without noticing that her French translator had picked up).</p>
<p>I really can&#8217;t praise enough Lauren Beukes&#8217; and her publishers&#8217; response to the problem I had. Given though the formatting issues with the ebook, and the fact that even once fixed you&#8217;ll still lose the font choices Beukes makes, this is one you should definitely read in physical copy if at all possible.</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://pechorinsjournal.wordpress.com/category/beukes-lauren/'>Beukes, Lauren</a>, <a href='http://pechorinsjournal.wordpress.com/category/science-fiction/'>Science Fiction</a>, <a href='http://pechorinsjournal.wordpress.com/category/south-african-literature/'>South African Literature</a> Tagged: <a href='http://pechorinsjournal.wordpress.com/tag/lauren-beukes/'>Lauren Beukes</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5458/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5458/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=5458&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://pechorinsjournal.wordpress.com/2013/03/18/zoo-city-by-lauren-beukes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>16</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/3ed8d5ba231400c3ae282b8fba3dff62?s=96&#38;d=wavatar" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">pechorinsjournal</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://pechorinsjournal.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/zoo-city-sa-cover-final.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Zoo-City-SA-cover-final</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The North Korean Bubble</title>
		<link>http://caffeinedreamsliquorschemes.com/2013/03/19/great-expectations-the-north-korean-bubble/</link>
		<comments>http://caffeinedreamsliquorschemes.com/2013/03/19/great-expectations-the-north-korean-bubble/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 03:53:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Immanuel C</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cultural Spotlight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[child]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cultural spotlight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[father]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[global issues]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[korea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[legacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[north korea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nuclear]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[son]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://caffeinedreamsliquorschemes.com/?p=687</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This is the 2nd of fifteen articles in CDLS’s &#8216;Spotlight On…&#8217; series Previous : Cyprus Quick disclaimer here: I didn&#8217;t mean for this article to get as long as it did. It sort of ran away from me. If you ask Colin, he will tell you that I have been dying to post an article on North Korea [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=687&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><i>This is the 2<sup>nd</sup> of fifteen articles in CDLS’s &#8216;Spotlight On…&#8217; series</i></p>
<p><em>Previous : <a href="http://caffeinedreamsliquorschemes.com/2013/03/19/cyprus-suddenly-relevant/">Cyprus</a></em></p>
<p><i>Quick disclaimer here: I didn&#8217;t mean for this article to get as long as it did. It sort of ran away from me.</i></p>
<p>If you ask Colin, he will tell you that I have been dying to post an article on North Korea for weeks. Every week I&#8217;ll work on one and I’ll tell him that this is finally the week I’ll post it. I sit down and write a paragraph and then I scrap it. I hate every approach I have taken to write about this topic and nothing I write interests me.</p>
<p>When it comes to North Korea, people quickly tend to fall into two camps: first the North Korea is crazy and is a parody of a cartoon super villain threatening everybody with nuclear attacks, camp. And there is the camp that says North Korea is the world’s best (worst?) example of human rights violations and they speak more on the plight of the North Korean people. Both views are incredibly accurate and there isn&#8217;t much you can say to disagree with that, but that doesn&#8217;t interest me. There are countless articles that take one side or another, explaining what’s going on in North Korea in depth.</p>
<p>I wanted to look at North Korea from the angle of a son having to live up to a family legacy.</p>
<p>Kim Jong-un is the youngest son of Kim Jong-il and the Supreme Leader of North Korea. He became the favourite to succeed his father after his older half-brother Kim Jong-nam had been caught attempting to enter Japan on a fake passport to see Tokyo Disneyland back in 2001. Kim Jong-un is a man stepping into the incredibly large shoes of his father while standing under the gargantuan shadow of his grandfather Kim Il-sung.</p>
<p>Kim Il-sung is North Korea’s greatest culture hero (a very liberal usage of the term, admittedly) and the personality cult associated with him is massive. For forty six years he led North Korea following its liberation from Japanese control in 1948. He is deified in North Korea as their Eternal Leader. Technically, even 19 years after his death, Kim Il-sung still rules the country. In 1997, the Juche Era dating system was introduced in North Korea which replaced the standard Gregorian calendar. The calendar begins with the birth of Kim Il-sung in 1912. While his son Kim Jong-il does not have the same level of deification, he still is an important figure in North Korea. The propaganda reports released by the North Korean government have built up such a vast mythology for these two men that the cult of personality associated with the Kims is basically a religion in itself.</p>
<p>Now imagine a child growing up and watching his father lead a nation and hearing the legendary exploits of his grandfather who built that self-same nation out of dirt and blood.</p>
<p>Imagine that child being educated and prepared for the day he takes over from his father.</p>
<p>Imagine you are this child. That for your whole life you are being told that you will one day lead a nation. That you would succeed these two legendary figures. That everything you do from the moment you take power, will be instantly compared to your predecessors and you will be found wanting.</p>
<p>Imagine that incredible weight and pressure placed upon your shoulders.</p>
<p>As children we tend to idolize our fathers regardless of how present they were physically. They are these immortal figures, larger than life and able to do anything. We look up to our fathers and build them up in our minds in such a way that nobody can ever live up to. I remember the day I discovered that my father couldn&#8217;t in fact do everything. As a child that shakes up your world discovering that they aren&#8217;t legendary figures, but rather just men. Flawed, great and everything in between.</p>
<p>Now imagine you never had that realization. Imagine that your entire society agrees that your father and grandfather are in fact these mythical figures. Imagine having to live up to that.</p>
<p>Living up to our parents is one of the hardest things we can do. Not only do our parents have their own expectations of us that we need to live up to but we have our own expectations that we feel they have of us. We see what our parents accomplished and we want to at least equal them and better what they did.</p>
<p>But how do you equal a deified figure that still rules your nation even in death? How do you surpass a father that is said to be able to control the weather based on his mood?</p>
<p>Imagining all of this, is it any wonder Kim Jong-un threatened the United States with a ‘pre-emptive nuclear attack’?</p>
<p>Kim Jong-un is trying to live up to a legacy that nobody can ever live up to.</p>
<p>Great Expectations is my favourite Dickens’ novel and it explores in great detail the perils of trying to live up to overbearing expectations. While I don’t sympathize with Kim Jong-un because of the conditions the North Korean people live in, I can understand how hard it is to live up to a legacy and what a son would do to live up to his father.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/687/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/687/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/687/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/687/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/687/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/687/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/687/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/687/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/687/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/687/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/687/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/687/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=687&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://caffeinedreamsliquorschemes.com/2013/03/19/great-expectations-the-north-korean-bubble/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>15</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://caffeinedreamsliquorschemes.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/northkorea.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://caffeinedreamsliquorschemes.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/northkorea.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">northkorea</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/d0a83266b47a4f0c80c5ac0d64c20959?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F1.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">immanuelcoke</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Godzilla’s Revenge</title>
		<link>http://merryfrolics.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/godzillas-revenge/</link>
		<comments>http://merryfrolics.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/godzillas-revenge/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 15:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Keith</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Film & TV]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[1960s]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[G]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Godzilla]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ishiro Honda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kaiju & Giant Monsters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science Fiction]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://teleport-city.com/wordpress/?p=598</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[If more Godzilla fans could get the broom out of their ass and actually enjoy the films rather than nitpick and dissect them under an electron microscope, they'd see that in its own way, for its own audience, Minya and <em>Godzilla's Revenge</em> are as effective and important to the series as the original.<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=598&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr00.jpg"><img src="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr00.jpg?w=470&#038;h=199" alt="gr00" width="470" height="199" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-38334" /></a></p>
<p>I am breaking little new ground when I point out that the original 1954 film <em>Godzilla</em> was a serious sci-fi horror film that is taken seriously by serious critics (seriously!), even the more annoying ones who usually refuse to give genre films the time of day. Few people would argue that it was a cinematic milestone, that it was to the crossover scifi/horror film what <em>Citizen Kane</em> was to movies about grumpy newspaper moguls and what <em>Pee-wee&#8217;s Big Adventure</em> was to the road trip film. Whatever the franchise may have become, <em>Godzilla&#8217;s</em> contribution to film history was as big as the monster itself, and not even Michael Medved will argue that one. Or maybe he will. I don&#8217;t really know him personally, so I can&#8217;t account for him.</p>
<p>Any movie that big will get a sequel, whether it wants or needs one or not. Or so it was back then. A movie had to be a success before it could get a sequel. I don&#8217;t know what has gone wrong these days that allows there to be theatrically released sequels to movies like <em>The Flintstones</em> and <em>Problem Child</em>, but then again, who am I to second guess the business strategy of Satan? Anyway, they made the sequel and it was pretty forgettable, but by the third film, they struck franchise gold and the Godzilla industry was born, along with thousands of American tourists going to Japan and shouting &#8220;Oh no! Is Godzilla!&#8221; and thinking they are the first ones to think of doing that. What <em>will</em> you cards think of next!?!</p>
<p>
<a href='http://merryfrolics.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/godzillas-revenge/gr17/' title='gr17'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="38431" data-orig-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr17.jpg" data-orig-size="848,358" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="gr17" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr17.jpg?w=470" data-large-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr17.jpg?w=848" width="150" height="63" src="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr17.jpg?w=150&#038;h=63" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="gr17" /></a>
<a href='http://merryfrolics.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/godzillas-revenge/gr18/' title='gr18'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="38432" data-orig-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr18.jpg" data-orig-size="848,358" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="gr18" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr18.jpg?w=470" data-large-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr18.jpg?w=848" width="150" height="63" src="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr18.jpg?w=150&#038;h=63" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="gr18" /></a>
<a href='http://merryfrolics.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/godzillas-revenge/gr14/' title='gr14'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="38428" data-orig-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr14.jpg" data-orig-size="848,358" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="gr14" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr14.jpg?w=470" data-large-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr14.jpg?w=848" width="150" height="63" src="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr14.jpg?w=150&#038;h=63" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="gr14" /></a>
<br />
Over the years, Godzilla underwent a series of evolutionary steps, most of them fostered by either ideological trends or, more realistically, the desire to make even more money off the monster. The long and winding road eventually transformed him from menacing destructive force to toe-tappin&#8217;, jig-dancin&#8217; superhero good guy. To put it in terms comic book readers can understand, he went from the dark spooky Batman to the Adam West Batman. Curiously enough, I always liked the Adam West Batman, just as I always liked the goofball heroic Godzilla. I could just imagine Godzilla turning to his trusty boy wonder of a sidekick, Angilas, and calling him &#8220;old chum.&#8221;</p>
<p>Like many children of the 1970s, I grew up watching dubbed imports of Godzilla&#8217;s many adventures, though unlike many children of the 1970s, I never grew out of the films, just like I never grew out of toys or messy sticky-up hair. My love for Godzilla, and my understanding of the movies, only grew as I tacked on year after year. And when I was but a wee sprout toiling in the fields, I found myself most attracted to a little gem called <em>Godzilla&#8217;s Revenge</em>. I absolutely loved the film. I mean, here was a movie that showed me if a kid is psychotic enough, he can travel to Monster Island, hang with monsters, and defeat criminals. Here was a movie that taught me the valuable lesson about dealing with your problems by resorting immediately to physical violence. During recess in school, we&#8217;d all run out to the playground and decide whether or not we were going to play <em>Star Wars</em> or <em>Godzilla</em>. When it was <em>Star Wars</em>, I was Chewbacca, albeit it a rather short version and without so much hair, the cool Sergio Leone bandoleer, and the laser crossbow (what was up with that thing anyway?). If we played Godzilla, I wanted to be Minya.</p>
<p>
<a href='http://merryfrolics.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/godzillas-revenge/gr15/' title='gr15'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="38429" data-orig-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr15.jpg" data-orig-size="848,358" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="gr15" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr15.jpg?w=470" data-large-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr15.jpg?w=848" width="150" height="63" src="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr15.jpg?w=150&#038;h=63" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="gr15" /></a>
<a href='http://merryfrolics.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/godzillas-revenge/gr11/' title='gr11'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="38425" data-orig-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr11.jpg" data-orig-size="848,358" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="gr11" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr11.jpg?w=470" data-large-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr11.jpg?w=848" width="150" height="63" src="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr11.jpg?w=150&#038;h=63" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="gr11" /></a>
<a href='http://merryfrolics.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/godzillas-revenge/gr16/' title='gr16'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="38430" data-orig-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr16.jpg" data-orig-size="848,358" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="gr16" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr16.jpg?w=470" data-large-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr16.jpg?w=848" width="150" height="63" src="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr16.jpg?w=150&#038;h=63" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="gr16" /></a>
<br />
Yes, Minya. Godzilla&#8217;s chubby, squealing adopted son. Minya, the most despised of all Godzilla monsters ever. I remember running around pretending to blow atomic smoke rings, then insisting that my friend who was pretending to be Gabera let me beat them up so we could accurately recreate scenes from the movie. I remember lining up Shogun Warriors and knocking them down, gleefully ignorant of how valuable they would eventually become. In this lies the greatest power of <em>Godzilla&#8217;s Revenge</em>, as well as the thing people most often just don&#8217;t get about it and Minya. It&#8217;s a movie for children, with a character for children. I&#8217;ve said it before, but it bears saying again: nothing annoys me more than twenty-five year old scifi nerds complaining about how goofy and childish <em>Godzilla&#8217;s Revenge</em> is. Well, no crap, Spock, it&#8217;s a damn children&#8217;s movie. What the hell did you expect? It&#8217;s like this annoying wannabe gangster rap guy who has this shitty show on Manhattan public access cable where he reviews video games and steals wrestling news from various websites and passes it off as his own stuff. I remember watching one episode (don&#8217;t ask why) where he was playing &#8220;Yoshi&#8217;s Revenge&#8221; or some game like that and complaining about how childish it was and how it wasn&#8217;t a good game for extreme gamers like himself.</p>
<p>
<a href='http://merryfrolics.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/godzillas-revenge/gr12/' title='gr12'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="38426" data-orig-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr12.jpg" data-orig-size="848,358" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="gr12" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr12.jpg?w=470" data-large-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr12.jpg?w=848" width="150" height="63" src="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr12.jpg?w=150&#038;h=63" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="gr12" /></a>
<a href='http://merryfrolics.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/godzillas-revenge/gr13/' title='gr13'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="38427" data-orig-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr13.jpg" data-orig-size="848,358" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="gr13" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr13.jpg?w=470" data-large-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr13.jpg?w=848" width="150" height="63" src="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr13.jpg?w=150&#038;h=63" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="gr13" /></a>
<a href='http://merryfrolics.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/godzillas-revenge/gr10/' title='gr10'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="38424" data-orig-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr10.jpg" data-orig-size="848,358" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="gr10" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr10.jpg?w=470" data-large-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr10.jpg?w=848" width="150" height="63" src="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr10.jpg?w=150&#038;h=63" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="gr10" /></a>
<br />
I don&#8217;t really know what these people&#8217;s problem is, and I&#8217;m no armchair psychologist so I&#8217;d rather not speculate, but it seems to all boil down to a desperate need to have one&#8217;s childish interests and hobbies justified as serious adult pursuits. Thus things like the &#8220;comics aren&#8217;t just for kids&#8221; campaign, or the demand that movies about a giant lizard knocking over major metropolitan areas be darker and more adult oriented. Well you know what? Most Godzilla movies are childish. Reading comic books is childish. Being a grown man who dresses up as Sailor Moon is both childish and disturbing, but you know what? That doesn&#8217;t make any of these things wrong or unenjoyable.</p>
<p>Face it &#8212; adult stuff is miserable. Adult stuff is paying taxes and watching <em>Gray&#8217;s Anatomy</em>. Adult stuff is trying to get a mortgage, listening to adult contemporary music, and going to see Italian films that don&#8217;t star Steeve Reeves. Childish stuff is listening to snotty punk rock, reading comics, talking about <em>Star Trek</em>, going to goofy conventions, wearing costumes, playing with dolls, and being open to learning new things. Being childish does not mean being irresponsible. Being childish is stealing a sneak peek at porn, hiding a copy <em>Penthouse</em> inside a copy of <em>Dragon</em> magazine so you can look at it in the Waldenbooks mall store. Being childish is loving what you love without shame, no matter how society may frown upon or disapprove of your passion. Being childish is going through life wide-eyed and amazed, unhindered by societal hang-ups about how one race shouldn&#8217;t get along with another, one age group shouldn&#8217;t like the same things as another. As an adult, I look at people around me and, despite my liberal view of all things social, I still see blacks, whites, Asians, whatever. I still see men, women, gays, lesbians, heteros. I don&#8217;t discriminate or disapprove, but I still see categories far more often than I see people.</p>
<p>
<a href='http://merryfrolics.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/godzillas-revenge/gr08/' title='gr08'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="38422" data-orig-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr08.jpg" data-orig-size="848,358" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="gr08" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr08.jpg?w=470" data-large-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr08.jpg?w=848" width="150" height="63" src="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr08.jpg?w=150&#038;h=63" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="gr08" /></a>
<a href='http://merryfrolics.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/godzillas-revenge/gr06/' title='gr06'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="38420" data-orig-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr06.jpg" data-orig-size="848,358" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="gr06" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr06.jpg?w=470" data-large-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr06.jpg?w=848" width="150" height="63" src="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr06.jpg?w=150&#038;h=63" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="gr06" /></a>
<a href='http://merryfrolics.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/godzillas-revenge/gr07/' title='gr07'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="38421" data-orig-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr07.jpg" data-orig-size="848,358" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="gr07" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr07.jpg?w=470" data-large-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr07.jpg?w=848" width="150" height="63" src="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr07.jpg?w=150&#038;h=63" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="gr07" /></a>
<br />
As a child, I remember growing up watching <em>Ultraman</em> and Godzilla films, playing with Shogun Warriors and pretending I was Jason in <em>Battle of the Planets</em>. At the time, I didn&#8217;t buy Japanese toys; I bought toys. I didn&#8217;t watch Japanese movies; I just watched movies. I didn&#8217;t have friends who were Japanese, Chinese, white, black, Mexican, boy or girl; I just had friends. Never once did it occur to me that I should not relate to these people because they were different from me, because not once did it occur to me that these people were all that different. Sure, we ate different things, were different colors, but what did that really matter? I was a different color than lots of people. We liked a lot of the same things and had fun together. It wasn&#8217;t until I began my journey to adulthood that I was taught lessons about alienating others because of their race, culture, gender. It wasn&#8217;t until later that I was told I couldn&#8217;t relate to <em>Ultraman</em>, because those were Japanese actors and not Caucasian ones. It wasn&#8217;t until adulthood that passion about learning, about having fun, and about doing things that made me happy became taboo and shameful.</p>
<p>
<a href='http://merryfrolics.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/godzillas-revenge/gr04/' title='gr04'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="38418" data-orig-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr04.jpg" data-orig-size="848,358" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="gr04" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr04.jpg?w=470" data-large-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr04.jpg?w=848" width="150" height="63" src="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr04.jpg?w=150&#038;h=63" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="gr04" /></a>
<a href='http://merryfrolics.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/godzillas-revenge/gr03/' title='gr03'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="38417" data-orig-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr03.jpg" data-orig-size="848,358" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="gr03" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr03.jpg?w=470" data-large-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr03.jpg?w=848" width="150" height="63" src="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr03.jpg?w=150&#038;h=63" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="gr03" /></a>
<a href='http://merryfrolics.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/godzillas-revenge/gr05/' title='gr05'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="38419" data-orig-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr05.jpg" data-orig-size="848,358" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="gr05" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr05.jpg?w=470" data-large-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr05.jpg?w=848" width="150" height="63" src="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr05.jpg?w=150&#038;h=63" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="gr05" /></a>
<br />
Being childish is a wonderful thing, something adults don&#8217;t do enough of except for the part about whining and crying about not getting your way. For some reason, everyone seems happy to maintain <em>that</em> aspect of childishness in their adult life, but they leave behind and even scoff at the wonder, curiosity, and willingness to experiment and learn. I have no reservations about being childish. If I&#8217;m drenched in a sudden downpour, oh well. Might as well splash around in the puddles and run wild. If I see a grassy hill, I might as well roll down it. If I see a toy I like, or a movie that amuses me, I might as well not cover that up under some repressive delusion of being &#8220;mature&#8221; or sophisticated. If I&#8217;m alive, I might as well try to enjoy as much of it as I can.</p>
<p>And this spirit of being childish, this beautiful immaturity that allows us to shed the chrysalis of mundane adulthood in which we must cocoon ourselves so much of the time, is the energy which keeps me supporting the so often maligned <em>Godzilla&#8217;s Revenge</em>. Even if I am old enough now, whatever that means, to see how shoddy the film is, even if I recognize all the stock photography and entire scenes lifted wholesale out of other Godzilla movies to pad out the running time, even if I see how bad it all is through adult eyes, I remember how completely and unconditionally I loved the film as a child. At that time, it becomes easy to remove the filter of bitterness and condescension that is adulthood, allowing me to watch the movie as I did when I was a wee one, but with the added dimension of wisdom. In that way, <em>Godzilla&#8217;s Revenge</em> has gotten even better for me with age.</p>
<p>
<a href='http://merryfrolics.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/godzillas-revenge/gr02/' title='gr02'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="38416" data-orig-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr02.jpg" data-orig-size="868,380" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="gr02" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr02.jpg?w=470" data-large-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr02.jpg?w=868" width="150" height="65" src="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr02.jpg?w=150&#038;h=65" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="gr02" /></a>
<a href='http://merryfrolics.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/godzillas-revenge/gr58/' title='gr58'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="38470" data-orig-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr58.jpg" data-orig-size="848,358" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="gr58" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr58.jpg?w=470" data-large-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr58.jpg?w=848" width="150" height="63" src="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr58.jpg?w=150&#038;h=63" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="gr58" /></a>
<a href='http://merryfrolics.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/godzillas-revenge/gr01/' title='gr01'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="38415" data-orig-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr01.jpg" data-orig-size="868,380" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="gr01" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr01.jpg?w=470" data-large-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr01.jpg?w=868" width="150" height="65" src="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr01.jpg?w=150&#038;h=65" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="gr01" /></a>
<br />
The film begins with one of the coolest fuzzed-out surf guitar/spy movie music theme songs I&#8217;ve ever heard. &#8220;March of the Monsters&#8221; ranks up there on the swankometer right alongside movie themes like &#8220;Our Man Flint&#8221; and &#8220;Shaft,&#8221; and is every bit as weird and funky as those songs. Right there you have reason enough to dig this movie from the get-go. We then meet young Ichiro. Ichiro is the lad who, among other things, showed us just how small a little kid&#8217;s micro-shorts could become. Little shorts are as much a defining icon of the 1970s Japanese monster movie as they were to Catherine Bach in <em>Dukes of Hazzard</em>, though given the choice at age seven of watching Ichiro in Daisy Dukes or watching Daisy Duke in Daisy Dukes, I would go with Daisy every time. I&#8217;m childish; I&#8217;m not insane.</p>
<p>Ichiro is a kid who a lot of kids could relate to at the time. His dad worked all day, and his mom worked evenings, so he rarely sees either of them. His only neighbor is a creepy inventor toy-maker type guy who is not nearly as cool as the inventor and his hard-bodied little bachelor pal from <em>Godzilla Versus Megalon</em>. This guy is just sort of, well, you know. Maybe not the guy you trust to take care of your kid when you are away. He looks like he was probably heavily involved in experimental theater during the 1960s. To make matters worse, every day when Ichiro walks home with his gal pal, he is pestered by a bully named Gabera. When you see these kids, you will realize that it&#8217;s akin to being bullied by, say, a gang consisting of Eddie Deezen, Matthew Broderick, and that guy who played Conan&#8217;s goofy sidekick in <em>Conan the Destroyer</em>.</p>
<p>
<a href='http://merryfrolics.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/godzillas-revenge/gr52/' title='gr52'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="38464" data-orig-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr52.jpg" data-orig-size="848,358" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="gr52" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr52.jpg?w=470" data-large-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr52.jpg?w=848" width="150" height="63" src="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr52.jpg?w=150&#038;h=63" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="gr52" /></a>
<a href='http://merryfrolics.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/godzillas-revenge/gr26/' title='gr26'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="38438" data-orig-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr26.jpg" data-orig-size="848,358" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="gr26" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr26.jpg?w=470" data-large-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr26.jpg?w=848" width="150" height="63" src="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr26.jpg?w=150&#038;h=63" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="gr26" /></a>
<a href='http://merryfrolics.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/godzillas-revenge/gr22/' title='gr22'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="38436" data-orig-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr22.jpg" data-orig-size="848,358" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="gr22" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr22.jpg?w=470" data-large-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr22.jpg?w=848" width="150" height="63" src="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr22.jpg?w=150&#038;h=63" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="gr22" /></a>
<br />
Because his parents are never around, and his only friends are a prudish little girl who doesn&#8217;t like trespassing in old buildings and a fruity hippie neighbor, Ichiro has created a disturbingly elaborate fantasy world which may or may not be augmented by the fact that those shorts he wears must restrict the flow of blood through his body, making it more likely that he would live in a happy hallucinatory land of make-believe. When he is alone and feelin&#8217; blue, Ichiro gets out his home-made matter transporting radio device and tunes in to his own subconscious. Ahh yes, back when kids used their imagination and played make-believe. </p>
<p>Ichiro&#8217;s trip through his own strange and twisted brain is pretty interesting. His radio transports him to Monster Island, home of Godzilla and plenty of other monsters. But to get there, Ichiro has to board a commercial jet liner that is completely empty and driven by auto-pilot. A telling subconscious symbol of his latchkey kid lifestyle? The plane deposits him alone on Monster Island, where he gets to hide in bushes and watch stock footage from various older Godzilla films, most frequently <em>Son of Godzilla</em> and <em>Godzilla Versus the Sea Monster</em>. After a hard day of watching Godzilla sort of walk around just randomly kicking the collective asses of his neighbors on Monster Island, one starts to wonder if this is how it is every day. I mean, does Godzilla wake up every morning and think, &#8220;Well, who&#8217;s ass am I gonna kick today?&#8221; Do they start shit with him, or does he simply pick the fights himself like some drunken redneck in a trailer park?</p>
<p>
<a href='http://merryfrolics.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/godzillas-revenge/gr45/' title='gr45'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="38457" data-orig-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr45.jpg" data-orig-size="848,358" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="gr45" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr45.jpg?w=470" data-large-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr45.jpg?w=848" width="150" height="63" src="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr45.jpg?w=150&#038;h=63" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="gr45" /></a>
<a href='http://merryfrolics.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/godzillas-revenge/gr43/' title='gr43'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="38455" data-orig-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr43.jpg" data-orig-size="848,358" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="gr43" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr43.jpg?w=470" data-large-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr43.jpg?w=848" width="150" height="63" src="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr43.jpg?w=150&#038;h=63" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="gr43" /></a>
<a href='http://merryfrolics.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/godzillas-revenge/gr46/' title='gr46'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="38458" data-orig-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr46.jpg" data-orig-size="848,358" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="gr46" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr46.jpg?w=470" data-large-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr46.jpg?w=848" width="150" height="63" src="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr46.jpg?w=150&#038;h=63" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="gr46" /></a>
<br />
What is an average day like for Godzilla? Not those special days when the Earth is threatened by strangers from another world and their big golden dragons, but rather, those days when there&#8217;s not much to do and no one invading our planet by building a robot that looks exactly like Godzilla instead of spending the money on something more useful and effective, like a neutron bomb. What is the Godzilla equivalent of kicking around the house in your underwear watching a little television? I&#8217;ve always been fascinated by pondering stupid questions like this. Like what does the Pope do when he isn&#8217;t out Poping? Does he read the paper? Does he own normal clothes or just those glittery Liberace robes? Does the Pope have a jogging outfit?</p>
<p>I wondered the same thing about Darth Vader, too. I mean, sure, there are days when he has to be all &#8220;Your powers are weak, old man&#8221; and throwing boxes around with his mind, but those days are probably few and far between in the greater scheme of things. So what was his average day like? Filling out paperwork? Going to long, boring meetings about revisions to the zoning laws? I mean, the guy was helping run an empire and all. There&#8217;s a lot of work involved with that sort of thing. The elevation of the mundane to art. Just once, I would like to see Captain Picard stepping out of the bathroom stall. Unfortunately, attempts to answer these questions often end up looking like <em>The Star Wars Holiday Special</em>. Or there are those late era Santo films where he&#8217;d already beat all the aliens, vampires, mafia, and devils Mexican theater could throw at him, so you had movies that consisted of stuff like Santo (in three piece suit and wrestling mask) driving to the bank or doing his taxes. At these times, I realize my fascination with seeing mundane everyday aspects of the lives of fantastic characters is usually not as cool in practice as it is in theory.</p>
<p>
<a href='http://merryfrolics.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/godzillas-revenge/gr39/' title='gr39'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="38451" data-orig-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr39.jpg" data-orig-size="848,358" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="gr39" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr39.jpg?w=470" data-large-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr39.jpg?w=848" width="150" height="63" src="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr39.jpg?w=150&#038;h=63" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="gr39" /></a>
<a href='http://merryfrolics.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/godzillas-revenge/gr40/' title='gr40'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="38452" data-orig-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr40.jpg" data-orig-size="848,358" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="gr40" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr40.jpg?w=470" data-large-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr40.jpg?w=848" width="150" height="63" src="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr40.jpg?w=150&#038;h=63" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="gr40" /></a>
<a href='http://merryfrolics.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/godzillas-revenge/gr41/' title='gr41'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="38453" data-orig-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr41.jpg" data-orig-size="848,358" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="gr41" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr41.jpg?w=470" data-large-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr41.jpg?w=848" width="150" height="63" src="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr41.jpg?w=150&#038;h=63" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="gr41" /></a>
<br />
Luckily, Godzilla&#8217;s everyday life consist primarily of getting into fights. Through the miracle of recycled footage, we see Godzilla rumble with Spiga the Spider, those giant praying mantises, and other old faves. When Ichiro is menaced by one of the monsters, he hauls ass through the jungle, which I think was a song by CCR, and falls down a hole. Actually, he falls into a really awful special effect which, along with a later scene of Leapin&#8217; Minya Poffo, will show you exactly why they chose to rely mainly on stock footage from other films for most of the effects shots. At this point, I would have imagined myself some wings, and probably a princess who looked just like Penny Robinson from <em>Lost in Space</em>. Ichiro goes instead for a vine rope being lowered by Minya. Incidentally, Minya looks a lot like Ichiro. They&#8217;re both very spherical in shape. Minya is able to shrink down to Ichiro size and speak English (or Japanese if you are watching the original version) with a &#8220;hyuk hyuk hyuk aw shucks, hoss&#8221; sort of <em>Country Bear Jamboree</em> accent.</p>
<p>
<a href='http://merryfrolics.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/godzillas-revenge/gr51/' title='gr51'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="38463" data-orig-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr51.jpg" data-orig-size="848,358" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="gr51" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr51.jpg?w=470" data-large-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr51.jpg?w=848" width="150" height="63" src="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr51.jpg?w=150&#038;h=63" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="gr51" /></a>
<a href='http://merryfrolics.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/godzillas-revenge/gr47/' title='gr47'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="38459" data-orig-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr47.jpg" data-orig-size="848,358" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="gr47" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr47.jpg?w=470" data-large-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr47.jpg?w=848" width="150" height="63" src="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr47.jpg?w=150&#038;h=63" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="gr47" /></a>
<a href='http://merryfrolics.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/godzillas-revenge/gr44/' title='gr44'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="38456" data-orig-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr44.jpg" data-orig-size="848,358" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="gr44" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr44.jpg?w=470" data-large-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr44.jpg?w=848" width="150" height="63" src="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr44.jpg?w=150&#038;h=63" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="gr44" /></a>
<br />
In a deep psychological move, Minya is very much like Ichiro in more ways than just being round. Minya comes from a single parent family, and that parent, Godzilla, is often absent from home. And hey, Minya is even constantly picked on my a big monster bully named &#8230; Gabera! This Gabera is a little more menacing than the other Gabera, though the shock of bright red Johnny Rotten hair undermines his appearance somewhat. Additionally, it looks like they started to add a tail to Gabera but then ran out of money. He&#8217;s got a saggy ass and really looks like he needs a tail to complete the whole picture. Imagine Godzilla without a tail. Yep, pretty silly. But at least Gabera can shoot electricity out of his hands. I don&#8217;t know if the Gabera picking on Ichiro could do that, but I suppose anything is possible in that crazy land we call Japan.</p>
<p>Hey you know what I just realized? <em>Godzilla&#8217;s Revenge</em> is just a movie adaptation of <em>Where the Wild Things Are</em>, the children&#8217;s book in which a depressed young boy travels to the land of cavorting monsters and generally has a hell of a good time.</p>
<p>
<a href='http://merryfrolics.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/godzillas-revenge/gr42/' title='gr42'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="38454" data-orig-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr42.jpg" data-orig-size="848,358" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="gr42" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr42.jpg?w=470" data-large-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr42.jpg?w=848" width="150" height="63" src="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr42.jpg?w=150&#038;h=63" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="gr42" /></a>
<a href='http://merryfrolics.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/godzillas-revenge/gr54/' title='gr54'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="38466" data-orig-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr54.jpg" data-orig-size="848,358" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="gr54" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr54.jpg?w=470" data-large-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr54.jpg?w=848" width="150" height="63" src="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr54.jpg?w=150&#038;h=63" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="gr54" /></a>
<a href='http://merryfrolics.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/godzillas-revenge/gr53/' title='gr53'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="38465" data-orig-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr53.jpg" data-orig-size="848,358" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="gr53" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr53.jpg?w=470" data-large-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr53.jpg?w=848" width="150" height="63" src="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr53.jpg?w=150&#038;h=63" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="gr53" /></a>
<br />
Just when things are getting good, Ichiro is disturbed and snapped back to reality. This happens several times so that we can set up the real world sub plot, conveniently broadcast over the Plot Point Specific Radio Broadcasting Network as listened to frequently by Gilligan and the Professor and many other people in b-movies and bad television shows. Pretty much every broadcast was about a storm, a bank robbery, or the fact that the Harlem Globetrotters plane went down over the Pacific Ocean. This one broadcasts the thing about the bank robbery, though it would have been pretty funny if Ichiro found Curly and Meadowlark Lemon stranded on Monster Island with him. The bank robbers, who are apparently not so good at robbing banks, happen to be hiding out in the old abandoned industrial hazard in which Ichiro likes to play. One of the bank robbers drops his wallet, which Ichiro promptly finds, which then means they must kidnap him.</p>
<p>But first, Ichiro must dream, dream, dream himself away to sweet, sweet Monster Island, where Minya introduces him to an unimpressed Godzilla, who would rather swat airplanes out of the sky than talk to his stupid son&#8217;s nerdy friends (who wouldn&#8217;t?). Sort of like if you had a fat, beer-swilling dad who sat on the back porch ignoring you in favor of swatting mosquitoes and flies. Hmm, when you think about it, Godzilla is a pretty bad parent. Minya also has a scuffle with Gabera, during which he grows to the size of &#8220;little monster&#8221; and loses the ability to speak English in favor of making a lame &#8220;Bwaah-bwaaah&#8221; sound. Gabera not only kicks Minya&#8217;s ass, he even does that thing where you hold your smaller opponent at bay by pressing your outstretched arm against their forehead, thus causing them the be too far away to hit you with their wildly swinging stubby little arms. This is a good way of fighting the short of stature, but you have to watch out because eventually, you&#8217;re going to do that one time too many, and they&#8217;re going to drop down and headbutt you in the balls. Happens every time.</p>
<p>
<a href='http://merryfrolics.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/godzillas-revenge/gr28/' title='gr28'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="38440" data-orig-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr28.jpg" data-orig-size="848,358" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="gr28" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr28.jpg?w=470" data-large-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr28.jpg?w=848" width="150" height="63" src="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr28.jpg?w=150&#038;h=63" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="gr28" /></a>
<a href='http://merryfrolics.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/godzillas-revenge/gr21/' title='gr21'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="38435" data-orig-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr21.jpg" data-orig-size="848,358" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="gr21" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr21.jpg?w=470" data-large-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr21.jpg?w=848" width="150" height="63" src="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr21.jpg?w=150&#038;h=63" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="gr21" /></a>
<a href='http://merryfrolics.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/godzillas-revenge/gr27/' title='gr27'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="38439" data-orig-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr27.jpg" data-orig-size="848,358" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="gr27" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr27.jpg?w=470" data-large-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr27.jpg?w=848" width="150" height="63" src="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr27.jpg?w=150&#038;h=63" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="gr27" /></a>
<br />
All the scenes involving Gabera are new to this film, and in a curious turn, rather than simply cut in stock footage of the infamous &#8220;learnin&#8217; how to blow atomic breath&#8221; scene from <em>Son of Godzilla</em>, they recreate the entire sequence here. For those of you who haven&#8217;t seen it, it&#8217;s the one where Minya can only blow harmless rings of blue smoke until Godzilla stomps on his tail, thus shocking him into blowing destructive atomic fire and honking like a donkey in heat.</p>
<p>This is cool and all, but the real world so often gets in the way of fantasy. In a rather imaginative segueway, Ichiro finds himself being attacked by jungle plants, only to wake up and find himself being kidnapped by the bank robbers. As bad as they are at robbing banks, they are even worse at kidnapping. Using all the wits and wiles afforded a kindergarten boy in micro-shorts, Ichiro befuddles and defeats his captors in a sequence that was no doubt the inspiration for the later <em>Home Alone</em> films. Yay! He&#8217;s a hero now! But not before dozing off one more time to see the final fight between Minya and big bully Gabera. This time, rather than cowering, Minya stands up to Gabera and manages to get a few cheap shots in until Gabera accidentally bites Godzilla, at which time Godzilla decides fun time is over and just kicks the shit out of Gabera himself. Since Gabera is about the same size and Godzilla, you gotta wonder why he was making Minya fight the monster to begin with. I mean, that&#8217;s like a father telling his seven-year-old to stand up to a bully like Mike Tyson.</p>
<p>
<a href='http://merryfrolics.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/godzillas-revenge/gr30/' title='gr30'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="38442" data-orig-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr30.jpg" data-orig-size="848,358" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="gr30" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr30.jpg?w=470" data-large-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr30.jpg?w=848" width="150" height="63" src="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr30.jpg?w=150&#038;h=63" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="gr30" /></a>
<a href='http://merryfrolics.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/godzillas-revenge/gr29/' title='gr29'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="38441" data-orig-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr29.jpg" data-orig-size="848,358" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="gr29" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr29.jpg?w=470" data-large-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr29.jpg?w=848" width="150" height="63" src="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr29.jpg?w=150&#038;h=63" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="gr29" /></a>
<a href='http://merryfrolics.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/godzillas-revenge/gr31/' title='gr31'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="38443" data-orig-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr31.jpg" data-orig-size="848,358" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="gr31" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr31.jpg?w=470" data-large-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr31.jpg?w=848" width="150" height="63" src="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr31.jpg?w=150&#038;h=63" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="gr31" /></a>
<br />
Anyway, everyone has fun beating up Gabera, and inspired by this show of familial violence, Ichiro wakes up with renewed vigor and, in front of his girlfriend, struts up and beats the crap out of his own Gabera in a fight that consists mainly of jumpcut shots of two young boys pulling on each other shirts. Actually, it&#8217;s a pretty realistic fight in that it is clumsy and really sucks. At the end of the day, Ichiro has beat down Gabera, impressed the little lady, and gained the respect of all his peers. So come on! What&#8217;s not to love? I mean, this movie is every little kid&#8217;s dream!</p>
<p>The movie was directed by none other than Inoshiro Honda, the man who gave us the dark and ominous original film, as well as most of the Godzilla films from the 1960s that people remember as the best of the bunch. In interviews, he expressed disappointment in the movement of Godzilla from an icon of terror into a do-gooder hero under pressure from the studios to make the series more consumer-friendly. While I understand his sentiments, he should also look at the fact that while Godzilla did indeed lose his power as a warning about the follies of man, he also became a symbol of hope about the future. While the later Godzilla films did not shake the world with portents of doom, they made children happy. They, in their own weird and colorful way, even taught children the lessons adults failed to learn from the original.</p>
<p>
<a href='http://merryfrolics.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/godzillas-revenge/gr35/' title='gr35'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="38447" data-orig-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr35.jpg" data-orig-size="848,358" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="gr35" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr35.jpg?w=470" data-large-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr35.jpg?w=848" width="150" height="63" src="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr35.jpg?w=150&#038;h=63" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="gr35" /></a>
<a href='http://merryfrolics.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/godzillas-revenge/gr36/' title='gr36'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="38448" data-orig-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr36.jpg" data-orig-size="848,358" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="gr36" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr36.jpg?w=470" data-large-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr36.jpg?w=848" width="150" height="63" src="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr36.jpg?w=150&#038;h=63" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="gr36" /></a>
<a href='http://merryfrolics.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/godzillas-revenge/gr37/' title='gr37'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="38449" data-orig-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr37.jpg" data-orig-size="848,358" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="gr37" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr37.jpg?w=470" data-large-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr37.jpg?w=848" width="150" height="63" src="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr37.jpg?w=150&#038;h=63" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="gr37" /></a>
<br />
I started thinking about environmental issues as a kid after seeing <em>Godzilla Versus the Smog Monster</em> and watching episodes of <em>Spectreman</em>. I started, honestly, thinking about the follies of war after seeing how much trouble it caused in Godzilla and other scifi films. As goofy and as immature as movies like <em>Godzilla&#8217;s Revenge</em> may seem to adults, and even to their creators, they do serve a genuine purpose. A couple years ago, with my blessing, my best friend back in Louisville gave her six-year-old daughter my copy of <em>Godzilla&#8217;s Revenge</em>. A Godzilla fan was instantly created. She forsook her interest in <em>Teletubbies</em> in favor of more Godzilla films, started pretending to be Minya instead of pretending to be a cat, and hasn&#8217;t stopped exploring since then. And you know why? Because she&#8217;s a child. Because she has that spark that keeps away the walls of prejudice, fear, suspicion, and bigotry that creep in as we get older. Like me when I was her age, she doesn&#8217;t know Japanese from American and doesn&#8217;t discriminate on such arbitrary grounds as race. She simply knows what she likes and wants to learn more about it.</p>
<p>
<a href='http://merryfrolics.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/godzillas-revenge/gr55/' title='gr55'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="38467" data-orig-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr55.jpg" data-orig-size="848,358" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="gr55" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr55.jpg?w=470" data-large-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr55.jpg?w=848" width="150" height="63" src="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr55.jpg?w=150&#038;h=63" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="gr55" /></a>
<a href='http://merryfrolics.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/godzillas-revenge/gr56/' title='gr56'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="38468" data-orig-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr56.jpg" data-orig-size="848,358" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="gr56" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr56.jpg?w=470" data-large-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr56.jpg?w=848" width="150" height="63" src="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr56.jpg?w=150&#038;h=63" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="gr56" /></a>
<a href='http://merryfrolics.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/godzillas-revenge/gr57/' title='gr57'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="38469" data-orig-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr57.jpg" data-orig-size="848,358" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-title="gr57" data-image-description="" data-medium-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr57.jpg?w=470" data-large-file="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr57.jpg?w=848" width="150" height="63" src="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr57.jpg?w=150&#038;h=63" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="gr57" /></a>
<br />
I won&#8217;t pretend that <em>Godzilla&#8217;s Revenge</em> doesn&#8217;t have its short-comings, or that I am completely able to overlook them all the way I did when I was in first grade. Yeah, Ichiro is annoying, so annoying in fact that I was inspired to invent the Ichirometer, the scale by which all annoying cinematic children are measured. And yeah, the movie is cheap. The majority of the monster scenes are from older, much better movies. When they do attempt a special effect, like when Minya jumps off the cliff to foil Gabera with the ol&#8217; &#8220;bad guy standing on the end of a teeter totter&#8221; type move, it&#8217;s pretty sorry. At the same time, as goofy as he is, Gabera always seemed cool to me when I was little, and it&#8217;s always good to see Godzilla kick some butt, even if most of it just consists of his greatest tropical island hits.</p>
<p>It also signaled the end of the &#8220;golden age&#8221; of Godzilla films and kicked off the &#8220;right silly age&#8217; under the guidance of new official Godzilla director Jun Fukuda. Of course, I adore most of those films as well, all full as they are of cyborgs and space monkeys and corn-on-the-cob-loving hippies. And of course you may be wondering at what point Godzilla actually gets any revenge. Well, he doesn&#8217;t really, unless you count the thrashing he gives Gabera in the final monster scene as revenge for the one time Gabera bit him. Seems a pretty small incident in the greater scheme of things. I&#8217;d like to thing that the revenge to which they refer is what they get now any time an overly serious Godzilla fan watches this movie. If you don&#8217;t like it, you don&#8217;t like it. All&#8217;s fair in taste. But don&#8217;t dislike it because it&#8217;s childish. If that&#8217;s your complaint about it, then do yourself and someone else a favor: give the movie to a child.</p>
<p><span class="infotext">1969, Japan. Starring Kenji Sahara, Machiko Naka, Tomonori Yazaki, Eisei Amamoto, Sachio Sakai, Kazuo Suzuki, Ikio Sawamura, Shigeki Ishida, Yutaka Sada, Chotaro Togin, Yutaka Nakayama, Yoshifumi Tajima, Little Man Machan, Haruo Nakajima, Hiroshi Sekita, Midori Uchiyama. Directed by Inoshiro Honda. <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00006FD9I?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=teleportcity&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=B00006FD9I">Buy it from Amazon</a><img style="border:none!important;margin:0!important;" src="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=teleportcity&amp;l=as2&amp;o=1&amp;a=B00006FD9I" border="0" alt="" width="1" height="1" />.</span></p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://merryfrolics.wordpress.com/category/film-tv/'>Film &amp; TV</a>  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=598&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://merryfrolics.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/godzillas-revenge/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/grfeat.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/grfeat.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">grfeat</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/fa6851f488aadfccfdbdebce02ff87f8?s=96&#38;d=monsterid&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">keithatc</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr00.jpg?w=470" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gr00</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr17.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gr17</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr18.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gr18</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr14.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gr14</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr15.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gr15</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr11.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gr11</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr16.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gr16</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr12.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gr12</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr13.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gr13</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr10.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gr10</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr08.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gr08</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr06.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gr06</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr07.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gr07</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr04.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gr04</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr03.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gr03</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr05.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gr05</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr02.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gr02</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr58.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gr58</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr01.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gr01</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr52.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gr52</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr26.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gr26</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr22.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gr22</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr45.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gr45</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr43.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gr43</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr46.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gr46</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr39.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gr39</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr40.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gr40</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr41.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gr41</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr51.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gr51</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr47.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gr47</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr44.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gr44</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr42.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gr42</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr54.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gr54</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr53.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gr53</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr28.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gr28</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr21.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gr21</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr27.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gr27</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr30.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gr30</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr29.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gr29</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr31.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gr31</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr35.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gr35</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr36.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gr36</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr37.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gr37</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr55.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gr55</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr56.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gr56</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://merryfrolics.files.wordpress.com/2002/01/gr57.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">gr57</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=teleportcity&#38;l=as2&#38;o=1&#38;a=B00006FD9I" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Conversation</title>
		<link>http://elroyjones.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/the-conversation/</link>
		<comments>http://elroyjones.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/the-conversation/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 14:45:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>elroyjones</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Autonomy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[INDEPENDENCE]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://elroyjones.wordpress.com/?p=3180</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[She hadn&#8217;t forgotten the relief scrawled all over James&#8217;s face when she picked him up in Myrtle Beach. He held her so tight she thought she&#8217;d break. She could feel him shudder as he choked back sobs. When she pulled away, his eyes welled up and tears ran down his face.  She watched him lean [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3180&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>She hadn&#8217;t forgotten the relief scrawled all over James&#8217;s face when she picked him up in Myrtle Beach. He held her so tight she thought she&#8217;d break. She could feel him shudder as he choked back sobs. When she pulled away, his eyes welled up and tears ran down his face.  She watched him lean over to get his bag, saw the nape of his neck that was replicated in her kids, felt a treacherous tug on her heart. His eyes had filled anew as he turned toward her. &#8220;James, what&#8217;s wrong?&#8221; He stopped. He looked down at her, his brows knit in consternation, &#8220;I was afraid I&#8217;d never see you again.&#8221; She reached for him and held him close.</p>
<p>They started a conversation.<br />
She asked &#8220;Why?&#8221; Why was he mad at her all the time? Why didn&#8217;t he trust her?<br />
He wasn&#8217;t mad. He didn&#8217;t know what to do. He&#8217;d always known who she was. When he came back from Vietnam, she was still there, the same as she was when he&#8217;d left. She was committed to her religion, when he was only going through the motions of habit, avoiding the conflict of examining where god went when you were so scared you shit yourself, when families were being blown to bits for reasons nobody knew. She hadn&#8217;t pestered him about it, she didn&#8217;t ask any questions. He felt that she understood who he was inside.<br />
&#8220;I wanted to know. I wanted to know what happened. I didn&#8217;t ask you because it wasn&#8217;t my business. I thought the church was your reason for living. Then why did you get so mad when I cut my hair?&#8221;<br />
&#8220;It was beautiful and soft and it smelled good. I liked to touch it before I went to sleep because it meant you were right there, with me. Every day, as soon as I got done work, I went home to get the kids to come see you at the market because I couldn&#8217;t wait for you to come home. When you cut it, I thought that was the beginning of the end. You were changing. I thought you didn&#8217;t love me.&#8221;</p>
<p>He said a lot more; private things she hadn&#8217;t expected, things he thought she just knew. They&#8217;d stayed through the weekend before they drove back home. They&#8217;d made it through the intervening years, trudging through some and sailing through others. They had ugly words and sweet words, more words than she&#8217;d imagined. In the end, whether she&#8217;d chosen her destiny, or they had created it, didn&#8217;t matter at all.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3180/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3180/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3180&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://elroyjones.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/the-conversation/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>41</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/21e9dfba7851063d7a62404210420278?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">elroyjones</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Paranoia, Meet Theism.</title>
		<link>http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.wordpress.com/2013/03/10/paranoia-meet-theism-theism-this-is-paranoia-youre-biological-father-6/</link>
		<comments>http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.wordpress.com/2013/03/10/paranoia-meet-theism-theism-this-is-paranoia-youre-biological-father-6/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2013 11:14:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>john zande</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Sketches on Atheism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ancestor cults]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[and the oldest of them all]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[animism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[atheism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[False Associations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[god]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Neurosis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new atheism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[origin of religion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[paganism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pantheism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Paranoia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[religion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[root of belief]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[superstition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Theism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Totemism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Unnatural]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.wordpress.com/?p=1440</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Just so there’s no doubt: Anthropomorphic theism is about as natural as tennis rackets, ice cream cones and bikinis. It is neither automatic nor inevitable. No religion has emerged twice anywhere on the planet, no single deity has been envisaged by two populations separated by time and geography, and not a solitary person in history [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1440&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/hancock-joseph-man-with-umbrella-under-a-regional-rain.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-1443" alt="hancock-joseph-man-with-umbrella-under-a-regional-rain" src="http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/hancock-joseph-man-with-umbrella-under-a-regional-rain.jpg?w=338&#038;h=450" width="338" height="450" /></a>Just so there’s no doubt: Anthropomorphic theism is about as natural as tennis rackets, ice cream cones and bikinis. It is neither automatic nor inevitable. No religion has emerged twice anywhere on the planet, no single deity has been envisaged by two populations separated by time and geography, and not a solitary person in history has arrived independently at Mithraism, Christianity, Islam, Zoroastrianism, Hinduism, Scientology or Judaism without it first being taught to them. That is an inalienable, unarguable truth. Theism (the progeny of far older generations of pantheism, Totemism, paganism, animism and the oldest of them all, ancestor cults) is nothing but the latest imaginative appendage to have grown out from (culturally-centric) superstition; itself nothing but the elaborately dressed-up residue cast off from blunders in causation and correlation. That’s all superstition is; irrational mistakes in cognition where we observe one event (B) happening after another event (A) and assume A is responsible for B. Upon sensing a storm approaching my wife’s deeply superstitious great grandmother would, I’m told, crawl beneath the kitchen sink and furiously beat pots and pans together until the lightning and thunder had passed. Not so surprisingly this method of chasing storm demons away worked every time. The storm would pass. The reasons why, of course, differed according to whom you asked.</p>
<blockquote><p><b>“The General root of superstition is that men observe when things hit, and not when they miss, and commit to memory the one, and pass over the other.” (Francis Bacon)</b></p></blockquote>
<p>Like theism, superstition is however also not natural. It will not rise instinctively like hunger, and no two populations will arrive at the same irrational fears. A monstrous, head-exploding, palm tree bending sneeze on the Banks Islands of Polynesia is cause for serious concern as someone is certainly talking badly of you, but for the Maoris in nearby New Zealand the same roof-lifting nose orgasm is reason to celebrate because someone fun is surely about to visit. <a href="http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/pf-paranoia.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-1386" alt="PF-paranoia" src="http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/pf-paranoia.jpg?w=241&#038;h=300" width="241" height="300" /></a>The tripwire for superstition is cultural, it’s anthropological, but this is not however to say there <i>isn’t</i> a physiological trigger buried deep inside the gnome that kicks the door open to culturally-centric superstition and through that paves the way for its uglier but more organised cousin, religion. There is, and it’s spelt  P  A  R  A  N  O  I  A.</p>
<p>Granted, on first inspection most will say paranoia, like superstition, is simply an unwelcomed cognitive clusterfuck, the information processing equivalent of a shipwreck, and in many ways it is just that. It is however an unavoidable, preordained shipwreck hardwired into each and every one of us… and for very good reason: the madness served us extremely well at a time not that very long ago when even the strongest of us were counted as snack items. A breeze bending blades of grass could easily be attributed (albeit in this instance incorrectly) to a stalking lioness and all the dangers that it implied. Danger is bad, and to get ahead of it we, as a species, played it safe and erred on the side of caution. We learnt to jump before (possible) peril arrived. The causal associations made between the unpredictable movement of grasses and the presence of danger (to use this example) was a good thing, a promotable skill, a biologically useful adaption that was slowly but surely etched into our gnome. To put it simply, our evolutionary path rewarded the lesser of two evils whereby the cost of paranoia was deemed lower than the cost of scepticism which, if wrong, extracts a painfully high price: namely death. The sceptical hominid might see the bending grass but take a moment to then survey surrounding trees and see if they too were bending. If they were then the probability of wind causing the movement of the grass increased but did not necessarily rule out the presence of a hungry lioness. Wrongly attributing the bending grass to an approaching lioness ninety-nine times out of a hundred was, it appears, far less costly than being wrong once. The paranoid lived on to practice (or fend off) increasingly bad pick-up lines whereas the brazen sceptic tired of jumping at the slightest rustle met a less than pleasant demise.</p>
<p>In a sentence, nature beatified the neurotic.</p>
<p>A tendency to make quick albeit mostly false associations was deemed more evolutionarily beneficial than more reliable but equally more time-consuming rational scepticism. There was a price to pay for this inbuilt paranoia, anxiety and suspicion, but the price was evidently considered tolerable in the face of the more costly alternatives. We are, as such, biologically predisposed to this neurosis. Paranoia is, at a genetic level, our default setting: the natural state of a human being at rest. Bending blades of grass are observed, synaptic nerve endings fire and the observation is linked to past events where the pattern of bending grass is followed by a blinding flash of sandy blonde fur and hazardously huge feline paws. What happens next is entirely involuntary. Up top there is a not-so mild biochemical explosion and norepinephrine floods the brain; the neurological equivalent of someone yelling “FIRE!” in a crowded theatre. Adrenal glands go off like solid rocket fuel motors and adrenalin saturates the sympathetic nervous system. Neurons in the visual cortex spark off at triple normal speed and time appears to slow. Faster than thought the liver dumps its store of glucose into the blood. The heart and lungs snap into overdrive flooding muscles with oxygen, and with that the body is near-instantly prepared for Flight or Fight: a survival mechanism that has changed little, if at all, through the last 830,000 generations.</p>
<p>That’s just the way it is and I can no sooner change that than I can change my eye colour. Today as I walk my dogs an abrupt rustle in the tall grass will make me jump. The likelihood of a lioness leaping out might be remote, a mouse is more probable, but my natural, pre-programmed bias to making the quicker and cheaper false association is there, ingrained. My speedy (life-preserving) reaction, which I’m not shy to admit might include yelping like a little girl, I can thank some deep time relative – perhaps Australopithecus afarensis – for. However, simply because some 830,000 generations ago this neurosis was deemed less expensive than careful scepticism does not mean there hasn’t been a hidden cost slowly accruing in the background; an expense steadily but surely building up like silt behind a once useful dam wall. The truth is there has been, and that cumulative cost is our stubborn attachment to superstition: the nucleus of theism and all its unnatural nonsense.</p>
<br /> Tagged: <a href='http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.wordpress.com/tag/ancestor-cults/'>ancestor cults</a>, <a href='http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.wordpress.com/tag/and-the-oldest-of-them-all/'>and the oldest of them all</a>, <a href='http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.wordpress.com/tag/animism/'>animism</a>, <a href='http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.wordpress.com/tag/atheism/'>atheism</a>, <a href='http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.wordpress.com/tag/false-associations/'>False Associations</a>, <a href='http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.wordpress.com/tag/god/'>god</a>, <a href='http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.wordpress.com/tag/gods/'>gods</a>, <a href='http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.wordpress.com/tag/neurosis/'>Neurosis</a>, <a href='http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.wordpress.com/tag/new-atheism/'>new atheism</a>, <a href='http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.wordpress.com/tag/origin-of-religion/'>origin of religion</a>, <a href='http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.wordpress.com/tag/paganism/'>paganism</a>, <a href='http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.wordpress.com/tag/pantheism/'>pantheism</a>, <a href='http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.wordpress.com/tag/paranoia/'>Paranoia</a>, <a href='http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.wordpress.com/tag/religion/'>religion</a>, <a href='http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.wordpress.com/tag/root-of-belief/'>root of belief</a>, <a href='http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.wordpress.com/tag/superstition/'>superstition</a>, <a href='http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.wordpress.com/tag/theism/'>Theism</a>, <a href='http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.wordpress.com/tag/totemism/'>Totemism</a>, <a href='http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.wordpress.com/tag/unnatural/'>Unnatural</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1440/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1440/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1440/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1440/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1440/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1440/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1440/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1440/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1440/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1440/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1440/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1440/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1440/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1440/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1440&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.wordpress.com/2013/03/10/paranoia-meet-theism-theism-this-is-paranoia-youre-biological-father-6/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>170</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c0a3dbb25b899dda42934295ee0d3a25?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">johnzande</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/hancock-joseph-man-with-umbrella-under-a-regional-rain.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">hancock-joseph-man-with-umbrella-under-a-regional-rain</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thesuperstitiousnakedape.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/pf-paranoia.jpg?w=241" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">PF-paranoia</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
