<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2013 20:02:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>International Families</title>
		<link>http://travelunites.com/2013/04/04/international-families/</link>
		<comments>http://travelunites.com/2013/04/04/international-families/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 13:00:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Travel Unites</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA["The Namesake"]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adoption]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethnic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[international family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jhumpa Lahiri]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[understand]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://travelunites.com/?p=871</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[“You are still young, free. Do yourself a favor. Before it&#8217;s too late, without thinking too much about it first, pack a pillow and a blanket and see as much of the world as you can. You will not regret it. One day it will be too late.” ―Jhumpa Lahiri, The Namesake How international is [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=871&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p style="text-align:right;">“You are still young, free. Do yourself a favor. Before it&#8217;s too late, without thinking too much about it first, pack a pillow and a blanket and see as much of the world as you can. You will not regret it. One day it will be too late.”<br />
―Jhumpa Lahiri, <strong>The Namesake</strong></p>
</blockquote>
<p>How international is your family? Do you have personal knowledge about whether the United States is better described as a Melting Pot or a Tossed Salad?</p>
<p>The small Midwestern town I grew up in seemed quite homogeneous and “vanilla.” Only later did I realize my home town had an unusual concentration of Slavic, Welsh, and Scottish names. Since no one knew the word <b>ethnic</b> in the 50’s and 60’s, we just knew that people ate different things for the holidays, and some families had many more letters in their names than others.</p>
<p>But perhaps your parents came here from another culture and you were among the first in your family to grow up in the States. That might have put you in a peculiar position as a little adult translating words or expectations you knew about from your peers for your less attuned parents. (Jhumpa Lahiri, now of Cambridge, is eloquent on the problems of juggling Bengali heritage with US adolescence in <b>The Namesake.</b>)</p>
<p>Or perhaps you are half of an international couple. Two adults meet and bond across unknown divides of expectations; surprising differences can continue to arise from the suitcases of your pasts without warning. Expand your horizons to include parents from different worlds and children forging a new unified world as they go, and it is hard to describe the world you all inhabit.</p>
<p>Perhaps you are part of a family which has moved internationally several times. Or one member of your family is away (on active military duty, for example) for extended periods of time. Both of these experiences provide intense opportunities or requirements for families to cope with international variations and realities. These can become crucibles for learning and bonding because of (or in spite of) the challenges faced.</p>
<div id="attachment_878" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 210px"><a href="http://travelunites.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/chinese-food.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-878" alt="Adding new foods to household menus builds bridges between cultures.Photo by Kornwa" src="http://travelunites.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/chinese-food.jpg?w=200&#038;h=300" width="200" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Adding new foods to household menus builds bridges between cultures.<br />Photo by Kornwa</p></div>
<p>Or perhaps you became an international family through adoption. That is our story. On some levels the question of whether you have an international relationship between adoptive parents and children can be moot. Parents are not required to accommodate an infant’s cultural expectations; there are none. But in my experience most parents try to incorporate some part of the child’s culture into their family life. The story of the application, the travel, first meeting, and the special things purchased during travel all become part of the child’s Story and should be treasured as much as any child’s arrival accounts. Food is another aspect of culture which is easy to introduce. Consistently the child learns that his or her country of origin is a safe and easy topic for discussion.</p>
<p>One question for all these constellations of people is what about travel to the cultures of origin? Who plans the trips? Who sets the priorities? When is the best time?</p>
<p>You will not be surprised to hear that I think travel to experience other cultures is a Good Thing. There are better and worse ways and times for making the first trip, though. Especially with international adoptions, the trip should happen at a favorable time for the young people involved. Individual preferences and needs should rule the plan.</p>
<p>While checking the spelling of the author’s name, I came across her very apt observation about the peculiar condition of living in a culture not your own:</p>
<blockquote><p>“For being a foreigner, Ashima is beginning to realize, is a sort of lifelong pregnancy &#8212; a perpetual wait, a constant burden, a continuous feeling out of sorts. It is an ongoing responsibility, a parenthesis in what had once been an ordinary life, only to discover that previous life has vanished, replaced by something more complicated and demanding. Like pregnancy, being a foreigner, Ashima believes, is something that elicits the same curiosity from strangers, the same combination of pity and respect.”<br />
<span style="line-height:1.5;">        ― Jhumpa Lahiri, </span><strong style="line-height:1.5;">The Namesake</strong></p></blockquote>
<p>There is a great deal to discuss in the situations I describe. I would love to hear your comments about “lifelong pregnancies” you have known!</p>
<p><strong style="line-height:1.5;">Boundaries divide. Travel unites.</strong></p>
<p>4 April 2013</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/871/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/871/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=871&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://travelunites.com/2013/04/04/international-families/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a932b3ff711a3d026441687b43285f69?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">travelunites</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://travelunites.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/chinese-food.jpg?w=200" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Adding new foods to household menus builds bridges between cultures.Photo by Kornwa</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cursi</title>
		<link>http://vocabat.com/2013/03/11/cursi/</link>
		<comments>http://vocabat.com/2013/03/11/cursi/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 20:14:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>vocabat</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Colombia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Emotions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Language]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Musings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Poetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spanish]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vocabat.com/?p=2723</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I went to a party the other night, and we were all having a merry old time. One of the guests started playing the guitar, and someone asked if he knew any songs by Ricardo Arjona. No, not Arjona, I pleaded. ¡Es muy cursi! Judging by the immediate chorus of indignant gasps and protestations, I had touched a [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2723&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I went to a party the other night, and we were all having a merry old time. One of the guests started playing the guitar, and someone asked if he knew any songs by Ricardo Arjona. No, not Arjona, I pleaded. <em>¡Es muy cursi!</em><i> </i>Judging by the immediate chorus of indignant gasps and protestations, I had touched a nerve. More than merely defensive of the singer, they took issue with my epithet of choice. <em>¿Y qué tiene de malo eso, ser cursi?</em> I didn&#8217;t stop there.<em> Es más</em>, I said. I&#8217;ve found that Hispanics on the whole tend to be much more <em>cursi</em> than Americans. Well, that was it. <em>Se armó la de Troya.</em> The women were then up in arms. Oh, what does she know about love? She&#8217;s just a cold, heartless <em>gringa</em>. How could she ever understand the way we Latinos feel and express ourselves? No, they didn&#8217;t actually say those things, but it&#8217;s what their whelps were basically communicating. As we&#8217;re all friends, I took their ribbing in stride. They wouldn&#8217;t let me live it down, though&#8211;the rest of the night, they kept making a big deal about all the music being <em>CURSI</em> and then looking at me as if to apologize for offending my stony artistic palate.</p>
<p>I wanted to <em>retirar lo dicho</em> immediately, and not because of the outcry from my friends. I knew that no feelings had been hurt, and I still stand by what I said—Ricardo Arjona <em>is </em>cheesy. Immensely so. And his music is not my cup of tea. But if someone wanted to, I&#8217;m sure they could lampoon many of my beloved Hispanic singers for being <em>cursi</em><i> </i>as well&#8211;Silvio Rodríguez, Julio Jaramillo, Chavela Vargas, etc. Why does <i>cursi</i> get such a bad rap? And what do we reveal about ourselves when we hiss and glare at this adjective as if it were the devil?</p>
<p><em>Cursi</em> means cheesy, especially in the sense of mushy, sentimental, sappy, lovey-dovey. Cloyingly sweet, sickeningly sweet. <em>Empalagoso, hostigante, acaramelado</em>. Someone who is <em>cursi</em> oozes <em>miel</em>&#8211;honey&#8211;and is thus <em>meloso</em>. Think of the Seinfeld episode where he and his girlfriend called each other Schmoopy, and you&#8217;ll have a good idea of <em>cursi</em>.</p>
<p><a href="http://vocabat.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/cursii.gif"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2725" alt="Cursi elefante" src="http://vocabat.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/cursii.gif?w=348&#038;h=349" width="348" height="349" /></a></p>
<p>It&#8217;s very subjective, though. I guess everyone has a certain degree to which they can tolerate mushiness. Predictably, it&#8217;s always other people&#8217;s sappiness that gets on your nerves; one almost never views their own actions as <i>cursi </i>unless their family and friends start giving them a hard time about their soft side. That is, we&#8217;re all hypocrites when it comes to being cheesy. All of us, of course, but the Spanish speakers.</p>
<p>I had a <em>cursi</em> friend in Bogotá named Jhon Carlos. Here&#8217;s how I described him to a friend back in 2010: &#8220;He&#8217;s kind of awkward, though awfully sweet and tender, also kind of cheesy and… eager. :)&#8221; Yes; very cheesy, this Jhon Carlos. And very eager<em>&#8211;muy intenso</em>&#8211;but so genuine and sincere. He filled my inbox for years with emails full of virtual flowers, cliché professions of love, and lots of <em>melosidad</em>. Although I rolled my eyes at the trite and sappy ways that he expressed his feelings for me, I respected him for being so heartfelt and unabashedly cheesy. <em>O sea</em>, for not holding back and for not apologizing for his cheesiness in an effort to put up a barrier of self-protection in case of rejection or mockery. People who dare to bare their hearts make themselves easy targets, but who wants to be the grinch who goes around ridiculing people for attempting to find and then luxuriate in love? Insecure people, that&#8217;s who.</p>
<p>My first boss in Colombia, Alba, once gave me a painfully <em>cursi </em>stuffed lion attached to a fuzzy cup that had two hearts on it and had HAPPY EVERYDAY emblazoned across the top. I was touched. The examples I could give of <em>cursi</em>-ness that I observed in Colombia could go on and on, and I&#8217;ve noticed it among Hispanic friends from other countries as well. And it&#8217;s one of my favorite things about them&#8211;I love my Hispanic friends and the Latin American culture at large for being so <em>cursi</em>. I do. No, I still prefer not to receive stuffed animals from love interests seeing as I exited childhood decades ago, but I will take a cheesy, over-the-top, melodramatic love any day over some serious, respectable, safe, buttoned-down alternative. Yawwwwn. <em>¡Qué pereza!</em></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://vocabat.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/128.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-2785" alt="Happy everyday" src="http://vocabat.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/128.jpg?w=480&#038;h=330" width="480" height="330" /></a></p>
<p>Hell, one could date Pablo Neruda and even find him <i>cursi </i>were they to insist on militancy against all sentimentality. Where&#8217;s the fun in that, though? And, who knows, maybe even Neruda got exhausted sometimes from the great pressure to be original and not <em>cursi&#8211;</em>after a long day of racking his brain for inspired, fresh symbols of love for his poems, perhaps the most he could muster up for Matilde was a little teddy bear he&#8217;d pick up at a nearby store. Maybe she even requested them, having been up to her eyeballs in sonnets and odes. There&#8217;s nothing wrong with being a little <i>cursi </i>from time to time, and if it’s your MO, well more power to you so long as your partner’s on the same <i>cursi</i> wavelength. Each set of lovers forms their own language and lexicon composed of their significant symbols and code words, and who really cares if some <em>fulano </em>scoffs and labels them as <em>cursi</em>? Ain&#8217;t nobody got time for that.</p>
<p>I also think of a gift I once received in Colombia of a set of pillows, one of which had my name crookedly embroidered inside a heart. You can probably guess whose name was in the other heart. As far as <em>cursi</em> goes, I&#8217;m pretty sure those pillows take the cake. And yet, very much out of character, I loved those pillows and not in spite of their adamant cheesiness but rather because of it. They were sincere, they were made and given with so much love, and their very existence was a brave, unironic, and unambivalent celebration of something very beautiful and worthy of praise, even if it were to later prove ephemeral. What am I, too good for <em>cursilería</em>? Of course not. Love is always worth celebrating, albeit imperfectly, albeit cheesily, albeit precipitately, albeit years after the fact.</p>
<p>In sum: What is love if not <em>cursi</em>? Love is supremely sentimental and gushy and ridiculous. And love means leaving your self-consciousness at the door, as well as your ego. I feel like you&#8217;re not really in love if you&#8217;re not regularly making a fool of yourself! But why hide our cheesiness within the safe confines of relationships? I admire people who can unblushingly own their feelings, hopes, and even disappointments without pussyfooting or pretending to not care all that much anyway. Although <i>cursi </i>people could use some work in the originality department, at least they care in the first place. There&#8217;s a lamentable epidemic of nonchalance and numbness and self-absorption these days, and cheesiness is a much better alternative to these terrible modes of subpar living. The way I see it, life is about caring. And since people have been caring for millennia, it&#8217;s awfully hard to express your care in a way that millions of other people haven&#8217;t already done. So, go ahead and be <em>cursi</em>. Those who would snarl and say bah humbug and rain on your parade have their own issues&#8211;just feel sorry for them. Ricardo Arjona, I still don&#8217;t like your music, but I respect you for sharing your <em>cursi </em>soul with us. There are certainly worse ways to be.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2723/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2723/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2723&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://vocabat.com/2013/03/11/cursi/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>21</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/1664ac9f58fbe08ce56a3609ecfa8c32?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">vocabat</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://vocabat.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/cursii.gif" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Cursi elefante</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://vocabat.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/128.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Happy everyday</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is Street Art&#8230;Art?</title>
		<link>http://hmunro.wordpress.com/2013/03/03/is-street-art-art/</link>
		<comments>http://hmunro.wordpress.com/2013/03/03/is-street-art-art/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2013 02:11:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>hmunro</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Paris]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Psychology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Banksy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chet Abraham]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Musée de la Poste]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Paris. street art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[street art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[urban art]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://hmunro.wordpress.com/?p=8446</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Is street art &#8230; art? I&#8217;ve often asked myself this question as I&#8217;ve strolled the streets of Paris. And now, thanks to an exhibit at Paris&#8217; Musée de La Poste, I can answer with a definitive &#8220;YES.&#8221; The exhibit Au-delá du Street Art brought together the work of many well-known urban artists including Miss.Tic, Banksy, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=8446&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Is street art &#8230; <em>art</em>?</p>
<p><a href="http://hmunro.wordpress.com/2011/07/03/where-graffiti-intersects-with-art/" target="_blank">I&#8217;ve often asked myself this question</a> as I&#8217;ve strolled the streets of Paris. And now, thanks to an exhibit at Paris&#8217; <a href="http://www.laposte.fr/adressemusee/visites-et-expositions/les-expositions-temporaires" target="_blank">Musée de La Poste</a>, I can answer with a definitive &#8220;YES.&#8221;</p>
<p>The exhibit <a href="http://butterflyartnews.com/2012/11/23/paris-au-dela-du-street-art-musee-de-la-poste/" target="_blank">Au-delá du Street Art</a> brought together the work of many well-known urban artists including Miss.Tic, <a href="http://www.banksy.co.uk/" target="_blank">Banksy</a>, Dran, Invader, Swoon and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shepard_Fairey" target="_blank">Shepard Fairey</a>.</p>
<p><a href="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-show-1030346-blog.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-8465" alt="Street art show 1030346 BLOG" src="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-show-1030346-blog.jpg?w=500&#038;h=333" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-show-1030358-blog.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-8467" alt="Street art show 1030358 BLOG" src="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-show-1030358-blog.jpg?w=500&#038;h=333" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-show-1030360-blog.jpg"><img alt="Street art show 1030360 BLOG" src="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-show-1030360-blog.jpg?w=500&#038;h=333" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-show-1030359-blog.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-8468" alt="Street art show 1030359 BLOG" src="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-show-1030359-blog.jpg?w=438&#038;h=648" width="438" height="648" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-show-1030361-blog.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-8470" alt="Street art show 1030361 BLOG" src="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-show-1030361-blog.jpg?w=500&#038;h=333" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p>I loved Dran&#8217;s droll take on TinTin&#8217;s adventures in France. &#8220;Because of a strike, no trains will run today,&#8221; reads the sign.</p>
<p><a href="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-tin-tin-1030410-fb.jpg"><img alt="Street art Tin Tin 1030410 FB" src="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-tin-tin-1030410-fb.jpg?w=467&#038;h=648" width="467" height="648" /></a></p>
<p>I also loved seeing Invader&#8217;s mosaics up close, along with a video of him working.</p>
<p><a href="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-show-1030362-blog.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-8471" alt="Street art show 1030362 BLOG" src="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-show-1030362-blog.jpg?w=500&#038;h=327" width="500" height="327" /></a></p>
<p>I was stunned by the quality of some of the works &#8230;</p>
<p><a href="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-show-1030373-blog.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-8472" alt="Street art show 1030373 BLOG" src="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-show-1030373-blog.jpg?w=500&#038;h=333" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p>&#8230; amused by their subversive humor  &#8230;</p>
<p><a href="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-show-1030385-blog.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-8474" alt="Street art show 1030385 BLOG" src="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-show-1030385-blog.jpg?w=500&#038;h=333" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-show-1030389-blog.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-8475" alt="Street art show 1030389 BLOG" src="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-show-1030389-blog.jpg?w=420&#038;h=648" width="420" height="648" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-show-1030405-blog.jpg"><img alt="Street art show 1030405 BLOG" src="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-show-1030405-blog.jpg?w=432&#038;h=648" width="432" height="648" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-show-1030394-blog.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-8476" alt="Street art show 1030394 BLOG" src="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-show-1030394-blog.jpg?w=500&#038;h=333" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p>&#8230; and charmed or moved by a few others.</p>
<p><a href="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-show-1030418-blog.jpg"><img alt="Street art show 1030418 BLOG" src="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-show-1030418-blog.jpg?w=500&#038;h=333" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-show-1030397-blog.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-8477" alt="Street art show 1030397 BLOG" src="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-show-1030397-blog.jpg?w=436&#038;h=648" width="436" height="648" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-show-1030416-blog.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-8479" alt="Street art show 1030416 BLOG" src="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-show-1030416-blog.jpg?w=500&#038;h=645" width="500" height="645" /></a></p>
<p>I enjoyed seeing the next generation of street-artists-in-the-making, huddled here for a lecture about Dran&#8217;s methods and message.</p>
<p><a href="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-show-1030419-blog.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-8481" alt="Street art show 1030419 BLOG" src="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-show-1030419-blog.jpg?w=500&#038;h=333" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p>But most of all I loved seeing Miss.Tic&#8217;s work in the museum &#8230;</p>
<p><a href="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-exhibit-misstic-1030354-blog.jpg"><img alt="Street art exhibit Misstic 1030354 BLOG" src="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-exhibit-misstic-1030354-blog.jpg?w=500&#038;h=333" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p>&#8230; and then recognizing it again on the streets of Paris. &#8220;I know who painted this!&#8221; I felt like telling the oblivious passersby.</p>
<p><a href="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-1030858-blog.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-8483" alt="Street art 1030858 BLOG" src="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-1030858-blog.jpg?w=432&#038;h=648" width="432" height="648" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-1030867-blog.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-8484" alt="Street art 1030867 BLOG" src="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-1030867-blog.jpg?w=432&#038;h=648" width="432" height="648" /></a></p>
<p>For me, that&#8217;s one of the cool things about street art: It fades into the background until you notice it. But once you notice it, you see it everywhere — like these slightly, um, <em>enhanced</em> &#8220;Do not enter&#8221; signs by <a href="http://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Clet_Abraham" target="_blank">Chet Abraham</a>.</p>
<p><a href="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/no-entry-sign-1020688-blog.jpg"><img id="i-8440" alt="Image" src="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/no-entry-sign-1020688-blog.jpg?w=422" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/no-entry-sign-1030965-blog.jpg"><img id="i-8447" alt="Image" src="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/no-entry-sign-1030965-blog.jpg?w=422" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/no-entry-sign-1030746-blog.jpg"><img id="i-8442" alt="Image" src="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/no-entry-sign-1030746-blog.jpg?w=422" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/no-entry-sign-1040161-blog.jpg"><img id="i-8451" alt="Image" src="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/no-entry-sign-1040161-blog.jpg?w=422" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/no-entry-sign-1040010-blog.jpg"><img id="i-8450" alt="Image" src="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/no-entry-sign-1040010-blog.jpg?w=422" /></a></p>
<p>Soon, I was spotting fun variations, like this one in the <em>Marais</em> &#8230;</p>
<p><a href="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/no-entry-sign-1020689-blog.jpg"><img id="i-8441" alt="Image" src="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/no-entry-sign-1020689-blog.jpg?w=638" /></a></p>
<p>&#8230; and this one, just outside the <em>Palais de Justice</em> &#8230;</p>
<p><a href="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/no-entry-sign-1030957-blog.jpg"><img id="i-8444" alt="Image" src="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/no-entry-sign-1030957-blog.jpg?w=411" /></a></p>
<p>&#8230; and this one, near a row of restaurants along the <em>Quai St. Michel</em> &#8230;</p>
<p><a href="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/no-entry-sign-1030826-blog.jpg"><img id="i-8443" alt="Image" src="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/no-entry-sign-1030826-blog.jpg?w=422" /></a></p>
<p>&#8230; and these, near the <em>Place Dauphine</em>.</p>
<p><a href="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/no-entry-sign-1030963-blog.jpg"><img id="i-8445" alt="Image" src="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/no-entry-sign-1030963-blog.jpg?w=422" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/no-entry-sign-1030969-blog.jpg"><img id="i-8448" alt="Image" src="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/no-entry-sign-1030969-blog.jpg?w=422" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/no-entry-sign-1030970-blog.jpg"><img id="i-8449" alt="Image" src="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/no-entry-sign-1030970-blog.jpg?w=422" /></a></p>
<p>I even found a knock-off of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vitruvian_Man" target="_blank">The Vitruvian Man</a>!</p>
<p><a href="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/no-entry-sign-1040177-blog.jpg"><img id="i-8452" alt="Image" src="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/no-entry-sign-1040177-blog.jpg?w=416" /></a></p>
<p>So by the time I saw Abraham&#8217;s work included in an ad paid for by the city of Paris, I wasn&#8217;t too surprised.</p>
<p><a href="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/no-entry-sign-sign-1040933-blog.jpg"><img id="i-8455" alt="Image" src="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/no-entry-sign-sign-1040933-blog.jpg?w=638" /></a></p>
<p>There are some who say street art makes the city look dirty and sloppy, that it&#8217;s vandalism of private property.</p>
<p><a href="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-1030788-blog.jpg"><img alt="Street art 1030788 BLOG" src="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-1030788-blog.jpg?w=432&#038;h=648" width="432" height="648" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-1030461-blog.jpg"><img alt="Street art 1030461 BLOG" src="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-1030461-blog.jpg?w=500&#038;h=333" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-st-mich-1030695-blog.jpg"><img alt="Street art st mich 1030695 BLOG" src="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-st-mich-1030695-blog.jpg?w=500&#038;h=333" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-1030871-blog.jpg"><img alt="Street art 1030871 BLOG" src="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-1030871-blog.jpg?w=500&#038;h=333" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-1040370-blog.jpg"><img alt="Street art 1040370 BLOG" src="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-1040370-blog.jpg?w=500&#038;h=333" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p>But others maintain that street art is our zeitgeist &#8230; an expression of who we are.</p>
<p><a href="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-doudou-1010256-cr-blog.jpg"><img alt="Street art doudou 1010256 CR BLOG" src="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-doudou-1010256-cr-blog.jpg?w=412&#038;h=648" width="412" height="648" /></a></p>
<p>Regardless of how you feel about it, I hope you can at least agree that it&#8217;s <em>art</em>.</p>
<p><a href="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-1010224-blog.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-8486" alt="Street art 1010224 BLOG" src="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-1010224-blog.jpg?w=432&#038;h=648" width="432" height="648" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-1020715-blog.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-8487" alt="Street art 1020715 BLOG" src="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-1020715-blog.jpg?w=500&#038;h=333" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-1020729-blog.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-8488" alt="Street art 1020729 BLOG" src="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-1020729-blog.jpg?w=500&#038;h=333" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-marais-1020682-blog.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-8495" alt="Street art marais 1020682 BLOG" src="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-marais-1020682-blog.jpg?w=432&#038;h=648" width="432" height="648" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-marais-1020682-detail-blog.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-8496" alt="Street art marais 1020682 detail BLOG" src="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-marais-1020682-detail-blog.jpg?w=418&#038;h=648" width="418" height="648" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-marais-1020685-blog.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-8497" alt="Street art marais 1020685 BLOG" src="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-marais-1020685-blog.jpg?w=500&#038;h=318" width="500" height="318" /></a></p>
<p>And if you don&#8217;t like it? Don&#8217;t worry. What&#8217;s here today &#8230;</p>
<p><a href="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2010/09/rue-du-chat-qui-peche-1040557-blog.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2058" alt="Rue du Chat qui Peche 1040557 BLOG" src="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2010/09/rue-du-chat-qui-peche-1040557-blog.jpg?w=500&#038;h=333" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p>&#8230; will be gone tomorrow.</p>
<p><a href="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/chat-qui-peche-1030645-blog1.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-8514" alt="Chat qui peche 1030645 BLOG" src="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/chat-qui-peche-1030645-blog1.jpg?w=432&#038;h=648" width="432" height="648" /></a></p>
<p>This is <del>street</del> art. Grrrrrr!</p>
<p><a href="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-this-is-1020721-fb.jpg"><img alt="Street art this is 1020721 FB" src="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-this-is-1020721-fb.jpg?w=432&#038;h=648" width="432" height="648" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/8446/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/8446/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=8446&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://hmunro.wordpress.com/2013/03/03/is-street-art-art/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>15</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/039975330492a57d6a90fcc49ad5b62b?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">hmunro</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-show-1030346-blog.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Street art show 1030346 BLOG</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-show-1030358-blog.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Street art show 1030358 BLOG</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-show-1030360-blog.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Street art show 1030360 BLOG</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-show-1030359-blog.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Street art show 1030359 BLOG</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-show-1030361-blog.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Street art show 1030361 BLOG</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-tin-tin-1030410-fb.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Street art Tin Tin 1030410 FB</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-show-1030362-blog.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Street art show 1030362 BLOG</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-show-1030373-blog.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Street art show 1030373 BLOG</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-show-1030385-blog.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Street art show 1030385 BLOG</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-show-1030389-blog.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Street art show 1030389 BLOG</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-show-1030405-blog.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Street art show 1030405 BLOG</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-show-1030394-blog.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Street art show 1030394 BLOG</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-show-1030418-blog.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Street art show 1030418 BLOG</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-show-1030397-blog.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Street art show 1030397 BLOG</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-show-1030416-blog.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Street art show 1030416 BLOG</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-show-1030419-blog.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Street art show 1030419 BLOG</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-exhibit-misstic-1030354-blog.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Street art exhibit Misstic 1030354 BLOG</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-1030858-blog.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Street art 1030858 BLOG</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-1030867-blog.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Street art 1030867 BLOG</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/no-entry-sign-1020688-blog.jpg?w=422" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/no-entry-sign-1030965-blog.jpg?w=422" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/no-entry-sign-1030746-blog.jpg?w=422" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/no-entry-sign-1040161-blog.jpg?w=422" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/no-entry-sign-1040010-blog.jpg?w=422" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/no-entry-sign-1020689-blog.jpg?w=638" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/no-entry-sign-1030957-blog.jpg?w=411" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/no-entry-sign-1030826-blog.jpg?w=422" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/no-entry-sign-1030963-blog.jpg?w=422" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/no-entry-sign-1030969-blog.jpg?w=422" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/no-entry-sign-1030970-blog.jpg?w=422" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/no-entry-sign-1040177-blog.jpg?w=416" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/no-entry-sign-sign-1040933-blog.jpg?w=638" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-1030788-blog.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Street art 1030788 BLOG</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-1030461-blog.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Street art 1030461 BLOG</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-st-mich-1030695-blog.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Street art st mich 1030695 BLOG</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-1030871-blog.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Street art 1030871 BLOG</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-1040370-blog.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Street art 1040370 BLOG</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-doudou-1010256-cr-blog.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Street art doudou 1010256 CR BLOG</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-1010224-blog.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Street art 1010224 BLOG</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-1020715-blog.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Street art 1020715 BLOG</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-1020729-blog.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Street art 1020729 BLOG</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-marais-1020682-blog.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Street art marais 1020682 BLOG</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-marais-1020682-detail-blog.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Street art marais 1020682 detail BLOG</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-marais-1020685-blog.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Street art marais 1020685 BLOG</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2010/09/rue-du-chat-qui-peche-1040557-blog.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Rue du Chat qui Peche 1040557 BLOG</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/chat-qui-peche-1030645-blog1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Chat qui peche 1030645 BLOG</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hmunro.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/street-art-this-is-1020721-fb.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Street art this is 1020721 FB</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sisters Got 99 Problems: Will Pope Francis Be One?</title>
		<link>http://broadsspeak.wordpress.com/2013/03/15/sisters-got-99-problems-will-pope-francis-be-one/</link>
		<comments>http://broadsspeak.wordpress.com/2013/03/15/sisters-got-99-problems-will-pope-francis-be-one/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 16:17:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>ashleighimus</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Catholic Church]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inquisition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jay-Z]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nuns]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pope Francis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vatican]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://broadsspeak.wordpress.com/?p=19</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Quick, what do Jay-Z and American nuns have in common? Answer: More than you might think. Jay-Z’s classic 99 Problems tells of how not women but the police are the biggest threat against him (okay he doesn’t say &#8220;women&#8221; but let us overlook for the moment his precise term). For progressive nuns, it is not [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=19&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://broadsspeak.wordpress.com/2013/03/15/sisters-got-99-problems-will-pope-francis-be-one/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/cf9db5ee0daacb06b5bb67761d6ab096?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ashleighimus</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://broadsspeak.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/cropped-dscn0322.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cropped-dscn0322.jpg</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>For Roger</title>
		<link>http://etheriel.wordpress.com/2013/04/05/for-roger/</link>
		<comments>http://etheriel.wordpress.com/2013/04/05/for-roger/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2013 11:23:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Grace</dc:creator>
		
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://etheriel.wordpress.com/?p=1903</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[“Start writing. Short sentences. Describe it. Just describe it.” Roger said, when I asked him about writer’s block. Then he quoted the first three paragraphs of his &#8220;Persona&#8221; review and told me that it had completely baffled him in 1967 but this strategy worked brilliantly. Tonight, as I sit here numbly staring at the screen [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1903&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-1904" alt="Rog 1" src="http://etheriel.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/img_9777.jpg?w=600&#038;h=400" width="600" height="400" /></p>
<p>“Start writing. Short sentences. Describe it. Just describe it.”</p>
<p>Roger said, when I asked him about writer’s block. Then he quoted the first three paragraphs of his &#8220;Persona&#8221; review and told me that it had completely baffled him in 1967 but this strategy worked brilliantly. Tonight, as I sit here numbly staring at the screen with the hardest writer’s block I’ve ever known, I place my fingers on the keyboard to follow the advice of the greatest man I know, and just describe it.</p>
<p>How do you describe it? Knowing Roger Ebert. Most people gasp in delight at the mention of his name, usually followed by outpourings of affections, “I grew up reading him,” they would say, “I watched him every week!” The connection is always personal. The love deep.</p>
<p>I didn’t know him like that. I didn’t grow up reading him and only caught At The Movies on television occasionally. We met through the internet – as writers – after he had lost the ability to speak, and that is where majority of our conversations took place. It started with a comment about &#8220;The Hurt Locker&#8221; that quickly descended into emails, and haiku, and then there was never a reason to stop. Roger is a natural conversationalist and a collector of interesting people. He loved holding court, even virtually, and playing matchmaker linking people together, introducing and shuffling. He had an innate sense for character and impeccable judgment of situations and he was proud of that, telling me that it was a gift. He brought the Far-Flung Correspondents together, even though at the beginning I thought it was bold if presumptuous – who is going to read about a couple random strangers talk about movies on the net just because Roger Ebert decided they should? But he was delighted in the idea and convinced that it was valuable, and he proceeded to make it happen. I remember standing at a freezing bus stop one winter morning on my way to a soul-crunching job when I got the email from Roger asking me to write for him. Feeling inadequate, I asked for time to think about it. “Why?” He asked. “I don’t have any academic background in film,” I said. “And you think I did?” “But I’m not you!” “You’re not me, that’s why I need you on the site. You are going to end up in a very interesting place in this lifetime.”</p>
<p>Those words sank into me like a shot to the heart, and I have never forgotten them.</p>
<p>And that’s how he was: persistent, decisive, wise, and generous. He embraced people from all walks of life with all kinds of beliefs. He was incredibly open-minded and thoughtful. Intensely curious – if something caught his attention he will focus on it until he figures it out. He also had a great reserve of sympathy and used them with abandon, especially for those who need them. He kept up correspondences with people who he feared would be lost without them, for years. He forwarded to selected friends letters of cries for help that he would receive, sometimes a stranger’s devastating life story, and asked for support. He was always busy and on a deadline but these stories kept coming, and he always found time for them when he could.</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-1905" alt="Rog 2" src="http://etheriel.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/img_9778.jpg?w=600&#038;h=400" width="600" height="400" /></p>
<p>I’m making it sound like I know him, and out of the hundreds and thousands of emails we’ve exchanged perhaps I do know a part of him, but not all. He was an intensely private person and one who kept great many friends, to each he has a particular personal connection to. I can’t help but feel that every one of those lucky people would feel exactly how I feel, having been basked in the glow of such a generous and joyful spirit.</p>
<p>In our short time I did come to know one side of Roger: his poetic, idealistic side, and that is the one we bonded over. He loved haiku and appreciated the Romantic poets. He could quote Yeats at the drop of a hat and work sonnets into an otherwise mundane paragraph that makes you wonder how it could have existed without. His fierce intelligence was unparalleled, and you could sense the gears turning, jolting, from one to the other. It is not unlike him to cover topics of philosophy, politics, culture, and film all in one email, before finishing it with a poetic flourish.</p>
<p>And then there was Ebertfest, the annual gathering of all that he loved in his home town of Champaign-Urbana, Illinois. I, along with the rest of the FFCs, was inducted into the circle of guests four years ago and made to feel at once at home. Roger organized a special brunch just for the Correspondents in that first year, all of whom he had never met, and spent time with each person, asking about their families, looking at the gifts presented to him from foreign lands, and patiently jotting down concise and hilarious notes that he would then ask someone to read aloud. We sat there and looked forward to those notes, those brief moments of connections from him. We all loved him and admired him. He sat on a couch against the wall or on a special lazy-boy armchair at the back of the beautiful Virginia theater and people huddled around him, taking photos and asking for autographs and telling him how much he means to them. He patiently indulged every request. At times you could tell he wanted to say something but couldn’t before the moment was gone and it frustrated him, but he never let it slow him down. He was always there and he was loved.</p>
<p>And that was what it came down to: how deeply and fiercely and widely Roger was loved by all who knew and did not know him. He was that kind of person: an inimitable man, a passionate soul, generous spirit, and utterly one of a kind. Beyond it all, he made it personal. Always. He believed in goodness and he lived it, every day. He loved Chaz and his family completely and he told the world about them. Millions of people are mourning the loss of someone whose words have touched them and resonated with that of their own. He never spoke from above – even though he had the power – he spoke from the heart.</p>
<p>And it is from the heart that this deep hole will remain. I have been lucky to know him, to love him, to scribble random notes and long thoughts to him, to be privy to his friendship and his protection. It is a pure honor. To me, he was a complicated mix of protective big brother, patient mentor, and loyal friend. He accepted everything I had to offer, spotted what I didn’t even know I had, and nurtured them, as he did for many others. He sent me my first Criterion film and introduced me to Simenon, Colette, Cather, McCarthy. We talked about Bresson. “You know… when someone falls in love with Bresson, it&#8217;s the sign of a true cineaste. Not everybody does.” A few weeks later, <i>Notes on the Cinematographer</i> by Bresson arrived in the mail. I didn’t tell him about my first film until it was finished. He never asked why, only that I send a DVD instead of an online screener. Then he wrote me a beautiful note, and it was enough. I’m not sure why he believed, but I am so, so grateful.</p>
<p>And that is all. When I saw the news on twitter (which he fittingly got me onto), I stared for a full long while and then clicked refresh, and refresh, and refresh, until the condolences started to blur and my chest felt hollow. I cried. I called my dearest friends and told them what an amazing person he was and how it is unfair and how I wish there was more time, but there was not. Then I found myself walking outside, down streets, walking like Rog once loved to do. It was sunny and people were coming home from work and everyone looked happy, but I felt numb. Eventually I ended up at a park that overlooked the freeway down a grassy hill with the sun shining brightly and dogs running around, playing (he would’ve liked that). I picked a spot and sat down, clasped my hands, looked to the tallest tip of a lone power tower on the horizon and said my goodbyes. Then, a gust of wind blew by, and I thought maybe somewhere he is looking down and saying: Gracie, I’ll get back to you.</p>
<div id="attachment_1906" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><img class="size-large wp-image-1906   " alt="Rog 3" src="http://etheriel.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/img_9779.jpg?w=600&#038;h=400" width="600" height="400" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Chicago, May 2011. Photos by Grace Wang</p></div>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1903/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1903/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1903&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://etheriel.wordpress.com/2013/04/05/for-roger/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>32</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/dd47d91291cdbbc8acc2ab0bac2db9f9?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F1.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Grace</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://etheriel.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/img_9777.jpg?w=600" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Rog 1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://etheriel.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/img_9778.jpg?w=600" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Rog 2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://etheriel.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/img_9779.jpg?w=600" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Rog 3</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Iconic</title>
		<link>http://tuckedintoacorner.wordpress.com/2013/04/02/wordpress-weekly-writing-challenge-iconic/</link>
		<comments>http://tuckedintoacorner.wordpress.com/2013/04/02/wordpress-weekly-writing-challenge-iconic/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 03:03:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tuckedintoacorner</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Humour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Miscellaneous]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boots]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clothing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPchallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iconic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[postaday]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tuckedintoacorner.wordpress.com/?p=222</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[For this week’s challenge, we want you to snap a photo of something that is iconic to you. It can even be a picture of your favorite pair of shoes that you wear nearly every day and has come to personify your personal style. Morning. The human drags herself out of bed and we wait by [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=222&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><i>For this week’s challenge, we want you to snap a photo of something that is iconic to you. It can even be a picture of your favorite pair of shoes that you wear nearly every day and has come to personify your personal style.</i></p>
<p><i>Morning</i>. The human drags herself out of bed and we wait by the wardrobe door. Nowadays it’s winter, and so we don’t get to live inside the big cozy space that our colleagues do. Still, we shiver and don’t protest, proud that the human relies on us so much. Our other colleagues are relegated to the rack, tucked away and hibernating. We like to think she chooses us so often because we are the best of the lot: in winter, scruffy sneakers and flimsy flats just can&#8217;t compete. Normally we can tell if the human is up with a good amount of time, or if she has overslept: if it’s the former, she’ll idly make lunch and gather her things. If it’s the latter, she’ll rush around, yank fabric on her feet and reach for us, then flutter around in a panic finding keys, books and mutter about buying lunch.</p>
<p>She keeps us on standby, probably so as not to have to dig around for us. We stand tall and proud by the door, ready and waiting. If she’s in a temper, which does seem to happen as she’s not a morning person, she’ll stomp around and it does irritate us a little bit. <i>Can’t she calm down or at least be a bit gentler?</i> Calm down, she does not: she has been known to express irritation with thrown items or kicked doors. We are careful not to leave scuff marks.</p>
<p>Sometimes we have to wait while she fusses around, makeup or selecting another top, and we just have to be graceful and obliging about it.</p>
<p>Once she’s done with her morning house-ritual, we walk together to the big vehicle that takes her to university. It’s a brief walk, but utterly silent. The human walks alone, and she jams little white things in her ears and takes out a little metal box. Occasionally sounds spill out from the box, and we suppose she must be listening to something quite loud. We must hinder her walking progress, because sometimes she looks down the road and sees the vehicle coming, and doesn’t get to the stop in time. This is when she’ll sometimes curse quietly and possibly scuff us against the ground; whether she is punishing us, or just annoyed at waiting, we can’t tell.</p>
<p>On the vehicle, we sit quietly. She takes out a book and either reads or writes, or just sits and listens to music. It’s often that she’ll stare out the window. Some days, which especially annoy her, are the ones where the vehicle has so many humans that some have to stand.</p>
<p><i>Midday.</i> The human will be at university and it’s our busiest time. She scuffs over pavement, taps over tiles, kicks leaves aside and digs her foot into soft flooring. We see hundreds, thousands of humans every day, and no two people are the same. These humans carry books with strange words and intriguing titles. Our human is interested by some, as we see by the way she tilts her head to get a better look at the book-spine and we imagine that she would want to study such things. Her own books are quite fascinating, we think, but we never get a chance to prove this theory because she doesn’t read aloud much. Sometimes she does, and the words are funny words, not at all the kind we hear in daily conversation.</p>
<p>The humans also carry bags and shiny boxes with which they take notes or talk to others. We wonder what we might be inclined to do if we were human for a day.</p>
<p>Our human often sits near her next class and has lunch. Other humans will join her and they will talk about anything. She will sometimes ask random questions or make idle comments, and the people will look at her like she might be speaking another language. Then again, given that she likes to read funny-word languages, she well might be.  She does speak a second language, too – not the funny words she reads aloud, but something different.</p>
<p>In class, we sit and listen quietly. We are interested by all the things the lecturing human is talking about; we don’t always understand it, but it sounds clever. Our human likes clever, and she diligently scribbles her notes. She comments that her handwriting is terrible, but we are hidden under her desk and we can’t see for ourselves.</p>
<p>Classes finish and the human walks to another place to get the big vehicle home. She doesn’t linger at university much; after class, she packs away her books and chats a bit with other humans before drifting away and calling her ‘see you later’. It’s around this time that we might punish her by hurting her legs or ankles; she will sometimes retaliate with threats to replace us, to throw us into the very back of the wardrobe where we shall never see the light of day again. The threat always works, and we behave ourselves. We don’t want to be tossed aside and forgotten.</p>
<p><i>Evening.</i> We have reached another evening. The human tugs us off and sets us down. She yawns and it’s evident she likes evenings better than mornings. Over the next few hours she comes alive again, waking up more and doing various tasks. We watch as she heads to the dining room for dinner, puts the radio on or flips it off with a murmur about a horrible piece of noise, not to be dignified with the title of <i>song</i>. At times she will put on our cousins, but the cousins look softer and more comfortable. We envy our cousins, who are not so tall and glossy.</p>
<p>Before bed, she will put us by the wardrobe and sometimes coax us into standing straight. By midnight, we are tired and starting to droop a bit. Even when she is asleep, she appears to hear us, and slips out of bed to encourage us to stand up. We do so, and by the light of one of her little metal gadgets, she will sometimes set a pair of the strange feet-fabric by us.</p>
<p>The temperature dips and we hear a clicking sound which is apparently meant to keep her warm. We stand there all night, waiting patiently for the morning when the human will next need us for the day.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/222/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/222/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=222&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tuckedintoacorner.wordpress.com/2013/04/02/wordpress-weekly-writing-challenge-iconic/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tuckedintoacorner.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/img_0076.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://tuckedintoacorner.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/img_0076.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_0076</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/ed1cb5866ab8ae7649c7e1cdc4821e84?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tuckedintoacorner</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Great South Gate of Jeonju: Pungnammun Remembers</title>
		<link>http://greenwalledtower.wordpress.com/2013/04/02/the-great-south-gate-of-jeonju-pungnammun-remembers/</link>
		<comments>http://greenwalledtower.wordpress.com/2013/04/02/the-great-south-gate-of-jeonju-pungnammun-remembers/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 12:26:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>David Stewart</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Dusk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPchallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[history]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iconic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jeonju]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Korea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pungnammun]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://greenwalledtower.wordpress.com/?p=1429</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The Prosperous South Gate they named me, and I have borne that name with pride for centuries. I have been a rampart against attackers and a conduit of prosperity to my people within; the First Fortress of the Honam region, I was the first, the greatest, and now I am the last. I am Pungnammun. [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1429&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://greenwalledtower.wordpress.com/2013/04/02/the-great-south-gate-of-jeonju-pungnammun-remembers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>27</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/69148ccb56f97ff7965c9c73d60e9ea8?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">greenwalledtower</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://greenwalledtower.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/pungnammun-sign.jpg?w=490" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Pungnammun sign</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://greenwalledtower.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/pungnammun-old.jpg?w=490" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Pungnammun in the 19th century. Source.</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://greenwalledtower.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/pungnammun-night.jpg?w=490" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Pungnammun at night</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fixing Education and Cyclical Poverty with Incentivized Parenting</title>
		<link>http://politicdiscourse.com/2013/04/03/fixing-education-and-cyclical-poverty-with-incentivized-parenting/</link>
		<comments>http://politicdiscourse.com/2013/04/03/fixing-education-and-cyclical-poverty-with-incentivized-parenting/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 12:06:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>J. Palmer</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[U.S. Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Welfare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education Reform]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Welfare Reform]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[accountability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poverty]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://politicdiscourse.com/?p=255</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In response to a new legislative proposal in Tennessee that seeks to tie student performance to welfare benefits, David Phillippe at Punditocracy wrote a critical response yesterday deeming the measure a “poverty punishment policy.” As a former public school teacher in a low income school district, some disturbing aspects regarding education in America lead me [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=255&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://politicdiscourse.com/2013/04/03/fixing-education-and-cyclical-poverty-with-incentivized-parenting/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>51</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/fa1cd70c251dc6ecc137f7099c5d0a54?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F0.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">politicdiscourse</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="https://encrypted-tbn3.gstatic.com/images?q=tbn:ANd9GcRAFAw1BbsBEChuZ8GRkQDPJpyIrFWZNvll7bvKBfFQawV9j2QTCA" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://media.economist.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/290-width/images/print-edition/20130119_IRC788_1.png" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Fool and His Folly</title>
		<link>http://marydpierce.com/2013/04/03/a-fool-and-his-folly/</link>
		<comments>http://marydpierce.com/2013/04/03/a-fool-and-his-folly/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 05:15:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>marydpierce</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[DPchallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dreams]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[folly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fools]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stonehenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://marydpierce.com/?p=4282</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There are variations of my grandfather&#8217;s story, but I prefer this one.  Mostly, because it came from my great-aunt Sophie and she never said anything that wasn&#8217;t true.  Or at least, true enough.  She was the keeper of our stories.  From births to deaths, weddings to wakes; new jobs, new homes, new dreams, if it [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4282&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_4286" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 539px"><a href="http://marydpierce.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/iconic-stonehenge-pm-smaller2.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-4286    " alt="iconic stonehenge pm smaller" src="http://marydpierce.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/iconic-stonehenge-pm-smaller2.jpg?w=529&#038;h=541" width="529" height="541" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">This is the photo of Stonehenge that set my grandfather&#8217;s heart ablaze.</p></div>
<p>There are variations of my grandfather&#8217;s story, but I prefer this one.  Mostly, because it came from my great-aunt Sophie and she never said anything that wasn&#8217;t true.  Or at least, <em>true enough</em>.  She was the keeper of our stories.  From births to deaths, weddings to wakes; new jobs, new homes, new dreams, if it involved a Webster, Aunt Sophie wrote it down.  That job fell to me a few years ago when, at the age of eighty-two, she fell off her bicycle, hit her head, and died.</p>
<p>(Let that be a lesson for you &#8212; <em>You are never too old to wear a helmet</em>.  Aunt Sophie would back me up on this if she could.)</p>
<p>This story began fifty years ago when grandpa Webster had a dream.  In it he dreamed that his ancestors had been druids, and this pleased him immensely.  The whole wise man, mystical nature thing.  He thought it might be true.  But, when he told others about it, they said &#8212; <em>Don&#8217;t be daft, you fool</em>.  <em>It&#8217;s just a dream.  </em>So he shut up about it.</p>
<p>Still.  A wisp of the dream remained.</p>
<p>Shortly after that grandpa bought a box.  He was fond of auctions, and even fonder of bidding on <em>blind</em> boxes &#8211; blind in the sense that you had no idea of the contents, but were willing to chance that there might be something of value inside.  In this instance, the thing of value was the tinted photo of Stonehenge you see above.</p>
<p>How that photograph took hold of my grandfather.  He kept it on his nightstand.  It was the last thing he looked to before he closed his eyes, and the first thing he saw upon waking, his wife coming in a poor second.  But she was patient because she loved him.  And she knew about his druid wish.  For even a wisp of a dream carries a sweet, smoky odor that a good spouse can smell.  She went to the public library and brought back a book &#8212; <em>The Stonehenge Myth &#8212; </em>and set it next to the photo on my grandfather&#8217;s side of the bed.</p>
<p>My grandparents owned a small farm at the time.  Eighty acres on which they grew corn and wheat and raised chickens, sheep, and some dairy cows.  (My father grew up on this farm, and knew before he was eighteen that he wanted something else in life, but that&#8217;s another story, for another time.)  Four months after his finding the Stonehenge photo, six months after the druid dream, my grandfather dragged home his first big rock, a four foot by two foot slab of stone that he slid off the back of a flat-bed trailer at the end of the sheep field.  The neighbors wondered what use could be made from a stone that size, but my grandmother had an inkling.</p>
<p>Over the next six months my grandfather brought home twelve more boulders and stone slabs of various sizes.  He paid his four strapping boys and their friends to help him arrange the stones in a circle.  He borrowed a backhoe and a front end loader.  He carried the Stonehenge photograph in his shirt pocket, and when people asked him what in blue blazes was he trying to build, he pulled out the photo and handed it to them.</p>
<p><em>This</em>, he said.  <em>I&#8217;m building this.  It&#8217;s iconic.</em></p>
<p>Some people thought he said <em>ironic</em>.</p>
<p>Over the years my grandfather and his folly became legend.  There were stories told that he danced drunken and naked in the moonlight among those stones.  Aunt Sophie said that wasn&#8217;t true.  She said that he simply found comfort in sitting in that stone circle while the sun rose or set and he could think about the day ahead of or behind him.  It brought him peace.</p>
<p>For my father and his brothers it brought them something else.  There were more than a few times when they and their friends dared one another to strip and whoop it up around the rocks.  For them, it was a level of coolness others didn&#8217;t have.</p>
<p><em>We were the only kids with Stonehenge in our back yard.</em></p>
<p>Fifteen years ago, as my grandparent&#8217;s fiftieth wedding anniversary approached, their sons wanted to gift them with a trip to England, to see the real Stonehenge, they said.  My grandparents turned them down.  Why spend all that money, when they were happy with the one they had?</p>
<p><em>I&#8217;m no fool</em>, my grandfather told his boys.</p>
<p>It was the truest thing I ever heard him say.</p>
<div id="attachment_4305" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 539px"><a href="http://marydpierce.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/a-stonehenge-1-pm1.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-4305" alt="The Webster family Stonehenge that stands in what used to be a sheep pasture on the farm.  The stones are not as big as they look, not nearly like those at the actual Stonehenge, but they were good enough for dancing around in the moonlight." src="http://marydpierce.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/a-stonehenge-1-pm1.jpg?w=529&#038;h=256" width="529" height="256" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The Webster family <em>Stonehenge</em> standing in the sheep pasture on the farm. The stones are not as big as they look, certainly not like those at the actual Stonehenge, but they&#8217;re good enough for dancing around in the moonlight.</p></div>
<p>n.b.  This is not a true story.  It is fiction.  I wanted to see if I had a photo that was iconic to me (for the <a href="http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2013/04/01/weekly-writing-challenge-iconic/">Weekly WP Writing Challenge</a>), and then make up a story to fit the picture.  Also, I <em>have</em> been to the real Stonehenge.  I wasn&#8217;t allowed to dance around the stones, though, naked or otherwise.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4282/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4282/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4282&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://marydpierce.com/2013/04/03/a-fool-and-his-folly/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>76</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/048b4ca39541e4ca73df55c6b09985aa?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">marydpierce</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://marydpierce.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/iconic-stonehenge-pm-smaller2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">iconic stonehenge pm smaller</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://marydpierce.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/a-stonehenge-1-pm1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The Webster family Stonehenge that stands in what used to be a sheep pasture on the farm.  The stones are not as big as they look, not nearly like those at the actual Stonehenge, but they were good enough for dancing around in the moonlight.</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Studio Night Saved my Marriage</title>
		<link>http://projectophile.wordpress.com/2013/04/03/how-studio-night-saved-my-marriage/</link>
		<comments>http://projectophile.wordpress.com/2013/04/03/how-studio-night-saved-my-marriage/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 16:24:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Clare</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://projectophile.wordpress.com/?p=514</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[“But there never seems to be enough time, to do the things you want to do once you find them…” &#8211;Jim Croce:  Musician, Lover, Dreamer, Mustache-Wearer A funny thing happens when you commit your life to another person:   You don’t get to do what you want all the time. Then the two of you make [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=514&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong><span style="color:#ff00ff;"><em>“But there never seems to be enough time, to do the things you want to do once you find them…”</em></span></strong><br />
&#8211;Jim Croce:  Musician, Lover, Dreamer, Mustache-Wearer</p>
<div id="attachment_508" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 347px"><a href="http://projectophile.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/jimcroce.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-508   " alt="jimcroce" src="http://projectophile.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/jimcroce.jpg?w=337&#038;h=337" width="337" height="337" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Jim never took anything for granted. Which is good, cause he died in a plane crash in 1973.</p></div>
<p>A funny thing happens when you commit your life to another person:   You don’t get to do what you want all the time.</p>
<p>Then the two of you make a new little person (or two or three), and then you really can’t do anything that you want, EVER.   You can’t get drunk and spontaneously  board a bus to Milwaukee.  You can’t eat ice cream for dinner.  You can’t get busy in the parking lot behind Radio Shack.*  You can’t even keep fresh cut flowers on the table, because certain little people will knock over the vase, spill the water and eat the flowers.</p>
<p>Don’t get me wrong—despite what my combat-boot-wearing self said 15 years ago about perpetuating the oppression of the patriarchy— I love being married.  I adore my children.  Being trapped in this straightjacket of domesticity is like being embraced in a warm, sticky hug, 24 hours a day, and I wouldn&#8217;t trade it for anything.</p>
<div id="attachment_512" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 378px"><a href="http://projectophile.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/whatdidijustdo.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-512  " alt="WHATDIDIJUSTDO" src="http://projectophile.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/whatdidijustdo.jpg?w=368&#038;h=392" width="368" height="392" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">When you get married in a basement, it&#8217;s all uphill from there.</p></div>
<p style="text-align:left;">However, there comes a time when you have to scrape off the boogers, pull on some real pants (with a belt), and shift your energy to more creative pursuits.  But, girl, it’s not as easy as it sounds.</p>
<p>Since I’ve started this blog, a couple of people have asked me, “where do you find the time to do all this crap?”  And the answer is, STUDIO NIGHT!</p>
<p><em>(Also, my house usually looks like this:)</em><br />
<a href="http://projectophile.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/picture-1143.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-511" alt="Picture 1143" src="http://projectophile.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/picture-1143.jpg?w=584&#038;h=421" width="584" height="421" /></a>Strangely, nobody ever asks Scott where he finds the time for his comics, but if they did, the answer would be “STUDIO NIGHT!” (plus a day job where nobody seems to pay attention to what he’s doing).</p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><strong><span style="color:#ff00ff;">WHAT IS STUDIO NIGHT?</span></strong><br />
STUDIO NIGHT is on Monday.  It starts when the kids go to bed. It ends when we go to bed.  It lasts about 3 hours.  There’s no TV watching, no talking about our days or about our feelings or what needs to be done around the house.  There is only doing.</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration:underline;">There are two simple rules to STUDIO NIGHT:</span><br />
<strong>1)    Do something creative</strong><br />
<strong>2)    Don’t bother me</strong></p>
<p><strong><span style="color:#ff00ff;">A BRIEF HISTORY OF STUDIO NIGHT:</span> </strong><br />
When I met Scott, he was already a father to an adorable 4-year-old boy.  We quickly settled into a routine that revolved around the custody schedule: Max nights (Tuesday, Thursday, every other weekend), and Date nights (Monday and Wednesday).  There was always enough time to spend with Max, and each other, and alone.  This worked well for a few years.</p>
<div id="attachment_517" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 441px"><a href="http://projectophile.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/215772_1015440498649_8312_n.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-517" alt="See why I married him?" src="http://projectophile.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/215772_1015440498649_8312_n.jpg?w=431&#038;h=296" width="431" height="296" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">See why I married him?</p></div>
<p style="text-align:left;">Then, in the span of 4 short years, Scott and I got married, had a baby, and then had another baby.   Oh, and I lost my job right before the first baby was born.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Suddenly, I was a full-time mommy.   I loved my babies, but at the end of the day I wanted nothing more than a glass of wine and some adult conversation.  I didn’t care so much about art, or writing, or making stuff.   It was enough to get through another day.</p>
<div id="attachment_513" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 536px"><a href="http://projectophile.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/img_2985.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-513 " alt="IMG_2985" src="http://projectophile.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/img_2985.jpg?w=526&#038;h=394" width="526" height="394" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Whoah, how did this happen?</p></div>
<p style="text-align:left;">I never stopped to think about how quickly the trajectory of life had changed.  My entire adult life &#8212; including college &#8212; had been occupied by challenging jobs that were full of outlets for creativity and even humor (like constructing a giant pair of women’s panties for a <a href="http://www.hospitalitynet.org/news/4017850.html" target="_blank">street theater action on Michigan Avenue,</a>  or orchestrating this <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zoX2PL-DTEA" target="_blank">Billion Dollar Bake Sale</a> in the state capitol).</p>
<p>I was used to sharing my days (and many evenings) with smart, passionate, funny adults.  And now they were shared with stinky, whiny, endlessly needy children.  I did get another job, but one that allowed me to stay home with the second baby.</p>
<p>Scott managed to keep up his gaming and other hobbies, and I’m not sure he understood my hunger to just DO NOTHING every night after the kids went down.  I tried to write, but it went nowhere.  Meanwhile, as Scott got more serious about his comics, we designated one or two nights a week for him to do nothing but draw. I <a href="http://kingcrowcomics.blogspot.com/2012/05/joy-of-supportive-wiferoad-to-cake-part.html">supported him wholeheartedly</a>, but inside I was feeling lonely and stuck.</p>
<div id="attachment_509" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 309px"><a href="http://projectophile.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/picture-690.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-509   " alt="Picture 690" src="http://projectophile.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/picture-690.jpg?w=299&#038;h=450" width="299" height="450" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Scott&#8217;s first comic expo. As you can see, I&#8217;m dying inside from lack of intellectual stimulation.</p></div>
<p style="text-align:left;">After a few months of self-pity, I stared hard at a list of projects that I could never find the time to finish.  Nothing big;  just little projects around the house, stuff that I could never get done when the kids were awake because they involved needles or power tools or toxic fumes.  Stuff that would make our daily lives just a little bit more beautiful.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Then I used Scott&#8217;s drawing nights to actually finish my projects.  And it felt really good. So I started a blog and promised to update it once a week, to give myself a false sense of accountability (and also because I was jealous that Scott had a blog and I didn’t).</p>
<p>And then &#8212; suddenly &#8212; I had something to write about.  And remembered how much I loved writing, and making beautiful things.  And maybe, how much I loved my husband.</p>
<p>Thank you, STUDIO NIGHT!</p>
<p><span style="color:#ff00ff;"><em>“I’ve looked around enough to know that you’re the one I want to go through time with.”</em></span></p>
<div id="attachment_507" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 384px"><a href="http://projectophile.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/jim-on-stool.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-507" alt="Jim on stool" src="http://projectophile.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/jim-on-stool-e1365004710664.jpg?w=374&#038;h=378" width="374" height="378" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Thanks, Jim!</p></div>
<p><strong><em> *We&#8217;ve never done any of these things.</em> </strong></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/514/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/514/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=514&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://projectophile.wordpress.com/2013/04/03/how-studio-night-saved-my-marriage/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>46</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/1b08a68f35bf8af3ef2cba8f1cd73691?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cfauke</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://projectophile.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/jimcroce.jpg?w=584" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jimcroce</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://projectophile.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/whatdidijustdo.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">WHATDIDIJUSTDO</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://projectophile.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/picture-1143.jpg?w=584" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Picture 1143</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://projectophile.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/215772_1015440498649_8312_n.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">See why I married him?</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://projectophile.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/img_2985.jpg?w=584" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_2985</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://projectophile.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/picture-690.jpg?w=584" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Picture 690</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://projectophile.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/jim-on-stool-e1365004710664.jpg?w=584" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Jim on stool</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
