<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2012 20:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>So Unfit For Purpose, It Couldn\&#8217;t Sort Out a Playground Punch-Up</title>
		<link>http://hughash.wordpress.com/2012/10/18/the-un-so-unfit-for-purpose-it-couldnt-sort-out-a-playground-punch-up/</link>
		<comments>http://hughash.wordpress.com/2012/10/18/the-un-so-unfit-for-purpose-it-couldnt-sort-out-a-playground-punch-up/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2012 13:12:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Hugh Ash</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Religion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Middle East]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Great War]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Iran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Israel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mahmoud ahmadinejad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ottoman Empire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Security Council]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Syria]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Turkey]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://hughash.wordpress.com/?p=904</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[If most folk were asked to name a list of the world’s most influential statesmen, Recep Erdogan’s would hardly trip off the tongue. Yet, as boss of the religiously orthodox AK Justice &#38; Development Party and Turkish Prime Minister for nine years, he heads one of the world’s few, fully-fledged Islamic democracies (and a NATO [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=904&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If most folk were asked to name a list of the world’s most influential statesmen, Recep Erdogan’s would hardly trip off the tongue.</p>
<p>Yet, as boss of the religiously orthodox AK Justice &amp; Development Party and Turkish Prime Minister for nine years, he heads one of the world’s few, fully-fledged Islamic democracies (and a NATO member), so his is a siren voice worth listening to every once in a while.</p>
<p>Erdogan’s had his moments of controversy, notably refusing to fess up to Turkey’s genocide of a million Armenians in 1915. And his backing of the misnamed ‘Peace Flotillas’, crewed by the usual, useful idiots – which tried to breach Israel’s maritime blockade of Gaza, in situ to stop Iranian munitions reaching the Hamas-run enclave – went down like a manky kebab with most of his Western friends.</p>
<p>Nonetheless, following Turkey’s long experience of Ottoman Empire in the Middle East, Erdogan knows much about how and why the region has disintegrated into the powder keg it is today and he can read the ominous runes better than most.</p>
<p>Which is why he recently gave the imperiously inept United Nations – especially the blustering, disjointed Security Council – a piece of his mind, singling out Syria in particular and charging, ‘The UN is losing its credibility by turning a blind eye to what is happening [there]. It is a human tragedy.’</p>
<p>With countless refuges escaping the loathsome Assad regime to camps over the Turkish border and Syrian artillery firing into Turkey – five Turks died and 11 were injured in a recent fusillade – Erdogan is articulating what the West has thought of the discredited UN for decades, but has been too timid to say so.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, he’s ordered his army to retaliate, if further provoked, amid fears the Assads, prompted by the Armageddon-seekers of neighbouring Iran, could escalate the conflict into an all-out, Shiite-versus-Sunni clash – not dissimilar to how ‘a little local difficulty’ in the Balkans, in 1914, ignited the Great War.</p>
<p>Syria, though, is only the tip of an explosive sand-dune and there’s no doubt Erdogan has an agenda to reprise Ottoman-style hegemony over the Middle East.</p>
<p>But he’s right in fingering UN culpability – and the botched peace mission of ex-UN Secretary General, Kofi Annan, to Damascus – in allowing the inter-religious civil war, said to have cost tens of thousands of lives to date, to rage on.</p>
<div id="attachment_905" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 357px"><a href="http://hughash.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/erdogan.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-905" title="erdogan" alt="" src="http://hughash.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/erdogan.jpg?w=347&#038;h=206" height="206" width="347" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">UN KNOCKER: Turkish Prime Minister Erdogan says the organisation is &#8216;losing credibility&#8217;</p></div>
<p>In reality, the UN General Assembly has become a soapbox for fully paid-up members of the nutters’ club, like Iran’s Mahmoud Ahmadinejad.</p>
<p>And the Security Council couldn’t sort out a scrap in a kindergarten schoolyard, while Putin’s Russia supports the indefensible Assads and amoral China couldn’t care a toss, so long as it can continue selling arms to anyone who pays.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, in the odd moments the UN does secure a flimsy degree of unanimity, its ineffectual, ‘Blue Helmet’ peacekeepers too often turn a mess into a downright catastrophe.</p>
<p>Witness the cock-ups they contrived in the 1971 Bangladesh atrocities, the 1994 Rwandan Genocide, not forgetting their abject failure to police the Second Congo War or intervene in the 1995 Srebrenica Massacre.</p>
<p>Failure, in fact, seems to be what the UN excels at when it sends in its bovver boys. Because, among other malfunctions, they failed to deliver food to the starving in strife-torn Somalia and prevent mass murder in Darfur.</p>
<p>And the peacekeepers haven’t exactly covered themselves in glory in other ways, having been accused of corruption, black-marketeering, drug-running and multiple sex crimes during missions to the Congo, Haiti, Liberia, Sudan, what’s now South Sudan, Burundi and Cote d’Ivoire.</p>
<p>Not that those at the very crest of the UN always set a shining example of probity.</p>
<div id="attachment_914" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 389px"><a href="http://hughash.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/annan3.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-914" title="Annan" alt="" src="http://hughash.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/annan3.jpg?w=379&#038;h=242" height="242" width="379" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">UN FAILURE? As Secretary General, Kofi Annan was rebuked in probe into the 2005 Iraq Oil-for-Food scandal that implicated his son, Kojo</p></div>
<p>Remember the 2005 probe into the Iraq Oil-for-Food scandal – said to have personally netted Saddam Hussein $1.7-billion in kickbacks – when holier-than-thou Secretary General Annan was rebuked over suspicions he steered lucrative contracts to a Swiss company that coincidentally employed his son, Kojo.</p>
<p>As counterpoints, the UN has sired some outstanding agencies under its umbrella, notably the World Health Organisation (WHO), International Monetary Fund (IMF), Educational Scientific &amp; Cultural Organisation (UNESCO) and the International Children’s Fund (UNICEF).</p>
<p>Shamefully, the same can’t be said of the High Commission for Refugees (UNHCR). Hijacked by West-bashers and harboring a vicious obsession against democratic Israel, it was once chaired by Gaddafi-ruled Libya and even founded a ‘human rights prize’ named in honour of the late, unlamented, homicidal maniac (how daft can the UN get, I hear you ask).</p>
<p>So Erdogan’s accusation that the organisation charged with bolstering world piece ‘is losing its credibility’ is somewhat passé. Because it already has.</p>
<p>Now comprising an unwieldy 193 nations, many with historic animus toward one another, maybe it’s high time the UN reminded itself of its original charter commitments – especially the wee bit which states, ‘<i>Human beings shall enjoy freedom of speech and belief and freedom from fear</i>.’</p>
<p>Because if members refuse to adhere to those noble principles, they shouldn’t be in the club in the first place – or the United Nations is a misnomer and not fit for purpose.</p>
<p>Take your pick, as 60s TV quizmaster Michael Miles would say.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/904/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/904/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=904&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://hughash.wordpress.com/2012/10/18/the-un-so-unfit-for-purpose-it-couldnt-sort-out-a-playground-punch-up/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/e56769d7f7122da6692e85aada837dfc?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">hughash</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hughash.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/erdogan.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">erdogan</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://hughash.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/annan3.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Annan</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cake Is a Food Group, Right?</title>
		<link>http://whiskeyintheam.wordpress.com/2012/10/18/cake-is-a-food-group-right/</link>
		<comments>http://whiskeyintheam.wordpress.com/2012/10/18/cake-is-a-food-group-right/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2012 16:24:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>whiskeyintheam</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cooking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Baking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cake]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cooking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Funny]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recipe]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://whiskeyintheam.wordpress.com/?p=163</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In an effort to keep you in tip-top boyfriend/girlfriend shape, I have decided to share an extra special page out of my cookbook with all ya’ll. This one is guaranteed to please and its super-duper easy…and it’s made from a box cake mix (I hate myself), liquor and heavy cream.What&#8217;s not to love? The filling is actually [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=163&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://whiskeyintheam.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/tiramisu-layer-cake-recipe.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-164 aligncenter" title="Tiramisu-Layer-Cake-Recipe" alt="" src="http://whiskeyintheam.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/tiramisu-layer-cake-recipe.jpg?w=300&#038;h=266" height="266" width="300" /></a></p>
<p>In an effort to keep you in tip-top boyfriend/girlfriend shape, I have decided to share an extra special page out of my cookbook with all ya’ll. This one is <i>guaranteed </i>to please and its super-duper easy…and it’s made from a box cake mix (I hate myself), liquor and heavy cream.What&#8217;s not to love?</p>
<p>The filling is actually more than enough to coat the cake in a nice healthy layer of saturated fat, but I like to make a little (lots) extra so I can eat it directly off the beaters and cry about my life choices.</p>
<p>Note:  This recipe calls for three 9” round/square/I don’t give tow shits what shape it is baking pans. I understand that since you are reading this (and probably are domestically disabled) you most likely don’t have three baking pans lying around. You obviously can use the same pan over and over, but it’s going to take a hell of a lot longer to bake all three cakes and let them cool. However, you can utilize this time to cyber stalk your “future husband” and hate text that mean girl from work who makes fun of your love handles. I like to pretend that I’m going to do sit-ups until the timer goes off, but I really end up watching Toddlers &amp; Tiaras and reliving pageant days in the fetal position and crying into my Miss Beaumont County sashes.</p>
<p>Moving on.</p>
<p><b><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Ingredients</span></b></p>
<p><b>Cake</b></p>
<p>1 (18.25 ounce) package moist white cake mix</p>
<p>1 teaspoon instant coffee powder</p>
<p>1/4 cup brewed coffee (I like to steal a cup from work)</p>
<p>1 tablespoon Kahlua</p>
<p><b>Filling</b></p>
<p>2 (8 ounce) container cream cheese (and none of this ‘reduced fat’ bullshit)</p>
<p>1 cup powdered sugar</p>
<p>4 tablespoons Kahlua</p>
<p><b>Frosting</b></p>
<p>2 cups heavy cream</p>
<p>1/4 cup powdered sugar</p>
<p>2 tablespoons Kahlua</p>
<p><b><span style="text-decoration:underline;">Directions</span></b></p>
<p>Preheat oven to 350 degrees F</p>
<ol>
<li>In an effort to make this extremely easy, line your 9”round pans with tin foil (stay with me) and spray them down with a nice heavy coat of non-stick cooking spray. (The tinfoil lining is super awesome, because after the cakes have finished baking, you just pull them out by the foil edges, peel it off, let them cool and you don’t have to worry about the cake sticking to the pan. <i>Genius</i>.)</li>
<li>Prepare the cake mix according to package directions. Divide two thirds of batter between 2 tin foil lined pans pans.</li>
<li>In a mixing bowl, stir instant coffee into remaining batter; pour into remaining lined pan.</li>
<li>Bake in the preheated oven for 20 to 25 minutes, or until a toothpick inserted into the center of the cake comes out clean. Let cool in pan for 10 minutes, and then lift out the cake by the tinfoil edges and transfer to a wire rack cool completely. Peel off the tin foil and burn yourself alive with the molten lava steam that rises from cake.</li>
<li>In a measuring cup, combine brewed coffee and 1 tablespoon Kahlua; set aside.</li>
<li>To make the filling: In a small bowl, using an electric mixer set on low speed, combine cream cheese, 1/2 cup powdered sugar and 2 tablespoons Kahlua; beat just until smooth. Cover with plastic wrap and refrigerate.</li>
<li>To make the frosting: In a medium bowl, using an electric mixer set on medium-high speed, beat the cream, 1/4 cup powdered sugar and 2 tablespoons Kahlua until stiff (that’s what she said). Fold 1/2 cup of cream mixture into filling mixture.</li>
<li>To assemble the cake: Place one plain cake layer on a serving plate. Using a thin skewer (handle of a wooden spoon/finger/sharpie), poke holes in cake, about 1 inch apart. Pour one third of reserved coffee mixture over cake, and then spread with half of the filling mixture. Top with coffee-flavored cake layer; poke holes in cake. Pour another third of the coffee mixture over the second layer and spread with the remaining filling. Top with remaining cake layer; poke holes in cake. Pour remaining coffee mixture on top. Spread sides and top of cake with frosting.</li>
</ol>
<p>If you are feeling extra fancy, you can crush up some semi-sweet chocolate and sprinkle it around the edges, or slice up a few strawberries and place them on top. Really, the world is your oyster. Go nuts.</p>
<p>Double high-fives if you completed this recipe without wanting to slit your wrists.</p>
<p>Love you, meant it.</p>
<p>Stephanie</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/163/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/163/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=163&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://whiskeyintheam.wordpress.com/2012/10/18/cake-is-a-food-group-right/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>21</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f9bb26af4487792123b275c5f14281ad?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">whiskeyintheam</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://whiskeyintheam.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/tiramisu-layer-cake-recipe.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Tiramisu-Layer-Cake-Recipe</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Your Dog Probably Doesn\&#8217;t Appreciate Modern Art</title>
		<link>http://weebeebird.com/2012/10/16/your-dog-probably-doesnt-appreciate-modern-art/</link>
		<comments>http://weebeebird.com/2012/10/16/your-dog-probably-doesnt-appreciate-modern-art/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2012 03:28:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>weebee</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[random bee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Color blindness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Color vision]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dogs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://weebeebird.com/?p=281</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[this week&#8217;s wordpress challenge is to post about color (details can be found here). so here is wee bee&#8217;s response: color blindness comes in many forms. there is your total color blindness, where the world is painted in hues of grey, but that is fairly rare for humans. a human with this type of color [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=281&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>this week&#8217;s wordpress challenge is to post about color (details can be found <a href="http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2012/10/15/weekly-writing-challenge-a-splash-of-color/">here</a>). so here is wee bee&#8217;s response:</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://weebeebird.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/yourdogprobablydoesntappreciatemodernart.png"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-282" title="yourdogprobablydoesntappreciatemodernart" alt="" src="http://weebeebird.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/yourdogprobablydoesntappreciatemodernart.png?w=819&#038;h=461" height="461" width="819" /></a></p>
<p>color blindness comes in many forms. there is your total color blindness, where the world is painted in hues of grey, but that is fairly rare for humans. a human with this type of color blindness, likely, is a monochromat (possessing only one color-picking-up cone in their eyes), as opposed to the usual trichromats of the rest of us normal-color vision people. more common is partial color blindness, which in humans can come in either blue-yellow or red-green vision deficiency form (there are multiple different subtypes of malfunctioning cones which can result in either of these deficiencies but they take a lot more explaining and are more boring than wee bee cares to get into). There is also the odd result of a number of human females actually being tetrachromats (they have four cones, one more than usual) &#8211; but that is just an interesting aside.</p>
<p>most humans have three cones, and a few (mostly males) of us have a form of color confusion. wee bee has a very old friend with such a color confusion, red-green color blindness, something which he has in common with your dog.</p>
<p>dogs are not totally color blind. just like wee bee&#8217;s friend, they are simply a bit color retarded. this, by the way, is totally pc &#8211; a person with an intellectual deficiency is mentally retarded, and a person with partial color blindness is not &#8220;color blind&#8221; in the same way that a mentally retarded adult is not comatose. in fact, after knowing this color retarded person for a very long time, wee bee has learned that it would probably be a lot less confusing to just have total, monochromatic color blindness. but no, dogs are red-green color blind, and from her color retarded friend, wee bee would like to share with you what the world of your dog might be like in terms of color.</p>
<p>likely, your dog has a strong affinity for the color blue, and probably yellow, as these are really the only two colors your dog can see. wee bee&#8217;s old, color retarded friend loves blue. the only colors she has ever seen him wear other than blue are white and black. he wears blue shirts, blue pants, blue tennis shoes, blue shorts, even blue socks underneath sandals with light blue straps and dark blue soles. the red-green color blind do not really &#8220;see&#8221; red and green.</p>
<p>sorry christmas. bye santa.</p>
<p>with a lot of effort, the red-green blind can sometimes guess with a fair amount of accuracy what another specific color is, but more likely their guess is going to be wrong. wee bee&#8217;s old, color retarded friend sees wee bee&#8217;s hair as very definitely brown, though it is red. the brighter the red she dyes it, the more he thinks it is brown.</p>
<p>if you&#8217;re going to buy a ball to play some catch, do not go with the red ball. be nice to your dog and go with a blue or yellow ball.</p>
<p>to your dog, a turtle may as well be red. this is how wee bee&#8217;s color retarded friend was discovered to be color retarded. he was having coloring time in grade school and kept coloring the turtles red. if your dog is anything like wee bee&#8217;s friend, your dog might be obstinately opposed to the notion that a turtle is not red at all.</p>
<p>that&#8217;s why you go with a blue ball. when red and green are indistinguishable, your dog is not <em>mentally</em> retarded simply because it cannot find that red ball in a sea of green &#8211; it is color retarded and the ball and grass simply look the same.</p>
<p>your dog also likely has an under-appreciation for art in general, especially as you get farther away from realism. humans use color to convey meaning in art; think picasso&#8217;s blue period. we attach emotional meaning to specific colors. so as you travel down the historical line of art and things begin to shift into more color-focused, emotional representations rather than realist-style portraits and landscapes, the emotional undertones can be lost on the color retarded.</p>
<p>when taken once to a &#8220;modern&#8221; modern art exhibit, you know the kind where it is nothing but colors and lines and dots and that sort of thing, wee bee&#8217;s friend was convinced for many days that he was missing an actual physical <em>thing </em>in the artworks &#8211; he thought maybe there were red people painted in there somewhere on the giant, completely red canvas. he assumed that he was unable to see the artwork properly, which had happened before with other artwork, and when he was finally told that no, that&#8217;s all there is &#8211; these colors on giant canvases &#8211; it was very clear that he had no appreciation for this sort of thing whatsoever. like many people even able to see the colors &#8220;properly,&#8221; he said &#8220;i don&#8217;t get it&#8221; and felt that this type of artwork was not even artwork.</p>
<p>what he didn&#8217;t realize though, during that time when he thought he was missing something in the artwork itself, was that he was right &#8211; only it wasn&#8217;t physical. humans, throughout our lives, attach sometimes quite specific emotional meanings to colors. some of this is rooted in our neurobiology &#8211; red is the color of blood, the color of danger, it feels daring and revs up our heart. green, as wee bee was once told in a neuroscience course, is the &#8220;easiest&#8221; color for a typical human to see. it is easy on our eyes, as our cones are more sensitive to the green wavelength of light. but it is also the color of summer, of birth, of a perfect lawn and barren trees regaining their leaves.</p>
<p>throughout our lives, our autonomic nervous and emotional systems are cataloging these colors into our minds so that when we approach a piece of art, we feel what might not otherwise be painted expressly through color alone.</p>
<p>so to your color retarded dog, a dog painted in bright red does not feel demonic. does not scream &#8220;cujo.&#8221; modern art isn&#8217;t for everyone, but it definitely isn&#8217;t for the color retarded either. don&#8217;t expect your dog to appreciate an andy-warhol-esque rendition of its dog self. if it could, your dog would probably shrug its shoulders and say &#8220;what&#8217;s the big deal?&#8221;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/281/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/281/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=281&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://weebeebird.com/2012/10/16/your-dog-probably-doesnt-appreciate-modern-art/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/8046a1b7b214d2bb88bdcd0d125394b9?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">weebeebird</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://weebeebird.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/yourdogprobablydoesntappreciatemodernart.png?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">yourdogprobablydoesntappreciatemodernart</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Colourful Language</title>
		<link>http://diannegray.wordpress.com/2012/10/18/colourful-language/</link>
		<comments>http://diannegray.wordpress.com/2012/10/18/colourful-language/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2012 20:12:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>diannegray</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Author]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[book]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPchallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[swearing in novels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the F-Word]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The queen's grimace]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://diannegray.wordpress.com/?p=1177</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[My mother is the only person on this earth I have to answer to if a character in one my books swears. She’s 82 years old and has a tongue as sharp and damaging as a machete – but she never swears. The worst words to come from her lips in a moment of rage [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1177&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://diannegray.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/swearing.png"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-1183" title="SWEARING" alt="" src="http://diannegray.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/swearing.png?w=300&#038;h=128" height="128" width="300" /></a>My mother is the only person on this earth I have to answer to if a character in one my books swears. She’s 82 years old and has a tongue as sharp and damaging as a machete – but she never swears. The worst words to come from her lips in a moment of rage are, ‘For Pete’s Sake!’</p>
<p>In fact, I only ever hear these words after she’s read my latest WiP. It usually happens in the food court on a Sunday morning where we meet for brunch after she’s done with the ‘church thing’.</p>
<p>‘For Pete’s sake, Dianne! Why did you have to use the &#8216;F&#8217; word in that novel? You know I hate the ‘F’ word! What am I going to tell the ladies at church and croquet?’</p>
<p>‘Tell them I use colourful language,’ I say. ‘They’re never going to pick up a book about demons anyway.’</p>
<p>It’s not that my work is spattered with the ‘F’ word. For Pete’s sake, I only use it once or twice in a novel (and now I’m worried I’m beginning to sound like her).</p>
<p><a href="http://diannegray.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/crying-angel.png"><img class="aligncenter size-thumbnail wp-image-1188" title="crying angel" alt="" src="http://diannegray.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/crying-angel.png?w=150&#038;h=140" height="140" width="150" /></a></p>
<p>If a character is angry or tough and it’s part of their speech pattern &#8211; they need to swear occasionally.  It’s part of life. I hear it every day. People say it at work and on the television – and I heard a policeman say it the other day when he tripped on the gutter and cracked his nose on the road at my feet. I didn’t say, ‘For Pete’s sake! Why did you have to swear?’ I said, ‘Are you okay? Here’s a tissue to stop the blood flow.’</p>
<p>There has to be a reason for a character to swear in a novel. It’s not gratuitous and not every second word the character says has to be is a profanity (unlike some people I see on the street). Granted, if I wrote a story about some of the kids who hang around my neighbourhood, my mother would probably spend a lot more time in church.</p>
<p>We’ll be sitting at brunch and my mother will look to the ceiling of the food court as if it holds the answers to everything and she’ll ask ‘Why did they ever invent the ‘F’ word?’</p>
<p>I don’t answer because I know she’s not talking to me.</p>
<p>I say, ‘I’m having a cappuccino and eggs benedict.’</p>
<p>‘It’s such an ugly word,’ she says.</p>
<p>‘Do you want a latte?’</p>
<p>‘Why did they invent it?’</p>
<p>‘The Latte?’</p>
<p>‘No, the ‘F’ word, for Pete’s sake!’<a href="http://diannegray.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/queen.png"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-1180" title="queen" alt="" src="http://diannegray.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/queen.png?w=300&#038;h=212" height="212" width="300" /></a></p>
<p>I then go into a spiel about the olden days where a couple had to have the consent of the King of England to have children so they would place a sign on their door that read ‘Fornicating Under Consent of King’ – a bit like a ‘Do Not Disturb’ sign on a motel door. I know this is only an urban legend, but I say it to make her happy because she a royalist.</p>
<p>The conversation then turns to Queen of England and the ‘F’ word is not mentioned again &#8211; until the next week when we sit down to brunch.</p>
<p><em><strong>Do you think twice about using that word in your work? Do you have a family member that acts as a ‘censor’ to your work?</strong></em></p>
<p>To participate, or see other entries in the Weekly Writing Challenge (<em>a splash of colour</em>) <a href="http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2012/10/15/weekly-writing-challenge-a-splash-of-color/">click here </a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1177/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1177/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1177&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://diannegray.wordpress.com/2012/10/18/colourful-language/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>137</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/4d5b976e6a34278beaa2c16c47c154ff?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">diannegray</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://diannegray.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/swearing.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">SWEARING</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://diannegray.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/crying-angel.png?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">crying angel</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://diannegray.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/queen.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">queen</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Red Packets &amp; Yellow Lions</title>
		<link>http://takingtotheopenroad.wordpress.com/2012/10/19/red-packets-yellow-lions/</link>
		<comments>http://takingtotheopenroad.wordpress.com/2012/10/19/red-packets-yellow-lions/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2012 00:47:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Peggy Tee</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Malaysia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chinese New Year]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[colour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPchallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[festival]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[postaweek]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://takingtotheopenroad.wordpress.com/?p=1127</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;Has the table been set?,&#8221; asks Eldest Auntie as I return to the kitchen for what seemed to be like the hundredth time. &#8220;Yes, and ChuenChuen has counted the chopsticks &#8211; we should have just enough for everyone.&#8221; Outside, controlled chaos reigns. The old, laminated formal dining table, peeling at the edges, has been expanded [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1127&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://takingtotheopenroad.wordpress.com/2012/10/19/red-packets-yellow-lions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://takingtotheopenroad.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/lions-cny.jpg?w=112" />
		<media:content url="http://takingtotheopenroad.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/lions-cny.jpg?w=112" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Lion dances, Chinese New Year</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/2dd74eebbf0721603b7b8e4f8370cf54?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">takingtotheopenroad</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8044/8096361221_1d1de3235c.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Pomelo and altar</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8466/8096380517_ef8f8575bb.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Lunch time</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8331/8096361179_da57d3c551.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">yu sang</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8056/8096368382_9fc704f200.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Chinese New Year colours</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8334/8096368286_85fba15604.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Lions CNY</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Behold the Binder of Women!</title>
		<link>http://mrvictim.wordpress.com/2012/10/18/behold-the-binder-of-women/</link>
		<comments>http://mrvictim.wordpress.com/2012/10/18/behold-the-binder-of-women/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2012 16:11:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Paul Murphy</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Benghazi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[binder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Candy Crowley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[debate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Obama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Romney]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[terrorism]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mrvictim.wordpress.com/?p=1718</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Okay. Pretty much every single &#8220;binders of women&#8221; joke has already been done &#8212; so why not just pile the hell on? I never claimed to be original or anything. If you want original humor, dig up Andy Kaufman.  If you saw the second Presidential debate &#8212; and I know you did &#8212; you were, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1718&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_1719" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 460px"><a href="http://mrvictim.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/romney-debate-anger-011.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1719 " title="romney debate anger" alt="" src="http://mrvictim.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/romney-debate-anger-011.jpg" height="270" width="450" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Darn you, Obama! Darn you to heck!</p></div>
<p style="text-align:left;"><em>Okay. Pretty much every single &#8220;binders of women&#8221; joke has already been done &#8212; so why not just pile the hell on? I never claimed to be original or anything. If you want original humor, dig up Andy Kaufman. </em></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">If you saw the second Presidential debate &#8212; and I know you did &#8212; you were, like me, struck by several things. First, those two men <i>really </i>dislike each other. Second, as FOX News angrily reported, the moderator, CNN reporter Candy Crowley, proved that she was firmly in the Obama camp by pointing out a blatant falsehood made by Mitt Romney on the subject of Libya. Shame on her! Shame!</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">The argument was about when was the first time that Obama called the Benghazi attack an &#8220;act of terrorism.&#8221; Obama said that he had used the term in a Rose Garden speech the day after the attack and Romney said that he hadn&#8217;t used the term for several weeks. Crowley informed the crowd that Obama was correct, at which point everybody cheered and began hitting Romney with sticks.</p>
<div id="attachment_1720" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 460px"><a href="http://mrvictim.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/obama-debate-anger-010.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1720" title="obama debate anger" alt="" src="http://mrvictim.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/obama-debate-anger-010.jpg" height="270" width="450" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">I have drones. Do. Not. Fuck. With. Me.</p></div>
<p style="text-align:left;">At the time I was struck by an odd thought: &#8220;who cares?&#8221; I didn&#8217;t understand why this was especially important. It was a terrible, messy tragedy. Our embassy had been overrun, four Americans were dead and everything was in chaos. It seems quite forgivable if the Administration didn&#8217;t know what the fuck had happened for a couple of days, especially given that the attack was simultaneous with other protests over that goddamned anti-Muslim video. Maybe Romney was right to claim the attack was a sign that the Administration&#8217;s Middle Eastern policy was failing. But then he should have been arguing that, not over the date Obama used the word &#8220;terrorism.&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">It depresses me that this is the level that the Presidential contest has sunk to. Nobody was debating the country&#8217;s ridiculous, self-destructive drug policy or whether it was sensible to use FLYING KILLER DEATH ROBOTS OF DOOM against people who disliked us. They were fighting over when the President first used a specific word to describe a really horrible event.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Wait. Was it &#8220;horrible&#8221; or &#8220;terrible&#8221;? Now I&#8217;m flip-flopping too. Please don&#8217;t tell Hannity.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><a href="http://mrvictim.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/baby-in-a-binder.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1736" title="baby in a binder" alt="" src="http://mrvictim.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/baby-in-a-binder.jpg" height="276" width="450" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Oh well. At least we got to hear Romney use the immortal phrase, &#8220;binders full of women.&#8221; Romney was saying that when he had been elected governor of Massachusetts he had been presented with an all-male cabinet, which he rejected because he wanted to include some women. Eventually he was brought the famous &#8220;binders full of women&#8221; to choose from, and he put lots of gals into his cabinet.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Personally, I find it difficult to muster much Liberal Outrage over this particular statement either. It was awkwardly expressed and vaguely condescending, but hardly a substantive gaffe. The phrase was, however, hilarious, and therefore I&#8217;ll be forever grateful to Mitt for coining it. Just last night I said to my wife, &#8220;Darling, you&#8217;re the only woman in MY binder!&#8221; and she punched me in the face. It was quite romantic.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Anyway, the debate was mildly entertaining as theater.  The biggest takeaway from it was that Obama clearly wants to be reelected, so he was willing to properly prepare for this second debate after the drubbing he received in the last one. So maybe Chris Matthews can stop crying now, okay?</p>
<h3 style="text-align:left;"><strong>Today&#8217;s Insta Poll</strong></h3>
<p style="text-align:left;"><a name="pd_a_6619749"></a>
<div class="PDS_Poll" id="PDI_container6619749" data-settings="{&quot;url&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/static.polldaddy.com\/p\/6619749.js&quot;}" style="display:inline-block;"></div>
<div id="PD_superContainer"></div>
<noscript><a href="http://polldaddy.com/poll/6619749">Take Our Poll</a></noscript></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1718/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1718/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1718&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://mrvictim.wordpress.com/2012/10/18/behold-the-binder-of-women/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>60</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/bcb0874f451cdbba9c2c1af3aae7b83d?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mrvictim</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mrvictim.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/romney-debate-anger-011.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">romney debate anger</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mrvictim.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/obama-debate-anger-010.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">obama debate anger</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mrvictim.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/baby-in-a-binder.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">baby in a binder</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Philly Don\&#8217;t Dial 911</title>
		<link>http://dontunderthinkit.wordpress.com/2012/10/18/philly-dont-dial-911/</link>
		<comments>http://dontunderthinkit.wordpress.com/2012/10/18/philly-dont-dial-911/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2012 16:07:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Rupert</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comedy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[restaurant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[philadelphia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mob]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[italian market]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[james gandolfini]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sandwich]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brisket]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[heartattack]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[names]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tough guys]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dontunderthinkit.wordpress.com/?p=352</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[My name is Rupert Hope Denton. Now close your eyes and conjure up an image of what Rupert Hope Denton might look like. A cherub perhaps? Surrounded by other cherubs with names like Caleb, Alexander and Tobias? Maybe Caleb, Alexander and Tobias are savagely beating Rupert Hope Denton with their lutes and harps for having [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=352&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://dontunderthinkit.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/we-don-t-dial-911.png"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-353" title="we-don-t-dial-911" alt="" src="http://dontunderthinkit.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/we-don-t-dial-911.png?w=300&#038;h=300" height="300" width="300" /></a></p>
<p>My name is Rupert Hope Denton.</p>
<p>Now close your eyes and conjure up an image of what Rupert Hope Denton might look like. A cherub perhaps? Surrounded by other cherubs with names like Caleb, Alexander and Tobias? Maybe Caleb, Alexander and Tobias are savagely beating Rupert Hope Denton with their lutes and harps for having such a wussy name. So when a guy called Rupert Hope finds himself in a city called Philly he ought to be scared.</p>
<p>Philadelphia is a tough city. Everyone looks like a character from The Wire, The Sopranos or Skins. I on the other hand look like a character from Doug. Everyone has a take no shit suffer no fools attitude. I on the other hand, am a fool and talk a lot of shit.</p>
<p>I’m standing in line at a restaurant in Italian Market in South Philadelphia. One of those establishments were the walls are covered with signed black and white photographs of boxers and musicians posing reverently with the owner. Do these people ever enjoy themselves?</p>
<p>Above the cashier hangs a framed image of handgun being thrust towards the customer, beneath it the bold letters <i>WE DON’T DIAL 911</i>. This is the first time I have been in a place where the management reserves the right to shoot the customer.</p>
<p>As I wait I watch two people, both resembling James Gandolfini, chatting in a booth. The conversation is vanilla but for some reason they are using a tone and urgency you’d expect at a drug deal that&#8217;s going wrong, “So I just got the new iPhone 5 and then one of the drivers at work told me that it ain’t much better than the previous model. So I’m thinking WHAT AM I DOIN’ WITH THIS PHONE?” He waves his phone around, “WITH THIS HERE PHONE, THAT AIN’T NO BETTER THAN THE PREVIOUS GUY, YA KNOW?”</p>
<p>The other Gandolfini brusquely removes several paper napkins from the dispenser leans over and mops his flustered forehead. He puts the phone down, “Thanks hun’, you’re a great wife,” he slams his leg of ham sized fist on the table and repeats, “YOU’RE A GREAT WIFE!” Dear god, that’s a husband and wife?</p>
<p>My turn comes to order. I approach the cashier who is wearing a Philadelphia Flyer’s cap pushed backwards and a Temple University hooded sweatshirt, the sleeves pushed up revealing his tattooed forearms. He doesn’t say anything he just stands at the counter and nods his head in acknowledgement. I give a reciprocal head nod but say nothing. We both wait for a moment before he says, “Whaddaya mute or somethin’?</p>
<p>“Come again?”</p>
<p>“Whaddaya want?” He points up at the sandwich menu chalked onto a blackboard above him.</p>
<ul>
<li><i>The</i> <i>Heartstopper</i>: Brisket, bacon, pastrami pecorino cheese, peppers, tomatoes, mayonnaise;</li>
<li><i>The</i> <i>Gutbuster</i>: Salami, brisket, fried egg, pecorino cheese, pepperjack cheese, tomatoes, mustard;</li>
<li><i>The</i> <i>Flatliner</i>: Chopped steak, bacon onion rings, cheddar, pecorino, mustard, mayonnaise).</li>
</ul>
<p>I glance again at the barrel of the gun bearing down on me, reminding me that, <i>WE DON’T DIAL 911</i>. I want to seek qualification about this. The sandwiches are obviously designed to shut down a human being’s vital organs. So what happens if my heart stops or my gut busts? What if one of the Gandolfinis flatlines? Will 911 be dialed then? Or, in accordance with the sign, will they just shoot us like we’re dying cattle? It’s a risk I don’t want to take. So I try and pick the healthiest option.</p>
<p>“I’ll have a Heartstopper.”</p>
<p>“Name?”</p>
<p>I feel the unfriendly eyes of the boxers and musicians who hang on the walls and have probably all been gunned down by the mob by now. I can’t say Rupert Hope Denton.</p>
<p>“Robert… o. Roberto… Bellini. Roberto Bellini, um,” I look at a poster of Sylvester Stallone jumping up and down in front of the Philadelphia Museum of Art, “Rocky Roberto Bellini.”</p>
<p>“Rocky Roberto Bellini?” He repeats back to me, “I only need your first name big man.” He yells back at the kitchen, “One Heartstopper for a blonde, skinny guy called Rocky.” I hear a snort of laughter/derision from the kitchen.</p>
<p>“6 bucks, Rocky.”</p>
<p>I get out my wallet I only have 2 dollars. I go to get my credit card, but freeze. My name is on my credit card.</p>
<p>“Hey, boy-o, we got customas ta serve, kapeesh? 6 bucks!”</p>
<p>I hand him my card, defeated. He examines it. He pauses, and scratches his head. He then points at me, “Wait a minute, you said your name’s Rocky Roberto Bellini,” he points at the card, “But this here, it says, Rupert Hope Denton.” He looks me in the eye.</p>
<p>I stammer something. But he ignores me.</p>
<p>“Hey, Rupert guess what?” He says.</p>
<p>I say nothing, I know what’s going to happen. He’s going to inform me the cards are stolen and (I look up at the gun) according to store policy he will shoot me.</p>
<p>“What?” Comes a voice from behind me. I spin around. The Gandolfinis have stopped eating and are looking past me at the cashier.</p>
<p>“This guy’s name is Rupert Hope!”</p>
<p>“Ya kiddin’ me?” The husband calls back, he looks to his wife, “Did ya hear that, Hope? This kid over there has our names: Rupert (he motions to himself) and Hope (he motions to his wife).” Then he bursts into laughter, slamming his hands on the table making it rattle. What the hell is happening? I ask myself.</p>
<p>Then, suddenly, his laughter turns into a choked gasping, his face contorts in pain, “My heart… My hear…” he wheezes, grabbing his chest, he lurches over sideways in the booth and goes silent. “Oh my god!” Hope yells, turning to the cashier.</p>
<p>“CALL 911!”</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/352/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/352/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=352&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://dontunderthinkit.wordpress.com/2012/10/18/philly-dont-dial-911/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://dontunderthinkit.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/we-don-t-dial-911.png?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://dontunderthinkit.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/we-don-t-dial-911.png?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">we-don-t-dial-911</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/92fd040c7f760a83c1da058b75350437?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ozsnafu</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dontunderthinkit.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/we-don-t-dial-911.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">we-don-t-dial-911</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Romanticizing the Indian Railway</title>
		<link>http://lonelyronin.wordpress.com/2012/10/18/romanticizing-the-indian-railway/</link>
		<comments>http://lonelyronin.wordpress.com/2012/10/18/romanticizing-the-indian-railway/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2012 15:46:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lonely Ronin</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Travelogue]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[British]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Indian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Patna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Railway]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ranchi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Station]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Trains]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wheeler]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://lonelyronin.wordpress.com/?p=146</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I still remember the days when as a child I would wait in my school bus at the railway crossing for the train to pass by. We all would enthusiastically count the number of bogeys that rattled past us and then shout the count together. All of us loved those big red trains hooting past [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=146&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I still remember the days when as a child I would wait in my school bus at the railway crossing for the train to pass by. We all would enthusiastically count the number of bogeys that rattled past us and then shout the count together. All of us loved those big red trains hooting past us with the earth shaking near them. They were the most amazing sight of the day and if some day it was the freight trains chugging past us which were way longer it was an even bigger treat. And if the count of bogeys crossed 50 it was an extra special day for us.</p>
<p>As I grew up the railways started to represent something more. It represented holidays for often we would board a train and go from Ranchi to Patna. It represented a hope that there was connectivity with my home town. It was the umbilical cord that tied us to our home town.</p>
<p>Train journeys in India are always a fun filled affair. True there is a lot of dust blowing at the stations carrying with it not so savory smells at times but its charm lies elsewhere. Railways are truly the lifeblood of India. They are the only means of transport that comes to the mind of an average Indian if he/she has to travel a long way. These steel tracks are like tendons that tie the country together. Whether you are down South in Tamil Nadu or in Assam or Punjab, the railways are a net that transcend all boundaries to form an unbreakable bond.</p>
<p>A railway station in India is the ultimate window to the Indian public life. There are air-conditioned waiting rooms as well as the all welcoming general sitting areas. The divide even though shocking represents India in its complete multitude, divided by money, united by the railway. When a train comes whether young or old, rich or poor, male or female, Bihari or Marathi, Hindu or Muslim all scramble towards the doors of the bogeys. In that moment of frenzy we all are one.</p>
<p>It is a place where we can see a lot of remnants of the colonial era. The railways were established to increase the British control over India but the ideas that flowed through it lead to a unification of the country which ultimately caused the Raj’s downfall.</p>
<p>In all my train journeys I have seen a lot of the life in my country. Once I met a Lady flight officer from the Indian Air Force (one of the first ladies to be a full officer on the force), another time a gentleman whose handbag had been nicked at the previous station and was in lot of distress, on another journey a cop who was telling me how politicians made a fool of the rural population, once I met a couple of train engine drivers who made for some interesting conversation, another time I met a lady whose little son somehow adored me no end and ended up sleeping in my lap, etc. etc. It is like no other socialization that one can indulge in. One can meet people from all walks of life in all different situations, some happy some not so, some stressed some not so, some angry some quiet, they are all there, in those train bogeys and at the stations.</p>
<p>The railways are careers of hope in India. When a person goes to a faraway city to attempt a public examination, his/her hope lies on the railway to reach there safe and sound on time. When a wedding party leaves one city for another on a joyous journey of union of two souls the railways form the bridge. When a soldier returns home after manning the borders, it is the railway that ensures his safe passage. Millions of livelihoods depend on railways. From those selling snacks on platforms to the millions of railway employees they all depend on the railway. It is like a parallel economy in India (the railways get a budget separate from that of the Central government which is a unique practice in the world.) The railways have given us brands like A.H.Wheeler and Co. (a chain of bookstores that operate virtually on every third station) and Ram-pyaari Chai (tea) (every tea seller brands their tea as Ram Pyaari.)</p>
<p>I can go on and on like this but in the end all that can be said is that nothing unites us Indians like the railways do. They are the lifeblood of the country. If the tracks are vessels, the trains are the lifeblood and the stations are the nodes.</p>
<p>Here are some pics for all of you to check out:</p>
<p><img id="il_fi" alt="" src="http://www.indianetzone.com/photos_gallery/10/Indian-railways_12575.jpg" height="209" width="300" /></p>
<p><img id="il_fi" alt="" src="http://www.railway-technology.com/uploads/feature/feature1409/5-naihati-railway-station.jpg" height="375" width="500" /></p>
<p><img alt="http://www.indiweb.in/wp-content/uploads/2012/03/indian-railways.jpg" src="http://www.indiweb.in/wp-content/uploads/2012/03/indian-railways.jpg" /></p>
<p><img alt="http://topnews.in/law/files/Indian-Railway.jpg" src="http://topnews.in/law/files/Indian-Railway.jpg" height="349" width="525" /></p>
<p><img id="il_fi" alt="" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_2JVoeZpk2-k/S7_3yqKSf7I/AAAAAAAABkE/wY0OOI0eHX0/s1600/51091625.barodarailroadstation_9663.jpg" height="439" width="648" /></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/146/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/146/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=146&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://lonelyronin.wordpress.com/2012/10/18/romanticizing-the-indian-railway/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>45</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/0e8c035253443078fa7882e8d646862d?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">kulguy123</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://www.indianetzone.com/photos_gallery/10/Indian-railways_12575.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://www.railway-technology.com/uploads/feature/feature1409/5-naihati-railway-station.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://www.indiweb.in/wp-content/uploads/2012/03/indian-railways.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">http://www.indiweb.in/wp-content/uploads/2012/03/indian-railways.jpg</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://topnews.in/law/files/Indian-Railway.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">http://topnews.in/law/files/Indian-Railway.jpg</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_2JVoeZpk2-k/S7_3yqKSf7I/AAAAAAAABkE/wY0OOI0eHX0/s1600/51091625.barodarailroadstation_9663.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Full House Redux</title>
		<link>http://tvfury.wordpress.com/2012/10/18/full-house/</link>
		<comments>http://tvfury.wordpress.com/2012/10/18/full-house/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2012 09:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>terryvandrovec</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[1990s]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bob Saget]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[D.J. Tanner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Full House]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[John Stamos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Francisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shawn Fury]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sitcom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[television]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Terry Vandrovec]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the Olsen Twins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TVFury]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tvfury.wordpress.com/?p=2949</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[That song. It&#8217;s stuck in my head again. &#8220;Whatever happened to predictability? The milkman, the paperboy, evening TV?&#8221; The funny thing is that as my oldest daughter has discovered Full House via reruns on Nickelodeon, I have found myself asking those very questions. OK, maybe not those exact questions. But watching a good, old-fashioned late [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2949&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>That song. It&#8217;s stuck in my head again.</p>
<p>&#8220;Whatever happened to predictability? The milkman, the paperboy, evening TV?&#8221;</p>
<p>The funny thing is that as my oldest daughter has discovered Full House via reruns on Nickelodeon, I have found myself asking those very questions. OK, maybe not those exact questions. But watching a good, old-fashioned late 1980s-to-mid-1990s sitcom does have me wondering if such shows still exist.</p>
<p><span id="more-2949"></span></p>
<p>The verdict: They probably do. (I&#8217;m too lazy to check.) It&#8217;s just that they&#8217;re not the only primetime options anymore and many of us are too cynical to buy into such shows. Take one of my faves: It&#8217;s Always Sunny in Philadelphia. It&#8217;s essentially an ensemble sitcom and some of the main players are related. Except the humor is twisted instead of wholesome, the plots putting screwball slants on the classics. Many of the shows on Disney Channel are sort of in old-school vein, but not really.</p>
<div id="attachment_2957" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://tvfury.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/425-fullhouse-cast-lc-121108.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-2957" title="425.fullhouse.cast.lc.121108" alt="" src="http://tvfury.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/425-fullhouse-cast-lc-121108.jpg?w=300&#038;h=222" height="222" width="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Those wacky Tanners were a San Francisco institution.</p></div>
<p>In my mind, Full House was part of a golden era for family sitcoms: Family Matters, Home Improvement, Boy Meets World, Step-by-Step, The Cosby Show, etc. And I fully admit that may be entirely incorrect – how many items are there in a golden era? – and more a product of my age at the time than historical reality. That theory is being enforced in my retro viewings.</p>
<p>A couple weeks ago, a middle-school aged D.J. Tanner was exposed to alcohol, her baby-faced boyfriend getting hammered at a party. More recently, the same Ms. Tanner wound up in the back of a van with the lead singer of a rock band who &#8220;never hears no.&#8221; Uh oh. The lesson-based subject matter seems inappropriately or awkwardly heavy considering how many people tuned in to watch toddler twins Mary-Kate and Ashley Olsen say, &#8220;You got it, dude.&#8221; (In hindsight, they may have been referring to mountains of money.) Even the premise of the show was meaty – Mama Tanner died. Nothing says laughs like death. Also, Kimmy Gibbler was full of cringe-worthy phrases.</p>
<p>Of course, there is an alternative – that I view the airing of these issues differently as the parent of a whole mess of kids, many of them girls; I&#8217;d prefer to avoid reality as long as possible. Enter Disney Channel, which is making a living off the family friendly sitcom thing without delving into social issues. Yes, Hannah Montana lost her mom, but there were very few references to that (and I may or may not have seen every single episode).</p>
<p>Regardless, it&#8217;s been interesting to watch my 8-year-old – who is fairly sophisticated for her age – get into the show. And I&#8217;ve followed suit. She seems to appreciate the three age groups represented by the Tanner girls without paying much mind to the cheesy dialogue and goofy dress of the era. I&#8217;m all in because of the nostalgia.</p>
<p>I had forgotten that the dreamy John Stamos was introduced first in the opening credits, making him (in my mind) the lead. I also had forgotten about the high-waist jeans. I take great joy in watching Bob Saget as the neat-freak dad after seeing him take on far bluer roles (ahem, Half Baked) later in his career – it adds a cheeky layer to the performance. The other day, I was taken aback when Stephanie Tanner – going through a dance phase – performed a routine to a Boyz II Men song. There&#8217;s no way that would happen today – using real top-40 music in a scene would cost too much. In hindsight, it seems utterly bizarre how many episodes were based around some sort of inter-family scheme, too. I&#8217;m not sure I&#8217;ve hatched so much as a single plot in my post-college life, let alone one a week – the amount necessary to fuel Full House.</p>
<p>According to its Wikipedia page, the show ran for eight seasons. Eight. Seasons. Now, it&#8217;s in syndication and seemingly in heavy rotation, at that. So people must be watching, although it&#8217;s unclear if they&#8217;re doing so for the quality – is it possible Full House is respectable on a critical level? – or the memories.</p>
<p>For me, it&#8217;s become a sociological study.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2949/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2949/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2949&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tvfury.wordpress.com/2012/10/18/full-house/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>26</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/e69cb20dde57f95808d6325820a536d4?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">terryvandrovec</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tvfury.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/425-fullhouse-cast-lc-121108.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">425.fullhouse.cast.lc.121108</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bikram Yoga Is a Hot Festering Mess</title>
		<link>http://mylabucketlist.com/2012/10/18/bikram-yoga-is-a-hot-festering-mess-bucket-list-progress-finding-my-radiant-weight/</link>
		<comments>http://mylabucketlist.com/2012/10/18/bikram-yoga-is-a-hot-festering-mess-bucket-list-progress-finding-my-radiant-weight/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2012 01:52:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>jenisleavingla</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Adventure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Deep thoughts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Progress toward a bucket-list item]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bikram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bikram yoga]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bucket list]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lose weight]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[posture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Religion and Spirituality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yoga]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mylabucketlist.com/?p=690</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Song of the day: &#8220;Nightcall&#8221; by Kavinsky. I mean, come on God. Listening to this song is better than seeing a double rainbow. It&#8217;s easy to romanticize bikram yoga if you haven&#8217;t done it in over a year. I made good on my promise to myself last night and got my 168-pound girl body downtown [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=690&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_696" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://mylabucketlistdotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/bikram.gif"><img class="size-medium wp-image-696" title="bikram" alt="" src="http://mylabucketlistdotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/bikram.gif?w=300&#038;h=270" height="270" width="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">not so far off from my experience, except fewer peeps</p></div>
<p><span style="color:#ff6600;"><strong>Song of the day</strong></span>: &#8220;Nightcall&#8221; by Kavinsky. I mean, come on God. Listening to this song is better than seeing a double rainbow.</p>
<div id="attachment_707" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 132px"><a href="http://mylabucketlistdotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/yoga1.png"><img class="size-thumbnail wp-image-707" title="Yoga" alt="" src="http://mylabucketlistdotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/yoga1.png?w=122&#038;h=150" height="150" width="122" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">it all seems so peaceful</p></div>
<p>It&#8217;s easy to romanticize <a href="http://www.bikramyoga.com/" target="_blank">bikram yoga</a> if you haven&#8217;t done it in over a year. I made good on my promise to myself last night and got my 168-pound girl body downtown to get my bikram on. I was all excited to go &#8211; you know, except for the dealing with people (social anxiety), parking, traffic, mat-etiquette, skimpy-clothing parts. But the exercise I was confident I could get through this time &#8211; I would skip out of the studio &#8211; like LITERALLY skip &#8211; exhibiting that lightness-of-existence Mary Tyler Moore had in the opening sequence of her eponymous TV show.</p>
<p>Yeah, not as magical as I remember. 1.5 hours later and I felt like I had done pretty much all the exercise required of me for the next two years, all the while facing a mental challenge I have no interest in facing &#8211; watching my puffy, scantily-clad body (because each garment of clothing means you are one step closer to death when practicing bikram) perform the postures in the floor-to-ceiling mirror that spans the length of the studio. Bikram, please remove the mirrors.</p>
<p><span id="more-690"></span></p>
<p>Our teach was Loren &#8211; a bald, gay, thirty-something Swedish guy, yes &#8211; wearing only a blue/white/black speedo, who talked about how he had run down most of the cartilage in his back by his early 20s. Practicing bikram allowed his body the space it needed to let the cartilage heal and grow. Not sure if that is scientifically accurate, but I like to pretend that little outburst of info was aimed at me since we had just done a posture that never sits well with my knees, and I had verbally expressed incredulity that I would be expected to perform it.</p>
<div id="attachment_700" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 122px"><a href="http://mylabucketlistdotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/glam-bathing-suit-0610-2-lgn.jpg"><img class="size-thumbnail wp-image-700" title="glam-bathing-suit-0610-2-lgn" alt="" src="http://mylabucketlistdotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/glam-bathing-suit-0610-2-lgn.jpg?w=112&#038;h=150" height="150" width="112" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">i will need to tan and tan some more and grow hair longer and dye it and work out</p></div>
<p>So, the temp is 105. The humidity of the room is &#8211; ideally &#8211; 40%. You&#8217;re basically in Florida in the dead of summer and someone says &#8211; hey, let&#8217;s sustain a series of postures and repeat each twice until an hour and thirty minutes has gone by! Oh, and our warm-up should probably last 45 minutes &#8211; meaning no &#8220;mat work&#8221; (sitting down) until we hit the tail-end of our fun!</p>
<div id="attachment_698" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 160px"><a href="http://mylabucketlistdotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/bikram-yoga-nyc.jpg"><img class="size-thumbnail wp-image-698" title="bikram-yoga-nyc" alt="" src="http://mylabucketlistdotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/bikram-yoga-nyc.jpg?w=150&#038;h=111" height="111" width="150" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">yeah mine don&#8217;t look like this</p></div>
<p>I wonder if <a href="http://www.bikramyoga.com/Bikram/bikram.php" target="_blank">Mr. Bikram</a> knew what he was getting into when he decided that this workout was the way to go. I mean, there are just so many disturbing aspects to it. It elicits the most primitive-sounding breath; I like to call it &#8220;dinosaur breath.&#8221; It&#8217;s essentially a result of breathing in and out only through your nose. We all know the nasal passages don&#8217;t offer a lot of in the way of physical room for inhaling that much-needed oxygen and exhaling its painfully sad brother carbon dio. Since the violence of the dinosaur breath is much more pronounced in some bikram goers than others, I am operating under the assumption that we are working with some deviated septums as well.</p>
<p>Or maybe people just don&#8217;t care what they sound like. The truth is, when you do bikram, you are dying a little. Your heart is beating so quickly and violently that it feels like it will expand to such a size that it will crash into the back of your chest cavity, shattering the latter to pieces. So now you are a hot sweaty mess who has just torn her heart muscle and whose dying stomach is forced to attempt to digest the shattered bone fragments that are a result of the rib-cage accident.</p>
<p>When all was unsaid and done last night, I did leave bikram feeling differently. Just not the &#8220;right&#8221; differently. I felt like 1) I was going to barf, 2) I was allowed to eat whatever I wanted for the rest of the night and 3) having watched myself in the mirror for the past 1.5 hours, I had no choice but to continue to pay to engage in this type of activity for the next two months in an effort to look better in a bathing suit for my <a title="SS Coachella to Jamaica: My goal(s). I think." href="http://mylabucketlist.com/2012/10/07/ss-coachella-to-jamaica-my-goals-i-think/" target="_blank">cruise to Jamaica</a> alongside my negative size-8 <a title="mamasbeendrinkin.com" href="http://www.mamasbeendrinkin.com" target="_blank">bestie</a>.</p>
<div id="attachment_703" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 160px"><a href="http://mylabucketlistdotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/cruise_ship.jpg"><img class="size-thumbnail wp-image-703" title="Cruise Ship Docked at Ocho Rios" alt="" src="http://mylabucketlistdotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/cruise_ship.jpg?w=150&#038;h=100" height="100" width="150" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">BRING IT</p></div>
<p>If what the bikram peeps say is true &#8211; that &#8220;practicing yoga in a heated room reveals to us our present condition,&#8221; I am clearly hanging on to life by a thin, thin thread. It has been nearly 24 hours and I still have a headache that, if it could speak, would say: &#8220;Excuse my German, but what in the fucking sam-hell fuck is going on?&#8221; But if I have to endure seeing an Asian woman stretch and contort for an hour while one of her shoulder-length black hairs sticks to the skin of her pale bare foot, my declining health is ok with me. Sticky skin and hair absolutely do not mix, and I don&#8217;t want to live in a world where they do. I will stay bikram-focused with my eyes closed for the next two months, listening as often as I possibly can to the French deej Kavinsky and his dark, intriguing &#8220;Nightcall&#8221; beats. I will wear my bathing suit on the cruise. Then I can die.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/690/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/690/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=690&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://mylabucketlist.com/2012/10/18/bikram-yoga-is-a-hot-festering-mess-bucket-list-progress-finding-my-radiant-weight/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>97</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/ec6e3f61ee7b66ed273258aaab5d7008?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jenisleavingla</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mylabucketlistdotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/bikram.gif?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bikram</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mylabucketlistdotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/yoga1.png?w=122" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Yoga</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mylabucketlistdotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/glam-bathing-suit-0610-2-lgn.jpg?w=112" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">glam-bathing-suit-0610-2-lgn</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mylabucketlistdotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/bikram-yoga-nyc.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bikram-yoga-nyc</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mylabucketlistdotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/cruise_ship.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Cruise Ship Docked at Ocho Rios</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>