<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 20:02:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Instagram: Creating A Generation of Fauxtographers</title>
		<link>http://alexnyup.wordpress.com/2013/03/08/instagram-creating-a-generation-of-fauxtographers/</link>
		<comments>http://alexnyup.wordpress.com/2013/03/08/instagram-creating-a-generation-of-fauxtographers/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 00:13:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Alex.NYU.Prague</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Digital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Instagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://alexnyup.wordpress.com/?p=25</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Image courtesy of Weighty Winds via flickr.com           On the seventh day, God created Facebook, and He saw that it was good. Circa 4.6 billion years later, social media experts attempted to isolate and split a single Facebook atom in order to clone its success. The result was an unanticipated and enormous success. [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=25&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://alexnyup.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/6827743514_1f9dbcf517_z.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image" id="i-24" alt="Image" src="http://alexnyup.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/6827743514_1f9dbcf517_z.jpg?w=487" /><br />
</a>Image courtesy of <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/weightywinds/6827743514/">Weighty Winds</a> via flickr.com</p>
<p>          On the seventh day, God created Facebook, and He saw that it was good. Circa 4.6 billion years later, social media experts attempted to isolate and split a single Facebook atom in order to clone its success. The result was an unanticipated and enormous success. Instead of creating a new Facebook, two opposite descendants arose; the witty Facebook status and wall post chromosomes formed a new site called Twitter, while the mobile upload and photo album DNA became that which we refer to as Instagram. The photo-sharing app burst onto the scene in early 2010 and has been rapidly gaining popularity. How much popularity? The InstaArmy is reported to be about <a href="http://www.geekshut.com/instagram-hits-100m-monthly-active-users/8930">100 million strong</a>. That’s more than the <a href="http://www.google.cz/publicdata/explore?ds=kf7tgg1uo9ude_&amp;met_y=population&amp;idim=place:3651000&amp;dl=en&amp;hl=en&amp;q=population%20of%20new%20york%20city">population</a> of New York City. Times ten. But what is it that makes this app so special? Is it the way the ‘Veranda’ filter can make a normal meal look like it came from a five star restaurant? Or the way ‘Hefe’ can transform a random side street into a spectacular destination? Maybe the way any filter can turn a regular girl into a #selfie-proclaimed supermodel #nomakeup #nofilter (#yeahright)? A typical post will garner at least 11 likes from friends. If you’re really good, you can get tens of thousands.</p>
<p>There’s no denying that Instagram can make one feel like a great photographer. When I post a photo of a black-and-white filtered landscape and it gets 70 likes, I feel like a star (The name&#8217;s Adams. <a href="http://www.anseladams.com/">Ansel Adams</a>).  But does taking a quick iPhone picture and slapping a filter on top of it qualify as photography? In the classical sense, I would say it does not. There is so much more to photography than anything one can do with an iPhone. Photographers spend days, weeks, lifetimes documenting places, events, and people. They can shoot hundreds of frames of the same shot to get what they feel is perfection. Personally, I have spent days upon weeks in the dark room working with film and printing photos so I could begin to understand the bare basics of the art of photography. No matter how much thought you put into your instagrams, the whole process maximum from taking to posting the photo takes about five to ten minutes (if you’re spending any longer you’re doing it wrong/need friends). Instagramming itself, to me, is more of a science than an art. One must figure out the proper angle and composition of the photo which makes the subject look most appealing to a viewer, which filter creates the most dramatic effect, at which time of day to post said insta to optimize the number of likes, and which hash tags to utilize to get the largest audience possible. It combines some photography skills along with SMS savvy and knowledge of marketing, including knowledge of your target audience and observation of feedback from your followers.</p>
<p>I don’t think Instagram poses any sort of a threat towards the art of photography; there is a clear division between what makes a good photo and what makes a good Instagram. To sum it up, <a href="http://geofflivingston.com/2012/08/14/instagram-killing-photography/">Geoff Livingston</a> said &#8220;For the vast majority of Instagram users, it’s about people sharing their lives, not engaging in photography as a profession or hobby.&#8221; I believe that while Instagram can be a good way for artists to show off their work, it does not merit any iPhone-wielding teenager a degree in photography. Digital enthusiasts and film fanatics alike can breathe a sigh of relief. (The minute you start seeing “Amaro” exhibits in photo galleries or “Lo-Fi” advertisements in magazines, then you can start to worry.)</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/25/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/25/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=25&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://alexnyup.wordpress.com/2013/03/08/instagram-creating-a-generation-of-fauxtographers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/7156534d850842137cc0d0d1b3bdddc0?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">alexnyup</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://alexnyup.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/6827743514_1f9dbcf517_z.jpg?w=487" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Business with a Side of Pleasure</title>
		<link>http://towelspacked.wordpress.com/2013/03/07/the-intersection-of-business-and-pleasure/</link>
		<comments>http://towelspacked.wordpress.com/2013/03/07/the-intersection-of-business-and-pleasure/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 21:15:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>towelspacked</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diplomacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[election]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Foreign Service]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outdoors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[safari]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://towelspacked.wordpress.com/?p=3108</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In the morning, a thick, billowing mist blanketed the densely forested slopes of Mt. Marsabit, the extinct shield volcano that lends its name to one of Kenya’s largest and most sparsely populated counties. The soupy fog completely enveloped the rustic cabins of Marsabit Lodge, obscuring from view the picturesque clearing on which it sits. The [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3108&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the morning, a thick, billowing mist blanketed the densely forested slopes of Mt. Marsabit, the extinct shield volcano that lends its name to one of Kenya’s largest and most sparsely populated counties. The soupy fog completely enveloped the rustic cabins of Marsabit Lodge, obscuring from view the picturesque clearing on which it sits. The tepid early morning light struggled to fight its way through the brume, but still managed to rouse D from his deep Sunday morning slumber, the first night of real rest he had enjoyed in a week during which consecutive 12-hour workdays melded into a continuous, frantic rush of last-minute pre-election preparations.</p>
<p><a href="http://towelspacked.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/old-samburu-women.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3113" alt="old Samburu women" src="http://towelspacked.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/old-samburu-women.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=683" width="1024" height="683" /></a></p>
<p>We both volunteered to serve as observers for Kenya’s first presidential election under its new constitution. S was assigned to cover a county in western Kenya. Because D had organized a <a title="Kenya’s badlands" href="http://towelspacked.wordpress.com/2012/12/10/kenyas-badlands/">work trip to Kenya’s remote northern lands</a> in December, the election team decided to send him to Marsabit, a grueling ten-hour drive from Nairobi.</p>
<p><a href="http://towelspacked.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/goat-herder.jpg"><span id="more-3108"></span><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3111" alt="goat herder" src="http://towelspacked.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/goat-herder.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=683" width="1024" height="683" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://towelspacked.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/child-with-sibling.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3109" alt="child with sibling" src="http://towelspacked.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/child-with-sibling.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=678" width="1024" height="678" /></a></p>
<p>By mid-morning, strong gusts of wind had dispersed the fog and were busy wreaking havoc on the dusty streets of Marsabit Town. The residents of this sleepy, forgotten part of northern Kenya wrapped their multi-colored shawls tighter and shielded their eyes from the dust clouds as they went about their business, attending open-air church meetings or stocking up at the Sunday market in anticipation of the elections. D and his companions criss-crossed the unmarked, bumpy roads, searching out the ramshackle primary schools that would serve as polling centers for Monday’s vote.</p>
<p><a href="http://towelspacked.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/shopping.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3115" alt="shopping" src="http://towelspacked.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/shopping.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=678" width="1024" height="678" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://towelspacked.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/wazee-wawili.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3118" alt="wazee wawili" src="http://towelspacked.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/wazee-wawili.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=683" width="1024" height="683" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://towelspacked.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/lady-in-red.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3112" alt="lady in red" src="http://towelspacked.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/lady-in-red.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=678" width="1024" height="678" /></a></p>
<p>The day’s work complete and Monday’s route mapped out, D turned the convoy back to the lodge, which is located ten minutes inside one of Kenya’s hardest to access national parks. In December, there had been no time for exploring. D had glimpsed a handful of buffalo in the swamp grass beneath the lodge when he arrived in the evening and saw half a dozen hyenas in the road on the way back out early the following morning. With a free afternoon this time around, D did not need his arm twisted when his Kenyan colleague suggested a game drive.</p>
<p><a href="http://towelspacked.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/smiling-woman.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3116" alt="smiling woman" src="http://towelspacked.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/smiling-woman.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=678" width="1024" height="678" /></a></p>
<p>The lodge manager spoke of another clearing deeper in the forest, called Paradise, and swore it would stun and amaze anyone who set eyes on it. The road wound its way lazily through the woods, descending precipitously and then ascending again up the steep, rocky hillsides. After 45 minutes, during which no animal deigned to show itself, D’s companions started wondering aloud if the drive was worth it. At last, the path crested one final time, bringing the car to the edge of a precipice.</p>
<p>There was a sign marking a viewpoint, the first indicator that this patch of wilderness actually belonged to a national park. A troupe of baboons had set up shop by the stone marker, but they scattered as the car pulled up and would not return, despite the driver’s best attempts to lure them out of the bush with an apple. The view really was magnificent. Whereas the lodge sits on a clearing made by a small, dried-up lake, Paradise is a full-blown crater. D found himself looking several hundred feet down a sheer cliff that encircled the lush basin, at the bottom of which a shallow lake persisted.</p>
<p><a href="http://towelspacked.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/paradise.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3114" alt="Paradise" src="http://towelspacked.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/paradise.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=678" width="1024" height="678" /></a></p>
<p>Two KWS rangers materialized out of the woods and pointed out the carcass of a baby buffalo that had been killed by lions inside the crater the previous day. They indicated the path to descend into the crater, but asked the driver to steer clear of the buffalo remains so as not to disturb the lions.</p>
<p>In addition to the baboons, the only mammalian denizens that had shown themselves during this game drive, Marsabit is also home to many unique bird species. However, D’s companions were utterly indifferent to the birds and he decided not to antagonize them by stopping the car at every flutter of wings. Even without the animals, the drive to Paradise was exceptionally pleasant, and a welcome respite before Monday’s hectic runaround.</p>
<p><a href="http://towelspacked.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/colorful-dress.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3110" alt="colorful dress" src="http://towelspacked.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/colorful-dress.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=678" width="1024" height="678" /></a></p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://towelspacked.wordpress.com/category/travel-2/'>Travel</a> Tagged: <a href='http://towelspacked.wordpress.com/tag/culture/'>culture</a>, <a href='http://towelspacked.wordpress.com/tag/diplomacy/'>diplomacy</a>, <a href='http://towelspacked.wordpress.com/tag/election/'>election</a>, <a href='http://towelspacked.wordpress.com/tag/foreign-service/'>Foreign Service</a>, <a href='http://towelspacked.wordpress.com/tag/nature/'>nature</a>, <a href='http://towelspacked.wordpress.com/tag/outdoors/'>outdoors</a>, <a href='http://towelspacked.wordpress.com/tag/photography/'>photography</a>, <a href='http://towelspacked.wordpress.com/tag/politics/'>politics</a>, <a href='http://towelspacked.wordpress.com/tag/safari/'>safari</a>, <a href='http://towelspacked.wordpress.com/tag/travel/'>travel</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3108/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3108/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3108&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://towelspacked.wordpress.com/2013/03/07/the-intersection-of-business-and-pleasure/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://towelspacked.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/three-women.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://towelspacked.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/three-women.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">three women</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/4637ce0982eee775cba6176e06c0cbae?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">towelspacked</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://towelspacked.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/old-samburu-women.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">old Samburu women</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://towelspacked.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/goat-herder.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">goat herder</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://towelspacked.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/child-with-sibling.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">child with sibling</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://towelspacked.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/shopping.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">shopping</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://towelspacked.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/wazee-wawili.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">wazee wawili</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://towelspacked.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/lady-in-red.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lady in red</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://towelspacked.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/smiling-woman.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">smiling woman</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://towelspacked.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/paradise.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Paradise</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://towelspacked.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/colorful-dress.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">colorful dress</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fifteen Assumptions That Might Be Useful to Make</title>
		<link>http://bellejarblog.wordpress.com/2013/03/07/fifteen-assumptions-that-it-might-be-useful-to-make/</link>
		<comments>http://bellejarblog.wordpress.com/2013/03/07/fifteen-assumptions-that-it-might-be-useful-to-make/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 03:47:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bellejarblog</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anxiety]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[assumptions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[astronomy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[depression]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[happiness or something like it]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[we are all made of stars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://bellejarblog.wordpress.com/?p=2005</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[1. Assume that you are loved. 2. Assume that those who love you find some kind of value in you and the things you do. 3. Assume, however, that you don&#8217;t need to be valuable in order to be worthy of love. 4. Assume that there is no one out there keeping a tally of [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2005&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>1. Assume that you are loved.</p>
<p>2. Assume that those who love you find some kind of value in you and the things you do.</p>
<p>3. Assume, however, that you don&#8217;t need to be valuable in order to be worthy of love.</p>
<p>4. Assume that there is no one out there keeping a tally of all of your failings, ready to throw it in your face when you&#8217;re either feeling too good or too awful about yourself.</p>
<p>5. Assume that if anyone actually <em>is</em> keeping a tally of all your failings, that act says more about them than it does about you.</p>
<p>6. Assume that you can&#8217;t make all of the people happy all of the time; maybe not even some of the people some of the time.</p>
<p>7. Assume that you will, over the course of your life, sometimes anger or disappoint the people you love.</p>
<p>8. Assume that when this happens, it isn&#8217;t the end of the world, even if that&#8217;s what it feels like.</p>
<p>9. Assume that there is never an end to learning, or growing, or discovering.</p>
<p>10. Assume that you will always find a way out, even when all the doors slam shut and everything feels impossible.</p>
<p>11. Assume that sometimes earnestness and optimism can trump irony and cynicism.</p>
<p>12. Assume that it&#8217;s possible to recapture the way you felt when you were young, how the perfect clockwork mechanism of the universe used to leave you breathless and giddy with wonder.</p>
<p>13. Assume that there will always be more stories to tell, or at the very least new ways of reinterpreting old fables.</p>
<p>14. Assume that nothing is permanent, that someday even the sun will disappear; remember that everything we see and touch and taste is made of stars that grew and pulsed and died long before this planet ever existed.</p>
<p>15. Assume that you are under some kind of obligation to make the world a better place.</p>
<p><a href="http://bellejarblog.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/earth_moon.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2006" alt="earth_moon" src="http://bellejarblog.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/earth_moon.jpg?w=490&#038;h=733" width="490" height="733" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2005/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2005/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2005&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://bellejarblog.wordpress.com/2013/03/07/fifteen-assumptions-that-it-might-be-useful-to-make/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>22</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/58674768ee8b27cc608763883ee09088?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bellejarblog</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://bellejarblog.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/earth_moon.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">earth_moon</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Your Artificially Intelligent Agent</title>
		<link>http://thoughtinfection.com/2013/02/24/your-artificially-intelligent-agent/</link>
		<comments>http://thoughtinfection.com/2013/02/24/your-artificially-intelligent-agent/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2013 17:15:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Smience</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thoughtinfection.wordpress.com/?p=141</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The moment that Watson became the Jeopardy champion will be remembered as a watershed moment in human history. It is the Gutenburg Bible of our time. Media interest in Watson seems to have reawakened this month, with IBM now talking about how exactly Watson is being implemented to help make difficult medical diagnoses. In this area where humans just [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=141&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The moment that Watson became the Jeopardy champion will be remembered as a watershed moment in human history. It is the Gutenburg Bible of our time.</p>
<p>Media interest in Watson seems to have reawakened this month, with IBM now talking about how exactly Watson is being implemented to help make <a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/bruceupbin/2013/02/08/ibms-watson-gets-its-first-piece-of-business-in-healthcare/">difficult</a><span style="font-style:inherit;line-height:1.625;"><a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/bruceupbin/2013/02/08/ibms-watson-gets-its-first-piece-of-business-in-healthcare/"> medical diagnoses</a>. In this area where humans just can&#8217;t process the amount of data necessary to make the best decision possible, Watson could be truly revolutionary. For now, Watson&#8217;s work will still need to be checked by meatspace doctors to make sure he doesn&#8217;t send some poor soul off to have a limb amputated unnecessarily, but this does not take away from the awesome power of data processing this will be putting into the hands of doctors.</span></p>
<p>This got me thinking about how life is going to change when we all have access to our own Watson. This raises important questions about how much control over our lives these intelligent agents will have. If you could have a hyper-connected computer intelligence which could monitor everything you say and do to check for errors and help you to consistently come to the best decisions, wouldn&#8217;t you want it? It is not only the high level decisions of doctors that could benefit from more data integration, but every decision we make as individuals could really benefit from a little more intelligence.</p>
<p>Lets take a simple example &#8211; the run of the mill job search in 2025</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;</p>
<p>Instead of writing a resume, you task your artificially intelligent agent (AIA) to investigate job opportunities. Under your direction, AIA will explore the internet for available job opportunities which might mesh well with your specific skills and knowledge. The stored knowledge base of your AIA might also play into the decision, as you two are really a team at this point and that should be taken into account. Other factors your AIA might take into account, are your interests or willingness to move, where your family and friends live, how much time you have available, how much money you want to make etc&#8230;</p>
<p>The beauty of getting your AIA to do all of this work is that it can make a decision which balances all of the many factors involved with a finesse that a lone human would never hope to achieve. So in just under an hour, AIA brings up 7 draft emails to companies she proposes she proposes would be a good fit for you.</p>
<p>You see that one job is in Sydney, Australia. Your ex-wife lives in Sydney. Do you really want to open that can of worms again? Does AIA have an eye on your romantic life with that option? Maybe AIA just wanted you to consider whether you are interested in rekindling some connection there&#8230; maybe if you decide against this it will lower AIAs ranking of putting you in a situation possibility of reconnecting you with youjr ex-wife&#8230; You have been down this road before, there is no point spending time trying to figure out what AIA is thinking&#8230; Scratch Sydney.</p>
<p>So of the remaining 6 emails: 4 are applying to open job postings that might be interesting to you, 1 is an email reaching out to an old friend at a company you used to work for to see if they are looking for anyone, and the last email is to a company that doesn&#8217;t have an open posting but that AIA inferred from public financial data that it could improve its profitability by 112% by hiring you. In short order, you look over all the emails with the attached optimized resumes and send them off.</p>
<p>The companies all have much more powerful AIA helping their decisions, so within a day or two you have heard back from all of those places you applied. Two of the applications were turned down flat, including the hail mary AIA sent to the company with no official posting. AIA is aware of the emotional impact that such a rejection might have on you, so she softens the blow by pointing out that there is no way to know what crazy strategy their corporate AIA has come up with.</p>
<p>AIA prioritizes what she thinks is the best offer and shows it to you. Its a short contract in San Francisco, the pay is good, and they only need 3 hours a day (under the normal 4-5 expected in many offices these days). AIA also shows you the better salary and work agreement she thinks she can negotiate for you.</p>
<p>&#8220;People used to do all this themselves, <span style="font-style:inherit;line-height:1.625;">what a headache that must have been&#8221;</span><span style="font-style:inherit;line-height:1.625;"> you think to yourself, shaking your head in nostalgic disbelief. You go ahead and tell AIA that you&#8217;ll accept the job in San Francisco.</span></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">&#8212;&#8212;-</p>
<p>Having an intelligence like Watson in your pocket will change every facet of your life; f<span style="font-style:inherit;line-height:1.625;">rom something as mundane as submitting tax forms or figuring out what to have for dinner, to the highest level social and medical decisions</span><span style="font-style:inherit;line-height:1.625;">. You cannot overestimate how significant of a change it will be to have a powerful artificial intelligence agent looking over your interests. Ultimately, the power of decision will still rest in your hands, but an AIA lets you better see the map of where those decisions lead. </span></p>
<p>In the end, with the emergence of AIAs we will address something we hate to admit to ourselves. We are shitty decision makers.  We do our best to weigh the relevant factors and come up with what we think will be the best plan, but we can really only take into account a fraction of what we should. How many ills of the world come about from bad decision making compounded upon mistakes? Some people might fear the loss of control associated with having an AIA help in your decision making, but at the end of the day the AIAs will make us smarter, and a smarter world is a better world.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/141/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/141/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=141&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thoughtinfection.com/2013/02/24/your-artificially-intelligent-agent/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/1efb004669bb7a539e361f3f064f4c63?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">immunews</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dad, Smiling</title>
		<link>http://applehillcottage.org/2013/03/08/54-dad-smiling/</link>
		<comments>http://applehillcottage.org/2013/03/08/54-dad-smiling/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 06:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Apple Hill Cottage</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Fathers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thankfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Time]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DP challenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[memories]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://applehillcottage.org/?p=3092</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[March 10, 2012. one year ago, Dad, Granddad, Pops, Sam died at the long old age of 90. there are bad memories of that time between when his body no longer worked and when his journey here ended. they are fading with time. and today i&#8217;m choosing to remember him smiling. His plane wrecked in training. [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3092&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://applehillcottage.org/2013/03/08/54-dad-smiling/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>78</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/2822f550d60f79ff141ee2ee811440ed?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">applehillcottage</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://applehillcottage.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/012.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Dad in his plane</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://applehillcottage.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/016.jpg?w=750" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Dad rowing</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://applehillcottage.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/020.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Dad and Mom on New Year&#039;s Eve</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://applehillcottage.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/096.jpg?w=522" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Dad and his new golf club</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://applehillcottage.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/086.jpg?w=495" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Dad at Christmas</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://applehillcottage.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/085.jpg?w=539" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Dad getting his hair done</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://applehillcottage.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/dadnancewedding.jpg?w=538" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://applehillcottage.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/092.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Dad and Ron</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://applehillcottage.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/080.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Dad, Aunt Ruth, and Uncle B</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://applehillcottage.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/1281.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Carol and dad</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://applehillcottage.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/158.jpg?w=750" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Dad&#039;s 89th</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://applehillcottage.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_1724.jpg?w=750" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Dad surrounded </media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://applehillcottage.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/160.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Dad smiling</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>No More Lies</title>
		<link>http://tworedtornados.wordpress.com/2013/03/06/no-more-lies-weekly-writing-challenge-truth-is-stranger-than-fiction/</link>
		<comments>http://tworedtornados.wordpress.com/2013/03/06/no-more-lies-weekly-writing-challenge-truth-is-stranger-than-fiction/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2013 00:50:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tworedtornados</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[People]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thoughts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ukraine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Unfinished Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adventure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[change]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPchallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[English]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eye]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[found]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[friends]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[friendship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kiev]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kyiv]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life lessons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lost]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[people]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[perspective]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[red]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[solo travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tornado]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tornados]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[truth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[two]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ukrainian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vacation]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tworedtornados.wordpress.com/?p=743</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I remember this day. I was sicker than a dog, some Ukrainian sinus infection that I refused to succumb to. I should have stayed in bed, but I wouldn&#8217;t. I continued to act healthy until I just couldn&#8217;t fake it anymore. Fever. Cough. Sinus pressure. I felt terrible. I was miserable. But this was the [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=743&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:left;"><a href="http://tworedtornados.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/wpid-imag0661_burst002.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-358 aligncenter" alt="wpid-IMAG0661_BURST002.jpg" src="http://tworedtornados.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/wpid-imag0661_burst002.jpg?w=300&#038;h=169" width="300" height="169" /></a>I remember this day. I was sicker than a dog, some Ukrainian sinus infection that I refused to succumb to. I should have stayed in bed, but I wouldn&#8217;t. I continued to act healthy until I just couldn&#8217;t fake it anymore. Fever. Cough. Sinus pressure. I felt terrible. I was miserable.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">But this was the day my neighbor&#8217;s daughter, Anya, brought out her books to show me how she could read English while I was waiting on my laundry. This was the day we played with clay putty, something I used to do with my grandma, something to me incredibly nostalgic. See that bracelet on my hand? She wanted to give me that, a prize she had won in class. She wouldn&#8217;t take no for an answer. I wore it for the rest of the trip, never stopping to think that it might look silly. I counted it precious. It was a comfort, a reminder of the day I learned the truth.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">And all it took to rattle my nice little American world was a little girl in a cramped Ukrainian apartment who wanted to show me her English.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">This was the day I finally understood that I wanted to make a difference, that I could make a difference, even if it was just teaching a little girl one word of English in a far-away country.</p>
<p>I suddenly remembered a day ten long years ago, standing outside my house at fifteen, breathing deeply of the wind and wondering where it had been, where it was going, and was that some kind of Eastern spice I smelled in the air? I was dying to go and find out. That girl was all fear and trepidation, unsure, and insecure. That fifteen-year-old girl had no idea of where she would be ten years later, that one day she would just up and go away for a month all on her own. Sometimes I remember the girl I was and smile, because I owe it to who I used to be to be who I am now.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><em>I owe it to myself to live my dreams.</em></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">We owe it to the young versions of ourselves to fulfill their dreams &#8212; those dreams we used to cherish.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">People have continually picked this one picture out of my hundreds and commented on how I&#8217;m &#8220;glowing&#8221; or &#8220;look really happy&#8221;. Maybe I had a fever. Maybe it was just because I was sick. Maybe it&#8217;s sweat. But the one comment I can&#8217;t argue with, the one that gets me every time, is: &#8220;You don&#8217;t look like that over here.&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Deep down inside, I know they are right.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">There&#8217;s only been a handful of times in my life that I can remember being really truly as happy as I was in that picture, when I was relaxed, didn&#8217;t care about how I looked, or if I was pretty, or if my tummy pudge was showing. Only six brief moments when I was convinced that life was going to be good and worth living. This was one of those moments, illness notwithstanding.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Because this was the day I realized that my life was a joke. I hadn&#8217;t been doing anything worthwhile or helping anyone or making anything better. I was treading water, just taking up space and wasting time playing games on people and computers. I hadn&#8217;t really been living the life I dreamed of in the secret attic of my mind, and I had spent a great amount of time and effort trying to convince myself otherwise. I claimed to want a career, a house, and a family. But did I? Had I only been pretending after all?</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">The truth?</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">I was living a lie.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">This was the day I stopped lying.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/743/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/743/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=743&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tworedtornados.wordpress.com/2013/03/06/no-more-lies-weekly-writing-challenge-truth-is-stranger-than-fiction/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>36</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/6e8787d5b6c466718a937e3191b9870d?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tworedtornados</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tworedtornados.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/wpid-imag0661_burst002.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">wpid-IMAG0661_BURST002.jpg</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Our Heroine</title>
		<link>http://ekantavasi.wordpress.com/2013/03/07/day-13-our-heroine/</link>
		<comments>http://ekantavasi.wordpress.com/2013/03/07/day-13-our-heroine/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 04:36:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Michael Shoemake</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Child]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fantasy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Growing up]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Knowledge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[myth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[original content]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Silence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ekantavasi.wordpress.com/?p=113</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Our heroine came, bouncing and slimy, into the world on the thirty-first day of April in the year 1998. She was, disappointingly, a thoroughly average infant, spitting and vomiting and excreting vile substances all across her poor parents’ little apartment. The child kept her guardians up at night, needed to be burped often, and, of [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=113&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Our heroine came, bouncing and slimy, into the world on the thirty-first day of April in the year 1998. She was, disappointingly, a thoroughly average infant, spitting and vomiting and excreting vile substances all across her poor parents’ little apartment. The child kept her guardians up at night, needed to be burped often, and, of course, rejected all edible objects in favor of the unique challenges which glass marbles and bits of organic petrochemical polymers posed to the human digestive system. She grew at about the average rate children grow at – or at least this author supposes so, finding little evidence to the contrary –- and soon found herself at four years of age, when her parents’ suspicions were finally confirmed by the family doctor; she was mute.</p>
<p>That she could not speak, though unfortunate, could hardly be counted as a mark against her, of course, but her parents found something far more troubling bubbling up in their beloved lump of flesh, a sin more worrisome than any infirmity of the body. Though I am sure you have guessed it by now –- for what horror could be more disturbing? –- I will say it outright, for the sake of those philistines who followed the same path as she: she rejected the Television.  Oh, yes! The very selfsame Television her parents had desperately hoped would bring them a few moments’ peace in the din of their lives, having grown awfully weary over the course of the past few years. Yes, rejected it outright, in fact! Its rude colors and insistent flashes, its repetitive and banal artificiality (for she never really gave the poor thing much of a chance beyond those first few glimpses) sent her reeling away. Gradually, however, her parents learned to ply her with books – and the older and more confounding, the better – in these she felt she had found a few true shades of light, the better picture of Nature.</p>
<p>Her parents also found, over time, that there was no difference whatever to her, in terms of preference, between the unseen flight of faeries and the highly-documented mycological phenomenon of faerie circles. She fawned over the fancies of mythology with a force equal to her love of natural philosophy. As she studied Ptolemy’s spheres and Newton’s motions, she imagined the Titans which frolicked, throwing the celestial orbs about and the gremlins which surely provided our wig-headed friend’s “equal and opposite” reactions, hiding away in all things. So, too, the feeble chains of time held no meaning in her brain, and they certainly did not hold her. She felt no less a connection to the theorems of Galileo than to the patient but harried advice that her father meted out in his distinctly sonorous tones. And when the girl was very still (as she was in the most wild and passionate throes of study) she felt she could hear the low thin shiver of the universe in her head, the trembling of a great giant at the bottom of a deep well.</p>
<p>Though to be sure, as she aged, her tastes did indeed change. Now she loved the structure of cells (and especially the mitochondria which tied her to the ancient Mother), now she loved those grim brothers and their strange and terrific tales, now the study of waves, now the delights of Baba Yaga and the flying stoves which populate Russian folktales. In her longest phase, she was entranced by Paracelsus, who seemed to wed the fancies of her soul for a sweet, fleeting time.</p>
<p>But for all her studies, our queer child could not be called an “intellectual,” as her head remained quite stubbornly unpointed and untroubled by matters of consistency. She saw no obstruction in contradiction; after all, if she could hold them without tension in the smithy of her own soul, why, then, could not the infinitely better, brighter, vaster universe do the same? (Why not indeed?)</p>
<p>Thusly, it seems our child had no place in the world, destined for solitude away from the rude souls of her sapiens brethren. “Very well,” she thought, when she was old enough to understand the suffering she must carry and the first throbs of loneliness touched her tender heart, “I will simply be alone; or, better, I will not be a person. So much grander to be a frog or a gnat or even a horse, pretentious though they are.” And when, in her eighteenth year, she leaped and buzzed and galloped her way out of the town, she did not look back more than three times and with only a meager few tears.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/113/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/113/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=113&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://ekantavasi.wordpress.com/2013/03/07/day-13-our-heroine/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/52dd003a4961cc1fa4a18809afa4157b?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">michaelshoemake</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>America’s Long Withdrawal from Afghanistan</title>
		<link>http://lightbox.time.com/2013/03/07/americas-long-withdrawal-from-afghanistan-photographs-by-yuri-kozyrev/</link>
		<comments>http://lightbox.time.com/2013/03/07/americas-long-withdrawal-from-afghanistan-photographs-by-yuri-kozyrev/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 12:31:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Patrick Witty</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Photo Essay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Afghanistan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kabul]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NOOR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yuri Kozyrev]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://lightbox.time.com/?p=67278</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[TIME contract photographer Yuri Kozyrev traveled to Afghanistan to document how the American military will bring the materials home from more than a decade of war.<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=67278&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the months leading up to the Normandy Invasion in the late spring of 1944, the U.S. shipped 1.6 million troops and 17 million tons of cargo to staging areas in the United Kingdom. If the numbers weren’t mind boggling enough, to reach the British Isles, the troops and cargo had to cross the Atlantic under threat of being sunk by German U Boats. That buildup was just one of untold numbers of logistical feats during that enormous war, one chapter in an ongoing legacy of remarkable exploits that extends to the retrograde, the military’s term for bringing all of our equipment home from Afghanistan.</p>
<p>For many good reasons, Afghanistan has been called a logistician’s nightmare. It is landlocked and far from a working port. Much of the country – especially in the east where a great deal of the fighting has taken place – is covered with mountains and threaded by decades-old roads and questionable bridges. The easiest way in and out of the country is a geopolitical minefield and the other two routes are three times as expensive.</p>
<p>And yet, for twelve years, logisticians have supplied troops with the equipment — large and small — necessary to fight a war. They have airdropped pallets of food and repair parts on remote bases, tossed “Speedballs” — body bags filled with ammunition and water — out of helicopters to troops under fire. And along the way, extra equipment has piled up at bases around Afghanistan. According to a December 2012 report to Congress by the by the Government Accountability Office, there is the equivalent of more than 90,000 twenty-foot containers of equipment all over Afghanistan. All together, there is $36 billion worth of vehicles, weapons systems, repair parts and utter junk scattered throughout the country, and bringing it home will cost an estimated $5.7 billion.</p>
<p>Last month, I traveled to eastern Afghanistan with TIME contract photographer Yuri Kozyrev to document how the American military will bring all of that stuff home from Afghanistan. The journey began at Forward Operating Base Altimur, a scrap of land at on a slope above a desert floor, deep in Logar Province. There, the paratroopers of Bull Battery, 173rd Airborne Brigade were busy tearing down much of the base. We met hardened veterans like Sgt. Mario Diaz, who was serving his third tour in Afghanistan and the second at FOB Altimur, which has both been his sanctuary from fighting and the site of some of the most difficult times in his 32 years. There were three privates on their first combat tour who were in third grade when the war began. They all joined up within two weeks of graduating from high school and met each other just before shipping out to Afghanistan.</p>
<p>When the troops are done packing their equipment, the destination for much of the gear is one of the yards at Bagram Airfield, the largest base in eastern Afghanistan. A quick drive around Bagram and you’ll see yard after yard of twenty and forty foot container stacked two high, vehicles that cost $570,000 each lined up by the hundreds waiting to be washed four times before they can be shipped home. Then at the end of the line, especially in the winter months when most of the equipment leaves Afghanistan by air, the Port Dogs of the 455th Expeditionary Airwing load cargo planes with trucks weighing a dozen tons and pallets weighing 10,000 pounds that the push onto the airplanes by hand.</p>
<p>Along the way, there are troops who sort and separate, update records and pack containers. Most of the equipment will come back to the U.S. for repairs and refitting for use in future training. Much of it will be staged at bases around the world, waiting at the ready for the next unseen war. Logisticians have been moving thousands of people and tons of supplies under horrendous conditions since war began. The retrograde from Afghanistan is an enormous challenge, one that will likely be studied decades from now when logisticians have to make similar magic happen again. “The numbers look intimidating, but we&#8217;re a big organization,” says Brigadier Felix Gedney, a British exchange officer serving as deputy commanding general for transition in the 1st Infantry Division. “It&#8217;s in the art of the possible that it&#8217;s achievable.&#8221;</p>
<hr />
<p><em><a href="http://lightbox.time.com/tag/yuri-kozyrev/"><strong>Yuri Kozyrev</strong></a> is a contract photographer for TIME and was named the 2011 <a href="http://www.poyi.org/69/41/" target="_blank">Photographer of the Year</a> in the Pictures of the Year International competition.</em></p>
<p><em><a href="http://nation.time.com/author/naterawlings/"><strong>Nate Rawlings</strong></a> is a reporter for TIME. He writes for the magazine’s Briefing section and about politics, government and military affairs for TIME.com.</em></p>
<hr />
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/67278/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/67278/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=67278&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://lightbox.time.com/2013/03/07/americas-long-withdrawal-from-afghanistan-photographs-by-yuri-kozyrev/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://timethemoment.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/koy201301300024.jpg?w=250" />
		<media:content url="http://timethemoment.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/koy201301300024.jpg?w=250" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">KOY201301300024</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/7d512d69c1de31de1ea1a26b1002bfb9?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F1.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">patrickwittytime</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>South Central Belfast</title>
		<link>http://vernacularisms.com/2013/03/07/south-central-belfast/</link>
		<comments>http://vernacularisms.com/2013/03/07/south-central-belfast/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 13:55:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>jasonoruairc</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[basketball]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bedford Street]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Belfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Boyz n the Hood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[British Army]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cabbie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[checkpoint]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[City Hall]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fear]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jason O'Rourke]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Literature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lower Ormeau Road]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ormeau Road]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RUC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[short story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[South Central Los Angeles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[taxi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[taxi depot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Troubles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vernacularisms.com/?p=908</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Rare birds have flown thousands of miles to land on the Lower Ormeau Road. It is a glorious summer Saturday and I am going across town to visit a friend who lives on the Antrim Road. They are standing outside the taxi depot: two black guys wearing basketball kit, bright primary-coloured vests and shorts. They [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=908&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://vernacularisms.com/2013/03/07/south-central-belfast/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/00c7363b379d75884e2b9a531473c21e?s=96&#38;d=wavatar&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jasonoruairc</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jasonoruairc.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/20121205_140548.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">20121205_140548</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fashion Shmashion</title>
		<link>http://thoughtcatalog.com/2013/fashion-shmashion/</link>
		<comments>http://thoughtcatalog.com/2013/fashion-shmashion/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 04:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Thought Catalog</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Clothes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Clothing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dressing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fashion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Malls]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Urban Outfitters]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thoughtcatalog.com/?p=173319</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Fashion forces me to think about who I am on some kind of deep, existential level. <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=173319&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_173337" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 594px"><img class="size-full wp-image-173337" alt="Shutterstock.com" src="http://thoughtcatalog.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/shutterstock_66016366-1.jpg?w=584&#038;h=584" width="584" height="584" /><p class="wp-caption-text"><a href="http://www.shutterstock.com/index-in.mhtml">Shutterstock.com</a></p></div>
<p>A while ago, I came across this gem of a quote while listening to an interview with Ira Glass on one of my regular podcasts, <i>WTF with Marc Maron</i>. As the topic of fashion was broached, Glass had this to say:</p>
<blockquote><p>Then I quickly throw on some clothes &#8212; the same outfit every day, pretty much. It’s just… I hate shopping because I hate myself and I don’t know what clothes to wear. And I get into an existential crisis when I have to choose clothes because I think &#8216;Well who am I, that I would wear this shirt rather than this one.&#8217; I’m not proud of that… There was a period about 10 years ago where I would have to get drunk in order to buy clothes.</p></blockquote>
<p>I think about this all the time, probably because this pretty closely captures how I feel when buying clothes. Shopping is torture. Screw waterboarding &#8211; let&#8217;s start dragging suspected terrorists to Urban Outfitters on Friday afternoons for v-neck tee shopping with snot-nosed hipsters. We might actually get some answers.</p>
<p>The problem isn&#8217;t that I hate clothing &#8211; I actually consider myself moderately interested in fashion. No, my distaste for shopping has more to do with the anxiety that it entails. For one thing, finding clothes in my size is a to-do. Don&#8217;t get me wrong &#8212; being small has its advantages. I can&#8217;t tell you how many times I&#8217;ve hidden in a modest crevice or disguised myself as a child to gain access to restricted areas. This is for legal reasons, not because I don&#8217;t know how many times. Point is, with smallness comes stealth, about which people over six feet know nothing. These advantages are of little help when it comes to fashion, however. Admittedly, the perpetual realization that the smallest-sized slacks in the men&#8217;s section are still far too big never fails to emasculate.</p>
<p>But the main reason I hate clothes shopping is similar to the reason Glass gives. It forces me to think about who I am on some kind of deep, existential level. What could possibly be more revolting than that? As if I don&#8217;t dislike myself enough, now I have to beat myself up with all the reasons why I&#8217;m not the kind of person who can wear white linen pants paired with an ironic Budweiser shirt. It looks great on the mannequin — why shouldn&#8217;t it look good on me? What&#8217;s he got that I don&#8217;t? I don&#8217;t hate mannequins in my normal life. While clothes shopping, however, my contempt for them is incandescent. Some small solace can be taken in the fact that they don&#8217;t have eyes.</p>
<p>In a way, it’s paralyzing to think about the vast array of clothing that I&#8217;ll never be able to wear. Particularly because, in each instance, it forces me to dwell on why, exactly, that may be the case &#8212; which defect in my physique or personality is responsible. Could I pull off one of those wispy, Middle-Eastern-looking scarves that Kanye West wears, for example? What does it say about me that the answer is absolutely not? Am I boorish and unrefined? Do I have a weird chin? Am I a bad rapper? The ensuing pit of anxiety is literally bottomless. And this is just one item of clothing&#8211;an accessory, at that. You get the idea.</p>
<p>A tank top is a good example of something I have never been able to wear convincingly. I wish I could. I really do. It&#8217;d be fantastic if I could throw my inhibitions and sleeves to the wind for just one day. I&#8217;ve tried it before. The result is me feeling highly uncomfortable and passersby looking at me disdainfully &#8211; condescendingly, as if to say, &#8220;nice try, little fella.&#8221; This item, as it turns out, is reserved for men with man-sized arms, as opposed to girly-men with bony shoulders and the biceps of a twelve-year-old with polio.</p>
<p>Some other examples of things I can&#8217;t wear:</p>
<p>A vest.</p>
<p>A useless garment. Still, it stings a little that I&#8217;ll never pull off the Will Smith in <i>Wild Wild West </i>look. Sigh.</p>
<p>A sideways belt.</p>
<p>As best I can tell, this look requires a carefree attitude and a skateboard. Neither of which I have.</p>
<p>A fedora.</p>
<p>This has become much more alluring since I started watching <i>Mad Men</i>. But times have changed since 1965 and I don&#8217;t go on cruises or hang out at the Olive Garden bar nearly enough to pull off a fedora convincingly.</p>
<p>Long story short &#8212; I don&#8217;t go clothes shopping very often. It&#8217;s not a pretty sight. If you know me, this is why I&#8217;ve never invited you or anyone else to join me on such an excursion. It starts about an hour in with sharp headaches followed by cold sweat and usually ends with me vomiting on a rack of cardigans while screaming at flustered Banana Republic employees to get their hands off me.</p>
<p>So for now I guess I&#8217;ll stick with my small, trusty collection of jeans, sweaters, and collared shirts ranging in color from light gray to navy to medium black. I&#8217;ll put off the clothes shopping til the next time I&#8217;m in the mood for an aneurysm. [tc-mark]</p>
<h3 style="padding-left:60px;">You should like Thought Catalog on Facebook <a href="http://www.facebook.com/thoughtcatalog">here</a>.</h3>
<p>[ad-mpu] </p>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=173319&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thoughtcatalog.com/2013/fashion-shmashion/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://thoughtcatalog.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/fashionsmashion.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://thoughtcatalog.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/fashionsmashion.jpg?w=150" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/1697c5ba542014f5a562dbd265a1413f?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tcguestwriters</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thoughtcatalog.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/shutterstock_66016366-1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Shutterstock.com</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
