<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2012 22:02:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>The Handmaid&#8217;s Tale. A Feminine Dystopia.</title>
		<link>http://oldnewortrue.wordpress.com/2012/09/09/the-handmaids-tale-a-feminine-dystopia/</link>
		<comments>http://oldnewortrue.wordpress.com/2012/09/09/the-handmaids-tale-a-feminine-dystopia/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2012 15:10:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Kate</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Book Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Backlist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Literature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Margaret Atwood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Feminism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Handmaid's Tale]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Utopia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dystopia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Satire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Allegory]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://oldnewortrue.wordpress.com/?p=500</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[dystopia: n. an imagined place or state in which everything is unpleasant or bad There are books that wrestle with your insides. They twist upon themselves, cramping, writhing, peristalsing until a  peculiar taste rises into your mouth. It surprises you with its bitter, jagged notes&#8230;this doesn&#8217;t do it justice.  The taste defies description. It is [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=500&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://oldnewortrue.wordpress.com/2012/09/09/the-handmaids-tale-a-feminine-dystopia/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://oldnewortrue.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/ht.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://oldnewortrue.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/ht.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">HT</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/ba376ce797fd6f89944d57f003bdf82d?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">oldnewortrue</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://oldnewortrue.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/ht.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">HT</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Who You Calling an Old Outsider?</title>
		<link>http://horsehorsetigertiger.net/2012/09/06/442/</link>
		<comments>http://horsehorsetigertiger.net/2012/09/06/442/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2012 06:05:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Saara</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Anshun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Language]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://horsehorsetigertiger.net/?p=442</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[老外/Laowai literally means “old outside” but actually just means “foreigner.” The “old” part connotes respect (see the words for teacher, wife, husband and elder: 老师， 老婆， 老公， 老人家, respectively). People usually call us laowai, and that’s fine. I can’t remember Chinese names for shit, so I make up my own names for everyone anyway [the [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=442&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>老外/Laowai literally means “old outside” but actually just means “foreigner.” The “old” part connotes respect (see the words for teacher, wife, husband and elder: 老师， 老婆， 老公， 老人家, respectively). People usually call us <em>laowai</em>, and that’s fine. I can’t remember Chinese names for shit, so I make up my own names for everyone anyway [the people in my neighborhood are Harriet Fruit-Lady, Stella Fruit-Lady, Cecelia NuoMiFan (best 糯米饭 in China, y’all!), Chinese Mr. Rogers (dude rocks a cardigan), and the Green Family (Their restaurant sign is green. Shut up! Clarity beats wit.)]. I hope that our neighbors have special names for us, like “American Fancystockings” and “Foreign Pretty-Glasses,” but I suspect that we’re just <em>The Laowai</em>.</p>
<div id="attachment_444" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 235px"><a href="http://horsehorsetigertigerdotnet.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4150.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-444 " title="She is anonymous. She is legion. " src="http://horsehorsetigertigerdotnet.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4150.jpg?w=225&h=300" alt="" width="225" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Can you spot the foreigner in this picture?</p></div>
<p>No bigs. We’re never going to blend. And it&#8217;s not like there are so many foreigners wandering Anshun&#8217;s streets that they need to differentiate us from each other. When we moved here, we were, as far as we know, the only two foreigners in town. One day at the visa office, we ran into one grumpy American (He was snappish with my waiban. Want to get on the shortlist of people I wouldn’t ask paramedics to pull from a burning cardboard box? Get snappish with the guy who went on a special trip to buy me a space heater because he read that it might get cold that weekend.), but when I asked him how long he’d be in Anshun, he said, “as little as possible,” so I&#8217;m sure he&#8217;s gone by now. Last Thanksgiving weekend, a 70-something Irish dude showed up at our house, and he’s cool. But we only saw him the once. We had Joanne for awhile, a hilarious, whip-smart Bruneian girl who springed (earlier than summering, later than wintering) on the beige shores of Anshun, but she’s abandoned us for stupid college (We miss you, Joanne!). Oh, and there’s a shady dude who wears shiny shirts and tells Eric to shave his beard so he can get with Chinese girls and pretends he’s (Mr. Shady, not Eric) British when he clearly isn’t (Has anyone heard of Oslo, England yet? Until then, he’s a creeper.). So I’m saying that, in this town, foreigners are rare. Even tourists don’t pop up much. Several months ago in our Byzantine open market, I walked past two stocking-capped, backpacked foreigners, but they, like many foreigners China, averted their eyes as soon as they saw me (Travelers, what’s up with that? I’ll talk to you in Mandarin if a total immersion experience is really that important to you.).</p>
<p>Anyway: Near campus, they’re used to us; we see the same people every day, get crazy with the small talk (us: Mandarin / them: Anshun’s dialect). Even the people we don’t often talk to see us enough to know we’re teachers at the college who like to snack on 小聚字 and wave at all the street dogs. No one calls us 老外, except 娜娜, who is 18 months old, and whenever she says it, her parents tell her instead to call us “Auntie” and “Uncle” (阿姨 and 叔叔). I’m sure they call us 老外 when we’re not around because what else would you call us? But they get that we&#8217;re not just 老外. Or at least we&#8217;re <em>their</em> 老外.</p>
<p>But whenever we leave our area, we attract stares. And giggles. And catcalls. We go to the train ticket office, and someone yells “haalllllooo” from across the street. When we look, they turn away and laugh.* We go shoe shopping, and mothers grab their toddlers and point and say “看到老外！” (Look at the foreigners!).</p>
<p>On the same day that I saw the two foreigners in the open market, a woman standing not two feet away pointed at me, laughed and yelled “老外！” over my head to her friend across the street. At the time, I hadn&#8217;t learned enough Chinese to deal gracefully, so I glared at her and harrumphed away, trying to cuss away the powerlessness.</p>
<p>I’ve since developed what I hope are friendlyish ways to deal with the attention—I ask people in Chinese how they knew we were foreigners (It’s a funny joke!) or ask them if they’re a foreigner too (Equally funny!). Sometimes, just starting a little conversation with whatever stranger is handy works—1) If the catcaller is still paying attention, they then figure out that I speak Chinese, but more importantly 2) Because the person I’m talking with usually responds graciously, with a combination of enthusiasm and, when I&#8217;m lucky, nonchalance (How I love not being a big deal!), I’m reminded that not every Chinese person is out to yell insensitive crap at me, that I can connect, in whatever momentary way, with the people in my community. Sadly, my Chinese isn’t good enough to have an in-depth conversation about the objectification of the other and the wacky cultural differences in expressions of respect and rudeness, but I take what I can get.</p>
<p>[Also, some people that I try to talk to just stare at me in shock and stammer that they don’t speak English (I don’t think my Chinese is <em>that</em> bad, so I’m not sure what that’s about). But usually, people are nice. I should more often give people the opportunity to remind me that they want to be nice to me.]</p>
<p>[Also also, sometimes, I do not respond gracefully. Sometimes, people catch me when I’m tired—a wise friend pointed out that sleep is the most important resource a PCV has—or hungry or stressed out, and I don’t react well. I stop; I glare; I tell them, in Chinese, to stop being rude (or, once, I mixed up two similar-sounding words and told some poor guy to stop being boring; he looked so sad. I feel really guilty about that one). Sometimes I talk to myself loudly in Chinese about rude people and how they’re annoying me to DEATH! which is so very passive aggressive of me, and I’m not proud, and I’m sorry that I’m not always the best foreigner I can be.]</p>
<p>My Chinese friends say that the catcallers and gawkers don’t mean it badly, that they’re just curious, that they’re trying to be friendly. I don’t exactly buy it. 1) Some of them do mean it badly, which is to say that they mean to make their friends laugh or to make themselves look good and aren’t thinking about us as people, which is understandable and human, but one of the lamer elements of being human. It’s lame when Americans do it—in our own, sneaky American way—to foreigners or homeless people or whomever we think is freaky. It’s lame when Chinese people do it to me. Plus, 2) even if they don’t mean it badly, I don’t know how much that matters. But maybe that’s because I’m American? It seems like my Chinese friends care more about what people <em>mean</em>; I care more about what people <em>do</em>. Neither is a better or worse way to look at things (Really; both have benefits and drawbacks, and of course, it’s so much more complex than I’ll make it sound in a blog post, and really, does it matter, ideas like better and worse?); it’s just difficult sometimes to reconcile two apparently opposing philosophies. And maybe one is a better outlook when you’re living in China, and the other is better when you’re in America.</p>
<p>It’s easy to rethink something or see it from someone else’s perspective, but it’s so difficult to unlearn an emotional reaction. So when strangers yell at me and laugh, I react the way I would in America—I get hurt. I feel angry. No matter how well they mean it. The best I can do most days is keep my auto-pilot reaction on the inside and react like a sane person on the outside. When I don’t have the energy for it, I try not to leave the area of our campus. All that is a lot of emotional work to go through. We have a few friends in town, but the language and culture barriers are such that hanging out with them isn’t exactly a comfort yet; it’s more like an investment in the possibility of future comfort.</p>
<p>I’m glad we moved to China. I love learning new things about Chinese—and, by extension, American—culture. I love learning to speak, read, and write Mandarin. I love that the high school girl that works in Green Family’s restaurant rubs my shoulder to say hello. I love that 娜娜 unwraps gum and gives it to me when I’m done eating at her parents’ restaurant. I love visiting schools in the countryside with our tutor and watching her start gleeful, liquor-fueled crap with people at banquets (even when I don’t understand the dialect she’s using). I love having the same conversation with the Harriet Fruit-Lady every day (You going home? / Yes. How’s business? / Good. / See you tomorrow!). I love working with my students. But living in China as a foreigner can feel isolated sometimes. Isolation, like a dearth of central heat or hot water in the kitchen, is one of the hardships I signed up for, but it still feels pretty whack. In philosophical moments, I get that this is a valuable experience for me to have. I grew up blond on a peninsula of blondness, and as I’ve moved from state to state, I’ve continued fit in, more or less. But in China, I’m irrevocably marked by my skin and my hair and my speech as an other. Of course, I still carry the privilege of being white and American and educated and temporarily-but-not-really-poor (fingers crossed!); I’m not going to pretend. But sometimes it does suck, and suck is suck is suck, no matter how much un-suck I&#8217;m otherwise granted, and no matter how much worse other people have it. Their good isn’t less good because mine is better, right? So the opposite is true too, I think. That’s probably several kinds of logical fallacy, but I’m sticking to it for now.</p>
<p>You are tempted to comment with something inspirational. You want to give me a practical solution. You want to line smog with silver. Please, gentle reader, resist. Sometimes things should be complicated and difficult. Let’s just let me struggle.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>*I should note here that laughter can mean very different things for Chinese people than it does for Americans. Laughter in both places communicates complex, amorphous emotions; but in each country, they&#8217;re slightly different complex, amorphous emotions; plus, where and when it&#8217;s appropriate to laugh is different. So, you know. You know?</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/442/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/442/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=442&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://horsehorsetigertiger.net/2012/09/06/442/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/275e48b764f712a897c019036423708e?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">saaramyrene</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://horsehorsetigertigerdotnet.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4150.jpg?w=225" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">She is anonymous. She is legion. </media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Next Wave of Computing</title>
		<link>http://twothirdsdone.com/2012/09/08/whentechnologies-collide-the-next-wave-of-computing-2/</link>
		<comments>http://twothirdsdone.com/2012/09/08/whentechnologies-collide-the-next-wave-of-computing-2/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2012 21:07:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>avram miller</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[about business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Post PC Period]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://twothirdsdone.com/?p=931</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This is an amazing graph from GigaOm (see story here).  As readers of my blog  know, I played a very significant role in creating residential broadband starting in 1992 and continuing until 1999, when I resigned my position at Intel as Corp. Vice President of Business Development. While I was sure then that the Internet [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=931&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://twothirdsdone.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/post-pc-slays-pc-11.png"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-932" title="post-pc-slays-pc (1)" src="http://twothirdsdone.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/post-pc-slays-pc-11.png" alt="" width="450" height="390" /></a><br />
This is an amazing graph from GigaOm (see story<a href="http://gigaom.com/2012/09/01/hp-dell-and-the-paradox-of-the-disrupted/"> here</a>).  As readers of my blog  know, I played a very significant role in creating residential broadband starting in 1992 and continuing until 1999, when I resigned my position at Intel as Corp. Vice President of Business Development. While I was sure then that the Internet would change everything, I could not have predicted these results.  Apple was still struggling after Steve Jobs’ return and had a market capitalization of just eight billion dollars.  Amazon had a market cap that was more than twice as high but was basically a book seller.  Google had just eight employees and was based in a garage. Microsoft’s market capitalization was about 270 billion. It had the highest market capitalization in the world, a position now occupied by Apple.  By the way, Intel’s was about 150 billion.  Both of these companies have about the same value now as they had 13 years ago.</p>
<p><strong>The PC Revolution Turns the Computer Industry on its Side</strong><br />
Microsoft, Intel, Dell, Compaq (which became part of HP after first acquiring Digital Equipment Corp a leader of the previous generation of computer companies) were all products of the PC revolution. Apple was not (more on this later).    The PC revolution is an example of what happens when two major and to some extent un-correlated technology discontinuities collide.   The PC industry happened because an independent semi conductor industry lead by Intel met up with an independent software industry lead by Microsoft, and unleashed by accident by IBM.  That flipped the computer industry. Until that time it was  pretty much a vertical where the major computer companies developed all their own technology from disks to operating systems. It was a world of proprietary architecture. The leading companies where IBM, Digital Equipment Company and HP.   Because both Microsoft and Intel were willing and eager to sell to anyone, many companies were formed such as Compaq and Dell to offer PC products. These companies developed little in the way of unique technology.  In fact, to some extent, their innovations were in sales and marketing strategies. I should also give credit to the disk industry which was lead by Seagate in the early days, but this industry did not play a leading role in creating the market.  The difference was that both Microsoft and Intel had near monopolies (we were taught not to say that word at Intel) on their segments ,while the disk  and memory industry had many players and never generated enough profit to be market leaders.  At one time it was thought that Microsoft and Intel had 120% of the profit of the PC industry (meaning many companies participating in the industry actually lost money).</p>
<p><strong>The House of Wintel</strong><br />
While Intel and Microsoft can both take credit for exploiting the opportunity that was created by the collision, neither company had that much to do with the other in the early days of the PC revolution.  In fact, each company would have preferred to see the other weakened and would actually take action from time to time to try to accomplish this. I remember that twice Intel had worked with Apple using Intel programers to convert the Mac OS to run on Intel Architecture (x86) during the 90s when the Mac ran on PowerPC chips only to have Steve Jobs decide not move to Intel. Steve probably was just leveraging Intel to put pricing pressure on Motorola who was the main supplier of the Power PC chips.  Intel also had an active Unix effort which drove Microsoft nuts.  Microsoft would refuse to take advantage of advanced features of Intels’ new microprocessors.  Microsoft even invested in a company called MicroUnity whose mission was to create a new microprocessor architecture that could leap over anything Intel was doing.  The company made amazing claims but failed to live up to them.  Anyway, not all was cozy in the “House of Wintel” as attested to by my friend, Steve McGeady, a former Intel Executive when he testified at the Microsoft Anti-Trust trial in 1998.</p>
<p><strong>The Internet Meets Broadband</strong><br />
Around the middle of 1995 two other technology trends were slated to collide.  They were residential broadband and the Internet.  The early stage of residential broadband (Cable modems and then DSL) was driven primarily by Intel under my direction.  At the time we started the development of cable modem technology in 1992, I was aware of the Internet.  Mosaic, the first browser developed at the University of Illinois by a team directed by Marc Andreessen, was released in 1993.  Netscape Navigator,  the first commercial browser was released towards the end of 1994.  I had a chance to invest in Netscape at a pre-money valuation of eighteen million dollars, which I passed on, thinking it was too expensive -one of the greatest mistakes I made as a venture investor.  At that time,  the internet was mostly used by engineers and academics in universities, businesses and government.  Corporations used things like cc:Mail and Lotus Notes.  Consumers were just beginning to use email within online services like AOL, Prodigy and CompuServe.  But both the business and consumer services were proprietary and it was not possible to communicate between them.  However, for a number of reasons, gateways were created to allow email to be sent out of these “email islands” to the internet and from there it was possible to connect to other islands.</p>
<p><strong>Residential Broadband the Child of TV</strong><br />
Residential broadband was build on a platform that was created for Television Transmission.   The key ingredient that made broadband possible was the development of Digital Cable Transmission of video.  General Instruments, who became Intel’s partners in creating residential broadband for the cable industry, demonstrated the capability to convert analog video to digital in 1989. The cable industry was excited about the potential of this capability and in 1992, John Malone, the CEO of TCI and, at the time, the de facto leader of the Cable Industry, coined the phrase, “the 500 Channel Universe”. I am sure that he never realized at that time he was laying the foundation for the multi million channel universe that is today&#8217;s internet.<br />
Coupled with this was the development of High Definition Television which was to use the same underlying technology.  I have repeated this story on my blog many times so I will not go into a lot of detail here.  Matt Miller, the CTO of General Instruments and I, came to the realization that interactivity would take place in the home via personal computers and not interactive TV&#8217;s and very importantly, that we could use the very same infrastructure developed for digital television to create a broadband network for PCs.  Our respective technical teams worked together to develop early cable modems and head-end equipment (the equipment that was located at the cable operators site). Intel developed the cable modem communications protocols  which we provided to the Cable Labs (the R&amp;D arm of the cable industry).  I evangelized the concept of residential broadband, meeting with the CEOs’ of all the major cable companies, and introduced the concept throughout the world.  Intel licensed manufacturers of cable modems such as Cisco and HP. The rest is as they say, is “history”.</p>
<p><strong>The Web Evolves as the New Platform for Computing and Business Models Change</strong><br />
After a few years, it was clear that the internet would become the online platform of choice for consumers and that applications would be based in the world wide web (www). From the perspective of Intel and Microsoft, the growth  in home computer sales driven in large extent by the availability and acceptance of broadband internet  was a good thing.  But contained in this good thing was something else. More and more of the value derived from using computers in the home was being transferred to the products and services running on the Internet or as we now say, the cloud.  Having a high speed network, wireless access in the home, and a great monitor was more important then having a fast CPU.<br />
Business models were changing.  Previously, consumers bought hardware and software.  Now, new elements were being introduced into the mix.  Consumers were paying monthly subscriptions for access to services like broadband or even music sites.  Importantly, advertising started to appear on the internet. At the time, 1994, I said “advertising will be the killer app of the internet”.    Companies like Intel, Microsoft and Dell were being left out of these growing segments of revenue.   I remember in the mid 90s, speaking to Paul Otellini’s staff at one of their strategy sessions.  Paul who is now the CEO of Intel was running the Microprocessor business at Intel then.  I shared with Paul and his senior managers, some of my thinking about the future of the computer industry and introduced the concept that companies could subsidize the purchase of consumer products if they could couple them with re-occurring service charges.  I said this kind of connection between hardware, software and services could change the business model of the computer industry. It took the iPhone to make this concept happen.   Intel was not in a good position to take advantage of the changes that would follow.  While the company had a very important position with respect to consumer awareness resulting from the very effective “Intel inside” campaign, it had no direct relationship with consumers.  I wanted Intel to start selling peripherals (something that Microsoft did) but frankly that would not have helped much.</p>
<p><strong>The Writing on the Wall for Intel</strong><br />
By the time I left Intel in 1999, the writing was pretty much on the wall.  I left partly in frustration that I was not able to get Intel  to understand that we were entering a new phase of the computer industry.  But frankly, I am not sure I could have made suggestions that would have changed the outcome. I would like to think that had I stayed at Intel, I would have convinced the company to acquire Qualcomm which today has a market cap close to that of Intel, but I am not sure.  I think Microsoft was in a better position to bridge the transition but because so much of the value became software based,  it would have taken very different leadership than that provided by Bill Gates and Steve Balmer.  Even companies like Cisco whose income was primarily derived from selling products to companies that provided internet infrastructure did not take advantage of the transition. Intel needs to find away to couple its primary product, the microprocessor, to the services consumers would be enjoying.  About five years, ago, I figured out how to do that and offered my ideas to Intel (without charge).  They were not appreciative and never took my suggestions seriously.  Probably worked out well for me because I could have gotten sucked back into Intel.</p>
<p><strong>Amazon the Emerges as a Leading Competitor to Apple</strong><br />
Amazon is also on the chart.  Amazon is not really a computer company although it is moving quickly in that direction.  It is an online retailer. Its’ competition is other retailers including Target and Walmart.  It started in the book business and has pretty much succeeded in wiping out traditional brick and mortar book sellers (sadly in some opinions).  It is having a major effect on the way all media is distributed.  But in my opinion the best is yet to come for Amazon (by the way, I own the stock). Amazon is trading at an all time high as I write this post.</p>
<p><strong>Google from Brilliance to Mediocrity</strong><br />
Google has done an amazing job monitoring the internet via advertising.  They are, of course, the leader in internet search.  But Google reminds me of of Microsoft.  They have a dominate  market share and a fantastic financial engine.  But their products are mediocre.  Their offerings in every segment other than search is not very inspiring.  Even hotmail and yahoo have more email users than gmail on the web.  Apple has the most email clients on mobile devices.  I recently said in a talk that I gave that “Google has the mediocrity of Microsoft without the greed of Bill Gates”.  They may be in a good position to take advantage of the next wave of computing which will be described later, but I personally doubt that they will.</p>
<p><strong>Apple the Company I Hate to Love</strong><br />
Finally, I have to talk about Apple the company I loved to hate and now hate to love.  As readers of this blog will know, I have a twisted history with Apple.  It started with meeting Steve Jobs in 1982 when he was just 25 years old, continued through the lawsuit between Franklin Computer where I was president. Apple pretty much killed the company via litigation. I have written much about Steve Jobs and Apple on this blog (do a search if you want to see those posts).  Apple, until recently, belonged to the pre-pc era of computing. While not a totally vertical company, Apple controlled most of the technology in their product.  In many ways, Apple reminded me of Digital Equipment Corp., they were the leader in mini computers.  Obviously, there are key differences.  Apple focused on creative professionals and consumers while Digital focused on Engineers and Scientists. Driven by their respective CEOs Ken Olsen and Steve Jobs, I believe they were building computers that they would want to use themselves.<br />
What has fueled the astounding growth of Apple is that they are riding the next wave of computing.  A phrase coined by John Gage, formally of Sun Microcomputer, sums it up:  The Network is the Computer.  But I want to add another concept: Ubiquitous Computing.  This means that everyone and to a lesser degree everything is connected and intelligent.  I believe this is actually gives rise to the driving factor of what we now call Cloud Computing.  The driver of Cloud Computing is reduction in complexity.  There are other benefits I am sure, like reduced cost, but reduction in complexity is the driver in my opinion.</p>
<p>Just take the issue of accessing  content.  Consumers started ripping music CDs to their computers in 1992.  Digital Compression made it possible for us to store a lot of music on our computers. Then small portable music players came our way that allowed us to take this music with us.  Most of these devices were pretty poor until Apple applied its amazing design capabilities and created the iPod in 2001.  Keeping music synced between a computer and an iPod was not to difficult or complicated.  iTunes was developed with this purpose in mind.  But as I am sure you have experienced, as you try to involve more and more devices (multiple computers, portable players,  and devices to drive home Audio/Visual systems) things get rapidly more complicated.</p>
<p>Eventually, Apple figured out that it is less complicated to store everything in one place “in the cloud” and have every device communicate with the cloud and not directly with each other.  But in doing this they are not really utilizing the open platform that is the internet.  They are just using the Internet infrastructure much in the way that the cable modem used the Cable TV infrastructure.</p>
<p><strong>Computers and Computing Everywhere</strong><br />
Ubiquitous Computing is driving other key technologies. Most prominent in this is mobile communications and form factors.  There is another force that will shape the future of computing and that is security for want of a better word.  As we put more and more of our information in the cloud we become more and more concerned about the security of that information.  I don&#8217;t just mean information theft.  I also mean our ability to access information now and in the future.</p>
<p><strong>When Technologies Collide Money is Made</strong><br />
I started this post talking about what happens when technology discontinuities collide.  I would like to give my views on the next wave of computing.  You can guess that Ubiquitous Computing which will be the driver of Cloud Computing is one of these discontinuities.  But what are the others? I think Network Intelligence will be one.  What I mean here is the application of data mining to personal interactions.  There is evidence of this already with data mining and crowd sourcing.  Amazon suggests  things that I might be interested in buying from looking at my buying patterns and those of others like me.  The same is true for Netflix.  Pandora uses Network Intelligent to suggest music I might like.  Much of these capabilities are being used to market to us.  But this is just a start.</p>
<p>Just think of all the information that a company like Apple will have about us.  It will be interesting to see if the regulatory structure can deal with the access such a company will have to our information.  I for one am not overly concerned, but maybe I should be.  The company that has the most information at the moment is undoubtably Google.  But they will have to recast themselves as a Network Intelligence Company.</p>
<p>I have a lot more to say on this topic but that will have to wait for future posts.</p>
<p><strong>Facebook does not Make the Cut&#8230;</strong><br />
Finally, you may have noticed that I said nothing about Facebook.  This is partly because Facebook was not on the graph but also because I think Facebook is the Yahoo of the next wave.  This statement my surprise some of you because of Facebook&#8217;s strong position in Social Media.  I personally spend a lot of time on Facebook and do believe in the future of Social Media but in the mid 90s I spent a lot of time doing email on AOL.  I still spend a lot of time doing email but have not been on AOL in ten years.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/931/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/931/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=931&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://twothirdsdone.com/2012/09/08/whentechnologies-collide-the-next-wave-of-computing-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/8e18dcc1c8efb92955656187dd932bdc?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">TwoThirdsDone</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://twothirdsdone.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/post-pc-slays-pc-11.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">post-pc-slays-pc (1)</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Decorating the Spaces Between Bricks</title>
		<link>http://katfriedrich.wordpress.com/2012/09/04/decorating-the-spaces-between-bricks/</link>
		<comments>http://katfriedrich.wordpress.com/2012/09/04/decorating-the-spaces-between-bricks/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2012 16:48:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>K.</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cities]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creativity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bricks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[city art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dispatchers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[legos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[monuments]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[street art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[temporary art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[urban art]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://katfriedrich.wordpress.com/?p=1540</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It takes an artistic eye to look at an ordinary wall and see potential spaces for art in the fissures between the bricks. Some artists see the blank spaces between objects as zones where new ideas can emerge. M.C. Escher used white space as a central part of his artwork. Now, in cities around the world, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1540&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It takes an artistic eye to look at an ordinary wall and see potential spaces for art in the fissures between the bricks. Some artists see the blank spaces between objects as zones where new ideas can emerge. <a href="http://www.mcescher.com/">M.C. Escher</a> used white space as a central part of his artwork.</p>
<p>Now, in cities around the world, artists are using plastic bricks to fill in empty spaces and &#8220;patch&#8221; broken walls and monuments. These &#8220;dispatchers&#8221; have collected their handiwork on <a href="http://www.dispatchwork.info/">a website</a> which includes <a href="http://www.dispatchwork.info/manifesto/">their manifesto</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p><em>I don&#8217;t enjoy living in dull and grey cities. Do you? Have you noticed that toys for kids are generally very shiny and colorful? I wonder why that is, given that they are to be brought up to live in mostly dull and gray cities as adults. Since I lived in many of such cities, I am seeking to improve the appearance of public spaces in different ways, in terms of what I consider improvement. Dispatchwork aims to seal fissures in broken walls worldwide, completing the material compilation in urban constructing and adding color to the urban greyscales.</em></p></blockquote>
<p>Like <a href="http://www.graphics.cornell.edu/online/mandala/disk.gif">Buddhist sand mandalas</a>, the repairs are intended to be temporary. Because the plastic will end up in our water systems eventually, I&#8217;d like to see this group experiment with biodegradable LEGOs. Unfortunately, <a href="http://www.architizer.com/en_us/blog/dyn/38781/earth-blocks-the-eco-friendly-lego/">the only biodegradable LEGO-style bricks that exist are a dull shade of brown</a>. Only their scent is attractive; apparently, they smell like green tea.</p>
<p>Since living in Chicago, I have been interested in art projects that reclaim damaged parts of city landscapes. There are many ways to introduce art into cities, including <a href="http://katfriedrich.wordpress.com/2011/12/06/how-majora-carter-changes-the-image-of-cities/">turning vacant lots into parks</a> and <a href="https://www.facebook.com/yarnbombing">yarn bombing</a>.</p>
<p>I participated in a Dispatchers project in Beverly, Massachusetts this weekend. We decorated the entrance of a graffiti-covered building with LEGO-shaped stickers.</p>
<div id="attachment_1541" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://katfriedrich.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dispatchers_2.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1541" title="dispatchers_2" src="http://katfriedrich.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dispatchers_2.jpg?w=300&h=225" alt="A Dispatchers event in Beverly, MA." width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Dispatchers standing next to an entrance covered with LEGO-style stickers.</p></div>
<p>We also inserted LEGOs into the foundation of a building at the Montserrat College of Art, as well as some other buildings including the Unitarian church on Cabot Street. We used friction and a small amount of silicone caulk to hold the LEGOs in place.</p>
<div id="attachment_1542" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://katfriedrich.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/558597_382504805154710_468013060_n.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1542" title="Inserting Lego bricks into the foundation of the Montserrat art school's Hardie Building" src="http://katfriedrich.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/558597_382504805154710_468013060_n.jpg?w=300&h=225" alt="Inserting Lego bricks into the foundation of the Montserrat art school's Hardie Building" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Inserting LEGO bricks into the foundation of the Montserrat College of Art&#8217;s Hardie Building.</p></div>
<p>Curious about whether Dispatchers have been at work in your city? Explore <a href="http://www.dispatchwork.info/">the Dispatchwork website</a> for more details and photos of the installations. Many of the installations are in Europe, but some are in Asia, the Middle East, and North America.</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://katfriedrich.wordpress.com/category/art/'>art</a>, <a href='http://katfriedrich.wordpress.com/category/cities/'>cities</a>, <a href='http://katfriedrich.wordpress.com/category/creativity/'>creativity</a> Tagged: <a href='http://katfriedrich.wordpress.com/tag/art/'>art</a>, <a href='http://katfriedrich.wordpress.com/tag/bricks/'>bricks</a>, <a href='http://katfriedrich.wordpress.com/tag/city-art/'>city art</a>, <a href='http://katfriedrich.wordpress.com/tag/dispatchers/'>dispatchers</a>, <a href='http://katfriedrich.wordpress.com/tag/legos/'>legos</a>, <a href='http://katfriedrich.wordpress.com/tag/monuments/'>monuments</a>, <a href='http://katfriedrich.wordpress.com/tag/street-art/'>street art</a>, <a href='http://katfriedrich.wordpress.com/tag/temporary-art/'>temporary art</a>, <a href='http://katfriedrich.wordpress.com/tag/urban-art/'>urban art</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1540/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1540/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1540&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://katfriedrich.wordpress.com/2012/09/04/decorating-the-spaces-between-bricks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/2f84af4a45e9c0b1219c0eb4bee99042?s=96&#38;d=&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">katanalyze</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://katfriedrich.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dispatchers_2.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">dispatchers_2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://katfriedrich.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/558597_382504805154710_468013060_n.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Inserting Lego bricks into the foundation of the Montserrat art school&#039;s Hardie Building</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gina Rinehart &#8211; Meme Mining</title>
		<link>http://wemattermedia.com/2012/09/09/gina-rinehart-meme-mining/</link>
		<comments>http://wemattermedia.com/2012/09/09/gina-rinehart-meme-mining/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2012 15:13:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>jonathanandrewbrown</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Analysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gender]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[class]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gina rinehart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[memes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mining]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[misogyny]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sexism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://wemattermedia.com/?p=203</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There is a big difference between criticising someone for their actions, their words or their values and criticising someone for their gender or appearance.<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=203&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://wemattermedia.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/screen-shot-2012-09-08-at-11-49-18-pm.png"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-204" title="Gina Rinehart" src="http://wemattermedia.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/screen-shot-2012-09-08-at-11-49-18-pm.png?w=300&h=160" alt="" width="300" height="160" /></a></p>
<p>One of my favourite parts of online culture is the spread of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_meme" target="_blank">memes.</a></p>
<p>Memes are a simple, creative and often hilarious way of making a point, subverting a culture, challenging hypocrisy or to simply have a good laugh.</p>
<p>Memes have also become a surprise source of political commentary and social change. Whenever a public figure makes a big statement you can almost instantly go online and find a series of memes co-opted from their words.</p>
<p>When it was reported that Australian mining magnate Gina Rinehart <a href="http://www.couriermail.com.au/business/gina-rinehart-tells-whingers-get-out-of-the-pub/story-fn7kjcme-1226461328341" target="_blank">made calls for the minimum wage in Australia to be lowered and criticised the country&#8217;s poor</a>, Australians leapt at the opportunity to respond. A variety of memes emerged responding to Rinehart&#8217;s comments:</p>
<p><a href="http://wemattermedia.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/rinehart.jpeg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-205" title="Rinehart" src="http://wemattermedia.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/rinehart.jpeg?w=300&h=200" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://wemattermedia.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/rinehart2.jpeg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-206" title="Rinehart2" src="http://wemattermedia.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/rinehart2.jpeg?w=300&h=212" alt="" width="300" height="212" /></a></p>
<p>Many of the memes provided an important outlet for Australians to respond to Rinehart&#8217;s statements. The role of humour and satire cannot be underestimated in terms of social impact. The memes have contributed to some important social, cultural and political discussions.</p>
<p>However, the spread of the meme has also raised some serious issues about how these online cultures can provide a platform for attacks of another kind:</p>
<p><a href="http://wemattermedia.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/kfc.jpeg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-207" title="KFC" src="http://wemattermedia.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/kfc.jpeg" alt="" width="194" height="259" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://wemattermedia.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/trainer.jpeg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-208" title="trainer" src="http://wemattermedia.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/trainer.jpeg" alt="" width="194" height="259" /></a></p>
<p>After seeing a string of images posted online criticising Rinehart on the basis of her appearance or gender <a href="https://twitter.com/JB_AU/status/244322121608753152" target="_blank">I tweeted the following:</a></p>
<blockquote><p>I love the Gina Rinehart memes calling her out on her bullshit, I do not however like the ones focusing purely on her gender or weight.</p></blockquote>
<p>There is a big difference between criticising someone for <em>their actions, their words or their values</em> and criticising someone for <em>their gender or appearance</em>. There is an inherent viciousness and hypocrisy in Rinehart&#8217;s recent statements towards the less fortunate in our community that is worthy of ridicule. Many of the memes that have spread relating to Rinehart  have been a vital way of helping the community process and respond to her statements. The community rejection of her values has been important, but the community is also served a great disservice by those who criticise Rinehart purely because of her weight or gender.</p>
<p>Just because Gina Rinehart is unpopular in the public eye, does not make it okay to stoop to this level. It&#8217;s cheap, it&#8217;s nasty and it lessens the impact of those making valid statements against her values. It helps to perpetuate the kind of stereotypes and misogyny we wouldn&#8217;t take being targeted at our loved ones so we shouldn&#8217;t accept this behaviour being targeted at our public figures, regardless of how unpopular they might be at the time.</p>
<p>We can do better as a community.</p>
<p>Satirise, argue and joke with Gina Rinehart all you like for her ridiculous views, values and words. <em>It&#8217;s actually really important that you do</em>, but before you make a cheap fat joke or a gendered attack on Rinehart think about the negative culture you&#8217;re contributing to.</p>
<p><strong>- Jonathan Brown</strong></p>
<p><strong>Jonathan is the Creative Director of We Matter Media. You can follow him <a title="JB_AU" href="http://www.twitter.com/jb_au" target="_blank">@JB_AU</a></strong></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/203/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/203/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=203&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://wemattermedia.com/2012/09/09/gina-rinehart-meme-mining/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>18</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://wemattermedia.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/screen-shot-2012-09-09-at-1-18-42-am.png?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://wemattermedia.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/screen-shot-2012-09-09-at-1-18-42-am.png?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Screen Shot 2012-09-09 at 1.18.42 AM</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">JB</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://wemattermedia.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/screen-shot-2012-09-08-at-11-49-18-pm.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Gina Rinehart</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://wemattermedia.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/rinehart.jpeg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Rinehart</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://wemattermedia.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/rinehart2.jpeg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Rinehart2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://wemattermedia.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/kfc.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">KFC</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://wemattermedia.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/trainer.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">trainer</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Camp: On Life, On Boyfriend, On Existence</title>
		<link>http://shrinksarentcheap.wordpress.com/2012/09/08/130/</link>
		<comments>http://shrinksarentcheap.wordpress.com/2012/09/08/130/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2012 00:03:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>shrinksarentcheap</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boyfriend]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[campfire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cleaning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cooking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[existence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[intangible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sims]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://shrinksarentcheap.wordpress.com/?p=130</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I was thinking of something and I came in the tent to write it down before I forgot it.  It&#8217;s gone now. Oh, yes.  It was because I was looking at the fire. Boyfriend built an exceptional fire.  It looked like it should be on the cover of Campfire Magazine.  It flickered while the clear [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=130&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I was thinking of something and I came in the tent to write it down before I forgot it.  It&#8217;s gone now.</p>
<p>Oh, yes.  It was because I was looking at the fire.</p>
<p><a href="http://shrinksarentcheap.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/campfire-01.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-131" title="campfire-01" src="http://shrinksarentcheap.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/campfire-01.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="666" /></a></p>
<p>Boyfriend built an exceptional fire.  It looked like it should be on the cover of Campfire Magazine.  It flickered while the clear lake seamed slowly around its lily pads in front of us.</p>
<p>I was watching him prepare our supper.  Cutting zucchini, potato, and onion, pouring oil, marinating chicken.  All by the light of the campfire and his headlamp.</p>
<p>And I was thinking about how this is really not so dissimilar from being at home.  He cooks, I clean, we eat.</p>
<p>Somehow, I was missing all of this from my life before.  Cooking was not enjoyable, it was a chore.  Probably because it consisted mostly of throwing a bag into the microwave for 15 minutes.</p>
<p>Cleaning.  Well, cleaning didn&#8217;t happen.  I just didn&#8217;t care.  I didn&#8217;t know to care.</p>
<p>I didn&#8217;t know to better my own existence with my own hands.</p>
<p>Not until he came along.</p>
<p>Somehow he knows how to live.  Where did he learn it?  Where did he learn that life is doing and doing is good?  That we and nature are intertwined?  That hard work ignites something in your brain?  Peace and happiness and contentment and self-respect.</p>
<p>Sometimes I try to decide whether or not I&#8217;d rather live real life, or just play the Sims.  The Sims is really fun.  There are goals and I know how to achieve them.  There is money and I know how to get it.  There is food, and I know what to eat.  I can exercise moving nothing more than my pointer finger on the mouse and get a hot body.  I can shop for as many clothes as I want.  I can garden without getting sweaty and touching worms.  I can fly to Egypt in ten minutes.  I can fall in love and get married in an hour.  I can have twelve children.  My life can be over and on to the reincarnation within days.  I can be a painter, a pianist, a writer, a scientist.  It&#8217;s easy.</p>
<p><a href="http://shrinksarentcheap.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/49743-the-sims-the-sims.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-132" title="49743-the-sims-the-sims" src="http://shrinksarentcheap.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/49743-the-sims-the-sims.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="375" /></a></p>
<p>Sometimes I really wish I could just ignore my own existence for such simplicity.  Just lose myself in a computer game for eternity.</p>
<p>But with Boyfriend, I&#8217;m telling you, there is this thing.  This unnamable, intangible thing.  I don&#8217;t know what else to call it except &#8220;living&#8221;.  But that isn&#8217;t good enough.</p>
<p>It is a spark.  It is an understanding.  Transcending existence.  Appreciating earth, people, intellect, art, water, and feeling.  Passion and calm.  War and peace.</p>
<p>Life and death.  In and out.  Ending and starting over.</p>
<p>It is fresh air.</p>
<p>And I am lucky to know it.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/130/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/130/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=130&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://shrinksarentcheap.wordpress.com/2012/09/08/130/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/9f4c3ad7d13bdca643f410fd531b56f4?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">shrinksarentcheap</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://shrinksarentcheap.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/campfire-01.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">campfire-01</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://shrinksarentcheap.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/49743-the-sims-the-sims.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">49743-the-sims-the-sims</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>This Is Only A Test</title>
		<link>http://figuringoutfulfillment.wordpress.com/2012/09/05/this-is-only-a-test/</link>
		<comments>http://figuringoutfulfillment.wordpress.com/2012/09/05/this-is-only-a-test/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2012 13:22:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bill</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Career]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fulfillment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Progress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[announcement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[attention]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Emergency Broadcast System]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nuclear war]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[test]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://figuringoutfulfillment.wordpress.com/?p=1752</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Ever since I was a kid, I wanted to be the announcer for the Emergency Broadcast System.  I was fascinated with the periodic tests of the EBS that aired on local television stations.  The dire sound of the two-tone Attention Signal &#8211; purposely designed to feel uncomfortable to the human ear &#8212; the button-down seriousness of [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1752&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://figuringoutfulfillment.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/reed_broadcast-test.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-1758" title="Emergency Broadcast System" src="http://figuringoutfulfillment.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/reed_broadcast-test.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="300" /></a>Ever since I was a kid, I wanted to be the announcer for the Emergency Broadcast System.  I was fascinated with the periodic tests of the EBS that aired on local television stations.  The dire sound of the two-tone <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Emergency_Alert_System_Attention_Signal_20s.ogg" target="_blank">Attention Signal </a>&#8211; purposely designed to feel uncomfortable to the human ear &#8212; the button-down seriousness of the announcer assuring us that this was &#8220;only a test&#8221; (even as an eight-year-old I could hear the implied &#8220;. . . this time!&#8221;) &#8212; every time I heard these, I stopped whatever I was doing and focused on the TV.  Even when I was too young to understand the implications of &#8220;a national emergency,&#8221; I sensed grave danger in the message.  Once I had learned about ICBMs and instant vaporization, mushroom clouds and fallout, the images I could then attach to the &#8220;test&#8221; made it all the more threatening, like the click of the hammer on an empty chamber in a game of Russian Roulette.</p>
<p>Two or three times while changing channels, I happened to turn to a station in the middle of broadcasting the test, so I missed the opening &#8220;only a test&#8221; voiceover and sat through twenty-five horrifyingly anxious seconds of the Attention Signal, wondering if this time it was the real thing and we were all going to die in a burst of nuclear fire.  It was like reading a Stephen King novel while riding a roller coaster, all in less than half a minute.  And then the announcer&#8217;s voice came on, and he let us all know that this had been a test of the Emergency Broadcast System, and we could get on with our lives.  For now.</p>
<p>Before I was even out of grade school, I <strong>wanted</strong> that announcer&#8217;s job.  I learned his script by heart, and said it out loud along with him during the test.  I can still repeat the message, and when I do I feel that same sense of authority and guidance that I associated with that announcement when I was a kid: <a href="http://figuringoutfulfillment.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/this-is-a-test1.docx">Click Here To Hear</a></p>
<p>Yes, that Attention Signal gave me a frisson of terror every time I heard it, but the announcer was always there to assure us that it was only a test, that we would get through this.  In fact, even if worse turned to worst, then, while he couldn&#8217;t do anything to prevent the cataclysm, he would be there to tell us where to go for news and official information.  But it never came to that, and really, what the announcer did every time was tell me that there was nothing to be scared of.</p>
<p>For almost as long as I can remember, I have wanted to be that person, in a way that seems almost irrationally disconnected from anything I actually did that was career-oriented.  Pre-med in college; teaching and marketing in Japan; practicing as a lawyer &#8212; none of that had anything to do with broadcasting or voiceover work.</p>
<p>But this week, a new class of students has entered school, and they&#8217;ve come to our career services office in varying degrees of good-hearted panic.  They&#8217;ve shared with me their hopes of finding the right job and career and their fears that they won&#8217;t, that they don&#8217;t have the right resume or connections or can&#8217;t network or don&#8217;t even know in which direction they should be moving.  And as I sat with them and spoke to them and assured them that they will get through this just fine, that the world is not coming to an end, and, here, let me pass along this news and official information &#8212; I realized that maybe, in a way, I have become the Emergency Broadcast System announcer I always wanted to be.  Relax, everyone.  This is just life.  This is only a test.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1752/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1752/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1752&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://figuringoutfulfillment.wordpress.com/2012/09/05/this-is-only-a-test/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>24</slash:comments>
<enclosure url="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Emergency_Alert_System_Attention_Signal_20s.ogg" length="35817" type="audio/ogg" />
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/1ffea5df9b966cab97f4a388b18dcbc5?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">wmacdonaldfof</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://figuringoutfulfillment.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/reed_broadcast-test.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Emergency Broadcast System</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Reluctant President</title>
		<link>http://msdrocks.wordpress.com/2012/09/07/the-reluctant-president/</link>
		<comments>http://msdrocks.wordpress.com/2012/09/07/the-reluctant-president/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2012 15:02:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Conversations With The Moon</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Bureauacracy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[acceptance speech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[barack obama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Candidate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[current-events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Democrat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DNC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Obama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[President]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quality speech]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Republican]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RNC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Speech]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://msdrocks.wordpress.com/?p=130</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Measured. Professional. Authoritative. Presidential. Safe. President Barack Obama&#8217;s acceptance speech at the 2012 Democratic National Convention in Charlotte was&#8230;okay. I expected more.  I expected passion.  I expected fire.  Or did I?  Things have changed a lot since that day in Denver 4 years ago.  Gone was the intensity.  Make no mistake, last night the President [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=130&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://msdrocks.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/tumblr_m9zilai5bz1qav5oho1_500.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-132" title="Obama Accepts Nomination On Final Day Of Democratic National Convention" src="http://msdrocks.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/tumblr_m9zilai5bz1qav5oho1_500.jpg?w=300&h=200" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></a>Measured. Professional. Authoritative. Presidential. Safe.</p>
<p>President Barack Obama&#8217;s acceptance speech at the 2012 Democratic National Convention in Charlotte was&#8230;okay.</p>
<p>I expected more.  I expected passion.  I expected fire.  Or did I?  Things have changed a lot since that day in Denver 4 years ago.  Gone was the intensity.  Make no mistake, last night the President made a quality speech.  About the issues that speak to me.  He&#8217;s my President. I will likely vote for him again.  It&#8217;s just that&#8230;there was something missing.</p>
<p>I tossed and turned in bed last night and continued to try to put my finger on what it was about the speech that let me down.  At the end of the day, for me, the speech lacked the heart and soul, the immediacy of speeches I&#8217;ve seen this President give in the past.  That Bill Clinton set the bar perhaps too high the day before is inconsequential.  Obama just didn&#8217;t bring it last night.  In fact, I haven&#8217;t seen him bring it in a while.</p>
<p>Obviously I don&#8217;t know the man personally.  But every fiber of my being is certain he is a good, decent, caring and compassionate man.  I am very glad he is our President and hope he gets reelected.  What disturbs me is the lack of passion.  This is not the same man I voted for.  Why?</p>
<p>I want to believe it is because the gravity of being the leader of the free world has sobered Obama.  Whereas Bush forty-three blindly fumbled through his presidency, I really believe Barack Obama gives a damn about what he is doing and how it affects people around the world.  That he reads 10 letters from citizens a night speaks volumes.  I think politician Obama passed away sometime in the last four years and President Obama was born.  I want to believe that the incomprehensible weight of the decisions the man has to make on a daily business has tempered his enthusiasm for hyperbole and rhetoric.  Look at his face in that famous picture where he and his staff are monitoring the Bin Laden mission.  Compare that face to the one of Bush 43 being told the World Trade Center was attacked.</p>
<p>I wanted to see the guy I saw in Denver last night.  That guy didn&#8217;t show.  I hope the guy that showed last night continues to grind away at what he cares about for the next four years.  I&#8217;m afraid the reality of the responsibilities, of the bitter political in-fighting, of the often frightening daily security briefings, have taken their toll on the man who inspired a nation 4 years ago.  I hope President Obama can reach down, for his own sake, and rekindle some of the fire that he once had.  I hope he can believe in himself again&#8230;as so many of us have.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/130/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/130/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=130&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://msdrocks.wordpress.com/2012/09/07/the-reluctant-president/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>56</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/cc8cac7de5a67c2736c6792389b1f1a7?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">karmaliveshere</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://msdrocks.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/tumblr_m9zilai5bz1qav5oho1_500.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Obama Accepts Nomination On Final Day Of Democratic National Convention</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>One Is Never Enough</title>
		<link>http://blogofthecourtier.com/2012/09/07/one-is-never-enough/</link>
		<comments>http://blogofthecourtier.com/2012/09/07/one-is-never-enough/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2012 15:10:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>William Newton</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bibliophile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Black Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bookshop]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[collecting]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogofthecourtier.com/?p=8051</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As if you could not guess, gentle reader, I am something of a bibliophile.  By this I do not mean that I collect beautiful, leather-bound volumes of first editions, nice as those are.  I mean that I love and collect books in many different subject areas, fiction and non-fiction, all of which I actually read [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=8051&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As if you could not guess, gentle reader, I am something of a bibliophile.  By this I do not mean that I collect beautiful, leather-bound volumes of first editions, nice as those are.  I mean that I love and collect books in many different subject areas, fiction and non-fiction, all of which I actually read AND display.  I am the sort of person who winces when he reads of decorators purchasing bulk lots of books by the yard from secondhand bookshops, graded by size, to fill up the shelves of someone whose taste in literature is generally limited to the airport newsstand variety of novel.  And more often than not my books have come to me via someone else&#8217;s previous collection.</p>
<p>On the British sitcom &#8220;Black Books&#8221;, bookshop owner Bernard Black is generally in an impenetrably foul mood.  He hates his customers interrupting his reading, smoking, and drinking, usually getting rid of these interlopers as quickly as possible.  And he has only two friends to speak of: his long-suffering shop assistant and flatmate Manny Bianco, and their mutual friend and fellow alcoholic/chainsmoker, Fran Katzenjammer.  If you have never seen the series, it is a wonderful mix of black comedy, misanthropy, and surrealism.  It is also about the love of books.</p>
<p>It is easy to understand why Bernard gets so fed up with the people who paradoxically both allow him to continue to have books to read, while at the same time they stop him from reading so he can serve them.  Many people in secondhand bookshops are more interested in browsing than buying, and if they do buy they rarely pick up anything more than one book at a time.  The amount of effort required for the shop owner to realize a sale is so much greater than the actual reward, that Bernard does not really care.  In one episode for example, when Manny has successfully managed to shift a large quantity of the stock through good salesmanship, Bernard becomes despondent since he will now have to contact a book supplier to send more books, something which he hates doing and, thanks to his customer handling technique, he almost never has to do.</p>
<p>I know of a bookshop in Barcelona with a proprietor not unlike Bernard in his way, where a few years ago I managed to purchase a book by my great-great-grandfather.  It is probably my most valued book in a rather extensive library (a collection still split between my current residence and my childhood home), since my ancestor inscribed it and gave it as a gift to a friend of his.  The following year I returned to see whether they had any more of his books, but instead of dealing with a pleasant and helpful young shop assistant as I had the previous visit, this time the old man himself quite literally shooed me out of the shop and refused to see whether he had anything: he was too busy smoking his pipe and talking with another elderly fellow.  Needless to say I have never returned there, as tantalizing as their stock is.</p>
<p>Another secondhand bookshop I know here in Washington is somewhat different in its view of its stock, for if you purchase four books you may take a fifth, free &#8211; lowest value, of course.  As it is run by a non-profit with a fairly high rate of book turnover, it does a reasonably brisk trade, and there are always new finds being placed on the shelves by the elderly ladies that work there.  I am particularly fond of tracking down rather technical history and architectural/artistic theory books, or English translations of lesser-kn0wn works by Balzac, and often have success at this shop.  Yet here again, one of the women behind the desk strikes me as a bit suspicious of her patrons, and a bit slow to serve, more interested in what she is reading than in serving.</p>
<p>Perhaps this has to do with the sort of person who would be attracted to working in a bookshop in the first place, or more particularly to working in a used bookshop.  People who love books often are only understood by other people who love books.  One can imagine that the scriptorium of a medieval monastery must have been somewhat similar to a secondhand bookshop in this respect, with some of the monks lingering lovingly over the words they were copying, or the librarian himself keeping choice books back for his own, private enjoyment.  In fact, one of the reasons Umberto Eco&#8217;s &#8220;The Name of the Rose&#8221; was such an engagingly-written tale was that it tried to capture that love &#8211; albeit an obsessive, unhealthy love &#8211; of the accumulation of more and more books, which has not really changed over the centuries.</p>
<p>At the moment back at the manse I have a stack of books which I have not yet read, and which I know I need to tackle, and I will definitely take the sensible option of getting through all of them before I even think of accumulating any more.  Yet even as I do so I cannot help but think about what books I want to read which are missing from my collection, or what wonderful discoveries of books or authors I have never heard of might be waiting for me at a secondhand book shop, charity shop, yard sale, or the like.  Unlike most addictions, the love of good books does not make one less, but rather more, of who you already are &#8211; provided, of course, that you try your best to be polite.</p>
<p><a href="http://blogofthecourtierdotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/scream.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-8057" title="scream" src="http://blogofthecourtierdotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/scream.jpg" alt="" width="480" height="270" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">Bernard Black (Dylan Moran) tries selling an unusual volume on &#8220;Black Books&#8221;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/8051/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/8051/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=8051&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://blogofthecourtier.com/2012/09/07/one-is-never-enough/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>40</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/616142c912caeb6a796e108512987892?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">wbdnewton</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://blogofthecourtierdotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/scream.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">scream</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mostly Incoherent Notes for a Future Essay</title>
		<link>http://roolily.wordpress.com/2012/09/06/mostly-incoherent-notes-for-a-future-essay/</link>
		<comments>http://roolily.wordpress.com/2012/09/06/mostly-incoherent-notes-for-a-future-essay/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2012 17:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ruth</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[". . a hole in the world . ." -- millay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journal, i.e., every post]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grieving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[healing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[living]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://roolily.wordpress.com/?p=12454</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This week, for the first time since he died almost 20 months ago, I&#8217;ve experienced sadness, disappointment and loneliness independent from the mourning. Usually, all of my moods have been a cocktail of emotions with the primary ingredient being sadness over his death. To put it more specifically (and to continue the awful metaphor &#8212; [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=12454&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="aligncenter"><img class="aligncenter" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8030/7943818100_6b13326908.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="350" /></p>
<p class="aligncenter">This week, for the first time since he died almost 20 months ago, I&#8217;ve experienced sadness, disappointment and loneliness <em>independent</em> from the mourning.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Usually, all of my moods have been a cocktail of emotions with the primary ingredient being sadness over his death. To put it more specifically (and to continue the awful metaphor &#8212; oh god, I&#8217;m laughing it&#8217;s such a bad metaphor) his absence sits like ice cubes, always, in every single drink: taking up space, dominating, clunking up against my lips, making noise against the sides of the glass, excruciating to swallow, melting into and diluting all the other elements.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">But this week was different. I realized I was feeling shitty all on my own. 100% Ruth&#8217;s Life Crap. That&#8217;s progress, right?</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">A part of the ice cubes is that I haven&#8217;t noticed myself feeling as much empathy as I did in years past. I see painful things happening, just like we all do, but it&#8217;s like my emotional quota is full &#8212; like I&#8217;ve been maxed out.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Today, this began changing, as well.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">A family I&#8217;m acquainted with is experiencing events which I&#8217;ve read about through Facebook and the dad&#8217;s blog. I haven&#8217;t asked for permission to link to his site; so, I apologize for being vague. Also, since language is powerful, I&#8217;m hesitant to assign labels to what is going on.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">What I can say is, reading his words this morning struck me deeply.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">For the first time in a long time, my tears are for someone besides myself.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Sometimes I think: stop. Just stop. Breathe. Something sacred is happening right now. Be quiet. Pay attention. But the autopilot (sheep) in me continues scrolling down the Facebook feed viewing image after image until, before I know it, I&#8217;m clicking the &#8220;like&#8221; button under some photo of a puppy. And so &amp; so&#8217;s swim team are season champions&#8212;&#8211;wait, what happened to stopping? Sacred moments pass (acknowledged or not). The treadmill keeps going.</p>
<p>Sometimes I think in whispers: <em>I don&#8217;t know what to do</em>. I don&#8217;t know why we die. I don&#8217;t know how some people are taken in a flash while others endure long, slow-motion battles for every moment of comfort, for any fraction of hope.</p>
<p>Sometimes I think in aches rather than words.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;</p>
<p>The father I mentioned above closed his post today with this, &#8220;For now, our mantra is as always: enjoy each other while we can.&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">I&#8217;m in awe.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Suddenly reminded of how grateful I am for the fun I had with my friend. We did enjoy each other, while we still could.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">And here are my ice cubes again. I&#8217;m tiny in a giant glass, clinging to a frozen chunk, it&#8217;s the only thing keeping my head above the surface. I ignore the freezing burns on my arms and chin, and hold more tightly.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">I see the treadmill. I see the people crying. I see the puppies and the swim teams. I hear the speeches. I hear the ice cubes. I hear the prayers and the tweets.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">That staircase in the photo, see it? The music before you go up is awfully good. But no one comes down from there. People will tell you they have the inside scoop, they have <em>signs</em>, they have Jesus(!), they have <em>conviction </em>that what&#8217;s at the top of those stairs is &#8212;&#8211;</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Sometimes my thoughts come as shouts: STOP. YOU KNOW DON&#8217;T KNOW.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">So, let&#8217;s just breathe for a minute.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Let&#8217;s enjoy each other while we can.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;</p>
<p><a href="http://www.tracemyip.org/" target="_blank"><img src="http://s2.tracemyip.org/tracker/1209/4684NR-IPIB/16785/5/njsUrl/" alt="counter code" border="0" /></a></p>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=12454&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://roolily.wordpress.com/2012/09/06/mostly-incoherent-notes-for-a-future-essay/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>21</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/68e347feb958fed6f433440c7005aa11?s=96&#38;d=identicon" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">roolily</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8030/7943818100_6b13326908.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://s2.tracemyip.org/tracker/1209/4684NR-IPIB/16785/5/njsUrl/" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">counter code</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>