<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 14:05:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Choose Your Own Adventure</title>
		<link>http://theothersideof55.wordpress.com/2011/03/27/choose-your-own-adventure/</link>
		<comments>http://theothersideof55.wordpress.com/2011/03/27/choose-your-own-adventure/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2011 00:07:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Margo Karolyi</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Essays on "The Other Side of 55"]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[change]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[choices]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Margo Karolyi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the other side of 55]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://theothersideof55.wordpress.com/?p=471</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Do you ever play the ‘What if?’ game with yourself?  You know the one I mean – “What if I’d travelled instead of going to college right out of high school?”  “What if I hadn’t married my high school sweetheart?” “What if I’d hung on to that cute little house [that’s now worth almost a [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=471&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://theothersideof55.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/whatif.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-472" title="WhatIf" src="http://theothersideof55.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/whatif.jpg?w=135&#038;h=115" alt="What If?" hspace="6" width="135" height="115" /></a>Do you ever play the ‘What if?’ game with yourself?  You know the one I mean – <em>“What if I’d travelled instead of going to college right out of high school?”  “What if I hadn’t married my high school sweetheart?” “What if I’d hung on to that cute little house [that’s now worth almost a million dollars]?” “What if I’d taken that job in [some exotic location]?” “What if I hadn’t won the lottery?”</em> (just kidding).  What if &#8230; What if &#8230; What if &#8230;</p>
<p>I suppose we all have wishes and dreams that never came true &#8211; things we wanted to try, places we could have travelled, paths we might have taken, people we may possibly have loved. Over the years, the number of ‘what ifs’ seem to grow and accumulate, leaving us to wonder how our lives might have turned out ‘if only’ we’d done things differently (at one time or another).</p>
<p>When my boys were little, they used to read books in the ‘Choose Your Own Adventure’ (CYOA) series.  These books were written in the second person (‘you’ as the protagonist) and every-so-many pages you had to make a choice.  Depending on which option you selected, you jumped to another page (forward or back) in the book (e.g., <em>‘You decide to follow Amy into the forest. Go to page 10’ ‘You decide to listen to your own instincts and go home. Go to page 12’</em>) and continued the adventure &#8211; until you had to make another choice &#8230; then another, and another, and another &#8230; and so on until the end (there were generally a dozen or more different ‘endings’ for each book). </p>
<p><a href="http://theothersideof55.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/chooseyourownadventurebook1.jpg" target="_blank"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-474" title="ChooseYourOwnAdventureBook" src="http://theothersideof55.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/chooseyourownadventurebook1.jpg?w=110&#038;h=175" alt="Choose Your Own Adventure Book" hspace="6" width="110" height="175" /></a>The great thing with these little books (each was 400 paragraphs / about 144 pages) was that they could be read many different times and each time it was a new story experience (and probable ending).  And while the reader might recall some of the scenarios used (because you jumped in and out of various scenes based on the alternatives offered at any number of points in the story), each time you made a different selection, you took a different path and ended up in a different place.  <em>SPECIAL NOTE: <a title="Flowchart for 'Choose Your Own Adventure' #2" href="http://flowingdata.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/08/CYO-2-Flowchart_8.pdf" target="_blank">here’s a flowchart </a>showing the various paths and outcomes for CYOA #2 – <span style="text-decoration:underline;">Journey Under the Sea</span>. </em></p>
<p>I started to wonder how my life would look as a CYOA book.  How many different paths – and outcomes – might there be?  Where would I be now if I’d chosen differently? What would I be doing? And who would I be doing it with?  The starting point, of course, would be to map out my life as I have lived it (to date).  But then – providing I could let go (in my mind only, of course) of certain ‘attachments’ (my home, my career, my kids, my husband, my cat) and go wild with my imagination – I could rewrite my life’s story with all the ‘what ifs’ fully explored.  What fun!</p>
<p>Here’s how it might start:</p>
<p><strong>Choose Your Own Adventure #55+ ‘The Search for Lost Opportunities’</strong></p>
<p><a href="http://theothersideof55.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/schoolnewspaperstaff19701.jpg" target="_blank"><img class="size-thumbnail wp-image-476 alignright" title="SchoolNewspaperStaff1970" src="http://theothersideof55.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/schoolnewspaperstaff19701.jpg?w=180&#038;h=120" alt="High School Newspaper Staff, 1970" hspace="6" width="180" height="120" /></a>(Page 1) You live in a small town in southern Ontario, Canada, the fourth child in a family of five.  You’ve led a reasonably uneventful life until now – a middle class existence in a middle class neighbourhood in a middle class town.  You are a straight A student who works part-time in a local retail store. You spend your Saturday nights attending dances at the local YMCA, and Sunday nights at the movies with a small group of friends.  Some of your classmates plan to go to work right out of high school, others have already applied to University, and some are unsure of their future.  However, after working on the school newspaper, you know exactly what career path you want to follow.</p>
<p>(Page 2) You make an appointment with your high school guidance counsellor and your parents attend the meeting with you.  You announce that you want to be a journalist.  Shocked, the counsellor says journalism is not an appropriate career choice for a young girl and suggests you consider becoming a teacher, a nurse, or a secretary instead.  Your parents agree, adding that they can’t afford to pay for three or more years of college anyway.</p>
<p><em>You listen to the guidance counsellor and enrol in a one-year secretarial course at the local community college.  Go to page 3.</em></p>
<p><em>You apply for a student loan and register in a journalism diploma program.  Go to page 5.</em></p>
<p><a href="http://theothersideof55.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/diploma.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-477" title="Diploma" src="http://theothersideof55.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/diploma.jpg?w=120&#038;h=120" alt="Diploma" hspace="6" width="120" height="120" /></a>(Page 5)  Three years later, you have earned your journalism diploma, graduating at the top of your class.  Your passion is writing personal interest stories.  Based on a number of articles about local civic officials that you penned as writing assignments and included in your portfolio, your hometown newspaper offers you an administrative position with the ‘added responsibility’ of writing articles about community events. This means you can live in your hometown, continue seeing the nice, dependable boy you started dating in high school, and earn a steady income with the local paper (although there would be little chance of promotion or more challenging assignments in the near future). </p>
<p>(Page 6) Two weeks before graduation, you hear back from one of the many (other) jobs you applied to. A large daily newspaper in Toronto (‘The City’) offers you a fairly low-paying junior copy-editing position, with the opportunity for promotion within six months to a year.  The environment would be extremely fast-paced, and exciting.  Your best friend has already accepted a fashion design job in the city and offers to share an apartment with you.  Your boyfriend and your parents are very unhappy about the idea of you accepting this job and moving to the city.</p>
<p><em>You take the job in your hometown.  Go back to page 3.</em></p>
<p><em>You take the job in the city.  Go to page 7.</em></p>
<p>Of course, you can see where this is going.  I get to ‘fill in the blanks’ with all the choices I didn’t make, all the people I never met, all the opportunities I missed.  By writing my own adventure, I can choose to remake my life the way I thought it was going to turn out. For better or for worse.</p>
<p><a href="http://theothersideof55.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/choicessignpost.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-478" title="ChoicesSignPost" src="http://theothersideof55.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/choicessignpost.jpg?w=150&#038;h=179" alt="Choices We Make" width="150" height="179" /></a>We make choices every single moment of every single day:  Coffee or tea? Cereal or toast? Yes or no? Left or right?  Open or close? Stop or go? Up or down? Buy or sell? Leave or stay?  Each one changes the outcome of our life’s adventure.  And who’s to say which is ‘right or wrong’?  Does anyone even know?  Some people say our lives are predetermined &#8211; completely mapped out for us even before we are born. Others suggest that we are completely on our own – that we make our own choices and set our own courses minute-by-minute. I’m somewhere in the middle, I suppose.  I believe in fate, not coincidence.  I’m convinced that certain people are destined to show up in our lives when we need them, that opportunities present themselves when we’re ready for them, that we have to experience pain and fear and loss in order to appreciate love and joy and happiness when we have it.  In order for me to be where I am today, I had to go through all the things I have experienced up to this point.  But were some of the people I met, the places I saw, the things I did placed in my path so that I would ‘choose’ them? I like to think so.</p>
<p>In the end I imagine all the paths of my CYOA story would wind up at the same ‘last page’ – I would come back to my hometown, give birth to my boys, take the job that ultimately leads to meeting my husband, make that last-minute decision to look at a house I was sure I wasn’t interested in buying, quit my job to pursue a career in writing.  Because this is exactly the page I’m supposed to be on when I reached &#8230; the other side of 55.</p>
<p><a href="http://theothersideof55.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/lifeisallaboutchoices.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-483" title="LifeIsAllAboutChoices" src="http://theothersideof55.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/lifeisallaboutchoices.jpg?w=300&#038;h=159" alt="Life Is All About Choices" width="300" height="159" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/471/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/471/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/471/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/471/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/471/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/471/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/471/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/471/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/471/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/471/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/471/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/471/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/471/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/471/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=471&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://theothersideof55.wordpress.com/2011/03/27/choose-your-own-adventure/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c8a03c218b3f9df32117e4baf2439700?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">margokarolyi</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theothersideof55.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/whatif.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">WhatIf</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theothersideof55.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/chooseyourownadventurebook1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ChooseYourOwnAdventureBook</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theothersideof55.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/schoolnewspaperstaff19701.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">SchoolNewspaperStaff1970</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theothersideof55.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/diploma.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Diploma</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theothersideof55.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/choicessignpost.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ChoicesSignPost</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theothersideof55.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/lifeisallaboutchoices.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">LifeIsAllAboutChoices</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Eagerness and the Netflix queue of the soul</title>
		<link>http://dougbeyer.wordpress.com/2011/04/24/eagerness-and-the-netflix-queue-of-the-soul/</link>
		<comments>http://dougbeyer.wordpress.com/2011/04/24/eagerness-and-the-netflix-queue-of-the-soul/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2011 17:26:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Doug</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[perfectionism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Perfectionism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Netflix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[queues]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dougbeyer.wordpress.com/?p=237</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Your Netflix queue is composed of two kinds of movies and TV shows: 1. Shows you will have delivered to you, watch, and return. 2. Shows you will have delivered to you but never watch, or shows you will never have delivered to you. Why do we queue up movies we won&#8217;t watch, or won&#8217;t even [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=237&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://dougbeyer.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/netflix.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-238" title="That Netflix red envelope" src="http://dougbeyer.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/netflix.jpg?w=277&#038;h=300" alt="" width="277" height="300" /></a>Your Netflix queue is composed of two kinds of movies and TV shows:</p>
<p>1. Shows you will have delivered to you, watch, and return.</p>
<p>2. Shows you will have delivered to you but never watch, or shows you will never have delivered to you.</p>
<p>Why do we queue up movies we won&#8217;t watch, or won&#8217;t even have delivered? Are we trying to impress someone? Are we trying to fool ourselves? Are we trying to change our own habits? Are we trying to <em>improve</em> our movie-watching? By what standard? And is it working?</p>
<p>The Netflix queue is a case study in perfectionism. It shows how we let our inner critic create guilt for us, which stops us from doing what we actually want to do in our lives. Here&#8217;s the thing: your actual movie-watching habits are <em>already</em> <em>perfect</em>. Netflix, like the entire universe, is there to let you do what you want to do. It&#8217;s a service that robotically delivers exactly what you ask for. So don&#8217;t try to impress the machine by delivering <em>Hotel Rwanda</em> to your house, if you know you&#8217;ll never be in the mood to actually watch it. Bubble up a show that interests you. Have something delivered that makes you eager to rip open that red envelope and make a batch of popcorn.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve been working on notes and ideas for a new story for a few weeks, and I&#8217;ve noticed a kind of &#8220;Netflix guilt&#8221; guiding my story. I&#8217;m writing about what I feel like it <em>should</em> be about, rather than what excites me. I fall into a pattern of making it about the Big Serious Drama of Life, and find that my mind wanders and instead of writing I go fiddle on the internet or play games on my phone. It&#8217;s because I&#8217;m letting my inner critic dictate the writing instead of joy. I&#8217;m not eager to return to my writing journal because it&#8217;s like a queue full of <em>Hotel Rwandas</em>. I need to clear those Important Dramas out of there and fill it up with action-adventures and crime thrillers &#8212; the stuff I actually like to watch. I am not impressing anybody by filling up my <em>private writing</em> with heavy and sober topics. Even more important, if I am not eager to return to that sober, pain-filled stuff, I am not writing.</p>
<p>Seriousness points are not the goal. Enjoying movie night is the goal. Getting your book written is the goal. Your tastes are already perfect.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/237/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/237/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/237/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/237/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/237/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/237/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/237/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/237/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/237/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/237/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/237/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/237/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/237/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/237/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=237&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://dougbeyer.wordpress.com/2011/04/24/eagerness-and-the-netflix-queue-of-the-soul/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/8debbebe53aecade15b0c59d75253ee6?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">omnidoug</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dougbeyer.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/netflix.jpg?w=277" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">That Netflix red envelope</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>All I need to know about exercise I learned from knitting</title>
		<link>http://fitknitchick.wordpress.com/2011/04/24/all-i-need-to-know-about-exercise-i-learned-from-knitting/</link>
		<comments>http://fitknitchick.wordpress.com/2011/04/24/all-i-need-to-know-about-exercise-i-learned-from-knitting/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2011 23:26:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>fitknitchick</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Fitness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Goals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Knitting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[knitting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exercise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[challenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[perseverance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[setbacks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[variety]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cross training]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fitknitchick.wordpress.com/?p=599</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I have two great passions in my life (besides my husband, and sometimes, my children); fitness and knitting. At first glance, they seem to be rather incompatible past times. One involves vigorous whole body movement, the other sitting on the couch, barely flicking one&#8217;s fingers for hours at a time. There are special clothes for [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=599&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I have two great passions in my life (besides my husband, and <em>sometimes</em>, my children); <strong>fitness</strong> and <strong>knitting</strong>. At first glance, they seem to be rather incompatible past times.</p>
<p>One involves vigorous whole body movement, the other sitting on the couch, barely flicking one&#8217;s fingers for hours at a time. There are special clothes for exercise. Not so much for knitting. You can knit and drink a glass of wine and watch TV simultaneously. No wine at the gym, last time I checked. Exercise is about <em>challenge</em> and <em>progress</em> and <em>setbacks</em> and <em>all out effor</em>t. And knitting? Turns out that fitness and knitting are more alike that one might think.</p>
<p>In fact, all I need to know about exercise I learned from knitting.</p>
<ol>
<li>
<div id="attachment_612" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://fitknitchick.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/img_2662.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-612" title="IMG_2662" src="http://fitknitchick.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/img_2662.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">I knit socks on 2.25 mm needles, with about 70 stitches around. The leg of a sock might have 70 rows in it; that 4900 stitches in one leg alone!</p></div>
<p><strong>Keep the goal in sight, but enjoy the process.</strong> When one spends hours making thousands of tiny stitches with small wooden sticks, thoughts of the finished object are unavoidable. But, focusing on the end of the project makes it feel more like work than an enjoyable way of spending your time. Concentrate on how the yarn feels running through your fingers. Stop to admire the evenness of your stitches. In the gym, listen to the beat of your heart. Note how it increases and decreases with your effort. Enjoy the feeling of your muscles as they work to press that weight over your head. The long-term goal is still a ways away; <em>revel in the moment</em>.</li>
<li><strong>Sometimes you have to go backwards before you can move forward.</strong> Knitters call this &#8216;TINKing&#8217; (that&#8217;s KNIT spelled backwards). It happens when you don&#8217;t read instructions (I can vouch for this one personally), or when you&#8217;re not truly paying attention to what you&#8217;re doing. Similarly, injuries happen during exercise when we try to advance ourselves too quickly or are distracted in the gym. <em>Setbacks happen and strength must be regained</em> before we can once again move forward.</li>
<li><strong>Always take detailed notes.</strong> If you want to remember what you did on the first sleeve so you can knit the second to match, take notes, lots of notes. Don&#8217;t count on yourself to remember the specifics or the details of your last workout. When you&#8217;re getting results in the gym, it&#8217;s much easier to figure out why (and keep progressing) if you know where you&#8217;re coming from.<em> Journalling is a truly effective way to measure progress.</em></li>
<li><strong>Be selfish; no one else appreciates your efforts as much as you do.</strong> I am a selfish knitter. I knit primarily for myself. I know that I will love what I&#8217;ve knit and will wear it with pride. Knits that I have gifted have not always been so obviously appreciated. <em>Exercise for you and you alone</em>. Don&#8217;t do it because someone else wants you to. Don&#8217;t do it because you think you should. Do it because you love how it makes you feel and look.</li>
<li>
<div id="attachment_610" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://fitknitchick.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/img_27991.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-610" title="IMG_2799" src="http://fitknitchick.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/img_27991.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Stranded knitting has always been difficult for me. Because I am a tight knitter, the fabric usually puckers. This sweater is for my daughter, and I&#039;m proud to say, it&#039;s my best stranded knitting yet!</p></div>
<p><strong>Don&#8217;t be afraid to try something new.</strong> For a long time I stuck to basic knitting projects. Things that I knew I could do well. If a pattern required a technique that I was unfamiliar with, I knit something else. Over the last few years, I&#8217;ve become more adventurous in  my knitting. What&#8217;s the worst that could happen? I might screw it up. I might not like it. I might have to rip it out. Or, maybe, just maybe, I might find something else that I&#8217;m really good at! There are lots of fitness options out there. Weight rooms not your thing? Try Zumba. Can&#8217;t stand running? Hop on a spin bike. The <em>options are nearly endless</em> and there are new tools and techniques to tackle almost weekly.</li>
<li>
<div id="attachment_611" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://fitknitchick.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/img_2630.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-611" title="IMG_2630" src="http://fitknitchick.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/img_2630.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">I gave up knitting this one in the evening; the lace rows were so long I would lose track of where I was and have to rip back row after row to find my mistakes.</p></div>
<p><strong>Know when tackling a challenge is a bad idea.</strong> I don&#8217;t knit complex lace at night. My attention is not focused and my eyes don&#8217;t work as well in the dark as they used to. Similarly, increasing my loads in the weight room is best left for when I&#8217;m feeling healthy and well, not when a cold is looming or I&#8217;m tired from a late night out. <em>Challenge is good, but not all the time</em>.</li>
<li><strong>Variety is a great motivator.</strong> I always have 3 or 4 projects on the needles (a simple sock in my purse, something complex for afternoons without the children). When I tire of one, I simply move on to another. Same thing with fitness. Bored with your current routine? If it&#8217;s a good one and you&#8217;ve seen results, switch it up for a week or two until you again need a change. I like to intersperse heaving weight training days with spinning days (love those cardio intervals!). Over the longer term, I might stick with a whole body training program for a month or two, then switch to body part training (one or two body parts a day) for a few weeks. <em>Rather than do nothing, do something else</em>!</li>
<li><strong>Surround yourself with like-minded people.</strong> Before I found <a href="http://www.ravelry.com" target="_blank">Ravelry</a> (an awesome online community of fiber artists; think Facebook for knitters), I had very few people to share my knitting obsession with. Now, I check in with my on-line knitting buddies daily for a dose of inspiration and support. I&#8217;ve learned a ton from these women and am continually motivated to try new techniques and patterns. Seek out friends and acquaintances who are as committed to exercise as you are. <em>Motivate each other</em> to do more and better.</li>
<li>
<div id="attachment_614" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://fitknitchick.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/knitting-needles.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-614" title="knitting needles" src="http://fitknitchick.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/knitting-needles.jpg?w=300&#038;h=283" alt="" width="300" height="283" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">I have a vase of needles like this on my mantle; I grabbed this image from the web.</p></div>
<p><strong>Always choose the right tool for the job.</strong> The knitter&#8217;s primary tool is a needle. But needles come in many different styles (single point, double point, circular, cable), sizes (from 1 mm all the way up to 20 mm and beyond) and weights (stainless steel, wood, laminate, bamboo). Different projects (and yarns) require different needles. If you use the wrong needle for the job, you&#8217;re bound to be unhappy with the final result. Same things goes with exercise. You need to <em>match the tool to your goals</em>. Want to put on muscle and gain strength? Forego the fixed machines and light weights. Pick up a kettlebell, some dumbbells, a barbell. Approach the squat machine with confidence. Get face to face with the chin up bar.</li>
<li><strong>Make time for it every day!</strong> In order to get better at something and actually see the results of your labors, you need to do it frequently. I&#8217;ve been to the gym and knit half a sleeve today&#8230; and it&#8217;s not even dinner time yet!</li>
</ol>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/599/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/599/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/599/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/599/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/599/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/599/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/599/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/599/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/599/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/599/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/599/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/599/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/599/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/599/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=599&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://fitknitchick.wordpress.com/2011/04/24/all-i-need-to-know-about-exercise-i-learned-from-knitting/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/38ef15ea53790bd8ba39d670a959a1b5?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">fitknitchick</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://fitknitchick.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/img_2662.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_2662</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://fitknitchick.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/img_27991.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_2799</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://fitknitchick.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/img_2630.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_2630</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://fitknitchick.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/knitting-needles.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">knitting needles</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ireland</title>
		<link>http://rotaryscholar2010.wordpress.com/2011/04/20/ireland/</link>
		<comments>http://rotaryscholar2010.wordpress.com/2011/04/20/ireland/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2011 13:06:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>rotaryscholar2010</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://rotaryscholar2010.wordpress.com/?p=652</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[For our last trip within Europe, Paul and I decided to visit Ireland and Scotland. We both have ancestors in these countries so thought it would be a neat to see where they had come from, even if we didn&#8217;t have enough time on this visit to track any long-lost cousins. Upon arriving in Dublin [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=652&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0124.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-664 aligncenter" title="KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA" src="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0124.jpg?w=500&#038;h=375" alt="" width="500" height="375" /></a></p>
<p>For our last trip within Europe, Paul and I decided to visit Ireland and Scotland. We both have ancestors in these countries so thought it would be a neat to see where they had come from, even if we didn&#8217;t have enough time on this visit to track any long-lost cousins.</p>
<p>Upon arriving in Dublin we decided to be real touristy and visit Ireland&#8217;s #1 attraction- the Guinness Factory. It was a very cool tour, although you don&#8217;t actually get to see the brewing process. I was amazed by the archival footage of the cooper (barrel maker) at work! I was equally amazed to realize they have been using the same yeast strain for the past 250 years. The building itself was a renovated factory that has won awards for its innovative interior. To &#8216;literally&#8217; top off our tour we headed up to the 7th floor gravity bar to enjoy a pint of Guinness while overlooking the city of Dublin.</p>
<div id="attachment_653" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0010.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-653" title="KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA" src="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0010.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Guinness Factory</p></div>
<div id="attachment_654" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0014.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-654" title="KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA" src="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0014.jpg?w=300&#038;h=233" alt="" width="300" height="233" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Enjoying a pint of Guinness high above Dublin</p></div>
<p>After our pint we headed into the historical district of Dublin to explore. We visited O&#8217;Connell Street, the Temple Bar district, Christchurch Cathedral, St Patrick&#8217;s Cathedral, Dublin Castle and Trinity College. We also strolled along the River Liffy and I went shopping in the main shopping district. I really liked Christchurch Cathedral with its medieval gothic architecture and quirky little bridge over the road. The building has the largest crypt in Ireland or the UK where they have many treasures on display, including the famous mummified cat and rat who were found after being trapped in an organ pipe for an unknown (long) time.  Later on in the visit we enjoyed live celtic music in a pub and the Jeannie Johnston famine ship. Amazingly, despite transporting over 2500 people to Canada during the Irish Famine no lives were lost on the Jeanie Johnston. This is incredible considering the tragic loss of life typical of the dangerous sea voyage from Ireland to the New World.  We also visited the Trinity College library, where the Book of Kells and an exhibit on the history of medicine were on display.</p>
<div id="attachment_655" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0027.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-655" title="KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA" src="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0027.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Christchurch Cathedral</p></div>
<p><a href="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0043.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-656" title="KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA" src="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0043.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a></p>
<div id="attachment_657" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0051.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-657" title="KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA" src="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0051.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">St Patricks Cathedral</p></div>
<div id="attachment_687" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0245.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-687" title="KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA" src="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0245.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The Jeanie Johnston- famine boat</p></div>
<div id="attachment_688" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0249.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-688" title="KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA" src="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0249.jpg?w=500&#038;h=375" alt="" width="500" height="375" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Irish Famine Memorial, presented to Dublin by Canada in 1997. Very Moving.</p></div>
<p>The next day we hopped on a train for Ireland&#8217;s West coast. Upon arriving in Galway city we joined up with our tour group and set off. The first stop was at the Ailwee caves and the Burren Birds of Prey Conservation Centre. We got to visit the large birds of prey, but weren&#8217;t able to have  a &#8216;fly by&#8217; because it was too rainy. The cave is the most famous of the thousands of caves that exist in the soluble rock of the karst landscape. They were show caves, so no squeezing or rappelling like we had done in Canada. There was a beautiful waterfall, ancient stalactites/ stalagmites,  a formation that looked like &#8216;praying hands&#8217; and even the remains of an extinct species of bear.</p>
<div id="attachment_658" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 235px"><a href="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0081.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-658" title="KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA" src="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0081.jpg?w=225&#038;h=300" alt="" width="225" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Waterfall in Ailwee Cave</p></div>
<p>After navigating many windy roads through territory characterized by abundant stone walls, we arrived at the Cliffs of Moher. The cliffs are roughly 650&#8242; high and are stunningly beautiful. We were incredibly lucky to arrive during a break in the coastal fog- the cliffs were shrouded in mist by the time we left. Amazing!</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0108.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-661" title="KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA" src="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0108.jpg?w=240&#038;h=320" alt="" width="240" height="320" /></a></p>
<div id="attachment_659" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0087.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-659" title="KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA" src="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0087.jpg?w=500&#038;h=375" alt="" width="500" height="375" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The Cliffs of Moher peeking out of the fog</p></div>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0098.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-660" title="KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA" src="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0098.jpg?w=240&#038;h=320" alt="" width="240" height="320" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">After a pub lunch in a small village we visited the megalithic Poulnabrone Dolmen (hole of sorrows) passage tomb. Rising against the stark Burren landscape, the 5000-6000 year old tomb is a reminder of the ingenuity of our ancient ancestors. The huge rocks marked the grave of between 16- 22 adults and 6 children. It is hard not to feel awed by the massive 6&#8242; by 9&#8242; monument erected so long ago- then you realize there are over 90 other monuments dotting the Burren. The Burren is a karst-landscape of scarred limestone with an inredible mixture of arctic, mediterranean and alpine plants and rare animals and insects clinging to life in the unique environment.  .</p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><a href="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0122.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-662 aligncenter" title="KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA" src="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0122.jpg?w=225&#038;h=300" alt="" width="225" height="300" /></a></p>
<div id="attachment_663" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0110.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-663" title="KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA" src="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0110.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Typical stone fences of West Ireland</p></div>
<p>The following day we visited Northern Ireland. I was a little apprehensive about the trip due to the recent murder of a young police officer by IRA terrorists. Despite this, the atmosphere was incredibly encouraging. People are standing together despite their differences to demand an end to the violence. I was encouraged to see how far the peace process had come- what a difference from the troubles of only a few years ago!</p>
<p>We started the day by driving along the only truly coastal highway of the UK and were treated to a beautiful view of Rathlin island and the outer Hebrides islands of Scotland. The first stop was at the carrick-a-rede (rock in the road) rope bridge. The 20m gap to the tiny island has been bridged for hundreds of years by salmon fishermen. Today the salmon are too scarce and the only use of the bridge is by visitors.</p>
<div id="attachment_672" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><img class="size-medium wp-image-672 " title="KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA" src="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0162.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" alt="" width="300" height="225" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Costal cliffs</p></div>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0172.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-671 aligncenter" title="KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA" src="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0172.jpg?w=400&#038;h=533" alt="" width="400" height="533" /></a></p>
<div id="attachment_670" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0166.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-670 " title="KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA" src="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0166.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Doing my Indiana Jones impression</p></div>
<p>The highlight of the day was visiting Giant&#8217;s Causeway. It is a unique geological formation consisting of thousands of hexagonal columns of rock. This formation can only be found at the Giant&#8217;s Cause way in Ireland and a tiny bit on the coast of a Scottish island across the water.  It formed as molten lava was forced to the surface at high speeds and rapidly cooled upon contact with sea water.</p>
<p>In Irish legend, it is said that the Giant Finn MacCool built the causeway in order to go to Scotland to challenge his rival, the giant Brenandoner. Upon seeing Brenandoner&#8217;s size, Finn raced back to Ireland&#8230; but it was too late. Brenandoner chased Finn back and it up to Finn&#8217;s quick thinking wife to save the day. She disguised her husband as a baby and invited Brenandoner in to see the &#8216;wee lad&#8217;. Brenandoner was shocked at the size of the infant; thinking &#8216;how big must his father be&#8217;! After making his excuses, Brenandoner fled back to Scotland, tearing up the causeway behind him.</p>
<div id="attachment_673" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 235px"><a href="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0173.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-673 " title="KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA" src="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0173.jpg?w=225&#038;h=300" alt="" width="225" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">A mountain of columns</p></div>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0176.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-674" title="KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA" src="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0176.jpg?w=500&#038;h=375" alt="" width="500" height="375" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0190.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-675" title="KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA" src="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0190.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a></p>
<div id="attachment_676" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0200.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-676 " title="KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA" src="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0200.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">White cliffs</p></div>
<div id="attachment_677" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0197.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-677" title="KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA" src="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0197.jpg?w=300&#038;h=199" alt="" width="300" height="199" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Castle ruins on the cliff</p></div>
<p style="text-align:left;">Our last stop of the day was in central Belfast. I felt totally safe while in the downtown area despite visiting the &#8216;most bombed hotel in Europe&#8217; which suffered nearly 40 blasts during the troubles. We also visited the Crown Liquor Saloon, a splendid pub with authentic decor dating from 1885. The interior features are marvellous; cosy snugs (private booths with little doors, thanks to Victorian modesty), stained glass, marble and antique woodwork. Legend has it that the owner&#8217;s were of a &#8216;mixed marriage&#8217;- one Catholic and one Protestant. The husband wanted to display the crown, but his wife would have none of it. They eventually came to a compromise- the crown is on the floor outside the door. It is on display, but is trampled on by every patron as the enter the pub. Paul and I then walked to the City Hall where there was an exhibition about the Titanic, which had been built in Belfast.</p>
<div id="attachment_678" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0203.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-678" title="KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA" src="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0203.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The most bombed hotel in Europe</p></div>
<div id="attachment_679" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 235px"><a href="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0204.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-679" title="KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA" src="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0204.jpg?w=225&#038;h=300" alt="" width="225" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The Crown</p></div>
<div id="attachment_681" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 235px"><a href="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict02101.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-681" title="KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA" src="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict02101.jpg?w=225&#038;h=300" alt="" width="225" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Belfast City Hall</p></div>
<p style="text-align:left;"> On the way out of Belfast we stopped to observe some murals painted by dissidents. I took some pictures but after a fair bit of thought have decided not to post them as I am philosophically opposed to their methods. I found it extremely disconcerting and made me really appreciate living in a country free of violent sectarian conflict. This stuff is still out there inciting hatred despite the progress made towards peace.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><a href="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0243.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-683" title="KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA" src="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0243.jpg?w=500&#038;h=375" alt="" width="500" height="375" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">The following day was one of the highlights of my entire year. I am really interested in ancient human history and had wanted to visit Newgrange for years. Newgrange is one of the most significant neolithic structures in Europe, possibly in the entire world.  It is older than the pyramids by at least 500 years and is approximately 1000 years older Stonehenge. The structure is 250&#8242; accross and 40&#8242; high with building materials from over 70 kilometres away. The stone carvings are beautiful and incredibly intricate. If only we knew their significance!</p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><a href="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0230.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-684" title="KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA" src="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0230.jpg?w=500&#038;h=666" alt="" width="500" height="666" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Newgrange was a multipurpose monument. Inside the central, cross shaped chamber are three enormous bowls. These were used to cremate the deceased, some of whom were then buried in the temple. The smallest basin is a bit of a puzzle- it is thought to have been either used in cremation of children or as a bowl in childbirth. Looking up in the central chamber, one sees an incredible corbelled roof made of overlapping boulders that come to a peak under a massive capstone. One of the most impressive things I learnt during the visit- in over 5000 years, the roof has never leaked!! This was achieved with stone age technology! How many modern buildings can claim to be that watertight?</p>
<div id="attachment_685" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0239.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-685 " title="KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA" src="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0239.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The rocks align with the precise spot where the sun rises on the winter solstice</p></div>
<p style="text-align:left;">Another incredible aspect of Newgrange is that it is perfectly lined up with the winter solstice. Every year on the 21st of December, daylight penetrates the inner chamber for only 17 minutes before it is released back into darkness for another year. Newgrange is only one of many passage tombs along the fertile Boine River Valley. Nearby, the even more massive and richly decorated Knowth was built to align with the equinoxes and Dowth also aligns with the Winter Solstice. This suggests a religious meaning, or at the very least shows us how very important the changing seasons were to the agricultural stone age people.</p>
<div id="attachment_686" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0236.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-686" title="KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA" src="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0236.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">White quarts and black eggs cover the facade of Newgrange</p></div>
<div id="attachment_690" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0227.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-690" title="KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA" src="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0227.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">View of Knowth from across the Boine Valley</p></div>
<p style="text-align:left;">We actually visited the Hill of Tara before going to Newgrange, but I was so excited about Newgrange I wanted to cover it first. The Hill of Tara is the ancient seat of the Irish Kings. It is said that 3/4 of Ireland can be seen from Tara on a clear day, and I certainly believe it! Sadly little remains of the ancient seat of the kings except a small passage tomb and an ancient coronation stone called the Lia Fail (Stone of Destiny).   Much of the area surrounding Tara, and indeed much of Ireland, was land belonging to monasteries. During Europe&#8217;s dark ages, Ireland was experiencing it&#8217;s golden age and was known as the &#8216;Island of Saints and Scholars&#8217;.</p>
<div id="attachment_689" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0219.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-689" title="KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA" src="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0219.jpg?w=500&#038;h=375" alt="" width="500" height="375" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">View from the Hill of Tara with medieval monastery</p></div>
<p>This is the end of &#8216;part one&#8217; of my trip to Ireland and Scotland. I must now return to working on my term essays for medical anthropology. I hope to post pictures and stories from our time in Scotland over the weekend.</p>
<p>Only 8 days till Kenya!</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/652/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/652/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/652/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/652/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/652/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/652/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/652/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/652/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/652/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/652/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/652/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/652/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/652/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/652/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=652&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://rotaryscholar2010.wordpress.com/2011/04/20/ireland/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c8d7f12a79e58a4091bc714636316cb9?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">rotaryscholar2010</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0124.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0010.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0014.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0027.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0043.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0051.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0245.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0249.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0081.jpg?w=225" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0108.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0087.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0098.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0122.jpg?w=225" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0110.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0162.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0172.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0166.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0173.jpg?w=225" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0176.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0190.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0200.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0197.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0203.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0204.jpg?w=225" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict02101.jpg?w=225" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0243.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0230.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0239.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0236.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0227.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://rotaryscholar2010.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/pict0219.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">KONICA MINOLTA DIGITAL CAMERA</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Kate Middleton and Prince William’s wedding details: from the dress to the guest list</title>
		<link>http://thefashioncaucus.wordpress.com/2011/04/24/456/</link>
		<comments>http://thefashioncaucus.wordpress.com/2011/04/24/456/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2011 17:49:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>thefashioncaucus</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Kate Middleton]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Royal Wedding]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thefashioncaucus.wordpress.com/?p=456</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[From the dress to the guest list, we’ve got it all! Wedding Gown – Who designed the dress? Details regarding Kate Middleton’s wedding gown have been kept a secret, as she has vowed not to reveal any details until she is seen at the ceremony. However, London’s Daily Mail reported some details of the design [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=456&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>From the dress to the guest list, we’ve got it all!</p>
<p><strong>Wedding Gown</strong> – Who designed the dress?</p>
<div id="attachment_457" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 238px"><a href="http://thefashioncaucus.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/engagement.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-457" title="Prince William and Kate Middleton" src="http://thefashioncaucus.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/engagement.jpg?w=228&#038;h=300" alt="" width="228" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Prince William &amp; Kate (Engagement Portrait by Mario Testino)</p></div>
<p>Details regarding Kate Middleton’s wedding gown have been kept a secret, as she has vowed not to reveal any details until she is seen at the ceremony. However, London’s <a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/femail/article-1377849/Royal-Wedding-Kate-Middleton-designs-dress.html" target="_blank"><em>Daily Mail</em></a> reported some details of the design early Monday morning.</p>
<p>The fashion savvy Kate Middleton will wear a dress which she designed herself!</p>
<p>The design is rumored to be reminiscent of the Renaissance period, taking inspiration from Middleton’s History of Art degree.</p>
<p>It has been reported that the bride has designed an ivory gown with satin and lace detail, a pearl button back and 10-foot train. The dress will also include what is described as a “nod” to the Emanuel wedding gown worn by Princess Diana.</p>
<p>34-year-old designer Sophie Cranston, of the low-key label Libelula, was tipped as the creator of Middleton’s dream design.</p>
<p><strong>Guest List</strong> – What celebrities will be there?</p>
<p>The royal family has just released the invite list with some expected, and some rather surprising, names. President Obama and First Lady Michelle did not make the cut of 1,900 lucky guests. Of the 1,900 guests, only 600 have been invited to the lunchtime reception at Buckingham Palace given by Queen Elizabeth. Furthermore, only 300 have been invited to the dinner at Buckingham Palace given by Prince Charles.</p>
<p>The list totals 1,000 friends and family members, 52 members of the royal family, 46 members of foreign royal families and 80 guests from Prince William&#8217;s charities.</p>
<p>Guests include:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Sir Elton John</strong>: A favorite of the royal family and memorable performer of “Candle in the Wind” at the funeral of Princess Diana.</li>
<li><strong>David and Victoria Beckham</strong>: As president of the U.K.&#8217;s Football Association, Prince William has become close friends with the Beckhams. Additionally, Victoria Beckham, the former Posh Spice, is one of Kate Middleton’s favorite designers.</li>
<li><strong>Rowan “Mr. Bean” Atkinson:</strong> The actor is a close friend of Prince Charles. Perhaps if things start dragging at the ceremony, Mr. Bean can lighten the mood.</li>
<li><strong>Guy Ritchie:</strong> The film maker and former spouse of Madonna is a friend of Prince William and Kate.</li>
<li><strong>Joss Stone:</strong> This soul-singer is a longtime friend of William and Harry, and even performed at the 2007 Concert for Diana and 2008 City Salute.</li>
</ul>
<p>It is also rumored that Kanye West has received an invitation.</p>
<p>The royal wedding will take place April 29 at Westminster Abbey.</p>
<p>Check back for more royal wedding updates!</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/456/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/456/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/456/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/456/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/456/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/456/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/456/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/456/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/456/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/456/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/456/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/456/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/456/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/456/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=456&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thefashioncaucus.wordpress.com/2011/04/24/456/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/b5b874a14c86d4595e9618791113e3ee?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">thefashioncaucus</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thefashioncaucus.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/engagement.jpg?w=228" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Prince William and Kate Middleton</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Let Me Translate That For You</title>
		<link>http://mompocalypse.wordpress.com/2011/04/22/let-me-translate-that-for-you/</link>
		<comments>http://mompocalypse.wordpress.com/2011/04/22/let-me-translate-that-for-you/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2011 12:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Tina</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Funny Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quotes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[translation]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mompocalypse.wordpress.com/?p=96</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There are a lot of little scripts people use when talking to the Procreation Nation. It starts with the ever-dangerous, &#8220;When are you due?&#8221; and ends with &#8220;How does it feel to have an empty nest?&#8221; They are mostly just polite fillers for strangers who are too tactful to tell you there is baby vomit [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=96&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There are a lot of little scripts people use when talking to the Procreation Nation. It starts with the ever-dangerous, &#8220;When are you due?&#8221; and ends with &#8220;How does it feel to have an empty nest?&#8221; They are mostly just polite fillers for strangers who are too tactful to tell you there is baby vomit in your hair. But, I have realized there is subtext to a lot of these phrases and I feel it is my job to translate some of them and save someone from getting punched the next time they tell a mother that she &#8220;has her hands full.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;When are you due?&#8221; = &#8220;FATTIE.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;You have your hands full!&#8221; = &#8220;Your kids are the most unruly bunch of demons to curse this earth. A pox upon ye for bringing them to Walmart!&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;You&#8217;re doing a great job with them.&#8221; = If the children are acting a fool and screaming like howler monkies, this one means, &#8220;I am afraid you are going to drive your mini-van off a bridge. Can I talk you down?&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;You had another one after the twins? You&#8217;re brave!&#8221; = &#8220;HOLY MOTHER OF PEARL. WHY DO YOU KEEP REPRODUCING. CONDOMS! STAT!&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Are they really twins?&#8221; = &#8220;The one on the left looks more like a midget in a sailor suit. I am not sure I trust him.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;They grow up so fast!&#8221; = &#8220;Except for during that period between 2 year and entering pre-kindergarten. That will stretch on so long you&#8217;ll think you&#8217;ve broken the space-time continuum.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;She looks like she has mischief in her eyes!&#8221; = &#8220;I need to see a priest. I think your daughter just ate my soul when I pinched her cheek.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Do you breastfeed?&#8221; = &#8220;I don&#8217;t care if you do, I just want to judge you.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Do you co-sleep?&#8221; = &#8220;I love judging moms!&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Do you spank?&#8221; = &#8220;I have Child Protective Services on speed dial.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Do you cloth diaper?&#8221; = &#8220;JUDGEY MC JUDGE-ERSON.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Are you having any more?&#8221; = &#8220;I really love schadenfreude.&#8221;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/96/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/96/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/96/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/96/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/96/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/96/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/96/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/96/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/96/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/96/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/96/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/96/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/96/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/96/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=96&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://mompocalypse.wordpress.com/2011/04/22/let-me-translate-that-for-you/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/bc4ccdd3e0598d89af1428a97e0d1417?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mompocalypse</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Two Months Off &#8212; Another Perspective</title>
		<link>http://ocularity.wordpress.com/2011/04/25/two-months-off-another-perspective/</link>
		<comments>http://ocularity.wordpress.com/2011/04/25/two-months-off-another-perspective/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 09:21:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>jmschroeder11</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Pontification]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[experience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unemployment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[employee]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[job search]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recruiter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[job boards]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[job listings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[networking]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ocularity.wordpress.com/?p=70</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I wrote a post two weeks after I had left my last job.  With two months now past, I would like to share what more I have learned, and which of the same lessons have been reinforced. 1.  Never neglect your professional network. I started with this one last time and will start with it here [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=70&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I wrote a post two weeks after I had left my last job.  With two months now past, I would like to share what more I have learned, and which of the same lessons have been reinforced.</p>
<p><strong>1.  Never neglect your professional network.</strong> I started with this one last time and will start with it here again.  Especially at an executive or &#8220;C-level,&#8221; your next position is far more likely to originate in your extended network.  Don&#8217;t let <span style="text-decoration:underline;">anyone</span> go more than a year without hearing from you, and not with a &#8220;humorous&#8221; forwarded email.  No matter how comfortable you are in your current role, <span style="text-decoration:underline;">now</span> is the time to start reinvigorating your network.  And if you are currently seeking a job, extend your network by asking your current contacts who else you should talk to, what groups you should be joining and what periodicals (web or otherwise) you should be reading.   In-person contact is best of all:  Having coffee or lunch with an acquaintance can yield surprisingly helpful leads and connections.</p>
<p><strong>2.  Take care not to call upon your most valuable networking resources too soon in your search. </strong>Unless you are a job-hopper, it is likely that your job-search skills will be a bit rusty when you begin your search.  Although it is tempting to contact first the people whom you know to be best &#8220;connected&#8221; or otherwise most able to assist you, start first with your friends.  Practice your &#8220;pitch,&#8221; in both email and voicemail forms, with people who know you and who will give you helpful feedback.  Brainstorm with them to help you refine your goals, your career summary, your descriptions of your skill set and strengths.  Although many in your network will be happy to help, there is a fatigue factor that sets in after an initial round or two of contact with your contacts, after which many people&#8217;s enthusiasm for assisting you will wane, so you want to save your most valuable contacts for the time when you are clear in your goals and your approach is polished.</p>
<p><strong>3.  Having multiple, targeted versions of your resume is critical if you are applying for different types of positions, or positions in different industries. </strong>Ideally, you should carefully review and revise your resume for each position for which you submit it, focusing on the job requirements and other information about the position.  Remember that the eye is drawn to the first few words of each item, so make them count.  And for functional resumes, order is extremely important &#8212; the reader will likely focus only on the first bullet point or two, in the first couple of functional areas.</p>
<p><strong>4.  Recruiters and some employers don’t want to talk to you if you are not currently employed.</strong> The extent of this irrational, indefensible mindset continues to astound me, especially among the recruiter industry.  When I was in a position to influence hiring (which was often in my last position), it never even occurred to me to discriminate against the currently unemployed.  People leave jobs for all sorts of reasons, most of which are not relevant to performance in the next position.</p>
<p><strong>5.  Don&#8217;t spend all day browsing job listings.</strong> Unless you have skills that are widely in demand, by the time a job is posted to job sites, yours will likely be one of hundreds or even thousands of resumes sent in response.  It may seem that there is &#8220;no harm in trying&#8221; by sending your resume.  However, you could be using your time in a more valuable way:  get some exercise, spend time with loved ones, or read a book about leadership or a biography of an historical person you admire.  For those few positions you find on job boards that seem too compelling, to pass up, try to reach out into your network to find someone on the inside of the employer, in order to obtain insights into (or even a direct referral to) the hiring decision-maker(s).  LinkedIn.com has some excellent resources for this task.</p>
<p><strong>6.  Be patient, but not inattentive.</strong>  Great jobs are out there, but require diligence and patience both.  Remember the reasons you left your last job.  Do not rush into a position that may have some of the same issues.</p>
<p>More to come&#8230;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/70/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/70/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/70/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/70/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/70/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/70/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/70/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/70/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/70/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/70/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/70/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/70/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/70/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/70/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=70&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://ocularity.wordpress.com/2011/04/25/two-months-off-another-perspective/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/2d1cc2936974ce823fa79837b25e75db?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jmschroeder11</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Peeps: Can They Be Trusted?</title>
		<link>http://nicoleanddime.com/2011/04/24/peeps-can-they-be-trusted/</link>
		<comments>http://nicoleanddime.com/2011/04/24/peeps-can-they-be-trusted/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2011 23:59:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Nicole</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Health & Fitness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Easter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food and Related Products]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Peeps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Processing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stale Peeps]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sugar]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nicoleanddime.com/?p=167</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Happy Easter! I just want to throw some food for thought out there. Why is it that Peeps taste WAY better stale than they do fresh out of the box? The texture and consistency are better, they don&#8217;t seem so sickeningly sweet&#8211;literally everything about them improves when they&#8217;re stale. That&#8217;s just not right. Food is [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=167&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Happy Easter! I just want to throw some food for thought out there. Why is it that Peeps taste WAY better stale than they do fresh out of the box? The texture and consistency are better, they don&#8217;t seem so sickeningly sweet&#8211;literally everything about them improves when they&#8217;re stale.</p>
<p><a href="http://nicoleanddime.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/just-born-marshmallow-peeps.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-169" title="JUST-BORN-MARSHMALLOW-PEEPS" src="http://nicoleanddime.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/just-born-marshmallow-peeps.jpg?w=400&#038;h=300" alt="" width="400" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>That&#8217;s just not right. Food is supposed to taste worse as it gets stale&#8211;it&#8217;s a biological defense mechanism that our taste buds and other senses are repulsed by staleness because it&#8217;s a sign that food is going bad and no longer edible. It&#8217;s like that experiment done a few years ago where a Happy Meal from McDonald&#8217;s left on the table for 6 months didn&#8217;t rot or show any signs of change. Is all this junk even technically &#8220;food&#8221;?</p>
<p><a href="http://nicoleanddime.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/peeps.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-168" title="peeps" src="http://nicoleanddime.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/peeps.jpg?w=400&#038;h=300" alt="" width="400" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>Bottom line, I think it&#8217;s a good thing that Peeps are only around once a year, as no one should make a habit out of eating anything that is essentially sugar coated in sugar and tastes better &#8220;stale&#8221; than &#8220;fresh.&#8221; But, that being said, there&#8217;s nothing wrong with enjoying them on Easter. I sure as hell do. In fact, I suggest setting some aside, letting them get nice and stale, and then having some Peeps s&#8217;mores at your first campfire of the summer.</p>
<p><a href="http://nicoleanddime.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/peeps-smores-1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-171" title="peeps-smores-1" src="http://nicoleanddime.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/peeps-smores-1.jpg?w=600&#038;h=899" alt="" width="600" height="899" /></a></p>
<p><em>Photo Sources: </em><a href="http://coffeeshopjournal.com/2010/04/02/easter-peeps/">Coffee Shop Journal</a>, <a href="http://www.junkfoodnews.net/marshmallow-peeps.htm">Junk Food News</a>, and <a href="http://steamykitchen.com/14980-easterpeeps-smores.html">Steamy Kitchen</a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/167/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/167/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/167/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/167/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/167/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/167/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/167/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/167/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/167/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/167/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/167/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/167/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/167/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/167/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=167&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://nicoleanddime.com/2011/04/24/peeps-can-they-be-trusted/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/d0843bf37a2fb646c3bcfacb35b95ff4?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">nicoleallday</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nicoleanddime.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/just-born-marshmallow-peeps.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">JUST-BORN-MARSHMALLOW-PEEPS</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nicoleanddime.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/peeps.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">peeps</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nicoleanddime.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/peeps-smores-1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">peeps-smores-1</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A bit of random Cape Town</title>
		<link>http://kerrymurrayphotography.wordpress.com/2011/02/03/a-bit-of-random-cape-town/</link>
		<comments>http://kerrymurrayphotography.wordpress.com/2011/02/03/a-bit-of-random-cape-town/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2011 16:45:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Kerry</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Documentary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Places]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[city]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[documentary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Landscape]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[South Africa]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://kerrymurrayphotography.wordpress.com/?p=1151</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#160; Albert Rd, Woodstock &#8211; 2011 Long Street, Cape Town &#8211; 2011 Full moon rise seen from Signal Hill &#8211; 2010 Tagged: Africa, city, documentary, Landscape, photography, South Africa, Travel<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=1151&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:justify;">&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align:right;">Albert Rd, Woodstock &#8211; 2011<a href="http://kerrymurrayphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/dsc_1063-copy.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1152" title="DSC_1063 copy" src="http://kerrymurrayphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/dsc_1063-copy.jpg?w=640&#038;h=425" alt="" width="640" height="425" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:right;">Long Street, Cape Town &#8211; 2011<a href="http://kerrymurrayphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/palmtree-mosque-copy.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1154" title="palmtree mosque copy" src="http://kerrymurrayphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/palmtree-mosque-copy.jpg?w=640&#038;h=425" alt="" width="640" height="425" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:right;">Full moon rise seen from Signal Hill &#8211; 2010<a href="http://kerrymurrayphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/lions-head-copy.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1153" title="lions head copy" src="http://kerrymurrayphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/lions-head-copy.jpg?w=640&#038;h=425" alt="" width="640" height="425" /></a></p>
<br /> Tagged: <a href='http://kerrymurrayphotography.wordpress.com/tag/africa/'>Africa</a>, <a href='http://kerrymurrayphotography.wordpress.com/tag/city/'>city</a>, <a href='http://kerrymurrayphotography.wordpress.com/tag/documentary-2/'>documentary</a>, <a href='http://kerrymurrayphotography.wordpress.com/tag/landscape/'>Landscape</a>, <a href='http://kerrymurrayphotography.wordpress.com/tag/photography/'>photography</a>, <a href='http://kerrymurrayphotography.wordpress.com/tag/south-africa/'>South Africa</a>, <a href='http://kerrymurrayphotography.wordpress.com/tag/travel/'>Travel</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1151/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1151/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1151/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1151/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1151/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1151/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1151/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1151/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1151/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1151/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1151/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1151/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1151/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1151/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=1151&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://kerrymurrayphotography.wordpress.com/2011/02/03/a-bit-of-random-cape-town/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/da305ea3934c302f719a43b36271040a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">kerrymurrayphotography</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://kerrymurrayphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/dsc_1063-copy.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_1063 copy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://kerrymurrayphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/palmtree-mosque-copy.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">palmtree mosque copy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://kerrymurrayphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/lions-head-copy.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lions head copy</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>PHOTO: It&#8217;s That Time of Year Again&#8230;</title>
		<link>http://365faceoff.wordpress.com/2011/04/23/photo-its-that-time-of-year-again/</link>
		<comments>http://365faceoff.wordpress.com/2011/04/23/photo-its-that-time-of-year-again/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2011 18:24:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>365faceoff</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://365faceoff.wordpress.com/?p=1187</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The time of year when sleep ceases to exist in favor of the three 10 page papers and presentations you have due next week.  I think the concept of  &#8221;dead week&#8221; might have existed at one point or another, but nowadays the weeks before finals accelerate into a full-on sprint.  I have left: three papers, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=1187&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://365faceoff.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/april23.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1188" title="april23" src="http://365faceoff.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/april23.jpg?w=490&#038;h=326" alt="" width="490" height="326" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;">The time of year when sleep ceases to exist in favor of the three 10 page papers and presentations you have due next week.  I think the concept of  &#8221;dead week&#8221; might have existed at one point or another, but nowadays the weeks before finals accelerate into a full-on sprint.  I have left: three papers, a 20 minute speech, one book to read, two massive final creative projects, one final exam, and one take-home final essay.  Could be much worse, though!</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">Anyway, here is the artist hard at work.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1187/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1187/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1187/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1187/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1187/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1187/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1187/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1187/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1187/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1187/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1187/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1187/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1187/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1187/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=1187&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://365faceoff.wordpress.com/2011/04/23/photo-its-that-time-of-year-again/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/a5c1e40d745ffbf9ee8e53f89b5c70ab?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">365faceoff</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://365faceoff.files.wordpress.com/2011/04/april23.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">april23</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>