<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 20:38:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Dad, Smiling</title>
		<link>http://applehillcottage.org/2013/03/08/54-dad-smiling/</link>
		<comments>http://applehillcottage.org/2013/03/08/54-dad-smiling/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 06:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Apple Hill Cottage</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Fathers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thankfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Time]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dads]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DP challenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[memories]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://applehillcottage.org/?p=3092</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[March 10, 2012. one year ago, Dad, Granddad, Pops, Sam died at the long old age of 90. there are bad memories of that time between when his body no longer worked and when his journey here ended. they are fading with time. and today i&#8217;m choosing to remember him smiling. His plane wrecked in training. [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3092&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://applehillcottage.org/2013/03/08/54-dad-smiling/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/2822f550d60f79ff141ee2ee811440ed?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">applehillcottage</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://applehillcottage.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/012.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Dad in his plane</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://applehillcottage.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/016.jpg?w=750" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Dad rowing</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://applehillcottage.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/020.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Dad and Mom on New Year&#039;s Eve</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://applehillcottage.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/096.jpg?w=522" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Dad and his new golf club</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://applehillcottage.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/086.jpg?w=495" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Dad at Christmas</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://applehillcottage.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/085.jpg?w=539" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Dad getting his hair done</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://applehillcottage.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/dadnancewedding.jpg?w=538" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://applehillcottage.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/092.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Dad and Ron</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://applehillcottage.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/080.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Dad, Aunt Ruth, and Uncle B</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://applehillcottage.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/1281.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Carol and dad</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://applehillcottage.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/158.jpg?w=750" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Dad&#039;s 89th</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://applehillcottage.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/img_1724.jpg?w=750" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Dad surrounded </media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://applehillcottage.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/160.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Dad smiling</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>No More Lies</title>
		<link>http://tworedtornados.wordpress.com/2013/03/06/no-more-lies-weekly-writing-challenge-truth-is-stranger-than-fiction/</link>
		<comments>http://tworedtornados.wordpress.com/2013/03/06/no-more-lies-weekly-writing-challenge-truth-is-stranger-than-fiction/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2013 00:50:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tworedtornados</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[People]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thoughts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ukraine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Unfinished Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adventure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[change]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPchallenge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[English]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eye]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[found]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[friends]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[friendship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kiev]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kyiv]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life lessons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lost]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[people]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[perspective]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[red]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[solo travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tornado]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tornados]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[truth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[two]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ukrainian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vacation]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tworedtornados.wordpress.com/?p=743</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I remember this day. I was sicker than a dog, some Ukrainian sinus infection that I refused to succumb to. I should have stayed in bed, but I wouldn&#8217;t. I continued to act healthy until I just couldn&#8217;t fake it anymore. Fever. Cough. Sinus pressure. I felt terrible. I was miserable. But this was the [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=743&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:left;"><a href="http://tworedtornados.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/wpid-imag0661_burst002.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-358 aligncenter" alt="wpid-IMAG0661_BURST002.jpg" src="http://tworedtornados.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/wpid-imag0661_burst002.jpg?w=300&#038;h=169" width="300" height="169" /></a>I remember this day. I was sicker than a dog, some Ukrainian sinus infection that I refused to succumb to. I should have stayed in bed, but I wouldn&#8217;t. I continued to act healthy until I just couldn&#8217;t fake it anymore. Fever. Cough. Sinus pressure. I felt terrible. I was miserable.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">But this was the day my neighbor&#8217;s daughter, Anya, brought out her books to show me how she could read English while I was waiting on my laundry. This was the day we played with clay putty, something I used to do with my grandma, something to me incredibly nostalgic. See that bracelet on my hand? She wanted to give me that, a prize she had won in class. She wouldn&#8217;t take no for an answer. I wore it for the rest of the trip, never stopping to think that it might look silly. I counted it precious. It was a comfort, a reminder of the day I learned the truth.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">And all it took to rattle my nice little American world was a little girl in a cramped Ukrainian apartment who wanted to show me her English.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">This was the day I finally understood that I wanted to make a difference, that I could make a difference, even if it was just teaching a little girl one word of English in a far-away country.</p>
<p>I suddenly remembered a day ten long years ago, standing outside my house at fifteen, breathing deeply of the wind and wondering where it had been, where it was going, and was that some kind of Eastern spice I smelled in the air? I was dying to go and find out. That girl was all fear and trepidation, unsure, and insecure. That fifteen-year-old girl had no idea of where she would be ten years later, that one day she would just up and go away for a month all on her own. Sometimes I remember the girl I was and smile, because I owe it to who I used to be to be who I am now.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><em>I owe it to myself to live my dreams.</em></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">We owe it to the young versions of ourselves to fulfill their dreams &#8212; those dreams we used to cherish.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">People have continually picked this one picture out of my hundreds and commented on how I&#8217;m &#8220;glowing&#8221; or &#8220;look really happy&#8221;. Maybe I had a fever. Maybe it was just because I was sick. Maybe it&#8217;s sweat. But the one comment I can&#8217;t argue with, the one that gets me every time, is: &#8220;You don&#8217;t look like that over here.&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Deep down inside, I know they are right.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">There&#8217;s only been a handful of times in my life that I can remember being really truly as happy as I was in that picture, when I was relaxed, didn&#8217;t care about how I looked, or if I was pretty, or if my tummy pudge was showing. Only six brief moments when I was convinced that life was going to be good and worth living. This was one of those moments, illness notwithstanding.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Because this was the day I realized that my life was a joke. I hadn&#8217;t been doing anything worthwhile or helping anyone or making anything better. I was treading water, just taking up space and wasting time playing games on people and computers. I hadn&#8217;t really been living the life I dreamed of in the secret attic of my mind, and I had spent a great amount of time and effort trying to convince myself otherwise. I claimed to want a career, a house, and a family. But did I? Had I only been pretending after all?</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">The truth?</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">I was living a lie.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">This was the day I stopped lying.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/743/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/743/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=743&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tworedtornados.wordpress.com/2013/03/06/no-more-lies-weekly-writing-challenge-truth-is-stranger-than-fiction/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/6e8787d5b6c466718a937e3191b9870d?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tworedtornados</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tworedtornados.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/wpid-imag0661_burst002.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">wpid-IMAG0661_BURST002.jpg</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Our Heroine</title>
		<link>http://ekantavasi.wordpress.com/2013/03/07/day-13-our-heroine/</link>
		<comments>http://ekantavasi.wordpress.com/2013/03/07/day-13-our-heroine/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 04:36:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Michael Shoemake</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Child]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fantasy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Growing up]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Knowledge]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[myth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[original content]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Silence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ekantavasi.wordpress.com/?p=113</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Our heroine came, bouncing and slimy, into the world on the thirty-first day of April in the year 1998. She was, disappointingly, a thoroughly average infant, spitting and vomiting and excreting vile substances all across her poor parents’ little apartment. The child kept them up at nights and needed to be burped often, and of [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=113&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Our heroine came, bouncing and slimy, into the world on the thirty-first day of April in the year 1998. She was, disappointingly, a thoroughly average infant, spitting and vomiting and excreting vile substances all across her poor parents’ little apartment. The child kept them up at nights and needed to be burped often, and of course rejected all edible objects in favor of the unique challenges which glass marbles and bits of organic petrochemical polymers posed to the human digestive system. She grew at about the average rate children grow at – or at least this author supposes so, finding little evidence to the contrary –and soon found herself at four years of age, when her parents’ suspicions were finally confirmed by the family doctor; she was mute.</p>
<p>That she could not speak, though unfortunate, could hardly be counted as a mark against her, of course, but her parents found something far more troubling bubbling up in their beloved lump of flesh, a sin more troubling than any infirmity of the body. Though I am sure you have guessed it by now – for what horror could be more disturbing? – I will say it outright, for the sake of those philistines who followed the same path as she: she rejected the Television.  Oh, yes! The very selfsame Television her parents had desperately hoped would bring them a few moments’ peace in the din of their lives, having grown awfully weary over the course of the past few years. Yes, rejected it outright, in fact! Its rude colors and insistent flashes, its repetitive and banal artificiality (for she never really gave the poor thing much of a chance beyond those first few glimpses) sent her reeling away. Gradually, however, her parents learned to ply her with books – and the older and more confounding, the better – in these she felt she had found a few true shades of light, the better picture of Nature.</p>
<p>Her parents also found, over time, that there was no difference whatever to her, in terms of preference, between the unseen flight of faeries and the highly-documented mycological phenomenon of faerie circles. She fawned over the fancies of mythology with a force equal to her love of natural philosophy. As she studied Ptolemy’s spheres and Newton’s motions, she imagined the Titans which frolicked, throwing the celestial orbs about and the gremlins which surely provided our wig-headed friend’s “equal and opposite” reactions, hiding away in all things. So, too, the feeble chains of time held no meaning in her brain, and they certainly did not hold her. She felt no less a connection to the theorems of Galileo than to the patient but harried advice that her father meted out in his distinctly sonorous tones. And when the girl was very still (as she was in the most wild and passionate throes of study) she felt she could hear the low thin shiver of the universe in her head, the trembling of a great giant at the bottom of a deep well.</p>
<p>Though to be sure, as she aged, her tastes did indeed change. Now she loved the structure of cells (and especially the mitochondria which tied her to the ancient Mother), now she loved those grim brothers and their strange and terrific tales, now the study of waves, now the delights of Baba Yaga and the flying stoves which populate Russian folktales. In her longest phase, she was entranced by Paracelsus, who seemed to wed the fancies of her soul for a sweet, fleeting time.</p>
<p>But for all her studies, our queer child could not be called an “intellectual,” as her head remained quite stubbornly unpointed and untroubled by matters of consistency. She saw no obstruction in contradiction; after all, if she could hold them without tension in the smithy of her own soul, why, then, could not the infinitely better, brighter, vaster universe do the same? (Why not indeed?)</p>
<p>Thusly, it seems our child had no place in the world, destined for solitude away from the rude souls of her sapiens brethren. “Very well,” she thought, when she was old enough to understand the suffering she must carry and the first throbs of loneliness touched her tender heart, “I will simply be alone; or, better, I will not be a person. So much grander to be a frog or a gnat or even a horse, pretentious though they are.” And, when, in her eighteenth year, she leaped and buzzed and galloped her way out of the town, she did not look back more than three times and with only a meager few tears.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/113/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/113/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=113&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://ekantavasi.wordpress.com/2013/03/07/day-13-our-heroine/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/52dd003a4961cc1fa4a18809afa4157b?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">michaelshoemake</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>America’s Long Withdrawal from Afghanistan</title>
		<link>http://lightbox.time.com/2013/03/07/americas-long-withdrawal-from-afghanistan-photographs-by-yuri-kozyrev/</link>
		<comments>http://lightbox.time.com/2013/03/07/americas-long-withdrawal-from-afghanistan-photographs-by-yuri-kozyrev/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 12:31:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Patrick Witty</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Photo Essay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Afghanistan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bagram]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kabul]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NOOR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yuri Kozyrev]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://lightbox.time.com/?p=67278</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[TIME contract photographer Yuri Kozyrev traveled to Afghanistan to document how the American military will bring the materials home from more than a decade of war.<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=67278&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the months leading up to the Normandy Invasion in the late spring of 1944, the U.S. shipped 1.6 million troops and 17 million tons of cargo to staging areas in the United Kingdom. If the numbers weren’t mind boggling enough, to reach the British Isles, the troops and cargo had to cross the Atlantic under threat of being sunk by German U Boats. That buildup was just one of untold numbers of logistical feats during that enormous war, one chapter in an ongoing legacy of remarkable exploits that extends to the retrograde, the military’s term for bringing all of our equipment home from Afghanistan.</p>
<p>For many good reasons, Afghanistan has been called a logistician’s nightmare. It is landlocked and far from a working port. Much of the country – especially in the east where a great deal of the fighting has taken place – is covered with mountains and threaded by decades-old roads and questionable bridges. The easiest way in and out of the country is a geopolitical minefield and the other two routes are three times as expensive.</p>
<p>And yet, for twelve years, logisticians have supplied troops with the equipment — large and small — necessary to fight a war. They have airdropped pallets of food and repair parts on remote bases, tossed “Speedballs” — body bags filled with ammunition and water — out of helicopters to troops under fire. And along the way, extra equipment has piled up at bases around Afghanistan. According to a December 2012 report to Congress by the by the Government Accountability Office, there is the equivalent of more than 90,000 twenty-foot containers of equipment all over Afghanistan. All together, there is $36 billion worth of vehicles, weapons systems, repair parts and utter junk scattered throughout the country, and bringing it home will cost an estimated $5.7 billion.</p>
<p>Last month, I traveled to eastern Afghanistan with TIME contract photographer Yuri Kozyrev to document how the American military will bring all of that stuff home from Afghanistan. The journey began at Forward Operating Base Altimur, a scrap of land at on a slope above a desert floor, deep in Logar Province. There, the paratroopers of Bull Battery, 173rd Airborne Brigade were busy tearing down much of the base. We met hardened veterans like Sgt. Mario Diaz, who was serving his third tour in Afghanistan and the second at FOB Altimur, which has both been his sanctuary from fighting and the site of some of the most difficult times in his 32 years. There were three privates on their first combat tour who were in third grade when the war began. They all joined up within two weeks of graduating from high school and met each other just before shipping out to Afghanistan.</p>
<p>When the troops are done packing their equipment, the destination for much of the gear is one of the yards at Bagram Airfield, the largest base in eastern Afghanistan. A quick drive around Bagram and you’ll see yard after yard of twenty and forty foot container stacked two high, vehicles that cost $570,000 each lined up by the hundreds waiting to be washed four times before they can be shipped home. Then at the end of the line, especially in the winter months when most of the equipment leaves Afghanistan by air, the Port Dogs of the 455th Expeditionary Airwing load cargo planes with trucks weighing a dozen tons and pallets weighing 10,000 pounds that the push onto the airplanes by hand.</p>
<p>Along the way, there are troops who sort and separate, update records and pack containers. Most of the equipment will come back to the U.S. for repairs and refitting for use in future training. Much of it will be staged at bases around the world, waiting at the ready for the next unseen war. Logisticians have been moving thousands of people and tons of supplies under horrendous conditions since war began. The retrograde from Afghanistan is an enormous challenge, one that will likely be studied decades from now when logisticians have to make similar magic happen again. “The numbers look intimidating, but we&#8217;re a big organization,” says Brigadier Felix Gedney, a British exchange officer serving as deputy commanding general for transition in the 1st Infantry Division. “It&#8217;s in the art of the possible that it&#8217;s achievable.&#8221;</p>
<hr />
<p><em><a href="http://lightbox.time.com/tag/yuri-kozyrev/"><strong>Yuri Kozyrev</strong></a> is a contract photographer for TIME and was named the 2011 <a href="http://www.poyi.org/69/41/" target="_blank">Photographer of the Year</a> in the Pictures of the Year International competition.</em></p>
<p><em><a href="http://nation.time.com/author/naterawlings/"><strong>Nate Rawlings</strong></a> is a reporter for TIME. He writes for the magazine’s Briefing section and about politics, government and military affairs for TIME.com.</em></p>
<hr />
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/67278/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/67278/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=67278&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://lightbox.time.com/2013/03/07/americas-long-withdrawal-from-afghanistan-photographs-by-yuri-kozyrev/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://timethemoment.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/koy201301300024.jpg?w=250" />
		<media:content url="http://timethemoment.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/koy201301300024.jpg?w=250" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">KOY201301300024</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/7d512d69c1de31de1ea1a26b1002bfb9?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F1.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">patrickwittytime</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>South Central Belfast</title>
		<link>http://vernacularisms.com/2013/03/07/south-central-belfast/</link>
		<comments>http://vernacularisms.com/2013/03/07/south-central-belfast/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 13:55:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>jasonoruairc</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[basketball]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bedford Street]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Belfast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Boyz n the Hood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[British Army]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cabbie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[checkpoint]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[City Hall]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fear]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jason O'Rourke]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Literature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lower Ormeau Road]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ormeau Road]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[RUC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[short story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[South Central Los Angeles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[taxi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[taxi depot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Troubles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vernacularisms.com/?p=908</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Rare birds have flown thousands of miles to land on the Lower Ormeau Road. It is a glorious summer Saturday and I am going across town to visit a friend who lives on the Antrim Road. They are standing outside the taxi depot: two black guys wearing basketball kit, bright primary-coloured vests and shorts. They [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=908&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://vernacularisms.com/2013/03/07/south-central-belfast/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/00c7363b379d75884e2b9a531473c21e?s=96&#38;d=wavatar&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jasonoruairc</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jasonoruairc.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/20121205_140548.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">20121205_140548</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fashion Shmashion</title>
		<link>http://thoughtcatalog.com/2013/fashion-shmashion/</link>
		<comments>http://thoughtcatalog.com/2013/fashion-shmashion/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 04:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Thought Catalog</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Clothes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Clothing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dressing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fashion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Malls]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Urban Outfitters]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thoughtcatalog.com/?p=173319</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Fashion forces me to think about who I am on some kind of deep, existential level. <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=173319&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_173337" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 594px"><img class="size-full wp-image-173337" alt="Shutterstock.com" src="http://thoughtcatalog.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/shutterstock_66016366-1.jpg?w=584&#038;h=584" width="584" height="584" /><p class="wp-caption-text"><a href="http://www.shutterstock.com/index-in.mhtml">Shutterstock.com</a></p></div>
<p>A while ago, I came across this gem of a quote while listening to an interview with Ira Glass on one of my regular podcasts, <i>WTF with Marc Maron</i>. As the topic of fashion was broached, Glass had this to say:</p>
<blockquote><p>Then I quickly throw on some clothes &#8212; the same outfit every day, pretty much. It’s just… I hate shopping because I hate myself and I don’t know what clothes to wear. And I get into an existential crisis when I have to choose clothes because I think &#8216;Well who am I, that I would wear this shirt rather than this one.&#8217; I’m not proud of that… There was a period about 10 years ago where I would have to get drunk in order to buy clothes.</p></blockquote>
<p>I think about this all the time, probably because this pretty closely captures how I feel when buying clothes. Shopping is torture. Screw waterboarding &#8211; let&#8217;s start dragging suspected terrorists to Urban Outfitters on Friday afternoons for v-neck tee shopping with snot-nosed hipsters. We might actually get some answers.</p>
<p>The problem isn&#8217;t that I hate clothing &#8211; I actually consider myself moderately interested in fashion. No, my distaste for shopping has more to do with the anxiety that it entails. For one thing, finding clothes in my size is a to-do. Don&#8217;t get me wrong &#8212; being small has its advantages. I can&#8217;t tell you how many times I&#8217;ve hidden in a modest crevice or disguised myself as a child to gain access to restricted areas. This is for legal reasons, not because I don&#8217;t know how many times. Point is, with smallness comes stealth, about which people over six feet know nothing. These advantages are of little help when it comes to fashion, however. Admittedly, the perpetual realization that the smallest-sized slacks in the men&#8217;s section are still far too big never fails to emasculate.</p>
<p>But the main reason I hate clothes shopping is similar to the reason Glass gives. It forces me to think about who I am on some kind of deep, existential level. What could possibly be more revolting than that? As if I don&#8217;t dislike myself enough, now I have to beat myself up with all the reasons why I&#8217;m not the kind of person who can wear white linen pants paired with an ironic Budweiser shirt. It looks great on the mannequin — why shouldn&#8217;t it look good on me? What&#8217;s he got that I don&#8217;t? I don&#8217;t hate mannequins in my normal life. While clothes shopping, however, my contempt for them is incandescent. Some small solace can be taken in the fact that they don&#8217;t have eyes.</p>
<p>In a way, it’s paralyzing to think about the vast array of clothing that I&#8217;ll never be able to wear. Particularly because, in each instance, it forces me to dwell on why, exactly, that may be the case &#8212; which defect in my physique or personality is responsible. Could I pull off one of those wispy, Middle-Eastern-looking scarves that Kanye West wears, for example? What does it say about me that the answer is absolutely not? Am I boorish and unrefined? Do I have a weird chin? Am I a bad rapper? The ensuing pit of anxiety is literally bottomless. And this is just one item of clothing&#8211;an accessory, at that. You get the idea.</p>
<p>A tank top is a good example of something I have never been able to wear convincingly. I wish I could. I really do. It&#8217;d be fantastic if I could throw my inhibitions and sleeves to the wind for just one day. I&#8217;ve tried it before. The result is me feeling highly uncomfortable and passersby looking at me disdainfully &#8211; condescendingly, as if to say, &#8220;nice try, little fella.&#8221; This item, as it turns out, is reserved for men with man-sized arms, as opposed to girly-men with bony shoulders and the biceps of a twelve-year-old with polio.</p>
<p>Some other examples of things I can&#8217;t wear:</p>
<p>A vest.</p>
<p>A useless garment. Still, it stings a little that I&#8217;ll never pull off the Will Smith in <i>Wild Wild West </i>look. Sigh.</p>
<p>A sideways belt.</p>
<p>As best I can tell, this look requires a carefree attitude and a skateboard. Neither of which I have.</p>
<p>A fedora.</p>
<p>This has become much more alluring since I started watching <i>Mad Men</i>. But times have changed since 1965 and I don&#8217;t go on cruises or hang out at the Olive Garden bar nearly enough to pull off a fedora convincingly.</p>
<p>Long story short &#8212; I don&#8217;t go clothes shopping very often. It&#8217;s not a pretty sight. If you know me, this is why I&#8217;ve never invited you or anyone else to join me on such an excursion. It starts about an hour in with sharp headaches followed by cold sweat and usually ends with me vomiting on a rack of cardigans while screaming at flustered Banana Republic employees to get their hands off me.</p>
<p>So for now I guess I&#8217;ll stick with my small, trusty collection of jeans, sweaters, and collared shirts ranging in color from light gray to navy to medium black. I&#8217;ll put off the clothes shopping til the next time I&#8217;m in the mood for an aneurysm. [tc-mark]</p>
<h3 style="padding-left:60px;">You should like Thought Catalog on Facebook <a href="http://www.facebook.com/thoughtcatalog">here</a>.</h3>
<p>[ad-mpu] </p>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=173319&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thoughtcatalog.com/2013/fashion-shmashion/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://thoughtcatalog.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/fashionsmashion.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://thoughtcatalog.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/fashionsmashion.jpg?w=150" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/1697c5ba542014f5a562dbd265a1413f?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tcguestwriters</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thoughtcatalog.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/shutterstock_66016366-1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Shutterstock.com</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Illusion of the “Similar Culture”</title>
		<link>http://iwasanexpatwife.com/2013/03/07/the-illusion-of-the-similar-culture/</link>
		<comments>http://iwasanexpatwife.com/2013/03/07/the-illusion-of-the-similar-culture/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 05:01:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Maria</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Adjustment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canada]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture Shock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Language]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adjustment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture shock]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[expat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[language]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://iwasanexpatwife.com/?p=4759</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The weirdest thing about moving to France was the culture shock. Not the fact that it existed — I was prepared for that.  No, what floored me was how intense it was, especially in comparison to my previous move. Who would have thought that adjusting to a Western culture would be more difficult than adjusting [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4759&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://iwasanexpatwife.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/the-illusion-of-the-similar-culture.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-4760" alt="The illusion of the similar culture" src="http://iwasanexpatwife.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/the-illusion-of-the-similar-culture.jpg?w=300&#038;h=199" width="300" height="199" /></a>The weirdest thing about <a title="Bordeaux in pictures | iwasanexpatwife.com" href="http://iwasanexpatwife.com/2011/06/02/bordeaux-in-pictures/" target="_blank">moving to France</a> was the<a title="What is culture shock? | iwasanexpatwife.com" href="http://iwasanexpatwife.com/2012/11/19/what-is-culture-shock/" target="_blank"> culture shock</a>. Not the fact that it existed — I was prepared for that.  No, what floored me was how intense it was, especially in comparison to my previous move. Who would have thought that adjusting to a Western culture would be more difficult than adjusting to an Asian one?</p>
<p>(The culprit was cockiness: I wildly overestimated my expat abilities because this was my fourth move and I thought I’d already made all my mistakes. One word: <i>hubris</i>.)</p>
<p>During those first challenging weeks in Bordeaux, the target of my wrath became the Internet café, where all the keyboards were — quite naturally — French. I’d never used a different keyboard layout before, and as a touch typist, it was discouraging to glance over a lengthy email I’d just written only to find a screen full of gibberish staring back at me. I was inadvertently signing my name “?qriq” instead of “Maria,” which seemed fitting in light of my brand-new identity crisis.</p>
<p>I was trudging back to my crappy temporary housing after another frustrating keyboard experience one day when Blaine called. Blaine and I have been good friends since high school, so I had no problem whining to him that I felt like a total loser who couldn’t seem to figure out how things worked in Bordeaux. Like the sweetheart he is, he started telling me how much he struggled when he moved to England twenty-plus years ago.</p>
<p>“Are you kidding me?” I snapped. “You think that’s hard? At least you didn’t have to learn <a title="Say what? | iwasanexpatwife.com" href="http://iwasanexpatwife.com/2012/03/26/say-what/" target="_blank">a different #@*&amp;$ language</a>.” (For the record, yes, he’s <i>still</i> my friend. The man is a saint.)</p>
<p>I made the same mistake a lot of people make: assuming that moving to a “similar” culture is a cakewalk. Blaine is the first to admit he thought the same thing, and we’re not alone. A study published in the <em>International Journal of Human Resource Management</em> found that</p>
<blockquote><p>“in the absence of complete information, expatriates may be creating stereotypes on the basis of language similarity. In particular, those expatriates who spoke the language of the host country expected an ‘easier’ experience…. In fact, these expatriates may need additional CCT [cross-cultural training] to help overcome their stereotypes or their inappropriate expectations.”</p></blockquote>
<p>I think there are three broad areas that trip up expats who move to a culture they think is similar to their own:</p>
<h3><b>Language (vocabulary, syntax, accent)</b></h3>
<p>George Bernard Shaw (or Oscar Wilde — take your pick) once observed, “England and America are two countries divided by a common language.” As an immigrant kid I have some experience in this matter, and I can say with utter certainty that you don’t know what mortification is until your English/Irish parents send you out to “buy some <i>fags</i> for us” in the presence of your snickering Canadian schoolmates.</p>
<p>“There are some amusing differences such as <i>pants</i>, which you quickly learn <a title="The wedding of my kitchen, and other embarrassing language mistakes | iwasanexpatwife.com" href="http://iwasanexpatwife.com/2010/08/08/the-wedding-of-my-kitchen-and-other-embarrassing-language-mistakes/" target="_blank">means something different</a>,” agrees Blaine. “Also, I had a <i>fanny pack</i>….”</p>
<p>Well, I never said he was cool.</p>
<p>Let’s turn for a moment to another brave voyager, Aisha Ashraf. (You might know her from her excellent blog, <a title="Expatlogue" href="http://expatlogue.wordpress.com/" target="_blank">Expatlogue</a>.) Aisha moved in the opposite direction, from England to Canada, and has had similar issues understanding <a title="Canadian English spoken here | iwasanexpatwife.com" href="http://iwasanexpatwife.com/2011/03/31/canadian-english-spoken-here/" target="_blank">Canadian English</a>.</p>
<p>“I had a cut on my finger so I asked at the hotel reception for a <i>plaster</i>,” she told me in an email.  “The woman at the desk gave me a blank look, shifted uncomfortably, then gave a little cough and asked if I&#8217;d like an elastic band. After I explained about the cut, she got the picture and her face lit up as she triumphantly iterated, ‘aaahhhh, a <i>Band-aid</i>!’ That was my first experience of speaking the same language yet appearing incomprehensible, and it was a really odd and unexpected feeling.”</p>
<h3><b>Procedural/logistical matters </b></h3>
<p>These are the practical aspects of daily life — those routines that are so mundane, you’ve never given them a second thought.</p>
<p>“It can be just minor things,” Blaine says, “but because you’ve grown up with only one way of doing something, you may have not have developed your flexibility bone* enough to consider that there might be another way. I can give you a trivial example: knowing the difference between a taxi and a private hire car. In Canada there’s only one kind of taxi. In England there are the more expensive official taxis, there are private hire cars — the mini cabs — and then there are the unlicensed mini cabs, which are another breed altogether. When you have to learn 20 new things like that a day, it makes you crazy.”</p>
<h3><b>Values/attitudes/behaviours</b></h3>
<p>People tend to fixate on language differences, but of course it goes much deeper than that — we often come up against values, attitudes, and behaviours that we mistakenly assume will be the same as ours. For Blaine, one of the biggest issues was the famous British reserve. “It’s true,” he says. “The stiff upper lip really does exist.”</p>
<p>“That’s funny,” says Aisha. “I find the Canadian veneer of politeness very difficult to penetrate. I find the British more direct — but maybe that&#8217;s just because I&#8217;m more familiar with the <a title="Lost in non-verbal translation | In Search of a Life Less Ordinary" href="http://www.insearchofalifelessordinary.com/2011/08/lost-in-nonverbal-translation.html" target="_blank">non-verbal cues</a>.”</p>
<p>So apologies to my dear friend Blaine for discounting the very real culture shock he experienced when he moved to Blighty. Scratching the surface reveals that Canadians and Brits aren’t so similar after all: they speak different Englishes, have different behaviours, and even — as I learned while writing this post — type with different keyboard layouts.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">* * *</p>
<h3>Glossary</h3>
<p><i>Fags</i>: British English for cigarettes<br />
<i>Pants</i>: British English for underpants; also, adjective that means “really bad”<br />
<i>Fanny</i> pack: Canadian English for bum bag<br />
<i>Plaster</i>: British English for Band-aid<br />
<i>Band-aid</i>: Canadian English for plaster</p>
<p>* “Flexibility bone” — LOL! See why I love this guy? <img src='http://s0.wp.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif' alt=':)' class='wp-smiley' /> </p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4759/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4759/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4759&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://iwasanexpatwife.com/2013/03/07/the-illusion-of-the-similar-culture/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f7c0530d6935345c1eb107fa0b807c38?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F0.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">iwasanexpatwife</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://iwasanexpatwife.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/the-illusion-of-the-similar-culture.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The illusion of the similar culture</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>This Story Needs Your Help</title>
		<link>http://tracycembor.com/2013/03/06/this-story-needs-your-help/</link>
		<comments>http://tracycembor.com/2013/03/06/this-story-needs-your-help/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 02:36:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>tracycembor</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blank page]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adventure]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rough draft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rivenloss]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creative process]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[world building]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[trade fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[innovation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[short story]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tracycembor.com/?p=759</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[But don&#8217;t worry, I&#8217;ll do most of the heavy lifting.  I want to write a short story in the next couple of weeks, and I want you&#8230; yes, you right there, stop looking down and fiddling with your phone like I can&#8217;t see you there&#8230; Ahem, as I was saying, I want you to help [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=759&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>But don&#8217;t worry, I&#8217;ll do most of the heavy lifting.  I want to write a short story in the next couple of weeks, and I want you&#8230; <em>yes, you right there, stop looking down and fiddling with your phone like I can&#8217;t see you there</em>&#8230; Ahem, as I was saying, I want you to help me with the story.  Don&#8217;t worry, you just have to click a few choices during the week to decide how the story progresses.  I&#8217;ll do the rest of the work.</p>
<h4>Where Did I Get This Idea?</h4>
<p>I loved reading the Choose Your Own Adventure stories when I was a kid.  It was so cool to be able to decide what the brave adventurer did next.  Writing a story gives me the same kind of control, but writing is a solitary activity.  I have been brainstorming writing activities that have collaborative input.  This is going to be our trial run together.  That&#8217;s where you come in&#8230; <em>and don&#8217;t think about closing your browser like you didn&#8217;t read this</em>&#8230;  I need your input for this project to succeed.</p>
<h4>What Do You Have To Do?</h4>
<p>Only three things&#8230; <em>and don&#8217;t roll your eyes at me</em>&#8230;</p>
<ol>
<li>Swing by my blog every 48 hours.</li>
<li>Read the piece of the story I have posted.</li>
<li>Vote in the polls.</li>
</ol>
<h4>What Kind of Story Are Going to Write?</h4>
<p>It&#8217;s going to be a steampunk adventure, so strap on your goggles and find your gyrospanners. Also, I added a page today for <a href="http://tracycembor.com/rivenloss-the-dreamless-city/">Rivenloss, the Dreamless City</a>, if you want to read a bit about the world. It&#8217;s not required reading though.</p>
<h4>Let&#8217;s meet our characters.  Guess what!  You can help me pick out names.</h4>
<p><img class="alignleft" alt="" src="http://media-cache-ec5.pinterest.com/550x/cf/c8/ae/cfc8aeba23771571dff9e8910b8de875.jpg" width="330" height="440" />She&#8217;s a determined young engineer at the South Foundry, not far from the Cobblecourt District in Rivenloss, the Dreamless City.  Like many newly minted engineers, she&#8217;s assigned to the Foundry Maintenance Division.  Responsibilities include coglight replacement, cogsbot servicing, and substandard equipment systems repair.  Drudge work. She&#8217;s gunning for a promotion and doing everything she can to keep overbearing supervisor willing to sign her promotion papers. She&#8217;s not about to let anyone muck it up for her.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a name="pd_a_6943942"></a>
<div class="PDS_Poll" id="PDI_container6943942" data-settings="{&quot;url&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/static.polldaddy.com\/p\/6943942.js&quot;}" style="display:inline-block;"></div>
<div id="PD_superContainer"></div>
<noscript><a href="http://polldaddy.com/poll/6943942">Take Our Poll</a></noscript></p>
<p><img class="alignright" alt="" src="http://media-cache-ec4.pinterest.com/550x/d6/45/3f/d6453fc91d4a41cf294db0f9c84b42fb.jpg" width="350" height="468" />He&#8217;s an idealistic young scientist searching for the truth about the Steam Meisters. He believes the answer may lay in the Foundry Moths and their chrysalis, if he can ever get his hands on one. He&#8217;s stirring up a hornet&#8217;s nest of trouble and does not know it yet. The City Vigilance, police force of Rivenloss, is keeping a close eye on him at the behest of the Central Planning Committee, a murky bureaucratic entity pulling more strings than the Engineers Guild may realize. Let&#8217;s hope his inquisitive mind doesn&#8217;t lead him down a dangerous path.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a name="pd_a_6943949"></a>
<div class="PDS_Poll" id="PDI_container6943949" data-settings="{&quot;url&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/static.polldaddy.com\/p\/6943949.js&quot;}" style="display:inline-block;"></div>
<div id="PD_superContainer"></div>
<noscript><a href="http://polldaddy.com/poll/6943949">Take Our Poll</a></noscript></p>
<p><img class="alignleft" alt="" src="http://media-cache-ec2.pinterest.com/550x/97/c9/e0/97c9e05715c7061153a8548b4f7d48b5.jpg" width="330" height="495" />He&#8217;s a surly engineering supervisor who seems surprisingly well connected, concidering his lackluster position at the South Foundry. If he gives an enterprising young engineer his stamp of approval, it can open doors to sweet opportunities at the District Cogsworks or the Machinery Annex. He is married, but his poor wife&#8217;s health is failing.  He&#8217;s not a squeaky clean character, and has a dark and troubled past. The Central Planning Committee has dirt on him, and they will not hesitate to flex their muscles if they believe some closely held secrets are in danger of leaking into Rivenloss.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a name="pd_a_6943952"></a>
<div class="PDS_Poll" id="PDI_container6943952" data-settings="{&quot;url&quot;:&quot;http:\/\/static.polldaddy.com\/p\/6943952.js&quot;}" style="display:inline-block;"></div>
<div id="PD_superContainer"></div>
<noscript><a href="http://polldaddy.com/poll/6943952">Take Our Poll</a></noscript></p>
<p>There, that wasn&#8217;t so bad was it?  Check back on Friday (probably in the evening) to read the first part of our story, and you can decide what happens next.  I can&#8217;t wait to see how this turns out, can you?</p>
<br /> Tagged: <a href='http://tracycembor.com/tag/adventure/'>adventure</a>, <a href='http://tracycembor.com/tag/blank-page/'>blank page</a>, <a href='http://tracycembor.com/tag/books/'>books</a>, <a href='http://tracycembor.com/tag/creative-process/'>creative process</a>, <a href='http://tracycembor.com/tag/entertainment/'>entertainment</a>, <a href='http://tracycembor.com/tag/fiction/'>fiction</a>, <a href='http://tracycembor.com/tag/innovation/'>innovation</a>, <a href='http://tracycembor.com/tag/rivenloss/'>Rivenloss</a>, <a href='http://tracycembor.com/tag/rough-draft/'>rough draft</a>, <a href='http://tracycembor.com/tag/short-story/'>short story</a>, <a href='http://tracycembor.com/tag/trade-fiction/'>trade fiction</a>, <a href='http://tracycembor.com/tag/world-building/'>world building</a>, <a href='http://tracycembor.com/tag/writers/'>writers</a>, <a href='http://tracycembor.com/tag/writing/'>writing</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/759/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/759/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/759/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/759/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/759/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/759/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/759/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/759/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/759/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/759/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/759/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/759/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/759/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/759/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=759&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tracycembor.com/2013/03/06/this-story-needs-your-help/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>43</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://tracycembor.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/girl-01.jpg?w=112" />
		<media:content url="http://tracycembor.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/girl-01.jpg?w=112" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Girl 01</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/3ff458d5de14c7d1aa8862073a5e278c?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tracycembor</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://media-cache-ec5.pinterest.com/550x/cf/c8/ae/cfc8aeba23771571dff9e8910b8de875.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://media-cache-ec4.pinterest.com/550x/d6/45/3f/d6453fc91d4a41cf294db0f9c84b42fb.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://media-cache-ec2.pinterest.com/550x/97/c9/e0/97c9e05715c7061153a8548b4f7d48b5.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>My Mind Is My Battlefield</title>
		<link>http://dontforgettofeedthebaby.com/2013/03/06/my-mind-is-my-battlefield/</link>
		<comments>http://dontforgettofeedthebaby.com/2013/03/06/my-mind-is-my-battlefield/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2013 15:30:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Kathy V.</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mental Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[depression]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mental health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parenting community]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[them's fighting words]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dontforgettofeedthebaby.com/?p=1887</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This is as true in everyday life as it is in battle: we are given one life and the decision is ours whether to wait for circumstances to make up our mind, or whether to act, and in acting, to live. ~ Omar N. Bradley Depression is an issue that has been getting a great [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1887&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>This is as true in everyday life as it is in battle: we are given one life and the decision is ours whether to wait for circumstances to make up our mind, or whether to act, and in acting, to live. ~ Omar N. Bradley</em></p>
<p>Depression is an issue that has been getting a great deal of press lately, particularly in the parenting community. The Parenting Magazine article <a href="http://www.parenting.com/article/xanax" target="_blank">Xanax Makes Me A Better Mom</a> shows just how pervasive and controversial this issue is: according to the article, parents are more than twice as likely as non-parents to experience depression, and the comments section illustrates just exactly how harsh and judgmental people can be about it &#8212; whether you&#8217;re taking pills or not, whether you&#8217;re in therapy or not, as soon as you use the word &#8216;depression&#8217; someone stands ready to condemn you for something.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve been depressed for my entire life. When I was 24, I first heard the word <a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmedhealth/PMH0001916/" target="_blank">dysthymia</a>: chronic, mild depression that lasts for years. It was a diagnosis which has made me view my entire dry, pessimistic personality as suspect. I&#8217;ve suffered repeated bouts of <a href="http://www.webmd.com/depression/double-depression" target="_blank">double depression</a> as well &#8212; dysthymia paired with an episode of major depression. It makes for a thick psychiatric folder and a lifelong struggle to feel even the most basic joys.</p>
<div id="attachment_1899" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://dontforgettofeedthebaby.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/depressed-woman.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1899" alt="Photo courtesy of sxc.hu" src="http://dontforgettofeedthebaby.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/depressed-woman.jpg?w=300&#038;h=208" width="300" height="208" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Photo courtesy of sxc.hu</p></div>
<p>I took medications (many, many medications) for five years. I&#8217;ve been in therapy with psychiatrists, psychologists, clinical social workers, and counselors for eleven. I&#8217;ve used all the conventional methods to treat depression, from SSRIs to Cognitive Behavioral Therapy. I know what works for me and what doesn&#8217;t.</p>
<p>Last summer, I went once more into a deep depression. Years of therapy had given me tools that helped me to deal with my dysthymia, and I had been functioning quite well without drugs for years. The scary thing about this depression, beyond the fact that my own mind was once more threatening my life and happiness, is that this time I&#8217;m a mom.</p>
<p>I have a son. I have to raise this child. I have to get up early every morning, put his needs before my own, and provide him with a safe, healthy environment. More than that, I have to teach him how to live in the world. How can I do that, if I&#8217;m mired in pain? How can I teach him to love life if I&#8217;m thinking of taking my own?</p>
<p><a href="http://dontforgettofeedthebaby.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/baby-face_edited-1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-1902" alt="Baby face_edited-1" src="http://dontforgettofeedthebaby.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/baby-face_edited-1.jpg?w=500&#038;h=363" width="500" height="363" /></a></p>
<p>My son, just by existing, has raised the stakes on my healing process. <em>I MUST GET BETTER.</em> For his sake, for my sake, for the sakes of all the people with whom I come into contact. I cannot refuse to do the things that I have to do to get better, not out of fear or shame or any other emotion that may weigh me down.</p>
<p>A recent <a href="http://www.inthepowderroom.com/read/me-time/2013-02-we-are-only-as-sick-as-our-secrets.html" target="_blank">article by The Bearded Iris</a> was titled &#8220;We Are Only As Sick As Our Secrets&#8221;. It&#8217;s a saying which is common theme in therapy. Being open about our pain, about the reasons behind our pain, alleviates that pain. It allows us to live more fully in our skins and to have more honest relationships with people. Though it may be hard and frightening, talking about our inner fears, hurts, and suppressed angers is a necessary part of healing.</p>
<p>Though it&#8217;s hard, I&#8217;ve been working to come to grips with my past &#8212; to expose my pain to fresh air and sunlight. Therapy has taught me a great deal about myself, about the things that made me the way I am, and about what I need to do to become the kind of person that I want to be.</p>
<p>When it becomes too hard, when it hurts too much and I face too much judgment and condemnation from my loved ones (who would be very happy to see me medicate the pain away, in spite of the fact that I know that drugs are only a superficial panacea for me), I think of my little son.</p>
<p>I think of him at seventy, or eighty, or ninety. I think of him telling his grandchildren about his life, and that of his parents. I think of him telling them about me.</p>
<p>If I give up, if I choose not to do the hard work of grappling with my pain, his story will be one of his own pain. It will be a story of feeling disconnected from his mother, of watching her shrivel into herself until she was completely unable to function. It may be a story of losing her altogether, and the terrible toll that had on the rest of his young life. I can&#8217;t bear to think of that.</p>
<p>If I don&#8217;t give up, if I do what needs to be done to face my demons and stand up for my own mental health, I can hope that his story will be one of pride and admiration. It will be a story of a strong, courageous woman who did not let life, stigma, condemnation, or her own mind keep her down. A woman who fought for what she loved and who raised him with the courage to do the same.</p>
<p>That&#8217;s the story I want to leave my son with. That&#8217;s the woman, the mother, that I want to be.</p>
<p>So the fight continues.</p>
<p><a href="http://dontforgettofeedthebaby.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/battle_of_barnet.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-1893" alt="Battle_of_barnet" src="http://dontforgettofeedthebaby.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/battle_of_barnet.jpg?w=243&#038;h=300" width="243" height="300" /></a></p>
<p><em>If you find yourself relating to me a little too closely, or you know someone who would, there&#8217;s lots of help available. Please don&#8217;t suffer in silence. Seek help. A basic Google search for &#8220;depression help&#8221; turns up an unbelievable <a href="http://www.google.com/#hl=en&amp;sugexp=les%3B&amp;gs_rn=5&amp;gs_ri=psy-ab&amp;cp=12&amp;gs_id=6b&amp;xhr=t&amp;q=depression+help&amp;es_nrs=true&amp;pf=p&amp;output=search&amp;sclient=psy-ab&amp;oq=depression+h&amp;gs_l=&amp;pbx=1&amp;bav=on.2,or.r_gc.r_pw.r_qf.&amp;bvm=bv.43148975,d.dmQ&amp;fp=e8eb7b2769946688&amp;biw=1920&amp;bih=1015" target="_blank">240,000,000 results</a>. You owe it to yourself, and even more importantly to your children, to get treatment.</em></p>
<p><strong><em>Let&#8217;s make sure that all our children have truly inspiring stories to tell of us.</em></strong></p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://dontforgettofeedthebaby.com/category/family/'>Family</a>, <a href='http://dontforgettofeedthebaby.com/category/mental-health-2/'>Mental Health</a>, <a href='http://dontforgettofeedthebaby.com/category/uncategorized/'>Uncategorized</a> Tagged: <a href='http://dontforgettofeedthebaby.com/tag/depression/'>depression</a>, <a href='http://dontforgettofeedthebaby.com/tag/mental-health/'>mental health</a>, <a href='http://dontforgettofeedthebaby.com/tag/parenting/'>parenting</a>, <a href='http://dontforgettofeedthebaby.com/tag/parenting-community/'>parenting community</a>, <a href='http://dontforgettofeedthebaby.com/tag/thems-fighting-words/'>them's fighting words</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1887/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1887/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1887&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://dontforgettofeedthebaby.com/2013/03/06/my-mind-is-my-battlefield/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>178</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/208729b6abd0e082589468c99eab2957?s=96&#38;d=monsterid&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">varyka</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dontforgettofeedthebaby.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/depressed-woman.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Photo courtesy of sxc.hu</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dontforgettofeedthebaby.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/baby-face_edited-1.jpg?w=500" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Baby face_edited-1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dontforgettofeedthebaby.files.wordpress.com/2013/03/battle_of_barnet.jpg?w=243" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Battle_of_barnet</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>When the Future Comes, What Are We All Going to Do With It?</title>
		<link>http://orkinpod.wordpress.com/2013/02/27/when-the-future-comes-what-are-we-all-going-to-do/</link>
		<comments>http://orkinpod.wordpress.com/2013/02/27/when-the-future-comes-what-are-we-all-going-to-do/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2013 03:19:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>orkinpod</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[the economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[What do I know?]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mechanization]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[neoliberalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[robotics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the future]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://orkinpod.wordpress.com/?p=58</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Last week I wrote about whether or not we really needed economic growth, and I claimed that the central problems facing our economy and our society were not about the size, scale, or growth of our economy, but rather about some deeper, undisclosed set of problems. This week I am trying, haphazardly and tentatively, to [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=58&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last <a href="http://orkinpod.wordpress.com/2013/02/20/do-we-need-economic-growth/">week</a> I wrote about whether or not we really needed economic growth, and I claimed that the central problems facing our economy and our society were not about the size, scale, or growth of our economy, but rather about some deeper, undisclosed set of problems. This week I am trying, haphazardly and tentatively, to work through what those problems might look like. Also to predict the future.</p>
<div id="attachment_59" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 333px"><a href="http://orkinpod.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/astounding-sf-sep-1952.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-59  " alt="For example, an economist looking at the big picture might ask why splitting the atom hasn't unlocked the key to our glorious communist future?" src="http://orkinpod.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/astounding-sf-sep-1952.jpg?w=323&#038;h=461" width="323" height="461" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">For example, an economist looking at the big picture might ask why splitting the atom hasn&#8217;t unlocked the key to our glorious communist future?</p></div>
<p>One of the things that bothers me about economics—both in its academic guise as a social science discipline and its neoliberal political guise as a quasi-religious faith in which bankers and CEOs serve as high priests—is its general failure to talk about what it’s <i>for.</i> Historians have a whole subfield, historiography, dedicated to how and why we write history. But because the economy is so self-evidently important to the fabric of our society, economists get a kind of pass. Economics is important because the economy is important. But what is the point of the economy, anyway? Is it possible to <i>not </i>have an economy? If the answer is no, than what is it about the concept of an “economy” that makes it an inevitable feature of human society? Why is the discipline of economics structured the way it is? Of course, those questions are scary because they lead to even harder questions about why the economy <i>itself</i> is structured the way it is.</p>
<p>I’m not saying I have answers to these questions. Still, it seems like economists, policy makers, and politicians love to fight over the <i>hows—</i>how does the economy run, how does it work, and the most specific whys: why this policy, why that policy—but are terrified to confront big picture questions: why is our economy arranged the way it is arranged, what is it accomplishing for who, and would we set it up that way again if we had to start over?</p>
<p>Even within the constrained context of neoliberal thought, economists, politicians, and business elites seem unwilling to ask even the most obvious of difficult questions. (Note: I define neoliberalism very broadly, and somewhat reflexively, as our society’s governing consensus with regard to global capital, sovereignty, and power-structures.)</p>
<p><span id="more-58"></span></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><b>In Which I Seem like I Will Get to the Point, but Don&#8217;t</b></p>
<div id="attachment_60" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 320px"><a href="http://orkinpod.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/science-fiction-cover-1934-granger.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-60 " alt="science-fiction-cover-1934-granger" src="http://orkinpod.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/science-fiction-cover-1934-granger.jpg?w=310&#038;h=448" width="310" height="448" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">One might go so far as to say that neoliberalism itself is <em>The Mightiest Machine!</em></p></div>
<p><span class="Apple-style-span" style="line-height:24px;font-size:16px;">This blog post is about the central problems facing Western style capitalism within the terms that neoliberalism has set for itself.  That means I’m disregarding global warming, which neoliberalism has sidelined, since it obviously has nothing to do with free trade or markets (with the exception of various weak-willed efforts to promote cap-and-trade, a market based solution to a problem that only a true ideologue would see as about markets.) Global warming is fundamentally not saleable, scalable, tradeable, or commodifiable—you can’t package and sell a disruption to the balance of nature any more than you can package and sell an earthquake. </span></p>
<p>I’m also not talking about structural violence or civil crisis such as mass-incarceration, colonialism, or the military industrial complex. These are all things that neoliberals have basically accepted as natural and inevitable features of the world, either due to a dramatic failure of imagination, or because they have a personal stake in those institutions and power structures.</p>
<p>Setting all of the violence and senselessness of modernity aside, what remains so hard to understand is why our nation’s elites, and the economists that serve as their high priests, refuse to confront what appears to me to be the central problem facing the global economy, even on their own narrow terms.</p>
<p align="center"><b>In Which I Start to Get to the Point, Finally</b></p>
<div id="attachment_65" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 210px"><a href="http://orkinpod.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/davidbrooks200.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-65 " alt="DavidBrooks200" src="http://orkinpod.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/davidbrooks200.jpg?w=200&#038;h=252" width="200" height="252" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">This is actually what I look like.</p></div>
<p>With all the panache of a young David Brooks, I have dubbed this problem the “making things” problem. What is the making things problem?  In the distant past, most people made a living by growing food.  This, after all, was what you needed to do if you wanted to wake up tomorrow morning and eat breakfast. Food production was centered around local communities, within which food and labor were generally distributed among neighbors and family members.</p>
<p>Mind you, I don’t mean to make this out as a perfect system, or some kind of pre-industrial paradise.  For one thing, there was no television, and I really like television. And because you relied on your immediate community for everything you needed, a natural disaster like a drought could do in your whole family. This was not some better, more natural way—it was just the basic, essential way that was. People grew food, interacted closely with the land, and relied on their immediate community for support when necessary.</p>
<p>Upon this model rested feudal systems, tribal systems, city states, proto-nation states, empires, religious hierarchies, trade caravans, social classes, gender roles, laws, and rules—goods were distributed all around the world (albeit very slowly). So I am not trying to say things were simple. But it was a very, very different kind of economy than what we got after the second industrial revolution.</p>
<p>What we got was a <i>making-things</i> economy. Farmers had become so productive that most people didn’t need to farm anymore. To a few people, it probably seemed stupid to farm when other farmers were making plenty of food. Most people, though, probably liked farming, or at least knew no other way. They stopped farming when other people decided it was stupid for them to be farming, and kicked them off their land (read: enclosure in England, read also: free trade agreements that make small-scale farming uneconomical for poor countries by insisting, in the name of “fairness,” that they trade on an equal footing with rich countries—which incidentally, became rich colonies by colonizing the poor countries oh…less than a century ago, but I’m not even going to go there).</p>
<p>Anyways, the economy we created was one in which people made shit. In exchange for making shit, citizens of wealthy countries got food, shelter, recreation, and healthcare (money made this trade easier, but it was not what they were getting, nor what they needed—it was and remains no more than the highly useful medium of exchange standing between ten hours in a factory and dinner on the table at the end of ten hours in a factory.)</p>
<p>Building the economy around making shit made sense, because a) we got more shit, and god knows people love their plastic crap, b) it came mixed in with modern education, sanitation, electricity, healthcare, and participatory democracy in a bundle of changes which almost certainly could not have been unbundled, and c) every (white, male, able) body who was willing to work their asses off got a half-way decent life for themselves, or at least their children—at least after they fought for said privilege and organized themselves into unions.</p>
<div id="attachment_61" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 352px"><a href="http://orkinpod.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/tops_in_science_fiction_1953spr_v1_n1.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-61  " alt="" src="http://orkinpod.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/tops_in_science_fiction_1953spr_v1_n1.jpg?w=342&#038;h=503" width="342" height="503" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Obviously, I&#8217;m referring to those science fiction writers who weren&#8217;t busy imagining the richly literary encounters between buxom ladies and tentacled space worms&#8230;</p></div>
<p>But now, something fundamental is changing. The science fiction writers of the mid 20<sup>th</sup> century predicted this change. In fact, many believed it was eminent. Perhaps, in a sad twist of fate, this is one reason it is so neglected by more “serious” people now. In 2013, we don’t really need <i>people </i>to make shit anymore, because we have robots that can make shit.</p>
<p>A lot of liberals and neoliberals and people in general don’t see this happening—what they think has happened is that manufacturing has moved overseas because of free trade agreements and globalization. And that <i>has </i>happened, and it wasn’t inevitable, and it wasn’t necessarily a good idea. But so far as I can tell, this overseas shift of manufacturing from places like Michigan to places like Bangladesh is a sort of giant global-history <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Macguffin">MacGuffin</a>.</p>
<p>It’s true that workers who don’t have rights, fair wages, environmental restrictions providing them with clean water and air, modern economies providing them with access to credit, and decent housing and healthcare, can make a T-shirt (or an iphone) a hell of a lot cheaper than a North American can. But people seem to believe that manufacturing will work in these countries the same way it worked in the United States—worker’s rights will improve, things will get better, the country will develop, wealth will be generated, and the third world will eventually rise to be like the first world, while the first world will by then be far ahead due to its mysterious “knowledge-based” economy.<i></i></p>
<p>I don’t think it will work that way. Cheap labor in poor countries under miserable conditions may be cheaper than hiring American workers. It may also be cheaper than robots and total mechanization. But, as the mechanization and modernization of manufacturing in America has demonstrated, manufacturing will never again lead to good jobs under a free market system, because only by mistreating workers can humans compete with machines. When the workers get restless, as they have at Foxconn, to take one example, corporations will not only improve conditions (as Foxconn may or may not be doing)—they will also make plans to replace most of their human employees with humanoid robots (as Foxconn is <a href="http://www.theverge.com/2012/12/11/3753856/foxconn-shenzhen-factory-automation-manufacturing-US-expansion">definitely</a> doing.)</p>
<p>To me, this begs a rather large question—the one that everybody is ignoring. When the future arrives (and I believe that it is very, very close), and machines can supply all the <i>things </i>that humans could possibly ever want, what is everybody going to<i> do?  </i></p>
<p>Mechanization does not have to be a curse. The coming robot revolution, and I truly believe it will be a robot revolution in something very close to the 1950s pulp-fiction sense, should be a blessing. It should mean wealth, leisure, freedom, and dignity for ever more human beings—eventually all human beings.  It should free us to pursue the things we truly love, like art, like love, like family, in place of the things we tolerate, like working in factories and office towers. This is the question that I see glaring back at me when I try to think about the problems facing our economy taken on it’s own terms—discounting humanitarianism, ecology, and structural violence—just money, trade, and straightforward metrics, just like the neoliberals like it.</p>
<p>I wonder whether or not we need leaders and thinkers who can figure out a long term plan for the future, and who have the courage to start implementing it. This is what the corporations, futurists, and government workers who spent the Great Depression <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Futurama_(New_York_World%27s_Fair)">planning in detail</a> for the highways, suburbs, and consumer goods they were going to start making in the post-war era did. Or do we need some kind of grass-roots response? An insurrection, or a movement?</p>
<div id="attachment_62" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 326px"><a href="http://orkinpod.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/if-science-fiction-magazine-1953-cover.jpg"><img class="wp-image-62 " alt="if-science-fiction-magazine-1953-cover" src="http://orkinpod.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/if-science-fiction-magazine-1953-cover.jpg?w=316&#038;h=448" width="316" height="448" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">This is an astoundingly literal depiction of the future I imagine in the last paragraph.</p></div>
<p>Our generation is not going to look like the Baby Boomer generation part 2—that ship has already sailed. And I doubt that it will be a future in which steady technological advance provides jobs enough for all—we can’t all design the next iPhone, although in the 20<sup>th</sup>-century-model economy we might have all helped to build them. Maybe the future will include tariff barriers that help people stick with the jobs they have now while the world figures out what’s coming next, rather than throwing millions of peoples into slums in the name of “globalization” and capitalist progress—but I’m not counting on it.</p>
<p>And maybe the robot revolution will mean that people, secure in their computer and machine-supported ability to have all the cool shit they can imagine, will go back to farming and crafts work and other traditional human occupations—not because they have to, but because they want to?</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/58/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/58/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=58&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://orkinpod.wordpress.com/2013/02/27/when-the-future-comes-what-are-we-all-going-to-do/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>28</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/15502c832808271a3cc0e454a5424d4f?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">orkinpod</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://orkinpod.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/astounding-sf-sep-1952.jpg?w=449" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">For example, an economist looking at the big picture might ask why splitting the atom hasn&#039;t unlocked the key to our glorious communist future?</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://orkinpod.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/science-fiction-cover-1934-granger.jpg?w=443" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">science-fiction-cover-1934-granger</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://orkinpod.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/davidbrooks200.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DavidBrooks200</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://orkinpod.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/tops_in_science_fiction_1953spr_v1_n1.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://orkinpod.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/if-science-fiction-magazine-1953-cover.jpg?w=452" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">if-science-fiction-magazine-1953-cover</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
