<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2012 21:02:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>The Funnies: They Just Keep Coming Back&#8230;and They Never Stop</title>
		<link>http://matthewkirshenblatt.wordpress.com/2012/12/13/the-funnies-they-just-keep-coming-back-and-they-never-stop/</link>
		<comments>http://matthewkirshenblatt.wordpress.com/2012/12/13/the-funnies-they-just-keep-coming-back-and-they-never-stop/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2012 07:44:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>matthewkirshenblatt</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Comics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Geek Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cartoons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creativity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[philosophy]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://matthewkirshenblatt.wordpress.com/?p=1384</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A cartoon is not a frivolous thing. It can look like a silly drawing or a caricature of life. Upon first glance, it seems to only exist on either a screen or a piece of paper. Sometimes, it even says witty things or does something stupid or endearing that can make us laugh. Cartoons have [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1384&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A cartoon is not a frivolous thing. It can look like a silly drawing or a caricature of life. Upon first glance, it seems to only exist on either a screen or a piece of paper. Sometimes, it even says witty things or does something stupid or endearing that can make us laugh.</p>
<p>Cartoons have been around for so long&#8211;on television, in movies, in the newspaper funny-pages and even on T-shirts&#8211;that we take them for granted. We don&#8217;t always take them seriously.</p>
<p>But consider. A cartoon is an archetype. It is an idea given form. In fact, it wouldn&#8217;t be too much of a stretch to even state that it is a Platonic Form: living glyphs essentialized to the point of becoming as close to pure concepts as is humanly possible &#8230; which of course is a misnomer.</p>
<p>Because cartoons aren&#8217;t human at all.</p>
<p>Some of them are wise-talking humanoid animals. Others are parodies of human beings that somehow possess their own sense of agency. There are even some that are inanimate objects given life. Often, the really old cartoons exist in very self-contained two-dimensional pocket-dimensions: in a mythological cycle of trickery, mayhem, and fun-loving nose-thumbing at fate.</p>
<p>And the really old cartoons can&#8217;t be destroyed. They can&#8217;t be smashed by falling anvils or mallets. They can&#8217;t be burned by fire or exploded by dynamite: at least, not for very long. They are used to dealing&#8211;and receiving&#8211;massive amounts of physical damage, and then coming back for more. And we&#8217;re not even talking about the ones that have a supernatural way of avoiding the damages of their enemies altogether just to&#8211;through some twisted fluke of fate&#8211;make them fall into their own traps.</p>
<p>They are like living rubber or silly-putty that just keeps bouncing back. A human being isn&#8217;t like that. When human beings fall, they break.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not too much of a stretch to say that cartoons are beings that are psychopaths or sociopaths by human standards: in worlds and cyclic realities where neither human physical and psychological standards even apply. They come from the same heightened mythic state as faeries, and gods; as legends and archetypes: in a place where slap-stick is not only futility and invincibility, but where the ridiculousness is the superhuman and the sublime. Some people might call this state a perpetual hell, or a utopia. But mostly, it just <em>is </em>and they just<em> are</em>.</p>
<p>In the end, you can&#8217;t destroy a cartoon because you can&#8217;t destroy an idea. Because even if you break the projector, or the television, or snap the DVD, or rip up the papers they are still there&#8211;pure ideas&#8211;in your head, mocking you, holding an oversized mallet in one hand as they stand in the darkest corner of your mind, knowing more than they do, doing more than they know, just waiting for that punchline: where you finally have to laugh at yourself.</p>
<p><img id="il_fi" alt="" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_mJ4lc_Q9Q6k/R7ove0osXRI/AAAAAAAAMXE/HWsvlo0i-N0/s320/WashamBugs6.jpg" width="320" height="298" /></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1384/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1384/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1384&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://matthewkirshenblatt.wordpress.com/2012/12/13/the-funnies-they-just-keep-coming-back-and-they-never-stop/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/4b38905cbbe0927a193d379f1e0f1827?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">matthewkirshenblatt</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_mJ4lc_Q9Q6k/R7ove0osXRI/AAAAAAAAMXE/HWsvlo0i-N0/s320/WashamBugs6.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Stitch by Stitch</title>
		<link>http://postsem.wordpress.com/2012/12/17/stitch-by-stitch/</link>
		<comments>http://postsem.wordpress.com/2012/12/17/stitch-by-stitch/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 06:32:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Alison</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grief]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meaning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[newtown]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sandy hook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tragedy]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://postsem.wordpress.com/?p=1101</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Five years ago, in the first winter of our relationship, I knit my lover a pair of mittens. They were perfect. I bought the wool, hand-spun, from a vendor at our Farmer’s Market on Broadway in New York City. It was a blustery October day, and I bought more of that grey yarn than I [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1101&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Five years ago, in the first winter of our relationship, I knit my lover a pair of mittens.</p>
<p>They were perfect.</p>
<p>I bought the wool, hand-spun, from a vendor at our Farmer’s Market on Broadway in New York City. It was a blustery October day, and I bought more of that grey yarn than I needed. And so began the meticulous process of crafting something for the one you love: Edging the gloves with a simple ribbing, two by two. Making them fingerless, with a top that flipped down. Fastening on antique leather buttons. Inside one of the flaps, I sewed a tag, upon which was neatly printed, “Handmade by Alison J. Killeen.”</p>
<p>He loved them, and even better, he <i>used</i> them. Over the years, predictably, they began to wear. The neat little slit in the thumbs, meant for texting and for pulling out his metro card, was the first to go. And so I unraveled the tops of the thumbs and re-knit them, reinforcing them with a stronger thread. But it was an impermanent solution. The palms wore thin, first from grasping at railings on the train, and later, the steering wheel of the car. Moths munched on their edges while they sat idle in summer. Last winter, they found their final days as the thumb slits tore again and unraveled before I took care to mend them, my lover’s triangle-tipped thumbs exposed to the cold.</p>
<p>This fall, five years later, using what was left of the hardy grey wool, I knit him a second pair of mittens, almost identical to the first. Perhaps it was sentimental, but before we discarded them, we held a little ritual for the first pair in our kitchen. I held the mittens in my hands, and my lover held my hands in his. Together, we spoke of the warmth they had provided to the wearer, of what objects they had held between their palms, of all the coffee spills they had endured. As we examined the wear and tear the years had brought to these woolen miracles, they began to whisper of all that has lapsed since we first found one another.</p>
<p>It seems to me that time passes so illegibly. Despite our best attempts to keep things just as they are, in the end, we are helpless to the powers of the universe: to gravity, to change, to chaos, to love.</p>
<p>Most years in November I settle in for the long winter, reveling in my double-pointed needles and indigo-blue dusks. I cut the nights with candlelight, quell the snow with stardust, calm the cold with steaming hot tea.</p>
<p>But this year has been different. This year not only have the nights been long, but my heart is long as well, stretched low as an anchor grazing the bottom of the sea. For whatever reason, though no one close to me has been in danger, I am feeling the losses around me more keenly. A friend’s husband dies, then another, and another. Yet another friend’s mother is slowly losing her battle with cancer. A loved one struggles with addiction. Relationships around me disintegrate and break. And the dark blue night thickens, exposing a bruised and ashen world.</p>
<div id="attachment_1102" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 600px"><a href="http://www.nytimes.com/imagepages/2012/12/15/nyregion/15shooting2.html"><img class="size-full wp-image-1102" alt="15shooting" src="http://postsem.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/15shooting.jpg?w=590&#038;h=359" width="590" height="359" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">via New York Times</p></div>
<p>Then last Friday, in Newtown, Connecticut, a gunman overtook sweet Sandy Hook Elementary School, and like the rest of the country I am blindsided. I am struck dumb by the absence of mercy, by the presence of carnage, by the hot iron of an expired rifle, the tiny bodies riddled with bullets, the silence and the sobs, the blood, the innocence, the flesh, the grief.</p>
<p>Time trods on. The night expands. A star moves across the deep. Our hearts break, our worlds implode, and we are left to ask: what will come of this?</p>
<p>Part of the pain of tragedy is the need we humans have to seek out the meaning in suffering. As one who finds little existential comfort in “eternal life”, I look for a way to make meaning of what is happening in the here and the now. Even a father who believes his child will live on in paradise might not be comforted by his belief. The child is still gone, and he is still left to sift through what to make of a world in which 20-year-old men kill six-year-old girls, and nineteen other children, besides.</p>
<p>In the face of such tragedy, even hope at times is too much to ask. It is too much to petition grief to turn about so sharply, to reverse the path of mourning, to wait for hope, to hope for life.</p>
<p>No, I want mending of a more earthly kind. As a knitter darns a tear, as a physician sutures a wound, so must we go about the process of grief. Slowly and methodically we go, taking care to don the thimble and pin the fabric. Perhaps we set down our work for a time and come back another day. Perhaps we rip it out and start again. We work, knowing our piece will never be as whole as it was when it was new. We work, knowing that it will be prone to tearing again, even in the same spot in which we mend. But the thread and needle must keep working, ever tenderly, slowly onwards, if our hearts are ever to beat again.</p>
<p>The deepest, bluest night of the year is but days away. With the winter solstice will come the shifting of our planet’s tilt, a change so incremental we will hardly notice it, but it will be massive in its power. Such a tiny step lengthens the day by mere minutes, but it has the power to alter the seasons, to melt ice and ignite fire, turn branch to leaf, seed to sprout. Yes, we will hardly notice it. But its shift will lay the groundwork for our whole world to change.</p>
<p>I don’t know how the parents and children of Newtown will fare in the coming days and years, and what awaits our country in the coming months is yet to be seen. What I do know is that our first task must be to tend to our grief, for by threading the needle, by tilting a twirling planet, we act out our trust that hope will return to us one day. Perhaps hope is found just in putting down that very first stitch.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1101/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1101/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1101&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://postsem.wordpress.com/2012/12/17/stitch-by-stitch/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/24670014d3e273fd576c8eae4e6a9aa7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Alison Killeen</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://postsem.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/15shooting.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">15shooting</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bard to the Future</title>
		<link>http://tombrownbooks.wordpress.com/2012/12/17/bard-to-the-future/</link>
		<comments>http://tombrownbooks.wordpress.com/2012/12/17/bard-to-the-future/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 11:48:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Tom Brown</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Authorship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[My books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[So Long, Shakespeare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creativity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[david cope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[david reid]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DNA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[futurology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[genetics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[So Long Shakespeare]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://tombrownbooks.wordpress.com/?p=662</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[One of the weird things about writing a novel set in the near-future was watching real life catch up with the imagined world of my story. It&#8217;s probably not a problem for more outlandish visions, but since So Long, Shakespeare depicts a future just one or two steps advanced from where we are now, there [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=662&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One of the weird things about writing a novel set in the near-future was watching real life catch up with the imagined world of my story. It&#8217;s probably not a problem for more outlandish visions, but since <a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/So-Long-Shakespeare-ebook/dp/B00A262MPS/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1355738913&amp;sr=8-1" target="_blank">So Long, Shakespeare</a> depicts a future just one or two steps advanced from where we are now, there was always a slight fear that reality might overtake fiction if I didn&#8217;t get a move on.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-685" title="Bard to the future" alt="" src="http://tombrownbooks.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/shakespearebttfsepia1.jpg?w=590"   /></p>
<p>The two most susceptible strands of my plot related to the discovery that artistic creativity is a genetic absolute. As yet, of course, there is nothing but <a href="http://hplusmagazine.com/2012/06/12/the-essential-psychopathology-of-creativity/" target="_blank">speculation as to the possibility of this</a>, or indeed its potential implications. In my novel, however, the discovery happens pretty much at the start, before being dramatically addressed in two ways. There&#8217;s the mathematical angle, whereby a stubborn Stratfordian accidentally uncovers the numerical manifestation of the creative gene at work &#8211; a constant which occurs throughout every writer&#8217;s <em>oeuvre</em>, which he dubs the &#8216;Muse Ratio&#8217;. And then there&#8217;s the more direct approach, whereby an acclaimed geneticist not only discovers the creative gene but deduces how to transfer it from one human being to another.</p>
<p>In the end, by treating the &#8216;creative gene&#8217; as a given, I created a firewall which prevented any present-day developments from overlapping too closely with the events of my book. Instead, those news stories which did resonate &#8211; for example <a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/uknews/6302847/William-Shakespeare-wrote-anonymously-published-play-expert-claims.html" target="_blank">Brian Vickers&#8217; 2009 Pl@giarism analysis on the likely authorship of Edward III</a> &#8211; spurred me on. A degree of realism, after all, was exactly what I was aiming for; as long as it didn&#8217;t make my central premise redundant, I was more than happy to embrace it.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.welcometoneko.com/2012/02/mattel-back-to-future-hoverboard.html" target="_blank"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-666" title="Mattel's new hoverboard replica" alt="" src="http://tombrownbooks.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/backtothefuturehoverboard1.jpg?w=590"   /></a>Now the book is out in the big wide world, I can relax at last. Henceforward, whatever truths are discovered about the nature of creativity need not concern me. My story is of its time. Even if its predictions are shown to be way off the mark, it will still have merit as a historical artefact, to be filed alongside <a href="http://gizmodo.com/5967983/the-back-to-the-future-hoverboard-is-2012s-worst-toy" target="_blank">hoverboards</a> and <a href="http://terminator.wikia.com/wiki/Judgment_Day" target="_blank">Judgement Day</a> as remnants of imagined futures that never came to pass.</p>
<p>All of which is a roundabout way of saying I no longer experience that creeping dread when a news story touches on ideas explored in my novel. Quite the contrary. When yesterday I heard of David Reid&#8217;s report on the BBC&#8217;s &#8216;Click&#8217; programme about <a href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/programmes/click_online/9777655.stm" target="_blank">computer programmes that replicate the styles, and arguably even souls, of great artists</a>, I was only too happy to track down the <a href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/programmes/click_online/9777655.stm" target="_blank">link</a>, take a look for myself, and simply savour the possibilities of what it had to say.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/662/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/662/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=662&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://tombrownbooks.wordpress.com/2012/12/17/bard-to-the-future/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/5e1295ef38ad0abbdce71207129b0b73?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">tom1978</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tombrownbooks.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/shakespearebttfsepia1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Bard to the future</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://tombrownbooks.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/backtothefuturehoverboard1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Mattel&#039;s new hoverboard replica</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Harm Reduction</title>
		<link>http://dontdoitalone.wordpress.com/2012/12/14/harm-reductionself-love/</link>
		<comments>http://dontdoitalone.wordpress.com/2012/12/14/harm-reductionself-love/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2012 04:05:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>the mitz</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Don't give up]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Self-care]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[don't give up]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self-care]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dontdoitalone.wordpress.com/?p=2</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I learned this from a wise, older woman many, many years ago. I have changed it many times since then.  5 years ago, the woman who thought of this was left by her wife. After 30 years together, her wife just got up and left. She had fallen in love with someone else. I hope [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I learned this from a wise, older woman many, many years ago. I have changed it many times since then.  5 years ago, the woman who thought of this was left by her wife. After 30 years together, her wife just got up and left. She had fallen in love with someone else. I hope that her list came back to her and she did what she could do to get through.</p>
<p>This is an assignment.  For the days when you don’t want to face the world and don’t think you can get out of bed.   But do it now. That way it’s already ready for you when things feel too hard.</p>
<p>You make a list. The list is of the most loving thing to the least loving thing you can do for yourself.  (Least harmful to most harmful).  When it feels too hard, you go down your list and try to do the most loving thing you can.  If the first thing on the list is too hard to do, just go down until you feel willing. That way, if you are like me, you can interrupt it before you get to the destruction. I just keep going down the list until I feel I can hang on until tomorrow. I used to go to the destruction first.  It feels better to start at the top.</p>
<p>You have to make your own list. No one else can make it for you.</p>
<p><strong>MY LIST </strong></p>
<p>Call a trusted friend and say everything.</p>
<p>Take a bath.</p>
<p>Breath.</p>
<p>Pray.</p>
<p>Ask myself what I need and try to take care of it.</p>
<p>Write in my journal.</p>
<p>Write a gratitude list.</p>
<p>Hug my son.</p>
<p>Eat a meal.</p>
<p>Drink water.</p>
<p>Cry.</p>
<p>Hug myself.</p>
<p>Remind myself that I am ok.</p>
<p>Read an inspirational book.</p>
<p>Go outside, Leave the house!</p>
<p>Go to the grocery store and talk to the clerk.</p>
<p>Drink five cups of coffee.</p>
<p>Drive really fast in the car, with the windows down and the music blaring.</p>
<p>Lay on the floor and cry and say &#8220;NOOOOO, It&#8217;s too hard!&#8221;</p>
<p>Make a batch of raw cookie dough and eat it.</p>
<p>Obsess about other people and their lives.</p>
<p>Check out and fantasize.</p>
<p>Stay in bed.</p>
<p>Stay in bed all day and watch an entire tv series.</p>
<p>Stay in bed all day, watch an entire tv series and eat a bag of semi-sweet chocolate chips.</p>
<p>Eat a bag of Lays bbq chips.</p>
<p>Call a therapist.</p>
<p>Refuse to eat or get dressed.</p>
<p>Pull the covers over my head and wait til tomorrow.</p>
<p>Start a fight with someone I love.</p>
<p>Try to end a relationship. Or a few.</p>
<p>Decide to pack up and leave my life, give up, move on.</p>
<p>Smoke a pack of cigarettes.</p>
<p>Get wasted.</p>
<p>Cut myself.</p>
<p>Find an anonymous person to have sex with.</p>
<p>Kill myself.</p>
<p>This is not to make you sad. It is actually to save yourself.</p>
<p>Some days the best thing you can do is hunker down and try not to hurt yourself or others.</p>
<p>Another woman in my life says it’s the days when we are not fit for human consumption that we have to practice extra care. Some days are like that. When I wake up and it feels too hard to be in the world or to be in my skin anymore. This happens to me once a month sometimes. Those are the days I remember my list. I start at the top.  I have not had to go to the bottom in a long time.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://dontdoitalone.wordpress.com/2012/12/14/harm-reductionself-love/mitzhands/#main" rel="attachment wp-att-33"><img class="alignnone size-thumbnail wp-image-33" alt="mitzhands" src="http://dontdoitalone.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/mitzhands.jpg?w=150&#038;h=147" width="150" height="147" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://dontdoitalone.wordpress.com/2012/12/14/harm-reductionself-love/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>21</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/70e1779fbff3b7aa6e9747e280d0cd8b?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mitzyking</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dontdoitalone.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/mitzhands.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mitzhands</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Disappointment in Doha</title>
		<link>http://chrisriedy.me/2012/12/14/disappointment-in-doha/</link>
		<comments>http://chrisriedy.me/2012/12/14/disappointment-in-doha/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2012 22:38:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>criedy</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reflection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[climate change]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[climate politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[doha]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[unfccc]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://chrisriedy.me/?p=2950</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Nobody expected much from the recent United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC) negotiations in Doha. And they appeared to have met those expectations by delivering, well, not much. The Conference of the Parties to the UNFCCC happens in December each year and sometimes these international negotiations can feel like a bad case of [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2950&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nobody expected much from the recent United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC) negotiations in Doha. And they appeared to have met those expectations by delivering, well, not much.</p>
<div id="attachment_2961" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 635px"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/90595710@N06/8249410946/sizes/k/in/pool-2099396@N24/"><img class="size-full wp-image-2961" alt="The UNFCCC negotiations in Doha, Qatar. Photo: Alexander Vlad." src="http://chrisriedy.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/dohacop18.jpeg?w=590"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The UNFCCC negotiations in Doha, Qatar. Photo: Alexander Vlad.</p></div>
<p>The Conference of the Parties to the UNFCCC happens in December each year and sometimes these international negotiations can feel like a bad case of deja vu. Nations from around the world come together and argue, there are conflicts between rich and poor nations over ambition and financing that remain unresolved, negotiators stay up all night and manage to pull a few small steps forward out of the bag, and those who care about climate action hail those small steps forward while decrying the failure to deliver the ambitious response that is needed. There is lots of noise and discussion but the ultimate goal of avoiding dangerous climate change continues to seem very distant.</p>
<p>The 18th Conference of the Parties (COP-18) took place in Doha, Qatar. Doha always struck me as a particularly unlikely place to achieve any sort of breakthrough on climate change. I spent two weeks there in 1999 and they were two of the worst weeks of my life. I was in the middle of a world backpacking adventure, but my funds were running low, so I took up some work with an environmental consulting firm in London. They sent me to Doha to work on developing a waste management plan for a natural gas processing facility. I arrived in what felt like hell on Earth.</p>
<p>The heat was terrible &#8211; maximums above 40 degrees Celsius most days. The gas processing plant was one of many human blights on what was already a desolate desert landscape. I was put up in luxurious &#8216;fly in, fly out&#8217; accommodation but felt completely disconnected from the local culture and from the predominantly Indian workforce that did all the hard labour on the plant. The place was full of Westerners out to make a buck as quick as they could by pumping out whatever fossil fuel they could find.</p>
<p>I felt guilty that my work was legitimising the extraction and burning of fossil fuels and contributing to climate change. I felt ashamed that I was living in air-conditioned luxury while migrant workers did hard labour in blistering heat. It became a pivotal moment in my life, where I decided to dedicate my career to work on sustainability. I wanted to stop the expansion of the fossil fuel industry and work for social justice. When I got back to London, I quit my job and began to make my way home, earlier than planned, to start a <a href="http://chrisriedy.me/2009/08/04/my-book-the-eye-of-the-storm/">PhD</a> at the <a href="http://www.isf.uts.edu.au">Institute for Sustainable Futures</a> on what Australia could to respond to climate change. I&#8217;ve been working there ever since.</p>
<p>When I heard that COP-18 would be held in Doha, my thoughts immediately turned to this experience. I thought about the vast sums of fossil fuel money pouring into Qatar. I thought about the crazy plans to air-condition the stadiums being built for the FIFA World Cup in Qatar in 2022, and the crazy amounts of energy that would require. And I mentally filed away COP-18 as another lost opportunity for international climate action.</p>
<p>So, what was actually achieved? There was an agreement to a Second Commitment Period under the Kyoto Protocol, running from 2013 to 2020. Although the Kyoto Protocol includes only a subset of the rich nations and will do little to dent growth in emissions, the agreement is important for ensuring continuity of accounting systems and the Clean Development Mechanism. Australia&#8217;s target of reducing emissions by 5% between 2000 and 2020 is now part of the Kyoto Protocol and there is scope to revisit the target in 2014 and hopefully increase its ambition.</p>
<p>Other processes were also established to increase the ambition of targets pledged by all countries. The Secretary-General of the UN will convene a meeting of world leaders on climate change in 2014 to focus specifically on this question.</p>
<p>There was less progress on other important items. At COP-17 in Durban in 2011, nations agreed to a timeline in which a new legally binding agreement on climate change would be established by 2015, to come into force in 2020. The difficult negotiations over what different countries will commit to as part of this agreement were left for future meetings.</p>
<p>There was also no agreement on how to implement commitments from wealthy nations to provide financing to help poorer nations to respond to climate change. Wealthy nations have pledged to secure $100 billion a year by 2020 in public and private financing to help poor countries cope with climate change, but have been vague about what they plan to do before then, according to <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2012/12/09/science/earth/talks-on-climate-produce-promises-and-complaints.html?ref=johnmbroder&amp;_r=3&amp;utm_source=Climate+Access+Newsletter&amp;utm_campaign=22ef130352-Weekly_Update_12_12_1212_12_2012&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;"><em>The New York Times</em></a>.</p>
<p>If you would like to read more about the detail of what was agreed in Doha, I would recommend the excellent analysis by the Climate Institute at its <a href="http://www.climateinstitute.org.au/news/cop18.html">COP18 mini site</a>.</p>
<p>The last few weeks delivered lots of bad news on climate change. The Global Carbon Project released its <a href="http://www.globalcarbonproject.org/carbonbudget/">Global Carbon Budget 2012</a>, showing that global emissions are continuing to grow. A <a href="http://www.unep.org/pdf/permafrost.pdf">report by the United Nations Environment Programme</a> warned that permafrost is beginning to melt, potentially triggering feedback loops that could lead to runaway climate change. It seems that every week brings more warnings from climate scientists. Yet the negotiations in Doha seem completely out of sync with these urgent warnings. I can only hope that the urgency will ramp up again as the deadline for a new legal agreement in 2015 approaches.</p>
<p>In the meantime, I find hope in the action that I see on the ground from governments, businesses and communities around the world who aren&#8217;t waiting around for an international agreement. Climate action doesn&#8217;t have to wait for the United Nations to agree, and it looks like we can&#8217;t afford to wait.</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://chrisriedy.me/category/articles/'>Articles</a>, <a href='http://chrisriedy.me/category/reflection/'>Reflection</a> Tagged: <a href='http://chrisriedy.me/tag/climate-change/'>climate change</a>, <a href='http://chrisriedy.me/tag/climate-politics/'>climate politics</a>, <a href='http://chrisriedy.me/tag/doha/'>doha</a>, <a href='http://chrisriedy.me/tag/unfccc/'>unfccc</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2950/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2950/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2950&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://chrisriedy.me/2012/12/14/disappointment-in-doha/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		<georss:point>-33.868901 151.207091</georss:point>
		<geo:lat>-33.868901</geo:lat>
		<geo:long>151.207091</geo:long>
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/44580aaadf5b85104588cdaf609447ff?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">criedy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://chrisriedy.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/dohacop18.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The UNFCCC negotiations in Doha, Qatar. Photo: Alexander Vlad.</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>I Breathe In, I Breathe Out</title>
		<link>http://ellyndoesyoga.wordpress.com/2012/12/13/i-breathe-in-i-breathe-out/</link>
		<comments>http://ellyndoesyoga.wordpress.com/2012/12/13/i-breathe-in-i-breathe-out/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2012 17:29:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>ellyn0991</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dexter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mental-health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[presence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yoga]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ellyndoesyoga.wordpress.com/?p=24</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Just a few minutes ago, I reached for my untouched cup of coffee to take a sip.  It was empty.  I started blankly into its depths, thinking, when did that happen? I drank the whole cup without knowing it, sipping it idly while doing—what had I been doing?  I couldn’t really recall that either.  I’d [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=24&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Just a few minutes ago, I reached for my untouched cup of coffee to take a sip.  It was empty.  I started blankly into its depths, thinking, <i>when did that happen?</i></p>
<p>I drank the whole cup without knowing it, sipping it idly while doing—what <i>had</i> I been doing?  I couldn’t really recall that either.  I’d been on my computer, doing <i>something</i>&#8230;I strained to remember the flavor of a single sip of the coffee, but it was gone.</p>
<p>This reminded me of a question posed at a yoga training earlier this year:</p>
<blockquote><p>How much time do you spend thinking about…</p>
<ul>
<li>What has happened</li>
<li>What is happening</li>
<li>What will happen</li>
</ul>
<p><strong><span style="font-size:medium;"><span style="line-height:24px;">???</span></span></strong></p></blockquote>
<p>For me, the outside choices greatly outweigh the central.  I flush with embarrassment over a stupid decision made five years ago; my stomach hurts as I worry about what could happen tomorrow.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, I drink a cup of coffee without realizing it.</p>
<p>I’m not saying it isn’t important to think about things outside of <i>right now</i>, but do we really have to think about the past and future <i>so much</i>, when doing so causes us to lose sight of the present?  It’s absurd, when you think about it: the <i>minority </i>of our (at least, of my) time is spent thinking about what I’m actually doing at the moment.  Everything else is devoted to things I have no control over—what’s already happened; or things I have very little control over—what’s not yet happened.</p>
<p>Over the years, I’ve gotten better at “practicing presence” on my yoga mat, but it’s still a challenge.  Moving through Sun B’s, I find myself wondering what I’m going to make for dinner, remembering I need to buy toilet paper.  Breathing in savasana, I realize I’m thinking about what happened last week on <i>Dexter </i>(and that’s rarely relaxing).</p>
<p>Per the suggestion of one of my instructors, lately in class I have been repeating to myself, <i>I breathe in, I breathe out</i>. Over and over.  <i>I breathe in, I breathe out.</i>  Sometimes, this leads to thought patterns like:</p>
<blockquote><p>I breathe in, I breathe out.  I breathe in, I breathe ou—oh, look at that girl, her stomach is so flat, and she has such beautiful back muscles, I should start weight training I don’t know how though, last time I did was in college, wow that was a while ago, I wonder whatever happened to that girl I used to see at the gym, what was her name, I wonder if she’s still with that guy, I should repaint my nails,</p></blockquote>
<p>And so on.</p>
<p>Some days, I think it’s getting easier.  Other days, I sit up from savasana and think, <i>it’s over?  Where did those 75 minutes go?</i></p>
<p>But I keep going back to this mantra, class after class: <i>I breathe in, I breathe out.</i></p>
<p>And slowly, I’ve started to carry this mindset outside the yoga room, doing <i>one thing at a time</i>.</p>
<p>I work at a juice bar, which means lots of repetitive work.  I do the same series of tasks every day.  It’s a great exercise for presence.  Washing one apple at a time, I try to notice the smoothness of its skin, the temperature of the running water.   Instead of being frustrated by the repetition, I try to appreciate it.  <i>I breathe in, I breathe out</i>.</p>
<p>Of course, the operative phrase is <em>I try</em>. There are still days when freshly washed apples rain down on my head from the shelf above, days when I think if I have to wash one more carrot, I will go on a carrot-killing spree, days when <i>I just don’t want to take the time to be present.</i></p>
<p>Because that’s the thing—presence requires time.  Presence means slowing down.  Is there anything in this world we have less control over than the passage of time?  For control freaks like me, this is a huge part of the challenge.  We are always looking ahead, wanting to know what’s coming and to get there as soon as possible just so we can move on to planning the next thing.  Being present requires letting go, accepting what you can control and admitting what you can’t.</p>
<p>And so I continue: <i>I breathe in, I breathe out.</i></p>
<div id="attachment_30" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://ellyndoesyoga.wordpress.com/2012/12/13/i-breathe-in-i-breathe-out/photo-on-12-14-12-at-11-35-am-2/" rel="attachment wp-att-30"><img class="size-medium wp-image-30" alt="Especially challenging when its Christmastime and there's a cat chewing on your fingers." src="http://ellyndoesyoga.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/photo-on-12-14-12-at-11-35-am-2.jpg?w=300&#038;h=222" width="300" height="222" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Especially challenging when its Christmastime and there&#8217;s a cat chewing on your fingers.</p></div>
<p><em>This is part one of a two-part post.  Look for the exciting conclusion next week!</em></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/24/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/24/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=24&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://ellyndoesyoga.wordpress.com/2012/12/13/i-breathe-in-i-breathe-out/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/6f28978f85c53931aca77ad5c8afacf8?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ellyn0991</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ellyndoesyoga.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/photo-on-12-14-12-at-11-35-am-2.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Especially challenging when its Christmastime and there&#039;s a cat chewing on your fingers.</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Reading the Unexpected</title>
		<link>http://callumjhackett.com/2012/12/14/reading-the-unexpected/</link>
		<comments>http://callumjhackett.com/2012/12/14/reading-the-unexpected/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2012 01:22:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Callum J Hackett</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google+]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[journalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[news]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social networks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[W. H. Auden]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://callumjhackett.com/?p=674</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Following individuals online is better than categorised news.<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=674&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you regularly use <a href="plus.google.com">Google+</a>, you&#8217;ll be aware of the recent introduction of &#8216;communities&#8217;, though the issue I wish to raise is relevant to everyone who reads news and commentary from any sources. This new feature offers the ability to join and read subject-specific groups, whereas users were previously accustomed to following individuals and seeing whatever was on their mind. Now, instead of listening to Charles, Caprice, and Chandelier post about astronomy one minute and gastronomy the next, you can base your content discovery on Chemistry, Cartography and Crochet, and you can also see comments on these subjects from people you don&#8217;t otherwise follow due to their enervating personalities. This superficially appealing capability represents what is actually a widespread problem across the internet, whether we&#8217;re considering social networks, news websites, forums or aggregators: the compartmentalisation of news and ideas limits the range of things you see to those things which you were already looking for.</p>
<p>So, you&#8217;re going to find things that you were hoping to find &#8211; how is that bad? Well, it isn&#8217;t always, but the trouble with our primate species is that we often act against our better judgement, and, in terms of news consumption, this means that we are far more likely to unknowingly seek to confirm our biases than we are to challenge our opinions. Just take a moment to think of your preferred news sources: when they&#8217;re covering something contentious, whether it&#8217;s about politics, ethics or pseudoscience, what are the chances that you could guess the author&#8217;s opinion before you even see the subtitle? They&#8217;re probably pretty high. Sometimes, it can do us good to refine our knowledge and our arguments by deliberately reading about things for which we already have a consolidated outlook, but much of the time we read news for its emotional rather than intellectual content, and the nourishment we feel is illusory. We allow ourselves the sense that we&#8217;re educating and informing ourselves despite the fact that we&#8217;ve made an implicit pact to turn to sources whose opinions we can predict in advance, meaning that we are never exposed to unconsidered questions and perspectives. This kind of insidious bias is partly the cause of phenomena such as the <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6Ly7Btx0Stg">rampant provincialism of U.S. news</a>.</p>
<p>However, this problem isn&#8217;t just confined to controversial political and moral questions; it also affects what we read about human culture and knowledge. If, for example, you join a handful of science-specific communities, or you follow science-specific accounts on twitter, instead of particular scientists each with a range of personal interests, you can be sure that you&#8217;ll come across a heap of relevant, enjoyable content, but you can also be sure that you&#8217;re never going to see that surprisingly fascinating article about W. H. Auden that Dr. Wigglesworth posted, which you&#8217;ll appreciate immensely when you&#8217;re in just the right mood to read it, but which you would never have uncovered yourself because you&#8217;re not so deeply connected to the world of literature that you&#8217;d have ever thought of finding it.</p>
<p>This is why I prefer to follow people rather than topics. I&#8217;m able to get a good sense of their character and interests, and while I know what kind of wonderful links and commentary to expect 90% of the time &#8211; all part of the initial attraction &#8211; I also look forward to that remaining 10% which I&#8217;d never have predicted or sought out myself, but which I still enjoy reading. We need that kind of spontaneous discovery. We need to be exposed to the unfamiliar and the unexpected, even if it&#8217;s only truly interesting one time out of a hundred. If all our interesting content is redirected from individuals to subject-specific sources, we will inevitably place subtle, unnoticed restrictions on the things that we see, and we will continue to reinforce our prejudiced ideas and interests without thinking.</p>
<p>Personally, I struggle with my own writing, both here and on social networks, because I know that many people who follow me have a select few major interests, while I want to be able to post equally passionately about linguistics and biology and cosmology and classical music and poetry without turning anybody off. I don&#8217;t ask you to be interested in all these things, and I&#8217;m probably never going to strike a balance that anyone else will think is optimal, but I do at least hope that intelligent, inquisitive individuals will be open to scrolling past a few unappealing posts so that they can eventually read and learn about things outside their usual interests once in a while. By following reliable people rather than rigid topics, you can be reasonably sure that you&#8217;ll get something exactly like that.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/674/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/674/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/674/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/674/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/674/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/674/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/674/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/674/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/674/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/674/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/674/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/674/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/674/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/674/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=674&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://callumjhackett.com/2012/12/14/reading-the-unexpected/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>19</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://callumjhackettdotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/google.png?w=140" />
		<media:content url="http://callumjhackettdotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/google.png?w=140" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Google+</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/90ad330df2a7a8e0d2140d5f842cbfb9?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F0.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Polednice</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Star Trekking Today</title>
		<link>http://thegazeboeffect.wordpress.com/2012/12/13/star-trekking-today/</link>
		<comments>http://thegazeboeffect.wordpress.com/2012/12/13/star-trekking-today/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2012 18:14:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>The Gazebo Effect</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Future]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science Fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exploration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Phaser]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Phazer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[replicator]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Star Trek]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tractor beam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[warp]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thegazeboeffect.wordpress.com/?p=12</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[For many Star Trek fans, one of the main attractions of the show is the futuristic technology. For some it’s the battle scenes where we watch bursts from the phaser banks and hear “Shields down to 60%” while others are excited by the concept of exploring the galaxy for the sake of scientific research, seeking [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=12&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:justify;">For many Star Trek fans, one of the main attractions of the show is the futuristic technology. For some it’s the battle scenes where we watch bursts from the phaser banks and hear “Shields down to 60%” while others are excited by the concept of exploring the galaxy for the sake of scientific research, seeking out new life and colonising new planets.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.startrekdesktopwallpaper.com/new_wallpaper/Star_Trek_Battle_Scene_freecomputerdesktopwallpaper_1600.shtml"><img class="size-full wp-image" id="i-20" alt="Image" src="http://thegazeboeffect.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/ship.jpg?w=580" width="580" height="212" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">One Star Trek enthusiast (who admittedly is a genuine engineer) has started a campaign to build a full scale replica of the Enterprise over the next 20 years which can travel to Mars in under 90 days using Ion Propulsion Engines. The <a href="http://www.buildtheenterprise.org/" target="_blank">Build The Enterprise</a> campaign has been turning heads of Trekkies (or Trekkers for the die-hards) around the world.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Obviously, the plan has received mixed reviews. There has been much admiration of the boldness and detail of the plan but equally there has been criticism, particularly at the cost &#8211; $40 billion per year for 20 years.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Anyway, the Enterprise is a 24<sup>th</sup> century ship. Even if we did have the money to build it, we don’t have the technology to kit it out. Or do we…</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">A lot of the technology we use in our everyday lives today featured prominently in the Star Trek arsenal of high tech gadgets. For example, the iPad is credited with being a revolutionary new technology developed by Steve Jobs. Please, Jean Luc was rocking that shit years ago.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.marketstar.com/blog/retail-channel/2011-war-of-the-tablets-part-2-%E2%80%93-what-the-future-holds/attachment/picard_ipad/#.UMzoLuR1GSo"><img class="size-full wp-image" id="i-22" alt="Image" src="http://thegazeboeffect.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/tablet.jpg?w=290" width="290" height="162" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Surprisingly, some of the technology, particularly from the original series, seems somewhat archaic compared to our devices. Look at Kirk&#8217;s communicator, it looks more like a phone that’s ten years out of date by todays standards than a 24<sup>th</sup> century technology. Especially when you consider that our phones are now looking more like tricorders, with all the tricks they can do. It was particularly surprising to see Spock show Captain Pike a paper printout in the episode ‘The Menagerie’. Although this can be forgiven considering it was a rehash of the pilot episode.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.bobwellsradio.com/newswortharchive2009.htm"><img class="size-full wp-image" id="i-24" alt="Image" src="http://thegazeboeffect.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/communicator.jpg?w=168" width="168" height="196" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">While we can pat ourselves on the back for surpassing the series in these respects, they won’t be much use in getting an Enterprise through space. For the full experience you need warp drive, tractor beams, phasers, transporters, shields, replicators, etc. You may be surprised to learn that we have already taken the first steps to these technologies too. Some of the most significant developments will leave you very impressed.</p>
<p><b>Replicators</b></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">These seemed like one of the most fictitious and unlikely pieces of kit. All the other elements of the ship seemed possible given enough time and research, but to make stuff appear out of thin air always seemed to be truly science fiction. Surprisingly, of all the elements of the Enterprise, this is the one we have made the most progress with. Everyone with even a passing interest in technology has heard of 3D printers, which can literally print complex objects with moving parts. Have a look at this video to see how invaluable 3D printers will probably become in the coming years.</p>
<span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='640' height='390' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/8aghzpO_UZE?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span>
<p>Still a long way to go until we can say &#8220;Tea. Earl Grey. Hot.&#8221; Another Picardism.</p>
<p><b>Tractor Beams</b></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">These beams were regularly used to apply forces to objects/ships to either pull them in or push them away. The Borg were fond of tractor beams to capture ships undamaged so that they could be harvested for new technologies. Scientists have made a small but significant breakthrough by using light beams to draw particles towards its source. Applications include possibly collecting particles from the tails of comets from a distance rather than risking entering the debris trail. This video explains it excellently (by the way, that youtube channel looks to be very good for science news based on first glance).</p>
<p><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9i1NJY8qUuk"><span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='640' height='390' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/9i1NJY8qUuk?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span></a></p>
<p><b>Warp Speed</b></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Arguably the most important system on an interstellar spaceship, faster than light speed is essential to make manned journeys to planets outside our solar system viable. Consider Proxima Centauri, the nearest star to or own Sun. Even if we could travel at near the speed of light, it would take at least 4.24 years to reach the star and a similar time to make the return journey. Adding to this the time needed to carry out tasks such as research etc. It is clear these time scales dictate that a ship must carry vast stores of supplies and energy.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">While travelling faster than the speed of light is well known to be impossible, scientists (including NASA) believe it may be possible to manipulate the fabric of space-time itself to ‘push’ the ship across the cosmos. By expanding the empty space behind the ship and contracting the space in front of it the ship slips through space-time at speeds high enough to shorten the journey to Proxima Centauri to just two weeks.</p>
<p><a href="http://io9.com/5963263/how-nasa-will-build-its-very-first-warp-drive"><img class="size-full wp-image" id="i-27" alt="Image" src="http://thegazeboeffect.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/space-time.jpg?w=379" width="379" height="379" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Note the bubble around the ship in this picture showing no change in the immediate vicinity, so the crew would not perceive anything unusual from their point of view. Unfortunately, the energy required to manipulate space-time like this is far too high but NASA actually have people working on how to make it a reality. Physicist Harold White has published work on this for them, exploring means of reducing the energy needed and proposing possible ship designs.</p>
<p><a href="http://ntrs.nasa.gov/archive/nasa/casi.ntrs.nasa.gov/20110015936_2011016932.pdf"><img class="size-full wp-image" id="i-28" alt="Image" src="http://thegazeboeffect.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/space-time-ship.jpg?w=277" width="277" height="321" /></a></p>
<p><strong>Phasers</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">The concept of firing energy beams has been the dominant choice of weapon by science fiction writers for some time now. The development of this technology is probably just a matter of time now. High power lasers already exist, in fact the Curiosity rover is currently blasting rocks on Mars by delivering a million watts of power for a few billionths of a second in order to analyse the glow from resulting plasma. See the before and after images of Curiosity’s wrath below. A high power beam like this would most likely be lethal if fired at a person considering the body doesn&#8217;t cope well with being turned into plasma.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.weirdwarp.com/2012/08/mars-rover-curiosity-is-firing-its-laser/"><img class="size-full wp-image" id="i-30" alt="Image" src="http://thegazeboeffect.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/curiosity.jpg?w=286" width="286" height="167" /></a><a href="http://www.wired.com/wiredscience/2012/08/before-and-after-chemcam/"><img class="size-full wp-image" id="i-31" alt="Image" src="http://thegazeboeffect.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/laser.jpg?w=286" width="286" height="153" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Considering the level of knowledge on star trek technology already discovered today, it may not be unreasonable to say that humans will be leaving our solar system and exploring the cosmic neighbourhood by the end of this century. Gene Roddenberry may have been bang on with his predictions on the timetable of space exploration. After all, it’s only about 50 years until &#8216;First Contact&#8217;. Then, we boldly go where no man has gone before.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.ex-astris-scientia.org/gallery/vulcans1.htm"><img class="size-full wp-image" id="i-33" alt="Image" src="http://thegazeboeffect.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/first-contact.jpg?w=443" width="442" height="233" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/12/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/12/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=12&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thegazeboeffect.wordpress.com/2012/12/13/star-trekking-today/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>12</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/14110384404d1c9857e15d799d1efd2c?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">thegazeboeffect</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thegazeboeffect.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/ship.jpg?w=580" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thegazeboeffect.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/tablet.jpg?w=290" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thegazeboeffect.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/communicator.jpg?w=168" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thegazeboeffect.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/space-time.jpg?w=379" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thegazeboeffect.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/space-time-ship.jpg?w=277" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thegazeboeffect.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/curiosity.jpg?w=286" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thegazeboeffect.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/laser.jpg?w=286" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thegazeboeffect.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/first-contact.jpg?w=443" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>When a Person Dies</title>
		<link>http://hotpinkunderwear.com/2012/12/06/when-a-person-dies/</link>
		<comments>http://hotpinkunderwear.com/2012/12/06/when-a-person-dies/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2012 18:55:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>meagan mac</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Musings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[On Dying]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[On Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beauty]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[death]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[girl]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grief]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[human desires]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[longing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[loss]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sadness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://hotpinkunderwear.com/?p=783</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Someone I dearly loved died this week. After I found out she had passed, I turned invisible. Creatures around me became their own planets, rotating in separate orbits. Someone turned down the earth&#8217;s volume knob and the little pilotman in charge of keeping our world spinning slowed everything down. The squirrel outside my car window acted [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=783&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Someone I dearly loved died this week.</p>
<p>After I found out she had passed, I turned invisible. Creatures around me became their own planets, rotating in separate orbits. Someone turned down the earth&#8217;s volume knob and the little pilotman in charge of keeping our world spinning slowed everything down.</p>
<p>The squirrel outside my car window acted like he couldn&#8217;t see me. I guess maybe he didn&#8217;t. But I saw him, and that made it worse because he was doing something important. It was obvious. He was focused and alive. The brown hairs on his back shivered. His tiny dark nails scratched the asphalt as he crossed in front of me.</p>
<p>Inside my car planet, I turned up the music, but familiar song lyrics took on new meaning.</p>
<p>&#8220;As many times as I blink I&#8217;ll think of you&#8230;I swear I won&#8217;t forget you.&#8221;</p>
<p>Everything reminded me that she was gone.</p>
<p>I drove downtown, but buildings shoved memories at me. That ugly place we worked together. We&#8217;d grab coffee at that Starbucks.</p>
<p>That restaurant was where we had lunch and she said it was okay that I left my job, that I left her. She said she wanted me to be happy and that I should pursue my passions. She hugged me goodbye, like always. She was so small, but she was the biggest person I&#8217;ve ever known.</p>
<p>December. Her birthday month.</p>
<p>Everything becomes a reminder. Or a metaphor.</p>
<p>Christmas carols. Rain. A woman walking alone.</p>
<p>I wait for my daughter to get off the bus. A little boy and his dad are waiting, too. The little boy stares up at a tall evergreen, tilting his head back further and further. His child face smiles up. All he can possibly see is sky. The vast, clouded mystery beyond where he stands. He giggles. He looks dizzy. He leans farther.</p>
<p>When he starts to fall backward, his face doesn&#8217;t change. He keeps smiling, like maybe he doesn&#8217;t know he&#8217;s falling. Or he&#8217;s not afraid. Maybe he trusts his father will catch him. Maybe he doesn&#8217;t mind falling, or he is so pleased with his profound, incomprehensible moment that he is holding on for as long as he can. Anyway, his father does catch him.</p>
<p>The sky is too heavy for me. Too risky. I don&#8217;t even want to watch this little boy finding joy in his wonder, because I just want to be sad. And angry.</p>
<p>All that space, white clouds, full of what? Too much carbon dioxide and humanity&#8217;s eventual demise. My death. What is there beyond that stupid sky, anyway?</p>
<p>Is she up there? Is she gone?</p>
<p>I want her back, damn it. And I&#8217;m sick of the rain. Fucking sky. She was my friend, my mentor. She inspired me to live better. To live stronger. I hate You, whoever you are, for taking her. For making her suffer with cancer.</p>
<p>I am still angry when my daughter steps off the bus. The lights are blinking. But she smiles at me like I am her sky. The world speeds up. Sounds are loud again.</p>
<p>I focus on her. I become visible, alive.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/783/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/783/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=783&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://hotpinkunderwear.com/2012/12/06/when-a-person-dies/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>109</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/4973382b521017e1f61fd1b3cdcd51fd?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">beingshe</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Top Photos of India Part 1: Places</title>
		<link>http://planetbell.wordpress.com/2012/12/12/top-photos-of-india-part-1-places/</link>
		<comments>http://planetbell.wordpress.com/2012/12/12/top-photos-of-india-part-1-places/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2012 03:11:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>planetbell</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kerala]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mumbai]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photo Essay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rajasthan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Delhi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Goa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hampi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tourism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uttar Pradesh]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://planetbell.wordpress.com/?p=452</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I set out to post my top 10 photos of my recent trip to India and quickly realized I could never accomplish that. Here are my top 18 photos of places, buildings, cityscapes and landscapes from India and later I will post favorite photos of people. I hope you enjoy. It may not be a [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=452&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I set out to post my top 10 photos of my recent trip to India and quickly realized I could never accomplish that. Here are my top 18 photos of places, buildings, cityscapes and landscapes from India and later I will post favorite photos of people. I hope you enjoy. It may not be a top 10 list but at least you don&#8217;t have to sit through a slideshow presentation of the 5322 photos that I took.</p>
<div id="attachment_453" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 1034px"><a href="http://planetbell.wordpress.com/2012/12/12/top-photos-of-india-part-1-places/photo-22/#main" rel="attachment wp-att-453"><img class="size-large wp-image-453" alt="Jama Masjid" src="http://planetbell.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/photo-22.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=584" width="1024" height="584" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">India&#8217;s largest mosque, the Jama Masjid in old Delhi. It can hold 20,000 worshippers at one time.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_454" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 1034px"><a href="http://planetbell.wordpress.com/2012/12/12/top-photos-of-india-part-1-places/photo-24/#main" rel="attachment wp-att-454"><img class="size-large wp-image-454" alt="The Taj Mahal" src="http://planetbell.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/photo-24.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=682" width="1024" height="682" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Does the Taj really need a caption? It is every bit as impressive as you can imagine.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_455" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 1034px"><a href="http://planetbell.wordpress.com/2012/12/12/top-photos-of-india-part-1-places/photo-21/#main" rel="attachment wp-att-455"><img class="size-large wp-image-455" alt="Amber Fort" src="http://planetbell.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/photo-21.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=563" width="1024" height="563" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The Amber Fort near Jaipur.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_456" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 1034px"><a href="http://planetbell.wordpress.com/2012/12/12/top-photos-of-india-part-1-places/photo-1/#main" rel="attachment wp-att-456"><img class="size-large wp-image-456" alt="Pushkar2" src="http://planetbell.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/photo-1.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=682" width="1024" height="682" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">One of the 500 temples in and around Pushkar, our favorite place in Rajasthan.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_457" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 1034px"><a href="http://planetbell.wordpress.com/2012/12/12/top-photos-of-india-part-1-places/photo-11/#main" rel="attachment wp-att-457"><img class="size-large wp-image-457" alt="Pushkar" src="http://planetbell.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/photo-11.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=614" width="1024" height="614" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Pushkar from the Saraswati Temple at Sunrise. We had to wake up at 4 AM and hike an hour to get the view, but it was worth it.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_458" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 1034px"><a href="http://planetbell.wordpress.com/2012/12/12/top-photos-of-india-part-1-places/photo-26/#main" rel="attachment wp-att-458"><img class="size-large wp-image-458" alt="City Palace" src="http://planetbell.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/photo-26.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=395" width="1024" height="395" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The CIty Palace in Udaipur was the most impressive of all the palaces and forts we saw in Rajasthan.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_464" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 1034px"><a href="http://planetbell.wordpress.com/2012/12/12/top-photos-of-india-part-1-places/photo-18/#main" rel="attachment wp-att-464"><img class="size-large wp-image-464" alt="Ellora" src="http://planetbell.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/photo-18.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=682" width="1024" height="682" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The largest monolithic carving in the world at the Ellora Caves. I don&#8217;t know what is more impressive, the fact that they took 200 years to carve this or that I was able to get a photo with only Kristi in it and no other tourists.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_463" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 1034px"><a href="http://planetbell.wordpress.com/2012/12/12/top-photos-of-india-part-1-places/photo-9/#main" rel="attachment wp-att-463"><img class="size-large wp-image-463" alt="Ajanta" src="http://planetbell.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/photo-9.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=682" width="1024" height="682" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">One of 29 caves carved into the cliff face at Ajanta. The caves served as either Buddhist monasteries or temples and date back to 200 B.C.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_462" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 1034px"><a href="http://planetbell.wordpress.com/2012/12/12/top-photos-of-india-part-1-places/photo-15/#main" rel="attachment wp-att-462"><img class="size-large wp-image-462" alt="Jodhpur Sunset" src="http://planetbell.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/photo-15.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=764" width="1024" height="764" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Mehrangarh Fort and Jodhpur at sunset. I like the local boy in the bottom of the frame pondering life.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_461" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 1034px"><a href="http://planetbell.wordpress.com/2012/12/12/top-photos-of-india-part-1-places/photo-13/#main" rel="attachment wp-att-461"><img class="size-large wp-image-461" alt="Blue city" src="http://planetbell.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/photo-13.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=682" width="1024" height="682" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The cubist cityscape of Jodhpur.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_460" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 1034px"><a href="http://planetbell.wordpress.com/2012/12/12/top-photos-of-india-part-1-places/photo-17/#main" rel="attachment wp-att-460"><img class="size-large wp-image-460" alt="Ranakhpur" src="http://planetbell.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/photo-17.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=682" width="1024" height="682" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The Ranakpur temple in Rajasthan. The Jain temple is made up of over 1444 unique pillars carved out of white marble. Amazing.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_459" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 1034px"><a href="http://planetbell.wordpress.com/2012/12/12/top-photos-of-india-part-1-places/photo-19/#main" rel="attachment wp-att-459"><img class="size-large wp-image-459" alt="Udaipur Palace" src="http://planetbell.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/photo-19.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=615" width="1024" height="615" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The Lake Palace at Udaipur, which is now a hotel. We looked online at rates and almost made a booking, thinking it was $80 per night. We recalculated and found out it was $800 per night. Due to that pesky zero we couldn&#8217;t afford it.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_465" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 1034px"><a href="http://planetbell.wordpress.com/2012/12/12/top-photos-of-india-part-1-places/photo-2/#main" rel="attachment wp-att-465"><img class="size-large wp-image-465" alt="Victoria Terminus" src="http://planetbell.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/photo-2.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=682" width="1024" height="682" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The Victoria Terminus in bustling Mumbai.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_466" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 1034px"><a href="http://planetbell.wordpress.com/2012/12/12/top-photos-of-india-part-1-places/photo-23/#main" rel="attachment wp-att-466"><img class="size-large wp-image-466" alt="Taj Hotel, Mumbai" src="http://planetbell.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/photo-23.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=650" width="1024" height="650" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The Taj Mahal Hotel in Mumbai.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_467" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 1034px"><a href="http://planetbell.wordpress.com/2012/12/12/top-photos-of-india-part-1-places/photo-25/#main" rel="attachment wp-att-467"><img class="size-large wp-image-467" alt="Hampi Sunrise" src="http://planetbell.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/photo-25.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=682" width="1024" height="682" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Sunrise at Hampi, one of the great archeological sites of India. At its height, over 500 years ago, the area was home to 1/2 million people.  Now the area consists of scattered ruins and banana plantations. The vibe in present day Hampi is very mellow &#8211; a great place for chilling out and doing some hiking.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_468" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 1034px"><a href="http://planetbell.wordpress.com/2012/12/12/top-photos-of-india-part-1-places/photo-20/#main" rel="attachment wp-att-468"><img class="size-large wp-image-468" alt="Goa Church 2" src="http://planetbell.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/photo-20.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=682" width="1024" height="682" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Our Lady of Immaculate Conception Church in Panjim, Goa. I tried to take a somewhat unique photo of the church, since most of them I saw online were the basic up-close photos of the white edifice.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_469" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 1034px"><a href="http://planetbell.wordpress.com/2012/12/12/top-photos-of-india-part-1-places/photo-8/#main" rel="attachment wp-att-469"><img class="size-large wp-image-469" alt="Goa Church" src="http://planetbell.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/photo-8.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=682" width="1024" height="682" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The cathedral at Goa again. The Portuguese old city of Panjim was laid-back and filled with excellent places to eat.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_470" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 692px"><a href="http://planetbell.wordpress.com/2012/12/12/top-photos-of-india-part-1-places/photo-6/#main" rel="attachment wp-att-470"><img class="size-large wp-image-470" alt="photo-6" src="http://planetbell.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/photo-6.jpg?w=682&#038;h=1024" width="682" height="1024" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The tea plantations of Munnar in the state of Kerala. The state&#8217;s motto, God&#8217;s own country, is apt.</p></div>
<p>If you like this, you might also like:<br />
1. <a href="http://http://planetbell.wordpress.com/2012/12/02/adventures-in-munnar-kristi-makes-peace-with-the-mountains-jeff-makes-controversial-comments-at-a-communist-rally-and-the-bells-go-to-fat-camp/">Adventure in Munnar: Kristi makes peace with the mountains, Jeff makes controversial comments at a communist rally and the Bell&#8217;s go to fat camp.</a></p>
<p>2. <a href="http://http://planetbell.wordpress.com/2012/10/23/indian-festivals-are-awesome-or-i-am-the-worlds-worst-dancer/">Indian Festivals are Awesome, or I am the World&#8217;s Worst Dancer</a></p>
<p>3. <a href="http://planetbell.wordpress.com/2012/10/14/escaping-india-in-tranquil-pushkar/">Escaping India in Tranquil Pushkar</a></p>
<p>4. <a href="http://planetbell.wordpress.com/2012/10/10/the-requisite-taj-mahal-photo-essay/">The Requisite Taj Mahal Photo Essay</a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/452/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/452/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=452&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://planetbell.wordpress.com/2012/12/12/top-photos-of-india-part-1-places/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>81</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://planetbell.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/photo-23.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://planetbell.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/photo-23.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Taj Hotel, Mumbai</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/0c989f0ba849231fa762be6ecaaa4279?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">planetbell</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://planetbell.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/photo-22.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Jama Masjid</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://planetbell.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/photo-24.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The Taj Mahal</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://planetbell.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/photo-21.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Amber Fort</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://planetbell.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/photo-1.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Pushkar2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://planetbell.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/photo-11.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Pushkar</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://planetbell.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/photo-26.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">City Palace</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://planetbell.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/photo-18.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ellora</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://planetbell.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/photo-9.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ajanta</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://planetbell.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/photo-15.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Jodhpur Sunset</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://planetbell.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/photo-13.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Blue city</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://planetbell.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/photo-17.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ranakhpur</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://planetbell.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/photo-19.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Udaipur Palace</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://planetbell.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/photo-2.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Victoria Terminus</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://planetbell.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/photo-23.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Taj Hotel, Mumbai</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://planetbell.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/photo-25.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Hampi Sunrise</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://planetbell.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/photo-20.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Goa Church 2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://planetbell.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/photo-8.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Goa Church</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://planetbell.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/photo-6.jpg?w=682" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">photo-6</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
