<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2012 01:02:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>How to Turn Social Media into Social Change</title>
		<link>http://thepostic.wordpress.com/2012/08/12/how-to-turn-social-media-into-social-change/</link>
		<comments>http://thepostic.wordpress.com/2012/08/12/how-to-turn-social-media-into-social-change/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2012 18:58:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>David</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Changing the World]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lifestyle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[philosophy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[society]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thepostic.wordpress.com/?p=473</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Today&#8217;s post is submitted by guest blogger Rob Garilli of Not Another Millennial. You can also view my guest piece on Rob&#8217;s blog. It’s no surprise that social media is central to the Millennial lifestyle. Members of Generation Y are often referred to as the first digital natives, meaning that they’re the first generation to have [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=473&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://thepostic.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/social-media-blog.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-476" title="social media blog" src="http://thepostic.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/social-media-blog.jpg" alt="Social Media" width="590" height="139" /></a></p>
<p><em>Today&#8217;s post is submitted by guest blogger Rob Garilli of <a title="Not Another Millennial Blog" href="http://www.notanothermillennial.com" target="_blank">Not Another Millennial</a>. You can also <a title="My guest piece" href="http://notanothermillennial.com/2012/08/09/internet-dave-saves-the-world/" target="_blank">view my guest piece</a> on Rob&#8217;s blog.</em></p>
<p>It’s no surprise that social media is central to the Millennial lifestyle. Members of Generation Y are often referred to as the first digital natives, meaning that they’re the first generation to have had technology be a part of their lives since birth. In fact, in a <a title="EURO RSCG articles" href="http://eurorscgsocial.com/millennials-and-social-media/" target="_blank">series of posts by the communication network Euro RSCG</a>, it was said that “for Millennials, social media is as seamlessly integrated into their lives as their computers and cell phones; it’s how they communicate and socialize, conduct business and explore the world.”</p>
<p>The effect social media has on people’s lives today is so extensive that the Huffington Post has published an article on “<a title="Tweeting While Eating article" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/02/28/tweeting-eating_n_1307422.html" target="_blank">Tweeting While Eating</a>.” The article pointed out that 47% of Millennials use Twitter while eating or drinking. According to HuffPost, the group also uses social media to find restaurant reviews and recommendations at a much higher rate than members of past generations.</p>
<p>We use it for many reasons, but the most powerful factor in social media is the ability to create global connections. Euro RSCG points out that 63% of Millennials use social media to stay connected with friends worldwide.</p>
<p>If you saw <a title="David's guest post" href="http://notanothermillennial.com/2012/08/09/internet-dave-saves-the-world/" target="_blank">David’s recent guest post on my blog</a>, you’ll remember a number of really great statistics he included. His argument that, with 96% of Millennials connected via the Internet, social media can become a powerful tool to generate real social change is compelling. It left me wondering, though; is it realistic?</p>
<p>Yes, social media is a source of connection, conversation, and community. It has become a veritable reflection of social culture today; I would argue that much of young people’s socialization today happens via social networking sites.</p>
<p><em>But does that necessarily mean that this power is, or even can be, harnessed for good?</em></p>
<p><strong>Politics is a Dirty Word</strong></p>
<p>Now, granted, politics is the not the exclusive arena we’re discussing when we use the term “social change.” However, I’d argue that most activism or cause-sharing revolves around areas such as politics, religion, and civil rights. All of these are pretty heavy topics, and most of them are taboo when it comes to dinner table discussion.</p>
<p>If we keep in mind that many people like to keep their political leans or religious beliefs private (and that the ones who don’t are often seen as obnoxious or preachy), where does that leave us?</p>
<p>Recently, a blogger known as Emily posted the results of a survey she’d administered on her website “<a title="Emily's Reading Room" href="http://www.emilysreadingroom.com/2012/08/when-authors-get-political-survey.html" target="_blank">Emily’s Reading Room</a>.” The topic was how certain groups felt when authors posted politically-tinged content on their Twitter accounts. The respondents included readers, bloggers, teachers and librarians, and fellow authors. In the general responses, Emily found that:</p>
<ul>
<li>55% of respondents were “bothered” when an author posted political content.</li>
<li>67% had chosen not to read books by those authors who had posted such content.</li>
<li>49% of respondents had chosen to unfollow authors due to posts with political content.</li>
</ul>
<p>This is obviously a very specific population of respondents. The survey also straddles a number of gray areas, which were noted by the respondents. For instance, were the tweets posted to professional or personal Twitter accounts?</p>
<p>Additionally, answers were generally group-dependent; it seems that fellow authors were more offended than readers or bloggers when their counterparts posted political content.</p>
<p>So why am I telling you all of this?</p>
<p><strong>“This Isn’t the Time or Place” </strong></p>
<p>How often have you heard the above phrase in conversation?  It is frequently used to shut down heavy or aggressive language in a setting that isn’t necessarily suited for the discussion. Sometimes it’s just employed by people who want to avoid certain conversations. Like any turn of phrase it is used for different reasons at different times.</p>
<p>And that’s precisely the problem. Our social landscape and our ways of communicating are intensely complex. It only makes sense, if social media is a reflection of our general social culture, that the rules and exceptions of discussion on social media be just as complicated.</p>
<p>To get a personal view on how people react to certain posts on social media networks, I created a Facebook poll and sent out some tweets to ask my friends and followers:</p>
<blockquote><p><em>When you see posts on Facebook and Twitter advocating social change or talking about politics, are you more likely to engage or scroll on past?</em></p></blockquote>
<p>I got a total of 12 responses over the span of a few hours. 9 respondents said they would choose to engage, and 3 chose the option “Scroll past – social media isn’t the venue for that.”</p>
<p>To get a little down and dirty, I asked for further clarification.</p>
<p>I found that 2 people would engage with such content, but conditionally. Both respondents cited requirements that the topic at hand be “a good cause” or “something I’m passionate about.”</p>
<p>One of the people who chose to ignore this type of content told me, “I go on Facebook to be entertained. If I wanted to be informed about social issues, I’d watch the news.”</p>
<p>Now, I understand that these polls were informal and hardly extensive. But let’s say that we can work with the following rough numbers: 58% of Millennials would respond to content on social media calling for some kind of social change. 17% would only do so if the cause was important to them. And 25% would ignore the content entirely.</p>
<p>So social media has the <em>potential</em> to create real change. How can we<em> maximize</em> that potential if a quarter of the Internet’s biggest audience isn’t speaking up or paying attention?  If social media isn’t the right venue for this kind of discussion, it begs the question: <em>what is?</em></p>
<p><strong>A Lesson from the Little Ones</strong></p>
<p>Matt Silverman, who writes for Mashable, is also interested in the effect social media has on today’s generation. This past May, he wrote <a title="Mashable profile" href="http://mashable.com/2012/05/10/millennials-social-media-adora-svitak/" target="_blank">a profile on Adora Svitak</a>, a 14-year-old who believes that, with social media, comes both power and responsibility.</p>
<p>At 14, Adora doesn’t fit snugly into the Gen Y timeline – she’s about three years too late to qualify. However, as a member of Generation Z, she probably has many habits similar to Millennials. If anything, members of Gen Z have been even more exposed to advances in technology than have Millennials. Because they weren’t there for the transition to newer and better forms of social media, they’ve only ever used them in their “concentrated” forms – the best of what today has to offer.</p>
<p>Today’s teens and tweens are so connected to social media that they use it, Adora says, to supplement their education and their social status. On Facebook, groups are created that align with course content – never took an art history class in high school or college? Well, now you can! And while you’re at it, you’d better catch up on the latest memes. It’s what all the cool kids are doing.</p>
<p>But that’s not all, Adora says. While discussing companies that use social media for advertising, the teen noted that flashy slogans and logos aren’t enough for today’s young consumers.</p>
<blockquote><p>I think that my peers deserve more than products to buy wrapped up in advertising. We need ideas to share and causes to believe in — opportunities to lead and teach. Teenagers invest themselves deeply in causes. There’s a lot of idealism to tap into. Teens don’t have cash, but they can do good by using their smarts.</p></blockquote>
<p>Millennials who don’t think engaging on social media is apropos could learn a lot from this perspective. If sites like Facebook and Twitter are becoming the social arena, then eventually they’ll inevitably have to assume discussions of politics and social change.</p>
<p><strong>Perception is Reality</strong></p>
<p>The weekly Twitter chat #millennialchat can see change on the horizon, too. <a title="#millennialchat" href="http://storify.com/millennialchat/how-can-millennials-use-social-media-to-make-good" target="_blank">On July 24th</a>, the topic of the hour was “how Millennials can use social media to make good giving decisions.”</p>
<p>By packaging a topic like charitable giving in a lively, informative and fun medium – such as a Twitter chat – we can hope to reach and retain more Millennial users. Like the marketers and advertisers Adora mentioned, we need to look at <em>how we’re presenting our ideas</em>.</p>
<p>To go back to <a title="Euro RSCG" href="http://eurorscgsocial.com/millennials-and-social-media/millennials-and-social-media-social-media-for-a-change/" target="_blank">Euro RSCG’s data</a>, 7 out of 10 Millennials believe social media is a force for change. They are comfortable with social media playing a dual role in their lives – conversely serious or playful when the occasion calls for it. Furthermore, 8 of 10 Millennials believe <em>it is their <span style="text-decoration:underline;">duty</span> to create change</em>.</p>
<p>As social media evolves, we evolve with it. For now, 30% of Millennials might not be so comfortable with using Facebook to champion causes. (<em>A number, by the way, that’s not so far off from my own informal findings</em>.) If we keep adjusting the approach we take and the content we create, we can change that. It also probably wouldn’t hurt to have a social network exclusively dedicated to discussions of politics, activism, and other social justice causes as a way of breaking the ice. Hey, Silicon Valley start-ups… get on that!</p>
<p>We need to keep asking questions and getting people engaged.  Those are the keys to building an intelligent, informed, and involved population – all qualities which contribute to democracy and the creation of real social change.</p>
<p>So back to the big question: <a title="Internet Dave Saves the World" href="http://thepostic.wordpress.com/2012/08/10/462/" target="_blank"><em>can social media really be used to generate change? </em></a>It seems so.</p>
<p>I still believe Millennials can save the world. They just need to work a little harder to make sure all of their friends, followers, and fellow pinners are on board.</p>
<p><em>You can connect with Rob via his blog, <a title="Twitter" href="http://www.twitter.com/MillenProblems" target="_blank">Twitter,</a> or <a title="Facebook" href="http://www.facebook.com/NotAnotherMillennial" target="_blank">Facebook</a> page. And remember, if you are interested in collaborating on a guest post for this blog, you can <a title="Guest Posting" href="http://thepostic.wordpress.com/guest-posts/" target="_blank">contact me here</a>.</em></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/473/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/473/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/473/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/473/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/473/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/473/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/473/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/473/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/473/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/473/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/473/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/473/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/473/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/473/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=473&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thepostic.wordpress.com/2012/08/12/how-to-turn-social-media-into-social-change/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/ee0d185f5b3679817f7eb71c23c1731a?s=96&#38;d=&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">thepostic</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thepostic.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/social-media-blog.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">social media blog</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Delight of Hand Writing</title>
		<link>http://scribedoll.wordpress.com/2012/08/12/the-delight-of-hand-writing/</link>
		<comments>http://scribedoll.wordpress.com/2012/08/12/the-delight-of-hand-writing/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2012 18:28:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>scribedoll</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Odds & Ends]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creativity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[handwriting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[katherine gregor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[musings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scribe doll]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://scribedoll.wordpress.com/?p=639</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I am sitting on a wooden bench, by the red-brick wall of a small Elizabethan palace.  I am leaning against the arm-rest.  My legs, stretched out before me, take up two thirds of the seat, and my bare toes are wriggling with the pleasure of sunshine.  Behind the bench, a few sprigs of lavender nod [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=639&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I am sitting on a wooden bench, by the red-brick wall of a small Elizabethan palace.  I am leaning against the arm-rest.  My legs, stretched out before me, take up two thirds of the seat, and my bare toes are wriggling with the pleasure of sunshine.  Behind the bench, a few sprigs of lavender nod to the breeze, and express their soothing fragrance.  The self-satisfied gurgle of the Tudor courtyard fountain is caressing my soul.  Somewhere in the vicinity, a crow is cawing.  I sense mockery in his or her tone.  On my lap, is my usual A4 spiral notebook; in my hand, my usual fountain pen.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>A gentleman and his wife stop to ask me directions for the café in the park.  Before I have a chance to point, he exclaims, “Oh, my goodness – you’re <em>writing</em>! And with a proper pen! It’s ages since I’ve seen anyone do that.  I’m impressed!”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>I am not used to strangers expressing <em>quite</em> so much astonishment, true, but I <em>am</em> used to getting looks; looks that combine puzzlement with wariness or a hint of admiration.  Sometimes, when I look up, I meet a supportive smile from the person opposite me on the Tube or across the coffee shop.  In my mid-forties, what used to be viewed as youthful quirkiness is now labelled as middle-age eccentricity but, the truth is, I have written with a fountain since I was nine years old – ever since I was sent to a a French school.  The teachers there demanded that we use nibs.  Allegedly, it helped improve our handwriting.  I have just never grown out of it.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>I derive great pleasure from writing with a fountain pen.  I love the soft murmur of a well worn-in nib as it glides on the paper, tracing glistening black swirls which turn into an elegant matt as they dry.  I own four fountain pens.  The latest addition (and the only non Parker-made), was crafted from a piece of 13th Century oak, recovered from the timber ceiling of York Minster.  The handsome nib is engraved with a pattern of swirls.  I have had it only a few months and it has not yet got used to the caprices of my hand.  It has not yet learnt to pace its ink flow.  It stumbles, rebels, catches on the paper, and scratches it with a harsh rasp.  I try and be patient and exercise it regularly, to train it to my fingers.  The eldest of the four saw me through my final school exams.  The stainless steel barrel is just the right thickness and weight for my hand.  The crimson plastic of the grip section has changed shape over the years, moulded by the inside of my right middle finger knuckle.  The small nib tip skates across the paper with seamless dexterity, and in almost total silence.  It is an old friend who knows all thoughts and whims, and is at one with my hand.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>I like the fact that you can hold a fountain pen in your hand lightly, and not have to force it down onto the paper as you have to do with a biro.  I like the boldness of the black ink that stands out against the white paper, like an uncompromising statement, ready to be counted.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Do not get me wrong.  I <em>can</em> type on a computer.  I have an excellent working relationship with my 13’’ MacBook Pro.  It always knows what I want, and executes it to perfection but I cannot open my heart to it.  I must hand-write it first, then convey it to Mac.  I <em>can</em>, when faced with time restrictions, create a text straight onto computer.  However, I always feel as though I have missed a stage of the process; like leaping from A to C without going through B; like eating a sandwich on the hoof instead of a sit-down meal; or jumping over a river without walking along the bridge.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Paradoxally, it can take me longer to come up with a sentence on a computer screen than on a  sheet of paper.  I stare at the screen and become aware of its almost imperceptible tremor.  I does not inspire me, yet I cannot look away, even though my eyes start feeling tired.  I get distracted by the low but monotonous whirr.  Thoughts and words start chasing one another at increasingly vertiginous speed, in a  chaotic game and I struggle to keep up.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">
<p><a href="http://scribedoll.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/blog-img_05622.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-648" title="Blog IMG_0562" src="http://scribedoll.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/blog-img_05622.jpg?w=225&h=300" alt="" width="225" height="300" /></a>The moment I pick up my fountain pen, thoughts and words get into pairs and stand in an orderly queue, waiting their turn to slide down the ink syphon and flow out smoothly through the nib onto the paper.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Because my thoughts have to obey the speed of my wrist, they become more focused, more anchored.  Words written on paper feel more tangible, more physical, more firmly rooted in soil – even more real.  Also, my handwriting reflects back to me my own feelings about what I am writing.  It is not as professionally neutral as the perfect Palatino font programmed on my Mac.  It becomes irregular, crooked and even illegible when I am writing out of duty or necessity.  However, the letters increase in size, the curves grow smoother, the loops acquire panache, and my penmanship becomes clearer when I mean the words I write.  One could say that my handwriting is quick at calling my bluff.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Any creative writing I do – be it a theatre review, a short story, or my weekly blog – I prefer to hand-write first, then copy/edit onto computer.  My novel, I am typing directly onto my laptop because I cannot bear the thought of having to copy 100,000 words.  I sometimes wonder if that is the reason I am finding it difficult to connect with my novel, and why it is taking me so long to write.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>In his marvellous, inspiring book, <em>The Places in Between</em>, Scottish historian and politician Rory Stewart narrates his journey on foot across Afghanistan, in 2002.  He talks about the serenity of mind he achieves while walking.  He refers to travel writer Bruce Chatwin, who</p>
<p><em>“concluded (&#8230;) that we would think and live better and be closer to our purposes as humans if we moved continually on foot across the surface of the earth.  I was not certain that I was living or thinking any better.”</em></p>
<p>I agree with him.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>What Rory Stewart feels about the physicality of travelling on foot is akin to how I feel about writing by hand.  It gives me a sense of achievement and continuity.  It is grounding and brings me peace of mind.  It is profoundly healing.  By translating my imagination into words, hand writing manifests the ethereal into the physical &#8211; with a solid, stone bridge.  I would not miss out on the walk over that bridge for anything in the world – there is a wonderful view from it.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align:right;">Scribe Doll</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<br /> Tagged: <a href='http://scribedoll.wordpress.com/tag/creativity/'>creativity</a>, <a href='http://scribedoll.wordpress.com/tag/handwriting/'>handwriting</a>, <a href='http://scribedoll.wordpress.com/tag/katherine-gregor/'>katherine gregor</a>, <a href='http://scribedoll.wordpress.com/tag/musings/'>musings</a>, <a href='http://scribedoll.wordpress.com/tag/scribe-doll/'>scribe doll</a>, <a href='http://scribedoll.wordpress.com/tag/writing/'>writing</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/639/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/639/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=639&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://scribedoll.wordpress.com/2012/08/12/the-delight-of-hand-writing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/670a1179cf2df7e4be4a8aa204440b1d?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">scribedoll</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://scribedoll.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/blog-img_05622.jpg?w=225" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Blog IMG_0562</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Adventures in Singapore: Shopping in Haji Lane</title>
		<link>http://unepetitemenagerie.wordpress.com/2012/08/11/adventures-in-singapore-shopping-in-haji-lane/</link>
		<comments>http://unepetitemenagerie.wordpress.com/2012/08/11/adventures-in-singapore-shopping-in-haji-lane/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2012 13:55:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>unepetitemenagerie</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clothes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clothing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[colorful]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fashion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[graffiti]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[haji lane]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hip]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hookah bars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shopping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[singapore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[street art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[style]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vacation]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://unepetitemenagerie.wordpress.com/?p=269</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Greetings from Singapore! I&#8217;ve been on the island for almost a week now and will be here until the 18th. It&#8217;s extremely warm and humid. I miss New York, but I&#8217;ll be back before I know it. Today, I headed over to Haji Lane, which is my all-time favorite place to shop in Singapore. I [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=269&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://unepetitemenagerie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/hafi.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-279" title="hafi" src="http://unepetitemenagerie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/hafi.jpg?w=480&h=317" alt="" width="480" height="317" /></a></p>
<p>Greetings from Singapore! I&#8217;ve been on the island for almost a week now and will be here until the 18th. It&#8217;s extremely warm and humid. I miss New York, but I&#8217;ll be back before I know it.</p>
<p>Today, I headed over to Haji Lane, which is my all-time favorite place to shop in Singapore. I consider it a little hipster alleyway, tucked neatly aside from the main streets. Here you will find a cluster of cute, independent boutiques filled with both international and local clothing, accessories, home goods and more. It&#8217;s also speckled with Middle Eastern cafes and hookah bars. Many buildings are covered in street art, so simply walking down the street is an experience in itself. I love that everything is so colorful; the vividness of the walls just creates such a wonderful vibe. It&#8217;s also a relatively short street, with stores flanking either side, but it still took me close to 4 hours to make it down and back (I entered almost every store).</p>
<div id="attachment_280" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 490px"><a href="http://unepetitemenagerie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/haj-copy.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-280" title="haj copy" src="http://unepetitemenagerie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/haj-copy.jpg?w=480&h=318" alt="" width="480" height="318" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">From a street off of Haji Lane. These shutters are so fucking awesome. WANT.</p></div>
<p style="text-align:left;"><a href="http://unepetitemenagerie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_16261.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-274" title="DSC_1626" src="http://unepetitemenagerie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_16261.jpg?w=480&h=318" alt="" width="480" height="318" /></a><a href="http://unepetitemenagerie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_1622.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-273" title="DSC_1622" src="http://unepetitemenagerie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_1622.jpg?w=480&h=318" alt="" width="480" height="318" /></a><a href="http://unepetitemenagerie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_1629.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-276" title="DSC_1629" src="http://unepetitemenagerie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_1629.jpg?w=480&h=318" alt="" width="480" height="318" /></a>I especially love shopping here because each boutique has its own personality; most of the store owners do a great job of creating fun, interesting and often cozy rooms in these old buildings. Most importantly, the merchandise is unique and just plain fun to look at, and everyone is sure to find something to suit his or her fancy.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://unepetitemenagerie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_16171.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-271" title="DSC_1617" src="http://unepetitemenagerie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_16171.jpg?w=480&h=318" alt="" width="480" height="318" /></a></p>
<div id="attachment_270" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 490px"><a href="http://unepetitemenagerie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_1615.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-270" title="DSC_1615" src="http://unepetitemenagerie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_1615.jpg?w=480&h=319" alt="" width="480" height="319" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Fixie store!</p></div>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://unepetitemenagerie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_1620.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-272" title="DSC_1620" src="http://unepetitemenagerie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_1620.jpg?w=480&h=361" alt="" width="480" height="361" /></a><a href="http://unepetitemenagerie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3075.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-289" title="IMG_3075" src="http://unepetitemenagerie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3075.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="640" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">I left after a successful albeit utterly exhausting solo shopping spree with: 1. a surprisingly amazing, slinky black dress that just looks like a piece of fabric on the hanger (hence no photo), 2. a studded collar shirt (&#8220;so edgy!&#8221; my mom exclaimed) because I am currently OBSESSED with studs, and 3. a sunny floral shirt. It was a very good day. Looking forward to my next visit.<a href="http://unepetitemenagerie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_16351.jpg"><img class="wp-image-284 aligncenter" title="DSC_1635" src="http://unepetitemenagerie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_16351.jpg?w=480&h=316" alt="" width="480" height="316" /></a><a href="http://unepetitemenagerie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_16421.jpg"><img class="wp-image-285 aligncenter" title="DSC_1642" src="http://unepetitemenagerie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_16421.jpg?w=480&h=314" alt="" width="480" height="314" /></a></p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://unepetitemenagerie.wordpress.com/category/uncategorized/'>Uncategorized</a> Tagged: <a href='http://unepetitemenagerie.wordpress.com/tag/clothes/'>clothes</a>, <a href='http://unepetitemenagerie.wordpress.com/tag/clothing/'>clothing</a>, <a href='http://unepetitemenagerie.wordpress.com/tag/colorful/'>colorful</a>, <a href='http://unepetitemenagerie.wordpress.com/tag/design/'>design</a>, <a href='http://unepetitemenagerie.wordpress.com/tag/fashion/'>fashion</a>, <a href='http://unepetitemenagerie.wordpress.com/tag/graffiti/'>graffiti</a>, <a href='http://unepetitemenagerie.wordpress.com/tag/haji-lane/'>haji lane</a>, <a href='http://unepetitemenagerie.wordpress.com/tag/hip/'>hip</a>, <a href='http://unepetitemenagerie.wordpress.com/tag/hookah-bars/'>hookah bars</a>, <a href='http://unepetitemenagerie.wordpress.com/tag/shopping/'>shopping</a>, <a href='http://unepetitemenagerie.wordpress.com/tag/singapore/'>singapore</a>, <a href='http://unepetitemenagerie.wordpress.com/tag/street-art/'>street art</a>, <a href='http://unepetitemenagerie.wordpress.com/tag/style/'>style</a>, <a href='http://unepetitemenagerie.wordpress.com/tag/travel/'>travel</a>, <a href='http://unepetitemenagerie.wordpress.com/tag/vacation/'>vacation</a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=269&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://unepetitemenagerie.wordpress.com/2012/08/11/adventures-in-singapore-shopping-in-haji-lane/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/e92619d27a8c7d4eec0c23684c644e1e?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">unepetitemenagerie</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://unepetitemenagerie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/hafi.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">hafi</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://unepetitemenagerie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/haj-copy.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">haj copy</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://unepetitemenagerie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_16261.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_1626</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://unepetitemenagerie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_1622.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_1622</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://unepetitemenagerie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_1629.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_1629</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://unepetitemenagerie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_16171.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_1617</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://unepetitemenagerie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_1615.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_1615</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://unepetitemenagerie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_1620.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_1620</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://unepetitemenagerie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_3075.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_3075</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://unepetitemenagerie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_16351.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_1635</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://unepetitemenagerie.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/dsc_16421.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_1642</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Grandma gets a smartphone</title>
		<link>http://piedtype.com/2012/08/11/grandma-gets-a-smartphone/</link>
		<comments>http://piedtype.com/2012/08/11/grandma-gets-a-smartphone/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2012 20:35:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>PiedType</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Media/Comm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[SciTech]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://piedtype.com/?p=25695</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Actually, despite the title, I don&#8217;t exactly have my new phone in hand yet. In theory I should have it, but there have been a few stumbling blocks along the way. First there were about two days of intensive web surfing and browsing, trying to make sense of all the calling plans offered by the [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=25695&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://piedtype.com/2012/08/11/grandma-gets-a-smartphone/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>21</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://piedtype.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/carriers1.jpg?w=120" />
		<media:content url="http://piedtype.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/carriers1.jpg?w=120" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">wireless carriers</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/13ef446214b9dc7ef5be19c26647eddc?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Pied Type</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://piedtype.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/carriers1.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">wireless carriers</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://piedtype.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/galaxys3.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Galaxy S3</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Screenplay: Preparation 3</title>
		<link>http://roguedoe.wordpress.com/2012/08/12/the-screenplay-preparation-3/</link>
		<comments>http://roguedoe.wordpress.com/2012/08/12/the-screenplay-preparation-3/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2012 05:15:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>roguedoe</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Silver Screen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Harry Potter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[how to write a screenplay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prisoner of azkaban]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[screenplay]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://roguedoe.wordpress.com/?p=3513</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Today the book informs me that my screenplay will be 120 pages long.  Ok.  I can live with that.  Also according to the book, the following events MUST take place on the following pages: Page 1: Immediately establish place, time, mood. Page 3: The question or idea that this story will explore. Page 10: What [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3513&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://roguedoe.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/cards1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3516" title="Cards1" src="http://roguedoe.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/cards1.jpg?w=500&h=348" alt="" width="500" height="348" /></a></p>
<p>Today <a href="http://www.amazon.com/How-Write-Movie-21-Days/dp/0062730665/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1344614775&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=how+to+write+a+screenplay+in+21+days" target="_blank">the book</a> informs me that my screenplay will be 120 pages long.  Ok.  I can live with that.  Also according to the book, the following events MUST take place on the following pages:</p>
<p><strong>Page 1:</strong> Immediately establish place, time, mood.<br />
<strong>Page 3:</strong> The question or idea that this story will explore.<br />
<strong>Page 10:</strong> What does the hero WANT? (Must relate to the question!)<br />
<strong>Page 30:</strong> Event happens that snatches the rug out from under hero.<br />
<strong>Page 45:</strong> Scene that begins hero&#8217;s growth.<br />
<strong>Page 60:</strong> Hero must COMMIT.<br />
<strong>Page 75:</strong> ALL IS LOST. (Then&#8230;maybe it isn&#8217;t.)<br />
<strong>Page 90:</strong> Beginning of the end.<br />
<strong>Page 120:</strong> Resolution.</p>
<p>I assume all screenplays do not rigidly follow this pattern, but let&#8217;s break down <em><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0304141/" target="_blank">The Prisoner of Azkaban</a></em> to see if it fits this formula.  I don&#8217;t have a copy of the <em>Prisoner of Azkaban </em>screenplay, so I&#8217;ll go by events I remember from the movie:</p>
<p><strong>Page 1:</strong> Harry&#8217;s hiding under his sheets, secretly doing his Hogwarts homework.<br />
<em>(Immediately establishes the conflict between the magic and the mundane.)</em></p>
<p><strong>Page 3: </strong> Harry is confronted by enormous dog.  Hears rumours of murderer Sirius Black.<br />
<em>(Main question of this film: who is Sirius Black?)</em></p>
<p><strong>Page 10: </strong> Difficult to tell what Harry wants at this point, but after the Dementors, I think what he wants most is to conquer his fear <em>(i.e. the Dementors).</em></p>
<p><strong>Page 30: </strong> GASP!  Sirius Black betrayed Harry&#8217;s parents!<br />
<em>(Talk about snatching the rug out from under someone&#8230;)</em></p>
<p><strong>Page 45: </strong> Harry decides he&#8217;s going to kill Sirius, if he can find him.  Cuz a thirteen year-old wizard can totally take on a mad mass murderer.<br />
<em>(This isn&#8217;t exactly what I call character growth, but it&#8217;s a new obsession for Harry.)</em></p>
<p><strong>Page 60:</strong>  Sirius snatches Ron.<br />
<em>(Harry&#8217;s going to save him, or die trying!)</em></p>
<p><strong>Page 75:</strong> Sirius has betrayed them!  Lupin has betrayed them!  No, Peter has betrayed them!<br />
<em>(All is lost!/No it&#8217;s not!/Yes, it is!)</em></p>
<p><strong>Page 90:</strong> DEMENTORS.</p>
<p><strong>Page 120:</strong> Harry is alone again, but not as alone as before.<br />
<em>(Resolution. The main themes of </em>Prisoner of Azkaban<em> are courage vs. fear, truth vs. falsehood, who people are vs. who they seem to be.)</em></p>
<p>I&#8217;m not sure I like this method of breaking down a story.  It seems very stiff and formulaic.   But I&#8217;ll go with it for now.  If I don&#8217;t like the results the formula gives me, I can always go back and chuck it out the window.  <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YqRd7T6HbuQ" target="_blank">(I prefer to think of them as guidelines rather than actual rules&#8230;)</a></p>
<p>Read <a href="http://roguedoe.wordpress.com/2012/08/10/the-screenplay-preparation/" target="_blank">Screenplay Preparation: Part 1</a>, <a href="http://roguedoe.wordpress.com/2012/08/10/the-screenplay-preparation-2/" target="_blank">Part 2</a>.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3513/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3513/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3513&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://roguedoe.wordpress.com/2012/08/12/the-screenplay-preparation-3/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/e4fa831402687fc0a06db5bf2a1ae54f?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">roguedoe</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://roguedoe.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/cards1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Cards1</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why did I skip these? Things I missed out on in Bolivia</title>
		<link>http://travelola.org/2012/08/12/bolivia-tourist-things-to-do-must-see/</link>
		<comments>http://travelola.org/2012/08/12/bolivia-tourist-things-to-do-must-see/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2012 09:16:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>finola</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[activity & sport]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bolivia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[south america]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lake Titicaca]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mines]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mountainbiking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[South America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://travelola.org/?p=2807</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[“A dominant impulse on encountering beauty is to wish to hold on to it, to possess it and give it weight in one’s life. There is an urge to say, ‘I was here, I saw this and it mattered to me.” ― Alain de Botton, The Art of Travel ‘You can’t come to Bolivia and [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2807&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://travelola.org/2012/08/12/bolivia-tourist-things-to-do-must-see/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">finolatravelola</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://blog.brazenbraden.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/05/lapaz.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fanfiction: What&#8217;s the use?</title>
		<link>http://kaitlinandmichaelbranch.com/2012/08/12/fanfiction-whats-the-use/</link>
		<comments>http://kaitlinandmichaelbranch.com/2012/08/12/fanfiction-whats-the-use/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2012 01:52:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Kaitlin</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Essays]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kaitlin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Book]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Musings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Philosophy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://kaitlinandmichaelbranch.com/?p=1456</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A great many bloggers I enjoy and admire have been talking about fanfiction in the last few months.  I&#8217;ve been quiet on this topic for the most part, even when I really want to jump in, because I know very well I&#8217;m biased.  I said it way back in my first post: my very first [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1456&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A great many bloggers I enjoy and admire have been talking about fanfiction in the last few months.  I&#8217;ve been quiet on this topic for the most part, even when I really want to jump in, because I know very well I&#8217;m biased.  I said it way back in my first post: my very first fumblings in writing were all fanfiction.</p>
<p>Fanfiction gets a bad rap.  At times, it deserves this.  If the only fanfiction you&#8217;ve ever read was &#8220;<a title="Ladies and Gentleman, please do not read without a glass of something strongly alcoholic, for your own safety." href="http://myimmortalrehost2.webs.com/">My Immortal</a>&#8221; (warning, have booze on standby for that one, my friends.)  then yeah, you&#8217;re going to think it&#8217;s dumb. But there are people who put real <a href="http://www.fanfiction.net/s/556538/1/Captain_My_Captain">effort</a> and thought into their fanfiction.</p>
<p>These kinds of fanfics have four things in common:  They respect the style of the original work, they use the world as a scaffold and not a crutch, they grow the characters, and they use English well.</p>
<p>What I&#8217;ve always found interesting is that many of the same principles apply in original fiction, so today I&#8217;m going to compare those principles and how they are applied in each aspect of writing.</p>
<p><strong>Respect of Style</strong></p>
<p>In fanfiction, this means that an author tries to take the writing or ambiance of the original work and put into their derivative.  Unless the author is going for comedy, they don&#8217;t write a Dark Souls fanfiction in a tone as sugar sweet as Disney movies.  While this is somewhat subjective, a fanfiction written in the same style as it&#8217;s original will almost always trump one written in an Alternate World.</p>
<p>In original fiction, this means respecting your genre.  There&#8217;s something to be said for genre breaking, but at the same time mislabeling your writing is akin to mislabeling the mayonnaise.  Reaching for vanilla pudding and getting mayonnaise would make anyone cranky, so if you&#8217;re going to write a romance novel, it needs to have some romancin&#8217; going on.  If you&#8217;re in the fantasy genre, something fantastic had better be happening.</p>
<p><strong>Strong Use of World</strong></p>
<p>In fanfic, this means the author knows what the world is.  They have studied it more extensively than &#8220;I read it once a while ago&#8221;.  Now, I&#8217;m not saying that to write a good fanfic you need to know every little detail, but the world should be familiar to you, and thus easy to access through the fanfiction.  It also means that the world is used to tell the story, and not <em>be </em>the story.</p>
<p>In original fiction, it&#8217;s the same thing, almost exactly.  We want and need characters, yes, but in a way the world should be it&#8217;s own character.  We should understand it well enough by the end of the story to give a basic run down of its characteristics. Maps are helpful, but they aren&#8217;t everything.  How big is it?  Are there many different land forms?  What&#8217;s the weather like?  My rule of thumb, actually, is to give an audience enough that writing a fanfiction would be easy and pleasurable, but avoid textbook numbers at all costs.  That means no &#8220;the population is X, the export is Y and the greatest import is Z.&#8221;</p>
<p><strong>Proper Use of English Language </strong></p>
<p>This is a no brainer on both counts.  Writing has rules for a reason.  When we write with the rules, readers can sink into the world.  When we break the rules, readers spend too much time working out what we&#8217;re trying to say.</p>
<p><strong>Dynamic Characters</strong></p>
<p>In fanfiction, you take a ready made character and then put them through trials and joys in order to change them in some way.  In original fiction, you <em>create </em>a character, and then put them through trials and joys in order to change them in some way.  Notice how the concept ran together after a little while?  This is the most important shared principle of fanfic and original writing.  In the end, both stories, and indeed, all stories, require <em>change.  </em>Whether you learn to orchestrate that change in fanfiction or original fiction, it&#8217;s up to you.</p>
<p>These four principles, once mastered in fanfic, can be fairly seamlessly transferred to original fiction.  There&#8217;s a lot of other hairy stuff to get through when striking a path into original fiction realms, such as world and character building from the ground up, but while fanfiction gets it&#8217;s bad rap from fumbling attempts at characterization and plot (and a dose of pretty-much-unethical publishing) it has it&#8217;s place and it has it&#8217;s uses.</p>
<p>What do you think?  Are you a fanfiction fan?  Did you cut your writing teeth on original or fan fiction?</p>
<p>Edit:  If you found your way here through Freshly Pressed, welcome and thank you for coming!  Here on the blog we write articles like this one, provide updates on our forthcoming books (see sidebar), and write a lot of flash fiction.  If you&#8217;d like to keep track our <a href="http://www.facebook.com/pages/The-Athele-Series/138271962938031">facebook </a>is here, and our <a href="https://twitter.com/TheAtheleSeries">twitter </a>is here.  Again, thank you for coming!</p>
<br /> Tagged: <a href='http://kaitlinandmichaelbranch.com/tag/blog/'>Blog</a>, <a href='http://kaitlinandmichaelbranch.com/tag/blogging/'>Blogging</a>, <a href='http://kaitlinandmichaelbranch.com/tag/book/'>Book</a>, <a href='http://kaitlinandmichaelbranch.com/tag/fiction/'>Fiction</a>, <a href='http://kaitlinandmichaelbranch.com/tag/musings/'>Musings</a>, <a href='http://kaitlinandmichaelbranch.com/tag/philosophy/'>Philosophy</a>, <a href='http://kaitlinandmichaelbranch.com/tag/writing/'>Writing</a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1456&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://kaitlinandmichaelbranch.com/2012/08/12/fanfiction-whats-the-use/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>29</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f1793458300ef64e2e60d3ed9d5e5731?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">eritta</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>It&#8217;s All in the Eyes: How an Optical Illusion May Help the Paralysed to Write</title>
		<link>http://nothingmentionednothinggained.wordpress.com/2012/08/12/its-all-in-the-eyes-how-an-optical-illusion-may-help-the-paralysed-to-write/</link>
		<comments>http://nothingmentionednothinggained.wordpress.com/2012/08/12/its-all-in-the-eyes-how-an-optical-illusion-may-help-the-paralysed-to-write/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2012 08:46:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>NE</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Disability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Eye movement (sensory)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Innovation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jean-Dominique Bauby]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Locked-in Syndrome]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New Scientist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Optical illusion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Paralysis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pierre and Marie Curie University]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reverse Phi Motion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nothingmentionednothinggained.wordpress.com/?p=339</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Some things are just too terrible for my mind to process. The story of Richard Marsh, who woke up in intensive care following a stroke with &#8221;full cognitive and physical awareness, but an almost complete paralysis of nearly all the voluntary muscles in my body&#8221; to hear doctors discussing whether to switch off his life support machine, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=339&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Some things are just too terrible for my mind to process. The story of Richard Marsh, who woke up in intensive care following a stroke with &#8221;full cognitive and physical awareness, but an almost complete paralysis of nearly all the voluntary muscles in my body&#8221; to hear doctors discussing whether to switch off his life support machine, was one of the most harrowing things I have ever read. A religious person would have read that story and prayed &#8211; but my instinctive reaction was to hope that science would find a way to make these terrible situations better. And as it happened, just two days after I read Marsh&#8217;s story in the Guardian, New Scientist carried a story of an amazing new technology that will allow locked-in survivors to communicate much more naturally and easily than they do now.</p>
<p>Amazingly, Marsh recovered and now has a healthy and active lifestyle. He has recovered 95% of his <a class="zem_slink" title="Cognition" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cognition" rel="wikipedia" target="_blank">cognitive ability</a> and has even taken up cycling. Other sufferers of <a class="zem_slink" title="Locked-in syndrome" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Locked-in_syndrome" rel="wikipedia" target="_blank">locked-in syndrome</a> are not so lucky but once it is recognised that their cognitive ability is intact, they may be able to communicate by blinking. French author <a class="zem_slink" title="Jean-Dominique Bauby" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jean-Dominique_Bauby" rel="wikipedia" target="_blank">Jean-Dominique Bauby</a> dictated his entire memoir, <a class="zem_slink" title="Le Scaphandre et le Papillon (The Diving Bell and the Butterfly)" href="http://www.rottentomatoes.com/m/diving_bell_and_the_butterfly" rel="rottentomatoes" target="_blank">The Diving Bell and the Butterfly</a>, by blinking, and the Sun carried a remarkable story of an even more remarkable woman and her inspiring young family who are living and loving life even though she is paralysed from the neck down. Her husband reads the alphabet to her and she blinks at the relevant letters to spell out her thoughts.</p>
<div id="attachment_345" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://nothingmentionednothinggained.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/eye.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-345" title="eye" src="http://nothingmentionednothinggained.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/eye.jpg?w=300&h=205" alt="" width="300" height="205" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">In locked-in syndrome, the eye is often the only voluntary muscle that can be moved at will.</p></div>
<p>This is inspiring and deeply moving, but one thing it cannot be is easy. Marsh described his lonliness in the long nights spent alone at the hospital, &#8221;the loneliess of knowing there&#8217;s no one there who really understands how to communicate with you.&#8221;</p>
<p>People have investigated using the eyes to write before now, but this is difficult as our eyes constantly make fast, jerky movements called saccade. When we look at something, we our eyes are constantly moving even if we think our gaze is fixed. Our eyes focus on something, then move, stop, move, stop again &#8211; much faster even than the blink of an eye. This enables us to see much more effriciently, but as we cannot consciously control the speed at which our eyes move in between stops, it has made it challenging for us to move our eyes smoothly enough to trace out letters that people around us can read.</p>
<p>But Jean Lorenceau, a researcher at the Pierre and Marie Curie University, Paris, has developed an ingenious <a class="zem_slink" title="Optical illusion" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Optical_illusion" rel="wikipedia" target="_blank">optical illusion</a>that will trick our eyes into moving</p>
<div class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://commons.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Ilusion_star.svg" target="_blank"><img class="zemanta-img-inserted zemanta-img-configured" title="English: This is an optical illusion in which ..." src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/d/de/Ilusion_star.svg/300px-Ilusion_star.svg.png" alt="English: This is an optical illusion in which ..." width="300" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">English: This is an optical illusion in which a static image appears to be moving due to the cognitive effects of interacting color contrasts and shape position. (Photo credit: Wikipedia).</p></div>
<p>smoothly &#8211; smoothly enough that we can draw with them. For all the locked-in patients in the world, this could change their lives. Unable to move, they must rely on others to meet every physical need, and the ability to communicate is absolutely essential. Marsh remembers some rough handling in hospital &#8211; this was probably not intentional, but when Marsh had no way to tell the nurses that he was uncomfortable, they could not have known to be more gentle. The ability to write will surely make it easier for locked-in patients to meet and communicate with new people &#8211; people who aren&#8217;t already familiar with the blinking system that a particular person has developed for their own use.</p>
<p>Phi motion is the technology used to convert still pictures into a moving film. Lorenceau has used a technology called &#8220;reverse phi motion.&#8221; By changing the colour of an object, that object can appear to be moving backwards. It&#8217;s a strange concept, and hard to believe until you&#8217;ve seen it:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.michaelbach.de/ot/mot_reverse-phi/index.html">http://www.michaelbach.de/ot/mot_reverse-phi/index.html</a></p>
<p>Lorenceau was idly watching an illusion just like this one when he noticed that his eyes were doing something unexpected &#8211; they were following a field of flickering dots smoothly, without saccade. This type of eye movement, called smooth pursuit, is what we use to track moving objects, but it is difficult for us to start and maintain it. Partly this is because when we are tracking a moving object, the still background constantly slips away from the moving object, injucing saccades. But reverse phi motion is different in that the background appears to move with a moving object, making it possible for us to track something smoothly.</p>
<p>Lorenceau has since designed his own reverse phi display, featuring 200 disks that switch between black and white and are projected on a gray background. People follow a moving dot with their eyes, and the reverse phi motion keeps their movement smooth enough that a gaze-tracking camera can follow the right eye&#8217;s movements and use them to move a cursor on a screen which will spell out words and sentences.</p>
<p>This technique is not natural, and Lorenceau did note that some people could pick it up much more readily than others. However, 6 volunteers were trained to control their <a class="zem_slink" title="Eye movement (sensory)" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eye_movement_%28sensory%29" rel="wikipedia" target="_blank">eye movements</a> in just three 30 minute sessions. Lorenceau is currently perfecting his training so that the technique can be learned by anyone, including paralysed patients. He seems to think it is possible &#8221;It&#8217;s like surfing, you move your eyes to get on the wave and once you&#8217;re on you just slide with it.&#8221;</p>
<h6 class="zemanta-related-title" style="font-size:1em;">Related articles</h6>
<ul class="zemanta-article-ul">
<li class="zemanta-article-ul-li"><a href="http://www.newscientist.com/article/mg21528766.100-gazetracking-illusion-lets-you-draw-with-your-eyes.html?DCMP=OTC-rss&amp;nsref=online-news" target="_blank">Gaze-tracking illusion lets you draw with your eyes</a> (newscientist.com)</li>
<li class="zemanta-article-ul-li"><a href="http://r.zemanta.com/?u=http%3A//www.guardian.co.uk/world/2012/aug/07/locked-in-syndrome-richard-marsh&amp;a=105124001&amp;rid=000001fa-fadc-000F-0000-000000000153&amp;e=f4846bd524aeea0f6bf1d81eecac9a64" target="_blank">Locked-in syndrome: rare survivor Richard Marsh recounts his ordeal</a> (guardian.co.uk)</li>
<li class="zemanta-article-ul-li"><a href="http://news.sciencemag.org/sciencenow/2012/07/write-to-me-only-with-thine-eyes.html?rss=1" target="_blank">Write to Me Only With Thine Eyes</a> (news.sciencemag.org)</li>
<li class="zemanta-article-ul-li"><a href="http://www.thesun.co.uk/sol/homepage/features/4254293/Brave-mum-with-locked-in-syndrome-vows-to-see-her-kids-grow-up.html#ixzz23GGgwiXV">http://www.thesun.co.uk/sol/homepage/features/4254293/Brave-mum-with-locked-in-syndrome-vows-to-see-her-kids-grow-up.html#ixzz23GGgwiXV</a></li>
</ul>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/339/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/339/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=339&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://nothingmentionednothinggained.wordpress.com/2012/08/12/its-all-in-the-eyes-how-an-optical-illusion-may-help-the-paralysed-to-write/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>19</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/4157a0de252ca454114118b00432c94f?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">naomistravels</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nothingmentionednothinggained.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/eye.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">eye</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/d/de/Ilusion_star.svg/300px-Ilusion_star.svg.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">English: This is an optical illusion in which ...</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Kasubi Tombs, a piece of history, very much alive</title>
		<link>http://worldsheritagetravel.wordpress.com/2012/08/12/kasubi-tombs-a-piece-of-history-very-much-alive/</link>
		<comments>http://worldsheritagetravel.wordpress.com/2012/08/12/kasubi-tombs-a-piece-of-history-very-much-alive/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2012 14:17:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>minqan</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Africa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[City]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Buganda]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kampala]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tombs of kings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uganda]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://worldsheritagetravel.wordpress.com/?p=628</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Finally I returned to Africa. This great continent is like a magnet for me and I wish to return to its heat, its coolness, its deserts, its green jungles and savannahs. Its great animals are in my dreams, Kilimanjaro is a still unreached goal and its cities make me curious and its people make me [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=628&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://worldsheritagetravel.wordpress.com/2012/08/12/kasubi-tombs-a-piece-of-history-very-much-alive/001_top2/" rel="attachment wp-att-669"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-669" title="001_top2" src="http://worldsheritagetravel.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/001_top2.jpg" alt="sunrise" width="580" height="190" /></a></p>
<p><strong>Finally I returned to Africa. This great continent is like a magnet for me and I wish to return to its heat, its coolness, its deserts, its green jungles and savannahs. Its great animals are in my dreams, Kilimanjaro is a still unreached goal and its cities make me curious and its people make me happy.</strong></p>
<div id="attachment_670" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 590px"><a href="http://worldsheritagetravel.wordpress.com/2012/08/12/kasubi-tombs-a-piece-of-history-very-much-alive/142_towns_tea/" rel="attachment wp-att-670"><img class="size-full wp-image-670" title="142_towns_tea" src="http://worldsheritagetravel.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/142_towns_tea.jpg" alt="Tea plantation" width="580" height="385" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Tea plantation</p></div>
<div id="attachment_671" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 590px"><a href="http://worldsheritagetravel.wordpress.com/2012/08/12/kasubi-tombs-a-piece-of-history-very-much-alive/150_towns_tomatos/" rel="attachment wp-att-671"><img class="size-full wp-image-671" title="150_towns_tomatos" src="http://worldsheritagetravel.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/150_towns_tomatos.jpg" alt="tomatos" width="580" height="320" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Selling tomatos, yes we bought a few</p></div>
<p>I was on a trip to Masai Mara National Park and gorillas in Uganda and few things there between. I will write about the whole trip later. One of th stops we made on the way, during the trip was Kampala and in Kampala the Kasubi Tombs of kings of Buganda. That&#8217;s right, Buganda. Buganda is a subnational kingdom within Uganda. On the way to Kampala we saw wonderful sunrise, we saw people transporting bananaas to a market on their bikes. We passed tea plantations, lots of them.In the market they were picked up by a truck. We saw small shop selling tomatos and pineapples. We stop at a place like that, where we got some pineapples for the lunch. Jany wanted to get two or three tomaos, he got about five kilos, maybe more.</p>
<div id="attachment_672" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 590px"><a href="http://worldsheritagetravel.wordpress.com/2012/08/12/kasubi-tombs-a-piece-of-history-very-much-alive/151_towns_banana/" rel="attachment wp-att-672"><img class="size-full wp-image-672" title="151_towns_banana" src="http://worldsheritagetravel.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/151_towns_banana.jpg" alt="banana transport" width="580" height="430" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Banana transport . This looks heavy.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_673" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 590px"><a href="http://worldsheritagetravel.wordpress.com/2012/08/12/kasubi-tombs-a-piece-of-history-very-much-alive/151_towns_banana2/" rel="attachment wp-att-673"><img class="size-full wp-image-673" title="151_towns_banana2" src="http://worldsheritagetravel.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/151_towns_banana2.jpg" alt="banana transport" width="580" height="385" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Banana transport version 2.0.</p></div>
<p>In Kampala we stayed there in a noisy camping, called Red Chili. The camping site was OK, there was wireless internet in the bar and a pool. But the place was crowded with people that wanted to party, so it was noisy and maybe not so good if you wanted to sleep. Thanks heaven for earplugs.</p>
<div id="attachment_674" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 590px"><a href="http://worldsheritagetravel.wordpress.com/2012/08/12/kasubi-tombs-a-piece-of-history-very-much-alive/156_towns_tombs_enter/" rel="attachment wp-att-674"><img class="size-full wp-image-674" title="156_towns_tombs_enter" src="http://worldsheritagetravel.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/156_towns_tombs_enter.jpg" alt="entering Kasubi Tombs" width="580" height="385" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Entering the Kasubi Tombs</p></div>
<p>Kampala is the capital of Uganda. It’s a big city, a bit chaotic, ugly and charming at the same time. We didn’t spend so much time there, but enough to go to a coffee shop and a market. Both were better than good. Ugandan coffee is truly nice and the market had some really nice crafts. I bought a mask for my collection and a comb.</p>
<div id="attachment_675" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 590px"><a href="http://worldsheritagetravel.wordpress.com/2012/08/12/kasubi-tombs-a-piece-of-history-very-much-alive/156_towns_tombs_enter2/" rel="attachment wp-att-675"><img class="size-full wp-image-675" title="156_towns_tombs_enter2" src="http://worldsheritagetravel.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/156_towns_tombs_enter2.jpg" alt="Kasubi Tombs" width="580" height="385" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Kasubi Tombs</p></div>
<p>We travelled by minibuses, called matatu, together with locals. It was an interesting experience, in a good way. We travelled through poor neighborhoods and better ones.  The poorer ones were packed with sheds, people, vibrant and full with life. The poverty was obvious and painful, children looking in garbage, dogs running around. It was some sort of organized chaos. We were told that there are about three million people in Kampala plus those living in that kind of places. There were butcheries with meat hanging outside, there were stuff everywhere, the streets were narrow and dusty.</p>
<div id="attachment_676" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 590px"><a href="http://worldsheritagetravel.wordpress.com/2012/08/12/kasubi-tombs-a-piece-of-history-very-much-alive/157_towns_tombs-2/" rel="attachment wp-att-676"><img class="size-full wp-image-676" title="157_towns_tombs" src="http://worldsheritagetravel.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/157_towns_tombs.jpg" alt="Kasubi Tombs" width="580" height="385" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Kasubi Tombs, roof inside one of the buildings</p></div>
<p>And then we went up on a hill to Tombs of Buganda Kings at Kasubi. This is the site of the burial grounds for four kabakas (kings of Buganda), and a UNESCO World Heritage Site since 2001. On 16 March 2010, some of the major buildings there were almost completely destroyed by a fire, the cause of which is under investigation. The site id being rebuilt.</p>
<div id="attachment_677" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 590px"><a href="http://worldsheritagetravel.wordpress.com/2012/08/12/kasubi-tombs-a-piece-of-history-very-much-alive/158_towns_tombs/" rel="attachment wp-att-677"><img class="size-full wp-image-677" title="158_towns_tombs" src="http://worldsheritagetravel.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/158_towns_tombs.jpg" alt="Kasubi Tombs" width="580" height="385" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Kasubi Tombs, the yard with some houses</p></div>
<p>Our gouide told us history of this amazing place, history of the kingdom of Buganda and history of Uganda. He showed us pictures of the kings. The kabakas buried at the site were:</p>
<ul>
<li>Muteesa I (1835–1884)</li>
<li>Mwanga II (1867–1903)</li>
<li>Daudi Chwa II (1896–1939)</li>
<li>Sir Edward Muteesa II (1924–1969).</li>
</ul>
<p>Suddenly we realized how little we actually know about recent history of this huge continent and this country. O rguide told us also about Idi Amin, how&#8217;s he got the power, the pretty good start and how monstruos he became. The history very much alive.</p>
<div id="attachment_678" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 590px"><a href="http://worldsheritagetravel.wordpress.com/2012/08/12/kasubi-tombs-a-piece-of-history-very-much-alive/159_towns_tombs/" rel="attachment wp-att-678"><img class="size-full wp-image-678" title="159_towns_tombs" src="http://worldsheritagetravel.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/159_towns_tombs.jpg" alt="Kasubi Tombs" width="580" height="356" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Kasubi Tombs, view from the top of the hill</p></div>
<p>We walked out in the area and looked at the tombs, looked at the houses and were told that desendants of the kings and their wives still live here. The heritage site is very much alive. We saw a women in great African dress with vibrant colors walk across the courtyard, we saw a guy with a goat, we saw children.Even if it is a museum, it still is home of people. The view from the hill was of the entire Kampala. The sunsets must be magnificent from here.</p>
<div id="attachment_679" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 590px"><a href="http://worldsheritagetravel.wordpress.com/2012/08/12/kasubi-tombs-a-piece-of-history-very-much-alive/159_towns_tombs2/" rel="attachment wp-att-679"><img class="size-full wp-image-679" title="159_towns_tombs2" src="http://worldsheritagetravel.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/159_towns_tombs2.jpg" alt="Kasubi Tombs" width="580" height="478" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Kasubi Tombs, woman, maybe she lives there?</p></div>
<p>After visiting the tombs we went back into the city for some lunch. We found a place on top of a building with a pretty nice view of the city, sat down and ordered sandwiches. The waiter came back few minutes lter telling us that they don&#8217;t have sandwiches, only goat. Never had a goat in my life, but this was too strange situation to try it. But the guys in our group decided for goat anyways. Well, the story doesn&#8217;t end here. After a while the waiter came back with a womderful question: &#8220;Do you want a dry or wet goat?&#8221; The difference was that both were stew, but one was cooked with veggies, the other without. I tried the wet goat from Jany&#8217;s plate and it was OK. We survived the lunch, one experience richer.</p>
<div id="attachment_682" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 590px"><a href="http://worldsheritagetravel.wordpress.com/2012/08/12/kasubi-tombs-a-piece-of-history-very-much-alive/159_towns_sunrise/" rel="attachment wp-att-682"><img class="size-full wp-image-682" title="159_towns_sunrise" src="http://worldsheritagetravel.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/159_towns_sunrise.jpg" alt="sunrise" width="580" height="367" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Sunrise in Uganda</p></div>
<p>Kampala is a city, maybe a little charming, but still a city with traffuc, dust and lots of things happening, but not to much nature to enjoy. If you pass it, go visit the tombs. The s<a href="http://whc.unesco.org/en/list/1022" target="_blank">ite (take a look at the link)</a> is worth it. How many globes? This is hard. Visually, maybe three, the history told by the guide: five, view from the hill: four or five. My grade is four globes out of five.</p>
<p><a href="http://worldsheritagetravel.wordpress.com/?attachment_id=140"><img title="globe" src="http://worldsheritagetravel.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/globe.jpg?w=33&h=35" alt="Globe" width="33" height="35" /></a><a href="http://worldsheritagetravel.wordpress.com/?attachment_id=140"><img title="globe" src="http://worldsheritagetravel.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/globe.jpg?w=33&h=35" alt="Globe" width="33" height="35" /></a><a href="http://worldsheritagetravel.wordpress.com/?attachment_id=140"><img title="globe" src="http://worldsheritagetravel.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/globe.jpg?w=33&h=35" alt="Globe" width="33" height="35" /></a><a href="http://worldsheritagetravel.wordpress.com/?attachment_id=140"><img title="globe" src="http://worldsheritagetravel.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/globe.jpg?w=33&h=35" alt="Globe" width="33" height="35" /></a></p>
<p>//Monika</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/628/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/628/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=628&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://worldsheritagetravel.wordpress.com/2012/08/12/kasubi-tombs-a-piece-of-history-very-much-alive/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/30d033346193a1760d08e68a32bfdd53?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">minqan</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://worldsheritagetravel.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/001_top2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">001_top2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://worldsheritagetravel.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/142_towns_tea.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">142_towns_tea</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://worldsheritagetravel.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/150_towns_tomatos.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">150_towns_tomatos</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://worldsheritagetravel.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/151_towns_banana.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">151_towns_banana</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://worldsheritagetravel.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/151_towns_banana2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">151_towns_banana2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://worldsheritagetravel.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/156_towns_tombs_enter.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">156_towns_tombs_enter</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://worldsheritagetravel.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/156_towns_tombs_enter2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">156_towns_tombs_enter2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://worldsheritagetravel.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/157_towns_tombs.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">157_towns_tombs</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://worldsheritagetravel.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/158_towns_tombs.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">158_towns_tombs</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://worldsheritagetravel.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/159_towns_tombs.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">159_towns_tombs</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://worldsheritagetravel.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/159_towns_tombs2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">159_towns_tombs2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://worldsheritagetravel.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/159_towns_sunrise.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">159_towns_sunrise</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://worldsheritagetravel.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/globe.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">globe</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://worldsheritagetravel.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/globe.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">globe</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://worldsheritagetravel.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/globe.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">globe</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://worldsheritagetravel.files.wordpress.com/2012/05/globe.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">globe</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Do You Choose Your Next Book?</title>
		<link>http://beautyisasleepingcat.wordpress.com/2012/08/12/how-do-you-choose-your-next-book/</link>
		<comments>http://beautyisasleepingcat.wordpress.com/2012/08/12/how-do-you-choose-your-next-book/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2012 14:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Caroline</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reading]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://beautyisasleepingcat.wordpress.com/?p=8299</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I just finished a novel by a Canadian author and while I was still reading that book, I was thinking of what I might want to read next. Every day I picked a title and put it under the book I was reading on my nightstand. The books kept on changing. Some candidates returned more [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=8299&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://beautyisasleepingcat.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/p1020074.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-8313" title="Livres" src="http://beautyisasleepingcat.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/p1020074.jpg" alt="" width="510" height="382" /></a></p>
<p>I just finished a novel by a Canadian author and while I was still reading that book, I was thinking of what I might want to read next. Every day I picked a title and put it under the book I was reading on my nightstand. The books kept on changing. Some candidates returned more than once and after a while I realized, they all had a common theme: 18th/19th century France. So either I was going to read a historical French novel (Chantal Thomas&#8217; <a href="http://www.amazon.fr/Les-Adieux-à-reine-Femina/dp/2020868628/ref=sr_1_sc_2?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1344751645&amp;sr=8-2-spell">Les Adieux à la reine</a> &#8211; <a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Farewell-My-Queen-Chantal-Thomas/dp/075382017X/ref=sr_1_sc_1?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1344751547&amp;sr=1-1-spell">Farewell my Queen</a>) or a French classic (Maupassant&#8217;s <a href="http://www.amazon.fr/Bel-Ami-Guy-Maupassant/dp/207040935X/ref=sr_1_4?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1344751690&amp;sr=1-4">Bel-Ami</a> fr. <a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Bel-ami-Classics-Guy-Maupassant/dp/0140443150/ref=sr_1_3?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1344751595&amp;sr=1-3">Bel-Ami</a> engl.). Funny enough both books have just been made into movies.</p>
<p>This made me wonder, how other people choose the books they are going to read next. I&#8217;m a mood reader and on top of that my moods change quite fast that&#8217;s why I never really know what I&#8217;m going to read until I finally start it. Before I do so however, I will have begun at least 5 &#8211; 10 books, reading first pages and first paragraphs. The only thing that is likely is that the book following the one I just finished will be very different. I will hardly ever read a crime novel after having finished one or a French classic after having come to the end of another French classic. It can happen but it is rare.</p>
<p>Unfortunately my system is faulty. Because I often give in to momentary moods, instead of waiting for an underlying theme to emerge, by the time I&#8217;m in the middle of a novel, it&#8217;s not always exactly what I wanted anymore. That&#8217;s when novellas and short stories come in handy. I&#8217;ll put the novel aside and read the one or the other shorter piece in between.</p>
<p>Last November I did something which proved to be really good. I made a list of all the novels, I felt like reading during the month, especially those which kept on returning, and in December I started to read from that list and whenever I finished a book, I picked the next one from my list. It worked really well and I didn&#8217;t pick one dud.</p>
<p>So, that&#8217;s me, usually, not able to tell you before I started it, what book I&#8217;m going to read next. And unfortunately forgetting those I felt like reading unless I make a note. The only exception of course is my readalong and some of the readalongs of others.</p>
<p>I have seen on other blogs that some people make a list for the whole year and stick to it. They will not necessarily read in order but they will pick books from the list. Others love an author so much that they will read their way through his or her books. Some have a small pile they read and then they make another small pile. Someone reads all the books from one editor. I know there are bloggers who only buy a book after having finished one, so the trip to the book shop will determine the next choice. Others will go to the library, bring home a huge amount of books, dip into them and finally settle for a very few.</p>
<p>While I don&#8217;t review them very often,when it comes to non-fiction I&#8217;m much more systematic. One book will lead to the next and most of them are connected.</p>
<p>As you can see, there is no end to the possibilities. I&#8217;m really curious to find out how you do it. Do you follow a plan or a list? Do you pick randomly? Do you stick to a genre?</p>
<p>How do you choose your next book?</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/8299/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/8299/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=8299&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://beautyisasleepingcat.wordpress.com/2012/08/12/how-do-you-choose-your-next-book/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>184</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/457b189b23563592957ee3ca857ebdde?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">beautyisasleepingcat</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://beautyisasleepingcat.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/p1020074.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Livres</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>