<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2011 19:42:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Cases of the Mondays doubled in US since 2008</title>
		<link>http://cassiebehle.wordpress.com/2011/03/28/cases-of-the-mondays-doubled-in-us-since-2008/</link>
		<comments>http://cassiebehle.wordpress.com/2011/03/28/cases-of-the-mondays-doubled-in-us-since-2008/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2011 18:37:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>cassiebehle</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creative writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sarcasm]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cassiebehle.wordpress.com/?p=172</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON—As weekend festivities draw to an close and another Monday morning quickly approaches,  workers everywhere are seen trudging to work in a manner that suggests they’re about to meet their maker. That is, those who even bother to show up at all. The Center of Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) released a detailed report today [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=172&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>WASHINGTON—As weekend festivities draw to an close and another Monday morning quickly approaches,  workers everywhere are seen trudging to work in a manner that suggests they’re about to meet their maker. That is, those who even bother to show up at all.</p>
<p>The Center of Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) released a detailed report today revealing startlingly new statistics on the spread of cases of the Mondays throughout the U.S. The report confirmed that cases of the Mondays has doubled since 2008, a statistic that has grown as exponentially as the recent worrisome outbreak of girls posing in photos with the highly contagious <a href="http://x90.xanga.com/00df725139032256887625/z204380310.jpg">fish lip pucker</a>. Shudder.</p>
<p>“I should be out there playing a round of golf with my buddies right now,” said a cranky President and CEO of CDC John Ashton, “but instead, I’m being a grownup and giving you this professional interview.”</p>
<p>“Seriously, look how nice it is outside! Stupid work always gets in the way of my fun,” he added, with the perfected pout of a three-year-old about to throw a monstrous tantrum.</p>
<p>The symptoms of a case of the Mondays include grudgingly attending work Monday morning after a feverish attempt to think of an excuse out of it late Sunday night. Symptoms can also include bitter feelings, loss of motivation, and nausea at the thought of not completing the big project that was due last Friday. Oftentimes these symptoms can develop into a serious bout of hooky. If you haven’t attended work for three or more days in a row or don’t know if you even still have a job, it is advised you seek a physician immediately.</p>
<p>So how do you know when you’ve got a bad case of the Mondays?</p>
<p>“It’s harder to tell than you think,” acclaimed case of the Mondays expert Sandra Williams told the press, “but if you’re one of the 95 percent of Facebook users who use their status to complain that it’s Monday EVERY Monday, you’re probably at risk.”</p>
<p>Because the onset of case of the Mondays’ symptoms almost always appear like clockwork Sunday, some workers often confuse a stubborn hangover for the disease. Doctors nationwide have seen a rash of workers coming into the office and mistaking the two, and are urging workers to forego an unnecessary trip to the clinic. Instead, they recommend workers take two Tylenol, drink plenty of water, calm the $*%&amp; down and grow up already.</p>
<p>The CDC recommends that certain people acquire the case of the Mondays vaccine as soon as possible to prevent the disease from spiraling out of control. These target groups include men and women between the ages of 23-65, breadwinners who support a family of 12 or more, superheroes and President Obama.</p>
<p>For those who cannot afford the costly vaccine, support groups are being held in major metropolitan areas every Sunday evening. Consult your local Chamber of Commerce to find times and locations in a city near you.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/172/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/172/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/172/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/172/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/172/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/172/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/172/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/172/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/172/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/172/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/172/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/172/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/172/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/172/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=172&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://cassiebehle.wordpress.com/2011/03/28/cases-of-the-mondays-doubled-in-us-since-2008/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/69a5ced5647864c3eda8115ba27c360f?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cassiebehle</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>National Marathon Race Recap</title>
		<link>http://thechaseproject.com/2011/03/27/national-marathon-race-recap/</link>
		<comments>http://thechaseproject.com/2011/03/27/national-marathon-race-recap/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2011 13:03:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Chase</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Exercise]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Running]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Self Esteem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[believing in yourself]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marathon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[national marathon]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thechaseproject.com/?p=3876</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Before I begin, I want to say thank you to each and every one of you who has joined me along this 18 week journey of training for my first marathon!  After the race yesterday, I definitely had a feeling of post-race disbelief, &#8220;it&#8217;s already over?&#8221;  It seemed such a long time coming and then the [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=3876&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://thechaseproject.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/0162.jpg"></a><a href="http://thechaseproject.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/017-11.jpg"></a><a href="http://thechaseproject.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/018.jpg"></a>Before I begin, I want to say <em>thank you</em> to each and every one of you who has joined me along this 18 week journey of training for my first marathon!  After the race yesterday, I definitely had a feeling of post-race disbelief, &#8220;it&#8217;s already over?&#8221;  It seemed such a long time coming and then the day came and went in a flash.</p>
<p>In the day and a half after I wrote my <a title="This is it." href="http://thechaseproject.com/2011/03/24/this-is-it/" target="_blank">last post</a>, I started preparing myself for the race.  I planned out my race outfit complete with long tights and gloves.  The forecast was calling for mid 30&#8242;s on Saturday morning and I was completely happy with that, because it was exactly what I had trained in the entire time.  My last long race, <a title="What I did wrong." href="http://thechaseproject.com/2010/10/19/what-i-did-wrong/" target="_blank">I felt unprepared </a>because I&#8217;d trained in the heat and race day was cool.  So for me, this was perfect.</p>
<p><a href="http://thechaseproject.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/015-11.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-3883" title="015-1" src="http://thechaseproject.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/015-11.jpg?w=410&#038;h=450" alt="" width="410" height="450" /></a></p>
<p>Over the 18 weeks of training, I became not only accustomed to running in the cold, but a huge fan of it.  I&#8217;d much rather bundle up and go out than feel like my inards are boiling because of the heat and humidity (which DC has lots of in July &amp; August). </p>
<p>The night before, my big carbo-loading meal was a half a loaf of french baguette with peanut butter.  Not interesting or special, but it was safe and I knew exactly how my body would react to it.  No worries of being up half the night with stomach upset because of foods I don&#8217;t typically eat.</p>
<p>On race day, I set 3 alarms&#8230; one for 4:30, one for 4:45 and one for 4:50, just in case.  I did snooze the first alarm out of habit but the second one got me up and moving quickly.  I managed to sleep pretty well minus a short awake period around 2:30.  I fell back asleep within a half an hour and dreamed typical marathon anxiety dreams &#8220;Oh no! I overslept!&#8221; and  &#8220;Oh no!  My contacts are a big as eggshells and I can&#8217;t put them in!&#8221; <em> Ok that&#8217;s not necessarily a &#8220;typical&#8221; dream&#8230;</em></p>
<p>I got up, drank a cup of coffee with soy creamer and ate a banana, got all my stuff together and Jeff and I were out the door at 5:25.  The start time was 7am, and we were about 30 minutes away.  Because the Metro wasn&#8217;t running early enough for the race, we expected traffic getting to the start.  There was lots of free parking available, but the lines just to get into the lot took us an extra 30 minutes.  We parked just around 6:30, hit up the &#8220;chemical toilets&#8221; as they were called in race literature (I usually say porta-potties) and went to meet Jen.</p>
<p>Jen and her boyfriend Rob came down from Baltimore for this race and I was super excited to see them! I didn&#8217;t actually get to see Rob because he was ushered off to the front of the start as an Elite runner.  He finished yesterday&#8217;s half-marathon in 1:16:52!  Thats a 5:52 pace!  I don&#8217;t think I could run that for one mile!  (If they ever get married and have kids they&#8217;re going to be bionic runner babies.)</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><img title="016" src="http://thechaseproject.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/0162.jpg?w=640&#038;h=480" alt="" width="640" height="480" /></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">It was early and cold, but I was so excited to see Jen.  She was running the half and we were in different corrals (I was all the way in the back!) but I (shhhhh) snuck into her corral with her so we could run together.  The nice thing about this race is that it&#8217;s small enough that both races start together and run together for pretty much the first 13 miles.  I was delighted to run with her because I thought it would help break up my race so it didn&#8217;t seem so long and lonely. </p>
<p style="text-align:left;">And it did. </p>
<p style="text-align:left;">The first thirteen miles flew by.  We chatted and caught up, we thanked all the crowds for their enthusiastic cheering, we slapped high-fives with the Howard University students and we just enjoyed ourselves.  The crowd support during the first thirteen miles was awesome.  Regrettably, I missed <a href="http://www.healthytippingpoint.com/2011/03/national-half-marathon.html" target="_blank">Emily and Caitlin </a>and their sign reading &#8220;Run bloggers!&#8221; (I think because Jen and I were too engaged in conversation!) but the other signs we saw were awesome.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>Hey!  You in the tights, Nice butt!</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>Your feet hurt because you&#8217;re kicking so much @$$!</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>Go Harder! Go Faster!  </strong><em>(guy holding next sign) </em><strong>That&#8217;s what she said!</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><strong>You&#8217;re really good at exercising! </strong></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">A lot of people cheered &#8220;Go Jen!&#8221; when they saw her shirt and then sometimes also yelled, &#8220;Go Jen&#8217;s running partner!&#8221;   <em>Note to self: make shirt with my name on it for next race.</em></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Jen did great around the hilly sections of mile 5 and 6 and really held her own.  She started to feel the pain around mile 11 and we trucked on through until we split just before mile 13.  We wished each other well and parted ways.  We would have hugged, but it was impractical with the crowds coming down the last half mile of the half marathon. </p>
<p style="text-align:left;">I peeled off and continued the course to the full.  As I reached into my fuel belt to pull out my earbuds, a guy next to me said, &#8220;<em>Here we go</em>, <em>huh?&#8221;</em></p>
<p style="text-align:left;"><em>&#8220;Yep.  Let&#8217;s get this done.&#8221;</em> </p>
<p style="text-align:left;">I started up my iPod, the beats kicked in and I was off.  It almost felt like any other Sunday training run.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">At the end of the half-marathon, as expected, there was a noticeable decrease in the field of runners.  Almost cruelly, the marathon course has you run past your car in the parking lot.  Can&#8217;t say I minded though because in my head, I thought to myself just how amazing I was that I wasn&#8217;t stopping at my car, stopping at a half-marathon, or stopping at all.  I was in this for good or bad. </p>
<p style="text-align:left;">After the split, around mile 13.5, I saw a person cheering with a sign that said, <strong>&#8220;You&#8217;re no longer a runner, you&#8217;re a MARATHONER.&#8221;</strong>  I almost burst into happy tears.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Then I realized I couldn&#8217;t breathe when I cry, so I quickly pulled myself back together.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">I settled into my pace and just started truckin&#8217;.  I passed the Capitol (for the third time).  I passed the Southwest waterfront.  I passed the industrial parks of Anacostia, an area that I would have never gone for any other reason.  I applauded the drum corps and baton twirlers at mile 22 (I think) because they were the only entertainment for miles.  I gave every person cheering a smile because I wanted them to know just how much I appreciated their support on what is certainly the hardest part of the race, both physically and mentally.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">The miles ticked by.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Twenty.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Twenty-one.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Twenty-two.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">I&#8217;d never run this far in my life.   And I was still running.  I  never stopped except for 2 quick refills of the fuel belt at water stations.  I didn&#8217;t linger at the water stops and I picked right back up again as soon as my water bottle was filled again.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">At mile twenty-three, my brain kicked in:<strong> YOU HAVE A 5K TO GO.  GET YOUR <em>@$$</em> ACROSS THAT FINISH LINE.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Twenty-four.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Twenty-five.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">I can see the stadium.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Twenty-six.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Where is the finish line!?</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Where is Jeff!?</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><img title="017-1" src="http://thechaseproject.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/017-11.jpg?w=286&#038;h=397" alt="" width="286" height="397" /></p>
<p style="text-align:left;">There he is!  <em>Hiyeee!!</em></p>
<p>Am I really doing this!?  Did I really just run a marathon?</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">BOOM.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">I crossed that finish line in <strong>4:21:07 </strong>with a huge smile across my face.</p>
<p>More importantly, I <em>finished upright</em>, which was my only goal from day one. </p>
<p>My secondary goal was to <em>not hate every minute of it the entire time </em>and I consider that a complete success as well.  I credit Weight Watchers, smart training and smart fueling  for getting me through my first marathon.</p>
<p>I never hit a wall, I never prayed for it to be over.  I don&#8217;t think I had much more to give and I don&#8217;t think I started out too fast. </p>
<p>My finish time was a <strong>9:58 </strong>pace which was very much on par with how my training runs went. </p>
<p>My splits: </p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Mile 1: </strong>10:37 (slow across the start line)</li>
<li><strong>Mile 2:</strong> 10:03</li>
<li><strong>Mile 3:</strong> 9:55</li>
<li><strong>Mile 4:</strong> 9:22</li>
<li><strong>Mile 5:</strong> 10:14 (first hill)</li>
<li><strong><strong>Mile </strong>6:</strong> 10:01</li>
<li><strong>Mile 7: </strong>10:21</li>
<li><strong><strong>Mile </strong>8:</strong> 10:10</li>
<li><strong>Mile 9:</strong> 9:55</li>
<li><strong>Mile 10:</strong> 10:04</li>
<li><strong>Mile 11: </strong>9:16 (oooh downhill!)</li>
<li><strong>Mile 12: </strong>10:08</li>
<li><strong>Mile 13:</strong> 10:11</li>
<li><strong>Mile 14:</strong> 8:48 (tunes kicked in!)</li>
<li><strong>Mile 15:</strong> 9:10</li>
<li><strong>Mile 16:</strong> 9:27 (truckin&#8217; along that waterfront)</li>
<li><strong>Mile 17:</strong> 9:14</li>
<li><strong>Mile 18:</strong> 9:32</li>
<li><strong>Mile 19:</strong> 9:46</li>
<li><strong>Mile 20:</strong> 10:02</li>
<li><strong>Mile 21:</strong> 9:55</li>
<li><strong>Mile 22:</strong> 10:01</li>
<li><strong>Mile 23:</strong> 10:34</li>
<li><strong>Mile 24:</strong> 9:27 (GET YO&#8217; @$$ ACROSS THAT FINISH LINE!)</li>
<li><strong>Mile 25:</strong> 9:51</li>
<li><strong>Mile 26:</strong> 9:26</li>
<li><strong>Mile 26.6:</strong> 5:42 (6.3 mph)</li>
</ul>
<p>I took a Gu at miles 5, 11, 16, and 22 which was more frequent than I expected to, but it felt like the right thing to do&#8230; and it was!</p>
<p>At the end, I got my medal and finally reunited with Jeff.  I was so happy to see him!</p>
<p>I also finally caught up with Jess!</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><img title="018" src="http://thechaseproject.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/018.jpg?w=640&#038;h=480" alt="" width="640" height="480" /></p>
<p>So, you might be wondering what Jess decided to do and how her race went&#8230;?  She decided to do the full because her shin/calf had improved quite a bit over the 3 weeks of physical therapy.  She felt as good as she felt during her last 22 mile long run, so she decided to go for it after having spent all this time training for the marathon.  And she successfully finished the entire 26.2! (yay!)  But it was a tough race which took all her mental endurance to get through. (boo) While we were chatting, she said she thinks she&#8217;ll stick with half marathons, knowing the leg issues that present themselves when she runs too much.  I&#8217;m proud of her for seeing it through and doing the best she could!  Go Jess!</p>
<p>Jen ran a 2:13:54 half-marathon which was not a PR for her, but she said it was her &#8220;most enjoyable race ever!&#8221;  I totally agreed!</p>
<p>At the very end, my friend Beth who is a seasoned marathoner asked me,<em> &#8221;So is it too soon to say if you&#8217;ll do another&#8230;?&#8221; </em></p>
<p>Maybe so.  We&#8217;ll see.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3876/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3876/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3876/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3876/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3876/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3876/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3876/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3876/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3876/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3876/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3876/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3876/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3876/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3876/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=3876&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thechaseproject.com/2011/03/27/national-marathon-race-recap/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>57</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/a6b8937c914ec9c78ac5449e36601c5c?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">cmcarb</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thechaseproject.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/015-11.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">015-1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thechaseproject.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/0162.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">016</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thechaseproject.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/017-11.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">017-1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thechaseproject.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/018.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">018</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>National Parks:  Death Valley, Zabriskie Point</title>
		<link>http://anotherheader.wordpress.com/2011/03/27/national-parks-death-valley-zabriskie-point/</link>
		<comments>http://anotherheader.wordpress.com/2011/03/27/national-parks-death-valley-zabriskie-point/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2011 22:07:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>anotherheader</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[National Parks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Southwest United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The List]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://anotherheader.wordpress.com/?p=7505</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It’s odd how traveling to a foreign land inspires you to see something you’ve missed closer to home.  But sometimes that is the way it works.  At least that is the way it works for us. We started thinking about a trip to see Death Valley while visiting Chile’s Atacama Desert. The Atacama’s parched landscapes [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=7505&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:justify;">
<p style="text-align:center;">
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 796px"><a href="http://anotherheader.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_0392.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-7510   " title="DSC_0392" src="http://anotherheader.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_0392.jpg?w=786&#038;h=478" alt="" width="786" height="478" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Harmony Borax Works </p></div>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-size:14pt;">It’s odd how traveling to a foreign land inspires you to see something you’ve missed closer to home.  But sometimes that is the way it works.  At least that is the way it works for us.</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-size:14pt;"><span id="more-7505"></span>We started thinking about a trip to see Death Valley while <a href="http://anotherheader.wordpress.com/2009/04/22/san-pedro-de-atacama-and-kari-gorge/">visiting Chile’s Atacama Desert</a>.  The Atacama’s parched landscapes intrigued us.  It inspired us to look closer at the desert lands nearer to our home in California.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size:14pt;"> </span></p>
<div class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 618px"><a href="http://anotherheader.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_0343.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-7514   " title="DSC_0343" src="http://anotherheader.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_0343.jpg?w=608&#038;h=330" alt="" width="608" height="330" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The view from Zabriskie Point </p></div>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-size:14pt;">If you are looking to see deserts in the United States, Death Valley is a good place to start.  With an average of about 1.6 inches of rain a year, Death Valley gets about 40 times more rain in a typical year than does the Chilean Atacama.  But, at low altitude, Death Valley is much warmer than the Atacama.  In both places, California’s Death Valley and Chile’s Atacama, the environment is severe.  And in both places the extreme conditions inform the landscapes.</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-size:14pt;">In Death Valley we based in Stovepipe Wells.  After our impromptu night at Panamint Springs<strong> </strong> on the western edge of the park, it took only a short trip to relocate the Airstream to Stovepipe Wells’ small RV Park.</span></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://anotherheader.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_0371.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7523" title="DSC_0371" src="http://anotherheader.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_0371.jpg?w=819&#038;h=455" alt="" width="819" height="455" /></a><a href="http://anotherheader.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_0308.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7524" title="DSC_0308" src="http://anotherheader.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_0308.jpg?w=819&#038;h=490" alt="" width="819" height="490" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-size:14pt;">With a base camp established it was time to explore Death Valley.  Unhitched our first destination was Zabriskie Point.  Zabriskie’s overlook provides a view from the top into a patch of barren, intensely yellow-colored badlands.  The badlands extend down into the valley.  The view is dramatic.  Still it’s a surprise that an <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zabriskie_Point_%28film%29">obscure movie</a> was, for some reason, named after this spot.</span></p>
<div id="attachment_7527" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 624px"><a href="http://anotherheader.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_0313.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-7527" title="DSC_0313" src="http://anotherheader.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_0313.jpg?w=614&#038;h=335" alt="" width="614" height="335" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">A bench with a view of Zabriskie Point</p></div>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-size:14pt;">With the warm light of the setting sun bringing out intense colors in the hillsides, we sped back to Stovepipe Wells.  On the way a stop just off the road took us to Harmony Borax Works and its interpretive trail.  Continuing from the Borax Works a short unpaved road winds through Mustard Canyon.  Mustard Canyon is not so much a canyon as a route through another set of low rounded yellow-green or mustard colored mounds.  At the margins of light the colors are brilliant.</span></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-size:14pt;">Indeed, Death Valley is at its best in the low light of the morning and evening.  During the peak of the day, the valley can look drab.  Yet, at the edges of the day, the same vistas become spellbinding.  In Death Valley, as it often is in the desert, it’s all about the light.</span></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><span style="font-size:14pt;"><a href="http://anotherheader.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_0283.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7529" title="DSC_0283" src="http://anotherheader.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_0283.jpg?w=819&#038;h=459" alt="" width="819" height="459" /></a><a href="http://anotherheader.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_03881.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7530" title="DSC_0388" src="http://anotherheader.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_03881.jpg?w=819&#038;h=542" alt="" width="819" height="542" /></a><a href="http://anotherheader.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_0396.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7531" title="DSC_0396" src="http://anotherheader.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_0396.jpg?w=819&#038;h=456" alt="" width="819" height="456" /></a><br />
</span></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/7505/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/7505/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/7505/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/7505/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/7505/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/7505/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/7505/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/7505/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/7505/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/7505/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/7505/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/7505/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/7505/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/7505/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=7505&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://anotherheader.wordpress.com/2011/03/27/national-parks-death-valley-zabriskie-point/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>19</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/7994dd9b604d8ee89fd4b1a9f887f4e0?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">anotherheader</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://anotherheader.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_0392.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0392</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://anotherheader.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_0343.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0343</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://anotherheader.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_0371.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0371</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://anotherheader.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_0308.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0308</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://anotherheader.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_0313.jpg?w=1024" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0313</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://anotherheader.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_0283.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0283</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://anotherheader.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_03881.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0388</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://anotherheader.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_0396.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0396</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Orchid Show: On Broadway at the NY Botanical Garden</title>
		<link>http://brandieraaschphotography.wordpress.com/2011/03/28/the-orchid-show-on-broadway-at-the-ny-botanical-garden/</link>
		<comments>http://brandieraaschphotography.wordpress.com/2011/03/28/the-orchid-show-on-broadway-at-the-ny-botanical-garden/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2011 10:58:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Brandie</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Nature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Broadway]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[New York Botanical Garden]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Orchids]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brandieraaschphotography.wordpress.com/?p=1011</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This weekend I decided to make the trip up to the Bronx to visit the New York Botanical Garden. The Orchid Show is currently on display with a theme entitled, &#8220;On Broadway&#8221;. There are over 300 orchid varieties on view and the New York Botanical Garden collaborated with the theater industry insiders on design. Check [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=1011&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This weekend I decided to make the trip up to the Bronx to visit the New York Botanical Garden. The Orchid Show is currently on display with a theme entitled, &#8220;On Broadway&#8221;. There are over 300 orchid varieties on view and the New York Botanical Garden collaborated with the theater industry insiders on design. Check it out:</p>
<div id="attachment_1012" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 608px"><a href="http://brandieraaschphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_0321-2.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1012" title="DSC_0321-2" src="http://brandieraaschphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_0321-2.jpg?w=598&#038;h=900" alt="" width="598" height="900" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">© Brandie Raasch 2011</p></div>
<div id="attachment_1013" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 608px"><a href="http://brandieraaschphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_0323-2.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1013" title="DSC_0323-2" src="http://brandieraaschphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_0323-2.jpg?w=598&#038;h=900" alt="" width="598" height="900" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">© Brandie Raasch 2011</p></div>
<div id="attachment_1014" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 650px"><a href="http://brandieraaschphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_0326-2.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1014" title="DSC_0326-2" src="http://brandieraaschphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_0326-2.jpg?w=640&#038;h=425" alt="" width="640" height="425" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">© Brandie Raasch 2011</p></div>
<div id="attachment_1015" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 650px"><a href="http://brandieraaschphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_0346-2.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1015" title="DSC_0346-2" src="http://brandieraaschphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_0346-2.jpg?w=640&#038;h=425" alt="" width="640" height="425" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">© Brandie Raasch 2011</p></div>
<div id="attachment_1016" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 650px"><a href="http://brandieraaschphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_0369-2.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1016" title="DSC_0369-2" src="http://brandieraaschphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_0369-2.jpg?w=640&#038;h=425" alt="" width="640" height="425" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">© Brandie Raasch 2011</p></div>
<div id="attachment_1025" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 650px"><a href="http://brandieraaschphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_0372-3.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1025" title="DSC_0372-3" src="http://brandieraaschphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_0372-3.jpg?w=640&#038;h=425" alt="" width="640" height="425" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">© Brandie Raasch 2011</p></div>
<div id="attachment_1026" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 650px"><a href="http://brandieraaschphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_0379-4.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1026" title="DSC_0379-4" src="http://brandieraaschphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_0379-4.jpg?w=640&#038;h=425" alt="" width="640" height="425" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">© Brandie Raasch 2011</p></div>
<div id="attachment_1027" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 650px"><a href="http://brandieraaschphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_0387-4.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1027" title="DSC_0387-4" src="http://brandieraaschphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_0387-4.jpg?w=640&#038;h=893" alt="" width="640" height="893" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">© Brandie Raasch 2011</p></div>
<div id="attachment_1028" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 650px"><a href="http://brandieraaschphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_0423-2.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1028" title="DSC_0423-2" src="http://brandieraaschphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_0423-2.jpg?w=640&#038;h=425" alt="" width="640" height="425" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">© Brandie Raasch 2011</p></div>
<div id="attachment_1029" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 650px"><a href="http://brandieraaschphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_0463-1.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1029" title="DSC_0463-1" src="http://brandieraaschphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_0463-1.jpg?w=640&#038;h=425" alt="" width="640" height="425" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">© Brandie Raasch 2011</p></div>
<p>This was actually the first time in the seven or so years I&#8217;ve lived in NYC that I&#8217;ve ever visited the Botanical Garden. You can catch The Orchid Show through April 25th, but I&#8217;d definitely go back again even after it ends just to walk the grounds, which are really beautiful. I have some additional images up on my <a href="http://www.facebook.com/pages/Brandie-Raasch-Photography/150666858662">Facebook page</a>, so if you&#8217;re interested check them out and maybe become a fan <img src='http://s2.wp.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif' alt=':-)' class='wp-smiley' /> </p>
<p>-B</p>
<p>[<a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/03/04/theater/04orchid.html">NY Times</a>]</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1011/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1011/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1011/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1011/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1011/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1011/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1011/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1011/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1011/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1011/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1011/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1011/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1011/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1011/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=1011&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://brandieraaschphotography.wordpress.com/2011/03/28/the-orchid-show-on-broadway-at-the-ny-botanical-garden/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>37</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/153ed863345803a819dc6ec24164b813?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">brandieraaschphotography</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://brandieraaschphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_0321-2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0321-2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://brandieraaschphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_0323-2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0323-2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://brandieraaschphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_0326-2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0326-2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://brandieraaschphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_0346-2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0346-2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://brandieraaschphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_0369-2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0369-2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://brandieraaschphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_0372-3.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0372-3</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://brandieraaschphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_0379-4.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0379-4</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://brandieraaschphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_0387-4.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0387-4</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://brandieraaschphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_0423-2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0423-2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://brandieraaschphotography.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/dsc_0463-1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0463-1</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Strict Teacher v. The Fun Teacher: 5 Ways I have Changed</title>
		<link>http://teachtraveltaste.com/2011/03/23/the-strict-teacher-v-the-fun-teacher-5-ways-i-have-changed/</link>
		<comments>http://teachtraveltaste.com/2011/03/23/the-strict-teacher-v-the-fun-teacher-5-ways-i-have-changed/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2011 11:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lindsay</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Teach.]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[new teachers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[puerto rico]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[strict]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[students]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[teach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Teacher]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[teaching methods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[teaching styles]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://teachtraveltaste.com/?p=1058</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I started out as the Strict Teacher: Being a young, female, and brand new high school teacher has got to be one of the toughest jobs around. I’m not saying I don’t love it, but it was definitely no piece of cake. I wanted to be taken seriously. I wanted students to see me as [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=1058&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong><em>I started out as the Strict Teacher:</em></strong> Being a young, female, and brand new high school teacher has got to be one of the toughest jobs around. I’m not saying I don’t love it, but it was definitely no piece of cake. I wanted to be taken seriously. I wanted students to see me as their teacher, disciplinarian, and NOT their best friend. I had only the highest expectations of my students and I responded with tough love. I realize now that I didn’t smile as a beginning teacher as much as I do in “real life.” When some of my students hated me for giving them zero’s for late work, or copying their classmates’ work, I reminded myself that they would thank me later. I convinced myself that it didn’t matter if they like me or not…</p>
<p><strong><em>I still stand firm in most of these principles, but I have changed a few things:</em></strong></p>
<p><strong>1. I smile a lot more. </strong>I think that first sentence says it all, don’t you think? =)</p>
<div id="attachment_1061" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://thekaufholds.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_17021.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1061" title="IMG_1702" src="http://thekaufholds.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_17021-e1300849221108.jpg?w=600&#038;h=290" alt="" width="600" height="290" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">With my homeroom class, whom I am very proud of today, for reasons which I will blog about later...</p></div>
<p><strong>2. I ask my students about their lives. </strong>I am truly, genuinely interested in what is going on with my students this year. I obviously can’t just tell myself to suddenly become interested in getting to know them, so this must have been a subconscious flip of the switch within me. Whatever the reason, I am so glad it happened. While there are some things I prefer to not know about them, it just so happens that they are fascinating and delightful human beings! And we have lots in common too. After all, every Wednesday I discuss the latest Glee episode with half of my homeroom….</p>
<p><strong>3. I remember that no student (or teacher) is perfect. </strong>I have not lowered my academic expectations for my students, but I have definitely lowered my behavioral expectations. Why was I expecting 15 and 16 year olds to act as mature as adults, anyway? And since when are all adults ridiculously mature (myself included)? Teenagers aren’t perfect, but they sure can be hilarious. I might as well enjoy the good times with them and allow the “fun” back in the classroom!</p>
<p><strong>4. I give them second chances. </strong> For example, I used to have a strict “NO late work” policy that would often cost them quite a few points. I still believe that learning to meet deadlines is a crucial life skill that should be emphasized in the classroom. However, I realized that I wasn’t giving my students a chance to learn from their mistakes. Thanks to tips from other veteran teachers, I developed a system where students get a few hall passes and one late work pass per semester. They can choose to use them if necessary, or they can turn them in at the end of the semester for extra credit points. It is very rare that I give extra credit and my students would literally do anything for it!</p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>5. I let them get to know me. </strong>I used to hide a lot of info about myself from my students. There is still a lot they don’t know about me (and never will!) but I am so much more open with them this year. And I can tell that it makes a difference. They love hearing funny stories about my childhood, teenage years, or about relationships (especially since they love “Mr. Kaufhold”).  When they feel that the know me, they are more willing to work hard in my classroom. And what a relief it is to be able to “be yourself” in your work place!</p>
<p><strong><em>So have I become the “Fun Teacher?” </em></strong>Not necessarily. Am I against the idea of being the &#8220;fun teacher?&#8221; Not necessarily. Do I want to be the &#8220;fun teacher?&#8221; Again&#8230;not necessarily. But I am glad I have lightened up. I enjoy my days so much more when I enjoy my students and myself. On the other hand&#8230;maybe I am able to lighten up because I started out as the &#8220;strict teacher?&#8221;</p>
<p><strong><em>What do you all think, which is better for a young, new teacher? Should we start out as strict? Or should we be the sweet, smiling, and silly people we would normally be in &#8220;real life?&#8221;</em></strong></p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://teachtraveltaste.com/category/teach/'>Teach.</a> Tagged: <a href='http://teachtraveltaste.com/tag/education/'>education</a>, <a href='http://teachtraveltaste.com/tag/fun/'>fun</a>, <a href='http://teachtraveltaste.com/tag/life/'>life</a>, <a href='http://teachtraveltaste.com/tag/new-teachers/'>new teachers</a>, <a href='http://teachtraveltaste.com/tag/puerto-rico/'>puerto rico</a>, <a href='http://teachtraveltaste.com/tag/smile/'>smile</a>, <a href='http://teachtraveltaste.com/tag/strict/'>strict</a>, <a href='http://teachtraveltaste.com/tag/students/'>students</a>, <a href='http://teachtraveltaste.com/tag/teach-2/'>teach</a>, <a href='http://teachtraveltaste.com/tag/teacher/'>Teacher</a>, <a href='http://teachtraveltaste.com/tag/teaching-methods/'>teaching methods</a>, <a href='http://teachtraveltaste.com/tag/teaching-styles/'>teaching styles</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1058/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1058/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1058/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1058/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1058/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1058/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1058/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1058/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1058/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1058/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1058/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1058/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1058/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1058/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=1058&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://teachtraveltaste.com/2011/03/23/the-strict-teacher-v-the-fun-teacher-5-ways-i-have-changed/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>41</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/4ee1002080e6d6ea005df13787f6b16a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lindsaykaufhold</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thekaufholds.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/img_17021-e1300849221108.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_1702</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>DEDICATION: JAPAN EARTHQUAKE AND TSUNAMI VICTIMS OF 2011</title>
		<link>http://photojournaljapan.wordpress.com/2011/03/22/dedication-2/</link>
		<comments>http://photojournaljapan.wordpress.com/2011/03/22/dedication-2/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2011 18:22:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Stack Jones</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Iwate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Miyagi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Northeastern Japan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sendai]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://photojournaljapan.wordpress.com/?p=169</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This photo gallery is in honor of Iwate, Miyagi, Fukushima, Ibaraki and other regions of Japan that have been destroyed by this disaster. But, no doubt like the mythical bird Phoenix, Japan will rebuild and rise again.<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=169&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This site is dedicated to the victims of the 2011 Japan earthquake and tsunami.</p>
<p><a href="http://photojournaljapan.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/kiomizu-gray.jpg"><img title="Kiomizu Gray" src="http://photojournaljapan.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/kiomizu-gray.jpg?w=655&#038;h=436" alt="" width="655" height="436" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://photojournaljapan.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/kiomizu.jpg"></a>I&#8217;m an American that has lived in the northeastern region of Japan for the past two and a half years. Sadly, many of the places that I discovered, such as the coastal towns of Yuriage, Shinko and Gamo are now gone. The communities that existed in these locations have been completely decimated as a result of a tsunami that followed the 9.0 earthquake that hit Iwate, Miyagi, Fukushima, Ibaraki and other prefectures. Many of my friends, their families, towns, homes and businesses are gone forever.</p>
<p>Japanese officials say the death toll is likely to exceed <a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2011/mar/21/japan-earthquake-death-toll-18000">18,000</a>. Miyagi, was one of the hardest hit prefectures, and may account for <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-pacific-12798579">15,000</a> deaths alone. The National Police Agency has reported that the overall number of bodies collected so far stood at <a href="http://www.660worl.com/article.aspx?id=de729f00-3aa0-4518-a469-81cf4efbdbba&amp;catid=0">8,649</a> with some 13,262 people still listed as missing. It has also been reported that there are more than 452,000 homeless.</p>
<p>The financial cost of the disaster has been estimated at <a href="http://ndn.org/blog/2011/03/aftershocks-us-economy-disaster-japan">260 billion USD</a>, according to the World Bank. It may take as long as five-years for Japan to rebuild.</p>
<p>The final toll of this triple devastation remains unknown as the Fukushima Dai-Ichi Nuclear Plant continues to leak radiation into the surrounding communities, and has not been contained. The threat of a complete meltdown continues as of this post.</p>
<p>The <a href="http://photojournaljapan.wordpress.com/japanese-photography/">photo gallery</a> is in honor of the victims of that culmination of disasters. I have no doubt that much like the mythical bird Phoenix, Japan will rebuild and rise again.</p>
<p>Let me know if any of these photos have touched you, or if you have your own story you&#8217;d like to share about this tragic event. Please, donate to the <a href="http://www.jrc.or.jp/english/index.html">Japanese Red Cross Society</a> to aid the victims of this terribly tragic event.</p>
<p><a href="http://photojournaljapan.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/candle.jpg"><img title="Candle" src="http://photojournaljapan.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/candle.jpg?w=655&#038;h=436" alt="" width="655" height="436" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://photojournaljapan.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/yamagata-castle-2.jpg"><img title="Yamagata Castle 2" src="http://photojournaljapan.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/yamagata-castle-2.jpg?w=655&#038;h=436" alt="" width="655" height="436" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://photojournaljapan.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/sakura-blossom2.jpg"><img title="Sakura Blossom" src="http://photojournaljapan.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/sakura-blossom2.jpg?w=655&#038;h=436" alt="" width="655" height="436" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://photojournaljapan.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/yamadera-falls.jpg"><img title="Yamadera Falls" src="http://photojournaljapan.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/yamadera-falls.jpg?w=655&#038;h=436" alt="" width="655" height="436" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://photojournaljapan.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/kyoto-temple.jpg"><img title="Kyoto Temple" src="http://photojournaljapan.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/kyoto-temple.jpg?w=655&#038;h=436" alt="" width="655" height="436" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://photojournaljapan.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/japan-sea.jpg"><img title="Japan Sea" src="http://photojournaljapan.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/japan-sea.jpg?w=655&#038;h=436" alt="" width="655" height="436" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://photojournaljapan.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/tojinbo-silouette-2.jpg"><img title="Tojinbo Silouette 2" src="http://photojournaljapan.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/tojinbo-silouette-2.jpg?w=655&#038;h=436" alt="" width="655" height="436" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://photojournaljapan.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/umbrella.jpg"><img title="Umbrella" src="http://photojournaljapan.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/umbrella.jpg?w=655&#038;h=436" alt="" width="655" height="436" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://photojournaljapan.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/samurai-last-stand.jpg"><img title="Samurai Last Stand" src="http://photojournaljapan.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/samurai-last-stand.jpg?w=655&#038;h=436" alt="" width="655" height="436" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://photojournaljapan.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/geisha-1.jpg"><img title="Geisha 1" src="http://photojournaljapan.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/geisha-1.jpg?w=655&#038;h=436" alt="" width="655" height="436" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://photojournaljapan.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/bar-boys.jpg"><img title="Bar Boys" src="http://photojournaljapan.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/bar-boys.jpg?w=655&#038;h=436" alt="" width="655" height="436" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://photojournaljapan.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/fukui-baby.jpg"><img title="Fukui Baby" src="http://photojournaljapan.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/fukui-baby.jpg?w=655&#038;h=436" alt="" width="655" height="436" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/169/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/169/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/169/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/169/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/169/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/169/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/169/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/169/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/169/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/169/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/169/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/169/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/169/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/169/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=169&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://photojournaljapan.wordpress.com/2011/03/22/dedication-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>30</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/79c5513c3aa78bddc711efee8c845276?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">stackjones</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://photojournaljapan.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/kiomizu-gray.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Kiomizu Gray</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://photojournaljapan.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/candle.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Candle</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://photojournaljapan.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/yamagata-castle-2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Yamagata Castle 2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://photojournaljapan.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/sakura-blossom2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Sakura Blossom</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://photojournaljapan.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/yamadera-falls.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Yamadera Falls</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://photojournaljapan.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/kyoto-temple.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Kyoto Temple</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://photojournaljapan.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/japan-sea.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Japan Sea</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://photojournaljapan.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/tojinbo-silouette-2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Tojinbo Silouette 2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://photojournaljapan.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/umbrella.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Umbrella</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://photojournaljapan.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/samurai-last-stand.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Samurai Last Stand</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://photojournaljapan.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/geisha-1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Geisha 1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://photojournaljapan.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/bar-boys.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Bar Boys</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://photojournaljapan.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/fukui-baby.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Fukui Baby</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8220;Emotions are the Foundations of Reason&#8221;</title>
		<link>http://seattleseconds.wordpress.com/2011/03/14/emotions-are-the-foundations-of-reason/</link>
		<comments>http://seattleseconds.wordpress.com/2011/03/14/emotions-are-the-foundations-of-reason/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2011 05:54:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>amcgrann</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[21st Century Skills]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Social Emotional Learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Teaching]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TED talk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[david brooks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social animal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social emotional learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TED talks]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://seattleseconds.wordpress.com/?p=1163</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;Emotions are the foundations of reason,&#8221; says David Brooks in today&#8217;s TED talk, &#8220;because they tell us what to value.&#8221; Mr. Brooks is one of my favorite columnists in the NYTimes. Articulate and smart, this TED talk shows that he is also very funny. It&#8217;s fascinating that he spent three years culling research about our [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=1163&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://seattleseconds.wordpress.com/2011/03/14/emotions-are-the-foundations-of-reason/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">amcgrann</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Adjustment Bureau</title>
		<link>http://thefilmlounge.wordpress.com/2011/03/22/the-adjustment-bureau/</link>
		<comments>http://thefilmlounge.wordpress.com/2011/03/22/the-adjustment-bureau/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2011 18:30:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>TheFilmLounge</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Adjustment Bureau]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blade Runner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Emily Blunt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[John Slattery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Matt Damon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Minority Report]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Philip K Dick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Terence Stamp]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thefilmlounge.wordpress.com/?p=59</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Phillip K. Dick with a sense of humour and a heart. It is true that almost all Phillip K. Dick adaptations, although beautifully imagined and bursting to the seams with interesting science fiction theories, are terribly bleak. Steeped in a sense of intense paranoia, previous works adapted for the big screen, Minority Report, A Scanner [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=59&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:justify;"><em><a href="http://thefilmlounge.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/the_adjustment_bureau_movie.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-60" title="the_adjustment_bureau_movie" src="http://thefilmlounge.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/the_adjustment_bureau_movie.jpg?w=300&#038;h=154" alt="" width="300" height="154" /></a><a class="zem_slink" title="Philip K. Dick" rel="homepage" href="http://www.philipkdick.com">Phillip K. Dick</a> with a <a class="zem_slink" title="Humour" rel="wikipedia" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Humour">sense of humour</a> and a heart.</em></p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">It is true that almost all Phillip K. Dick adaptations, although beautifully imagined and bursting to the seams with interesting science fiction theories, are terribly bleak. Steeped in a sense of intense paranoia, previous works adapted for the big screen, <a class="zem_slink" title="Minority Report" rel="rottentomatoes" href="http://www.rottentomatoes.com/m/minority_report">Minority Report</a>, <a class="zem_slink" title="A Scanner Darkly" rel="rottentomatoes" href="http://www.rottentomatoes.com/m/scanner_darkly">A Scanner Darkly</a> and <a class="zem_slink" title="Blade Runner" rel="rottentomatoes" href="http://www.rottentomatoes.com/m/blade_runner">Blade Runner</a>, frequently lack a sense of fun and spend most their time exploring the darker recesses of the human mind.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">It is refreshing then to see an adaptation of Dick’s work which is not only fun and pacey, but also has a heart. Although technically a science fiction movie, <a class="zem_slink" title="The Adjustment Bureau" rel="rottentomatoes" href="http://www.rottentomatoes.com/m/adjustment_bureau">The Adjustment Bureau</a> could also as accurately be described as a political drama or even more so as a romance. The central story follows <a class="zem_slink" title="Matt Damon" rel="rottentomatoes" href="http://www.rottentomatoes.com/celebrity/matt_damon">Matt Damon</a>’s presidential hopeful as he loses his first run at the Senate, shortly after he meets <a class="zem_slink" title="Emily Blunt" rel="rottentomatoes" href="http://www.rottentomatoes.com/celebrity/1163951-emily_blunt">Emily Blunt</a>’s ‘Elise’ a dancer who is destined for greatness and they have a fleeting moment in which they both feel drawn to one another.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Instep The Adjustment Bureau, a group of shadowy figures, dressed in immaculate suits and sporting 1950’s style trilbies. The Bureau set to make sure the two are never together and here unwinds the story of a group of people working for an unseen &#8216;upstairs&#8217; who keep everything to the right plan. Being together will ruin any chance either of them has of fulfilling their dreams, and it is this contradiction which fuels the narrative.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Damon is likable as the politician who succeeds by telling the truth and although this isn’t his most challenging role of recent years he is perfectly adequate to the role and brings a sense of humour and light touch to some of the more explosive scenes in the movie.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Damon, is able supported by a great cast including, <a class="zem_slink" title="John Slattery" rel="wikipedia" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Slattery">John Slattery</a> bringing a spirit of Mad Men to the management of his Bureau team and Antony Mackie, bringing a heart to the apparently automated Bureau. <a class="zem_slink" title="Terence Stamp" rel="rottentomatoes" href="http://www.rottentomatoes.com/celebrity/terence_stamp">Terrence Stamp</a> brings the authority needed and keeps the guessing game of who really runs the Bureau moving with his frequent appearances.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">It is with Emily Blunt however that the film really shines. Blunt is mesmerising as the aloof yet emotional Elise, her acerbic wit and carefree attitude with Damon in the early scenes builds well to a fully formed character, allowing her performance during the films climactic final act to be heart-breaking, engaging and truly believable; of all the British actresses currently working in Hollywood, Blunt is really starting to cut a reputation for herself as someone who can offer something other than the standard British girl routine.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">Director Nolfi, has fun with this film and his use of special effects is subtle to allow the film to feel possible throughout, while also doing some tricks just for the hell of it, without giving too much away, you’ll be amazed where some of those doors lead, and when some of them lead there for only a few seconds, you can feel the excitement of the creative team coming through the screen, some of those ‘What if?’ meetings clearly arrived in the final film.</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">The Adjustment Bureau has a lot of fun with its function blurring the lie between sci-fi, reality and a genuinely engaging love story which ultimately asks the question, What do you give up, when you give in to love?</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">****</p>
<p style="text-align:justify;">&nbsp;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/59/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/59/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/59/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/59/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/59/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/59/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/59/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/59/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/59/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/59/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/59/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/59/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/59/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/59/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=59&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thefilmlounge.wordpress.com/2011/03/22/the-adjustment-bureau/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>32</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/19c59509ac14bee5f440e64a240a81d2?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">otisbear</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thefilmlounge.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/the_adjustment_bureau_movie.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">the_adjustment_bureau_movie</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Last of last summer&#8217;s sun dried tomatoes</title>
		<link>http://stowell.wordpress.com/2011/03/28/last-of-last-summers-sun-dried-tomatoes/</link>
		<comments>http://stowell.wordpress.com/2011/03/28/last-of-last-summers-sun-dried-tomatoes/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2011 07:08:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Food,Photography &#38; France</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Digital photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food and Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[France]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography holiday]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://stowell.wordpress.com/?p=995</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Misty Monday morning made me look at these remnants of last summer&#8217;s heat. It&#8217;s hard to remember the summer sun after a long cold winter, and to imagine that it will be hot enough to dry trays of tomatoes. Even though the clocks  sprung forward on Sunday, I&#8217;ll be cutting firewood today. Yesterday&#8217;s  poule au [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=995&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a rel="attachment wp-att-996" href="http://stowell.wordpress.com/2011/03/28/last-of-last-summers-sun-dried-tomatoes/sun_dried_tomatoes_oil/"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-996" title="sun_dried_tomatoes_oil" src="http://stowell.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/sun_dried_tomatoes_oil.jpg?w=449&#038;h=690" alt="" width="449" height="690" /></a>Misty Monday morning made me look at these remnants of last summer&#8217;s heat. It&#8217;s hard to remember the summer sun after a long cold winter, and to imagine that it will be hot enough to dry trays of tomatoes. Even though the clocks  sprung forward on Sunday, I&#8217;ll be cutting firewood today. Yesterday&#8217;s  poule au pot was good  - comforting and warming &#8211; but now I&#8217;m looking forward to peaches, melons and cherries. Just no pleasing me.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/995/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/995/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/995/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/995/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/995/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/995/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/995/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/995/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/995/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/995/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/995/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/995/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/995/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/995/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=995&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://stowell.wordpress.com/2011/03/28/last-of-last-summers-sun-dried-tomatoes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/ff5417406128577ced0dab49495142fc?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">stowell</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://stowell.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/sun_dried_tomatoes_oil.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sun_dried_tomatoes_oil</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The No. 1s are done: VCU shocks Kansas</title>
		<link>http://sports.nationalpost.com/2011/03/27/no-1s-are-done-vcu-shocks-kansas/</link>
		<comments>http://sports.nationalpost.com/2011/03/27/no-1s-are-done-vcu-shocks-kansas/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2011 20:52:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>The Associated Press</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Basketball]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NCAA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kansas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NCAA men's basketball tournament]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Virginia Commonwealth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jamie Skeen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[VCU]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Final Four]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://sports.nationalpost.com/?p=25383</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[By Jaime Aron SAN ANTONIO — They missed short shots and long ones. Even free throws were far from gimmes. Just like that, Kansas followed the lead of all the other No. 1 seeds and bowed out of the NCAA tournament before the Final Four — only the Jayhawks are stuck with the added agony [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=25383&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>By Jaime Aron<br />
</strong></p>
<p>SAN ANTONIO — They missed short shots and long ones. Even free throws were far from gimmes.</p>
<p><span id="more-25383"></span>Just like that, Kansas followed the lead of all the other No. 1 seeds and bowed out of the NCAA tournament before the Final Four — only the Jayhawks are stuck with the added agony of stumbling while staring down the easiest path to a national championship that any team ever faced.</p>
<p>[np-related]</p>
<p>Kansas actually didn’t even come close against No. 11 Virginia Commonwealth, getting behind early and hardly threatening on the way to a 71-61 loss in the finals of the Southwest regional on Sunday.</p>
<p>“We’re crushed,” coach Bill Self said. “We tried real hard and just came up empty against a team that was better than us today.”</p>
<div id="attachment_25395" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 320px"><a rel="attachment wp-att-25395" href="http://sports.nationalpost.com/2011/03/27/no-1s-are-done-vcu-shocks-kansas/vcu-2/"><img class="size-full wp-image-25395" title="The Virginia Commonwealth Rams celebrate after defeating the Kansas Jayhawks." src="http://nationalpostsports.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/vcu1.jpg?w=310&#038;h=263" alt="" width="310" height="263" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">REUTERS/Mike Stone</p></div>
<p>The Jayhawks walked off the court blank-faced, hands on hips, occasionally peeking at the wild celebration around them. Marcus Morris tried holding off the tears, but had to pull his jersey over his face by the time he reached the edge of the court.</p>
<p>He probably didn’t want to see the stat sheet, either. Kansas made only 35.5 percent of its shots and 9.5 percent of 3-pointers, both season lows. The Jayhawks hit 15 of 28 free throws (53.6 percent), narrowly better than their season-low.</p>
<p>“Probably the best game they played ever, probably the best game ever as a school,” Markieff Morris said. “We let them beat us. We missed a lot of shots we normally make. We missed a lot of free throws that we normally make.”</p>
<p>A victory would’ve sent Kansas into a Final Four matchup against eighth-seeded Butler, then no better than a No. 2 seed in the finals. Had the Jayhawks won it all, they would’ve shattered the record for the highest sum of seeds faced by the champion.</p>
<p>But instead of strolling into Houston next weekend as the heavy favorites, Kansas became the third No. 1 seed to lose to a No. 11, joining Connecticut in 2006 and Kentucky in 1986.</p>
<p>The difference in this upset: the Huskies lost in overtime and the Wildcats in the final seconds, while the Jayhawks were drummed. Their last lead was 10-9. They were down by a season-high 14 at halftime and trailed by 16 before rallying to within two, yet never got nearly that close again.</p>
<p>“Seeds are so overrated,” Self said. “It’s about matchups. Their players could play for us any day.”</p>
<p>Kansas reached the regional finals on an 11-game winning streak. In the tournament, the Jayhawks hadn’t trailed by more than two points, and won by at least 14, in victories over teams seeded 16th, ninth and 12th.</p>
<p>As much as they claimed they would respect VCU as much as a Duke or North Carolina, the Big 12 champions still knew they were facing the fourth-place finisher from the Colonial Athletic Association. The lack of respect may have oozed out during a pregame meeting of team captains, when — according to VCU’s Joey Rodriguez and two of his teammates — one of the Morris twins said, “The run ends here.”</p>
<p>The soft road and perhaps a bit of overconfidence may have conspired against the Jayhawks (35-3).</p>
<p>Kansas opened strong and had the majority of the crowd on its side. But once a few things went right for VCU, everything went its way. The Jayhawks allowed spurts of 11-0 and 10-2. Along the way, the Morris twins each missed a pair of free throws, typical of the sloppiness that also included turnovers and missed shots, some that never should’ve been taken.</p>
<p>A 17-4 rally early in the second half made things interesting, but Kansas couldn’t sustain its surge.</p>
<p>The final minutes were a perfect example of what went wrong.</p>
<p>When Marcus Morris missed two short shots and Markieff rebounded the second miss, VCU’s Jamie Skeen snatched the ball right out of his hands. Next time down, Tyrel Reed shot an airball on a baseline jumper. Then Marcus Morris threw up a 3-pointer that was way too hard and punched it out of bounds when he went for the rebound.</p>
<p>By the time Tyshawn Taylor made a layup with 24 seconds left, the Jayhawks were down by eight.</p>
<p>Thousands of Jayhawks fans stood in stunned silence, arms crossed, while the small group of VCU supporters chanted “Hey, Hey, Goodbye.”</p>
<p>Self’s teams have underachieved before, getting to the Final Four only once in his eight seasons. Just last year, the Jayhawks were ousted in the second round while carrying the No. 1 overall seed; they were bounced in the first round in 2005 and ‘06.</p>
<p>What’s next for the Jayhawks?</p>
<p>Much depends on whether the Morris twins return for their senior year. Kansas already has to replace two senior starters in the backcourt, Reed and Brady Morningstar.</p>
<p>“We didn’t accomplish what we set out to accomplish, so it’s hard for me to say it’s a special year,” Self said. “It won’t sting from lack of trying or lack of effort. It will sting because these opportunities — I wish they came yearly, but they don’t come yearly. And you’ve got to make the most of opportunities when you get them and we didn’t do that.”</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/25383/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/25383/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/25383/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/25383/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/25383/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/25383/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/25383/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/25383/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/25383/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/25383/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/25383/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/25383/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/25383/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/25383/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&amp;blog=256907&amp;post=25383&amp;subd=freshlypressed&amp;ref=&amp;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://sports.nationalpost.com/2011/03/27/no-1s-are-done-vcu-shocks-kansas/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/f0e41e4725731ac63585905d892b7cbe?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">associatedpressnp</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nationalpostsports.files.wordpress.com/2011/03/vcu1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The Virginia Commonwealth Rams celebrate after defeating the Kansas Jayhawks.</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>