<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2012 23:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Gaza and Mourning</title>
		<link>http://wstaylor.me/2012/11/17/gaza-and-mourning/</link>
		<comments>http://wstaylor.me/2012/11/17/gaza-and-mourning/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2012 21:30:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Stephen Taylor</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[casualties]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gaza]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[guided missiles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[images of violence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[israel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[judith butler]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[middle-east]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mourning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[southern israel]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://wstaylor.me/?p=386</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;m struck by how often this cycle of events seems to happen: the Israeli military kills and maims large numbers of Palestinians with guided missiles, and the Palestinians fire fewer rockets at Israel and kill and maim a much smaller number. The numbers and the mismatch are not my main problem (although the calculation of [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=386&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m struck by how often this cycle of events seems to happen: the Israeli military kills and maims large numbers of Palestinians with guided missiles, and the Palestinians fire fewer rockets at Israel and kill and maim a much smaller number. The numbers and the mismatch are not my main problem (although the calculation of proportionality seems perverse in my opinion), nor is the question of who fired first. Can we really justify either party by saying that they are more responsible for either killing innocent people first, or killing innocent people on a larger scale?</p>
<p>If you watch <a href="http://www.cnn.com/video/?/video/bestoftv/2012/11/15/nr-life-in-gaza-strip-seshay-intv.cnn">this video</a> – which is framed with the required “balance” of one Israeli and one Palestinian – you can’t really ignore the fact that only one of them is in a place where the building is beng visibly shaken by nearby missile strikes. Ah, but the other interviewee has images of his children, and asks us to sympathize with their fear and the danger they are in. Of course we don&#8217;t see their fear or hear its cause. That’s because it’s actually a lot more dangerous to be a civilian in Gaza than in southern Israel, actually an order of magnitude more dangerous and more fear-inducing. Compare the amount of ordinance directed at Gaza versus the amount of damage done to Israeli infrastructure. There is, in fact, almost no comparison. And yet, of course, there is; that is the comparison, the fact that one side is much larger.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m not interested in arguing about that comparison. I&#8217;m actually interested in what happens to observers like us, and how we think, when that kind of comparison seems like the important question, when it appears that the answer to such questions is important in some way. Haven&#8217;t we accepted something unacceptable when we see images of violence and death and we have to make a decision about which death to wearily accept and which to mourn? How has it got to the point that it could possibly be deemed okay for any civilian to be bombed? It’s one thing to criticize the false equivalence, by which both sides are equally sinned against or sinning. But when we complain about the false equivalence, are we agreeing that some kinds of sins deserve to punished by death?</p>
<p>The last time Israel invaded Gaza, Judith Butler wrote a book called <em>Frames of War</em>, in which she tried to theorize – using a familiar set of theoretical texts and continental philosophers – how and where and why some kinds of life become “grievable” while others do not. She noted that when Israeli children die, it is seen &#8211; as it should be &#8211; as a loss of life that can be grieved. But when Palestinian children die, their very lives can seem like the provocation that made it necessary to kill them, in self-defence. I find this to be a compelling argument. I&#8217;m left asking myself the question of when and whether and why and how we might have an obligation to “protect” a life. It made me think of the ways that the UN’s “Responsibility to Protect” doctrine can become the cause of a war, the way Palestinians are dying, right now, to protect Israelis, and the way more Israelis will, eventually, die because someone thought that would protect Palestinian lives. Can we not ask that question differently?</p>
<p>Talking about &#8220;protection&#8221; and &#8220;grieving&#8221; always seems to presume the presence of a corpse, and also focuses all of our attention onto that corpse. Absent is the hand that pulled the trigger. We might also find ourselves asking the question of whether a life is worth protecting/saving/grieving. The life is the thing in question, but as such, it’s also the thing that must justify itself: failing its nomination as “life,” it can be killed. This is not where Judith Butler wants the argument to go, of course. If some lives are grievable, aren’t others killable? Why do we take violence for granted while making life plead its case? Why isn’t all violence illegitimate by default? Why isn’t all life sacred, by definition?</p>
<p>When we argue that a child was innocent, that a civilian should not have been targeted, the rhetoric of violation has a hidden consequence: if the child should not have been killed, doesn’t the not-child suddenly emerge out of the protection we’ve just extended towards the innocent, as guilty? If it’s because they are children that we cannot kill them, what can we say about those who are not children? And while killing militants is easier if killing civilians is harder, that’s not an argument that killing them is justified. In fact, if some forms of killings are justified, then the fact that we live in a world filled with justifications–the fact that our soil is soaked with blood–means we will never run out of justifications to turn into violence. We will be reduced to comparing them, to see whose crimes are worse.</p>
<p>When we compare the two lists, we show something important about the massive imbalance in force between the two “sides.” But is that the most important thing? I wonder if we also create a market in deaths when we suggest that there is some kind of ratio or exchange or commensurability between these numbers, that deaths can be understood by relations of exchange and comparison. Were the handful of Israelis who were killed justified, because so many Palestinians paid for it with their lives? Or should we note the massive inequity in death rates without avoiding that suggestion? Or without suggesting that some kind of more equitable death ratio would be less scandalous? Can we complain about the imbalance without suggesting that there is a balance?</p>
<p>The only thing I feel certain about is that there is nothing to feel good or certain about here. I don’t know that there is any statement you can make about an obscenity like this one that doesn’t make you a worse person for saying it. Reading about Gaza right now doesn’t even make me angry. It just makes me more tired, more frustrated, more rotten. I don’t think there is any clarity to be found here, or there. I can only be disgusted with myself, that I share humanity with people <a href="http://readwrite.com/2012/11/15/unbelievable-the-idf-has-gamified-its-war-blog">who think there is something to be felt here other than despair.</a></p>
<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=386&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://wstaylor.me/2012/11/17/gaza-and-mourning/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://wstaylordotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/301188_1.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://wstaylordotme.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/301188_1.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">301188_1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/9a7303364e169f017f516d99d400345c?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">billygoatcamb</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Goodbye, Twinkie the Kid</title>
		<link>http://roachlife.wordpress.com/2012/11/18/goodbye-twinkie-the-kid/</link>
		<comments>http://roachlife.wordpress.com/2012/11/18/goodbye-twinkie-the-kid/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2012 17:20:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>John Sherman</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Life in Brooklyn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[essay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fruit Pie the Magician]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hostess]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hostess twinkies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[junk food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[TV commercials]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Twinkie the Kid]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[twinkies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://roachlife.wordpress.com/?p=735</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[We never saw it coming. There was no warning, no time to say, “You know you really ought to have a Twinkie. It’s been so long, and who knows how much longer they’ll be around.” Don’t be stupid, any of us would have said. Twinkies will be around forever. Not so. Twinkie the Kid is gone. This, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=735&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://roachlife.wordpress.com/2012/11/18/goodbye-twinkie-the-kid/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>16</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/3e17ee261123b5b7cb73b922be2aa0bd?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=R" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">johnsherman2011</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://roachlife.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/planet-of-the-apes.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">&#34;Planet of the Apes&#34; (1968)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://roachlife.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/twinkiethekid.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Twinkie the Kid</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>When Holidays Collide</title>
		<link>http://nittygrittydirtman.wordpress.com/2012/11/18/when-holidays-collide/</link>
		<comments>http://nittygrittydirtman.wordpress.com/2012/11/18/when-holidays-collide/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2012 15:48:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Kevin</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nitty Gritty Dirt Man]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thanksgiving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nitty gritty dirt man]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thanksgiving]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nittygrittydirtman.wordpress.com/?p=4591</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Thanksgiving is around the corner, and that can only mean one thing.  My PHSD is about to kick in. Post-Holiday Stress Disorder, or PHSD, is the only way I can describe what happens to me once turkey day is done &#8212; and in less than a week, it&#8217;s about to come on full force. Just [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4591&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://nittygrittydirtman.wordpress.com/2012/11/18/when-holidays-collide/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>24</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/d39cd4611c1052f7526666111dbc60a6?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">santakev</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nittygrittydirtman.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/stress.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">stress</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nittygrittydirtman.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/img_2322.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Wrapping Paper</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nittygrittydirtman.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/img_2317.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Holiday Newsletter</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nittygrittydirtman.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/img_1888.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">August</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://nittygrittydirtman.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/img_2334.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Nutcracker</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Facebook &amp; Emotional Pornography</title>
		<link>http://amatterofbaobabs.wordpress.com/2012/11/18/facebook-emotional-pornography/</link>
		<comments>http://amatterofbaobabs.wordpress.com/2012/11/18/facebook-emotional-pornography/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2012 10:24:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Rachel Hayter</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advocacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[awareness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[charity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emotional pornography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[facebook]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pornography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sincerity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[society]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[suffering]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://amatterofbaobabs.wordpress.com/?p=642</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[My Facebook newsfeed is littered with images of suffering: a uniformed soldier cradling his child at an airport; a young girl who has lost her hair from cancer treatment; a bloodied newborn with his heart on the outside of his body; a chained dog who has been mutilated by his owners; a bruised woman who [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=642&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>My Facebook newsfeed is littered with images of suffering: a uniformed soldier cradling his child at an airport; a young girl who has lost her hair from cancer treatment; a bloodied newborn with his heart on the outside of his body; a chained dog who has been mutilated by his owners; a bruised woman who has been beaten by her husband. The images always involve visual distress and come accompanied with a caption in the vein of: 1 like = 1 prayer; 1 like = 1 respect; ignore = you don’t care.</p>
<p>Gratuitous images like these exist in my newsfeed because people or organisations post them, with the sole ambition of increasing their online popularity. The image poster is exploiting the pain of the image’s subjects, to improve their own social media presence. Your online interaction with the image serves as an endorsement of that exploitation. What makes this kind of blatant grab for likes more ugly, is its guise as a gesture of goodwill and concern for the image’s sufferer.</p>
<p>These images are not about raising awareness. If an image were intended for that purpose, specifics like name, time and place would be given. They’re not, so we aren’t to know which person, disease or war is accountable. It’s even possible that these images have been gleaned from old sources and are five, even ten years old. Of course, this is irrelevant; your gut response and consequent ‘prayer’ or ‘respect’, represented by the clicking of a button, is all that really matters.</p>
<p>Gut responses to images of people or animals in pain are just that. Humans feel empathy by instinct. Displaying your hard-wired capacity for empathy, without direction or application, by liking, commenting on and sharing these kinds of images is emotional pornography. It doesn’t make a skerrick of difference for the subjects featured. What it achieves, is a cheap and nasty boost in activity for the poster of the image, and a deluded sense of do-goodery for the person interacting with that image.</p>
<p>For sincerity’s sake, when you’re confronted with an image in your newsfeed that tugs your heartstrings and urges for your all-powerful like – restrain yourself! Instead, take your ‘1 prayer’ and ‘1 respect’ and next time you see a vendor spruiking The Big Issue, stop, have a chat and buy a copy. Donate some money or volunteer your time for Legacy, The Cancer Council, RSPCA, Doctors Without Borders, UNICEF – whomever floats your charitable boat. But PLEASE, do the (Facebook) world a favour and take a stand against false advocacy and emotional pornography.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/642/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/642/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=642&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://amatterofbaobabs.wordpress.com/2012/11/18/facebook-emotional-pornography/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>55</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/7ba38b16498245683b33d6f6372721fd?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">amatterofbaobabs</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Walden; or, Life in the Woods</title>
		<link>http://watsonweltanschauung.wordpress.com/2012/11/17/walden-or-life-in-the-woods/</link>
		<comments>http://watsonweltanschauung.wordpress.com/2012/11/17/walden-or-life-in-the-woods/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2012 20:14:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Watson Weltanschauung</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[India]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[american literature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[emerson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[himalayas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[philosophy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spinoza]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thoreau]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transcendentalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[walden]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wilderness]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://watsonweltanschauung.wordpress.com/?p=727</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There are nowadays professors of philosophy, but not philosophers&#8230; To be a philosopher is not merely to have subtle thoughts, nor even to found a school, but so to love wisdom as to live according to its dictates, a life of simplicity, independence, magnanimity, and trust. It is to solve some of the problems of [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=727&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>There are nowadays professors of philosophy, but not philosophers&#8230; To be a philosopher is not merely to have subtle thoughts, nor even to found a school, but so to love wisdom as to live according to its dictates, a life of simplicity, independence, magnanimity, and trust. It is to solve some of the problems of life, not only theoretically, but practically. </em>(12)</p>
<p>&#8220;It is a vulgar error to suppose that you have tasted huckleberries who never plucked them&#8221; (138).</p>
<p>As I went about my wanderings through the Uttaranchal Himalayas, I had with me Thoreau&#8217;s <em>Walden</em>, which turned out to be wonderfully timely and appropriate reading. I only barely finished it within my last day of hiking, having been totally exhausted from scaling rocks and whatnot all day, not to mention the rarity of light and my unwillingness to use my headlamp except in case of emergency (like when I heard an animal outside the tent at 3300m up and went out searching, clutching my Swiss Army knife like a crazy person and hoping I didn&#8217;t fall off the cliff in the total darkness but for my one beam). I enjoyed reading some more literary philosophy like this; though I often find heavily metaphorical writing obtuse or exhausting, this was a nice break from treatises and essays and the like. Thoreau&#8217;s writing is really a joy to read, and the philosophy behind it &#8211; though I find myself taking issue on several points &#8211; has something to teach everyone. In this post I&#8217;m going to reflect on a few specific quotes that spoke to me particularly, because I&#8217;m too tired and scatterbrained to write something coherent on the whole.</p>
<p>There were certainly notes of Thoreau that seemed to echo Epicurus, though he quotes many philosophers and not this one in particular. But he admonished those who think they need things like tea and coffee, when he knows that the truest pleasure is having what is needed and living simply. This is very Epicurean &#8211; he at one point writes that his cabin at Walden Pond will be grander than the grandest houses in the town. He remarks at the beginning of the book: &#8220;Most men, even in this comparatively free country, through mere ignorance and mistake, are so occupied with the factitious cares and superfluously coarse labours of life that its finer fruits cannot be plucked by them&#8221; (5).</p>
<p>As I traveled these days, I wore but one set of clothes. Though I stunk to high heaven, I felt validated by dear Thoreau: &#8220;I say, beware of all enterprises that require new clothes, and not rather a new wearer of clothes&#8221; (19). Certainly by the end of this journey I was a new wearer, in more ways than one.</p>
<p>He makes a relevant remark regarding the student of his time, and I dare say the student of our time: &#8220;I mean that they should not <em>play</em> life, or <em>study</em> it merely, while the community supports them at this expensive game, but earnestly <em>live</em> it from the beginning to end. How could youths better learn to live than by at once trying the experiment of living? Methinks this would exercise their minds as much as mathematics&#8230; Even the <em>poor</em> student studies and is taught only <em>political </em>economy, while that economy of living which is synonymous with philosophy is not even sincerely professed in our colleges. The consequence is, that while he is reading Adam Smith, Ricardo, and Say, he runs his father in debt irretrievably&#8221; (40-41). This is perhaps more true than ever, and one of the issues I am trying to confront this year&#8230; (the state of learning philosophy, not irretrievable debt &#8211; although almost holla ND financial aid).</p>
<p>I have a certain affinity for philosophies that manage to combine a degree of elitism or at least strong criticism of society with a healthy dose of self-hatred. &#8220;I never dreamed of any enormity greater than I have committed. I never knew, and never shall know, a worse man than myself&#8221; (61). I&#8217;m not being facetious here. I have a hard time believing those who proclaim the evils of society without proclaiming, in equal volume and tenor, the evils of themselves. And oneself is exactly what Thoreau is writing about here; it may very well be a useful critique of society, but it is more urgently a call to <em>know oneself</em>.</p>
<p>While my project is developed around the idea that philosophy demands to be lived, I fully acknowledge that there are many, if not infinitely many, ways to live philosophically. In these days of mountain hiking, I tried to live a somewhat different philosophical life from what I have been doing up until now with my project. For the majority of each day, I was doing nothing but walking and thinking. &#8220;For the most part, I minded not how the hours went. The day advanced as if to light some work of mine; it was morning, and lo! now it is evening, and nothing memorable is accomplished. Instead of singing like the birds, I silently smiled at my incessant good fortune&#8221; (89). I didn&#8217;t try to help or affect the lives of the orphans I met in the villages &#8211; I just got to know them, and their aspirations, and their daily lives. I experienced so many things in such a minimal way, and I have everything and nothing to show for it.</p>
<p>One thing I constantly feel guilty about &#8211; Watson Fellowship or not &#8211; is the time I spend stationary, reading or sitting and doing nothing but thinking. I have an internal impulse that tells me this is a waste of time, reinforced by the constant inquiries as to whether I am alright, or if I am bored, or if there is something I would like to do (what I am doing!). Thoreau eloquently defends this behavior: &#8220;but [the farmer] does not realize that the student, though in the house, is still at work in <em>his</em> field, and chopping in <em>his</em> woods, as the farmer in his&#8230;&#8221; (107).</p>
<p>&#8220;Every man is the builder of a temple, called his body, to the god he worships, after a style purely his own, nor can he get off by hammering marble instead. We are all sculptors and painters, and our material is our own flesh and blood and bones&#8221; (176). I find this sentiment to be true, and I often remind myself of it when I make unhealthy choices. But Thoreau means more than just diet and exercise here, obviously. However, this aside, I had some problems with his use of and allusions to Eastern philosophy. He refers often to Indian and Chinese philosophy, almost always in praise. Having been now in India for several months, I find he quite mischaracterizes the philosophies, if they can be so generalized in the first place. Most of the Hindus I have met put no thought into their religion. The isolated villages in the north all follow Hinduism as a part of life that is not a choice, or something to question or reflecton, but just actions that one takes. One goes to worship three days at the temple in the same way one gathers wood for fuel. In the more affluent south I found many borderline-cultish Hindu gurus who collected (quite a lot of) money from their devoted followers. To grant the virtue of simplicity to this religion is a grave error. They are as crowded with ceremony and pomp as any other aspect of culture; there are 84 million Hindu gods, and rituals and traditions that do nothing but detract from the simplicity of life are pervasive (&#8220;&#8230;how deep the ruts of tradition and conformity!&#8221;). In some ways here I also feel to be reacting against those who label Spinoza as closer to the eastern philosophies; I think this is a gross misreading and it ultimately comes down to reason. Eastern philosophies do not value reason, at least not in comparison to the West. Look simply at the method of teaching &#8211; it is primarily a set of easy-to-remember maxims. But perhaps now I&#8217;ve gone too far.</p>
<p>After trudging up the slopes to the tents, I read another validating passage: &#8220;How much more interesting an event is that man&#8217;s supper who has just been forth in the snow to hunt, nay, you might say, steal, the fuel to cook it with!&#8221; (197). Upon making it to the tents, I had a silent but joyful evening with the watchman (who spoke no English except &#8216;welcome&#8217;) and we chopped some wood for our fire, sat by the embers, and cooked a warm meal of rice, daal, and chapati. Indeed an interesting supper.</p>
<p>My time alone in the hills was lonely at moments, but almost painfully illuminating in how I now understand myself. I pushed myself to the edge &#8211; physically, emotionally, and mentally. I was scared out of my mind at times; sometimes I was so cold I couldn&#8217;t bring myself to put my fingers near the fire for fear of the sharp but necessary pain; at moments my legs quivered and my heart throbbed in my throat, not trained for such hikes and such altitude; but all of this was necessary. To know myself I had to know my boundaries &#8211; and perhaps I did not yet even find them. I learned to listen and respond to my body, and I began to build the strength of my mind in overcoming these physical weaknesses. It was rewarding in that I almost broke. &#8220;What was the meaning of that South-Sea Exploring Expedition, with all its parade and expense, but an indirect recognition of the fact that there are continents and seas in the moral world, to which every man is an isthmus or an inlet, yet unexplored by him, but that it is easier to sail many thousand miles through cold and storm and cannibals, in a government ship, with five hundred men and boys to assist one than it is to explore the private sea, the Atlantic and Pacific Ocean of one&#8217;s being alone&#8230;&#8221; (253).</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/727/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/727/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=727&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://watsonweltanschauung.wordpress.com/2012/11/17/walden-or-life-in-the-woods/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/e1b94ee132b5156df66718033545a56d?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ballsofoddness</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>I Don’t Enjoy the Ride</title>
		<link>http://narrativeodyssey.com/2012/11/17/i-dont-enjoy-the-ride/</link>
		<comments>http://narrativeodyssey.com/2012/11/17/i-dont-enjoy-the-ride/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2012 02:10:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Tim</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[reading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ben Lerner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[character]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creative non-fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ernest hemingway]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[escape]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[human condition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jack Kerouac]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[literature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[memoir]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mid life crises]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Moveable Feast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Raimond Gaita]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self reflections]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tony Birch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://narrativeodyssey.com/?p=185</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[From my day-to-day reality, I long to escape. I&#8217;ve been waiting for winter to end (I live down under) so I can load up the four-wheel drive and head into the country to light a fire, build a camp, and catch my dinner; boy&#8217;s own stuff. Yet in my reading, I struggle with such tales. [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=185&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignright" title="Road Trip" alt="" src="http://aphs.worldnomads.com/OffTheBeatenPath/22448/iStock_000003676011Small.jpg" height="209" width="312" />From my day-to-day reality, I long to escape. I&#8217;ve been waiting for winter to end (I live down under) so I can load up the four-wheel drive and head into the country to light a fire, build a camp, and catch my dinner; boy&#8217;s own stuff. Yet in my reading, I struggle with such tales. <a title="On the Road" href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/70401.On_the_Road" target="_blank">Jack Kerouac&#8217;s On the Road</a> was something I thought I&#8217;d love, but which never really took my imagination with it. I&#8217;m afraid we parted ways when we reached Denver. And of Hemingway&#8217;s writings, I was most captivated by his self-reflections in <a title="Breakfast in Melbourne" href="http://narrativeodyssey.com/2012/08/03/breakfast-in-melbourne/" target="_blank">A Moveable Feast</a> than anything else. Writerly journeys are perhaps not for me. I don&#8217;t think I enjoy the ride.</p>
<p>What I seem to love though are books that reach deep into the human condition. Characters, both man and boy whose fragility is their strength, who may not travel widely but venture into the depths of who they are.</p>
<p>A couple of months ago I picked up a copy of <a title="Leaving the Atocha Station" href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/11100788-leaving-the-atocha-station" target="_blank">Leaving the Atocha Station by Ben Lerner</a>. I&#8217;d shelved it because I&#8217;d a few others on my list to get through first. This morning I impulsively pulled it from the shelf to read something non-work related; to escape. Instantaneously I loved it. Two scenes in, the lead character hasn&#8217;t really gone anywhere, but already I know so much about what troubles him. I can&#8217;t say the same about Kerouac&#8217;s Sal.</p>
<p>So from my recent readings I&#8217;ve learned the genres I most want to read are that <a title="Shadowboxing" href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/575739.Shadow_Boxing" target="_blank">fictional exploration of who we are and how we have become</a>, or the non-fictional memoirs of <a title="The Happy Life" href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13148133-the-happy-life" target="_blank">mid-life crises</a> and <a title="Romulus My Father" href="http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/432450.Romulus_My_Father" target="_blank">the influences on our lives</a>. That&#8217;s not to the exclusion of other genres. And I know I must break out and read more widely. Yet, to know what I love most and to stick with, is new to me. I&#8217;ve forever spent my days searching far and wide to find the things I might learn to love, only to be perpetually disappointed and exasperated. Now finally, through my reading and writing, I&#8217;m learning that I don&#8217;t need to travel to find what I&#8217;m looking for. To look deeply at who I am and what I&#8217;m about, I need not stray too far.</p>
<br /> Tagged: <a href='http://narrativeodyssey.com/tag/ben-lerner/'>Ben Lerner</a>, <a href='http://narrativeodyssey.com/tag/books/'>books</a>, <a href='http://narrativeodyssey.com/tag/character/'>character</a>, <a href='http://narrativeodyssey.com/tag/creative-non-fiction/'>creative non-fiction</a>, <a href='http://narrativeodyssey.com/tag/ernest-hemingway/'>ernest hemingway</a>, <a href='http://narrativeodyssey.com/tag/escape/'>escape</a>, <a href='http://narrativeodyssey.com/tag/fiction/'>Fiction</a>, <a href='http://narrativeodyssey.com/tag/human-condition/'>human condition</a>, <a href='http://narrativeodyssey.com/tag/jack-kerouac/'>Jack Kerouac</a>, <a href='http://narrativeodyssey.com/tag/literature/'>literature</a>, <a href='http://narrativeodyssey.com/tag/memoir/'>memoir</a>, <a href='http://narrativeodyssey.com/tag/mid-life-crises/'>mid life crises</a>, <a href='http://narrativeodyssey.com/tag/moveable-feast/'>Moveable Feast</a>, <a href='http://narrativeodyssey.com/tag/raimond-gaita/'>Raimond Gaita</a>, <a href='http://narrativeodyssey.com/tag/reading/'>reading</a>, <a href='http://narrativeodyssey.com/tag/self-reflections/'>self reflections</a>, <a href='http://narrativeodyssey.com/tag/tony-birch/'>Tony Birch</a>, <a href='http://narrativeodyssey.com/tag/travel/'>travel</a>, <a href='http://narrativeodyssey.com/tag/writing/'>writing</a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=185&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://narrativeodyssey.com/2012/11/17/i-dont-enjoy-the-ride/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a4797cc25c5fe8922fc81c7d16e17bd8?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Tim</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://aphs.worldnomads.com/OffTheBeatenPath/22448/iStock_000003676011Small.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Road Trip</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lake Erie</title>
		<link>http://writersite.org/2012/11/17/lake-erie/</link>
		<comments>http://writersite.org/2012/11/17/lake-erie/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2012 13:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>lucewriter</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Creative Nonfiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Memoir]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family memories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family photos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lake Erie]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LaPlaisance Bay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LaSalle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Michigan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nonfiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing memoir]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://writersite.org/?p=294</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[by guest blogger Wilma Kahn When I was small, the lake was an omnipresent feature in my life. Large, too large to see it all, it curved into the horizon, so we could view but one small portion of the enormous sloshing drop. Held in the embrace of fragile fingers of land lay tons of [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=294&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>by guest blogger Wilma Kahn</p>
<p><a href="http://luannecastle.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/jeannie-2.jpg"><img class="alignleft  wp-image-314" alt="" src="http://luannecastle.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/jeannie-2.jpg?w=233&#038;h=240" height="240" width="233" /></a>When I was small, the lake was an omnipresent feature in my life. Large, too large to see it all, it curved into the horizon, so we could view but one small portion of the enormous sloshing drop. Held in the embrace of fragile fingers of land lay tons of water, gallons of waves.</p>
<p>I early developed the notion that I was part of the lake or it a part of me.  I have retained this feeling; and in fact, it has generalized to any large body of water—lake or sea. And I doubt that I am the only person who looks at Lake Michigan’s miraculous blue or the great grey Atlantic and says, “Mine.”</p>
<p>But back to my <i>special</i> lake, the dour, the grey-green, the shallow, the cloud-shrouded Erie.  Lake Erie’s rocks are granite, quartz, and shale; its shells, snail and clam. Its sand is taupe, soft, nonabrasive; its bottom sand or clay; its seaweed velvety green, swaying in the rhythm of the waves.</p>
<p>How did I spend hours and hours outside as a child, fair with reddish hair, without being burned by the sun? Was it the Lake Erie clouds? Or that most of the time I romped in the waves, a freshwater dolphin, a creature of sea? I jumped through the swells in arc after arc, or swam underwater, eyes open, blowing a fine stream of bubbles through my nose and tickling the legs of my friends. We stood on our hands, wheeled through the blue, grabbed gobs of sand, threw them, or let them melt from our hands. We crawled back onto land only after our fingertips had shriveled and our lips turned blue. But on land we shivered and felt heavy as rocks, no longer warmed and buoyed by the lake.</p>
<p>The shore changed each year, sometimes shallow, sometimes deep, sometimes rock, sometimes sand, sometimes clay. In years of clay, we children became potters, digging up the dark residue of prehistoric plants, rubbing it on our arms and legs, attracting snapping horseflies. We fashioned cups and bowls and ashtrays for our parents, those huge indolent creatures who sat and smoked while we made art and slapped flies.</p>
<p>Sometimes we built cities of sand along the shore, with houses, roads, bridges, and motes.  Any house could have a pool—dig a few inches and the lake would well up, cool and pure. Stones, reeds, driftwood, sea glass, all lay close at hand for each architect’s use. I know the feel of hand smoothing sand, from crude heap to finished city. And at night, the tide would reclaim it all, suck it—sand, stick, and stone—into the watery matrix, roll it around, and spread it along the shore.</p>
<p>###</p>
<p>Do you consider the place where you grew up a source&#8211;or <i>the</i> source&#8211;of your creativity?</p>
<div id="attachment_316" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://luannecastle.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/aerial-veiw-of-grand-view-beach.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-316  " alt="" src="http://luannecastle.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/aerial-veiw-of-grand-view-beach.jpg?w=590"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Aerial view of Grand View Beach on Lake Erie</p></div>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=294&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://writersite.org/2012/11/17/lake-erie/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>43</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/0d1e713c2e526b4da9e15e9732ff27bc?s=96&#38;d=retro&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lucewriter</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://luannecastle.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/jeannie-2.jpg?w=291" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://luannecastle.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/aerial-veiw-of-grand-view-beach.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fishing For Shooting Stars</title>
		<link>http://livenowandzen.com/2012/11/17/shooting-stars/</link>
		<comments>http://livenowandzen.com/2012/11/17/shooting-stars/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2012 18:12:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>livenowandzen</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Being Present]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Perspective]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[constellations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[geminids]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[leonids]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meteors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[perspective]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sky view]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[universe]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://livenowandzen.com/?p=3917</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Meteor showers are like fishing. You go, you enjoy nature. Sometimes you catch something. I love outer space. I marvel at the vastness of the universe and how I am but a speck on a pebble in the reaches of it all. It&#8217;s very humbling. While in college at the University of Colorado, I took [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3917&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;"><em>Meteor showers are like fishing. You go, you enjoy nature. Sometimes you catch something.</em></p>
<div id="attachment_3918" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 179px"><a href="http://livenowandzen.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/image5.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-3918" title="Image" alt="" src="http://livenowandzen.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/image5.jpg?w=169&#038;h=300" height="300" width="169" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Oh how I love my Sky View app.</p></div>
<p>I love outer space. I marvel at the vastness of the universe and how I am but a speck on a pebble in the reaches of it all. It&#8217;s very humbling. While in college at the University of Colorado, I took a few courses in astronomy, not because I thought I would do well (I&#8217;m an English major and was told there would be no math) but because I wanted to learn more about space. So, I studied comets, black holes, and galaxies. I was aided by a friend who knew the constellations and would point them out to me on random occasions when we were out of the reaches of the light pollution of the city. I know what you&#8217;re thinking. Isn&#8217;t this the gal who used to have nightmares about UFOs in grade school? And yes, that is true. Although the possibility exists that there is life elsewhere in the universe, I&#8217;m no longer concerned that said life is in any hurry to come here, colonize our planet, and turn me into their house pet. (As I told my husband the other day, any life form that <em>is</em> intelligent enough to get here and still desire this rock will have no trouble taking it and annihilating us all. They&#8217;ve got higher intelligence and space travel. We have <em>Honey Boo Boo</em><em>. </em>We&#8217;d be weaker than kittens.)</p>
<p>In November of 2001, when Joe was six months old and we were just two months beyond the terrorist attacks of 9/11, I read there would be a Leonid meteor shower. The earth would be passing through a dust cloud shed by a comet hundreds of years ago and viewers with a clear, dark sky would see thousands of meteors falling per hour. Shunning all better parental judgement, we woke our sleeping child, belted him into his car seat, and drove an hour east of Denver to a country road in the middle of farm country to catch the show. It was one of the most amazing things I&#8217;ve ever seen. Meteor after meteor flashed across the sky as my exhausted husband and I stared up through the open sunroof of our Toyota 4Runner, infant son strapped safely in the middle of the backseat.</p>
<p>Yesterday morning as I was perusing some news sites, I noted that our planet is in the midst of another encounter with the Leonids. This one would not be as spectacular, but I didn&#8217;t see how I could pass up the opportunity to share the experience with our sons. So, before bed, I announced to the family that I would be waking up at 2:30 a.m. to check for clear skies. If I found some, then we would be driving a small distance from city lights to look up at the stars. I figured that at worst we would see nothing but constellations and have exhausted boys today. Maybe I&#8217;d have a tired headache too, but with a gingerbread latte I could live with that.</p>
<p>At 2:30, the alarm on my iPhone began barking (literally&#8230;I like the barking dog alarm) and I begrudgingly awoke. I stayed in bed for a few minutes, debating the merits of my great, big idea. I nearly scrapped it on the basis that I had only slept two hours so far, but ultimately decided that I could sleep when I am dead. Steve was still out cold, so I went in to wake Luke as he was the most excited about my plan to begin with. He awoke fairly easily, hopped out of bed, put some socks on with his long-underwear pajamas, and went downstairs to grab some milk for the road. Steve was the next conquest. When I told him I was going to drive off into the night alone with Luke, he decided he should man up and crawled from the bed. Joe at last acquiesced to join us when we told him he&#8217;d be alone in the house when we left. We drove 10 minutes west, parked the car on the other side of the hogback from our home, opened the sunroof, and waited. We pulled out the Sky View app on my phone and searched for constellations. We found Orion&#8217;s belt, Cancer, Gemini, and Taurus. We remarked at how bright Jupiter was, and Joe reminded us that the Big Dipper is located within Ursa Major, the large bear. The meteor shower was not fantastic, but we each saw at least one or two cross the sky. Luke remarked that he&#8217;d never seen a shooting star before, and that made it all worthwhile. At least we were all together as a family in the adventure of stargazing. That sort of memory is priceless, even if the meteors don&#8217;t show up.</p>
<p>Sometimes I shake my head at the things I force my kids to do just so I can share with them things that are important to me. I want them to view the planet and the universe with wonder and appreciation as I do. Something about the unfathomable expanse of space puts everything into perspective when life gets overwhelming. Although the meteor shower last night was less of a shower and more of an occasional raindrop, no worries. I read that the Geminid meteor shower will occur on a new moon on Thursday, December 13th, and it&#8217;s predicted to have more than 100 shooting stars per hour. If our boys aren&#8217;t at school on December 14th, you&#8217;ll know why.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3917/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3917/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3917&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://livenowandzen.com/2012/11/17/shooting-stars/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>23</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/91d794e2e5ebdd3184e9b4b1e49af688?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">livenowandzen</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://livenowandzen.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/image5.jpg?w=169" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Shame</title>
		<link>http://abetternhs.wordpress.com/2012/11/16/shame/</link>
		<comments>http://abetternhs.wordpress.com/2012/11/16/shame/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2012 13:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>abetternhs</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://abetternhs.wordpress.com/?p=3075</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Masaccio: The Expulsion of Adam and Eve from Eden 1425 Through the concrete physicality of the two figures and the arid landscape around them, Masaccio makes believable the first dolorous steps of human beings on earth, in the solitude of the shame of sin and the dramatic experience of pain. Quoted from &#8216;Medicine in Art&#8217; [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3075&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://abetternhs.wordpress.com/2012/11/16/shame/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>36</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/4dcb6d078bdf7ddd31cc62ed44fa3f10?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">abetternhs</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://abetternhs.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/masaccio-theexpulsionofadamandevefromeden-restoration.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Masaccio-TheExpulsionOfAdamAndEveFromEden-Restoration</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Without Plug or Productivity</title>
		<link>http://subjectobscura.wordpress.com/2012/11/17/without-plug-or-productivity/</link>
		<comments>http://subjectobscura.wordpress.com/2012/11/17/without-plug-or-productivity/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2012 02:57:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Aidan</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[capitalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[play]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[typewriters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[work]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://subjectobscura.wordpress.com/?p=141</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[With one click of the mouse, I became a collector. I bought a second typewriter. I bought my first typewriter in October 2011.  Goodwill opened a store in the area, which my partner and I promptly checked out. It turned out to be a well-planned visit as I found a Smith-Corona Classic 12 in fine [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=141&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With one click of the mouse, I became a collector. I bought a <em>second</em> typewriter.</p>
<div id="attachment_156" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 592px"><a href="http://subjectobscura.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/img_3644.jpg"><img class="wp-image-156 " style="border:1px solid black;" title="IMG_3644" alt="Olympia Model &quot;S&quot;" src="http://subjectobscura.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/img_3644.jpg?w=582&#038;h=387" height="387" width="582" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The new: Olympia Model &#8220;S&#8221;</p></div>
<p>I bought my first typewriter in October 2011.  Goodwill opened a store in the area, which my partner and I promptly checked out. It turned out to be a well-planned visit as I found a <span style="color:#003366;">Smith-Corona Classic 12</span> in fine condition sitting on the shelves, waiting to be snagged by the first analog-enthusiast to cross its path. I didn&#8217;t know it yet, but I was one such enthusiast.</p>
<div id="attachment_155" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 592px"><a href="http://subjectobscura.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/img_3596.jpg"><img class="wp-image-155 " style="border:1px solid black;" title="IMG_3596" alt="Smith-Corona Classic 12" src="http://subjectobscura.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/img_3596.jpg?w=582&#038;h=387" height="387" width="582" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The less-new: Smith-Corona Classic 12</p></div>
<p>Over the months that followed, I would learn how to properly clean it, fix some of the keys that were stuck, and that, while the office supply store does not carry the ribbons I needed, e-commerce would make finding such things possible. Every step of the way, I was excited. I was engaging with a technology that had supposedly become outdated and loving it.</p>
<p>Not least of all, I was enjoying the use of the machine. The purposeful pressure placed on each key, the arm slapping the roller and the paper superstitiously interceding so a character may appear. Over and over. I&#8217;d type nonsense and streams of consciousness and letters to my partner a room away. Just to be <em>typing</em>. I would type the same thing over and over again; craft a letter in many drafts. Just to make use of the machine.</p>
<p>Even as I enjoyed this endeavor, I found myself wondering why it was so enjoyable. Was I really doing anything other than what I did on a daily basis at my job, i.e. rendering language into writing via a machine? What was so enjoyable about doing this on a typewriter?</p>
<p>Well, I do enjoy typing, generally. I am good at it: fast, proficient, etc. But that wasn&#8217;t enough to explain the joy I was experiencing with my Classic 12. I don&#8217;t have a definitive answer on that point, although I have my suspicions. It has to do with the very meaning of what it is to “use” such a thing; of what use can be made of a so-called &#8220;old&#8221; and &#8220;outdated&#8221; technology. Certainly,  typewriters are not widely used productively, if they are used that way at all. Maybe in some dusty corner of industry, but otherwise I cannot imagine anyone is typing up reports on a typewriter, even an electric one. And data-entry? What would it even mean on a typewriter? That is technology we could not even think before the computer.  So it seems evident that the typewriter is outmoded.</p>
<p>So my delight in using it is influenced by the fact that it is so utterly removed from that realm: work. It is an activity entirely divorced from that mindless slog. And, unlike work, it is an act of choice and not necessity. It has a scope that is always self-determined. It partakes in wonder; the child-like delight of play. Play not as the opposite of work, but work that is <i>fulfilling: </i>of me and the end-product, but <span style="text-decoration:underline;">not</span> a business’s bottom line.</p>
<p>Buying a typewriter is a purchase against the grain: it is almost always used, it is a product whose supply is dwindling rather than being created in excess, it engages one in an activity at odds with the über-productive &#8220;Puritan&#8221; work ethic of corporate America. In short, it&#8217;s wonderful. I am glad to now have a couplet, and so a little more of myself, too.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/141/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/141/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=141&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://subjectobscura.wordpress.com/2012/11/17/without-plug-or-productivity/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>20</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/4e378a034866332ff863ddf3d0f6d695?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">noisiverevision</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://subjectobscura.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/img_3644.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_3644</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://subjectobscura.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/img_3596.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_3596</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>