<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2012 20:44:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>What Makes a Post Freshly Press-able: Bacon in a Toaster</title>
		<link>http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2012/09/27/what-makes-a-post-freshly-press-able-bacon-in-a-toaster/</link>
		<comments>http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2012/09/27/what-makes-a-post-freshly-press-able-bacon-in-a-toaster/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2012 20:40:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>michelle w.</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Freshly Pressed]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tactics/Tips]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dailypost.wordpress.com/?p=10334</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Every day, a handful of WordPress.com bloggers are featured in Freshly Pressed. And every day, many more wonder, “What do I have to do to get Freshly Pressed?” Well, it’s time to reveal what the folks who push the launch button are thinking. Each week, we&#8217;ll take a close took at one post and why [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=10334&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Every day, a handful of WordPress.com bloggers are featured in </em>Freshly Pressed<em>. And every day, many more wonder, “What do I have to do to get Freshly Pressed?”</em></p>
<p><em>Well, it’s time to reveal what the folks who push the launch button are thinking. Each week, we&#8217;ll take a close took at one post and why we thought it was Press-worthy. We hope we can provide insight into the process and give you tips and tools to make your blog the best it can be.<br />
</em>________________________________________________</p>
<p>When we think about what we once imagined &#8220;the future&#8221; would be like, lots of us have the same initial reaction as <a title="Bohemian Radio" href="http://philloz3000.wordpress.com/" target="_blank">Bohemian Radio</a>: when do I get my flying car already?</p>
<p><span id="more-10334"></span></p>
<p><a href="http://dailypost.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/bacon.jpg"><img class="alignleft  wp-image-10351" title="Toaster Bacon!" src="http://dailypost.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/bacon.jpg?w=168&h=220" alt="Toaster Bacon!" width="168" height="220" /></a>Or at least a personal jetpack; 2012 isn&#8217;t quite living up to 20th century science-fiction&#8217;s promises. Bohemian Radio&#8217;s latest post, <a title="Bacon in a Toaster" href="http://philloz3000.wordpress.com/2012/09/25/bacon-in-a-toaster-a-future-too-awesome-to-happen/" target="_blank">Bacon in a Toaster: A Future Too Awesome To Happen</a>, takes a closer look at 1975&#8242;s idea of the future-that-isn&#8217;t.</p>
<p>The post didn&#8217;t just draw us in because of the idea of toaster bacon (although that might be what got us through the front door), but because it was just plain fun. Sometimes, we like to read something that educates, inspires, or that we can relate to viscerally–but sometimes, we just want to crack up.</p>
<h2>It made us laugh. A lot.</h2>
<p>Consider his description of the Hi-Fi Sphere, a record player gone futuristic by virtue of its Sputnik-esque design:</p>
<blockquote><p>Long-playing Hi Fidelity records are round. Rolling Stones are round, Barry White is round. Your ears are round. Your head is round, and your face-talking hole is round. So should your high-fidelity, sound-barking, audio-making equipment set be: Round. EXTRA BONUS: Round(ish) speakers on an extendo-matic telescoping antenna-looking thingy, for maximum head-injury potential. When not in use, the giant round sound thing closes to form a perfectly symmetrical aluminum sphere, blending in naturally with all your other giant ball-shaped décor.</p></blockquote>
<p>You had us at &#8220;face-talking hole.&#8221;</p>
<h2>While we were wiping away tears of laughter, it made us think about bigger questions.</h2>
<p><a href="http://dailypost.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/future-tv.jpg"><img class="wp-image-10352 alignright" title="Television... of the FUTURE" src="http://dailypost.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/future-tv.jpg?w=224&h=274" alt="Television... of the FUTURE" width="224" height="274" /></a>Reading about 1975&#8242;s idea of Future Television–wired-antenna-ready, and replete with multiple analog clocks for ease of global timekeeping–reminded us of how little we can actually predict about what technology will look like 30 years from now, and how bad we are at guessing what kinds of tools will actually make life easier and better.</p>
<p>When we think about what the world will look like in 30 years, we&#8217;re naturally constrained by our experience of the world <em>today</em>. But as technology advances, in spurts and bounds, it changes the ways we relate to it, the ways we use it, and how we&#8217;d like it to function. The Future Television  seems absurd to us today, knowing what we like our TVs to do and how we use them; how absurd will our idea of a big honking 72&#8243; television seem to our grandkids, when they&#8217;ve got satellite receivers grafted directly onto their retinas?</p>
<h2>Did we mention the Turkey Gun?</h2>
<p>Perhaps we shouldn&#8217;t find the Turkey Gun so absurd in a world that has embraced <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Go-Gurt">Go-Gurt</a> (or &#8220;Frubes&#8221; for you Brits), but this description made us guffaw:</p>
<blockquote><p>Based on absolutely no evidence or experience, the top futurologists of 1962 determined that earthly utensils, dishes and even solid food itself would be absolutely useless, if not deadly – and possibly Communist – in 1975 outer space. The answer? Based on the same physics principles that modern, 21<sup>st</sup> century pastry bags employ, this marvelous “Expelling device screws onto punctured can and is operated by squeezing to force food through the nipple.” Say that again: “Force food through the nipple.” Science!</p></blockquote>
<p>Laughter lowers blood pressure and stress hormones, increases energy and creativity, and just makes us feel good. Do we need a better reason than that?</p>
<p>(Before you leave a comment: yes, we know this post has a few, er, choice words. To our eyes, the few four-letter words in this post weren&#8217;t used gratuitously and flowed from the bluntly informal tone that made the piece so funny to us.)</p>
<p>What did you think of this choice? Will you read more from <a title="Bohemian Radio" href="http://philloz3000.wordpress.com/" target="_blank">Bohemian Radio</a>?</p>
<p><em>For more on Freshly Pressed, check out <a href="http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2012/09/19/what-makes-a-post-freshly-press-able-a-space-for-learning/" target="_blank">last week’s Freshly Press-able post</a>, read our roundup of <a href="http://en.blog.wordpress.com/2012/09/04/freshly-pressed-editors-picks-for-august-2012/">Editors’ Picks for August</a>, or read <a href="http://en.support.wordpress.com/freshly-pressed/">So You Want to Be Freshly Pressed</a>.</em></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/10334/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/10334/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=10334&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2012/09/27/what-makes-a-post-freshly-press-able-bacon-in-a-toaster/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/2367004060918e221dcb9799584e9279?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Michelle, Communications</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dailypost.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/bacon.jpg?w=227" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Toaster Bacon!</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dailypost.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/future-tv.jpg?w=246" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Television... of the FUTURE</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gnawing the Story Bone</title>
		<link>http://brevity.wordpress.com/2012/09/25/gnawing-the-story-bone/</link>
		<comments>http://brevity.wordpress.com/2012/09/25/gnawing-the-story-bone/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2012 12:15:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dinty W. Moore</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Brevity Updates]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Teaching Resources]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alexis Paige]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Annie Dillard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robert Creeley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing Life]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://brevity.wordpress.com/?p=2884</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[“Pursue, keep up with, circle round and round your life… Know your own bone: gnaw at it, bury it, unearth it, and gnaw at it still” —Thoreau, as quoted in Annie Dillard’s The Writing Life A GUEST POST FROM ALEXIS PAIGE: I am a writer first, but once I become a teacher, I will use [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2884&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:right;">“Pursue, keep up with, circle round and round your life…<br />
Know your own bone: gnaw at it, bury it, unearth it, and gnaw at it still”<br />
—Thoreau, as quoted in Annie Dillard’s <em>The Writing Life</em></p>
<p><strong>A GUEST POST FROM ALEXIS PAIGE</strong>:</p>
<p><a href="http://brevity.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/abc-201.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-2887" style="margin:5px 20px;" title="abc (20)" src="http://brevity.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/abc-201.jpg?w=300&h=219" alt="" width="300" height="219" /></a>I am a writer first, but once I become a teacher, I will use smoke and mirrors to get my students unstuck, to get them gnawing on their own bones. We do rapid-fire writing drills. I play keen illusionist to their bored bravado, ratcheting the intensity with cliché—<em>C’mon, guys! Time’s a-wasting! There’s money on the line! (Who says such things?) </em>In fact, our whole selves are on the line, and we all know this, hence, the magic show. As writers, we sometimes have to trick ourselves into <em>going there</em>: we have to dodge our conscious minds with sporting maneuvers.</p>
<p>I do, anyway. Each time I write (or teach) I stand at this conscious edge, with my mind’s cartoonish miasma at my back—all of its limitations and lost points and monkeys and awful fucking chatter. Still, going there and beyond is the point, the singular, impossible point, and sometimes it is also the reward. The point is to hold my breath and throw my whole body into the deep that others may do the same—whether in writing or life. The point is to do it because others have done it before, and their doing it mattered.</p>
<p>So I find prompts in writing books or online, and I save them in my teacher’s Rolodex. My students sniff corny from a mile off; corny doesn’t get you <em>there. </em>The good prompts mimic the jumping off point, that feeling of running headlong at the abyss until your breath is ragged, your steps loose engines of wholeness, and your rhythm your own little rain dance.  <em>I remember. I don’t remember. I think. I don’t think. I fear. I don’t fear. I love. I don’t love.  I am.  I am not. </em>Good stuff comes from the litotes; some higher force comes to bear in the negations, and tamps the language into shiny coins.  My students fear the surprises that emerge here; they don’t want to share them. “That’s good,” I tell them, “go on…” And here again, I am convincing myself.</p>
<p>“What’s your larger theme?” my writing buddy Sarah asks about my current memoir project. I don’t want it, but I need her to ask this, to prompt me in this way. She says, “I think it’s: <em>Why Alcoholism?</em>” I have to stop for a few days and ask the question until it becomes a koan. W<em>hat is the theme? What is the theme? Why? Where am I going? What do I want people to do or feel? </em>The questions seem aimless, rising dust motes in my ears. And then I have it: it is not <em>Why alcoholism?</em> Not exactly. It is so simple, it seems silly to write it down, but I do anyway&#8211;on a sticky note with the closest available marker:</p>
<p><em>WHO AM I?</em></p>
<p>“What am I to myself/ that must be remembered,/ insisted upon/ so often?” Robert Creeley writes in his poem “The Rain.”  Ultimately, we keep writing and prompting and asking not because we want to know so much as we need the relief that comes after the knowing, the relief that comes after the awful black mounting and the storms marching upon us. We need the rain to come and wash us clean.</p>
<p>&#8211;</p>
<p><em><strong>Alexis Paige</strong>’s </em>writing has appeared in<em>Transfer Magazine, 14 Hills: The SFSU Review, Seven Days: Vermont’s Independent Voice, Prison</em> <em>Legal News, Ragazine</em>, and on<em> Brevity</em>’s Nonfiction Blog. Alexis was twice named a top-ten finalist of <em>Glamour</em> Magazine’s annual personal essay contest. She received an M.A. in poetry from San Francisco State University and is pursuing an MFA in Creative Nonfiction from the Stonecoast low-residency program in Maine. She is at work on a memoir about how 749 days in the Texas criminal justice system taught her to grow up. She lives and teaches in Vermont.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0984616667/brevitynonfic-20" target="_blank"><strong>~ Want to Write Flash Nonfiction? Read the Rose Metal Guide ~</strong></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2884/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2884/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2884&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://brevity.wordpress.com/2012/09/25/gnawing-the-story-bone/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c7d42654cbb0914c0d5a92475b3aa4b9?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">brevity</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://brevity.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/abc-201.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">abc (20)</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Plain Writing</title>
		<link>http://maasmith.com/2012/09/25/plain-writing/</link>
		<comments>http://maasmith.com/2012/09/25/plain-writing/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2012 23:08:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Maggie</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[law]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[plain language]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://maasmith.com/?p=2490</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A few weeks ago at work, there was a seminar about the Plain Writing Act, which President Obama signed into law on October 13, 2010. The purpose of the act is just as it says: to require federal agencies use plain writing in every covered document issued or substantially revised. I think the Plain Writing [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2490&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A few weeks ago at work, there was a seminar about the <a href="http://plainlanguage.gov">Plain Writing Act</a>, which President Obama signed into law on October 13, 2010. The purpose of the act is just as it says: to require federal agencies use plain writing in every covered document issued or substantially revised. I think the Plain Writing Act should have been signed into law a long time ago, because who wants to read through legal jargon when they’re trying to get information about health insurance? It’s especially unfair to the elderly, who shouldn’t have to hire a lawyer just to read about their choice of assisted living centers, nursing homes, etc.</p>
<p>I learned that the general public reads at about an 8<sup>th</sup> grade level. I don’t think that’s a good thing, but I suspect that with college becoming (supposedly) more affordable these days, and with more people going to college, the nation’s average reading level should rise, hopefully to around the 10<sup>th</sup> grade level or even higher. Most documents intended for the public viewing and produced by the government are most definitely not written at an 8<sup>th</sup> grade or even a 10<sup>th</sup> grade level; they’re written at about a 16<sup>th</sup> grade level, which is the reading level of the average college senior. Something’s wrong with that picture.</p>
<p>Of course, the plain writing principles don’t have to apply to just legal or government writing. As George Orwell says in his essay “<a href="https://www.mtholyoke.edu/acad/intrel/orwell46.htm" target="_blank">Politics and the English Language</a>,” “As I have tried to show, modern writing at its worst does not consist in picking out words for the sake of their meaning and inventing images in order to make the meaning clearer. It consists in gumming together long strips of words which have already been set in order by someone else, and making the results presentable by sheer humbug.”</p>
<p>So here are a few plain writing tips:</p>
<p>-Use short sentences.</p>
<p>-To quote The Elements of Style, “Omit needless words.”</p>
<p>-If you have a big word, chances are you can find a smaller word or a group of smaller words that mean the same thing and cause less confusion.</p>
<p>-Don’t use noun or adjective strings. Instead of something like, “Draft laboratory animal rights protection regulations” you can say “Draft regulations to protect the rights of laboratory animals.”</p>
<p>-When using any kind of acronym or abbreviation, always define it. Most people don’t have the time, patience, or energy to go hunting for the meanings of abbreviations.</p>
<p>-It might seem like common sense, but it’s often forgotten: write for your audience. Think about who they are. If they’re business professionals, it’s suitable to write at a 10<sup>th</sup> grade level or higher. If they’re third graders, write at a third grade level.</p>
<p>Plain writing is simple and beautiful by itself, without all those extraneous adverbs and adjectives. The whole point of writing is to convey a message, and if that message is lost among jargon and acronyms and meandering sentences, then you’ve missed the point and your readers are not absorbing your message.</p>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2490&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://maasmith.com/2012/09/25/plain-writing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/77422ba2002fe2358002ecc1781aceb2?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F1.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">maasmith7</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Carta Da Aquarello, the Best Possible Impression, and Evil Babies</title>
		<link>http://onestreetshy.com/2012/09/25/verona-italy-and-carta-da-aquerello-the-best-possible-impression-and-evil-babies/</link>
		<comments>http://onestreetshy.com/2012/09/25/verona-italy-and-carta-da-aquerello-the-best-possible-impression-and-evil-babies/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2012 21:33:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>onestreetshy</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Travel and Travel Essays]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[David Sedaris]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Italian language]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jennifer Allison]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[La Bella Figura]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[languages]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[verona italy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[watercolor]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://onestreetshy.com/?p=706</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Yesterday I spent some time “talking” to Lucia, the owner of the art supply store I frequent on Corso Cavour.  I was specifically looking for a large piece of watercolor paper.  Although I’ve no idea what I’m going to paint on it, I’m sure whatever or whoever it is will no doubt be unclothed.  Not [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=706&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://onestreetshy.com/2012/09/25/verona-italy-and-carta-da-aquerello-the-best-possible-impression-and-evil-babies/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>21</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/53ed0436e151045aa952cd834da9085f?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">onestreetshy</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Happy National Comic Day!</title>
		<link>http://bohemianonrye.com/2012/09/25/happy-national-comic-day/</link>
		<comments>http://bohemianonrye.com/2012/09/25/happy-national-comic-day/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2012 21:14:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>bohemianonrye</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://bohemianonrye.com/?p=117</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[That&#8217;s right, fans of sequential art in all its forms! And in celebration, here is a post I wrote about five comics that writers should read. Enjoy! &#8212; Comics. I love comics. They really were what made childhood awesome. My dad and I would go to the comic shop every week and buy stacks and [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=117&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>That&#8217;s right, fans of sequential art in all its forms! And in celebration, here is a post I wrote about five comics that writers should read. Enjoy!<br />
&#8212;</p>
<p>Comics. I love comics. They really were what made childhood awesome. My dad and I would go to the comic shop every week and buy stacks and stacks of comics, and as a result, I&#8217;ve never stopped loving them.</p>
<p>You don&#8217;t have to write comics, but there is a lot you can learn as a writer from them: characterization through dialogue, the importance of a strong image, the power of silence. Don&#8217;t ever tell me comics aren&#8217;t literature. They can be as powerful as a novel &#8211; memorable, emotional, character-driven. So what if it has pictures?</p>
<p>So! This week we have 5 comics for writers. I&#8217;ve tried to avoid long-running series &#8211; it wouldn&#8217;t be fair to go, &#8220;Read Batman&#8221; would it? &#8211; but there may be one or two that was technically serialized or came in multiple parts. Whatever.</p>
<p>1. Blankets by Craig Thompson</p>
<p><a href="http://smg.photobucket.com/albums/v423/winterjade/?action=view&amp;current=blankets.jpg" target="_blank"><img alt="Photobucket" border="0" src="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v423/winterjade/blankets.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>I started college with this graphic novel. It was the largest book I had ever owned, and it still dwarfs most of my collection (along with Thompson&#8217;s most recent work, Habibi, which is also worth reading). It is a beautiful story about growing up, falling in love, having it fall apart, and then putting your life together again. It&#8217;s Catcher in the Rye, Garden State and all those other teens-and-early-twenties-trying-to-make-sense-of-the-world movies and books altogether with beautiful dreamlike inkwork.</p>
<p>2. Watchmen by Alan Moore</p>
<p><a href="http://smg.photobucket.com/albums/v423/winterjade/?action=view&amp;current=watchmen.jpg" target="_blank"><img alt="Photobucket" border="0" src="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v423/winterjade/watchmen.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>At the basest look, Watchmen is a story about super heroes. And that alone makes it awesome. But when you start taking apart the characters, looking at them as they peel apart throughout the story, you realize that it&#8217;s a story about human beings. Each person in this book represents all the things a hero can be, and what a hero can become for a world that may or may not deserve him.</p>
<p>Speaking of heroes&#8230;</p>
<p>3. The Killing Joke by Alan Moore</p>
<p><a href="http://smg.photobucket.com/albums/v423/winterjade/?action=view&amp;current=Killingjoke.jpg" target="_blank"><img alt="Photobucket" border="0" src="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v423/winterjade/Killingjoke.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>This comic does pretty much the opposite of what Watchmen did. What we have here is a decoded, dissected look at a villain (a villain who plays the part of the narrator, at that). And then, as we think we know what is sanity and insanity, what is good and evil, the reader questions just how different the protagonist and antagonist are.</p>
<p>4. Maus by Art Spiegelman</p>
<p><a href="http://smg.photobucket.com/albums/v423/winterjade/?action=view&amp;current=maus.jpg" target="_blank"><img alt="Photobucket" border="0" src="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v423/winterjade/maus.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>This was the first &#8220;non-super-hero, not-for-kids comic&#8221; I ever read. It is a metafictional plot in which a father recounts his experiences as a Jew during World War II to his son (who is a comic artist). With all races being represented by animals &#8211; Germans are cats, Jews are mice, etc. &#8211; it is left up to Spiegelman&#8217;s amazing storytelling to make each creature unique enough in voice and features that they can be told apart.</p>
<p>5. Scott Pilgrim by Bryan Lee O&#8217;Malley</p>
<p><a href="http://smg.photobucket.com/albums/v423/winterjade/?action=view&amp;current=ScottPilgrim.jpg" target="_blank"><img alt="Photobucket" border="0" src="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v423/winterjade/ScottPilgrim.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>I love Scott Pilgrim. I love this entire series so hard. When it was first pointed out to me at a local comic shop in Richmond, I had my doubts. But what started as this fantastical, video-game-esque surreal world became&#8230;well, it all became suddenly very real. Suddenly, you were seeing your own relationships, your own friendships, your own misconceptions of events.* It suddenly became this weird headtrip that put together every love you&#8217;ve ever had. It&#8217;s a lot of fun, and then it punches you in your heart-face.</p>
<p>*not in the movie. I liked the movie alright, but just&#8230;nope, everything was exactly as it seemed in the movie. Fuck.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/117/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/117/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=117&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://bohemianonrye.com/2012/09/25/happy-national-comic-day/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/0efad13a2891bd807e4275fef371ab76?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bohemianonrye</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v423/winterjade/blankets.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Photobucket</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v423/winterjade/watchmen.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Photobucket</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v423/winterjade/Killingjoke.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Photobucket</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v423/winterjade/maus.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Photobucket</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v423/winterjade/ScottPilgrim.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Photobucket</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>At Home Play Along: Family Traditions</title>
		<link>http://cheekydiva.wordpress.com/2012/09/25/blogger-idol-at-home-play-along-family-traditions/</link>
		<comments>http://cheekydiva.wordpress.com/2012/09/25/blogger-idol-at-home-play-along-family-traditions/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2012 22:01:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>juliebrowning18</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[On Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Other Stuff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Random thoughts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogger idol]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogger idol play at home]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[contest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[postaday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cheekydiva.wordpress.com/?p=1530</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Here&#8217;s to more attention whoring!!  Thanks so much to Blogger Idol for this at home game, for which, you don&#8217;t even need a TV!  Family Traditions.  Ah,  what memories.  It&#8217;s like a sweet and sour sauce poured on my life.  The traditions of the dysfunctional family I was born into being the sour, and the [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1530&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_1542" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 258px"><a href="http://cheekydiva.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/images-341.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1542 " title="Stock Birthday Party Clip Art, Google" src="http://cheekydiva.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/images-341.jpg" alt="" width="248" height="263" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Isn&#8217;t that sweet? Yeah, whatever. it didn&#8217;t look that way at MY house.</p></div>
<p>Here&#8217;s to more attention whoring!!  Thanks so much to <a href="http://www.facebook.com/bloggeridol" target="_blank">Blogger Idol</a> for this at home game, for which, you don&#8217;t even need a TV!  Family Traditions.  Ah,  what memories.  It&#8217;s like a sweet and sour sauce poured on my life.  The traditions of the dysfunctional family I was born into being the sour, and the traditions of the amazing family I created being the sweet.  I think the best way to tackle this project is just to do the traditions of both families separately, in list form.  So, without further extra wordy words, here goes:</p>
<p>Traditions in my family (as a child)</p>
<p><span style="color:#ff0000;"><strong>-Drunken dish throw!-</strong></span>- Who?  Mom and Dad only.  Sorry kids, you only get to watch through your fingers and cower in fear. When?-each and every night!!!!! Even Sunday, Sunday, Sunday!</p>
<p><span style="color:#ff0000;"><strong>-Who is she?</strong></span>- A game just for the kids.  Whenever Mom was screaming at Dad about who he was sleeping with, since she didn&#8217;t mention real names, only slurs and hints, it was our job to figure out who it was.  The lucky winner would then present mom with the correct answer for the prize.  Usually a good smack in the face.</p>
<p><strong><span style="color:#ff0000;">-What&#8217;s for dinner?</span></strong>  We asked this question a lot more than I care to remember.  Sadly, the question was usually asked <em>after </em>our dinner was put on our plate.  My mother used  food as a weapon,  <a href="http://wp.me/p2BTAP-hO">read here</a>, and sometimes it was unrecognizable.  All we knew for sure was that it was made with that special secret ingredient&#8211;bourbon.</p>
<p><span style="color:#ff0000;"><strong>-Let&#8217;s put up the Christmas tree and then unwrap all the presents!!!</strong></span>&#8211;But let&#8217;s get shitliquoured first.  Yep.  We never knew exactly what that artificial tree would look like when put together.  Some years it did in fact resemble a tree.  Some years it looked like an interstate rest stop sculpture gone awry.  Regardless, unwrapping all the presents underneath was just as much fun&#8211;fun for the drunks who did it-who also had to re wrap and tag everything when they sobered up.  Not such a fun game on the back end now was it?</p>
<div id="attachment_1538" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 282px"><a href="http://cheekydiva.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/images-321.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1538 " title="Stock Retro Christmas Clip Art, Google" src="http://cheekydiva.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/images-321.jpg" alt="" width="272" height="185" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Ok, baby, that&#8217;s enough oohing and aaaahing. Santa needs a cocktail. We still have to ruin the kids&#8217; Christmas.</p></div>
<p>Traditions in my family (as a mom)</p>
<p><span style="color:#ff0000;"><strong>-PE Class-</strong></span>-when the weather was bad and I was stuck in the house with my three screaming kids, I would have a gym class for them.  I would yell and scream and make them drop and give me twenty and shit like that.  Wearing polyester coaches shorts and tube socks added to the fun.</p>
<p><span style="color:#ff0000;"><strong>-Homemade Halloween costumes.</strong></span>  No son of mine ever had a store bought Halloween costume.  Even when all I had to dress them up in was a cardboard box, some egg cartons and tin foil.  Quit your whining, Nancy,  you&#8217;re a robot.  Do you want candy or don&#8217;t you?</p>
<div id="attachment_1539" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 235px"><a href="http://cheekydiva.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/images-331.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1539 " title="Original source unknown.  I got this copy from consumercredit.com" src="http://cheekydiva.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/images-331.jpg" alt="" width="225" height="169" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">I think my new Halloween tradition will be killing myself before any of the other kids see me. Thanks Mom!!!</p></div>
<p>And my personal favorite&#8211;<span style="color:#ff0000;"><strong>Let&#8217;s see if we can get someone to call Child Services On Mommy!</strong> </span> I swear, my youngest son hurt himself intentionally just to win this game.  He has a file at least 3 inches thick at our clinic and was constantly covered with bruises or had some broken bone.  He also yelled in the check out line at Wal-Mart one day:</p>
<p>&#8220;Maybe you wouldn&#8217;t hit me if you didn&#8217;t drink so much, mommy.&#8221;  He was almost old enough to drive when he did that, and I can&#8217;t even count the eyeballs that fell out and went rolling across the floor.  I didn&#8217;t know whether to congratulate him on his epic score, die laughing, or kick the shit out of him right there.    It looks like the youngest in the family is the undisputed champ at that game.</p>
<p>By the grace of God, all three of my children lived to adulthood, and I wring my hands in anticipation for the day I can totally mess with the heads of their yet unborn children,  all in the name of Family Traditions, of course.</p>
<p>-</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://cheekydiva.wordpress.com/category/on-writing/'>On Writing</a>, <a href='http://cheekydiva.wordpress.com/category/other-stuff/'>Other Stuff</a>, <a href='http://cheekydiva.wordpress.com/category/random-thoughts/'>Random thoughts</a>, <a href='http://cheekydiva.wordpress.com/category/relationships/'>Relationships</a> Tagged: <a href='http://cheekydiva.wordpress.com/tag/blogger-idol/'>blogger idol</a>, <a href='http://cheekydiva.wordpress.com/tag/blogger-idol-play-at-home/'>blogger idol play at home</a>, <a href='http://cheekydiva.wordpress.com/tag/blogging/'>blogging</a>, <a href='http://cheekydiva.wordpress.com/tag/contest/'>contest</a>, <a href='http://cheekydiva.wordpress.com/tag/humor/'>humor</a>, <a href='http://cheekydiva.wordpress.com/tag/postaday/'>postaday</a>, <a href='http://cheekydiva.wordpress.com/tag/writing/'>writing</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1530/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1530/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1530/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1530/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1530/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1530/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1530/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1530/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1530/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1530/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1530/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1530/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1530/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1530/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1530&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://cheekydiva.wordpress.com/2012/09/25/blogger-idol-at-home-play-along-family-traditions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>73</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://cheekydiva.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/images-331.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://cheekydiva.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/images-331.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">images (33)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/9f4395508a91780f86677bf2d0d11bfa?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">juliebrowning18</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cheekydiva.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/images-341.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Stock Birthday Party Clip Art, Google</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cheekydiva.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/images-321.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Stock Retro Christmas Clip Art, Google</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cheekydiva.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/images-331.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Original source unknown.  I got this copy from consumercredit.com</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>One Awkward Interview</title>
		<link>http://oneawkwardyear.wordpress.com/2012/09/25/one-awkward-interview/</link>
		<comments>http://oneawkwardyear.wordpress.com/2012/09/25/one-awkward-interview/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2012 19:27:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>oneawkwardyear</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Just Straight up Awkward]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[career]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jobs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nsync]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[work]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://oneawkwardyear.wordpress.com/?p=1191</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Friends! Hello from the land of the late twenties, it’s glorious over here. Last night I went to bed at 8:15. Livin’ the dream! Seriously, though, the last few weeks have actually been quite a whirlwind of good things. I finally got a smartphone,  perfected the art of brewing loose-leaf tea and a great, great [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1191&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:left;">Friends! Hello from the land of the late twenties, it’s glorious over here. Last night I went to bed at 8:15. Livin’ the dream!</p>
<p>Seriously, though, the last few weeks have actually been quite a whirlwind of good things. I finally got a smartphone,  perfected the art of brewing loose-leaf tea and a great, great friend gave me a homemade BLT for my birthday. Pro tip for the many people vying to be my best friend: bacon helps. Especially when piled high between two slices of white bread and slathered with mayo. Nom nom!  And on top of all that, there have been some thrilling new developments at my office, which I’ve been working towards for quite some time. As bumper stickers everywhere proclaim: Life is good.</p>
<p>One result of these new shakeups: I get to interview and hire an assistant! Well, I have to share the assistant with my director but whatever, semantics. I am now one assistant closer to being this bitch:<br />
<img class="aligncenter" src="http://25.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m8z2y1aaoq1rdmihdo5_250.gif" alt="" width="160" height="160" />A lifelong goal nearly achieved.</p>
<p>The problem is, when it comes to being the boss, I’m a little less Miranda Priestly and more Michael Scott. (<a href="http://24.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lxrg45r9RH1qkxxc1o1_500.jpg">hehe</a>!) I want my colleagues to think I am the greatest person on earth and love me like I’m an extension of their own family.</p>
<p>This makes the interview process especially tedious, as I have to physically restrain myself from turning the interview into the Liz Ho Comedic Story Hour: All Puns, All The Time.</p>
<p>Interviews are awkward even without anyone busting out the joke-time finger guns. “Why do you think you are the right candidate for this job?” “Thoughts on teamwork?”  “Tell me a time you used creative problem solving techniques.” WHAT does that even meeeaaann?! I just spend the whole time wondering what the person thinks about me and trying not to be too weird. It doesn’t help I don’t have a clue what I’m looking for, I’ve never had an assistant before. I just want someone who thinks I’m hilarious and does all my work for me. I don’t think that’s too much to ask.</p>
<p>I did some Google research to find some interview tips, but it’s all just way too corporate mumbo jumbo for my tastes. To make the process smoother and more efficient, I have compiled what I believe to be a pretty foolproof list of questions I think will help me find the perfect assistant:</p>
<p>- How are you at sandwich making?<br />
- Do you clear the time on the <a href="http://oneawkwardyear.wordpress.com/2012/05/24/one-angry-list/">communal microwave</a>?<br />
- N’Sync or BSB? (There is CLEARLY a right answer here, but I&#8217;ll accept opposition, if accompanied by a spirited debate.)<br />
- Favorite season of The Wire?<br />
- Favorite rendition of The Wire theme song?<br />
- Does my hair look OK today?<br />
- Knock, knock&#8230;<br />
- Are you vegan? (anyone answering &#8216;yes&#8217; to this one is instantly eliminated.)<br />
- Can you try to juggle these highlighters?<br />
- Did you have any American Girl Dolls? Which one?<br />
- How do you feel about Zooey Deschanel?<br />
- Name three things you like about me, just based on the short time we’ve had here.<br />
- Now go get me a bagel.</p>
<p>And then I’ll just send them out the door like this:</p>
<p><img class="aligncenter" src="http://24.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lwnondkatV1qg40zoo3_250.gif" alt="" width="160" height="160" />PERRRRFECT. Send me your resume if you&#8217;re interested! xo</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://oneawkwardyear.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/miranda.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1198" title="miranda" src="http://oneawkwardyear.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/miranda.jpg" alt="" width="490" height="325" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1191/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1191/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1191&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://oneawkwardyear.wordpress.com/2012/09/25/one-awkward-interview/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>42</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/38db96ed6f9ff0d8c6f17b66f0e2e3b5?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">oneawkwardyear</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://25.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_m8z2y1aaoq1rdmihdo5_250.gif" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://24.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lwnondkatV1qg40zoo3_250.gif" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://oneawkwardyear.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/miranda.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">miranda</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Stop Sausaging Around</title>
		<link>http://seetravelmag.com/2012/09/25/six-sausage-sayings/</link>
		<comments>http://seetravelmag.com/2012/09/25/six-sausage-sayings/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2012 19:30:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Aurora Night</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Europe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Germany]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sausage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wurst]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://seetravelmag.com/?p=1012</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[After beer and bread, the most important staple in the German diet is sausage. Germans call it Wurst. It&#8217;s pronounced vurst. In honor of the wonderful German tradition of Oktoberfest (yes, I know it&#8217;s still September&#8230;I&#8217;ll explain later), I thought we&#8217;d spend a few minutes chatting about the Wurst. Germans serve up over 1500 kinds [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1012&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://seetravelmag.com/2012/09/25/six-sausage-sayings/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>22</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/fb6da6f3ab80345685b89436cf010307?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jeleigh</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://seetravelmag.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_3104.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">IMG_3104</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Battambang – A Microcosm of Cambodia.</title>
		<link>http://dominicstafford.wordpress.com/2012/09/25/battambang-a-microcosm-of-cambodia/</link>
		<comments>http://dominicstafford.wordpress.com/2012/09/25/battambang-a-microcosm-of-cambodia/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2012 14:14:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dominic Stafford Photography</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Photo Essay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Battambang]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cambodia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dominic Stafford]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dominicstafford.wordpress.com/?p=635</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A microcosm of modern Cambodia. A mix of the old and the new. Locals treasure the traditional culture, and this pride can be seen on a daily basis. It&#8217;s different to other provincial capitals. Not as dusty, not as poor, not as boring, not as lost. Over the years, power of this old town has [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=635&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A microcosm of modern Cambodia. A mix of the old and the new. Locals treasure the traditional culture, and this pride can be seen on a daily basis. It&#8217;s different to other provincial capitals. Not as dusty, not as poor, not as boring, not as lost. Over the years, power of this old town has switched hands more times than one can count on one of them &#8211; the last being the French. The Sangker river threads through the middle, on it&#8217;s way from Pailin, and onward to the Tonle Sap lake. Crossing which, is the old railway, which can now only be ridden on small motorized bamboo beds. Battambang&#8217;s got it all. A strange place, but it&#8217;s unusual qualities hold elegance. I head back regularly&#8230;<a href="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_6836.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-636" title="main road through town, battambang cambodia" src="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_6836.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="333" /></a><a href="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_6717.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-655" title="bamboo train in battambang cambodia" src="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_6717.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="333" /></a><a href="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_6841.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-637" title="real life in battambang cambodia" src="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_6841.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="333" /></a><a href="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_6861.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-638" title="evening market in battambang cambodia" src="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_6861.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="333" /></a><a href="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4434.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-659" title="fish at the market in battambang cambodia" src="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4434.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="333" /></a><a href="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4368.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-640" title="monks on a mountain in battambang cambodia" src="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4368.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="334" /></a><a href="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4337.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-649" title="phnom sampeu in battambang cambodia" src="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4337.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="333" /></a><a href="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_0457.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-647" title="pagoda on the sangker river in battambang cambodia" src="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_0457.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="333" /></a><a href="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4227.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-642" title="fishing on the sangker river in battambang cambodia" src="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4227.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="333" /></a><a href="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_0475.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-644" title="river crossing in battambang cambodia" src="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_0475.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/635/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/635/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=635&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://dominicstafford.wordpress.com/2012/09/25/battambang-a-microcosm-of-cambodia/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>20</slash:comments>
		<georss:point>0.000000 0.000000</georss:point>
		<geo:lat>0.000000</geo:lat>
		<geo:long>0.000000</geo:long>
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a68e761f811fd837a659cff5ef705fd2?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">dominicstafford</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_6836.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">main road through town, battambang cambodia</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_6717.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bamboo train in battambang cambodia</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_6841.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">real life in battambang cambodia</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_6861.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">evening market in battambang cambodia</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4434.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">fish at the market in battambang cambodia</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4368.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">monks on a mountain in battambang cambodia</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4337.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">phnom sampeu in battambang cambodia</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_0457.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">pagoda on the sangker river in battambang cambodia</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_4227.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">fishing on the sangker river in battambang cambodia</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://dominicstafford.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/img_0475.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">river crossing in battambang cambodia</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>You&#8217;re Probably A Yoga Instructor If&#8230;</title>
		<link>http://theviewfrommymat.com/2012/08/14/youre-probably-a-yoga-instructor-if/</link>
		<comments>http://theviewfrommymat.com/2012/08/14/youre-probably-a-yoga-instructor-if/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2012 03:51:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Heather Colvin</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Yoga]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anusara]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ashtanga]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bandhas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chakra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[handstand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[headstand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lululemon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pincha]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shit yogis say]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the science of yoga]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[triangle pose]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yoga]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yoga instructors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yoga miami]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yoga students]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[yoga sutras]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[you are probably a yoga instructor if]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://theviewfrommymat.com/?p=580</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[When someone tells me &#8220;Hey, I&#8217;m a yoga instructor, too&#8221; I immediately feel connected to them.  Not because I know that they too have touched sweaty, calloused feet at the end of a hot, hot class to show their students a good savasana; and not because I know they probably have valuable insights about being [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=580&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://theviewfrommymat.com/2012/08/14/youre-probably-a-yoga-instructor-if/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>25</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/3c7ebf69046a2a63e300ae306d061098?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">theviewfrommymat</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>