<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2012 21:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>I Found Him! 50&#8230;Fat&#8230;Diabetic&#8230;And Ahead of You</title>
		<link>http://trexrunner.com/2012/11/27/i-found-him/</link>
		<comments>http://trexrunner.com/2012/11/27/i-found-him/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2012 02:10:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>trexrunner</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://trexrunner.com/?p=1860</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Y&#8217;all, the past two days have been two of the weirdest days of my life. As you probably saw, the picture below has been floating around the Facebook and the internet for the past few days. Why is that weird? Well, I TOOK THAT PICTURE back in May at the Flying Pig Marathon (which turned [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1860&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Y&#8217;all, the past two days have been two of the weirdest days of my life. As you probably saw, the picture below has been floating around the Facebook and the internet for the past few days.</p>
<div id="attachment_1861" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://trexrunner.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/p1000383.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1861" title="P1000383" alt="" src="http://trexrunner.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/p1000383-e1354065384960.jpg?w=590"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The picture that will live in infamy</p></div>
<p>Why is that weird? Well, <a title="The one that isn’t funny – Flying Pig Marathon Weekend, Part 2" href="http://trexrunner.com/2012/05/08/the-one-that-isnt-funny-flying-pig-marathon-weekend-part-2/">I TOOK THAT PICTURE back in May</a> at the Flying Pig Marathon (which turned into a half marathon for me). So imagine my shock when I see that familiar looking picture being shared by not one but several of my Facebook friends, who had gotten it from other people. My first thought was &#8220;What a coincidence! Someone else took a picture of that guy too!&#8221; And then I checked my files and nope&#8230;it was ME. Seriously, the amount of shock cannot be overstated. And then I found out it was shared on <a href="http://www.happyplace.com/19452/how-to-shame-everyone-behind-you-during-a-marathon">HappyPlace</a>, and Stumbleupon, and by running groups all over Facebook! All of a sudden, a picture from my blog had gone viral after being posted seven months ago. And in typical T-Rex luck, it wasn&#8217;t even of me, but I was willing to let that slide since OMG.</p>
<p>With the help of <em>many</em> of my readers, I was able to get credit for the picture from many different sites. <a href="http://fiftyinfives.com">Halbert</a> somehow bullied the people from HappyPlace into <a href="http://www.happyplace.com/19452/how-to-shame-everyone-behind-you-during-a-marathon">giving me photo rights</a> (it even says my name on it! LOOK!) and everyone else who saw it was very proactive about sharing the link to the original race report. All of a sudden, the questions starting pouring in and it seemed like everybody and their mother wanted to know who this guy was. The only problem? Well, from that picture, you guys have as much information as I do.</p>
<div id="attachment_1863" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://trexrunner.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/128749662775983341.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1863" title="128749662775983341" alt="" src="http://trexrunner.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/128749662775983341.jpg?w=590"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Stalking isn&#8217;t funny, but this picture is.</p></div>
<p>Here&#8217;s how the epic stalking took place. I seriously creeped myself out while looking for him, but I was tireless. I HAD to find him! This is not meant to give stalkers ideas, but I recognize that it probably does. Sorry I&#8217;m not sorry &#8211; the people needed to know.</p>
<p>1. I knew my approximate finishing time for the half marathon, and I knew he was a 5o year old man. That&#8217;s it. So first, I filtered through all of the Flying Pig&#8217;s half marathon results for men ages 50-54.</p>
<p>2. Because everyone starts in different corrals, I knew his finishing time could be a good bit faster or slower than mine based on whether he started ahead of or behind me, so I focused on people within a half an hour of my approximate finishing time (I have blocked the actual time from memory).</p>
<p>3. I then cross referenced the bib numbers in the results with the race photos and searched through them. The problem? Grey is a very popular shirt color in the 50-54 male demographic&#8230;and so are black shorts. So then I had to find other identifiers- in this case, the headband and headphones.</p>
<p>4. Finally, I came across a picture that matched. I audibly shrieked.</p>
<div id="attachment_1862" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 436px"><a href="http://trexrunner.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/thomas.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1862" title="thomas" alt="" src="http://trexrunner.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/thomas.jpg?w=590"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Ladies and gentleman, allow me to introduce you to Thomas!</p></div>
<p>Now, if Thomas had Facebook, the search would have been over&#8230;but Thomas does not have Facebook, at least that I could find. The next step was therefore to search for everyone with his first and last name on Whitepages.com. I didn&#8217;t know what state he was from, but I figured Ohio would be a good start since that is where the race is and most participants are local. I got 4 matches with his first and last name and his age. Finally, I started searching the results by entering in the random cities that those 4 Thomases were from until I got a match! I&#8217;m sorry, I know you guys are so creeped out right now, but this was NECESSARY.</p>
<p>I was literally shaking when I called him because honestly, I was afraid he was going to be either a) really mad that his picture is everywhere b)  really creeped out that I found him (can&#8217;t say I would blame him) or c) that it wouldn&#8217;t be the right Thomas and all my efforts would be for naught. Obviously, no one answered when I called and I left what was surely a very frantic sounding message on his voicemail. An hour later, I was on the phone with my grandma and the number called me back. Sorry, Nana! Gotta go! IT&#8217;S THOMAS!</p>
<p>And sure enough, I had found the right guy. Pretty much the first question he asked me was &#8220;Did my son put you up to this?&#8221; Fortunately, his son had called him just an hour before I did and told him that his picture was everywhere. Thomas thought it was a joke and when I called, he thought I was in on it. Nope! As you might expect from someone who made a shirt like that, he has an awesome sense of humor and was more than happy to talk to me about the race and the picture that has made him famous! Here&#8217;s the pseudo-interview (again, the kind of <a title="Interview with the Race Director: Baton Rouge Beach Marathon" href="http://trexrunner.com/2012/11/13/interview-with-the-race-director-baton-rouge-beach-marathon/">hard hitting journalism</a> you&#8217;ve come to expect from me), during which I was so nervous that I am sure I sounded like an 11 year old girl meeting Justin Bieber. As always, italicized text indicates my enlightened thoughts and are not Thomas&#8217; fault.</p>
<div id="attachment_1864" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 478px"><a href="http://trexrunner.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/article-1313994-0b28bfc8000005dc-677_468x341.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1864" title="article-1313994-0B28BFC8000005DC-677_468x341" alt="" src="http://trexrunner.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/article-1313994-0b28bfc8000005dc-677_468x341.jpg?w=590"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The Biebs has nothing on Thomas.</p></div>
<p><strong>Was this your first half marathon? </strong></p>
<p>No, it was my second. I ran the Pig in 2011 with my daughter also. My goal this year was to beat my time from last year.</p>
<p><strong>Did you do it?</strong></p>
<p>Yes, I did, but I was a little ticked off. My finish time was somewhere around 2:45, but I thought I could finish in the 2:30-2:39 range. My main goal was to beat 2:40. Well, I ate one of those GU gel things around mile 10 and started wretching (<em>OMG! Sounds just like me!)</em>. I had to stop and catch my breath for about 5 minutes, during which time I saw the 2:45 guy run past. I was so mad! From that point on I made it my goal to catch up with that pace group, and then I made it my goal to beat them, which I did.</p>
<p><strong>When and why did you start running?</strong></p>
<p>I ran in high school and college, but life gets in the way. I started running again about 4-5 years ago as a way to get back in shape and spend time with my daughter, who is also a runner. We have run both half marathons together and we&#8217;re talking about running the full marathon next year, but I don&#8217;t know about that yet. <em>(It was at this point that I pointed out to Thomas that if I have finished 27 marathons and I was running behind HIM, then clearly, he could do a marathon too.)</em></p>
<p><strong>Where did you get the idea for the shirt?</strong></p>
<p>Well, I thought about what would piss me off the most if I read it on a shirt that was in front of me. (<em>I&#8217;m still laughing about that. Best reason ever.</em>) I wanted to needle people as much as possible, kind of get to them, you know? I know it would motivate <em>me! </em>In 2011, my shirt said &#8220;Finish or Death,&#8221; and the front of my shirt said that this year, but I added the rest onto the back for this year.</p>
<p><strong>What is the best comment anyone has made to you about the shirt?</strong></p>
<p>I&#8217;m very hard of hearing and I wear two hearing aids, plus I always have my ipod and my headphones on, so even though I know people say things to me about it during the races, I don&#8217;t always hear them. A lot of people slap me on the back as they run past, though. This year, after the race, I was walking back to my car when a lady stopped me in the parking lot and said &#8220;I saw that damn shirt in front of me the whole race and I tried like anything to beat it and I couldn&#8217;t!&#8221; My response was &#8220;How did that make <em>you </em>feel?&#8221; <em>(I died. Then he asked me if it was me that spoke to him in the parking lot, and I said no. He did beat me, though!)</em></p>
<p>When I explained to Thomas how I found him (including my results/picture cross referencing), he actually laughed and told me that HE DOES THAT to people that he finds in his finisher photos! He remembers people that he crosses the line with and then goes back and looks for their bib numbers in the pictures so he can see if he beat them or not. I about lost it. Thomas is officially my hero/new best friend. I told him that I am determined to conquer Flying Pig after my epic failure this year, and he said he would think about running the full too. He couldn&#8217;t believe that I travel and run as much as I do, but I couldn&#8217;t believe I was talking to <em>the </em>guy in the most talked about shirt on the internet.</p>
<p>And that, my friends, is the story of the man behind the best race shirt you&#8217;ll ever see. I hope you enjoyed meeting him as much as I did!</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1860/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1860/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1860&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://trexrunner.com/2012/11/27/i-found-him/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>191</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/1d0dab7149bf0248ceb96e5bb20660c2?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">trexrunner</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://trexrunner.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/p1000383-e1354065384960.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">P1000383</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://trexrunner.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/128749662775983341.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">128749662775983341</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://trexrunner.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/thomas.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">thomas</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://trexrunner.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/article-1313994-0b28bfc8000005dc-677_468x341.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">article-1313994-0B28BFC8000005DC-677_468x341</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statue</title>
		<link>http://jaschmehl.wordpress.com/2012/11/27/statue-flash-fiction/</link>
		<comments>http://jaschmehl.wordpress.com/2012/11/27/statue-flash-fiction/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2012 21:12:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>jaschmehl</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fear and panic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flash fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rome]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[short story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Statue]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://jaschmehl.wordpress.com/?p=152</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Amelia stood on the edge of the tour group cluster and dutifully stared at the statue. She didn&#8217;t belong with these people. The only person close to her age was the guide and she suspected she made him uncomfortable. His engineered expressions that elicited laughter from his usual audience of octogenarians evoked only sighs from Amelia. She [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=152&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://jaschmehl.wordpress.com/2012/11/27/statue-flash-fiction/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/afc8d3717a6aae51e09b38f42814bef3?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jaschmehl</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jaschmehl.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/statue.png?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">statue</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Booby Machine</title>
		<link>http://thejigglybits.com/2012/11/23/the-booby-machine/</link>
		<comments>http://thejigglybits.com/2012/11/23/the-booby-machine/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2012 04:09:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Teeny Bikini</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[breasts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cleaning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comedy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[funny]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Inspirational]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thejigglybits.com/?p=587</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;Wow. You have the cleanest ceiling ever,&#8221; I said, as a my large breast was smashed like a pancake in the booby machine. The nurse was taken aback. [I am making polite conversation, lady. Hello? Work with me, okay?] &#8220;Um&#8230; yes, I guess we have cleaners,&#8221; she said laughing. &#8220;And they clean the ceiling?! That&#8217;s [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=587&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;Wow. You have the cleanest ceiling ever,&#8221; I said, as a my large breast was smashed like a pancake in the booby machine.</p>
<p>The nurse was taken aback.</p>
<p>[I am making polite conversation, lady. Hello? Work with me, okay?]</p>
<p>&#8220;Um&#8230; yes, I guess we have cleaners,&#8221; she said laughing.</p>
<p>&#8220;And they clean the ceiling?! That&#8217;s impressive,&#8221; I said. And I wasn&#8217;t even faking the &#8220;impressed part.&#8221;</p>
<p>All cleaning impresses me &#8211; as long as I don&#8217;t have to do it.</p>
<p>&#8220;Yeah, I used to clean my ceilings until I started working again. I have 3 kids,&#8221; she said, as if she needed to explain herself.</p>
<p>She is re-adjusting my massive tata for the side x-ray now. When the booby machine clamps downward on the breast from the top, it is weird.</p>
<p>When it clamps inward to take the side x-ray, that shit <em>hurts</em>.</p>
<p>&#8220;So let me get this straight, you clean your ceiling? Really?&#8221; I said, with the appropriate amount of shock and admiration.</p>
<p>&#8220;Yes, twice  a year. I mean I used to,&#8221; again, justifying her behavior.</p>
<p>I am hardly a domestic goddess. But I do have my list of things that Ain&#8217;t Getting Cleaned By Me In This Lifetime&#8230;<a href="http://thejigglybits.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/undomestic.jpg"><img class="alignright  wp-image-591" style="margin-top:10px;margin-bottom:10px;" title="undomestic" alt="" src="http://thejigglybits.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/undomestic.jpg?w=200&#038;h=156" height="156" width="200" /></a></p>
<p><strong>Windows.</strong></p>
<p>Six years ago, my cheaper-than-cheap ass brought new windows for my dining room because it was freezing in the winter. The sales guy was so excited to explain the best function of the double-hung windows.</p>
<p>&#8220;Wait until you see this!,&#8221; he said, completely primed to ejaculate any second &#8211; he was so happy. And he pushed in two levers so the bottom half of the window opened inward. &#8220;Now, you can clean the outside of the window while you are <em>in</em>side your house!&#8221;</p>
<p>[Insert orgasm here. His, not mine.]</p>
<p>Of course, I looked at him like he was explaining quantum physics to me.</p>
<p>&#8220;People clean the windows on the <em>outside.&#8221; </em>I said legitimately confused.<em> &#8221;</em> Why? That is what the rain is for and dirt is supposed to be outside. That is where it lives.&#8221;</p>
<p>He thought that was super funny. [Yes, me and my super funny vagina making the salesman laugh again. How <em>do</em> we do it?  Next, we will juggle and do Kegel exercises simultaneously. Behold!]</p>
<p><strong>The roof.</strong></p>
<p>Once I got up early on a Saturday [I know. Right? It was a miracle. Pigs also flew.  And Lindsay didn't hit anyone with her car. It was a magical day.] My neighbor, Bobby, was on his roof with a broom-y thing and buckets of cleaning stuff.</p>
<p>Scrub.</p>
<p>Scrub.</p>
<p>Scrub.</p>
<p>Bobby was really focused on the scrubby broom. [Dude, YOU. ARE. GONNA. DIE!]</p>
<p>Of course, I said, &#8220;So whatcha doin&#8217;?&#8221; [because I am nosey.]</p>
<p>He replied matter-of-factly, &#8220;Cleaning the roof.&#8221;</p>
<p>[Really?! I guess I should of asked <em>why</em>? Because if he falls to his death, it will be a huge problem <em>for me</em>. Duh. Who will clean up dead things in my backyard place. Me? Everyone knows I am not emotionally-equipped to maintain my home alone. Dude, focus on living, focus on my needs. <em>Helloooo... </em>]</p>
<p>Note to self: If you ever sell this house, do not buy another one. Get an apartment and shut up.</p>
<p>Now, that I think of it &#8211; all of the house exterior chores are out of bounds. I can barely keep up with the inside.</p>
<p>Anyway, I don&#8217;t do anything that requires my feet to be more than 2 feet off the ground. It&#8217;s unnatural.</p>
<p>Which leads to my next point&#8230;</p>
<p><strong>Cleaning the ceiling.</strong> Who even knew that was thing?</p>
<p>I don&#8217;t do ladders. Ladders are for other people <del> who like to die a stupid death</del>. I can&#8217;t even wrap my brain around accomplishing this task without a Xanax.</p>
<p>Or some wine.</p>
<p>A barrel of it.</p>
<p>I wish the nurse didn&#8217;t feel she needed to sound apologetic to a complete stranger about not cleaning the stupid ceiling.</p>
<p>Which is yet another reason I shouldn&#8217;t procreate.</p>
<p>If I jettison a person out of my sweet honeypot, that will be the last task I ever complete.</p>
<p>That includes cleaning.</p>
<p>My house would be shithole.</p>
<p>&#8216;Cause my honeypot [vagina, vajayjay, Her Royal Highness] would need 25 years to recuperate, massive amounts of pampering, and a car, maid and butler.</p>
<p>And if I had 3 kids?!</p>
<p>I would probably stab anyone who said the word Pine Sol in a 3-mile radius.</p>
<p>Then, I would go to jail.</p>
<p>And jail is not cute.</p>
<p>I keep looking around the big office as one of my mammoth tatas is being squished in the booby machine and the other pendulous tata just hangs there. It is the cleanest place on earth I determine and it smells like a potpourri factory exploded.</p>
<p>Which is very relaxing, for some reason. If my boob weren&#8217;t being held hostage, I might want to curl up in a big topless ball and nap.</p>
<p>Like my cats who literally fall asleep <em>while</em> they are walking.</p>
<p>But I am a little distracted by the truckloads of parting gifts.</p>
<p>They are everywhere.</p>
<p>Glass containers lined up on the window sill like soldiers with pink nail polish and hats and combs and brushes. You name it.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s like a Booby Game Show with lots of pink prizes.</p>
<p>Usually I would consider backing up a U-Haul and loading up on the free stuff. [Yes, I am tacky like that.]</p>
<p>When all is said and done, I just take one pink nail polish.</p>
<p>I figure a clean bill of health is all I really want.</p>
<p>And that&#8217;s exactly what a got. Cancer-free boobies.</p>
<p>That is the best kind of clean.</p>
<p>I mean really.</p>
<p>+++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++++</p>
<p><strong><span style="color:#ff6600;">Like this blog?</span> </strong><strong>Please forward</strong> <strong>it</strong> to people who have computers, by using the nifty buttons below &#8211;  or <strong>SUBSCRIBE!</strong> :)</p>
<p><a title="Yes, Like Us on Facebook! Click here." href="http://www.facebook.com/pages/The-Jiggly-Bits/310134895767906" target="_blank">Yes, <strong>Like Us on Facebook!</strong> Click here.</a></p>
<p><sup>© The Jiggly Bits. All rights reserved.</sup></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/587/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/587/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/587/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/587/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/587/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/587/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/587/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/587/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/587/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/587/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/587/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/587/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/587/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/587/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=587&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thejigglybits.com/2012/11/23/the-booby-machine/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>165</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://thejigglybits.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/pink-nail-polish_gal.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://thejigglybits.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/pink-nail-polish_gal.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">pink-nail-polish_gal</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f230ae2cfb9fd47c07595282e4bd65ad?s=96&#38;d=wavatar&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mynameistaryn</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thejigglybits.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/undomestic.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">undomestic</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Changing the Queer Narrative in Popular Media</title>
		<link>http://vemccarroll.wordpress.com/2012/11/30/changing-the-queer-narrative-in-popular-media/</link>
		<comments>http://vemccarroll.wordpress.com/2012/11/30/changing-the-queer-narrative-in-popular-media/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 03:03:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Victoria McCarroll</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[reflections]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brokeback mountain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cinema]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gay romance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lgbt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[queer]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://vemccarroll.wordpress.com/?p=96</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Tonight I&#8217;m listening to the soundtrack to Brokeback Mountain. The instrumental pieces by Gustavo Santaolalla are so beautiful, but listening to it makes me think a lot about the tragic gay story and how Hollywood tells queer stories to a straight audience. I appreciate the impact Brokeback Mountain has had on mainstream culture, but I think it&#8217;s time [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=96&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tonight I&#8217;m listening to the soundtrack to <em>Brokeback Mountain</em>. The instrumental pieces by Gustavo Santaolalla are so beautiful, but listening to it makes me think a lot about the tragic gay story and how Hollywood tells queer stories to a straight audience. I appreciate the impact <em>Brokeback Mountain </em>has had on mainstream culture, but I think it&#8217;s time for straight audiences to support a different gay narrative, one that allows for the possibility of happiness and fulfillment.</p>
<p>I remember first viewing <em>Brokeback Mountain. </em>I was sixteen at the time, and I had already spent several years seeking out gay media&#8211;always in secret, as I was not out at the time. Of course, I cried. Some years later I found the short story on my sister&#8217;s bookshelf and furtively read it. I loved the short story as much as I loved the movie, and I now have my own copy on my bookshelf.</p>
<p>What I find most interesting about <em>Brokeback Mountain</em> is it&#8217;s the only major film about a gay romance that I can recall becoming popular in the mainstream. Sure, we&#8217;ve had films such as <em>Milk </em>and <i>Monster</i> (another one that made me cry), but I can&#8217;t think of another mainstream film where gay romance was the focus. For that reason, I think <em>Brokeback Mountain </em>holds a unique spot in LGBT film history.</p>
<p><span id="more-96"></span></p>
<p>And for another reason as well. I&#8217;ve seen a lot of LGBT movies since I was sixteen, from <em>Saving Face </em>to <em>Patrik, Age 1.5</em> (one of my personal favorites). Hell, I&#8217;ve been known to rent movies just because I knew they had a gay scene in them (<em>Kiss Kiss, Bang Bang</em>, anyone?). Most of these films have not become popular outside the LGBT audience, and I think that&#8217;s because they were made with an LGBT audience in mind.</p>
<p>I looked up <em>Brokeback Moutain</em> on IMDb to check the year when it was made, and then I referred to the user made movie lists to remind myself of some other queer films I had seen. I was surprised to see that the first eight lists were not LGBT specific. I can&#8217;t say for sure, but I have to wonder: was <em>Brokeback Mountain </em>made for straight people?</p>
<p>I know a statement like that would ruffle more than a few feathers. I&#8217;m not saying it&#8217;s a bad thing, just that it&#8217;s interesting. Whether or not the film was made for a straight audience, it remains true that <em>Brokeback Mountain</em> was quite successful with a straight audience. It&#8217;s a film that I think remains a cultural touchstone, and so it&#8217;s important to keep in mind the kind of message it sent.</p>
<p><em>Brokeback Mountain </em>is a tragedy. The two main characters can never pursue their romance openly; they both marry women to keep up appearances. At the end, Jack becomes the victim of a hate crime. It&#8217;s not the most progressive story told about two gay men. I won&#8217;t deny it&#8217;s a beautiful film, but I don&#8217;t find it particularly promising that the one popular gay romance story is one that ends in homophobic violence.</p>
<p>During the summer, I wrote content for a queer women of color website. One thing the founder asked of me and my fellow interns was that we not reinforce a narrative of victimhood. She wanted to focus on queer women of color taking power and fighting oppression, rather than on those women falling victim to hatred and bigotry.</p>
<p><em>Brokeback Moutain </em>is a story of victimhood, and I think it was popular in part because of that. Though Jack speaks often of wanting to have a real relationship with Ennis, neither character is threatening to a straight audience. They don&#8217;t flaunt their homosexual desires. They&#8217;re both masculine. They&#8217;re not looking to get married. They&#8217;re just two men trying to navigate their same sex desires. And they are unsuccessful.</p>
<p>Yes, there are many tragic queer stories. LGBT people are brutalized and murdered all the time. <em>Brokeback Mountain</em> does not tell an unrealistic story. But I think it&#8217;s critical that we stop and examine why the only popular gay romance story in film is one that ends in death.</p>
<p>Earlier today, I read a post by a young woman who talked about holding hands with her girlfriend in public. I expected the story to end with someone calling them dykes or trying to hurt them. Instead, the post talked about a woman smiling at the pair. It&#8217;s a simple gesture that meant a lot to this young woman. I want to hear more stories like this. I want to see a new film rise up&#8211;not to displace <em>Brokeback Mountain</em>, but to show that it&#8217;s possible to be queer and be happy.</p>
<p>It <em>is </em>possible to be queer and be happy. Even with the Ugandan kill the gays bill, even with awful people like Rick Warren spouting homophobic hatred. We&#8217;ve got a long way to go, but we&#8217;ve made a lot of progress. I think it&#8217;s time for a new story to be told to a straight audience&#8211;one that reminds society that LGBT people are not just victims.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/96/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/96/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=96&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://vemccarroll.wordpress.com/2012/11/30/changing-the-queer-narrative-in-popular-media/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>21</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/824ba46b4f61a112417115d03fa29d5a?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">vemccarroll</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Thirty-Two Months of Grief</title>
		<link>http://ptbertram.wordpress.com/2012/11/27/thirty-two-months-of-grief/</link>
		<comments>http://ptbertram.wordpress.com/2012/11/27/thirty-two-months-of-grief/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2012 02:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Pat Bertram</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grief]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[relationships]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dead]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[death of a soul mate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ferris wheel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[living alone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spiraling down into grief]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thirty-Two Months of Grief]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://ptbertram.wordpress.com/?p=5955</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I haven’t been writing much about grief lately. It’s been thirty-two months &#8212; 977 days &#8212; since my life mate/soul mate died. In that time, many others have suffered grievous losses, and to continue mentioning my grief seems like all I’m doing is whining. Still, this is my loss, and what other people experience, no [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=5955&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://ptbertram.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/3-2-11.jpg"><img class="alignleft  wp-image-5956" title="Ferris Wheel" alt="" src="http://ptbertram.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/3-2-11.jpg?w=180&#038;h=133" height="133" width="180" /></a>I haven’t been writing much about grief lately. It’s been thirty-two months &#8212; 977 days &#8212; since my life mate/soul mate died. In that time, many others have suffered grievous losses, and to continue mentioning my grief seems like all I’m doing is whining. Still, this is my loss, and what other people experience, no matter how horrific, doesn’t lessen my sorrow. I don’t have the same sort of raw pain that I did at the beginning, of course, nor do I have the gut-wrenching angst that so often bedeviled me during those first months, but I do experience bouts of sadness and yearning.</p>
<p>My emotions are on a slow Ferris wheel ride, usually sliding down into sadness on Saturdays, the day he died &#8212; a day that apparently is etched in my very psyche &#8212; and then a gradual climb to hope and possibility on Monday and Tuesday.</p>
<p>Even when Saturday’s sorrow is fleeting, as it often is now, I find that I am at my most vulnerable then, and any hurtful word, thoughtlessness, or setback can send me spiraling down into grief. Without him to talk to, without my being able to casually mention the slights and so slough them off, the unkindnesses take hold and remind me that I am alone. Which reminds me that he is dead. Which makes me grieve.</p>
<p>I can handle being alone. I can even handle his being out of my life. What I can’t handle is his being dead. It’s possible he still exists somewhere, perhaps lolling on the shores of some cosmic sea, a cat purring in his arms, but I have no way of knowing for sure. All I know is that he is out of this earthly life. Gone. Deleted. I still cannot wrap my mind around that. And I still can’t help feeling that he was cheated out of a couple of decades of life.</p>
<p>Sometimes I pretend to believe that he left so that I could experience life in a way we couldn’t experience together, but other times, especially on the day of the month that he died &#8212; such as today &#8212; I find it impossible to pretend that this new experience of life alone is a positive thing. And even if it is for the best, it comes at the cost of his life, and that is too big of a price to pay.</p>
<p>If I sound discouraged today, the truth is, I am dis-courage-d. Have lost my courage. Sometimes I am strong and forward looking, but on this 977th day of his goneness, I am unable to gather the courage to believe that any good will come from his being dead and my being alone. I’d give anything to see him one more time, to have him smile at me or say an encouraging word, but no matter how much I yearn for such an encounter, it’s not going to happen in this lifetime.</p>
<p>I am used to the ups and downs now, so I know all I have to do is hang on, and in a day or two, when I am less tired perhaps, I’ll find my courage again. And some day I might even come to believe that this new experience of life alone truly is a positive thing.</p>
<p>***</p>
<p><a href="http://patbertram.com/" target="_blank">Pat Bertram</a> is the author of the conspiracy novels <a href="http://www.secondwindpublishing.com/product_info.php?manufacturers_id=17&amp;products_id=82" target="_blank"><i>Light Bringer</i></a>, <a href="http://www.secondwindpublishing.com/product_info.php?manufacturers_id=17&amp;products_id=50" target="_blank"><i>More Deaths Than One</i></a><i>, </i><a href="http://www.secondwindpublishing.com/product_info.php?manufacturers_id=17&amp;products_id=47" target="_blank"><i>A Spark of Heavenly Fire</i></a><i>, </i>and <a href="http://www.secondwindpublishing.com/product_info.php?manufacturers_id=17&amp;products_id=60" target="_blank"><i>Daughter Am I</i></a><i>. </i>Bertram is also the author of <a href="http://www.secondwindpublishing.com/product_info.php?manufacturers_id=17&amp;products_id=94&amp;osCsid=cbb8e1271da539770275973f637711dd" target="_blank"><i>Grief: The Great Yearning</i></a>, “an exquisite book, wrenching to read, and at the same time full of profound truths.” Connect with <a href="https://plus.google.com/117707913422514281227/about" target="_blank">Pat on Google+</a></p>
<br /> Tagged: <a href='http://ptbertram.wordpress.com/tag/dead/'>dead</a>, <a href='http://ptbertram.wordpress.com/tag/death-of-a-soul-mate/'>death of a soul mate</a>, <a href='http://ptbertram.wordpress.com/tag/ferris-wheel/'>Ferris wheel</a>, <a href='http://ptbertram.wordpress.com/tag/living-alone/'>living alone</a>, <a href='http://ptbertram.wordpress.com/tag/spiraling-down-into-grief/'>spiraling down into grief</a>, <a href='http://ptbertram.wordpress.com/tag/thirty-two-months-of-grief/'>Thirty-Two Months of Grief</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5955/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/5955/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=5955&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://ptbertram.wordpress.com/2012/11/27/thirty-two-months-of-grief/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>49</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c87f1e7be44f06eff597e9a481b68868?s=96&#38;d=identicon" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Pat Bertram</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://ptbertram.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/3-2-11.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Ferris Wheel</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sculpture By the Sea</title>
		<link>http://picturette.wordpress.com/2012/11/06/sculpture-by-the-sea/</link>
		<comments>http://picturette.wordpress.com/2012/11/06/sculpture-by-the-sea/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2012 11:21:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>picturette</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[australia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bondi]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[picturette]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sculpture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sculpture by the sea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sydney]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tamarama]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://picturette.wordpress.com/?p=2129017864</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I finally managed to get down to Sculpture by the Sea on the weekend. Ever since I moved to Sydney I have been meaning to check it out but I kept leaving it until the last minute and then for some reason I would never get there. I saw the sculpture park in Western Australia [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2129017864&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I finally managed to get down to <a href="http://www.sculpturebythesea.com/Home.aspx" target="_blank">Sculpture by the Sea</a> on the weekend. Ever since I moved to Sydney I have been meaning to check it out but I kept leaving it until the last minute and then for some reason I would never get there. I saw the sculpture park in Western Australia a couple of times, so I am happy I finally got to do the coastal walk on the opposite side of Australia! The walk between Bondi and Tamarama is pretty breathtaking already, the sculptures literally add another dimension. Sculpture by the Sea is on again in March 2013 at Cottesloe Beach in WA and also in June 2013 at Aarhus in Denmark.<br />
<img src="http://picturette.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/sxs_2012-17.jpg?w=590" alt="" title="SxS_2012-17"   class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2129017866" /><br />
<img src="http://picturette.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/sxs_2012-18.jpg?w=590" alt="" title="SxS_2012-18"   class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2129017867" /><br />
<img src="http://picturette.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/sxs_2012-16.jpg?w=590" alt="" title="SxS_2012-16"   class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2129017865" />Rachel Couper &amp; Ivana Kuzmanovska &#8211; <em>mirador</em><br />
<img src="http://picturette.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/sxs_2012-15.jpg?w=590" alt="" title="SxS_2012-15"   class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2129017870" /><br />
<img src="http://picturette.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/sxs_2012-19.jpg?w=590" alt="" title="SxS_2012-19"   class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2129017871" /><br />
<img src="http://picturette.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/sxs_2012-28.jpg?w=590" alt="" title="SxS_2012-28"   class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2129017894" />Steinunn Thórarinsdóttir (IS) &#8211; <em>trace &#8211; sphere &#8211; gate</em><br />
<img src="http://picturette.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/sxs_2012-10.jpg?w=590" alt="" title="SxS_2012-10"   class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2129017876" /><br />
<img src="http://picturette.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/sxs_2012-11.jpg?w=590" alt="" title="SxS_2012-11"   class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2129017875" />Cave Urban &#8211; <em>mengenang (memory)</em><br />
<img src="http://picturette.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/sxs_2012-2.jpg?w=590" alt="" title="SxS_2012-2"   class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2129017878" /><br />
<img src="http://picturette.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/sxs_2012-5.jpg?w=590" alt="" title="SxS_2012-5"   class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2129017879" />Jock Clutterbuck &#8211; <em>waterlily 2009</em><br />
<img src="http://picturette.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/sxs_2012-261.jpg?w=590" alt="" title="SxS_2012-26"   class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2129017895" />Dave Mercer &#8211; <em>view tm</em><br />
<img src="http://picturette.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/sxs_2012-6.jpg?w=590" alt="" title="SxS_2012-6"   class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2129017881" />Paul Kaptein &#8211; <em>and in the endless pauses, there came a sound</em><br />
<img src="http://picturette.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/sxs_2012-7.jpg?w=590" alt="" title="SxS_2012-7"   class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2129017882" />Kate Stehr &#8211; <em>the drogue</em><br />
<img src="http://picturette.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/sxs_2012-4.jpg?w=590" alt="" title="SxS_2012-4"   class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2129017883" />Gillie &amp; Marc Schattner &#8211; <em>the travellers have arrived</em><br />
<img src="http://picturette.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/sxs_2012-3.jpg?w=590" alt="" title="SxS_2012-3"   class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2129017884" /><br />
<img src="http://picturette.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/sxs_2012-1.jpg?w=590" alt="" title="SxS_2012-1"   class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2129017886" />Alex Richie &#8211; <em>kaleidoscope cube</em><br />
<img src="http://picturette.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/sxs_2012-27.jpg?w=590" alt="" title="SxS_2012-27"   class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2129017891" />Right: Ruth Downes &amp; Geoff Webster &#8211; <em>casting around</em><br />
<img src="http://picturette.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/sxs_2012-22.jpg?w=590" alt="" title="SxS_2012-22"   class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2129017888" />Karin van der Molen &#8211; <em>surprise</em><br />
<img src="http://picturette.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/sxs_2012-231.jpg?w=590" alt="" title="SxS_2012-23"   class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2129017898" />Kristin McIver &#8211; <em>view piece</em></p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://picturette.wordpress.com/category/events/'>events</a>, <a href='http://picturette.wordpress.com/category/photography/'>photography</a> Tagged: <a href='http://picturette.wordpress.com/tag/art/'>art</a>, <a href='http://picturette.wordpress.com/tag/australia/'>australia</a>, <a href='http://picturette.wordpress.com/tag/bondi/'>bondi</a>, <a href='http://picturette.wordpress.com/tag/photography/'>photography</a>, <a href='http://picturette.wordpress.com/tag/picturette/'>picturette</a>, <a href='http://picturette.wordpress.com/tag/sculpture/'>sculpture</a>, <a href='http://picturette.wordpress.com/tag/sculpture-by-the-sea/'>sculpture by the sea</a>, <a href='http://picturette.wordpress.com/tag/sydney/'>sydney</a>, <a href='http://picturette.wordpress.com/tag/tamarama/'>tamarama</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2129017864/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2129017864/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2129017864&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://picturette.wordpress.com/2012/11/06/sculpture-by-the-sea/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>46</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c239ea2092c0edd80e507eefd0ea9264?s=96&#38;d=retro&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">picturette</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://picturette.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/sxs_2012-17.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">SxS_2012-17</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://picturette.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/sxs_2012-18.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">SxS_2012-18</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://picturette.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/sxs_2012-16.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">SxS_2012-16</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://picturette.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/sxs_2012-15.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">SxS_2012-15</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://picturette.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/sxs_2012-19.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">SxS_2012-19</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://picturette.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/sxs_2012-28.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">SxS_2012-28</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://picturette.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/sxs_2012-10.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">SxS_2012-10</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://picturette.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/sxs_2012-11.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">SxS_2012-11</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://picturette.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/sxs_2012-2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">SxS_2012-2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://picturette.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/sxs_2012-5.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">SxS_2012-5</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://picturette.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/sxs_2012-261.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">SxS_2012-26</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://picturette.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/sxs_2012-6.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">SxS_2012-6</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://picturette.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/sxs_2012-7.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">SxS_2012-7</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://picturette.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/sxs_2012-4.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">SxS_2012-4</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://picturette.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/sxs_2012-3.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">SxS_2012-3</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://picturette.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/sxs_2012-1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">SxS_2012-1</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://picturette.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/sxs_2012-27.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">SxS_2012-27</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://picturette.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/sxs_2012-22.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">SxS_2012-22</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://picturette.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/sxs_2012-231.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">SxS_2012-23</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>On the Origins of Craft Brewing</title>
		<link>http://maureenogle.com/2012/11/28/my-brain-at-work-on-the-origins-of-craft-brewing/</link>
		<comments>http://maureenogle.com/2012/11/28/my-brain-at-work-on-the-origins-of-craft-brewing/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2012 21:56:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Maureen Ogle</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[A Historian At Work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beer]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://maureenogle.com/?p=6484</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As avid readers (because there are some, right??) know, Jack McAuliffe, the acknowledged founder of the craft brewing movement, is a friend. In January, Boston Beer Company &#8212; known to you as Sam Adams &#8212; will introduce New Albion Ale, based on the recipe Jack used to make his first beer in the late 1970s. [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=6484&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As avid readers (because there are some, right??) know, Jack McAuliffe, the acknowledged founder of the craft brewing movement, is a friend. In January, Boston Beer Company &#8212; known to you as Sam Adams &#8212; <a href="http://allaboutbeer.com/daily-pint/whats-brewing/2012/07/the-return-of-new-albion-americas-first-craft-brewery-gets-a-revival/" target="_blank">will introduce New Albion Ale,</a> based on the recipe Jack used to make his first beer in the late 1970s.</p>
<div id="attachment_45" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 262px"><a href="http://maureenogle.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/jack-scaled500.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-45" alt="" src="http://maureenogle.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/jack-scaled500.jpg?w=590"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">photo courtesy of Michael E. Miller and Jack McAuliffe</p></div>
<p>That means that lately there’s been an unusual amount of attention paid to Jack and to his brewery, New Albion. Which means that I’ve been hearing more than the usual iterations of a question I’m often asked: “Is New Albion really important?”   <span id="more-6484"></span></p>
<p>By which the questioner means:</p>
<blockquote><p> “Hey, McAuliffe’s brewery only lasted a few years. Most people interested in craft beer had never even heard of the guy until your book came out. He can’t be that important.”</p></blockquote>
<p>To which I usually say something like</p>
<blockquote><p>“He deserved the credit. Would someone else have done what he did? Eventually. But at the time, he inspired others to do what he’d done, namely cobble together some raw materials, build a brewery, and make beer.”</p></blockquote>
<p>(And I mention <a href="http://www.sierranevada.com/about/history.html" target="_blank">Ken Grossman and Sierra Nevada</a> as an example of the direct influence of Jack and New Albion.)</p>
<p>So that’s the background. (Yeah. You know me: The background takes more time than the main point. What can I say? I’m a historian. Context is everything.)</p>
<p>Anyway, this has been on my mind. Or, more accurately, my brain has been busy pondering the “Would someone else have done what he did?” I say “apparently” because I didn’t realize I was even thinking about this until yesterday, when the following crashed into my brain’s foreground and grabbed my attention:</p>
<p>When people have asked me the aforementioned question, I’ve usually skipped over the “would someone else have done what he did” part and spoke mainly to the “direct influence” part of why Jack matters. Because of course I had no idea if someone else <em>would</em> have done what Jack did.</p>
<p>Until now. Thanks to my busy brain, I now have a different take on the issue of “does Jack matter?” (*1) It goes like this.</p>
<p>It’s hard to imagine that a craft brewing industry wouldn’t have shown up eventually, right? After all, at the same time that craft of beer pioneers were doing their thing, the “good coffee” movement started. Other entrepreneurs were experimenting with a return to good bread. Micro-distilleries began showing up in the early 1990s. Natural foods were going great guns in the 1980s.</p>
<p>So at some point someone would have come up with a “craft brewing industry.” (*2)</p>
<p>BUT: it’s not clear to me that, without Jack (or some one like Jack) it would have looked like the do-it-yourself, self-reliant industry that it was and to a certain extent still is.</p>
<p>Let me explain:</p>
<p>Jack’s brewery failed, but the <em>way</em> he built his company became the foundational model for the craft brewing industry that emerged in the early 1980s.</p>
<p>Ken Grossman, for example, had already dreamed about opening a brewery, a dream inspired in part by his love of good beer but also by a visit to <a href="http://www.anchorbrewing.com" target="_blank">Anchor Brewing</a> in San Francisco. But when Ken visited Anchor, he saw an insurmountable obstacle: a full-blown brewery with “real” brewing equipment. Grossman knew he couldn’t pull that off, or at least not until he’d devoted a few decades to saving the many thousands of dollars such a venture would require.</p>
<p>When he visited New Albion, however, he saw instantly that here was a model that he could emulate and do so with relatively little cash. (He and his then-partner Paul Camusi scrounged $50,000 in start-up funds, mostly from family.) If he could find spare parts, which was what Jack had done, he could use his engineering/carpentry/handyman skills to build a brewhouse.</p>
<p>So he did, and so did other early pioneers, and the rest, as the cliche goes, is history.</p>
<p>But let’s ponder an alternative history, one based on a combination of speculation and fact.</p>
<p>Here’s a fact, one based on my six years spent thinking and writing about meat in America:</p>
<p>Food and food fads are like anything else: if there’s a profit to be made, if there’s a fad to ride, someone will jump in and try to make some money on it.</p>
<p>In the 1980s, for example, a couple of marketing types in California noted the interest in “natural” foods and began selling “Rocky the Ranger” chickens, which they touted as free-range and natural. The chickens weren’t, but that didn’t matter. Plenty of people were willing to pay big bucks for natural poultry. (Among them was Wolfgang Puck, just then hitting his stride and his celebrity, who began serving Rocky at his restaurants. He was none too pleased to discover, during a blind taste test, that neither he nor other tasters could tell the difference between high-priced Rocky and plain ol’ chicken).</p>
<p>Here’s another, more relevant example:</p>
<p>In the mid-1980s, <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Samuel_Adams_(beer)" target="_blank">Jim Koch, then working at Boston Consulting Group,</a> had a early-mid-life crisis and decided he needed a job with more soul than helping Fortune 500 types figure out how to make billions rather than millions. Brewing was in his family (as he’s fond of pointing out, he’s the fifth generation to work in beer), and when he pondered his future while perched on a barstool, he noticed that yuppies, as they were called then, were dropping serious money to pay for imported beer (think Heineken and St. Pauli).</p>
<p>That market niche intrigued him. After a bit of investigation, Jim learned that there were a handful of people scattered around the country making what amounted to nineteenth-century beers (real, pure, made from four ingredients, blah blah blah). There, Koch decided, lay his future. In this case, he skipped the do-it-yourself route and instead contracted to brew his lager using “real” brewmasters at “real” breweries.</p>
<p>Jim Koch happens to be a guy with a soul. (*3)  The company he built melds with and has been a key component of the craft beer industry.</p>
<p>But it’s clear that what Koch did, some other suit-and-tie could have done, too. (*4)</p>
<p>Which brings me, finally, to my point. (Thanks for sticking with me).</p>
<div id="attachment_6562" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 1034px"><a href="http://maureenogle.com/2012/11/28/my-brain-at-work-on-the-origins-of-craft-brewing/brewing-company/" rel="attachment wp-att-6562"><img class="size-large wp-image-6562" alt="" src="http://maureenogle.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/brewing-company.jpg?w=1024&#038;h=640" height="640" width="1024" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">New Albion Brewing, c. 1977. Photo courtesy of Jack McAuliffe</p></div>
<p>Had Jack McAuliffe not built his whacky, nineteenth-century-inspired, spare-parts brewery, a craft beer industry would have emerged anyway. But it likely would have been built by suits-and-ties; business types with more interest in profit than beer who’d wangled bank loans and built a brewery along the same lines as conventional brewing (read: Anheuser Busch) except in miniature. And then, I’m guessing, sold to the first big brewer who came along (and remember that both Miller and AB “came along” and started buying/acquiring shares in small fry in the late 1980s).</p>
<p>Instead of the “think local/think pure and real” craft brewing industry we’ve got now, with all its glory, creativity, and dynamism, we’d have ended up with a bastardized version in which the Big Boys made a few shitty “craft” beers, and instead of the few thousand breweries that now exist in the U. S., we’d probably still have, oh, 79 or 80. And I doubt we’d have locally owned and operated brewpubs. We might have chain restaurants with brewing equipment prominently displayed behind glass, but that’s not quite the same thing as the truly fascinating, truly local brewpub culture that has flourished in the U. S. in the past 30 years.</p>
<p>So. Jack matters not because he succeeded &#8212; he didn’t &#8212; but because of the way he built his company: from scraps, with next to no cash, and with a truckload of heart, soul, and hard work.</p>
<p>End of great idea.</p>
<p>For now.Part of my busy brain has been thinking hard about a new book and what it wants to write (and why would I get in its way!?) is a book about, well, I’m not quite sure yet but something about the craft beer industry, the nature of contemporary capitalism, the shift to the local, and the way all things digital have transformed all of it. I have the feeling I’m going to be thinking this book out loud, if you will, here at the blog. So it’s possible that this is a tentative first step toward this vague, amorphous, and possibly bad idea that’s churning around in my brain. We’ll see.</p>
<p>And comments and feedback are most welcome. Have at it.</p>
<p>Oh: And no, not quite finished with meat book. But I have  written a major chunk of that<a href="http://maureenogle.com/2012/11/08/still-peddling/" target="_blank"> pesky new chapter my editor wanted. </a></p>
<p>UPDATE AFTER THE FACT: I should have included this link first time around. Two years ago, Jay Brooks and Natalie and Vinnie Cilurzo went to the New Albion site with Jack. Ja<a href="http://brookstonbeerbulletin.com/the-new-albion-brewery-site-30-years-later/" target="_blank">y made sure to document the visit.</a></p>
<p>__________</p>
<p>*1: I’m continually impressed by how much work my brain does without me even asking it to. Brains are important, you know? If we have a Mother’s Day and a National Pizza Day, and a “Talk Like A Pirate” day, why in hell don’t we have a “Thank Your Brain” day?</p>
<p>*2: Hmmm. That raises a fascinating question that I only thought of while writing this blog entry: How long would it have taken Charlie Papazian to go the next step; to travel from homebrewing-as-national-movement, which was what he was primarily interested in in the late ‘70s and early ‘80s, to “let’s take homebrewing to the next step”?</p>
<p>*3: Some would disagree with that view. But I would argue that one need only look at the way he’s operated his company to know that when he said he intended to build a corporation with a heart and soul, he meant it.</p>
<p>*4: Indeed, the essence of the messy craft beer boom of the 1990s was precisely that: suit-and-tie types bringing in big money to cash in on what was then seen as a profitable market niche.</p>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=6484&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://maureenogle.com/2012/11/28/my-brain-at-work-on-the-origins-of-craft-brewing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>47</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/7a154f3ceb16a6845a00910185a17b73?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">maureenogle</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://maureenogle.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/jack-scaled500.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://maureenogle.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/brewing-company.jpg?w=1024" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Few Words On the Airport Bar</title>
		<link>http://thisiswhyimdrunk.wordpress.com/2012/11/29/a-few-words-on-the-airport-bar/</link>
		<comments>http://thisiswhyimdrunk.wordpress.com/2012/11/29/a-few-words-on-the-airport-bar/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2012 11:52:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bryan Roth</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[A Few Words]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Airport]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[friendship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thisiswhyimdrunk.wordpress.com/?p=1076</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;The Wright Brothers would kick us all right in the $#%@ right now if they knew.&#8221; &#8211; Louis C.K. Flying sucks. But, as The Ones Who Invented Flight, it is our inalienable right to alter and forcefully evolve what that experience means and what relationship we have with it, imparting true American virtues of impatience, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1076&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_1088" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/shnakepup/"><img class="size-full wp-image-1088" alt="" src="http://thisiswhyimdrunk.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/3756320937_0d5e9fdc2d_b.jpg?w=590"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Photo via jayRez on Flickr</p></div>
<p style="text-align:center;">&#8220;The Wright Brothers would kick us all right in the $#%@ right now if they knew.&#8221; &#8211; Louis C.K.</p>
<p>Flying sucks.</p>
<p>But, as <a href="http://www.nps.gov/wrbr/index.htm">The Ones Who Invented Flight</a>, it is our inalienable right to alter and forcefully evolve what that experience means and what relationship we have with it, imparting true American virtues of impatience, greed and contempt for anyone outside friends or family we&#8217;re traveling with.</p>
<p>As The Ones Who Invented Flight it is our unfortunate reality to have willingly bastardized this marvel of modern transportation into something we need, we love and then decry its virtues in order to make ourselves feel better about unforeseen circumstances that &#8220;ruin&#8221; our days. <a href="http://www.comedycentral.com/video-clips/1myllo/stand-up-louis-ck--uncensored---the-miracle-of-flight">This guy gets it</a>.</p>
<p>It is fitting then, that one of the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pub">best things about flying didn&#8217;t originate with us</a>, The Ones Who Invented Flight. <strong>Thank god for the airport bar</strong>.<br />
<span id="more-1076"></span></p>
<p>As a means of travel, flying is incredibly efficient and amazing. We can traverse the globe as we please. As a means of travel, flying has also been able to showcase the worst parts of us as The Ones Who Invented Flight. We complain, we push and we complain and push and passive-aggressively sigh heavy breaths until the purpose of flying comes forth &#8211; we&#8217;re just in it just to get ours.</p>
<p>What &#8220;ours&#8221; is could be many things, but what it is most certainly is an effort to obtain what we want at the expense of others. This is why we want the best parking at the airport, why we feel the need to form lines before we actually form a line to board the airplane and why we curse under our breath at airline employees who haven&#8217;t called our boarding group number. We lament the fact we haven&#8217;t gotten from A to B in the fastest way possible for <em>us</em>.</p>
<p>But most important, among all this insanity, we find a timeless oasis to put all of these things aside. Because for as much as the airport shows us how rampant American impatience and greed can be, it also shows us how simple it is to find common ground and swap a story or two over beer.</p>
<p>The airport bar is an oasis because (percentage-wise) only a select few choose to indulge. Prices are high, but the men and women who saunter up to the bar take part in the true American act of &#8220;taking a load off.&#8221; Springsteen would be proud, wouldn&#8217;t he? Blue collar raising a glass with each other, and even sometimes, executives. We drink American beers &#8211; sometimes locally made &#8211; and we share stories of where we&#8217;re from, where we&#8217;re going and why we can&#8217;t wait to get there.</p>
<p>At the airport bar, solo travelers find companions who may share some common ground in the need to get away from it all for a moment or two. Because at the airport bar, what makes us lousy, selfish savages Out There, whittles away to general decency In Here.</p>
<p>The airport bar is an oasis because it gives us strength through imbibing (responsibly) to put up with the crap. The airport bar is an oasis because when we are without friends, it reminds us of the kindness of strangers among a sea of callousness.</p>
<p>The airport bar is an oasis because in the midst of coming and going all over the world, what it is, in the end, <em>is a little piece of home</em>.</p>
<p><em>*Note: This <del>rant</del> love letter was inspired by lots of travel in recent months.</em></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1076/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1076/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1076&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thisiswhyimdrunk.wordpress.com/2012/11/29/a-few-words-on-the-airport-bar/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>56</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/44fbbbd2e049a2cb38e5ef0e0c9b3b70?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">thisiswhyimdrunk</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thisiswhyimdrunk.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/3756320937_0d5e9fdc2d_b.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dear Santa Claus</title>
		<link>http://fishofgold.wordpress.com/2012/11/29/dear-santa-claus/</link>
		<comments>http://fishofgold.wordpress.com/2012/11/29/dear-santa-claus/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2012 21:17:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>goldfish</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[postaday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Xmas]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fishofgold.wordpress.com/?p=13321</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The Daily Post told me to &#8220;Picture the one person in the world you really wish were reading your blog. Write her or him a letter.&#8221; I chose you, Santa. I know it&#8217;s been a long time since I&#8217;ve written. Sorry about that. When I was a little girl, you were a powerful motivator. I [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=13321&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_13327" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 621px"><a href="http://fishofgold.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/christmas-santa-claus-2.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-13327 " alt="" src="http://fishofgold.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/christmas-santa-claus-2.jpg?w=590"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">I hope you don&#8217;t actually look this creepy.</p></div>
<p><a href="http://dailypost.wordpress.com/2012/11/29/daily-prompt-15/" target="_blank">The Daily Post</a> told me to &#8220;Picture the one person in the world you really wish were reading your blog. Write her or him a letter.&#8221; I chose you, Santa. I know it&#8217;s been a long time since I&#8217;ve written. Sorry about that.</p>
<p>When I was a little girl, you were a powerful motivator. I had to behave myself all year (well, mostly November and December &#8211; your threats didn&#8217;t work too well in July) so that you would visit. You stopped bringing me presents when I was still in single digits. I hope you can understand that I kind of lost faith in you for a little while.</p>
<p>I was a skeptic from early on. It began with the fact that we didn&#8217;t even have a chimney. How would you get inside without a chimney? My mom assured me that you didn&#8217;t need one even though a chimney was integral to all the stories about you. The seed of doubt had been planted. Then, I realized that you had the same handwriting and even used the same wrapping paper as my mom. My doubt strengthened. She told me that you were so busy that you had enlisted her into your Christmas army. If it wasn&#8217;t for her help and help from parents like her, there was no way that you could finish all that work in time for Christmas. I believed her for a little while, but eventually, I thought you were a sham.</p>
<p>Can you ever forgive me? You see, I had a lot going on in my life then. I didn&#8217;t trust the people closest to me. My mom&#8217;s insistence that she was part of your elf army just struck me as another lie in a long list of them. I wish I had believed her. I wish I could have hung on to you for a little while longer. I miss your visits. I miss the anticipation of Christmas eve where I could hardly sleep because I was excited. I miss opening my eyes on Christmas morning and running downstairs to find that you had eaten the cookies we left out.</p>
<p>I took you for granted, Santa. I threw you away. I cast aside the kindest, most magical person in the whole world, because I couldn&#8217;t or just didn&#8217;t want to believe. Well, I&#8217;d like to believe in you now, if that&#8217;s alright. I know I&#8217;m a little old, but I&#8217;d like to believe in you. Please, don&#8217;t feel like you need to leave something at my house (even though I do have a chimney now). Could you use one of my Christmases to visit the house of a kid like me instead? Visit a kid who has already had too much adulthood forced upon them and doesn&#8217;t want to believe in you. Tell that kid that it&#8217;s alright to let his or her guard down, if only for one day a year. Tell them that there will be plenty of time for being an adult later on, but now, it&#8217;s time to be a kid. It&#8217;s okay to believe.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ll leave some cookies and milk on the counter for you this year if you&#8217;d like to take a rest at my house.</p>
<p>Thanks for everything, Santa.</p>
<p>Love,</p>
<p>Goldfish</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://fishofgold.wordpress.com/category/prompts/postaday/'>postaday</a> Tagged: <a href='http://fishofgold.wordpress.com/tag/xmas/'>Xmas</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/13321/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/13321/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/13321/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/13321/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/13321/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/13321/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/13321/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/13321/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/13321/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/13321/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/13321/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/13321/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/13321/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/13321/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=13321&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://fishofgold.wordpress.com/2012/11/29/dear-santa-claus/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>68</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/7a56f22af32099e3e5546fc380c3e9b9?s=96&#38;d=wavatar&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">goldfeesh</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://fishofgold.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/christmas-santa-claus-2.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Spinach Brownies Are Okay Unless You Have To Eat Them</title>
		<link>http://eggton.com/2012/11/29/spinach-brownies-are-okay-unless-you-have-to-eat-them/</link>
		<comments>http://eggton.com/2012/11/29/spinach-brownies-are-okay-unless-you-have-to-eat-them/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2012 21:18:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Eggton</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Recipes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brownies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[semisweet brownies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spinach]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://eggton.com/?p=8719</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[My grandma wasn&#8217;t going to win any prizes in the gourmet food department but she could cook the crap out of some cream of mushroom soup.  She put it in everything except ice cubes&#8211;which makes sense, but not for the reasons you&#8217;d think.  It makes sense because her ice cubes already had stuff in them. [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=8719&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://eggton.com/2012/11/29/spinach-brownies-are-okay-unless-you-have-to-eat-them/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>97</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/35aa2322d0124d692cc0205de41dedb8?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">eggton</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://eggton.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/spinach-2-small.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://eggton.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/semisweet-brownie.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://eggton.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/brownie-2.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://eggton.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/thunder-resting.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
