<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2012 23:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Rebirth</title>
		<link>http://lymphomasucks.wordpress.com/2012/11/04/rebirth/</link>
		<comments>http://lymphomasucks.wordpress.com/2012/11/04/rebirth/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2012 03:48:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>lymphomasucks</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[My Cancer Story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[birthday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bone marrow transplant]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dad]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[debt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DNA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[donor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[father]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[half-match]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[immune system]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[irony]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nightmare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rebirth]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reborn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stupid lifeguards]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[water park]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://lymphomasucks.wordpress.com/?p=308</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Well it’s officially official.  My bone marrow transplant, formerly known as my stem cell transplant, is a go.  In exactly twelve days, I shall be “re-born”.  I’m not trying to sound deep or all metaphoric.  Scientifically and medically speaking, I will be a whole new person.  Everything in my bones and in my DNA that [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=308&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well it’s officially official.  My bone marrow transplant, formerly known as my stem cell transplant, is a go.  In exactly twelve days, I shall be “re-born”.  I’m not trying to sound deep or all metaphoric.  Scientifically and medically speaking, I will be a whole new person.  Everything in my bones and in my DNA that says I’m Cristina will be gone.  I am my father’s daughter but come November 16, I will be much more than that.  It’s an overwhelming thought and come to think of it, it <i>is</i> metaphoric.</p>
<p>In case you didn’t know yet, my father is going to be my bone marrow donor.  After my only sister did not turn out to be a match, an extensive search by the national bone marrow registry turned up nothing.  Not even one potential match.  In a world where the average white person has 10-15 potential matches, this Hispanic had not a one.  This hard reality sparked a new-found passion for me.  If this is my reality, how many other Hispanics and minorities is this happening to?  Apparently, too many are facing my same reality.  A fire within me for this need to be filled began to grow inside me.  As I voiced my concern to the media and the media began to validate my voice, my father was being tested as a potential half-match for my much needed transplant.  This fire within me was about to have gasoline poured on it.</p>
<p>As my biological father, it was a scientific inevitability that he would be a half-match.  We all get half of our DNA from our fathers and the other half from our mothers.  My father was preferred by doctors over my mother because he’s never had children and that’s a bigger plus for his immune system that he would be passing onto me.  My mother didn’t hide her disdain at the fact that she would not be my hero but that my father would be the one to save my life.  A beloved church family member one day told my mother, “Don’t be upset!  You already had the privilege of giving life to this wonderful creature.  Now her father gets to experience the same!”  My mother gave in instantly to that thought and had to admit to the intense significance of the situation.  I’ll admit, it struck me too.</p>
<p><i>WARNING:  If you are prone to crying while reading, please grab a tissue.  Or two.  This is about to get intense.</i></p>
<p>My dad owes me.  I’m not an ungrateful child.  He has done everything and anything for me but despite all that, the man just plain owes me.  Big time.</p>
<p>In the summer of 2009, my parents, niece, and my husband and I, decided to take a weekend trip to a water park here in Texas a mere three hours away.  A hint?  It starts with ‘S’ and ends with ‘bahn’.  My mother and my husband banded together in order to stay off the rides.  They’re not big fans of bodies of water and slides that spit you out as they don’t know how to swim.  They used my then 6 year old niece as an excuse to stay by the kiddie pools.  My father and I, on the other hand, took the opportunity to partner up and get on every single ride the park had to offer.  As the day began to come to an end and we prepared to leave, I asked my dad if we could get on one last ride.  He of course said yes and we headed off, inner tube in tow, to the last ride of the day.</p>
<p>It was supposed to be the most relaxing ride in the whole park but it turned out to be our worst nightmare.  The self-propelled river took us on a tour of the park and the signs indicated that the ride ends in the actual natural river from which the park gets it’s water.  I told my dad we needed to get off before the end of the ride because the river is deep and he can’t swim.  I know you know where this is going.</p>
<p>There was one last exit before the end of the ride and, you guessed it, we missed it.  It wasn’t marked and it didn’t look like a very ‘official’ exit, so we kept going.  I saw the end of the ride up ahead and my dad floating toward it in his tube ahead of me.  We’d been separated a little ways back and I wasn’t able to remind him about the deep river at the end.  I didn’t think twice about it and thought, “Oh, he’ll remember what I told him about the river being deep and he’ll just stay on his tube.”  I couldn’t have been more wrong.</p>
<p>I came off the ride in my tube backward not even a minute after my father.  As my tube turned to face forward slowly, I began to scan the crowd that was walking up the exit stairs to the left out of the river.  No Dad.  Hmm.  I scanned the people in their tubes floating out ahead of me.  Still no Dad.  HMMMM.  And then I saw it.  A lonely tube out in the water about 10 yards away.  There was violent splashing a few feet away from it.  The lifeguards at the exit of the ride were chatting away with each other, completely oblivious to what was going on right in front of them.</p>
<p>“DADDY!!!,” I screamed at the top of my lungs as I jumped off my tube and swam furiously toward my drowning father.  I swam up behind him, hooked my arms under his arms, and pulled him up enough out of the water so that he could finally breathe.  He couldn’t say anything as he was coughing and gasping for air but his eyes said it all.  He was happy to see me.  The lifeguards finally swam up to us and helped my dad to the safe edge of the river.  I was angry, scared, and grateful all at the same time.  I’d almost lost my dad that day.</p>
<p>After yelling at the lifeguards for not doing their job and fuming at the management, all I wanted to do was go home with my family intact and forget about the whole thing.  My worst nightmare had almost come true and I wanted to get as far away from that place as possible.  I buried it deep and put it out of my mind and even got angry anytime my mother would bring it up.  And I did make myself forget about it.  But my father never forgot.  He would only tell me now and again how I’d saved him and how he owed me his life.  I would brush it off and tell him that I only did what any child would do for their parent.  He would never reply but the disagreement on his face told me different.</p>
<p>I never thought about that day again until the day we were told that my father had been chosen as my bone marrow donor.  I later asked my father if he was sure he wanted to go through with the surgery required for a bone marrow donation.  He looked me square in the eyes and said, “You saved my life once.  Now I get to save yours.”</p>
<p>I felt the air leave my lungs as I began to comprehend what he’d just said.  He’d felt indebted to me for three years and I’d brushed it off like it was nothing.  Now that my own life needed saving, I inherently understood how he felt about the day I’d saved his.  As much as I had wanted to forget about that day, he hadn’t.</p>
<p>Whenever my dad had talked about that day at the water park, he would say it was the day he’d been reborn from the water.  His brush with death had made him value his life and blessings on a much, much deeper level.  I could never fully understand the immense value he had placed on what I had done for him until my own face-off with death.  I can now say that I understand the magnitude of saving a life and the preciosity of preserving it.  And now, in an irony that I’m sure is not lost on you, his rebirth has made mine possible.  Had I lost my father on that fateful day, my life now on this earth would most assuredly be coming to an end.  While my mother is also a half-match, she would not be the best candidate for me as a donor.  I came from her womb and so her cells would be the same ones doctors are now trying to change.</p>
<p>And so, come November 16th, I too shall be reborn.  My doctor tells me it will be my second birthday and should be celebrated with the same significance as my original birthday.  My own bone marrow production, in which lies my DNA and immune system that has failed me, will be shut down by chemotherapy in the days leading up to the transplant.  It will be replaced with two pints of my father’s healthy bone marrow, drawn out with surgery from his hip bones in his back that same day.  He’ll be in pain for about a week while doctors keep a close eye on me in the hospital for about three weeks to make sure my body doesn’t reject his marrow.  His immune system will slowly become my immune system.  His blood type will be my new blood type.  His DNA will be my full DNA, not just half.  Future blood tests will show no more DNA traces of Cristina.  But I get to live.  My father’s debt will be cancelled out.</p>
<p>I’ll always be me in my heart, mind, and spirit even though on paper, I’ll actually be my father.  I’m my father’s daughter and now he’ll also be the biggest part of me.  So one day, even when he’s long gone from this earth, he will still in essence live on through me.  I couldn’t ask for more noble blood to be running through my veins.</p>
<p>And who wouldn’t want a second birthday?</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/308/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/308/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=308&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://lymphomasucks.wordpress.com/2012/11/04/rebirth/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>6</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/99d2c8d310d916d8e07740bc3b74968d?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">lymphomasucks</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The 5th of November and Ahistorical Anarchists</title>
		<link>http://juicyecumenism.com/2012/11/05/the-5th-of-november-and-ahistorical-anarchists/</link>
		<comments>http://juicyecumenism.com/2012/11/05/the-5th-of-november-and-ahistorical-anarchists/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2012 15:14:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Bart Gingerich</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anarchy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Barton Gingerich]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[country]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[election]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[England]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Guy Fawkes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[history]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[patriotism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[state]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Kingdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[V for Vendetta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Voting]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://juicyecumenism.com/?p=4794</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The intrepid explorers of the internet wilds may be noticing some of their friends posting this little ditty today: Remember, remember The fifth of November The gunpowder treason and plot. I know of no reason Why the gunpowder treason Should ever be forgot. This is a rather strange poem for Americans recite—it’s much more British [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4794&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_4795" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 539px"><a href="http://theird.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/guyfawkesmasks_dailymail_121106_large.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-4795" title="guyfawkesmasks_dailymail_121106_large" alt="" src="http://theird.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/guyfawkesmasks_dailymail_121106_large.jpg?w=590"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The past decade has witnessed rampant Catholic absolutism. (Photo Credit: The Daily Mail)</p></div>
<p>The intrepid explorers of the internet wilds may be noticing some of their friends posting this little ditty today:</p>
<blockquote><p>Remember, remember<br />
The fifth of November<br />
The gunpowder treason and plot.<br />
I know of no reason<br />
Why the gunpowder treason<br />
Should ever be forgot.</p></blockquote>
<p>This is a rather strange poem for Americans recite—it’s much more British in character. It references <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Guy_Fawkes_Night#cite_note-Huttonp43-47">Guy Fawkes Night</a> in the UK. For Yanks, however, it has become the rallying cry for supposed anarcho-libertarians, especially amongst the youth.</p>
<p>In the last decade, Guy Fawkes masks and other paraphernalia have become the symbols of populist revolt thanks to <i><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/V_for_vendetta">V for Vendetta</a></i>. The brainchild of hairy leftist and comic-book legend Alan Moore, the printed series narrated a revolutionary warring against a dystopian fascist regime in Britain. The protagonist, named V, battles against authority with his knives, explosives, ideas, and penchant for alliteration. And he’s not just going to battle for your usual free markets; he wants everybody to do as they please, as long as no one else is hurt (a very common rubric for post-Enlightenment liberalism). Of course, this material didn’t gain such a level of popularity in the States by printed media alone; instead, most young Americans got their notions from the film starring Hugo Weaving and Natalie Portman.</p>
<p>Now wannabe revolutionaries across the nation don Guy Fawkes disguises and quote “Remember, remember the fifth of November,” whether it be a teenager’s prepubescent meditations on how no one should tell him what to do or the massed (tear-gassed) protestors of Occupy and Anonymous. The film, with its enigmatic characters and symbolic violence (including iconic fictional demolitions of Old Bailey and Big Ben to the tune of the 1812 Overture), left quite an expanse for adolescent imaginations.</p>
<p>Too bad it’s a <a href="http://www.cracked.com/article_18606_8-historic-symbols-that-mean-opposite-what-you-think.html">historical calumny</a>.</p>
<p>Guy Fawkes pretty much wanted the exact opposite of anarchism in all its various inconsistent forms. He was caught guarding gunpowder under the House of Lords, thus putting Parliament (the representative, legislative branch in British government) in grave danger. He and the other Gunpowder plotters hoped to blow up the Protestant King James I, his Privy Council, most of Parliament, and the Church of England’s bishops at the State Opening. The goal of the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gunpowder_Plot">Gunpowder Plot</a> was to re-instate a Roman Catholic monarch upon the throne, probably along absolutist lines.</p>
<p>It turns out that, after the plan was foiled, the nation rejoiced that its entire government wasn’t blown to smithereens. The people of England lit bonfires (and, later, fireworks) to celebrate that the king’s life was preserved from assassination. The Church authored a <a href="http://justus.anglican.org/resources/bcp/1662/nov5.pdf">special service</a> to the Book of Common Prayer. Unfortunately, the Gunpowder Plot also reinforced anti-Catholic sentiments in the UK, making life quite difficult for peaceable English Roman Catholics.</p>
<p>So yeah, blowing up the one representative body in your nation in favor of an absolutist monarch aligned with the Roman See&#8217;s Magisterium does not spring from the insoluble pillars of anarcho-libertarianism.</p>
<p>Therefore, when you see your young Jacobin compatriot tossing about Guy Fawkes references, here are a few helpful recommendations:</p>
<p><strong>1. </strong>        If you’re Anglican, make sure he’s not plotting to blow up either your property or your person with blackpowder explosives.</p>
<p><strong>2.    </strong>     Remark on how you didn’t know this person was a Catholic monarchist.</p>
<p><strong>3.    </strong>     Warn them about the gibbet at <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tyburn">Tyburn</a>.</p>
<p><strong>4. </strong>        Link to this post.</p>
<p><strong>5.     </strong>    Debate the merits of Gary Johnson as a presidential candidate.</p>
<p><strong>6.  </strong>       Exercise your right to participate in the electoral process tomorrow, thanking God you were preserved from pyromaniacal Papists.</p>
<p><strong>7.   </strong>      Remember and pray this little phrase from Evening Prayer: “O Lord, save the State.”</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://juicyecumenism.com/category/uncategorized/'>Uncategorized</a> Tagged: <a href='http://juicyecumenism.com/tag/anarchy/'>anarchy</a>, <a href='http://juicyecumenism.com/tag/barton-gingerich/'>Barton Gingerich</a>, <a href='http://juicyecumenism.com/tag/country/'>country</a>, <a href='http://juicyecumenism.com/tag/election/'>election</a>, <a href='http://juicyecumenism.com/tag/england/'>England</a>, <a href='http://juicyecumenism.com/tag/guy-fawkes/'>Guy Fawkes</a>, <a href='http://juicyecumenism.com/tag/history/'>history</a>, <a href='http://juicyecumenism.com/tag/nation/'>nation</a>, <a href='http://juicyecumenism.com/tag/patriotism/'>patriotism</a>, <a href='http://juicyecumenism.com/tag/state/'>state</a>, <a href='http://juicyecumenism.com/tag/united-kingdom/'>United Kingdom</a>, <a href='http://juicyecumenism.com/tag/v-for-vendetta/'>V for Vendetta</a>, <a href='http://juicyecumenism.com/tag/voting/'>Voting</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4794/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4794/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4794&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://juicyecumenism.com/2012/11/05/the-5th-of-november-and-ahistorical-anarchists/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/40671962684f4181a9b7fd873ca310f7?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">bgingerich</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://theird.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/guyfawkesmasks_dailymail_121106_large.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">guyfawkesmasks_dailymail_121106_large</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Level Up! Bring Your Best Game to Health</title>
		<link>http://rarasaur.wordpress.com/2012/11/03/level-up-bring-your-best-game-to-health/</link>
		<comments>http://rarasaur.wordpress.com/2012/11/03/level-up-bring-your-best-game-to-health/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2012 05:51:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>rarasaur</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[diabetes geek]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cheats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diabetes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diabetes awareness month]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gaming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[secondary goals]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://rarasaur.wordpress.com/?p=2182</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Sticking to a good-health-plan involves a lot of management skills, a surprising amount of which can be learned from video games. Here are a few gamer rules that we apply to our own diet: Primary goals should be hierarchical, planned, and rewards unto themselves. Secondary goals should be unexpected and celebrated. Cheats should be limited, [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2182&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_2193" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 310px"><img class="size-medium wp-image-2193" title="donkeykong2" alt="" src="http://rarasaur.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/donkeykong2.jpg?w=300&#038;h=242" height="242" width="300" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Is your good-health-plan strong, like Donkey Kong?</p></div>
<p>Sticking to a good-health-plan involves a lot of management skills, a surprising amount of which can be learned from video games.</p>
<p>Here are a few gamer rules that we apply to our own diet:</p>
<ol>
<li>Primary goals should be hierarchical, planned, and rewards unto themselves.</li>
<li>Secondary goals should be unexpected and celebrated.</li>
<li>Cheats should be limited, earned, and saved till needed.</li>
<li>Know your arsenal.</li>
<li>When you have to restart a level, it doesn&#8217;t diminish your chances of success.</li>
<li>Play with the expectation that life will interrupt.</li>
<li>Don&#8217;t get into gamer-wars or become a game-missionary, or you&#8217;ll quickly lose friends.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Primary goals should be hierarchical, planned, and rewards unto themselves.</strong><br />
Make a list of primary goals, which are goals that are rewards upon themselves. Put them in order and remind yourself that achievements are won in steps! An example would be: (1) Eat only the required amount of calories every day for 2 months, (2) Lose 20 pounds from you start-game weight, (3) Keep 20 pounds off for 2 months. If you happen to lose 20 pounds before you reach Level 2, great! It&#8217;ll make Level 2 easy when you get there, but &#8212; you aren&#8217;t there yet.  It&#8217;s important to remind yourself that each level has it&#8217;s own rewards, and that hierarchy has a purpose.</p>
<p><strong>Secondary goals should be unexpected and celebrated.</strong><br />
A secondary goal is like dropping one or two pant sizes, or having your skin clear up, or making a gym buddy. It&#8217;s not something you should expect if it&#8217;s not your primary goal, but it&#8217;s pretty great. And as something pretty great, it should be celebrated!</p>
<p><strong>Cheats should be limited, earned, and saved till needed.</strong><br />
Cheats shouldn&#8217;t be taken for granted and used at random. Whether your cheat is a food or a day off from exercise, you should create a system where you earn the right to it. Maybe even give yourself a physical token to represent it! Then, just like in a game, save that shortcut for when you really need it. Cheats don&#8217;t grow on trees!</p>
<p><strong>Know your arsenal</strong>.<br />
Memorize the list of things, people, and places you need to succeed in your goals. What foods can you eat? Know them! You should be able to glance at a menu and know what you can eat and what you can&#8217;t. Are there things you need to exercise? Make sure you have them with you so you can&#8217;t make excuses.</p>
<p><strong>When you have to restart a level, it doesn&#8217;t diminish your chance of success.</strong><br />
Stuff happens, try not to be restarted more than one level at a time. When you start over, know it&#8217;ll be easier the second time around, and have faith! Success is still within your grasp.</p>
<p><strong>Play with the expectation that life will interrupt</strong>.<br />
Life interrupts. People interrupt. If you take those interruptions too seriously, that angst will transfer to your game and put you behind your goals.</p>
<p><strong>Don&#8217;t get into gamer-wars or become a game-missionary, or you&#8217;ll quickly lose friends.</strong><br />
You&#8217;re excited about your good-health-plan, we get it. It&#8217;s working, we get it. If you try to convert people or tell everyone about all the details of it all the time, though, you&#8217;ll just alienate people.</p>
<p><span style="color:#ffffff;">.</span></p>
<p>And on that note, thanks for your patience as I blog my way through Diabetes Awareness Month.</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://rarasaur.wordpress.com/category/geekery/diabetes-geek/'>diabetes geek</a>, <a href='http://rarasaur.wordpress.com/category/living/health/'>health</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2182/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2182/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2182/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2182/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2182/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2182/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2182/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2182/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2182/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2182/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2182/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2182/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2182&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://rarasaur.wordpress.com/2012/11/03/level-up-bring-your-best-game-to-health/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>11</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://rarasaur.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/donkeykong2.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://rarasaur.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/donkeykong2.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">donkeykong2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/5bd9564edf7ca5da9507cffc12b5ea95?s=96&#38;d=monsterid&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">rarasaur</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://rarasaur.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/donkeykong2.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">donkeykong2</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Giving Wings to This Burden</title>
		<link>http://warycontraryandnovirginmary.wordpress.com/2012/11/05/giving-wings-to-this-burden/</link>
		<comments>http://warycontraryandnovirginmary.wordpress.com/2012/11/05/giving-wings-to-this-burden/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2012 09:07:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>No Virgin Mary</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Addiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alcohol]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Drinking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hope]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sobriety]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://warycontraryandnovirginmary.wordpress.com/?p=245</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;So what is it about drinking that makes you not want to stop?&#8221; asked my mental health nurse, today. I had to think about it for awhile. &#8220;I have no sense of time&#8221;, I replied. &#8220;When I&#8217;m boozed, every moment is just that: a moment. Every booze night is nothing but a series of NOW [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=245&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;So what is it about drinking that makes you not want to stop?&#8221; asked my mental health nurse, today.</p>
<p>I had to think about it for awhile.</p>
<p>&#8220;I have no sense of time&#8221;, I replied.<br />
&#8220;When I&#8217;m boozed, every moment is just that: a moment. Every booze night is nothing but a series of NOW with no thought about the future. I don&#8217;t get sick, I don&#8217;t get tired. I can drink beer for 20 hours and never throw up, never pass out. My body doesn&#8217;t know it should stop, my mind certainly doesn&#8217;t want to stop, and before I know it, the sun is up, I&#8217;m incoherent and the world crashes in on me again, taking me away from what is basically a magical place of No Worrying, hurling me into a place of pure self-hatred and regret&#8221;.</p>
<p>I lose days to drinking. The 12 &#8211; 18 hours of the drinking, plus the day or two hangover and comedown that sees me unable to move from the couch, crying at the drop of a hat.</p>
<p>I can&#8217;t do it any more. If I want a future, a life that is fulfilling, I just have to face the fact that it cannot involve alcohol.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve made this decision on numerous occasions, but for the first time, it&#8217;s a relief. It isn&#8217;t something I feel I have to do to please others, this decision is solely for me, this time. It isn&#8217;t something I feel conflicted about. I am not sad that I will never share another wine with my mother, or drunk karaoke sing with my friends. Sure, I will miss those moments and I will struggle with them, but I&#8217;ve finally reached that place where all of that comes second to giving myself the very best chance that I have to live the life I dream about.</p>
<p>With any luck, my GP will prescribe me the magic no-booze pills that will help me to stay on track. If not, well, I&#8217;ll have to smack myself up the face every time I think about having a drink. I want one with every fibre of my being, but that feeling will pass. The self-hatred and disappointment of a binge is what stays with me forever.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s been a long and shitty road, but I&#8217;m so incredibly happy to be done with it. You cannot imagine the weight that has been lifted from my shoulders.</p>
<p>Onwards and upwards, amigos!</p>
<br /> Tagged: <a href='http://warycontraryandnovirginmary.wordpress.com/tag/addiction/'>Addiction</a>, <a href='http://warycontraryandnovirginmary.wordpress.com/tag/alcohol/'>Alcohol</a>, <a href='http://warycontraryandnovirginmary.wordpress.com/tag/drinking/'>Drinking</a>, <a href='http://warycontraryandnovirginmary.wordpress.com/tag/hope/'>Hope</a>, <a href='http://warycontraryandnovirginmary.wordpress.com/tag/sobriety/'>Sobriety</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/245/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/245/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=245&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://warycontraryandnovirginmary.wordpress.com/2012/11/05/giving-wings-to-this-burden/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>20</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/65d50837c851d26e6cde9e4aa8a91339?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">britarded</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rusting &amp; Rebirth</title>
		<link>http://eocathcart.wordpress.com/2012/11/04/rusting-rebirth/</link>
		<comments>http://eocathcart.wordpress.com/2012/11/04/rusting-rebirth/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2012 00:39:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Odin Cathcart</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Art]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://eocathcart.wordpress.com/?p=472</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In 1981 a controversy erupted over the installation at Federal Plaza in New York City over Tilted Arc a steel sculpture 120 feet long by 12 feet high. Eight years later, workers cut the sculpture into three pieces in the dead of night and carted it away as scrap. In many ways the work of [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=472&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://eocathcart.wordpress.com/2012/11/04/rusting-rebirth/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/643f0eea5979efb8583442f601307868?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F0.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=X" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">rabbit</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://eocathcart.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/4017979358_2a520f7b78.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">4017979358_2a520f7b78</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://eocathcart.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/2246720211_223854d14e.jpeg?w=454" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">2246720211_223854d14e</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Does Limestone Stop Hair From Growing? And Other Strange Questions.</title>
		<link>http://kategoesexploring.wordpress.com/2012/11/04/does-limestone-stop-hair-from-growing-and-other-strange-questions/</link>
		<comments>http://kategoesexploring.wordpress.com/2012/11/04/does-limestone-stop-hair-from-growing-and-other-strange-questions/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2012 19:11:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Kate</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Peru]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[danger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[funny]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kids]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[limestone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marriage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quotes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://kategoesexploring.wordpress.com/?p=295</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The everyday conversations I have in Peru are often hilarious. Junior, the eleven-year-old I live with, is unintentionally funnier than 90% of the comedians I&#8217;ve seen, even after three years of the Edinburgh festival. For example, he explained to me very matter-of-factly that everyone feels comfier when they have something on their head; I&#8217;d have [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=295&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="color:#800000;">The everyday conversations I have in Peru are often hilarious. Junior, the eleven-year-old I live with, is unintentionally funnier than 90% of the comedians I&#8217;ve seen, even after three years of the Edinburgh festival. For example, he explained to me very matter-of-factly that everyone feels comfier when they have something on their head; I&#8217;d have understood it if he meant fluffy hats or scarves, but at the time what he had on his head was a kitchen chair. He also thinks that Laurie, Imogen and I should never be separated, because British people should talk to fellow Brits rather than Peruvians, and that when I do the washing up I&#8217;m practising for when I get married. Marriage isn&#8217;t a sure thing though; Junior has told me that my eligibility as a bride depends entirely upon how much I weigh and whether or not that weight is acceptable to my future husband.</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#800000;">When Imogen sat cross-legged a metre from a cliff edge, Junior ran over to warn her that the wind was going to blow her off it. When she moved to sit with her legs dangling off a wall, he told her she was safer there because only her head would be blown off. He&#8217;s also tried to teach us that if we laugh too much our insides will explode, and has asked whether the reason Laurie has short hair is that a piece of limestone fell onto his head when he was a child. I can&#8217;t even begin to understand that last one. I looked up &#8216;limestone&#8217; in two different Spanish dictionaries before letting myself accept my original translation.</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#800000;">Peruvian adults ask some very strange questions too. Last night Carlos asked me why I have brown hair instead of black hair, why I haven&#8217;t visited Russia, how many British people live in Russia and, when I couldn&#8217;t answer him, why I&#8217;ve never thought to look for this information on Facebook. The same evening, when I was teaching Imogen to tell the time in Spanish, Gloria&#8217;s sister misheard my English to an impressive degree and thought I was saying I didn&#8217;t want children. I had to try to justify being 22 and childless to a group of Catholics while avoiding any mention of my very non-Catholic views on contraception. I failed.</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#800000;">I still don&#8217;t fully understand the Peruvian mindset. When I went to the gym with Juan Carlos (another member of my Peruvian family – I know he&#8217;s some sort of cousin, but I’ve lost track), he was adamant that I had to do the same dance class as him because he couldn&#8217;t leave me upstairs without a man to look after me. But I was only a metre away from the stairs &#8211; and if I&#8217;d shouted for help I would&#8217;ve been rescued (by a boxer, no less) in under thirty seconds. The explanation Juan Carlos offered for his paranoia  (my word, not his, obviously) was that Peruvian men don&#8217;t respect women. I can&#8217;t argue with that, but even in Peru, spending ten minutes alone on a cross-trainer is not dangerous.</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#800000;">Peruvian views on danger are almost unbelievable. Other things I have been told are dangerous include walking too far, catching buses and taking taxis, which leaves me with exactly zero forms of transport. If I do make it out of Villa el Salvador, I have to remember that returning home late at night is dangerous &#8211;  but so is staying in a hostel in Lima, the nearest city. Going out on my own is dangerous, but if I brave it and anything does happen to me, nobody would blame me;  it would be Laurie&#8217;s fault for not going with me, even if I didn’t want him to and never told him I was leaving. He&#8217;d be held responsible purely because he&#8217;s a man. Doing anything special for Halloween is dangerous because it&#8217;s a celebration of the Devil&#8217;s birthday, and some of my students now believe I&#8217;m going to hell because they saw me making a skeleton costume out of duct tape. Cross-dressing is dangerous, not having a hot drink in the morning is dangerous and putting my bag on the floor for any length of time is incredibly dangerous and irresponsible, even if it&#8217;s just the floor of my bedroom. Not wearing shoes is the most dangerous thing of all; even when I&#8217;ve just woken up and I&#8217;m sitting on top of my duvet, I get told off if I&#8217;m only wearing socks, and Gloria&#8217;s reaction if she sees me coming out of the shower without my flip-flops on is priceless. By now, I&#8217;ve learnt to ignore the warnings, because I have done all these things (well, almost all of them &#8211; I left the cross-dressing to Laurie) and SURVIVED.</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#800000;">On the other hand, things that are not considered dangerous include letting unsupervised </span><span style="color:#800000;"></span><span style="color:#800000;">children open tins using massive carving knives, eating fruit that&#8217;s been soaked in bleach, using plugs that give you electric shocks  and </span><span style="text-decoration:underline;"><a title="Scissors dance" href="http://www.environmentalgraffiti.com/news-scissor-dancers-peru"><span style="color:#800000;text-decoration:underline;">dancing with scissors</span></a></span><span style="color:#800000;"> (part of a traditional Peruvian dance that I got to see last week; you can&#8217;t see the scissors in my photo, but trust me, they&#8217;re there). I don&#8217;t understand this country, but at this point I don&#8217;t think I want to. It&#8217;s so much funnier this way.</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#800000;"><a href="http://kategoesexploring.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dscf0450.jpg"><span style="color:#800000;"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-310" title="Scissors dance" alt="" src="http://kategoesexploring.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dscf0450.jpg?w=590"   /></span></a></span></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/295/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/295/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=295&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://kategoesexploring.wordpress.com/2012/11/04/does-limestone-stop-hair-from-growing-and-other-strange-questions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>25</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/11e9435c1db3d667502d02fcc234ae62?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">kategoesexploring</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://kategoesexploring.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dscf0450.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Scissors dance</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Politics of Brand</title>
		<link>http://alignment.wordpress.com/2012/11/04/the-politics-of-brand/</link>
		<comments>http://alignment.wordpress.com/2012/11/04/the-politics-of-brand/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2012 21:18:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Jonathan</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[government]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brand]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[postaweek2012]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://alignment.wordpress.com/?p=2225</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The U.S presidential election is imminent and, not surprisingly, politics are dominating everyone’s conversations.  Last week a work colleague and I had an on-going discussion of whether brands have political connotations. We started with an observation about cars in the office parking lot: more Republicans own BMW&#8217;s while more Democrats own Jeeps. Cars turned into sports: Democrats [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2225&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The U.S presidential election is imminent and, not surprisingly, politics are dominating everyone’s conversations.  Last week a work colleague and I had an on-going discussion of whether brands have political connotations.</p>
<p>We started with an observation about cars in the office parking lot: more Republicans own BMW&#8217;s while more Democrats own Jeeps. Cars turned into sports: Democrats prefer football while Republicans prefer baseball. We tried to find a pattern with fast food restaurants but couldn&#8217;t.</p>
<p>My colleague then speculated that logo color might reveal something about political leanings.  Coca-Cola, Verizon, and Oracle would all be considered Republican while Pepsi, AT&amp;T, and SAP would be Democratic.  Chick-fil-A’s red logo seems to be consistent with their <a href="http://www.cnn.com/2012/08/02/living/chick-fil-a-reaction/index.html" target="_blank">recent political controversy</a>.</p>
<p>While it’s an intriguing notion, the theory didn’t stand up to a little on-line sleuthing. The neuro-insight research firm <a href="http://www.buyologyinc.com" target="_blank">Buyology</a> studied consumers’ non-conscious connections to brands and <a href="http://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/new-study-reveals-that-democrats-and-republicans-disagree-on-the-brands-they-love-most-158868315.html" target="_blank">discovered variations</a> by political affiliation:</p>
<div align="center">
<table border="1">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td><b>Democrats</b></td>
<td><b>Republicans</b></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Most Desired Car</td>
<td>Jeep</td>
<td>BMW</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Most Desired Electronics</td>
<td>Sony</td>
<td>Sharp</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Most Desired Insurance</td>
<td>Progressive</td>
<td>Allstate</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Most Desired Restaurant</td>
<td>Wendy&#8217;s</td>
<td>Subway</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Most Desired Coffee Shop</td>
<td>Starbucks</td>
<td>Dunkin&#8217; Donuts</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</div>
<p>Allstate’s blue logo disproves our theory but at least we got the cars correct.</p>
<p>It turns out trying to associate brands with political preferences is a popular topic. According to consumer research firm <a href="http://research.yougov.com" target="_blank">YouGov</a>, which ranked 1,100+ brands for quality, value, and willingness to recommend, <a href="http://www.brandindex.com/article/top-red-and-blue-brands" target="_blank">the top brands</a> for each political party are as follows:</p>
<div align="center">
<table border="1">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><b>Democrats</b></td>
<td><b>Republicans</b></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Google</td>
<td>Fox News Channel</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Amazon.com</td>
<td>History Channel</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Cheerios</td>
<td>Craftsman</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Clorox</td>
<td>Chick-fil-A</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Dawn</td>
<td>Johnson &amp; Johnson</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</div>
<p>The results seem to imply Republicans watch more TV while Democrats spend more time on-line.</p>
<p>Even social media has joined in.  The digital agency Engage cross-referenced polling data with influence and Facebook &#8220;likes&#8221; to correlate food preference with politics. Their conclusion? “<a href="http://www.buzzfeed.com/rubycramer/2-charts-that-explain-what-your-food-says-about-yo" target="_blank">Conservatives like Cracker Barrel, while Red Bull leans left</a>.”</p>
<div class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 226px"><a href="http://cdn.foodbeast.com.s3.amazonaws.com/content/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/food-politics-chart.jpg"><img class="  " title="The Politics of Food" alt="" src="http://cdn.foodbeast.com.s3.amazonaws.com/content/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/food-politics-chart.jpg" height="179" width="216" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Infographic by engage</p></div>
<p>I don’t know if any of this can be used to project the election winner but it’s good fun.</p>
<p>So readers, what do you think? Do your politics fit these brand preferences?</p>
<br /> Tagged: <a href='http://alignment.wordpress.com/tag/brand/'>brand</a>, <a href='http://alignment.wordpress.com/tag/politics/'>politics</a>, <a href='http://alignment.wordpress.com/tag/postaweek2012/'>postaweek2012</a>, <a href='http://alignment.wordpress.com/tag/social/'>social</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2225/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2225/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2225&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://alignment.wordpress.com/2012/11/04/the-politics-of-brand/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>17</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f18b1b88a558bd9eb3ad0dd64d961fcb?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Jonathan</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://cdn.foodbeast.com.s3.amazonaws.com/content/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/food-politics-chart.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The Politics of Food</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>INSHA&#8217;ALLAH</title>
		<link>http://marietaylorink.com/2012/11/04/inshaallah/</link>
		<comments>http://marietaylorink.com/2012/11/04/inshaallah/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2012 07:46:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Marie Taylor</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[reflections]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Allah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[death]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[will of God]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://marietaylorink.com/?p=1738</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A couple of years ago when I was recovering from illness and couldn’t yet live on my own I rented a room for a year from a very sweet family who had originally come from the Middle East. They took me into their home and into their hearts and when I eventually moved back to [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1738&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A couple of years ago when I was recovering from illness and couldn’t yet live on my own I rented a room for a year from a very sweet family who had originally come from the Middle East. They took me into their home and into their hearts and when I eventually moved back to Sacramento we kept in touch.</p>
<p>A few weeks ago I enjoyed a happy phone conversation with my friend and I heard about the wonderful, long overdue trip she, her husband and two college-age daughters took this summer to visit their aging parents and grandparents in Iran. We ended our talk with my promise to make the two-hour drive to visit them over the upcoming holidays.</p>
<p>Saturday afternoon I was a little surprised to see my friend’s phone number blinking on the receiver.I could immediately tell from the tone of her voice that something was not right. She said that two days ago her oldest daughter awoke from sleep because she was having trouble breathing. They dialed 9-1-1 and she was taken to emergency. A short while later she went into a deep coma. The rest of the story is like a bad dream.</p>
<p>They discovered the daughter had an inoperable cyst in her brain and the next day tests showed that her brain activity had ceased altogether. My friend ended by saying that they would be taking her off life support Sunday afternoon. There are no words to reply to news like this so we wept together on the phone, she for her daughter and I for her.</p>
<p>The girl was just 21, a recent college graduate who was planning on entering medical school and hoping to later work with Doctors without Borders. She was very intelligent and extroverted with a larger-than-life personality and laugh. She lit up the house with her warmth and vitality.</p>
<p>When children die before their parents, the natural order is disturbed. It is especially painful when the children are young and did not drink deeply of all that life has to offer. Right now my friend and her family are in shock. Real grieving will arrive later when they realize there will be no future with this daughter in it. Family holidays will never be the same, the day of her birth will now be mirrored on the calendar with the day of her death, in their old age there will be one daughter missing from their bedside.</p>
<p>After we hung up I thought about my friend’s sudden and dramatic loss and compared it to another phone call I had received just last week. This was also an announcement about death but this time the person was my age. He was dying from terminal cancer and had only weeks left to live. His family, too, were in shock but there was time for their leave-taking, there was time to give and ask for forgiveness, to express love and say goodbye. His life had been long enough for many opportunities.</p>
<p>In both cases the families are asking “why.” Why him, why her, why now, why like this. It reminds me of that period of time when a child is four or five and follows every statement with the question – why? Why is the sky blue? Why is sugar sweet? Why do birds fly? Why do we have five fingers? Eventually, the parent in exasperation will often say, “Just because.” Because ends further interrogation. This non-answer becomes the answer.</p>
<p>Why are some deaths so terrible, why is there illness, why do the innocent suffer, why isn’t life fair … the big questions can’t be answered by the mind; they are divine mysteries. To make this life bearable, to appreciate its sweetness, to live through the dark as well as the light and find some peace, we have to disengage our egos. We have to give up our desire to control life’s direction and outcome, and to acknowledge our submission and our dependence on the Divine. When we are Christians, we say Not my will but Thine be done; when we are Muslims, we say Insha’Allah. Bon voyage, Shahed.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><em>&#8220;…All shall be well, and all shall be well, and all manner of thing shall be well&#8221;. Julian of Norwich</em></p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://marietaylorink.com/category/reflections/'>reflections</a> Tagged: <a href='http://marietaylorink.com/tag/allah/'>Allah</a>, <a href='http://marietaylorink.com/tag/death/'>death</a>, <a href='http://marietaylorink.com/tag/will-of-god/'>will of God</a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1738&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://marietaylorink.com/2012/11/04/inshaallah/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>54</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/5bcfc6c85ec1e55dea459069d5352a9e?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">marieataylor</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Old Abandoned Houses</title>
		<link>http://umanbn.wordpress.com/2012/11/04/old-abandoned-houses/</link>
		<comments>http://umanbn.wordpress.com/2012/11/04/old-abandoned-houses/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2012 17:35:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>umanbn</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[abandoned house]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Architecture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[house after storm]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[old wooden house]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://umanbn.wordpress.com/?p=1594</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#160; There is something I like about old houses. Like old people, their faces tell a story. They stand for some kind of failure, because in the end they collapse. Yet at the same time, they tell a story of success, because their age means, for a while at least, they stood the test of [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1594&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>There is something I like about old houses. Like old people, their faces tell a story. They stand for some kind of failure, because in the end they collapse. Yet at the same time, they tell a story of success, because their age means, for a while at least, they stood the test of time. They weathered storms, they kept out the rain and heat. They sheltered their inhabitants and gave them a home to return to after a hard day. I cannot help but ask myself, who lived in them and what memories do they hide. Were the people who lived in them happy and why did they eventually leave? Also, from a purely aesthetic point of view, I love how they weather and age,  returning slowly to the landscape around them.  I wonder what history, culture and economic circumstances caused them to be built as they are in the first place.<a href="http://umanbn.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/old-house.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1595" title="Old house" alt="" src="http://umanbn.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/old-house.jpg?w=590"   /></a><a href="http://umanbn.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/old-wooden-house-2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1598" title="Old wooden house 2" alt="" src="http://umanbn.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/old-wooden-house-2.jpg?w=590"   /></a><a href="http://umanbn.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/abandoned-house.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1602" title="Abandoned House" alt="" src="http://umanbn.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/abandoned-house.jpg?w=590"   /></a><a href="http://umanbn.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/old-wooden-house-coloured1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1600" title="Old Wooden house coloured" alt="" src="http://umanbn.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/old-wooden-house-coloured1.jpg?w=590"   /></a><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1597" title="Old wooden House" alt="" src="http://umanbn.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/old-wooden-house.jpg?w=590"   /><a href="http://umanbn.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/old-house-2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1596" title="Old house 2" alt="" src="http://umanbn.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/old-house-2.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1594/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1594/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1594&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://umanbn.wordpress.com/2012/11/04/old-abandoned-houses/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>43</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://umanbn.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/old-house.jpg?w=97" />
		<media:content url="http://umanbn.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/old-house.jpg?w=97" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Old house</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/47c4574d6a7ed44fdffc05a8bfa5dca5?s=96&#38;d=retro&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">umanbn</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://umanbn.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/old-house.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Old house</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://umanbn.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/old-wooden-house-2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Old wooden house 2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://umanbn.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/abandoned-house.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Abandoned House</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://umanbn.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/old-wooden-house-coloured1.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Old Wooden house coloured</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://umanbn.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/old-wooden-house.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Old wooden House</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://umanbn.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/old-house-2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Old house 2</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Literature Snob Reads the Hunger Games. And Likes It.</title>
		<link>http://jamesroom.org/2012/11/04/a-literature-snob-reads-the-hunger-games-and-likes-it/</link>
		<comments>http://jamesroom.org/2012/11/04/a-literature-snob-reads-the-hunger-games-and-likes-it/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2012 22:21:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>jamesroom964x</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[1984]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Inspiration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Literature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Philosophy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tyranny]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hunger Games]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kindle]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://jamesroom.org/?p=235</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[; ; It started when I was little. I would always have a problem with the books we were reading in school. Unluckily for me, I think I discovered cynicism before most of the kids in school, so I had no problem slamming Harry Potter for plot holes, or Animal Farm as ham-fisted when I [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=235&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://jamesroomdotorg.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/hunger-games.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-236" title="hunger games" alt="" src="http://jamesroomdotorg.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/hunger-games.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p> ;</p>
<p> ;</p>
<p>It started when I was little. I would always have a problem with the books we were reading in school. Unluckily for me, I think I discovered cynicism before most of the kids in school, so I had no problem slamming Harry Potter for plot holes, or Animal Farm as ham-fisted when I was a kid. My literary snobbery only got worse as I grew older, went to college, and actually got some good books under my belt. But apparently, I wasn&#8217;t paying very much attention to the great literature I was reading, because the snobs are always the worst characters. Take Elizabeth Bennett&#8217;s mother in <i>Pride and Prejudice. </i>She&#8217;s controlling and ridiculous in her obsession with names, wealth and reputation. In <i>In Search of Lost Time, </i>Proust gives us dozens of examples of snobbery in all its forms, from the pathetic salon of the Verdurins, to Legrandin&#8217;s poor social graces, and even the supposedly irreproachable Guermantes. They all let their snobbery show, and the consensus time and time again, is that snobs are always miserable. They see the worst in people and things,  instead of the best.</p>
<p>So, I decided to let literature actually perform its function, and let it teach me something. I originally neglected the Hunger Games trilogy out of hand. Anything I see prominently displayed as I walk into Barnes and Noble usually ends up in the dustbin of my mind. But since I have Amazon Prime, I borrowed the first one for free on my Kindle, and gave it a shot. I didn&#8217;t expect much, but what I found was far better than I could have hoped for.</p>
<p>Like so many readers of this series, I stormed through the first book in a flurry, and then devoured the next two immediately thereafter. I&#8217;d say the entire series took me about five days to read. To get it out of the way, I did have some problems with the books. For one, while the prose is crisp, and as evidenced, it pulls the reader in and moves the plot along, sometimes it feels as if that&#8217;s all it&#8217;s doing. Suzanne Collins is never going to blow anyone&#8217;s mind with her lush descriptions, or challenge the conventions of the novel as an art form. Sometimes the books feel like laundry list of events. One thing happens, Katniss kills something, she thinks about it. I wasn&#8217;t sure how many more descriptions of wilderness meals I could endure by the time I finished Mockingjay.</p>
<p>No, the charm of these novels lies not in their structure, nor their flowing elegant prose, but in the most important component of fiction: the characters. It was not Collins&#8217; gift for intense, suspenseful writing that kept me turning the pages, but rather my sincere concern for the characters. And for me, the characters were compelling because they were all wrestling with themes that are so central, so human, that I couldn&#8217;t <em>not </em>find out how they resolved their problems. Truly, there may be nothing new under the sun. Collins writes about the things man has always written about, love and loss, war and peace. But she does so through the lens of characters we care about, which makes her work more compelling than a dry text on ethics or philosophical meanderings on right and wrong.</p>
<p>No character is more emblematic of this than Peeta. As much as Katniss might be the narrator, and the &#8220;main&#8221; character, this is really Peeta&#8217;s story, because in the end, it&#8217;s a story about good triumphing over evil. However, even in its triumph, good does not emerge without its scars and regrets. As we get older, and read more &#8220;advanced&#8221; texts, we&#8217;re told that simple two dimensional characters are no longer good enough. The perfect hero, who never makes any mistakes, is not complex enough, he&#8217;s not true enough to life. Of course, this is a matter of artistic taste, as many literary traditions have glorified the perfect unsullied hero. Perhaps it says something about our culture that we want, even need faults, even in our heroes, lest we feel badly about our fallible, fragile selves. I found the opposite with Peeta. He was so simple, so unswervingly good, that I came to rely on him, just as Katniss did, as a touchstone of morality, a compass that would <em>always </em>point in the right direction no matter what the gamemakers threw at them.</p>
<p>One of Peeta&#8217;s most interesting qualities is actually his lack of them. He isn&#8217;t particularly fast, or skilled with weapons, especially after he has his prosthetic leg implanted. Katniss is a much better warrior and survivor. Peeta sort of bumbles through, making lots of noise, and forcing Katniss to save him time and time again. Especially for a male character, this seems strange. But Peeta, crucially, has something that Katniss doesn&#8217;t. He has that unrelenting constancy of goodness, that saves not only him, but Katniss as well. Katniss may be the girl on fire, by the time she gets to the Hunger Games, but Peeta prevented her spark from being snuffed out in the rain and the cold all those years earlier. Indeed, Peeta giving Katniss the burned bread is really the &#8220;beginning&#8221; of the whole story. Without that one, crucial act of love and kindness, Katniss wouldn&#8217;t have survived the winter, and the entire shape of Panem history would have been different. If that one event drives the whole plot, there must be something special about it. And there is. It was special because, it was that special kind of love, that acts for no reason. It&#8217;s a stupid love in the best sense of the term. It sees no consequences, like the slap that awaits Peeta from his mother. It&#8217;s the same love that made Katniss volunteer for Prim, or that made Gale set off into the woods with 800 people after District 12 was bombed. Peeta got slapped, Katniss got sent to the 74th Hunger Games, and Gale got caught up in the war. But for all of them, there was never really a choice. They were victims of that irrational sense of compassion for other human beings that looks ridiculousin a context of consequences and self-preservation, but is really the best in all of us. <em><br />
</em></p>
<p>We&#8217;re taught a cruel accounting of cost and benefit. Help people, but help yourself first. But Collins reaches us through these characters because they aren&#8217;t calculators. We&#8217;re constantly warned to never act on our emotions, but these characters do, and somehow, it just seems <em>right. </em>That&#8217;s because they act on the one emotion that can never lead astray. It&#8217;s that emotion, that natural human feeling that no amount of Hunger Games nor Quarter Quells, nor Peacekeers can suppress. It&#8217;s the human spirit that Winston Smith says won&#8217;t let the Party and O&#8217;brien get away with what they plan to do in <em>1984. </em>It&#8217;s something that defies control, like the Mockingjay. The Mockingjays were the descendants of the Capitol Jabberjays, but as Katniss says at one point: &#8220;they pick up on other bird&#8217;s melodies, replicate them, and transform them into something new.&#8221; The characters who act out of selfless compassion are rebellious in the same way, and are therefore just as big a threat to the Capitol. This is because the Capitol can&#8217;t plan for them. It can&#8217;t foresee when a Katniss might volunteer, or when Johanna will sacrifice herself to remove Katniss&#8217; tracker. These acts defy logic. There is no risk benefit analysis beneath them.</p>
<p>Owing someone is a huge theme for Katniss. She feels indebted to Peeta, and so she shows him compassion. She even goes back to the bread scene, many years ago, and says &#8220;It&#8217;s always the first gifts that are the hardest to pay back.&#8221; And she&#8217;s right, because she can&#8217;t pay it back, because it doesn&#8217;t work like that. Peeta did what he did for no other reason than that he loved her, in a very human way. He couldn&#8217;t stand to see her suffer. Katniss continues this line of thinking even when Finnick rescues Peeta from the fog. Haymitch tells her that she could live &#8220;a thousand lifetimes and still not deserve him (Peeta).&#8221; But even that isn&#8217;t right because &#8220;deserve,&#8221; isn&#8217;t a word that applies to those feelings, and to those selfless actions.  This kind of moral, balance sheet just won&#8217;t balance when you run into an inexhaustible supply of good like Peeta. He completely changes the game, which is exactly what he explains he wants to do in the first place, at night on the roof before the first Games.</p>
<p>Peeta refuses to play by the rules, and in fact, he can&#8217;t. He&#8217;s too good for the situation he&#8217;s been thrust into, and so he needs Katniss to bail him out, and sometimes make the tough decisions. In the end, that&#8217;s what Katniss admires about Peeta the most, and what is best about him: his defiant humanity. He&#8217;s tossed into an inhuman situation, but he still clings to his love and compassion for Katniss. If this series is about love and compassion in the end, it&#8217;s also at least partly about control. Even Snow only does what he does for fear that Panem would spiral out of control and into barbarity. But these two concepts are intertwined. Because the Capitol is a harsh and cruel place, that compassion will necessarily be defiant, like the Mockingjay, or Katniss and Peeta holding hands, or of course, the poison berries.</p>
<p>And that defiance is critical, because of what it awakens in everyone else. Very few would have had the defiant attitude and the presence of mind to eat the berries. It didn&#8217;t matter though, because once the rest of Panem saw it, they were affected. Perhaps infected might be a better word. Infected with the notion that things didn&#8217;t have to be the way they were. We can&#8217;t predict rare events, because well, they&#8217;re rare. Those uncalculated acts of kindness, compassion and love that keep Peeta and Katniss going are rare events. The Hunger Games operates on the assumption that the tributes will descend into barbarity and kill each other like animals. What it doesn&#8217;t account for, what it can&#8217;t account for, are the rare events, the outliers, the blips, the selfless acts that destroy Katniss&#8217; accounting of who owes what to whom. It took 73 years for two contestants to act the way Katniss and Peeta did, but in the end, they did. Selflessness, that special kind of stupid love, may be rare, but it exists. And when it does finally show itself, and it will, it is impossible to ignore. It took Peeta to put that one spark of life into Katniss on that cold winter day. It took both of them to spark the revolt when they chose the berries. Collins does an admirable job of showing us that just one spark can start a fire. I wish more young adult books could include such an uplifting and moral message.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/235/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/235/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=235&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://jamesroom.org/2012/11/04/a-literature-snob-reads-the-hunger-games-and-likes-it/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>45</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/dcefa399df0c0583ac6a962344ea9f8c?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jamesroom964x</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://jamesroomdotorg.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/hunger-games.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">hunger games</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>