<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2012 23:02:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>My Long Forgotten Spam</title>
		<link>http://badlandsbadley.wordpress.com/2012/11/08/my-long-forgotten-spam/</link>
		<comments>http://badlandsbadley.wordpress.com/2012/11/08/my-long-forgotten-spam/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2012 04:45:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>badlandsbadley</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[E-mail spam]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[email]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Email address]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Facebook features]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Google]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jerry Brown]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spam]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://badlandsbadley.wordpress.com/?p=4534</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As people comment on my posts, I do my best to respond. It is the least that I can do. Well, actually the least would be to completely ignore you, but the SECOND least I can do is trying to respond. Sometimes, though, a few fall through the cracks. They end up in my spam [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4534&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="aligncenter" title="spam" alt="spam" src="http://www.easycomputeracademy.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/Email-Spam.jpg" height="504" width="403" /></p>
<p>As people comment on my posts, I do my best to respond. It is the least that I can do. Well, actually the least would be to completely ignore you, but the SECOND least I can do is trying to respond.</p>
<p>Sometimes, though, a few fall through the cracks. They end up in my spam folder and just get completely missed. It seems unfair, though, that these never get responded to. That’s why I thought I would take a few minutes and respond to a few comments from my spam folder.</p>
<p><em>Hello there, simply was aware of your weblog through Google, and found that it’s truly informative. I’m going to be careful for brussels. I will be grateful when you continue this in future. Numerous people will probably be benefited out of your writing. Cheers!</em>: <strong>Charles Myrick on “<a href="http://badlandsbadley.wordpress.com/2012/10/23/man-arrives-at-own-funeral-alive-likely-ruins-very-nice-service/" target="_blank">Man Arrives At Own Funeral Alive, Likely Ruins Very Nice Service</a>”</strong></p>
<p>Charles:</p>
<p>Thank you for the kind words. My goal has always been to benefit people through my writing, so hearing someone say these things is a dream come true.</p>
<p>I, however, do not know what this post had to do with brussels. Are we talking brussels sprouts or the city Brussels? Either way, this is very confusing to me.</p>
<p>I guess it really doesn’t matter, though, if you are going to say such nice things. You are a delight and I hope that Google leads you back to my page many times.</p>
<p><em>Thank you for the good writeup. It actually was once a enjoyment account it. Glance advanced to far delivered agreeable from you! By the way, how can we communicate?</em>: <strong>Superheet on “Man Arrives At Own Funeral Alive, Likely Ruins Very Nice Service”</strong></p>
<p>Superheet:</p>
<p>Um… thanks, I think. I’ll be honest with you. I am not too sure what that meant. I guess you enjoyed my writing? We’ll pretend that’s what you said.</p>
<p>The easiest way to communicate with me would be by sending me messages, though they seem to always end up in my spam for some reason. A little known fact, though, is that I am great with smoke signals. Just go outside and build a giant bonfire, then send a few strategic plumes up into the air. I guarantee you I will know exactly what you’re saying.</p>
<p><em>Hello. And Bye</em>: <strong>XRumerTest on “<a href="http://badlandsbadley.wordpress.com/2012/09/18/febreze-teaches-us-about-the-scent-of-the-sun/" target="_blank">Febreze Teaches Us About the Scent of the Sun</a>”</strong></p>
<p>XRumerTest:</p>
<p>Uh…</p>
<p><em>Gov. Jerry Brown’s new driver’s licenses for ILLEGAL Aliens better have the words “ILLEGAL ALIEN” stamped across the front of the license to distinguish it from the licenses that are used as identification by US Citizens and/or LEGAL residents.</em><strong>: Silver Account on “<a href="http://badlandsbadley.wordpress.com/2012/10/17/nathans-inferno-a-drivers-license-bureau-tale/" target="_blank">Nathan’s Inferno</a>”</strong></p>
<p>Silver Account:</p>
<p>I’m not sure I agree with you on that point, but it hardly seems relevant. I am not an illegal alien nor am I Governor Jerry Brown. Thanks for reading, I guess, but let’s try to stick to the issues at hand.</p>
<p><em>[...] US Daily Review best heart rate monitor, how to train for a triathlon, how to train for a marathon, fitness certifications, heart rate zones, threshold training, best cardio exercise, health club fitness program, physical education programs, metabolic testing, emotional fitness, sacramento fitness event, seattle fitness event, sacramento marathon trainingTopExerciseWorkouts-The Best Workouts for Men and WomenLatest News on How to Import from China to IndiaThe Life and Times of Nathan Badley… [...]</em>:<strong>Z-Code System Review Exposes Automated Sports Betting System on “Dear Cupcakes: An Apology”</strong></p>
<p>Z-Code System Review Exposes Automated Sports Betting System:</p>
<p>Go away.</p>
<p>Now I remember why I never open my spam folder.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4534/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4534/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4534&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://badlandsbadley.wordpress.com/2012/11/08/my-long-forgotten-spam/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f8e44c94a11b63121bea68db40ecd125?s=96&#38;d=monsterid&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">badlandsbadley</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://www.easycomputeracademy.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/Email-Spam.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">spam</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Can’t Seasteading Get Off The Ground?</title>
		<link>http://thisruthlessworld.wordpress.com/2012/10/04/why-cant-seasteading-get-off-the-ground/</link>
		<comments>http://thisruthlessworld.wordpress.com/2012/10/04/why-cant-seasteading-get-off-the-ground/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2012 17:18:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Amused</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gender]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Freedom ship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Galt's Gulch]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Libertarianism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Patri Friedman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Peter Thiel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[seasteading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tax heavens]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thisruthlessworld.wordpress.com/?p=845</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[For years now, slow-news days have brought us the breaking news that the world’s richest people &#8212; and hence the world’s best &#8212; fed up with taxation, government regulation, and having to co-exist with the unwashed masses without hunting them for sport, are about to go off to live on a modified oil rig, a [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=845&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://thisruthlessworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/sealand.jpg"><img src="http://thisruthlessworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/sealand.jpg?w=300&#038;h=200" alt="" title="Sealand" width="300" height="200" class="alignright size-medium wp-image-849" /></a>For years now, slow-news days have brought us the breaking news that the world’s richest people &#8212; and hence the world’s best &#8212; fed up with taxation, government regulation, and having to co-exist with the unwashed masses without hunting them for sport, are about to go off to live on a modified oil rig, a “project” known as <a href="http://www.slate.com/articles/health_and_science/new_scientist/2012/09/floating_cities_seasteaders_want_to_build_their_own_islands_.html">”seasteading”</a>.  Alternatively, they may inhabit <a href="http://www.inthesetimes.com/article/3328/">a giant cruise ship</a>.</p>
<p>On the surface, it looks like a perfect futuristic Galt’s Gulch, a cluster of manicured, pastel-colored apartment buildings separated from the world of “parasites” by the forbidding ocean, but yet within a safe distance of some friendly country, one that does not mind having billionaire excrement, broken champagne bottles, and an occasional dead body washing up on its beaches.  There are no taxes to pay, no building codes, no labor laws, no zoning regulations, no legal protections for non-residents (you know, the cleaning staff) &#8212; a paradise.  <span id="more-845"></span></p>
<p>And yet, although the technology that allows seasteads and residential ships to be created and maintained has existed for decades, “the best people” (a nod to William M. Thackeray) are in no big hurry to make seasteading a reality.  Sure, they occasionally <a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2011/08/18/peter-thiel-seasteading_n_930595.html">throw a little money</a> at such projects, paltry contributions indeed &#8212; relative not only to the probable cost of such a project, but most importantly, relative to the wealth of the donors.  Nonetheless, everything about their approach to this venture tells me it exists primarily as a political talking point, not as an actual, physical undertaking.  It sure seems they don’t really want to live on a seastead as much as they want to talk about the evils of government. So what’s the problem?</p>
<p>If you’ve clicked on the links above, you probably know at this point that artists’ conceptions of what Galt’s seabases will look like is probably the most definite thing about the endeavor.  Everything else is … blurry.  The ideas about how seasteads will make money, how they will interact with land-based nation-states, how they will maintain law and order, and how they will defend against inevitable attacks are <a href="http://www.motherjones.com/politics/2012/06/seasteading-institute-conference-libertarian-utopia">all over the place</a>.</p>
<p>Still, out of this primordial soup of embryonic ideas, a certain picture of what a seastead would be like emerges.  And that picture does little to support the enthusiasts’ avowed commitment to liberty and small government.</p>
<p>Economically, the best of circumstances would make a seastead similar to Dubai, all glittery Space Age on the surface, but built and sustained by huge armies of workers brought in from the Third World.  In Dubai, such people are basically  <a href="http://www.independent.co.uk/voices/commentators/johann-hari/the-dark-side-of-dubai-1664368.html">imprisoned by their employers and treated like slaves</a>: enticed under false premises; made to work 14-hour days in hellish heat; fed in amounts barely adequate to sustain life; paid pennies, and sometimes not at all; housed in conditions eerily reminiscent of World War II-era concentration camps; not allowed to leave for years.  Would seasteading masters be deterred by a risk of revolt?  I think not.  Worker revolts may be violent and spectacular, but that only masks the reality of how rarely they happen.  There is a variety of relatively easy ways to make people tolerate slave-like conditions: bring together workers from disparate regions, so that cultural barriers impede cooperation; shuffle them around, constantly bring in new faces, keep the work force fluid, so that it is never stable enough for people to develop trust and cultivate the bonds necessary to enable them to stand up to those in charge.</p>
<p>The consensus among seasteading enthusiasts seems to be that such communities will make money in <a href="http://www.alternet.org/story/140253/seasteading%3A_libertarians_set_to_launch_a_%28wet%29_dream_of_%27freedom%27_in_international_waters?page=0%2C1">restricted commodities</a>: pharmaceuticals that do not have to satisfy safety standards or get government approval before being allowed on the market; illegal drugs; surgeries that may or may not be performed by people skilled in medicine; or simply brilliant scientific and technological ideas (although those who float that last one do not seem to realize that formulating such ideas in a marketable form requires research facilities and the cooperation of large numbers of highly educated specialists who aren’t likely to be as gullible as the Himalayan farmers who get lured to Dubai).</p>
<p>Politically, it is certain that the management of a seastead will <i>not</i> be democratic &#8212;  Patri Friedman, the creator of Seasteading Institute, <a href="http://www.cato-unbound.org/2009/04/06/patri-friedman/beyond-folk-activism/">expressly rejects democracy</a> for the fact that it gives political power to too many people who disagree with Libertarianism.  Consequently, the system will be kind of like the Soviet Union &#8212; a system that bills itself as “free”, but permits only one party access to power and bans any deviation from that party’s ideology as an act of treason and sabotage.  As noted in China Mieville’s piece on the “Freedom Ship”, the creators of <i>that</i> community expressly intend it to be a dictatorship.   <i>Unlike</i> was the case in the Soviet Union, however &#8212; or today’s North Korea, for that matter &#8212; <a href="http://www.slate.com/articles/news_and_politics/politics/2010/10/turn_on_start_up_drop_out.html">women will be completely disenfranchised</a> in seasteading communities if Peter Thiel, the founder of PayPal and one of the major backers of Seasteading Institute, has his way.  (I am not convinced by the counter-arguments that others in the seasteading movement do not “necessarily” share Thiel’s view of women’s suffrage.  Friedman’s complaint that democracy allows the “wrong” people to have influence over the political process suggests otherwise.)  In other words, it will be like some of the worst totalitarian states in modern history &#8212; except that for women, it will be even worse.  All in the name of “freedom”.</p>
<p>The attitude of prominent seasteaders towards women’s role in public life suggests that were this project to come to fruition, few women would move there willingly if they can afford to stay away &#8212; especially since being in the middle of a goddamned ocean means you can’t leave unless the men in charge let you.  Thus, most female residents of seasteads will probably be prostitutes and mail-order brides, both categories trafficked from the Third World.</p>
<p>And with all that, a picture of a seastead emerges &#8212; an isolated box filled to the brim with luxury goods, drugs, trafficable women and billionaires’ precious children, very marketable commodities all.  Which, of course, will make the seastead <i>extremely</i> attractive to pirates.</p>
<p>This brings me to the next thorny issue: defense.  Since the sale of weapons other than small firearms is  highly restricted, and countries like the United States or Great Britain are unlikely to sell cruise missiles and such to a seastead, it goes without saying that these freedom-loving communities will immediately get in bed with rogue states and terrorist groups.  In addition, since any pirate group with even an ounce of common sense will try to seize a seastead by infiltrating the work force &#8212; and perhaps even the resident community &#8212; this government-free paradise will have to run pretty extensive background investigations and operate an extremely intrusive web of police surveillance and espionage.  Welcome to <i>1984</i>.  Think of how much freedom you are willing to sacrifice in the name of freedom &#8212; and that, without even considering the <i>monetary</i> cost, and how it will be accomplished without levying taxes (no cheating now, kids; a tax is still a tax, even if you call it a “maintenance fee”).</p>
<p>I don’t know, all this sounds pretty miserable and dystopian to me &#8212; even for one of the “haves” aboard such a community.  This may explain why seasteading enthusiasts do not take this project past the brie-and-champagne conference stage.  But more than the probability of a publicity nightmare were such a community to exist, more than the cost and the danger at pirates’ hands, it is the philosophies and the personalities involved that make such a project unrealistic.  To put it simply, you cannot succeed at a cooperative venture founded on the spirit of freedom from having to cooperate, manned by people whose philosophy equates cooperation with vice. And to put it more bluntly, there isn’t a seaworthy vessel big enough to contain the combined egos of several hundred super-rich assholes, whose participation in the project is inspired by a sense of entitlement to never have to compromise, other people’s interests be damned. The fact that even the most luxurious seastead or ship will still force residents to occupy a much smaller space and live much more tightly bound to each other than they would have been on land, will only exacerbate the tensions.</p>
<p>On this, the example of one floating residential community is instructive.  <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MS_The_World">MS The World</a> is a cruise ship owned by its residents, and it’s been ploughing the waves for nearly a decade now.  Note, The World is not a Galt’s Gulch.  <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2002/09/01/us/on-ship-of-condos-life-s-an-endless-cruise.html?pagewanted=all&amp;src=pm">Members are not permitted to claim the ship as their primary residence, so it is not a tax haven; and most residents spend only a few months onboard at a time.</a>  It is merely an ultra-luxury retirement community for those few who can afford it.   Still, even here, in a floating community whose residents did not sign up for tax-dodging or ideological reasons, the reality of entitled behavior cannot be avoided. The resident who spoke to the New York Times, put it in the gentlest terms possible, but you still get the idea:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8221;We have to get along,&#8221; said Geoffrey Thompson, 59, a retired advertising executive from Monterey, Calif., when asked about his neighbors on The World. &#8221;We share the same backyard.&#8221; His backyard tilted from side to side in the horizon of his two-bedroom apartment&#8217;s windows as he spoke, seated on a sedan-sized sofa. &#8221;There&#8217;s more type A personalities on board per capita than anywhere else in the world,&#8221; Mr. Thompson said. &#8221;No passive bones in the body.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/845/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/845/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=845&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thisruthlessworld.wordpress.com/2012/10/04/why-cant-seasteading-get-off-the-ground/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/849260008d0626b824c96d8208ae7198?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">khozyajka</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thisruthlessworld.files.wordpress.com/2012/10/sealand.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Sealand</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Out of Answers? You\&#8217;re Not Out of God.</title>
		<link>http://nextpages.wordpress.com/2012/11/09/out-of-answers-youre-not-out-of-god/</link>
		<comments>http://nextpages.wordpress.com/2012/11/09/out-of-answers-youre-not-out-of-god/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2012 16:08:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Mark Love</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[hermeneutics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scripture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[theology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[answers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[college students]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[faith]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Job]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nextpages.wordpress.com/?p=416</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I have the privilege of teaching the Bible to college freshman. For most of them, the Bible is mostly a set of impressions. Even if they know some Bible stories, they really know very little about the Bible. They think of the Bible primarily through some religious assumptions that have been modeled before them. This [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=416&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I have the privilege of teaching the Bible to college freshman. For most of them, the Bible is mostly a set of impressions. Even if they know some Bible stories, they really know very little about the Bible. They think of the Bible primarily through some religious assumptions that have been modeled before them. This is true whether they are Christians or not. And some of these get in their way of knowing God.</p>
<p>The biggest untested assumption that they bring to Scripture is that it is some kind of answer book, that it speaks with one voice on all topics. The Bible is a great monolith, and so is God who is purported to be pulling all the levers.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s the thing about this view of God and Scripture. If a sensitive, reflective, thoughtful student has begun to entertain questions about all that he or she has inherited, then they&#8217;ve got a crisis of faith. To question puts them outside the boundary.</p>
<p>And these students have questions. They have questions about violence and the degradation of the planet and homosexuality and gender and power in the church. And too often, the very presence of these questions makes them feel dangerous to themselves.</p>
<p>A few weeks ago, I taught on the book of Job. Job is placed in a conundrum. His experience does not square with what he believes about God. Job is committed to holding on to his integrity, which includes two things&#8211;his faith in God and his personal experience of life. His wife wants him to give up the faith in God part. &#8220;Why do you hold on to your integrity? Curse God and die.&#8221; His friends want him to deny his personal experience. &#8220;These kinds of things don&#8217;t happen to the upright. Confess your sins (a rough paraphrase).&#8221; But Job persists, requiring that his understanding of God conform to his experience of life. And in the process he says some pretty sketchy things about God.</p>
<p>In the end, Job is humbled and perhaps satisfied in his encounter with God. Not because he gets answers, but because he gets the presence of God. This is enough. And perhaps more importantly, God upholds Job. God scolds the safe-talking friends who refuse to move past their answers about God, &#8220;My wrath is kindled against you and your two friends; for you have not spoken of me what is right, as my servant Job has.&#8221; God affirms Job, the one who moves beyond answers to a more direct encounter with God.</p>
<p>I told my students that there will come a day in their lives when their answers about God no longer conform to their personal experience of the world. This does not mean they are out of God. There&#8217;s God beyond our answers about God, and God honors those who relentlessly pursue the living God.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/416/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/416/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=416&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://nextpages.wordpress.com/2012/11/09/out-of-answers-youre-not-out-of-god/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/c0dbfe59ff502c623b493c986de84c1f?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">drmarklove24</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>My Ideal Bookshelf</title>
		<link>http://closedthecover.wordpress.com/2012/11/09/my-ideal-bookshelf/</link>
		<comments>http://closedthecover.wordpress.com/2012/11/09/my-ideal-bookshelf/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2012 14:18:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Lilee</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Autobiography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Classic Literature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Book of Eli]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bookshelf]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Canterbury Tales]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Epic of Gilgamesh]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fables and fairy tales]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lewis Grizzard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[literature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Malcolm Gladwell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sasha Frere-Jones]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shelf-Awareness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://closedthecover.wordpress.com/?p=703</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In this morning&#8217;s edition of the Shelf-Awareness newsletter there was a review of the new book, My Ideal Bookshelf by Thessaly La Force, editor, illus. by Jane Mount (Little, Brown, $24.99 hardcover, 9780316200905, November 13, 2012). I thought it was a unique concept.  The review, in part, stated, &#8220;Every reader will, at some point, face the [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=703&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://closedthecover.wordpress.com/2012/11/09/my-ideal-bookshelf/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>28</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/b6a371d96dd8f74c0946175587726306?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ashlilee</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://closedthecover.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/ideal110912.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ideal110912</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Like Time, My WordPress Reader Waits For No Man</title>
		<link>http://adlibb3d.wordpress.com/2012/11/07/wordpress-like-time-waits-for-no-man/</link>
		<comments>http://adlibb3d.wordpress.com/2012/11/07/wordpress-like-time-waits-for-no-man/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2012 06:35:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Ad-libb3d</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Being Funny]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Master Archive]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Morning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Superdog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WordPress]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://adlibb3d.wordpress.com/?p=461</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Remember when you were a kid and it seemed like you had too much time? I can remember being eight years old and having so much free time that I didn’t know what to do with it all. I became an expert at making up ways to stay busy. I could fill up an entire [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=461&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://adlibb3d.wordpress.com/2012/11/07/wordpress-like-time-waits-for-no-man/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>34</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/2dfc0d58181b47ad6546b97d26a56af4?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">adlibb3d</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://adlibb3d.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/toomanyblogs.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">howdoesonestaycurrent</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://adlibb3d.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/coffee.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ahhh-coffee</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Meet the Portland Urban Sketchers</title>
		<link>http://petescully.com/2012/11/08/meet-the-portlands/</link>
		<comments>http://petescully.com/2012/11/08/meet-the-portlands/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2012 23:28:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>pete scully</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[sketchbloggery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drawing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moleskine 11]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[people]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[portland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[urban sketchers]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://petescully.com/?p=4709</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[One of the reasons I wanted to go back to Portland was to sketch with the Portland Urban Sketchers, partly because I have at least met several of them before, and partly because I love their work on USk PDX. We met at Floyd&#8217;s Coffee in Old Town, and I got a breakfast burrito and sketched People. I traditionally only sketch [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4709&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a title="PDX Floyds by petescully, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/petescully/8152573694/"><img alt="PDX Floyds" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8061/8152573694_c743c21da8_z.jpg" height="607" width="600" /></a><br />
One of the reasons I wanted to go back to Portland was to sketch with the <a href="http://urbansketchers-portland.blogspot.com/"><strong>Portland Urban Sketchers</strong></a>, partly because I have at least met several of them before, and partly because I love their work on USk PDX. We met at Floyd&#8217;s Coffee in Old Town, and I got a breakfast burrito and sketched People. I traditionally only sketch People when those People are also Sketchers &#8211; it&#8217;s like it&#8217;s &#8216;alright&#8217;. Still, I need the practise, and I&#8217;ve been doing a lot more of it lately. Anyway, it was good to catch up with some familiar faces &#8211; Linda, Alanna, Kalina, Vicky, Pascale - and meet some more, such as Greg (who I actually drew in Lisbon but never met), Deb, Andrea, Marta, Marco, Cassie, Angelika, Gary (hope I&#8217;ve not missed anyone out!) - and of course, to watch them sketch. One thing I know about myself is that I don&#8217;t tend to sketch quite as much when I am talking, but when I meet other sketchers I do love to talk. About pens, mostly. And Magneto.<br />
<a title="sketching with the pdx urban sketchers by petescully, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/petescully/8152539804/"><img alt="sketching with the pdx urban sketchers" src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7128/8152539804_356f49a4ac_z.jpg" height="406" width="640" /></a><br />
After Floyd&#8217;s I took a brief interlude to sketch in the rain (see the sketch at the bottom, drawn by Skidmore Fountain in very wet conditions), before rejoining the group at Old Town Pizza, an interesting old place full of things to look at at draw. It was a fun afternoon with lots of conversation, and I am glad to have gone. A shame we couldn&#8217;t have all sketched outside, but the rain really was pouring, and it was nice and friendly inside.<br />
<a title="PDX Urban Sketchers by petescully, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/petescully/8168017312/"><img alt="PDX Urban Sketchers" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8206/8168017312_635ecbd98a_z.jpg" height="503" width="640" /></a><br />
<a title="Portland Urban Sketchers (with me) by petescully, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/petescully/8167954424/"><img alt="Portland Urban Sketchers (with me)" src="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8339/8167954424_c086f0107a_z.jpg" height="480" width="640" /></a><br />
<a title="Portland sketchbooks by petescully, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/petescully/8167926333/"><img alt="Portland sketchbooks" src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7139/8167926333_5e783d76e2_z.jpg" height="480" width="640" /></a></p>
<p>Here&#8217;s to the next time!</p>
<p><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/petescully/8152480311/" title="PDX rainy skidmore by petescully, on Flickr"><img src="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7259/8152480311_f0f4f6756b_b.jpg" width="500" height="765" alt="PDX rainy skidmore"></a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4709/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4709/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4709&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://petescully.com/2012/11/08/meet-the-portlands/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/0b9792ab50983b07fc5e6f6756821295?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">petescully</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8061/8152573694_c743c21da8_z.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">PDX Floyds</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7128/8152539804_356f49a4ac_z.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">sketching with the pdx urban sketchers</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8206/8168017312_635ecbd98a_z.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">PDX Urban Sketchers</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8339/8167954424_c086f0107a_z.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Portland Urban Sketchers (with me)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7139/8167926333_5e783d76e2_z.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Portland sketchbooks</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7259/8152480311_f0f4f6756b_b.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">PDX rainy skidmore</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Weaning Baby Doll: A Logical Counterpart</title>
		<link>http://thelaughingmom.wordpress.com/2012/11/09/the-weaning-baby-doll-a-logical-counterpart-to-the-breast-milk-baby/</link>
		<comments>http://thelaughingmom.wordpress.com/2012/11/09/the-weaning-baby-doll-a-logical-counterpart-to-the-breast-milk-baby/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2012 14:31:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>The Laughing Mom</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Commentary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[breast milk baby]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[breastfeeding]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[commentary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[funny story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[motherhood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nursing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parenting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weaning]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thelaughingmom.wordpress.com/?p=1793</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In case you haven&#8217;t heard, the latest baby doll rage for the holiday season is The Breast Milk Baby by Berjuan Toys. The Breast Milk Baby is an actual doll that simulates breastfeeding by suckling on plastic rose petals attached to a cute little top worn by the child. It&#8217;s hard to take the concept [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1793&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://thelaughingmom.wordpress.com/2012/11/09/the-weaning-baby-doll-a-logical-counterpart-to-the-breast-milk-baby/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f3e0f691b5e9650cb970d2ee4025ac54?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">errita5</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thelaughingmom.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/breast-milk-baby.png" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">breast milk baby</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Brass Neck: Felix and the Steampunks</title>
		<link>http://felixpearce.wordpress.com/2012/09/11/brass-neck-felix-and-the-steampunks/</link>
		<comments>http://felixpearce.wordpress.com/2012/09/11/brass-neck-felix-and-the-steampunks/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2012 14:14:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Felix Pearce</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thoughts]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[costuming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[steampunk]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[subculture]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://felixpearce.wordpress.com/?p=151</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;ve just come home from my second trip to Steampunk at the Asylum, an annual steampunk convention held in the lovely city of Lincoln.  It&#8217;s a marvellous occasion stuffed with eccentrics in the grandest British tradition: dressing up like characters from a Victorian science fiction novel, obsessing about tea and politeness, and parading round town [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=151&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://felixpearce.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dsc00590.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-155   alignleft" title="DSC00590" src="http://felixpearce.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dsc00590.jpg?w=244&#038;h=324" alt="" width="244" height="324" /></a></p>
<p>I&#8217;ve just come home from my second trip to <a title="Asylum homepage" href="http://steampunk.synthasite.com/" target="_blank">Steampunk at the Asylum</a>, an annual steampunk convention held in the lovely city of Lincoln.  It&#8217;s a marvellous occasion stuffed with eccentrics in the grandest British tradition: dressing up like characters from a Victorian science fiction novel, obsessing about tea and politeness, and parading round town confusing the locals with glee.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s also a subculture which is increasingly fascinating me as a phenomenon in its own right. I discovered the Asylum online in time to attend last year&#8217;s event, and instantly loved it simply for the costuming angle &#8211; I&#8217;m an inveterate thesp and sartorial eccentric, and have loved dressing up since I was a child. The more I discover about the culture that&#8217;s evolving out of it, though, the more I think it&#8217;s doing something genuinely unique.</p>
<p><span id="more-151"></span>The term &#8220;<a title="Wikipedia: steampunk" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Steampunk" target="_blank">steampunk</a>&#8221; was coined as an ironic take on &#8216;cyberpunk&#8217; and originated as a name for an emerging literary genre in the 80s and early 90s. Over time the genre acquired all the usual trappings of a popular flight of imagination &#8211; tabletop roleplaying games, local groups of enthusiasts, costumers and prop-makers &#8211; and it now seems to be snowballing into a subculture proper.</p>
<p><a href="http://felixpearce.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/martin_asylum_timechair.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-159 alignright" title="martin_asylum_timechair" src="http://felixpearce.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/martin_asylum_timechair.jpg?w=225&#038;h=300" alt="Photo by Martin Strain." width="225" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>What fascinates me is that it&#8217;s remarkably distinct from most other subcultures I&#8217;ve experienced. As a teenager I was into rock and metal and as a student in the late 1990s I was a goth; by association I&#8217;ve gained insights into cultures like the original version of punk and the many-coloured BDSM world. What strikes me most about steampunk in comparison to all these is how unlike them it is.  Steampunk isn&#8217;t merely about a shared love of a genre of music &#8211; in fact, steampunk music is almost defined by its eclecticism, varying from <a title="The Men That Will Not Be Blamed For Nothing" href="http://www.myspace.com/blamedfornothing" target="_blank">wildly talented comic punk</a> to <a title="BB BlackDog - What You Need" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2mLwfPPofbs" target="_blank">Sabbath-esque classic metal</a> to <a title="Pocketwatch" href="http://pocketwatchtheband.com/" target="_blank">lush, folk-influenced Victorian macabre</a> and satirical <a title="Professor Elemental - Fighting Trousers" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0iRTB-FTMdk" target="_blank">chap-hop</a>. It&#8217;s not about hedonism in the way goth and BDSM are. My memories of the Whitby goth weekend are mostly characterised by endless hangovers, leather restraints as fashion accessories, stiletto heels getting stuck between century-old cobblestones, and once receiving a death threat from a girl in a lycra catsuit for touching her boyfriend&#8217;s hairstyle. Almost all the goths I knew were in their 20s or 30s; the older generations sported poignantly ironic &#8220;Sad Old Goth&#8221; T-shirts, available at the annual market. The attendees at this year&#8217;s Asylum ranged in age from eight to eighty and were of all shapes, sizes and races (I knew exactly one non-white goth in my entire time in the culture); there were several wheelchair and cane users present as well, and unless I miss my guess a couple of visible trans people too. I find that degree of inclusiveness wonderfully refreshing &#8211; so many other subcultures are dominated by affluent white twentysomethings and preoccupied with the ever ephemeral &#8220;cool&#8221;.</p>
<p><a href="http://felixpearce.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dsc00577.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-154 alignleft" title="DSC00577" src="http://felixpearce.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dsc00577.jpg?w=251&#038;h=188" alt="" width="251" height="188" /></a></p>
<p>There&#8217;s the breathtaking creativity of the scene. The number of beautiful props and costumes on display was astounding, and there&#8217;s a strong vein of beautifying the functional in the aesthetic; one gent who attended Saturday&#8217;s attempt to break the world record for the largest gathering of steampunks was entertaining the queue with a beautifully steampunked portable musical machine, mounted in a leather case as gentle classical tones poured out of an array of glistening chrome funnels.</p>
<p>And then there&#8217;s the way the attending steampunks behave. The organisers of Asylum have a catchphrase that goes &#8220;Be splendid!&#8221; &#8211; and people do. Locals ask if you&#8217;d mind posing for a photo rather than just snapping you (usually after asking for an explanation of what on earth they&#8217;ve just walked into the middle of, bless their hearts); press photographers are strongly encouraged to come in Victorian costume and ejected if they misbehave. Seeing this, it occurs to me to wonder what the &#8216;punk&#8217; in steampunk really means.</p>
<p>Back in the 1970s, punk was a conscious rejection of the repressive behavioural norms of the day &#8211; a bitter blow to the already crumbling hold of old-fashioned standards on society. Forty years later we live in the age of the ASBO and the reality-show celebrity, and people are <a title="BBC News article" href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-16740199" target="_blank">wandering around in public in their pyjamas</a>; perhaps there was a baby in the bathwater of propriety after all, and perhaps steampunks, underneath the gentle self-parody and Utopian fantasism, are also conscious of that in some way. In our quest for freedom we&#8217;ve created a world where fame is arbitrary rather than based on skill and achievement, where standards of public dress and behaviour are at an all-time low, everything&#8217;s a cheap commodity and rudeness is almost cool in its own right &#8211; so what&#8217;s punk now, in a world where everyone acts like Sid Vicious? In such an inverted reality, does it become &#8216;punk&#8217; to subvert the dominant cultural norm by being <em>more </em>polite<em>, </em><em>more</em> well-dressed, <em>more </em>creative?</p>
<p><a href="http://felixpearce.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/martin_asylum_castle_exit.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-156 alignright" title="martin_asylum_castle_exit" src="http://felixpearce.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/martin_asylum_castle_exit.jpg?w=158&#038;h=210" alt="Photo by Martin Strain" width="158" height="210" /></a></p>
<p>Personally, I look at modern Pagans, sustainable living nuts and the many small-scale attempts to find an alternative economic model to capitalism that go on in the subcultural holes and corners of Britain, and I think that looking for the good in our own ancient history could well be a form of rebellion in a very temporal world. My flatmate and I have both acknowledged the faint unease that goes along with wearing fantastified Victorian costume &#8211; the consciousness that Britain&#8217;s age of empire was a brutal time for anyone not lucky enough to be one of Her Majesty&#8217;s own &#8211; but it was also a time of <a title="The Men That Will Not Be Blamed For Nothing - Brunel" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=21QqXumEWFU" target="_blank">hope and innovation</a>. Victorians thought in a way that at times completely ignored the confines of our own soggy island and the facts of the physical world as they seemed to be laid out at the time; many of their engineering creations endure to this day and have inspired generations. That spirit of determination and positive change is something I seek for throughout my life, and I certainly hope to honour the idea in whatever steampunk creations I come up with over time.</p>
<p>The Asylum is now in its fourth year and growing every time. Human nature loves to complain and there&#8217;s a certain degree of grousing among the &#8220;old guard&#8221; about the dilution and cheapening of the ethos (although steampunks even <a title="Just Glue Some Gears On It..." href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TFCuE5rHbPA">complain in style</a>), but I for one am keen to learn, and look forward to the opportunity to get to know some of that old guard.</p>
<p>Photography: myself and Martin Strain.</p>

<a href='http://felixpearce.wordpress.com/2012/09/11/brass-neck-felix-and-the-steampunks/dsc00577/' title='DSC00577'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="154" data-orig-file="http://felixpearce.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dsc00577.jpg" data-orig-size="2592,1944" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;U20i&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1347110475&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;40&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0.01&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-description="&lt;p&gt;Photo by Martin Strain&lt;/p&gt;
" data-medium-file="http://felixpearce.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dsc00577.jpg?w=300" data-large-file="http://felixpearce.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dsc00577.jpg?w=1024" width="150" height="112" src="http://felixpearce.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dsc00577.jpg?w=150&#038;h=112" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="Steampunk motorcycle" title="DSC00577" /></a>
<a href='http://felixpearce.wordpress.com/2012/09/11/brass-neck-felix-and-the-steampunks/dsc00590/' title='DSC00590'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="155" data-orig-file="http://felixpearce.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dsc00590.jpg" data-orig-size="1944,2592" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;U20i&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;1347116694&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;40&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0.00625&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-description="&lt;p&gt;Photo by Martin Strain&lt;/p&gt;
" data-medium-file="http://felixpearce.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dsc00590.jpg?w=225" data-large-file="http://felixpearce.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dsc00590.jpg?w=768" width="112" height="150" src="http://felixpearce.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dsc00590.jpg?w=112&#038;h=150" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="Impressive steampunk costume" title="DSC00590" /></a>
<a href='http://felixpearce.wordpress.com/2012/09/11/brass-neck-felix-and-the-steampunks/martin_asylum_castle_exit/' title='martin_asylum_castle_exit'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="156" data-orig-file="http://felixpearce.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/martin_asylum_castle_exit.jpg" data-orig-size="540,720" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-description="&lt;p&gt;Photo by Martin Strain&lt;/p&gt;
" data-medium-file="http://felixpearce.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/martin_asylum_castle_exit.jpg?w=225" data-large-file="http://felixpearce.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/martin_asylum_castle_exit.jpg?w=540" width="112" height="150" src="http://felixpearce.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/martin_asylum_castle_exit.jpg?w=112&#038;h=150" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="Steampunks leaving Lincoln Castle" title="martin_asylum_castle_exit" /></a>
<a href='http://felixpearce.wordpress.com/2012/09/11/brass-neck-felix-and-the-steampunks/martin_asylum_jetpackrace/' title='martin_asylum_jetpackrace'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="157" data-orig-file="http://felixpearce.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/martin_asylum_jetpackrace.jpg" data-orig-size="540,720" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-description="&lt;p&gt;Photo by Martin Strain&lt;/p&gt;
" data-medium-file="http://felixpearce.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/martin_asylum_jetpackrace.jpg?w=225" data-large-file="http://felixpearce.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/martin_asylum_jetpackrace.jpg?w=540" width="112" height="150" src="http://felixpearce.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/martin_asylum_jetpackrace.jpg?w=112&#038;h=150" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="Jetpack racer" title="martin_asylum_jetpackrace" /></a>
<a href='http://felixpearce.wordpress.com/2012/09/11/brass-neck-felix-and-the-steampunks/martin_asylum_lincolncathedral/' title='martin_asylum_lincolncathedral'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="158" data-orig-file="http://felixpearce.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/martin_asylum_lincolncathedral.jpg" data-orig-size="720,960" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-description="&lt;p&gt;Photo by Martin Strain&lt;/p&gt;
" data-medium-file="http://felixpearce.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/martin_asylum_lincolncathedral.jpg?w=225" data-large-file="http://felixpearce.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/martin_asylum_lincolncathedral.jpg?w=720" width="112" height="150" src="http://felixpearce.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/martin_asylum_lincolncathedral.jpg?w=112&#038;h=150" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="Lincoln cathedral" title="martin_asylum_lincolncathedral" /></a>
<a href='http://felixpearce.wordpress.com/2012/09/11/brass-neck-felix-and-the-steampunks/martin_asylum_timechair/' title='martin_asylum_timechair'><img data-liked='0' data-reblogged='0' data-attachment-id="159" data-orig-file="http://felixpearce.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/martin_asylum_timechair.jpg" data-orig-size="720,960" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta="{&quot;aperture&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;credit&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;camera&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;caption&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;created_timestamp&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;copyright&quot;:&quot;&quot;,&quot;focal_length&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;iso&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;shutter_speed&quot;:&quot;0&quot;,&quot;title&quot;:&quot;&quot;}" data-image-description="&lt;p&gt;Photo by Martin Strain.&lt;/p&gt;
" data-medium-file="http://felixpearce.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/martin_asylum_timechair.jpg?w=225" data-large-file="http://felixpearce.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/martin_asylum_timechair.jpg?w=720" width="112" height="150" src="http://felixpearce.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/martin_asylum_timechair.jpg?w=112&#038;h=150" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="Steampunk mobility scooter inspired by H G Wells&#039;s Time Machine. Photo by Martin Strain." title="martin_asylum_timechair" /></a>

<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/151/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/151/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=151&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://felixpearce.wordpress.com/2012/09/11/brass-neck-felix-and-the-steampunks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/e4e973582607b32fb844cf3f3e6c0209?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">felixpearce</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://felixpearce.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dsc00590.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC00590</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://felixpearce.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/martin_asylum_timechair.jpg?w=225" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">martin_asylum_timechair</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://felixpearce.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/dsc00577.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC00577</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://felixpearce.files.wordpress.com/2012/09/martin_asylum_castle_exit.jpg?w=225" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">martin_asylum_castle_exit</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Favorite.</title>
		<link>http://somethingtoreadforthetrain.wordpress.com/2012/11/08/the-favorite/</link>
		<comments>http://somethingtoreadforthetrain.wordpress.com/2012/11/08/the-favorite/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2012 15:51:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>crfricke</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Book Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writer-life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children's literature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fairy tales]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Irene Haas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nostalgia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reading]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Little Moon Theater]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://somethingtoreadforthetrain.wordpress.com/?p=536</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It should be almost as blasphemous to pinpoint a favorite book as it is to single out a favorite child, especially if you&#8217;re a Reader with a Capital R. What will the others think? Will the Grimms become bitter? Will Peter Pan, knowing that he&#8217;s loved but not (gasp!) my favorite, develop some deeply-seated childish [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=536&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It should be almost as blasphemous to pinpoint a favorite book as it is to single out a favorite child, especially if you&#8217;re a <a href="http://somethingtoreadforthetrain.wordpress.com/2011/11/14/on-the-opportunity-of-losing-a-job-maurice-sendak-and-the-book-that-told-me-what-i-want-to-be-when-i-grow-up/">Reader with a Capital R</a>. What will the others think? Will the Grimms become bitter? Will Peter Pan, knowing that he&#8217;s loved but not (gasp!) my favorite, develop some deeply-seated childish drive for attention? That is, more than he already has? It&#8217;s a risky move, both because someone on the shelf might get offended , and because there&#8217;s always the chance&#8211;some say&#8211;that you might change your mind.</p>
<p>But I won&#8217;t change my mind, even if my favorite book has lots of competition.</p>
<p>In my apartment there&#8217;s a special shelf, where my Grimms live, all of my Sendak, Barrie, and Trina Schart Hyman. Also, most of the criticism of the aforementioned hang out there as well. It&#8217;s the place of honor, away from the YA paperbacks and college poetry textbooks, where my 1st edition of <a href="http://somethingtoreadforthetrain.wordpress.com/2011/12/14/not-my-mother-syfys-neverland-and-j-m-barries-peter-pan-part-two/">Barrie&#8217;s <em>The Little White Bird</em></a> sits next to Lore Segal and Randall Jarrell&#8217;s<em> The Juniper Tree,</em> illustrated by Maurice Sendak, which was given to me by a good friend in a time of <a href="http://somethingtoreadforthetrain.wordpress.com/2011/11/14/on-the-opportunity-of-losing-a-job-maurice-sendak-and-the-book-that-told-me-what-i-want-to-be-when-i-grow-up/">book-need</a>. All of Maria Tatar&#8217;s <em>Annotated</em> series (<em>Hans Christian Andersen, The Grimms, Peter Pan</em>) are here, along with a copy of <em>War of the Worlds,</em> as illustrated by Edward Gorey, and <em>A Child&#8217;s Christmas in Wales,</em> as illustrated by the late, beautiful, Trina Schart Hyman. Audrey Niffennegger&#8217;s <em>The Three Incestuous Sisters,</em> next to both volumes of Tony Kushner&#8217;s study of the work of Maurice Sendak.</p>
<p>All of this is not to brag, but to say that it might surprise some of you readers, who&#8217;ll have already been exposed to my rants and exultations about many of these titles, that none of these (not even <em>Peter and Wendy,</em> illustrated by Trina Schart Hyman!) is my favorite book of all time. In fact, the author of this book is someone whose name has never appeared on this blog before. It&#8217;s a book I grew up with without attaching any significance to the name, the way I now do with my hoarded information about authors of books that I love. I love this book not because there&#8217;s any thrilling backstory or deep personal turmoil in the making of it. It&#8217;s simple, beautiful, and, sadly, out of print.</p>
<p>This, dears, is my favorite book of all time:</p>
<p><a href="http://somethingtoreadforthetrain.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/il_fullxfull-334391077.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-539" title="il_fullxfull.334391077" alt="" src="http://somethingtoreadforthetrain.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/il_fullxfull-334391077.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>Irene Haas, author and illustrator of <em>The Maggie B.</em> and <em>A Summertime Song,</em> published <em>The Little Moon Theater</em> in 1981. I grew up listening to my mother read it to me at bedtime, and I&#8217;m not ashamed to say that it had a bigger impact on my personal taste and aesthetics than anything I read in graduate school.</p>
<p>The book is about a trio of performers: Jojo, Jip, and Nicolette (the woman, the dog, and the cat, respectively), who travel the countryside in their wagon, entertaining townsfolk at each stop. The book is a little different from other children&#8217;s books with traditional narratives, and also the fairy tales from which many children&#8217;s books take their cues, in that Jojo, Jip, and Nicolette don&#8217;t have any expressed conflict or goal in the beginning of the story. They&#8217;re a traveling theatre troupe, they always have been, and we can probably assume that they will continue to be so after the last page is turned. There&#8217;s nothing wrong with their life, nor is anyone trying to convince them that there might be.</p>
<p>The plot, then, is about other people who are <em>not</em> Jojo, Jip, and Nicolette.</p>
<p><a href="http://somethingtoreadforthetrain.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/3028693118_f50bf3cfbb_z.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-542" title="3028693118_f50bf3cfbb_z" alt="" src="http://somethingtoreadforthetrain.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/3028693118_f50bf3cfbb_z.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>For instance, Rose, pictured above, whom the troupe meets in a village as they look for a place to set up for the evening&#8217;s show. Rose wishes she could go to the show that night, but her mother has told her she can&#8217;t, because Rose insists on making a spectacle of herself by wearing two different colored socks. Jojo, Jip, and Nicolette&#8211;being theatre folk and thus endlessly tolerant and open-minded&#8211;invite Rose to be a part of the show instead, and through the magic of theatre and story-telling, they convince Rose&#8217;s mother that being a little different is really not so terrible after all. The show, of course, is presented as a fairy tale.</p>
<p><a href="http://somethingtoreadforthetrain.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/il_570xn-334391223.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-543" title="il_570xN.334391223" alt="" src="http://somethingtoreadforthetrain.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/il_570xn-334391223.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>Although our main trio of protagonists aren&#8217;t necessarily the ones with a quest or conflict (which is a little to the left of traditional), <em>The Little Moon Theater</em> does apply a more traditional <em>pattern</em> to its plot: Rose is the first of 3 people whom the Little Moon troupe helps with a problem. The significance of the three-part plot structure is plucked straight from fairy tales, in which the hero must usually accomplish three tasks, or must try three times to open a certain door or rescue a certain princess. He or she might earn the help of three magical beasts, or might recover three magical objects. 3 is everywhere&#8211;3 is important.</p>
<p>In <em>The Little Moon Theater,</em> however, 3 isn&#8217;t as important to our protagonists as it is to the strange little woman following them around from town to town. After each performance, as the troupe packs up their show, they&#8217;re interrupted by the untimely arrival of a funny little grandmotherish creature, who&#8217;s usually caught in a tree or dunked in a lake because of her barely-functioning fairy godmother wings.</p>
<p><a href="http://somethingtoreadforthetrain.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/little-moon.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-544" title="little moon" alt="" src="http://somethingtoreadforthetrain.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/little-moon.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>You see, every time the troupe grants someone&#8217;s wish&#8211;Rose with one yellow and one red sock, the boy whose family thinks his pet snake is dangerous when it&#8217;s really misunderstood, and (my favorite) the hobo dog who wishes, intensely, for the moon&#8211;by bringing them aboard the <em>Little Moon</em> and including them in the show, they&#8217;re overriding the wish-granting power of the fairy godmother. She has only has one wish left to grant before she can retire, but she always seems to get to the scene a little too late. The troupe nurse her through the night (she&#8217;s a frail thing), and say goodbye the next day, to move on to the next town, and the next show. The godmother is always grateful, but a little annoyed that she&#8217;s still one wish away from resting her old bones.</p>
<p><a href="http://somethingtoreadforthetrain.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/il_570xn-334391195.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-545" title="il_570xN.334391195" alt="" src="http://somethingtoreadforthetrain.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/il_570xn-334391195.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>Eventually the troupe has its own wish to be granted. On a frosty night, when their only audience is a family of friendly wolves, they wish to be warm, and finally the fairy grandmother (who crashes into a pile of snow) can have her retirement. Simple, beautiful, out of print.</p>
<p><a href="http://somethingtoreadforthetrain.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/3028693112_e21c02e678_z.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-546" title="3028693112_e21c02e678_z" alt="" src="http://somethingtoreadforthetrain.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/3028693112_e21c02e678_z.jpg?w=590"   /></a></p>
<p>When I was younger&#8211;meaning young enough to have the story read to me&#8211;I never questioned the truthfulness, the mere fact, of Jojo, Jip, and Nicolette&#8217;s little band as they exist on the page. They are a troupe, they have no backstory. They simply exist, and always have, and of course Jip and Nicolette are fully sentient collaborators, despite their being a cat and dog.</p>
<p>However. When I was in high school, my obsession with this book swelled into something more complicated, thanks (don&#8217;t laugh) to the hit teen film <em>She&#8217;s All That.</em> The film, which was unremarkable, used a song by the band Sixpence None the Richer, and of course a music video, featuring the two fresh-faced leads from the film, was produced and splattered all over MTV, which I&#8217;d watch at a friend&#8217;s house. Something about that video, in my teenage years, sparked a memory of this book which I&#8217;d loved, and something about the lead singer&#8217;s face and hair, her musician/companions, the lights, the whimsy, made me sad and full of book-nostalgia. Yes, the video and the song are truly mediocre, and watching it means looking more than one should ever have to at Freddie Prinze Jr.&#8217;s face. But I was a teenager, and there it is.</p>
<span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='640' height='390' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/8N-qO3sPMjc?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span>
<p>I took up the book again, and because I was a sullen and <em>very</em> nerdy teenager predisposed to question everything, I began thinking much more about the <em>who</em> and <em>what</em> of Jojo, Jip, and Nicolette, and connecting them symbolically with the pretty singer in the video and her human companions. Suddenly the anthropomorphism was strange, and sad&#8211;what if Jojo was a real human girl, and Jip and Nicolette were human too, really, after all? What would they look like in human form? What if they grew up, and grew out of the troupe? Or worse, much worse, what if Jojo was the only human, a girl, and what if the Little Moon Theater was her pretend game? Because I couldn&#8217;t get this sad little scenario out of my head, I wrote a play adaptation which ended, after all of the wish-granting and theatrical hijinks, with Jojo the girl, alone in her room, a stuffed cat and dog inert and unmoving tossed next to her on the floor. I was, as I said, very nerdy, and more than a little morose. But <em>The Little Moon Theater</em> became the first children&#8217;s book that spoke to me about something irretrievable&#8211;what exists and is left behind after growing up starts, and play-acting ends. You know it was there, and it happened, but now you&#8217;re different, and there&#8217;s no getting it back. There would be many more books that would give me this same feeling, and which had been written most carefully by people who understood that feeling too&#8211;<em>Peter Pan,</em> of course, and much of the work of Maurice Sendak. But this was the first. It was, all at once, an overwhelmingly sad and satisfying feeling, which made me cherish the book and also feel a sort of protectiveness about it.</p>
<p>In my trips down memory lane, I run across reviews that somehow made it from their original print sources onto the everlasting archives of the web. A review from <em>The Christian Science Monitor,</em> written when the book was released in 1981, summarized the book thus: &#8220;the story, with all the beauty and whimsy of an old-fashioned fairy tale, concerns a little girl who travels around the countryside with her dog and cat.&#8221;</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve been accused, many times, of over-thinking things, and of relentlessly finding the &#8220;sad&#8221; and the symbolic in incidents that, to anyone else, would seem trivial at best. But when I read this summary, written by someone who did, after all, like the book in their banal way, I can&#8217;t help but feel like they just didn&#8217;t get it. And by not getting it, they&#8217;re perpetuating those fears that teenage-me worked to confront and banish. They&#8217;re not just a dog and cat, I want to say, and they&#8217;re certainly not <em>Jojo&#8217;s,</em> in the sense that she owns them. They&#8217;re real&#8230;aren&#8217;t they? Maybe it doesn&#8217;t matter. I loved this book, and I still do. Because of this book, I have too many polka dots in my closet, and I write plays in which one character, at the very least, is wearing a top hat. I can&#8217;t describe my ideal wedding reception without referring to the illustrations in this book. So perhaps the possibility that these characters aren&#8217;t as real to others as they were to me, back in my childhood, doesn&#8217;t matter.</p>
<p>But then again, I think, as I look at my own dog and cat sleeping on the couch, and I remember how lonely it was to be a child, and how strong the urge to create another world around oneself really was, maybe it does matter. Maybe it matters very much that Jip and Nicolette are never just a dog and cat. It mattered to child-Cate, and for some reason, it still matters to me.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/536/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/536/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=536&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://somethingtoreadforthetrain.wordpress.com/2012/11/08/the-favorite/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>17</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/60c6d74e47f0a69735b2668dedebe519?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=R" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mauveincognito</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://somethingtoreadforthetrain.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/il_fullxfull-334391077.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">il_fullxfull.334391077</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://somethingtoreadforthetrain.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/3028693118_f50bf3cfbb_z.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">3028693118_f50bf3cfbb_z</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://somethingtoreadforthetrain.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/il_570xn-334391223.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">il_570xN.334391223</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://somethingtoreadforthetrain.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/little-moon.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">little moon</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://somethingtoreadforthetrain.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/il_570xn-334391195.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">il_570xN.334391195</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://somethingtoreadforthetrain.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/3028693112_e21c02e678_z.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">3028693112_e21c02e678_z</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Yes, I&#8217;m a millennial.</title>
		<link>http://misadventuresblog.com/2012/11/07/yes-im-a-millennial/</link>
		<comments>http://misadventuresblog.com/2012/11/07/yes-im-a-millennial/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2012 04:34:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>jwmisadventures</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[musings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[millennial communication]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[millennials at work]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[working with millennials]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://misadventuresblog.com/?p=3199</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Last week at a work event I witnessed a roundtable discussion on the challenges older adults face when communicating with millennials. It was interesting to hear people 10 to 20 years older than me speak candidly about their frustrations getting through to my generation. A variety of causes were blamed, ranging from the popularity of [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3199&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last week at a work event I witnessed a roundtable discussion on the challenges older adults face when communicating with millennials. It was interesting to hear people 10 to 20 years older than me speak candidly about their frustrations getting through to my generation. A variety of causes were blamed, ranging from the popularity of text messaging to excessive praise from parents. A professional facilitator led the session, which lasted for several hours.</p>
<p>I sat in the back of the room, intrigued and a bit ashamed, and didn&#8217;t make a peep. I&#8217;m not sure if anyone participating in the conversation recognized the fact that I fell into the demographic they were describing, and I didn&#8217;t want to derail the energy in the room.</p>
<p>The thesis statement of the conversation was that millennials were bad at communication. That we pretty much lack the ability and initiative to interact with others in a productive way. There were even suggestions that younger people should be trained on ways to better engage with older generations as they enter the workforce.</p>
<p>I couldn&#8217;t help but feel a little bit stereotyped.</p>
<p>I know. I&#8217;m the anomaly. My entire profession is based on promoting clear communication.</p>
<p>But it wasn&#8217;t really the criticism that bugged me. It was the feeling of being casually defined by a broad term that made me uncomfortable. Yes, I&#8217;m a millennial, based on the year I was born. But I&#8217;m a lot of other things, too. For example, I&#8217;m a great baker and I make really good mixed CDs. I&#8217;m a dog lover and a world traveler.</p>
<p>Sure, go ahead and sum up my existence in a few phrases. I can take it. But you don&#8217;t see me or my peers sitting around, lamenting the inability of older generations to engage with <em>us</em>.</p>
<p>I get it though. We text incessantly. We have ADD. We ask &#8216;why.&#8217; And we speak too fast and say &#8220;like&#8221; a lot. But we grew up with the INTERNET for pete&#8217;s sake, and cell phones and e-books and coed dorms. We lack the eloquence of Shakespearean actors, true, but man can we tweet with finesse.</p>
<p>The world has become a faster place, and as people growing up in it, we&#8217;re simply trying to adapt.</p>
<p>I think that as sure as the sun will rise tomorrow, generations will always have challenges understanding each other and figuring out how to relate. This will continue to make parents crazy and teenagers rebellious, and ensures a place for detention in high schools from now through eternity. I understand how aggravating it must be to work with people my age and our endless quirks and eccentricities, but I believe that learning how to listen to us &#8211; maybe in ways you&#8217;ve never tried &#8211; is worth the effort.</p>
<p>You never know what you&#8217;ll learn when you least expect it.</p>
<p>We use slang and we swear a lot. It&#8217;s disgraceful. But we also can do things that would blow your mind. Just give us a chance and let your listening skills evolve with your patience.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3199/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3199/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3199&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://misadventuresblog.com/2012/11/07/yes-im-a-millennial/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>21</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/5847e72ace8c665b8526fb1dec9cea4c?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">jwmisadventures</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>