<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2013 21:02:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="Freshly Pressed: Editors&#039; Picks" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>OkCupid is Riddled with Psychos, and I&#8217;m One of Them</title>
		<link>http://keychangesblog.com/2013/02/19/okcupid-is-riddled-with-psychos-and-im-one-of-them/</link>
		<comments>http://keychangesblog.com/2013/02/19/okcupid-is-riddled-with-psychos-and-im-one-of-them/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2013 12:40:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Nic</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Dating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Emotional Meltdowns]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[I Just Might Die Alone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Comedy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LGBT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[okcupid]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online dating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pyschosis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Relationships]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://keychangesblog.com/?p=1686</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[There’s no easy way to say this, so here it goes: My friend and I have a ghost OkCupid account. I know, it’s weird and we need therapy. But this fake profile has proven itself to be immensely helpful and afforded us opportunities that simply don’t exist when playing by the standard OkCupid rules – [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1686&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;"><img class=" wp-image-1687 aligncenter" alt="okc" src="http://keychangesblog.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/2013-02-19_07-15-59_931.jpg?w=270&#038;h=479" width="270" height="479" /></p>
<p>There’s no easy way to say this, so here it goes: My friend and I have a ghost OkCupid account. I know, it’s weird and we need therapy. But this fake profile has proven itself to be immensely helpful and afforded us opportunities that simply don’t exist when playing by the standard OkCupid rules – including but not limited to:</p>
<ol>
<li>Stalking people without having them know that YOU are the one visiting their profile five times per <span style="text-decoration:line-through;">hour</span> day.</li>
<li>Seeing what your real profile looks like to outsiders, and if it is listed as “replies often” or “replies selectively.”</li>
<li>Spending inordinate amounts of time browsing profiles on the site. (Doing this from your real profile would cause your “Last Online” meter to perpetually read “Online Now,” making you look like a desperate person who probably has four cats and a freezer full of ice cream/maybe eight DiGournos – and that’s just not ideal.)</li>
</ol>
<p>The other day I logged into this secret weapon in order to check out some dude’s pictures, and inevitably ended up combing through the profiles of every gay man in Connecticut (because <em>what else is new?</em>).</p>
<p>And then I came across a page that was hilarious, well written, and actually fun to read. And – bonus! He was really cute.</p>
<p>Unaccustomed to such compelling content on the site, I decided it was imperative that I send him a message. I spent a good twenty minutes coming up with something that referenced the things I liked most about his profile while simultaneously introducing myself as someone who is funny, well-read, and totally worth his hand in marriage.</p>
<p><i>Sent</i>.</p>
<p>And then I went to check our compatibility match and saw that we were rated as 50% enemies. <i>That’s weird</i>, I thought, <i>we’re so similar.</i></p>
<p>AND THEN.</p>
<p>I looked to the top of my screen and came to the earth-shattering realization that I had <i>sent the message from the ghost account!</i> (The ghost account, mind you, is a straight man from Tennessee with no pictures.)</p>
<p>Unsure of whether or not to cry or laugh or scream bloody murder, I did all three.</p>
<p>I tried to ask myself, “What would a normal person do to fix this?” but instantly realized that a normal person would never be in this predicament to begin with. Then I tried to ask myself, “WWJD?” but realized that Jesus would never need to create a ghost account in the first place because he’s Jesus and would probably just be like “I’m the son of God and I’m going to browse anonymously right now, and you’re going to be fine with that – okay, Cupid?”</p>
<p>So then I evaluated my realistic options:</p>
<ol>
<li>Send the exact same message from my real account and pray that he’d just chalk up the duplicate message to a strange OkCupid glitch.</li>
<li>Come up with a brand new message to send him from my real account – one written in a markedly different tone than the one sent from the fake account – and hope that he’d just be like, “Hm. Two guys named Nic in the same day. <i>Weird</i>.”</li>
<li>Say this: <i>Hey &#8211; I&#8217;m about to come off as the creepiest person ever, but well, my friend and I have a ghost OkCupid account for stalking purposes&#8230; and I just accidentally sent you a message from it. I know. I need therapy. But the thought of formulating a NEW message that didn&#8217;t involve anything from the sent-from-creepy-TN-profile original message was too daunting, so I&#8217;m just coming clean. </i></li>
</ol>
<p>Inexplicably, I somehow decided that number three was the best option and I sent it and I KNOW – anyone on the receiving end of a message like that should absolutely be cautious that the sender is a psychopath and probably block him or her.</p>
<p>In the heat of the moment, though, I ridiculously expected that he would see it and be like, “Wow, I admire this guy’s honesty. <i>He’s keeping it real</i>. He’s also handsome and brilliant!” and then message me with something to the effect of, “Hey, thanks for the message. You seem like someone I could spend the rest of my life with, probably. Totally okay about the ghost account; I understand. Let’s meet up for a drink sometime and maybe get married?”</p>
<p>Instead, I got this: <i>Haha. Well, this profile is very different from the other.</i></p>
<p>Polite, but doesn’t exactly open the floor for me to respond with anything at all. The subtext was obviously very <em>I’ve-seen-both-messages-and-you’re-crazy-but-I’m-just-going-to-give-a-dead-end-response-now-so-that-you-don’t-continue-to-stalk-me, </em>but really, the fact that he responded at all is probably more closure than I deserve in this whole scenario anyways, so I guess on some level I got lucky.</p>
<p>What did I learn from this experience? A few things:</p>
<ol>
<li>I’m the biggest contradiction ever. Like, my sending of the overly honest second message was clearly me trying present this whole, “I’m just going to be <i>so</i> real with you right now. I’m that kind of person – I’m impulsive and transparent and don’t care what people think. <i>I’m just doin’ me!</i>” vibe to him – but someone who doesn’t care what others think would never create a ghost profile in the first place, so,<em> yeah.</em> Contradiction.</li>
<li>Sometimes, when trying to make yourself not seem like a crazy person even though you are, it’s okay and extremely necessary to lie and take the secret with you to the grave.</li>
<li>Life would be so much easier as a <i>non-</i>crazy person to begin with. (But how to become one?)</li>
</ol>
<p>Oh and also – I really, <i>really</i> need to stop trying so hard.</p>
<p>But <a title="Not OK, Cupid" href="http://keychangesblog.com/2012/07/06/not-ok-cupid/">this we knew</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1686/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1686/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1686&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://keychangesblog.com/2013/02/19/okcupid-is-riddled-with-psychos-and-im-one-of-them/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>28</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/644f82bc3b0622354ece0c69de344439?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ctnicolas</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://keychangesblog.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/2013-02-19_07-15-59_931.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">okc</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Eric Carle and iPad Babies</title>
		<link>http://acvoice.com/2013/02/18/eric-carle-and-ipad-babies/</link>
		<comments>http://acvoice.com/2013/02/18/eric-carle-and-ipad-babies/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2013 02:41:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Craig Campbell</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Books]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[adhd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eric carle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[eric carle museum of picture book art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hyperlinks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[iBaby]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ipad baby]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[multi-tasking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[online learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[singularity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the Scared is scared]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://acvoice.com/?p=11883</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[(Craig Campbell)&#8211; Last Friday, my visiting parents and I drove to Hampshire College to take a look at the Eric Carle Museum of Picture Book Art. For a 10-minute bus ride and $6 admissions fee, I recommend the museum for anyone who has ever read a picture book – that is, everyone. The gallery displayed [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=11883&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://cultofmac.cultofmaccom.netdna-cdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/iPadBaby.jpg"><img src="http://acvoice.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/ipadbaby.jpg?w=547&#038;h=363" alt="DSC_0079" width="547" height="363" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-11885" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://acvoice.com/author/ccampbell15/">(Craig Campbell)&#8211;</a> Last Friday, my visiting parents and I drove to Hampshire College to take a look at the <a href="http://www.carlemuseum.org/Home">Eric Carle Museum of Picture Book Art</a>.  For a 10-minute bus ride and $6 admissions fee, I recommend the museum for anyone who has ever read a picture book – that is, everyone.  </p>
<p>The gallery displayed original drafts of illustrations from a variety of classic children’s literature, including a special exhibit on <em>Charlotte’s Web</em>, anniversary illustrations by Maurice Sendak, and Carle’s own tissue paper collages that make up the striking images in <em>The Very Hungry Caterpillar</em>.  As I browsed the collection, I perceived a distinct sense of familiarity with many of the images; I had evidently read the stories at some point in childhood.  Although I couldn’t put a finger on the narrative associated with any of the pictures, I felt, on a visceral level, what I had felt some 15 years ago when experiencing them for the first time.  <em>The Night Kitchen</em> was exhilarating and fantastically escapist; <em>Sylvester and the Magic Pebble</em> elicited the comfort of familial affection; the<em> Frog and Toad </em>series aroused a feeling of giddy platonic appreciation. </p>
<div id="attachment_11888" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><img src="http://acvoice.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/frog-and-toad-pic.jpg?w=300&#038;h=275" alt="Frog and Toad by Arnold Lobel" width="300" height="275" class="size-medium wp-image-11888" /><p class="wp-caption-text"><em>Frog and Toad</em> by Arnold Lobel</p></div>
<p>In my ‘Senses in Motion’ research seminar, a recurring point of discussion has been the effect of sensory stimuli in digital media.  One of my classmates showed us the “iPad baby,” a picture (above) of an infant reading a Dr. Seuss book on the Apple device.  We agreed that we should be wary of the increasing prevalence of digital culture in the lives of children and its effect on the developing brain; however, we unanimously voiced this concern while all looking at the picture on our own<em> individual iPad screens.</p>
<p>One of <a href="http://acvoice.com/2012/01/31/math-multitasking-and-modern-education-a-commentary-on-e-learning/">the issues with “online learning”</a> is the ever-growing abundance of hyperlinks on webpages.  <a href="http://www.quicksprout.com/2011/08/01/6-advanced-ways-to-improve-your-search-engine-rankings/">Sites are encouraged</a>, in fact, to fill their text with external links as it raises their search engine indices.  However, the convention of linking diverse sources disrupts the temporal linearity of any textual thought.  Each link serves as its own digression to another topic, and so the wholeness of an otherwise cogent text becomes fundamentally fragmented.  Replete with blue underlined phrases, Wikipedia is so successful because of its relatively concise presentation of a general topic, with plenty of opportunities (links) for tangential discovery.  However, research confirms that, although web-based learning increases students’ ability to “multitask,” it diminishes their capacity to think <a href="http://www.kappanmagazine.org/content/92/4/8.abstract">abstractly and creatively. </a></p>
<p>So why is “multitasking” considered a desirable, employable skill?  Studies indicate that media multitasking results in <a href="http://mashable.com/2012/08/13/multitasking-infographic/">sloppier performance</a> in each simultaneously executed activity.   This is not surprising: consider the dual lines of mental processing necessary to drive a car and use a cell phone at the same time. </p>
<p>The more we replace physical media with constantly changing digital forms, the more efficient we become at processing multiple sources of data at once; we train our eyes to hurriedly follow the changing images in front of us.  Try this experiment: open a new tab in this browser and look at your browsing history for the past week.  How many sites listed do you even remember visiting?  Are you noticing just </em><em>how many</em> different Facebook links show up stacked on top of one another?  Check the time stamps; how many different pages did you navigate through in any <em>one</em> minute?</p>
<p>“Multi-tasking,” <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Human_multitasking#Continuous_partial_attention">as we understand it</a>, comes from the term “computer multi-tasking.”  As technology charges fearlessly and endlessly onward, the dread of <a href="http://singularity.org/what-is-the-singularity/">The Singularity</a> – the moment when robots become self-aware – continues to foment in the collective consciousness.  But the converse is rarely considered; in the age of <a href="http://www.cdc.gov/ncbddd/adhd/timeline.html">record numbers of ADHD diagnoses</a>, shouldn’t we be worried about what happens when we train our minds, and our kid&#8217;s minds, to model the multitasking of computers, robots, and machines?</p>
<p>Children’s literature is designed to build the foundation of <a href="http://vimeo.com/58659769">“abstract thinking” in young people</a>.  Simple picture books teach a basic understanding of right and wrong, of the superlative value of family and friendship, and the notion that being “lost” is the worst conflict one could ever face.  Besides learning how to apprehend language, reading picture books facilitates parent-child bonding, develops fine motor skills (turning thin pages) in readers, and encourages fastidious attention.  Remember how often you wanted to read the same story, over and over again, despite the fact that you knew each word by heart?</p>
<p>If the generation of iBabies were to enter the Eric Carle Museum 20 years from now, would their brains be capable of the visceral childhood associations that I had?  Or would the barrage of unrelated images juxtaposed throughout their childhood lives hinder their sense of what the messages of those stories even were?</p>
<p>Only in picture books is the medium more important than the narrative, and a book in hand is by no means the same as a book on screen.</p>
<div id="attachment_11890" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://carinbondar.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/very-hungry-caterpillar.jpg"><img src="http://acvoice.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/very-hungry-caterpillar.jpg?w=300&#038;h=202" alt="The Very Hungry Caterpillar by Eric Carle" width="300" height="202" class="size-medium wp-image-11890" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text"><em>The Very Hungry Caterpillar</em> by Eric Carle</p></div>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://acvoice.com/category/books/'>Books</a>, <a href='http://acvoice.com/category/media/'>Media</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/11883/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/11883/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/11883/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/11883/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/11883/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/11883/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/11883/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/11883/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/11883/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/11883/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/11883/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/11883/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=11883&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://acvoice.com/2013/02/18/eric-carle-and-ipad-babies/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://acvoice.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/ipadbaby.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://acvoice.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/ipadbaby.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0079</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/3e5712570ddbb2bfae17638ee395c653?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F0.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ccampbell15</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://acvoice.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/ipadbaby.jpg?w=547" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0079</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://acvoice.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/frog-and-toad-pic.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Frog and Toad by Arnold Lobel</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://acvoice.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/very-hungry-caterpillar.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The Very Hungry Caterpillar by Eric Carle</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Movie Scene Doppelgänger: The Futility of Trying to Recreate a Magic Moment</title>
		<link>http://fishandbicycles.com/2013/02/19/movie-scene-doppelganger-the-futility-of-trying-to-recreate-a-magic-moment/</link>
		<comments>http://fishandbicycles.com/2013/02/19/movie-scene-doppelganger-the-futility-of-trying-to-recreate-a-magic-moment/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2013 21:55:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Fish &#38; Bicycles</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Fish & Bicycles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cinema]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Portland]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://fishandbicycles.com/?p=10877</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[So, rewind a few weeks, to February 2nd, Groundhog Day to be precise, and, as corny as it sounds, my family and I watched, as we do every year, the 1993 Bill Murray comedy Groundhog Day. We&#8217;ve watched the movie many times, each time I tend to notice something I hadn&#8217;t noticed before, or a [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=10877&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://fishandbicylces.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/vdaymoviesgroundhogday_gallery_primary.jpg"><img src="http://fishandbicylces.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/vdaymoviesgroundhogday_gallery_primary.jpg?w=300&#038;h=221" alt="VDayMoviesGroundhogDay_gallery_primary" width="300" height="221" class="alignright size-medium wp-image-10878" /></a>So, rewind a few weeks, to February 2nd, Groundhog Day to be precise, and, as corny as it sounds, my family and I watched, as we do every year, the 1993 <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bill_Murray">Bill Murray</a> comedy <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Groundhog_Day_(film)"><em>Groundhog Day</em></a>.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ve watched the movie many times, each time I tend to notice something I hadn&#8217;t noticed before, or a particular scene strikes me as funnier than it had before, or something like that, and this time was no different. It took me a couple of weeks to fully piece this year&#8217;s revelation together, and here it is:</p>
<ul>
The snowball fight scene is the cinematic doppelgänger of the lobster scene from <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Woody_Allen">Woody Allen</a>&#8216;s 1977 film <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Annie_hall"><em>Annie Hall</em></a>. (see the lobster scene below)</ul>
<p>The photo shown above is from a scene where Bill Murray&#8217;s and Andie MacDowell&#8217;s characters are having a magical moment. Murray&#8217;s Phil has been harnessing his experience of reliving the same day over and over again in order to learn as much as he can about MacDowell&#8217;s Rita, a strategy which, at first seems to be working. Phil deftly manages to shift Rita&#8217;s impression of him as a cynical, arrogant, and selfish jerk to a sensitive guy with deep interest in her as a person, as well as someone who seems to share her values. They build a snowman together, and, after a spontaneous snowball fight with some kids, they kinda inadvertently fall close to each other in the snow, their eyes lock, and they kiss. It&#8217;s sweet and playful.</p>
<p>But, Phil overreaches. Managing to persuade Rita to come see his room at the B&amp;B, his selfishness returns, he becomes extremely pushy with sexual advances, culminating in a slap to the face and Rita&#8217;s swift, angry departure.</p>
<p>His attempt the &#8220;next day&#8221; to recreate the magic moment is painful to watch, so forced and fake and duplicitous, the antithesis of what Rita would want:</p>
<p><span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='640' height='390' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/1-fyMqpuE0k?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span></p>
<p>And, of course, it doesn&#8217;t work. It will never work. That&#8217;s why the original moment was magical. It was the coming together of two people whom at first didn&#8217;t seem at all well-suited for each other, yet in the surprise that they could actually get along and have fun, affection and even love, or at least the possibility of love, happened.</p>
<p>Now, rewind 16 years, and try to remember, if you can, a scene from <em>Annie Hall</em>, Woody Allen&#8217;s Alvy and <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Diane_Keaton">Diane Keaton</a>&#8216;s Annie are on a little getaway to the seaside, when hilarity breaks out in the kitchen, as Alvy and Annie are trying to cook lobsters, but the lobsters have somehow scattered about the floor.</p>
<p>Once again, you have two VERY different people coming together, taking delight in the fact that, despite their differences, they are having a lot of fun.</p>
<p>But, as we know, sadly, Alvy and Annie grow apart. And, Alvy, like Phil from <em>Groundhog Day</em>, is under the mistaken impression that he can recreate that magical lobster moment with someone else.</p>
<p>Here are both scenes spliced together:</p>
<p><span class='embed-youtube' style='text-align:center; display: block;'><iframe class='youtube-player' type='text/html' width='640' height='390' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/hWtgUq9mfx0?version=3&#038;rel=1&#038;fs=1&#038;showsearch=0&#038;showinfo=1&#038;iv_load_policy=1&#038;wmode=transparent' frameborder='0'></iframe></span></p>
<p>As one YouTube commenter wrote: </p>
<blockquote><p>This is perhaps the best scene about what chemistry is. And how it can only be found and lived, not recreated, not replaced.</p></blockquote>
<p>So, yeah, it&#8217;s chemistry, or magic, or something, and it has a shelf life.</p>
<p>As I said, it took me a while to fully formulate this post, to connect the dots across 16 years of film history, but it finally came together this past weekend, in Portland, Oregon, where, <a href="/2013/02/13/out-of-office-mini-vacation-edition/">as I mentioned</a>, I was on a mini-vacation with my wife and 15-year old son.</p>
<p>On Saturday, we, along with, it seemed, 95% of the population of Portland, visited <a href="http://www.omsi.edu/">OMSI</a> (the Oregon Museum of Science &amp; Industry). We went to OMSI not only because it&#8217;s supposed to be an amazing place, but also because our son had been there several years ago on a class trip, having stayed the night on the premises, and it was&#8230;</p>
<p>&#8230;magical!</p>
<p>We were careful to honor the memories of that magic, and asked him if he was sure that he wanted to go, he was now 15 after all, and perhaps, we wondered, he&#8217;d think it was for younger kids and not his thing at all anymore.</p>
<p>And yet, when asked, he enthusiastically said, &#8220;YES!!! OMSI&#8217;s AWESOME!!!&#8221;</p>
<p>Fast Forward, and we&#8217;re standing outside in the rain, waiting to get in, or we&#8217;re wandering around the museum checking out the exhibits, and he&#8217;s noticeably quiet, a quiet that, we&#8217;d soon find out, represented disappointment.</p>
<p>The magic could not be recreated, for whatever reasons, maybe the fact that he&#8217;d been with his classmates and friends last time, or the fact that they got to have a sleepover in a museum (how cool is that?!), and the fact that he&#8217;s now a little older and he&#8217;s there with his parents, etc.</p>
<p>Anyway, the lesson here is pretty obvious: Should you have magic moments, savor every frickin&#8217; drop, breathe it all in and gather it up and store it away in your heart and mind, take some photos and video if you want, so that you can think of and feel those precious, unique memories, whenever you summon them.</p>
<p>Just, please avoid the disappointment and don&#8217;t try to manufacture them again. </p>
<p>Trust me. It.won&#8217;t.work.</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://fishandbicycles.com/category/fish-bicycles/'>Fish &amp; Bicycles</a> Tagged: <a href='http://fishandbicycles.com/tag/cinema/'>cinema</a>, <a href='http://fishandbicycles.com/tag/culture/'>culture</a>, <a href='http://fishandbicycles.com/tag/family/'>family</a>, <a href='http://fishandbicycles.com/tag/portland/'>Portland</a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/10877/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/10877/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/10877/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/10877/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/10877/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/10877/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/10877/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/10877/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/10877/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/10877/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/10877/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/10877/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/10877/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/10877/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=10877&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://fishandbicycles.com/2013/02/19/movie-scene-doppelganger-the-futility-of-trying-to-recreate-a-magic-moment/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/583fda3362be63f22ceff8303f55a230?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">F&#38;B</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://fishandbicylces.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/vdaymoviesgroundhogday_gallery_primary.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">VDayMoviesGroundhogDay_gallery_primary</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Suicide &amp; How My Brother Saved Me From Drowning</title>
		<link>http://forwardwalking.com/2013/02/15/suicide-how-my-brother-saved-me-from-drowning/</link>
		<comments>http://forwardwalking.com/2013/02/15/suicide-how-my-brother-saved-me-from-drowning/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 15:28:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Seth Adam Smith</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Depression]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Love]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brother]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Suicide]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://forwardwalking.com/?p=1352</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I&#8217;m the youngest of six kids. I have two brothers&#8211;the oldest is David and the other is Sean. Sean and I didn&#8217;t get along when we were younger. Don&#8217;t get me wrong, it was nothing serious. More of a personality difference. I liked Sci-Fi, he liked sports. I wanted to watch cartoons, he wanted to [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1352&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_1358" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 490px"><a href="http://forwardwalkingdotcom2.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/smith-brothers-kids.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-1358 " alt="David, Me, and Sean" src="http://forwardwalkingdotcom2.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/smith-brothers-kids.jpg?w=480&#038;h=318" width="480" height="318" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">David, Me, and Sean</p></div>
<p>I&#8217;m the youngest of six kids. I have two brothers&#8211;the oldest is David and the other is Sean.</p>
<p>Sean and I didn&#8217;t get along when we were younger.</p>
<p>Don&#8217;t get me wrong, it was nothing serious. More of a personality difference. I liked Sci-Fi, he liked sports. I wanted to watch cartoons, he wanted to push me over and watch Rocky. As for sentimentality, Sean&#8217;s got a big heart but pretends to be a bit rough around the edges—like a Teddy bear dipped in cement.</p>
<p>One day when I was six, Sean completely reversed his role of a &#8220;big bully&#8221; brother by doing something that I&#8217;ve never forgotten—he saved my life. I was playing with some water toys at a pool, and went too far into the deep end. Not knowing how to swim, I panicked and started to splash around, crying out for help. I went under the water thinking, <em>&#8220;This is it. How could I have been so stupid?&#8221;</em></p>
<p>While underwater, I heard someone dive. Opening my eyes, I saw a figure swim towards me, reach out, and pull me up to safety. I gasped for air as my eyes focused on the person who had rescued me.</p>
<p>&#8220;Sean?&#8221; I said, disbelieving.</p>
<p>&#8220;Don&#8217;t look so surprised,&#8221; chuckled Sean. &#8220;You&#8217;re annoying, but you&#8217;re still my little brother.&#8221; He then set me down at the edge of the pool.</p>
<p>My six-year-old brain was reeling: <em>My brother Sean just saved me from drowning.</em></p>
<p>As unbelievable as it was to me then to be saved by my brother, fourteen years later Sean would save me from drowning a second time—only a different kind of drowning.</p>
<p>I was twenty years old, and I was going through hell. I had made a lot of bad choices, offended a lot of good people, lost a lot of wonderful opportunities, suffered from severe depression, and become addicted to prescription drugs. I was drowning in my life. &#8220;This is it,&#8221; I thought to myself. &#8220;How could I have been so stupid?&#8221;</p>
<p>And so, one morning early in September of 2006 I clocked out of work, and drove back to my empty house. I scribbled some notes in my journal while taking a full bottle of sleeping pills and half a bottle of pain killers. I then went into the garage, climbed into the car, and fell asleep.</p>
<p>By all accounts, I should be dead.</p>
<p>But, by some miracle, my Dad found me. He pulled me out of the car and called 911. I faded in and out of consciousness on the way to the hospital. When I got there, I remember seeing Sean&#8217;s shirt moving around the hospital. I&#8217;m sure that Sean was attached to his shirt, but under the influence of all the drugs I had taken, all I could see was his brightly-colored shirt. At one point, I remember waking up and seeing my Dad and Sean hovering over me. Sean had tears in his eyes.</p>
<p>Within a day I was released from the hospital. With the help of Sean, I hobbled from the car to my bedroom. I laid down on the king-size bed and stared up at the ceiling, contemplating how my life wasn&#8217;t any better after my failed attempt at suicide.</p>
<p>I felt Sean sit down on the other side of my bed. We sat in silence for a long time, lost in our own thoughts.</p>
<p>&#8220;You don&#8217;t have to stay here and watch me, Sean,&#8221; I quietly said. &#8220;I&#8217;ll be fine.&#8221;</p>
<p>He then said something which I&#8217;ve never forgotten:</p>
<p>&#8220;Seth, I almost lost my little brother. I&#8217;m not going anywhere.&#8221;</p>
<p>And with those words, it was as if Sean had saved me from drowning a second time. I realized how much my brother—this crusty old Teddy bear dipped in cement—cared about me, his little brother. I thought about my family (my parents, my brothers, and my sisters), and realized how much life I had—and how much life I had almost given up.</p>
<p>Sean&#8217;s words weren&#8217;t lengthy or profound, but they made me realize that my life mattered to other people; his words gave me hope to move forward in my life.</p>
<p>Now, I want to make it very clear that depression and suicide aren&#8217;t issues that are easily or instantly solved. While Sean may have rescued me from &#8220;the deep end&#8221; of the depression pool, the dangers of the water will always be there for those who linger at the pool. Some of us—through our poor choices—get too close to the deep end of depression, while others unwittingly fall into it. Some people flounder and struggle in the water longer than others. My rescue and recovery from depression were more than just a single event. It was a journey—but  that journey started with Sean&#8217;s words.</p>
<p>All of us, at some point in our lives, will wade through the waters of depression and doubt. During those difficult times, we simply cannot rescue ourselves from drowning. We all need the love and support of someone who will  reach out to us and lift us to safety.</p>
<p>Reach out to someone in your life today. Your words don&#8217;t need to be lengthy or eloquent, and you don&#8217;t need to be perfect yourself. Just reach out. For that person who is struggling, it could make all the difference in their world.</p>
<p>I will forever be grateful to my brother Sean for twice saving me from drowning.</p>
<p><em>To learn more about the author of this article, </em><a href="http://www.sethadamsmith.com/about" target="_blank"><em>please click here</em></a><em>.</em></p>
<div id="attachment_1357" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 563px"><a href="http://forwardwalkingdotcom2.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/33748_783783265069_17830570_41477502_2577677_n-e1360775810455.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1357" alt="Sean, Me, and David" src="http://forwardwalkingdotcom2.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/33748_783783265069_17830570_41477502_2577677_n-e1360775810455.jpg?w=720"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Sean, Me, and David</p></div>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1352/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1352/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1352/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1352/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1352/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1352/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1352/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1352/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1352/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1352/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1352/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1352/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1352/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1352/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1352&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://forwardwalking.com/2013/02/15/suicide-how-my-brother-saved-me-from-drowning/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>31</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://forwardwalkingdotcom2.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/smith-brothers-kids.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://forwardwalkingdotcom2.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/smith-brothers-kids.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Smith Brothers Kids</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/154ff0df301d7f599d5c0f6cdb1a765d?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">SethAdamSmith</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://forwardwalkingdotcom2.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/smith-brothers-kids.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">David, Me, and Sean</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://forwardwalkingdotcom2.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/33748_783783265069_17830570_41477502_2577677_n-e1360775810455.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Sean, Me, and David</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Horse Meat &#8211; The Hardest Thing To Digest Is That It\&#8217;s Your Fault.</title>
		<link>http://themakingprogressblues.wordpress.com/2013/02/15/horse-meat-the-hardest-thing-to-digest-is-that-its-your-fault/</link>
		<comments>http://themakingprogressblues.wordpress.com/2013/02/15/horse-meat-the-hardest-thing-to-digest-is-that-its-your-fault/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 12:22:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>thatoscarindia</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Country life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Media]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://themakingprogressblues.wordpress.com/?p=518</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[No doubt you are outraged about the horse meat scandal. You have every right to be – criminality, profiteering, potential fraud, all have led to many people eating an animal they would probably prefer to see in the 3.20 at Kempton and possibly also ingesting dangerous veterinary drugs.  However, I’m going to come at this [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=518&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>No doubt you are outraged about the horse meat scandal. You have every right to be – criminality, profiteering, potential fraud, all have led to many people eating an animal they would probably prefer to see in the 3.20 at Kempton and possibly also ingesting dangerous veterinary drugs. <a href="http://themakingprogressblues.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/findus.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-519" alt="findus" src="http://themakingprogressblues.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/findus.jpg?w=300&#038;h=225" width="300" height="225" /></a></p>
<p>However, I’m going to come at this from another angle and it’s this: it’s your own bloody fault. There you go.</p>
<p>I know, I know; you’re not happy. It’s not your fault is it? It’s the government, the supermarkets, criminals and Goodness knows who else.</p>
<p>But it’s not just them, you see. It’s you.</p>
<p>After a week of this story my patience has finally snapped, and it’s time someone told you a few home truths.</p>
<p>Many of us have been banging on for years about this stuff, trying to make you care about the need for better food labeling, about fairness for farmers, about the need to support local farms to avoid all our food coming from giant, uncaring corporate agri-businesses which churn out cheap product to feed the insatiable appetite of supermarket price-cutting.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ve been highlighting the unfairness of UK farmers being forced to meet 73 different regulations to sell to supermarkets which don’t apply to foreign suppliers, and talking about our children growing up with no understanding of food production and, more than all of this, about the way supermarkets have driven down and down and down the cost of meat to the point where people think it’s normal to buy 3lbs of beef (in burgers) for 90p.</p>
<p>And you wouldn&#8217;t listen. It was like shouting into a gale.</p>
<p>Through the years of New Labour, when farming and the countryside were demonised, you wouldn&#8217;t listen. You cheerfully chose to believe that all farmers were Rolls Royce driving aristocrats, as painted by John Prescott. You had no sympathy. You wanted a chicken for £2 and your Sunday roast for a fiver. Well, you got them didn&#8217;t you? And hundreds of farmers went to the wall. And you still didn&#8217;t care because Turkey slices were ten for 60p.</p>
<p>And now you’re furious, because it turns out that when you pay peanuts for something it’s actually not very good. Who knew eh?</p>
<p>And before you start, don’t even think about the “it’s all right for the rich who can go to local butcher’s shops but what about the poor?” line. The number of people who can’t afford adequate amounts of food is tiny – tragic and wrong, yes, but tiny. Supermarkets don’t make their billions from them hunting in the “reduced” basket, they make their money from millions of everyday folk filling a weekly trolley. You, in other words.</p>
<p>Until the mid 1990s, Britain was also full of good local abattoirs. They were run by people who knew the local farmers who used them, and the local butchers which sold the meat. They were closed in their hundreds by new health and safety regulations which made it impossible for small abattoirs to compete with giant companies doing the job more cheaply.</p>
<p>We tried to tell you, you didn&#8217;t care.</p>
<p>And of course, unlike the previous generation you were “too busy” to actually cook. You were so busy that the idea of making a meal, then making two more out of the left-overs, was like something from <i>Cider With Rosie</i> to you. You bought a meal every night. And so it had to be cheap.</p>
<p>We tried to tell you. You just pointed out that Hugh Fearnley-Whittingstall went to Eton and sneered at us.</p>
<p>Cheap rearing abroad. You didn&#8217;t care. Cheap slaughtering by machine. You didn&#8217;t care. Cheap meat full of crap and off-cuts. You didn&#8217;t care. Frozen blocks of meat off-cuts from the abattoir floor being trucked in from Poland to ensure your pack of mince was cheap enough. You didn&#8217;t care. In fact you didn&#8217;t know, but that’s because you didn&#8217;t care.</p>
<p>But we cared. We kept trying to tell you. We launched campaigns, we wrote letters, we raised funds for adverts. Nobody knows what they’re eating anymore, we said. Nobody recognises how hard it is for farmers here to produce quality meat at a price they can sell because of the supermarkets.</p>
<p>And you didn&#8217;t care.</p>
<p>Well, now you know you&#8217;ve been munching on Dobbin and his various nasty drugs, possibly for years. And now you care.</p>
<p>And yes, you&#8217;ve been misled, cheated, lied to. But you must also take some of the responsibility. You didn&#8217;t tell supermarkets you wanted quality, you just watched the ads which said “175 products cheaper at Asda this week than Tesco” and went to Asda. You made the market they sold in to, you set their priorities. They gave you what you wanted.</p>
<p>So what will you do now? Now that you care.</p>
<p>How about this&#8230;</p>
<p>Rather than just moaning at MPs why not actually think about what you eat, what you buy, where it comes from? Why not visit a farm on an open day? Take the kids, show them where their food comes from. If it’s a good farm, why not try to use your consumer power accordingly to make more farms that way? To make them viable. Why not have a think about how you could make meat go further without spending more, through cooking, and thus be able to buy good, British, assured quality meat? <a href="http://themakingprogressblues.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/46260_openfarmlogo.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-520" alt="46260_OpenFarmLogo" src="http://themakingprogressblues.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/46260_openfarmlogo.jpg?w=720"   /></a></p>
<p>If you do that, I’ll stop blaming you, and some good may come of all of this.</p>
<p>The culprits responsible for all this will be found, and no doubt tried and hopefully convicted. With luck new rules will be introduced to make a repeat harder. But the market will find a way – it always does. So long as there is a demand for vast quantities of ultra-cheap meat, people will find a way to supply it. So long as people remain uninterested in where their food comes from and how it&#8217;s made, someone will cut corners.</p>
<p>It’s a ravenous beast, the market. Like its customers, as it turns out.</p>
<p>So now that you care I&#8217;ll tell you that we&#8217;ve been highlighting the plight of dairy farmers this year; explaining how supermarkets are paying such a pittance that they can’t stay in business and milk is increasingly coming in from abroad, where standards are lower. Pleasingly people noticed. Some people. If you weren&#8217;t one, perhaps, given events, you might like to now?</p>
<p>And when you&#8217;ve done that, take a look at the video in the link below, which details the Countryside Alliance’s hard-fought campaign on country-of-origin food labeling.  Whilst you were suggesting the CA was only interested in fox hunting, it was doing this, for you, and now you know why.</p>
<p>SOS Dairy: <a href="http://www.fwi.co.uk/articles/29/12/2012/136833/sos-dairy-farmers-end-2012-with-heads-held-high.htm">http://www.fwi.co.uk/articles/29/12/2012/136833/sos-dairy-farmers-end-2012-with-heads-held-high.htm</a></p>
<p>Food labelling: <a href="http://www.countryside-alliance.org/ca/campaigns-food-farming/our-step-towards-victory-on-meat-labelling">http://www.countryside-alliance.org/ca/campaigns-food-farming/our-step-towards-victory-on-meat-labelling</a></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/518/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/518/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=518&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://themakingprogressblues.wordpress.com/2013/02/15/horse-meat-the-hardest-thing-to-digest-is-that-its-your-fault/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>394</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/11908846098d5c2a81af014a32b20aad?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">thatoscarindia</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://themakingprogressblues.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/findus.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">findus</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://themakingprogressblues.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/46260_openfarmlogo.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">46260_OpenFarmLogo</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>I’ll Take Four Burgers And A Heart Attack, Please</title>
		<link>http://carrierubin.com/2013/02/18/ill-take-four-burgers-and-a-heart-attack-please/</link>
		<comments>http://carrierubin.com/2013/02/18/ill-take-four-burgers-and-a-heart-attack-please/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2013 14:25:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Carrie Rubin</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Well-Being]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Heart Attack Grill]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lifestyle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nutrition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[obesity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[public health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social ecological model]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://carrierubin.com/?p=3105</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Is it just me, or does the following quote horrify you? “The unapologetically unhealthy restaurant . . . serves . . . 9,982-calorie ‘quadruple bypass burgers.’ (Patrons who are able to finish them are escorted to their cars in wheelchairs.) Customers who weigh over 350 pounds eat free.” Surely You Jest That quote comes from [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3105&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://carrierubin.com/2013/02/18/ill-take-four-burgers-and-a-heart-attack-please/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>297</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/0a8df8edda5b38ad558b7de24ffe2bd8?s=96&#38;d=monsterid&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">drrubin</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://carrierubin.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/quadruple.jpg?w=206" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Quadruple Bypass Burger® Image credit: heartattackgrill.com</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://carrierubin.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/social-ecological-model-21.gif?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image credit: Partners in Action (depts.washington.edu)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://carrierubin.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/nesting-dolls.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">“Hey, my sweet Oksana, some American debil finally bought those ugly babushkas!”</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Are You Listening?</title>
		<link>http://windhorseblog.wordpress.com/2013/02/15/are-you-listening/</link>
		<comments>http://windhorseblog.wordpress.com/2013/02/15/are-you-listening/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 00:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Zen Doe</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Being There]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[buddhism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[compassion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[horses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[inspiration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mindfulness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[poetry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zen]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://windhorseblog.wordpress.com/?p=204</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[At the paddock gate, stop to become horse. The whirlwind of everyday thoughts has no useful place here Leave grind-mind at the gate, as you would your shoes outside the door of the temple Listen! Listen with your fingertips, to the cold of the latch Hear with your eyes, the beads of night-dew frozen now in splendid [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=204&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>At the paddock gate, stop to become <em>horse</em>.<br />
The whirlwind of everyday thoughts has no useful place here<br />
Leave grind-mind at the gate,<br />
as you would your shoes outside the door of the temple</p>
<p>Listen! Listen with your fingertips, to the cold of the latch<br />
Hear with your eyes, the beads of night-dew frozen now in splendid prisms.</p>
<p>Listen!  Become a great wide door to the heart<br />
Inhale the sound of your boots shuffling<br />
across red clay frozen mud manure and scraps of hay<br />
taste the undulations of hills and trees<br />
dawn murmurings of frost and nascent green, waiting</p>
<p>Listen without commentary<br />
without opinion, without the need to add or take away<br />
listen to the wide sky, and to the slow breathing of the horses<br />
as they come forward, steaming breath,<br />
hearing you, in just this way</p>
<p>***************************************</p>
<p>I love this Stephen Covey quote:</p>
<blockquote><p>Most people do not listen with the intent to understand; they listen with the intent to reply.</p></blockquote>
<p>How do we listen, really?  Do we listen <em>in order to</em> judge, to dismiss, to find a point of contention?  Do we listen only well enough to gauge when a response - a grunt &#8211; is called for?  Do we listen to gather evidence that we are right and that they are wrong? Do we listen so that we can reply, or one-up the speaker?  When the sunrise speaks to us, do we compare it to another, or simply let it fill us?</p>
<p>Each of us yearns to be heard, to be understood.  How well, how deeply, do we listen?</p>
<p>To listen deeply<em> is</em> compassion.</p>
<p>Last night, considering these things and how to write about them, I went to the paddock fence.  Kit, my black and white spotted draft horse meandered over to greet me.  I often talk with the horses about writing.  No, I don&#8217;t expect answers, but they do tend to put me in a receptive mood.</p>
<p>You see, for the past millenia or two, horses have refined the art of listening far, far beyond the capacity of any human being.  They are prey animals, profoundly attuned to the slightest shift in temperature, movement, sound.  Their ability to read body language, scent, and the slightest nuance of thought, is what keeps them alive.  Horses listen.  While we&#8217;re busy anthropomorphizing about what they&#8217;re thinking, they&#8217;re simply paying attention &#8211; <em>and responding</em>, one hundred percent.</p>
<p>Kit approached the fence.  She raised her gargantuan head as though to kiss me.  She gently brushed the hair from the left side of my face, and positioned her monstrous nostril directly over my left ear, covering it.  And then, she sighed, long and slow.  She withdrew a bit, reached around to the other side of my face, and put her nose next to my right ear.  Again, she exhaled, warm and soft, and long.</p>
<p>So tempting to make something - to imagine that she was &#8220;saying&#8221; something.  So easy to create a story where Kit was sending me a particular message.  But, that would be adding frost to snow.  Perhaps better just to smile my heart wide open and receive the gift.</p>
<p>To listen, really listen, is to risk being changed by what you hear.</p>
<p><a href="http://windhorseblog.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/426060_2820485392719_1407509531_n-copy.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-238" alt="426060_2820485392719_1407509531_n - Copy" src="http://windhorseblog.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/426060_2820485392719_1407509531_n-copy.jpg?w=300&#038;h=198" width="300" height="198" /></a></p>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=204&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://windhorseblog.wordpress.com/2013/02/15/are-you-listening/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>120</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f33a0d1bb87686e8cc5e4d0066b7a4a2?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">zendoe</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://windhorseblog.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/426060_2820485392719_1407509531_n-copy.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">426060_2820485392719_1407509531_n - Copy</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>What Three Things Are Always In Your Refrigerator?</title>
		<link>http://foodandwinehedonist.com/2013/02/18/what-three-things-are-always-in-your-refrigerator/</link>
		<comments>http://foodandwinehedonist.com/2013/02/18/what-three-things-are-always-in-your-refrigerator/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2013 11:21:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>a2sicilian</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Cooking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cheese]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Home]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[italian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[locavore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shopping]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://foodandwinehedonist.com/?p=3791</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In every issue, Bon Appétit magazine features a Q&#38;A with a celebrity asking about his or her quirky food habits and favorite things to eat. Until a few years ago, it had always included this question: “What three things are always in your refrigerator?” I was intrigued by that question and was bummed when they [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3791&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In every issue, Bon Appétit magazine features a Q&amp;A with a celebrity asking about his or her quirky food habits and favorite things to eat. Until a few years ago, it had always included this question: “What three things are always in your refrigerator?” I was intrigued by that question and was bummed when they stopped asking it.  The decision may have been made because celebrity refrigerators sometimes aren’t very interesting—I remember several saying the one thing that’s always in their refrigerator is a bottle of champagne. Bor-ing. (Next to the leftover smoked salmon pizza from Spago, right?)</p>
<p>I still think it’s a cool question, as it lends interesting insight into a person’s tastes and cooking styles. If I were to answer, I’d say things like good European cheeses, lemons, and fresh herbs including thyme, cilantro, and basil. Still, I realize those answers aren’t particularly exciting and are a little predictable. So I thought I’d take this exercise a little farther and highlight three things in my refrigerator that are slightly unique yet surely staples of The Sicilian’s diet:</p>
<p><strong>Pecorino Romano Cheese.</strong> Our family absolutely loves this cheese, and it is always in my refrigerator. It has pushed aside Parmigiano-Reggiano (considered by the Italians as the king of cheeses) to become our family favorite. (And it’s less expensive than authentic Parmigiano-Reggiano, too.)</p>
<p>Always made from sheep’s milk (“pecora” means “sheep” in Italian), Pecorino Romano is hard, sharp, and salty with just a tiny hint of musk, yet without the heaviness of a cow’s milk cheese. It is made primarily on the island of Sardinia, just off Sicily (apparently my affinity for it is in my genes!). It was also a staple of soldiers’ diets in ancient Rome. It is absolutely wonderful grated on pasta, or on sautéed or roasted broccoli, or on freshly made kale chips. My family loves a dish I make with rigatoni, Italian chicken or turkey sausage, sliced hot peppers, and kale that I braise in a sauté of garlic, thyme, fennel seed and chicken broth, topped with grated Pecorino Romano. My favorite comfort food in the whole world is spaghetti topped with marinara sauce, toasted pine nuts, and Pecorino Romano.  I’m telling you, once you go Pecorino Romano, you won’t go back. <img src='http://s1.wp.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif' alt=';)' class='wp-smiley' /> </p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://foodandwinehedonist.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/photo11.jpg"><img class="wp-image aligncenter" id="i-3794" alt="Image" src="http://foodandwinehedonist.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/photo11.jpg?w=510&#038;h=383" width="510" height="383" /></a></p>
<p><span style="color:#ffffff;">food</span></p>
<p><strong>The Redheads Hummus.</strong> A few years ago, I was with a friend (who happens to be very health conscious and fit), perusing the appetizers list at a downtown Ann Arbor restaurant. “How about we split some hummus with veggies and pita chips?,” I suggested. She flashed the mischievous grin of someone about to say something controversial. “You know, I just don’t ‘get’ hummus,” she said. Wow. Even my Dad will eat hummus.</p>
<p>Yet I kinda know what she means. At some point hummus replaced the Lipton’s French Onion and Frito Lay Bean dips of our parents’ generation as a “healthy alternative,” but the store-bought versions are often so bland you might as well eat spackling. So how did hummus get so ubiquitous? So we can say at least we’re not eating Frito Lay Bean Dip? If I make my own I add plenty of lemon juice and season it adequately, but I can never leave store-bought hummus alone. I find myself adding lemon juice, or capers, or chipotle hot sauce, or just about anything I can conjure up in the fridge to give it some flavor. Until I met the Redheads, which is an interesting hummus hybrid:</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://foodandwinehedonist.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/photo10.jpg"><img class="wp-image aligncenter" id="i-3796" alt="Image" src="http://foodandwinehedonist.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/photo10.jpg?w=381&#038;h=508" width="381" height="508" /></a></p>
<p><span style="color:#ffffff;">Locavore</span></p>
<p>Produced by two cute redheads (of course) in Lake Leelanau, Michigan, <span style="text-decoration:underline;"><a title="The Redheads" href="http://www.redheadsinc.com/" target="_blank">The Redheads</a></span> hummus is pretty addictive. “Made With Many Organic Ingredients,” it says on the label, including the typical garbanzo beans, extra virgin olive oil, lemon juice, and tahini, but it gets an extra kick of umami from “organic gluten free tamari.” The product is currently only sold in Michigan, and in Ann Arbor it can be found at  Whole Foods Market, Peoples’ Food Coop, and Arbor Farms Market, and can also  be ordered online and FedExed to your home. Flavors include garlic, pesto, sundried, and cherry chipotle. And admittedly, I don’t ALWAYS have it in my refrigerator, but the Redheads are good Michigan girls and deserve a shout-out.</p>
<p><span style="color:#ffffff;">health</span></p>
<p><strong>Roasted Walnut Oil.</strong> For as long as I can remember, I’ve been making salad dressings with extra-virgin olive oil, and only extra-virgin olive oil. No matter whether the acid in the dressing was lemon juice or balsamic, cider, red wine, or sherry vinegar, the oil was always extra virgin olive. And then I was introduced to roasted walnut oil by Ann Arbor personal<span style="text-decoration:underline;"> <a title="chef Karen Eddy" href="http://www.a2chef.com/" target="_blank">chef Karen Eddy</a></span>, when she helped me host a dinner in my home, and a whole new world of salad possibilities opened up. And bonus—it’s a good source of Omega-3 fatty acids. Oils can vary widely in quality depending on brand, so I recommend the La Tourangelle brand:</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://foodandwinehedonist.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/photo12.jpg"><img class="wp-image aligncenter" id="i-3798" alt="Image" src="http://foodandwinehedonist.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/photo12.jpg?w=381&#038;h=508" width="381" height="508" /></a></p>
<p><span style="color:#ffffff;">healthy eating</span></p>
<p>Roasted walnut oil offers  such a warm depth of flavor, you can drizzle a little on some salad greens with a few splashes of vinegar and some generous grinds of black pepper and salt, and you’ve got a quick salad for lunch. For a little more effort, make a dressing of it with a little Dijon mustard, balsamic or sherry vinegar, some finely minced shallot, salt and pepper. Toss it with greens and some crumbled blue cheese or goat cheese, add some toasted walnuts, maybe some dried cranberries. I still go through large bottles of extra virgin olive oil in no time, but roasted walnut oil is always in my refrigerator (this delicate oil would go rancid in the cupboard next to the olive oil).</p>
<p><strong>So what are three interesting staples of your diet in your refrigerator? Any weird ones out there? Fess up, and leave your three things in the comments section below.</strong></p>
<p>Happy noshing,</p>
<div id="attachment_1701" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 140px"><a href="http://foodandwinehedonist.files.wordpress.com/2012/03/sicilian1.jpeg"><img class=" wp-image-1701  " alt="The Sicilian" src="http://foodandwinehedonist.files.wordpress.com/2012/03/sicilian1.jpeg?w=130&#038;h=144" width="130" height="144" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The Sicilian</p></div>
<p><span style="color:#ffffff;">cooking</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#ffffff;">home</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#ffffff;">family</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#ffffff;">Food</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#ffffff;">Blogging</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#ffffff;">Writing blogging</span></p>
<p><span style="color:#ffffff;">Blogging</span></p>
<p><strong><em>Coming this Friday (Feb 22nd) &#8211; Special Guest Post!  - The Hedonist</em></strong></p>
<p><span style="color:#ffffff;">blogging </span></p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3791/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3791/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3791&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://foodandwinehedonist.com/2013/02/18/what-three-things-are-always-in-your-refrigerator/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>91</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://foodandwinehedonist.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/photo11.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://foodandwinehedonist.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/photo11.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">photo(11)</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/0f045d3e7f5e5de0b2541e5186d9497d?s=96&#38;d=wavatar&#38;r=X" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">a2sicilian</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://foodandwinehedonist.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/photo11.jpg?w=630" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://foodandwinehedonist.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/photo10.jpg?w=470" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://foodandwinehedonist.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/photo12.jpg?w=470" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Image</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://foodandwinehedonist.files.wordpress.com/2012/03/sicilian1.jpeg?w=272" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The Sicilian</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Russian Meteor Could Be Pope Resignation Conspiracy, but I Prefer Science</title>
		<link>http://mjwrightnz.wordpress.com/2013/02/18/russian-meteor-could-be-pope-resignation-conspiracy-but-i-prefer-science/</link>
		<comments>http://mjwrightnz.wordpress.com/2013/02/18/russian-meteor-could-be-pope-resignation-conspiracy-but-i-prefer-science/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2013 05:26:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Matthew Wright</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Environment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Satire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Astronomy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[climate]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Current events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humour]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[meteor strike]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Science fiction]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mjwrightnz.wordpress.com/?p=21410</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It was one of those awful coincidences. Last Friday evening I was having a few beers with a friend, in a local pub. He was calculating the likely impact energy if 2012 DA14 &#8211; due to make a close pass over Indonesia &#8211; were to ever hit us. There are websites with Java script that [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=21410&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>It was one of those awful coincidences. Last Friday evening I was having a few beers with a friend, in a local pub. He was calculating the likely impact energy if 2012 DA14 &#8211; due to make a close pass over Indonesia &#8211; were to ever hit us.</h3>
<div id="attachment_19301" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 410px"><a href="http://mjwrightnz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/wright_earth.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-19301" alt="Earth. An image I made with my Celestia installation (cool, free, science package)." src="http://mjwrightnz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/wright_earth.jpg?w=720"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Earth. An image I made with my Celestia installation (cool, free, science package).</p></div>
<p>There are websites with Java script that do this, but it’s easy yourself if you have figures for velocity and mass –  a function of volume and density – plus the formula and a calculator. (Yes, I know it had been published, but it&#8217;s fun to do the math. I&#8217;m a geek and so are my friends. Remember&#8230;geeks won&#8230;.)</p>
<p>Nobody realised another object was about to explode over Chelyabinsk &#8211; &#8216;Tankograd&#8217; of Second World War fame.</p>
<p>The 1200 injured from flying glass is the largest human toll recorded from a meteor strike. The cost to Russia will be in the millions of roubles. Not to mention the fact that thousands of people are facing sub-zero temperatures in windowless homes, until they can be fixed.</p>
<p>All that because the Pope resigned. Well, it&#8217;s obvious. The Conspirating Ruling Archaic Poodles, a secret cabal nobody has ever heard of, used their stooges to drop one of their orbiting Bombs Utilising Low Level Seekrit Hyper Invisible Termination on the Vatican, thus covering up the Pope’s resignation, but because secret organisations always make basic arithmetical errors, it hit Russia instead. I have proof this is true, because they fly in invisible black helicopters. Well, have you seen one? Quite. Proves they exist&#8230;</p>
<p>And yes, I know that is a really, really stupid theory&#8230;but hey, it&#8217;s <a href="http://www.infowars.com/did-russia-shoot-down-meteor/" target="_blank">not the dumbest one out there</a>.</p>
<p>Needless to say, the science involved actually answers all questions. First off &#8211; the energy involved is mind-blowing on the scale of us mere humans.</p>
<p>How mind blowing? Try this. The Russian rock was maybe 10,000 tonnes mass and 17 metres diameter, by NASA estimate. Yet still exploded with an energy equivalent, some estimates suggest, of around 500,000 tons of TNT. How come?</p>
<p>Well, it’s entirely to do with kinetic energy, which you calculate according to the formula 1/2 MV&lt;exp&gt;2.  It was moving at over 63,000 km/h when it hit the atmosphere. That gave it a kinetic energy (roughly) of around 500,000,000,000,000 joules. Translated into human terms, that&#8217;s what a 1-kilowatt fan heater would emit if run constantly for<strong> 15,844 years</strong> (it would run out in about March in that last year).</p>
<p>That&#8217;s a lot of energy. So why did it explode? At the speed this sucker hit us, it was moving so fast it couldn&#8217;t push the atmosphere out of the way. The air was compressed ahead of it, got super-hot, and then began vapourising the front side of the meteor. But the back side was still ice-cold. After a while, differential thermal stresses exceeded the tensile strength of the object – and boom! A lot of the kinetic energy translated into a massive shock wave, shattering glass over that huge area, and powerful enough to be detected in Alaska. Some became heat. Some was retained in the fragments of meteor that hurtled into the ground, which will be found sooner or later (they&#8217;re looking now).</p>
<p>The take-home lesson from Friday? The odds of a damaging meteor hitting us, by human time-spans, are low . But these things do happen. And we didn’t see this one coming despite a determined effort of late to detect everything in our vicinity that might be a threat. We’ve even found the S-1VB stage from Apollo 12, which is lobbing around in a weird orbit nearby. But Friday’s rock – still a city-buster – was too small.</p>
<div id="attachment_21417" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://mjwrightnz.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/636px-jupiter_showing_sl9_impact_sites.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-21417" alt="A Hubble picture of Jupiter after it had been machine-gunned by Comet Shoemaker-Levy in 1994. NASA, public domain, via Wikipedia." src="http://mjwrightnz.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/636px-jupiter_showing_sl9_impact_sites.jpg?w=300&#038;h=283" width="300" height="283" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">A Hubble picture of Jupiter after it had been machine-gunned by Comet Shoemaker-Levy in 1994. NASA, public domain, via Wikipedia.</p></div>
<p>Worse, even if we had seen it, there was nothing we could have done.  The laws of physics are clear; Bruce Willis and a gang of Texan oil-riggers aren’t going to save the day at the last moment. <a title="Forget the Mayan rubbish – this is the REAL astro-apocalypse. Now." href="http://mjwrightnz.wordpress.com/2012/12/16/forget-the-mayan-rubbish-this-is-the-real-astro-apocalypse-now/">I’ve explained why in an earlier post </a>– check it out. Even if you could carry enough rocket fuel to get to an incoming rock and blow it up (which you can’t….trust me…) most of the bits will still hit the Earth with the same net kinetic energy. And it&#8217;s that energy that&#8217;s the problem.</p>
<p>That doesn’t mean we can’t find ways of handling it. Given decades of warning,  even spray-painting the side of a space rock black will work, by changing the way it re-radiates solar energy, asymmetrically. Over years, that will change the orbit.</p>
<p>Of course, space debris usually isn&#8217;t isolated. A comet can break up, leaving trails of objects following its original orbit. Jupiter was slammed by just such a train &#8216;o doom  in 1994. There&#8217;s a fair chance that we might have to try and deflect half a dozen potential impactors all at once.</p>
<p>Personally I’m not going to lose sleep over it. No point worrying about things we can’t control. And the prospect of being slammed by a space rock is pretty far down the list. Here in New Zealand, for instance, it’s more likely we’ll be hit by an earthquake – in fact, there was a small one in my city on Saturday and another tremor this morning.</p>
<p>What’s your take? Should we worry about that which we cannot control? Or get on with life?</p>
<p><em>Copyright © Matthew Wright 2013</em></p>
<p>‘<strong>Kindness 2013’</strong> returns next week. <strong>Coming up this week</strong>: more sixty-second writing tips, Write It Now part 6 – and more.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/21410/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/21410/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=21410&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://mjwrightnz.wordpress.com/2013/02/18/russian-meteor-could-be-pope-resignation-conspiracy-but-i-prefer-science/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>53</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/a1b9f8718bcd5d6f844d6c888fbb7531?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mjwrightnz</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mjwrightnz.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/wright_earth.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Earth. An image I made with my Celestia installation (cool, free, science package).</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mjwrightnz.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/636px-jupiter_showing_sl9_impact_sites.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">A Hubble picture of Jupiter after it had been machine-gunned by Comet Shoemaker-Levy in 1994. NASA, public domain, via Wikipedia.</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Trustworthy Voices</title>
		<link>http://justabovesunset.wordpress.com/2013/02/17/trustworthy-voices/</link>
		<comments>http://justabovesunset.wordpress.com/2013/02/17/trustworthy-voices/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2013 04:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Alan</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Economic Confidence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Economic Fairness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Economic Recovery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Minimum Wage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion Journalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thomas Friedman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Billionaires for Human Sacrifice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Columnists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Conventional Wisdom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[First Amendment Rights]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Freedom of the Press]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Friedman Unit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Grand Bargain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[How to Unparalyze Us]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Informed Citizens]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mass Marketing of Misinformation on Economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion Columnists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Paul Krugman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Raising the Minimum Wage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reform That Cuts Taxes For The Rich And Corporations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rise of Western Democracies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Slow the Growth of Both Social Security and Medicare Entitlements]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Rights of Man and the Citizen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Who to Trust]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://justabovesunset.wordpress.com/?p=19167</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The eighteenth century gave us lots of things – like Mozart and the steam engine and the guillotine – but it also gave us modern democracies. Monarchies would no longer do. Thanks to Rousseau and others, there was new talk of the rights of man and the citizen – as opposed to the divine or hereditary [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=19167&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">The eighteenth century gave us lots of things – like Mozart and the steam engine and the guillotine – but it also gave us modern democracies. Monarchies would no longer do. Thanks to Rousseau and others, there was new talk of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Declaration_of_the_Rights_of_Man_and_of_the_Citizen" target="_blank">the rights of man and the citizen</a> – as opposed to the divine or hereditary or de facto rights of any king or queen. Citizens could run any country just as well, or better, than some loopy king – they had their own interests in mind and, in charge, would make decisions for the common good. The whim or greed of personal issues of one man would no longer determine day-to-day life for everyone else.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">That&#8217;s how things should be, so the French beheaded their king and queen, and quite a few others, and over here, we also decided we could run this place ourselves – we needed no king at all. Eventually even the British worked out a system where their king or queen at any given moment didn&#8217;t matter much at all. Their monarchs, and all those subordinate peers of the realm, became revered and respected curiosities, like fine old furniture. The House of Lords retained some power for a time, but it eventually became no more than a collection of loveable eccentrics, if you like fox hunting. All the action was in the House of Commons, and the Prime Minister, chosen by the majority party in the House of Commons, administered the affairs of the nation, with the king or queen&#8217;s blessing, which was, eventually, no more than a formality. Other western nations worked out analogous arrangements and Western Democracy was born. Now and then a dictator would arise, assuming monarchial powers, but each of those came to a bad end – like Mussolini hung dead by his heels. Citizens there had had enough of him. Here, George Washington stepped down after two terms. He didn&#8217;t want the presidency to be anything other than a temporary position of trust, granted by the citizens. He knew the age of kings was over. The world had changed.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">There was only one problem with this. It became everyone&#8217;s duty to become an informed citizen – that&#8217;s the only way a democracy works. Otherwise you&#8217;d have chaos – folks voting for nonsense because they really didn&#8217;t know a damned thing about the issues at hand. Yes, we don&#8217;t have a direct democracy, where we each vote on every little thing, but in our representative republic we do vote for those who we think will represent our own interests and the general interests of the nation. You have to know something about the issues, at least in a broad sense, to choose the man or woman to send to Washington to do the right thing. You also have to have a sense of what the right thing might be.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">That&#8217;s hard to come by. That&#8217;s the reason the very first amendment to the Constitution establishes an almost absolute right of free speech, and assures a free press, and keeps religion off to the side, as not an official function of government. All issues can be aired openly – no one is told to shut up, unless they&#8217;re shouting fire in a crowded theater. The press can present all the relevant facts, or what they see as relevant facts, as long as they don&#8217;t lie or commit slander or libel. They can even publish government secrets in some cases, because some of what is secret is no more than what&#8217;s embarrassing and what everyone really needs to know. The <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pentagon_Papers" target="_blank">case of the Pentagon Papers</a> comes to mind – in the end, the press had a First Amendment right to publish information significant to all of us understanding our own government&#8217;s policies, even if they weren&#8217;t pretty – or maybe precisely because they weren&#8217;t pretty. As for those walking around muttering about what God really wants the government to do, because God told them so, such folks are a dime a dozen and seldom agree with each other, and God&#8217;s not exactly parting the clouds and verifying which of them got it right and which of them was having auditory hallucinations. Nothing can be verified. What such folks say is always interesting, but it&#8217;s never that useful. The original agreement was to put that God stuff off to the side. Absolutist talk about the will of God was what got us into trouble in the first place. Kings talked that way.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">That leaves us all with a need to know something about the issues of the day, at least in a broad sense, so we can decide what the right thing to do might be – and then elect an appropriate mayor or governor or congressman or senator or president to do just that. It&#8217;s just that there are endless people telling you what the right thing to do is, and you have to listen to them, because no citizen has the time or energy or even the inclination to do the necessary research. There&#8217;s the job and the wife and kids and the bills to pay and all the rest, and no one&#8217;s a combination economist and political scientist and historian. Someone had to do the grunt work for us, and distill it all down into a form we can understand, rather quickly. The cable news folks purport to do that for us – some watch Fox News to get a sense of what&#8217;s up, and what might be the right thing to do about it. Bill O&#8217;Reilly and Sean Hannity and the rest will tell you that. Others turn to MSNBC for the same – Rachel Maddow or Ed Schultz might do that, even if Chris Matthews is useless. CNN won&#8217;t tell you anything except on Sunday morning, if then. Fareed Zakaria digs deep and explains things clearly. The nightly broadcast news is useless – a quick skim of what&#8217;s hot but little more.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">There&#8217;s talk radio too, with Rush Limbaugh, and wherever Glenn Beck is hanging out these days. Those two are fiery but a bit absurd, or an acquired taste – but there are also the major columnists. The problem there is the issue of reliability. Paul Krugman is an actual economist, with a Nobel Prize and everything – he deals with actual data and verified statistical trends – but on the conservative side, Charles Krauthammer is a former psychiatrist of all things, and George Will is simply a sour and prissy conservative who stuck around for years. They bring little to the table, other than strong opinions based on… strong opinions. William Kristol is the most amusing – the editor of the Weekly Standard and the man who said the Iraq War would be a breeze, and that the whole idea that the Sunni and Shia wouldn&#8217;t get along sheer nonsense, and who was the man behind convincing John McCain that Sarah Palin was wonderful and would assure McCain&#8217;s election. Kristol is still taken seriously for some reason, at least at Fox News – but then they also trot out Karl Rove and just hired Herman Cain. Where citizens turn to find out what&#8217;s what is a minefield.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">What citizens get is either polemic or very conventional wisdom, which is seldom wisdom at all. The master of that is <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thomas_Friedman" target="_blank">Thomas Friedman</a> of the New York Times, whose most popular book is <a title="The World Is Flat" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_World_Is_Flat" target="_blank">The World Is Flat</a> – several hundred pages of the obvious on globalization. He does know the Middle East, but even there tends to state the obvious, and then there&#8217;s the once-famous <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Friedman_Unit" target="_blank">Friedman Unit</a> – a term first coined by Duncan Black on May 21, 2006. You see, a Friedman is a unit of time equal to six months. It has to do with the Iraq War, and how things might turn out – &#8220;the next six months&#8221; was the period in which, according to Friedman, &#8220;we&#8217;re going to find out… whether a decent outcome is possible.&#8221; Friedman made these six-month predictions for two and a half years, actually at least fourteen different times. It became a running joke. Any time anyone said &#8220;the next six months will be critical,&#8221; or said &#8220;just wait six months,&#8221; everyone would smile and say, &#8220;Ah, a Friedman Unit, an FU, as it were.&#8221; On the other hand, the &#8220;the newspaper of record&#8221; paid him for such analysis.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">You might also remember <a href="http://atrios.blogspot.com/2007_08_12_archive.html" target="_blank">how he initially felt about that war</a> as he explained to Charlie Rose on PBS:<br />
</span></p>
<p style="margin-left:36pt;"><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">I think it [the invasion of Iraq] was unquestionably worth doing, Charlie. … We needed to go over there, basically, um, and um, uh, take out a very big state right in the heart of that world and burst that bubble, and there was only one way to do it. … What they needed to see was American boys and girls going house to house, from Basra to Baghdad, um and basically saying, &#8220;Which part of this sentence don&#8217;t you understand?&#8221; You don&#8217;t think, you know, we care about our open society, you think this bubble fantasy, that we&#8217;re just gonna to let it grow? Well Suck. On. This. Okay.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">That was crude and brutal, and made no geopolitical sense, or moral sense, but that&#8217;s what everyone was feeling at the time. That&#8217;s what he offers. What he thinks everyone is thinking, because he thinks it, and it&#8217;s usually true – and the opposite of useful insight. He&#8217;s a mirror, not a searchlight. A few years later he said <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2007/09/30/opinion/30friedman.html" target="_blank">9/11 Is Over</a> and he was just wrong about America&#8217;s need to break down doors from Basra to Baghdad for widespread fellatio by force, because sexual violation and dominance via oral rape was America&#8217;s moral right and in our self-interest. He didn&#8217;t say he&#8217;d been wrong – just that time had passed and there were other things we could do now.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">That might make Friedman seems like a moral monster, but he&#8217;s still chatting with Charlie Rose and writing columns for the New York Times. He also has changed his ways. His latest is <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/02/17/opinion/sunday/friedman-how-to-unparalyze-us.html?pagewanted=all" target="_blank">How to Unparalyze Us</a> – about political gridlock in Washington and the debt crisis and economics and entitlements – which is not his area of expertise at all. It doesn&#8217;t matter. He makes his arguments:<br />
</span></p>
<p style="margin-left:36pt;"><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">Apple is currently sitting on $137 billion of cash in the bank. There are many reasons Apple has not spent its cash hoard, but I&#8217;ll bet anything that one of them is the uncertain economic and tax environment in this country. Think about how much better we&#8217;d all be if Apple, and the many other companies sitting on cash, felt confident enough in the future to spend it. These are the most dynamic companies in the world. They don&#8217;t need any government help to innovate.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">Does that seem right? Dean Baker at the Center for Economics and Policy Research calls this <a href="http://www.cepr.net/index.php/blogs/beat-the-press/its-sunday-and-thomas-friedman-is-abusing-economics-again" target="_blank">mass marketing of misinformation on economics</a>:<br />
</span></p>
<p style="margin-left:36pt;"><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">Okay, Apple is so uncertain about the economic and tax environment in the U.S. that they don&#8217;t invest. (Funny how that works since they sell largely to a world market of which the U.S. is a substantial part, but not the majority.)<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">Friedman goes on to say this:<br />
</span></p>
<p style="margin-left:36pt;"><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">Message: There is no doubt our economy is primarily being held back by the deleveraging and drop in demand that resulted from the 2008 financial crisis. But they are being reinforced today by uncertainty and worry that we do not have our political house in order and, therefore, our tax, regulatory, pension and entitlement frameworks are all in play. So businesses, investors and consumers all hold back just enough for us not to be able to move the growth and employment meters with any robust momentum.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">The whole idea is that the way to get the economy moving again is with a &#8220;grand bargain&#8221; that &#8220;slows the growth of both Social Security and Medicare entitlements&#8221; along with &#8220;reform&#8221; that cuts taxes for the rich and corporations. Friedman says that even a cab driver would know this, but Baker, the actual economist here, is having none of it:<br />
</span></p>
<p style="margin-left:36pt;"><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">Okay, let&#8217;s imagine that one of Friedman&#8217;s cab drivers had access to the Internet and could go to the National Income and Product Accounts that the Commerce Department posts. The cab driver would explain to Friedman that investment in equipment and software is actually pretty healthy. Measured as a share of GDP it is almost back to its pre-recession level. Furthermore, apart from the tech bubble days of the late 90s it has never been much higher than it is today. …<br />
</span></p>
<p style="margin-left:36pt;"><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">In short there is no reason to expect investment to be much higher than it is currently. It doesn&#8217;t appear that uncertainty is very important in this picture.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="margin-left:36pt;"><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">Friedman&#8217;s cab driver would then explain to him that he is also wrong about consumption. Consumers are actually spending at a high rate relative to their income, not the low rate he seems to believe. …<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">Baker has tables and graphs that document this, with details, but notes Friedman also offers this:<br />
</span></p>
<p style="margin-left:36pt;"><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">Our choice today is not &#8220;austerity&#8221; versus &#8220;no austerity&#8221; – that is a straw man argument offered by both extremes. It&#8217;s about whether we phase in – in the least painful way possible – a long-term plan that balances our need to protect the most vulnerable in this generation while funding the most opportunities for the next generation, and still creating growth. We can&#8217;t protect both generations in full anymore, but we must not sacrifice one for the other – favoring nursing homes over nursery schools – and that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re on track to do.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">Baker:<br />
</span></p>
<p style="margin-left:36pt;"><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">You have to love the line:<br />
</span></p>
<p style="margin-left:36pt;"><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">&#8220;We can&#8217;t protect both generations in full anymore.&#8221;<br />
</span></p>
<p style="margin-left:36pt;"><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">Somehow Friedman missed the fact that the problem we are facing is a lack of demand. We need people to spend more not less. How does austerity reduce unemployment and get the economy back to full employment? It hasn&#8217;t worked in Ireland, Greece, Spain, the United Kingdom or anywhere else that can be identified. How on earth does the fact that we now face a huge gap in demand mean that we are less well-situated to &#8220;protect both generations.&#8221; (Of course he doesn&#8217;t say anything about income distribution.)<br />
</span></p>
<p style="margin-left:36pt;"><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">Again, if Friedman could be taught some intro economics it would be hugely helpful here. Suppose Friedman gets his wish for a grand bargain and everyone working today knew that they would be seeing sharply lower Social Security and Medicare benefits in the future. All of those consumers who Friedman thinks are paralyzed by uncertainty will suddenly realize that they can be certain that they will need more money to support themselves in retirement because the Thomas Friedmans of the world have taken away their Social Security and Medicare.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">Friedman is writing nonsense again, of the moral-monster sort actually, and Dave Johnson at Seeing the Forest <a href="http://seeingtheforest.com/tom-friedman-explains-the-problem-with-the-economy/" target="_blank">adds this</a>:<br />
</span></p>
<p style="margin-left:36pt;"><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">You see, the problem isn&#8217;t high unemployment leaving people out of the economy, resulting in businesses not having enough customers coming in the door. That is not the reason businesses don&#8217;t feel confident enough to expand and hire.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="margin-left:36pt;"><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">And the budget problem isn&#8217;t because Bush doubled the military budget after Reagan did the same, after cutting taxes on the rich… And never mind that the budget didn&#8217;t have a deficit before those things… And never mind that they said they were &#8220;cutting the government&#8217;s allowance&#8221; and &#8220;starving the beast&#8221; in order to manufacture a deficit crisis so they could scare people into cutting the things we do to make our lives better. Never mind that they said that was the plan…<br />
</span></p>
<p style="margin-left:36pt;"><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">The real problem with our economy is that regular working people have too much, and the wealthy and their corporate masks have too little.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="margin-left:36pt;"><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">And we need a &#8220;Grand Bargain&#8221; imposed on us from the top, instead of just going with the results of the election we just had or all of the polls in which people said they want JOBS, higher taxes on the wealthy and corporations, military spending decreased, and better retirement and health care packages for regular people…<br />
</span></p>
<p style="margin-left:36pt;"><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">Tom Friedman thinks the wealthy people at the top should be making the decisions, not the people. Surely anyone can see the wisdom in that, right?<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">Right, and <a href="http://www.nndb.com/people/525/000022459/" target="_blank">don&#8217;t forget this</a>:<br />
</span></p>
<p style="margin-left:36pt;"><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">Thomas L. Friedman is a three-time Pulitzer Prize recipient for The New York Times. In 1978 he married an heiress to a fortune in shopping mall properties, and her $3-billion makes the Friedmans one of America&#8217;s wealthiest families.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">One blogger put the whole thing this way – <a href="http://digbysblog.blogspot.com/2013/02/another-billionaire-calls-for-human.html" target="_blank">Another Billionaire Calls for Human Sacrifice</a> – but that may be too harsh, or maybe not. Friedman and his fellow plutocrats argue that raising the minimum wage would hurt business, deepening the recession, but Paul Krugman, the economist, says <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/02/18/opinion/krugman-raise-that-wage.html?hp&amp;_r=0" target="_blank">that&#8217;s not so</a>:<br />
</span></p>
<p style="margin-left:36pt;"><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">First of all, the current level of the minimum wage is very low by any reasonable standard. For about four decades, increases in the minimum wage have consistently fallen behind inflation, so that in real terms the minimum wage is substantially lower than it was in the 1960s. Meanwhile, worker productivity has doubled. Isn&#8217;t it time for a raise?<br />
</span></p>
<p style="margin-left:36pt;"><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">Now, you might argue that even if the current minimum wage seems low, raising it would cost jobs. But there&#8217;s evidence on that question &#8211; lots and lots of evidence, because the minimum wage is one of the most studied issues in all of economics. U.S. experience, it turns out, offers many &#8220;natural experiments&#8221; here, in which one state raises its minimum wage while others do not. And while there are dissenters, as there always are, the great preponderance of the evidence from these natural experiments points to little if any negative effect of minimum wage increases on employment.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="margin-left:36pt;"><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">Why is this true? That&#8217;s a subject of continuing research, but one theme in all the explanations is that workers aren&#8217;t bushels of wheat or even Manhattan apartments; they&#8217;re human beings, and the human relationships involved in hiring and firing are inevitably more complex than markets for mere commodities. And one byproduct of this human complexity seems to be that modest increases in wages for the least-paid don&#8217;t necessarily reduce the number of jobs.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="margin-left:36pt;"><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">What this means, in turn, is that the main effect of a rise in minimum wages is a rise in the incomes of hard-working but low-paid Americans &#8211; which is, of course, what we&#8217;re trying to accomplish.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">And it should go without saying that thinking of workers as bushels of wheat or Manhattan apartments is moral monster territory. It&#8217;s just that this won&#8217;t happen:<br />
</span></p>
<p style="margin-left:36pt;"><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">So Mr. Obama&#8217;s wage proposal is good economics. It&#8217;s also good politics: a wage increase is supported by an overwhelming majority of voters, including a strong majority of self-identified Republican women (but not men). Yet GOP leaders in Congress are opposed to any rise. Why? They say that they&#8217;re concerned about the people who might lose their jobs, never mind the evidence that this won&#8217;t actually happen. But this isn&#8217;t credible.<br />
</span></p>
<p style="margin-left:36pt;"><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">For today&#8217;s Republican leaders clearly feel disdain for low-wage workers. Bear in mind that such workers, even if they work full time, by and large don&#8217;t pay income taxes (although they pay plenty in payroll and sales taxes), while they may receive benefits like Medicaid and food stamps. And you know what this makes them, in the eyes of the GOP &#8211; &#8220;takers,&#8221; members of the contemptible 47 percent who, as Mitt Romney said to nods of approval, won&#8217;t take responsibility for their own lives.<br />
</span></p>
<p><span style="color:black;font-family:Tahoma;font-size:10pt;">There you have it. This has nothing to do with the economics, or the particular issues at hand. It&#8217;s kind of abstract, in a moral way, or an immoral way. Yes, it is everyone&#8217;s duty to become an informed citizen – that&#8217;s the only way a democracy works. Otherwise you&#8217;d have chaos – folks voting for nonsense, or voting for those who will vote for nonsense, because they really didn&#8217;t know a damned thing about the issue at hand. And we have columnists, and the cable news folks, explaining things they don&#8217;t quite understand, so we understand those things just as badly as they do. No one expected this. We just wanted no more kings – but nothing is ever simple.</span></p>
<p><a href="http://justabovesunset.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/getoveryourself.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-19181" alt="GetOverYourself" src="http://justabovesunset.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/getoveryourself.jpg?w=300&#038;h=300" width="300" height="300" /></a></p>
<br />  <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=19167&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://justabovesunset.wordpress.com/2013/02/17/trustworthy-voices/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>9</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/ff8da738a3dacb21b278b6dac6e2ca39?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">justabovesunset</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://justabovesunset.files.wordpress.com/2013/02/getoveryourself.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">GetOverYourself</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
