<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
	<atom:link href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	<description>Just another Wordpress.com weblog</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 21:02:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>
<cloud domain='freshlypressed.wordpress.com' port='80' path='/?rsscloud=notify' registerProcedure='' protocol='http-post' />
<image>
		<url>http://s2.wp.com/i/buttonw-com.png</url>
		<title>FreshlyPressed</title>
		<link>http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com</link>
	</image>
	<atom:link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/osd.xml" title="FreshlyPressed" />
	<atom:link rel='hub' href='http://freshlypressed.wordpress.com/?pushpress=hub'/>
		<item>
		<title>Influenza and You (And the Spanish Flu, Too)</title>
		<link>http://other-nations.com/2012/12/04/a-z-of-weird-animals-part-i-influenza-and-you-and-the-spanish-flu-too/</link>
		<comments>http://other-nations.com/2012/12/04/a-z-of-weird-animals-part-i-influenza-and-you-and-the-spanish-flu-too/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2012 21:40:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Neil Griffin</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[A-Z of Weird Animals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Humans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[american history]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[environment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[epidemics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[history]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[influenza]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pandemic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spanish flu]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[viruses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WWI]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://other-nations.com/?p=189</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I apologize for the absence of a post on Sunday. It&#8217;s the end of semester, so everything&#8217;s getting a bit hairy. Part I: The Spanish Flu I had a little bird Its name was Enza, I opened the window, and in-flu-enza. On March 4th, 1918, an unnamed soldier stationed at Camp Funston, a US army [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=189&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://other-nations.com/2012/12/04/a-z-of-weird-animals-part-i-influenza-and-you-and-the-spanish-flu-too/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>21</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://othernationsdotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/campfunston.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://othernationsdotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/campfunston.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">campfunston</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/41251475e8dc5440aecc5fbba5d9787b?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">ncgriffi</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://othernationsdotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/campfunston.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Camp Funston&#039;s emergency hospital. Doesn&#039;t look that fun to me. </media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://othernationsdotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/keepcalm.jpg?w=203" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Keep Calm And DON&#039;T EAT WHEAT. Britain&#039;s propaganda posters are a bit catchier. </media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://othernationsdotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/cityofexeter.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">The City of Exeter, pride of Exeter, bane of Philadelphia. </media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://othernationsdotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/libertyloan.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">A parade is a superb idea during an epidemic. </media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://othernationsdotcom.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/headinsand.jpg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Philadelphia&#039;s government. Credit: colourbox.com</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Sad Christmas Music?</title>
		<link>http://christythomas.com/2012/12/04/christmas-advice-column-why-sad-christmas-music/</link>
		<comments>http://christythomas.com/2012/12/04/christmas-advice-column-why-sad-christmas-music/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2012 20:20:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Christy Thomas</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Advent]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[church]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hymn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advent hymns]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christmas Carols]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[In the Bleak Midwinter]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://christythomas.com/?p=2380</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Dear Christmas Advice-Giver, Why are some of the religious Christmas Carols so sad when this is the season of happiness?  I mean, really, “In the Bleak Midwinter?”  Nothing like a downer.  Aren’t we all supposed to be just super joyful right now?  And what does “bleak” mean anyway? Signed, “Bleakless” Dear Bleakless, Here’s the situation: [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2380&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://thoughtfulpastor.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/advent-candle-blur.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2407" alt="advent-candle-blur" src="http://thoughtfulpastor.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/advent-candle-blur.jpg?w=590"   /></a>Dear Christmas Advice-Giver,</p>
<p>Why are some of the religious Christmas Carols so sad when this is the season of happiness?  I mean, really, “In the Bleak Midwinter?”  Nothing like a downer.  Aren’t we all supposed to be just super joyful right now?  And what does “bleak” mean anyway?</p>
<p>Signed, “Bleakless”</p>
<p>Dear Bleakless,</p>
<p>Here’s the situation:  For much of Christian church history (i.e., before advertising took over the world), the four weeks before Christmas Day were weeks of soul-searching, fasting, and preparation.  The formal name for this time is Advent, which simply means “coming toward.”  So, we are “coming toward” the entrance of Jesus into the world.  The question before the people is this:  “Why?  Why does the world need a Savior?”</p>
<p>Let us think about it and take a few minutes to intentionally enter the suffering of the world.  As a starter, consider the untold millions who are what is called &#8220;food insecure.” They really don&#8217;t know if there is adequate food even for the day to keep them from gnawing, weakness-inducing, muscle-wasting hunger.  Next, notice the pockets of extreme political instability. We see people sitting on their spark-ready tinderboxes, just waiting for the next provocation, imagined or real, to appear.  Finally, we might look at economic and climate uncertainties. With a tightly interconnected world economy and a fragile and vulnerable infrastructure, the relative comfort experienced by many could realistically disappear within hours.</p>
<p>Now, does the world need redeeming?  Do we need to be set free from the binding chains of darkness?  Do we need healing?  Do we need to connect with people across the divide of intractable differences? Do we need to use our creative minds for the larger good rather than mutual destruction?  Do we need to relearn the rhythms of life, work, play and worship that nourish and fill us rather than overly-stimulate us and then squeeze the last drop of life-moisture from us?</p>
<p>If we can answer “yes” to any of those questions, then music that reflects the deep longings of the soul makes a lot more sense.  Seriously, most of us really do want world peace for Christmas.</p>
<p>So, let’s think a bit about the push to be “super joyful” right now.  Where do you primarily see that message?  Mostly from businesses who want you to buy their stuff, the more expensive the better and, lots and lots of it.  They hold out promises that if you do, you will find utter bliss upon either giving or receiving that stuff.</p>
<p>Certainly gift-giving is a great idea. I don’t want to dismiss that custom.  We need celebrations, and we especially need them as the days become shorter and the nights become longer. We need lights and music and festivities.  We need Christmas Day.</p>
<p>But a world with only lights, and never the darkness to appreciate them, quickly turns dull and unappreciated.</p>
<p>Look at some of the words to “In The Bleak Midwinter.”</p>
<p style="padding-left:30px;"><em>Angels and archangels may have gathered there,</em><br />
<em>cherubim and seraphim thronged the air;</em><br />
<em>but his mother only, in her maiden bliss,</em><br />
<em>worshiped the beloved with a kiss.</em></p>
<p dir="ltr" style="padding-left:30px;"><em>What can I give him, poor as I am?</em><br />
<em>If I were a shepherd, I would bring a lamb;</em><br />
<em>if I were a Wise Man, I would do my part;</em><br />
<em>yet what I can I give him:  give my heart.</em></p>
<p>This song, originally written as a Christmas poem by Christina Rosetti in 1872, was set to music in the early 1900’s.  The words beautifully show both the loneliness (bleakness, empty, hard, cold) of Jesus’s birth and our human incapacity to give adequately in response to such a great gift given to us.</p>
<p>By entering into some of the sorrow of the season, we gain greater capacity to find the delight and joy in it as well.</p>
<p>Merry Christmas,<br />
Your friendly Christmas Advice-Giver</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2380/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2380/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2380&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://christythomas.com/2012/12/04/christmas-advice-column-why-sad-christmas-music/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>24</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/ac44f40fdd875f2df2ca5f5d7a0411bc?s=96&#38;d=wavatar&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">thoughtfulpastor</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thoughtfulpastor.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/advent-candle-blur.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">advent-candle-blur</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Editor is Dead! Long Live the Editor!</title>
		<link>http://literatureandlibation.com/2012/12/04/craft-and-draft-the-editor-is-dead-long-live-the-editor/</link>
		<comments>http://literatureandlibation.com/2012/12/04/craft-and-draft-the-editor-is-dead-long-live-the-editor/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2012 20:35:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Oliver</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Literature]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Writing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[craft and draft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Editing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[post-nanowrimo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[so you want to be a novelist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the ending to lost really pissed me off]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://literatureandlibation.com/?p=1920</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[If you NaNo&#8217;d and are now in a post-NaNo writing coma, you may not be ready to face the harsh realities of the raw novel landscape. The world changed while you slept. You grew a beard. Sandra Bullock visited you and told your parents you were engaged to be married with hilariously unexpected results. When you [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1920&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you NaNo&#8217;d and are now in a post-NaNo writing coma, you may not be ready to face the harsh realities of the raw novel landscape. The world changed while you slept. You grew a beard. <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0114924/">Sandra Bullock visited you</a> and told your parents you were engaged to be married with hilariously unexpected results.</p>
<p>When you finally wake up, you&#8217;re going to have to edit. A lot. And not like, fix a couple grammatical mistakes or missed commas, but full-blown, angry, word-drunk edit in which you destroy your own art without impunity, in some weird backwards attempt to build it back up again, better, stronger.</p>
<p>I took a cursory glance at my &#8220;manuscript&#8221; and before I processed what I was doing, I had deleted massive swaths of content, rewritten several sections almost entirely, and realized that I still didn&#8217;t have enough distance from my writing to objectively make any meaningful comments. 4 hours later, I stopped.</p>
<p>Just kidding. I didn&#8217;t really stop, I just ran out of &#8220;being awake.&#8221;</p>
<p>Editing is when you move your armies in to occupy the territory you won during your word conquests. It&#8217;s where you can use your left brain to clear the battlefield of all the dead metaphors and corpses of analogies that your right brain abandoned to rot. It&#8217;s your chance to hone your paragraphs to razor-perfection like blades on a whetstone. A chance to make those descriptions shine like a suit of full plate mail.</p>
<p>I love editing. It&#8217;s fun to find things that you just <em>nailed </em>the first time around, and equal amounts of fun to beat yourself up over the border-line brain damage you had when you wrote that scene about the army of ninja wolves who could fly (because they had jetpacks).</p>
<p>But you need to be careful when you edit; it&#8217;s too big a time investment with too much on the line to undertake unprepared. To see you through this harrowing journey, I offer the following boon(s):</p>
<p><strong>1. Train yourself to be offended by mistakes</strong></p>
<p>This ties loosely into <a href="http://literatureandlibation.com/2012/08/30/craft-and-draft-the-proof-is-in-the-reading/">proofreading</a>, but involves a lot more than just looking for passive constructs or dangling modifiers. This is about really noticing when something is wrong, and being actively disgusted by it. You need to learn the difference between &#8220;less&#8221; and &#8220;fewer&#8221; and have a visceral gut reaction when you see something like, &#8220;he needed less calories, due to his access to the liquid chocolate larder.&#8221;</p>
<p>Learn what pisses you off about bad writing and internalize it. Swallow it, eat it, live off of it as your only means of sustenance until those mistakes burn inside your body like the sputtering carbon of a dying star. <span style="font-style:normal;line-height:24px;">If you&#8217;re emotionally connected to the writing (especially to the negative) you&#8217;re more likely to catch and correct errors that a less invested editor might overlook. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-style:normal;line-height:24px;">Get mad at your writing. Demand more of it and more of yourself.</span></p>
<p><strong>2. Remove context</strong></p>
<p>Your mind naturally fills in blanks and establishes patterns of things it thinks it already knows. If you read your own work, in order, knowing exactly who does/says/kills what next, you&#8217;re likely to gloss over weak writing and glaring mistakes. To avoid this, pull the context blanket off of your scene. He&#8217;s been too warm and cozy, snuggled up in your plot line like a lazy teenager. Make him get up and go outside, look at him in other context, and see that he&#8217;s been under that blanket for so long that he&#8217;s thin and pasty and probably smells pretty bad.</p>
<p>Objectivity regarding your own work is really challenging, but viewing your work outside of itself can help you get that much needed distance. It&#8217;s easier to break apart a single scene or exchange and edit that, than it is to try and edit the entire work at once.</p>
<p>This has the added bonus of allowing you to analyze your tone and voice to see if it is strong enough to stand alone in a short example. If it is, chances are you&#8217;ve got a pretty decent manuscript on your hands. If it&#8217;s not, keep on editin&#8217;.</p>
<p><strong>3. Know when to hold &#8216;em, know when to fold &#8216;em</strong></p>
<p>This is a personal editing weakness of mine. My editing kryptonite, if you&#8217;ll allow the cliche. Sometimes, you&#8217;re really, really, <em>really </em>committed to that scene where your protagonist has a steamy threesome with a sexy anthropomorphized grasshopper and a giant jar of honey, but it just doesn&#8217;t seem to fit in with your realistic romantic comedy set in modern day Chicago. You can&#8217;t find the resolve to delete the scene, because you put a lot of thought and craft into it, and it seems wrong to just delete it.</p>
<p>I used to say, &#8220;Suck it up, cowboy. It&#8217;s for the sake of the story! Delete that shit!&#8221;</p>
<p>Now I say, &#8220;Hey, that could work with other context, or if you made the grasshopper into an actual woman. Save that shit!&#8221;</p>
<p>When I edit, I leave a second document open. If I find a scene or piece of dialogue that I really like but just doesn&#8217;t seem to fit the theme or plot, I cut and paste it into this &#8220;holding document.&#8221; The writing isn&#8217;t lost, but it&#8217;s not cluttering up the main story, either. It&#8217;s a way to psychologically distance yourself from what you&#8217;ve fallen in love with.</p>
<p>After a while, you can go back and read the stuff you cut out.  Out of context, you might hate it and realize that it really wasn&#8217;t very good in the first place. Or you might find inspiration in some random aside to start a whole new story. You can&#8217;t lose!</p>
<p><strong>4. Alpha and Omega</strong></p>
<p>Writers spend a lot of creative energy on beginnings and endings. The middle seems inconsequential; just a means to get from origin to exit. It makes sense to really make sure your beginnings and endings work, as they are the delicious 9-grain bread to your literature sammich.</p>
<p>Pay attention to how you start things. Is the beginning of each section engaging? Does it transition well from the previous section? Is your reader going to want to keep reading, or did you leave them alone in the West-Virginian woods with nothing more than a pointed stick to fend for themselves? As you begin a section, be sure to set the hook in your readers mind, don&#8217;t just dangle it out there hoping they&#8217;ll nibble at it.</p>
<p>As you near the end (or an end) make sure things seem to be organically coming together. Make your endings have meaning, insight, purpose. Readers tend to like resolution to conflict, when and where possible, even if it isn&#8217;t a happy resolution.</p>
<p>Don&#8217;t pull a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lost_(TV_series)">Lost</a>. Don&#8217;t leave me wanting to kill you after I&#8217;ve invested SIX FREAKING SEASONS of time by writing some cop-out, bull-shit, &#8220;they were dead the whole time but don&#8217;t worry because they&#8217;re in pseudo-heaven now, and please forget about all those other loose ends to really intriguing shit we left out&#8221; ending.</p>
<p>That shit is weak.</p>
<p>But whatever you do, make sure you actually get back to your manuscript and edit it. It&#8217;s great practice that will ultimately improve your writing, and there&#8217;s always the possibility that you can (after many hours of revision) turn it into something that a publisher may want to read without barfing! We can all dream, right?</p>
<div id="attachment_1922" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 870px"><a href="http://literatureandlibation.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/patapsco-025.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1922" alt="&quot;Editing is like walking through an old overgrown railway tunnel. You have a lot of weeds and vines to hack through, but when you emerge on the other side you have a whole new view of the world.&quot; -Oliver Gray, circa right now" src="http://literatureandlibation.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/patapsco-025.jpg?w=590"   /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">&#8220;Editing is like walking through an old overgrown railway tunnel. You may have a lot of weeds and vines to hack through, but when you emerge on the other side you have a whole new view of the world.&#8221; -Oliver Gray, circa right now</p></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1920/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/1920/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1920&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://literatureandlibation.com/2012/12/04/craft-and-draft-the-editor-is-dead-long-live-the-editor/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>24</slash:comments>
	
		<media:thumbnail url="http://literatureandlibation.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/patapsco-025.jpg?w=150" />
		<media:content url="http://literatureandlibation.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/patapsco-025.jpg?w=150" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Patapsco 025</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/ae92ec92852f0fedc0a619984cb8d178?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2F1.gravatar.com%2Favatar%2Fad516503a11cd5ca435acc9bb6523536%3Fs%3D96&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Rum</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://literatureandlibation.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/patapsco-025.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">&#34;Editing is like walking through an old overgrown railway tunnel. You have a lot of weeds and vines to hack through, but when you emerge on the other side you have a whole new view of the world.&#34; -Oliver Gray, circa right now</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>I Feel Pretty</title>
		<link>http://mcalpinetankersleyblog.com/2012/12/04/i-feel-pretty/</link>
		<comments>http://mcalpinetankersleyblog.com/2012/12/04/i-feel-pretty/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2012 11:30:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>mcalpine tankersley</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[architecture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[houses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[interior design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ornament]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mcalpinetankersleyblog.com/?p=2355</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Ask most contemporary architects what they think of decoration in architecture and you&#8217;re apt to elicit a diatribe of snobbery. As a matter of fact, the ornate branches of architecture are sometimes treated like a flamboyant uncle at the family reunion: fun to look at it for a bit but not to claim or take [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2355&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://mcalpinetankersleyblog.com/2012/12/04/i-feel-pretty/2012-11-29_001/" rel="attachment wp-att-2356"></a><a href="http://mcalpinetankersleyblog.com/?attachment_id=2358" rel="attachment wp-att-2358"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-2358" alt="" src="http://mcalpinetankersley.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/2012-11-29_003.jpg?w=640&#038;h=446" height="446" width="640" /></a></p>
<p>Ask most contemporary architects what they think of decoration in architecture and you&#8217;re apt to elicit a diatribe of snobbery. As a matter of fact, the ornate branches of architecture are sometimes treated like a flamboyant uncle at the family reunion: fun to look at it for a bit but not to claim or take seriously. I think, however, that decoration and ornament have a distinct place in the building arts. After all, Architecture&#8217;s inspired roots have always been planted in the soils of the natural world. Even the staid classical orders and designs of the Greek and Romans were hymns mused of nature. One need only look around the garden, forest or ocean and know that Mother Nature is hardly a Shaker &#8211; she seems to shamelessly revel in the Baroque.</p>
<p>A true piece of Architecture that lacks some type of whimsical beauty is like a room without accessories: coldly bare and lacking something for the eye to caress;  these rooms look unused. Similarly, buildings void of even the smallest decorative gesture lack a generous and habitable sensibility. Rooms without accessories look uninhabited and buildings without some sense of decoration look uninhabitable. I dare to mention the word &#8220;pretty&#8221; in terms of discussing architecture because &#8220;pretty&#8221; is seen as the F-word of architecture. But I&#8217;m complimented when one (of our houses or rooms) is pronounced as pretty; that means the eye of the describer has found something within which pleases the heart.</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://mcalpinetankersleyblog.com/2012/12/04/i-feel-pretty/2012-11-29_001/" rel="attachment wp-att-2356"><img class="alignleft  wp-image-2356" alt="" src="http://mcalpinetankersley.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/2012-11-29_001.jpg?w=720&#038;h=1199" height="1199" width="720" /></a><a href="http://mcalpinetankersleyblog.com/2012/12/04/i-feel-pretty/2012-11-29_004/" rel="attachment wp-att-2359"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-2359" alt="" src="http://mcalpinetankersley.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/2012-11-29_004.jpg?w=640&#038;h=662" height="662" width="640" /></a></p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><a href="http://mcalpinetankersleyblog.com/2012/12/04/i-feel-pretty/2012-11-29_006/" rel="attachment wp-att-2364"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-2364" alt="" src="http://mcalpinetankersley.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/2012-11-29_006.jpg?w=640&#038;h=1530" height="1530" width="640" /></a><a href="http://mcalpinetankersleyblog.com/2012/12/04/i-feel-pretty/2012-11-29_005/" rel="attachment wp-att-2360"><img class="wp-image-2360 aligncenter" alt="" src="http://mcalpinetankersley.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/2012-11-29_005.jpg?w=560&#038;h=679" height="679" width="560" /></a><br />
All Content on this Site is the Property of McAlpine Tankersley Architecture. Copyright © 2012 McAlpine Tankersley Architecture, All Rights Reserved Worldwide</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2355/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/2355/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=2355&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://mcalpinetankersleyblog.com/2012/12/04/i-feel-pretty/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>10</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/da76f68bddbdd78c4fe2ff616121f792?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mcalpinetankersley</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://mcalpinetankersley.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/2012-11-29_003.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://mcalpinetankersley.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/2012-11-29_001.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://mcalpinetankersley.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/2012-11-29_004.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://mcalpinetankersley.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/2012-11-29_006.jpg" medium="image" />

		<media:content url="http://mcalpinetankersley.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/2012-11-29_005.jpg" medium="image" />
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Single Story of Soviet Russia</title>
		<link>http://thesqueakyrobot.com/2012/12/03/a-single-story-of-soviet-russia/</link>
		<comments>http://thesqueakyrobot.com/2012/12/03/a-single-story-of-soviet-russia/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2012 22:20:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>squeakyrobot</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photography]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Story time!!]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[culture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[essay]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[psychology]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[russia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[society]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[travel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[USSR]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thesqueakyrobot.com/?p=4245</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[“I don’t know what hunger is,” said Mikhail: teacher, father, product of the Soviet Union. It was strange hearing that from him, even more so with a bright smile in his eyes and overall jovial demeanor, as if he were discussing a recent hockey victory and not a supposedly sore subject. Rather, as an American [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4245&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://thesqueakyrobot.com/?attachment_id=4240" rel="attachment wp-att-4240"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-4240" alt="DSC_0845" src="http://thesqueakyrobot.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dsc_08451.jpg?w=678&#038;h=1024" height="1024" width="678" /></a></p>
<p>“I don’t know what hunger is,” said Mikhail: teacher, father, product of the Soviet Union. It was strange hearing that from him, even more so with a bright smile in his eyes and overall jovial demeanor, as if he were discussing a recent hockey victory and not a supposedly sore subject. Rather, as an American it was strange hearing that. I think of the USSR, and I think of tanks, grayness, secrecy, scary and impenetrable Cyrillic lettering, looming misery, and long bread lines in inclement weather; the depressing and immoral yield of a communist machine; the enemy of capitalism and, consequently, freedom. So how could Mikhail even utter the words: “I was a teenager. I didn’t have problems”? Of course you had problems! The single story I know says so! You are a product of the Soviet Union, Mikhail, and nothing else.</p>
<p>Such is the danger of the single story. A single story,<strong><a href="http://www.ted.com/talks/chimamanda_adichie_the_danger_of_a_single_story.html" target="_blank"> as eloquently illustrated by novelist Chimamanda Adichie</a>,</strong> pigeonholes the world to the scope of one individual. It’s a narrative that compresses a diverse group into one single stereotype, one plot with no room for subplots or alternate story lines: Africans are poor, starving, and wholly isolated from everything &#8220;Western&#8221; (Adichie mentions how her American roommate was surprised to hear that there were Britney Spears fans in Nigeria), Middle Easterners are violent Muslims, and the Swiss are wealthy pacifists.  These are the stories we repetitively hear. As such, the way we perceive the world becomes inaccurate and oversimplified. This has serious real-world implications that present physical threats to our well being, like invasive TSA screenings, <strong><a href="http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2008/jul/01/raceissues.russia" target="_blank">Russian skinheads targeting anyone who looks foreign</a></strong>, and <a href="http://www.upworthy.com/meet-the-17-year-old-who-blew-the-lid-off-racial-profiling-with-his-ipod" target="_blank"><strong>unjust racial profiling in major cities</strong></a>. Just as venomous is the abstract, spiritual harm. Single stories hijack possibilities of realistic images and expectations: while traveling through China, a girl asked me why all American girls are rich, beautiful, tall, and skinny. Little girls in Nepal, Argentina, Romania, Peru, Mongolia, and Spain had similar questions, all the while expressing a collective desire to be white, blonde, and blue-eyed.</p>
<p>These stories also present an existential danger. We become sheltered by a self-fashioned bubble of cognitive dissonance and ignorance, one that saves us from a world that is complex and difficult to understand but also endlessly diverse, forever intriguing, and unimaginably colorful. Adichie warns about the dangers of the single story: “All of these stories make me who I am. But to insist on only these negative stories is to flatten my experience and to overlook the many other stories that formed me. The single story creates stereotypes, and the problem with stereotypes is not that they are untrue, but that they are incomplete. They make one story become the only story.” As with any kind of story, incompleteness is unsavory. And yet we live, often obediently, by unfinished yet close-ended narratives.</p>
<p>America gets a single story of Russia. In history classrooms, pop culture references, and even present-day politics and foreign relations (Mitt Romney recently declared Russia the nation’s number one foe), there’s this archaic story of Russian brutality. The Russian experience is merciless in weather, culture, and life. Villains in American movies are frequently Russian (still considered a classic choice that, interestingly enough, was popularized in the 50s and 60s due to certain world events) and they&#8217;re often depicted as unfeeling ruthless psychopaths &#8211; with thick, don&#8217;t-fuck-with-me accents &#8211; to mimic an extreme yet fabricated Soviet mentality (villains such as Rosa Klebb, Ivan Vanko, Irina Spalko, among countless others). Also popular in America are Yakov Smirnoff&#8217;s Soviet reversal jokes: &#8220;In America, you watch Big Brother. In Soviet Russia, Big Brother watch you!&#8221; These punch lines offer a laughter-through-tears kind of comedy, one that mocks the Russian vernacular while incorporating heavy Orwellian undertones that suggest an intrinsic lack of control and, in turn, Soviet-spurred hopelessness and nihilism. Yakov Smirnoff jokes are still alive and still funny.</p>
<p>But beyond that, an American will consider a Russian to be inextricable from Russia’s recent history, politics, and that famous, unchanging Russian mentality. The Russians have an unshakeable pride and stalwartness, one that whitewashed the great Napoleon’s formidable yet naïve assault during a pitiless Russian winter. And then we get the story of America vis-à-vis Russia, its conniving Cold War arch-nemesis – brutality against outsiders, disavowers of the system. We get the story that Russian Communism was godless and, thus, evil, that it left its people fighting for their lives while at the mercy of a small yet maliciously powerful elite. All Russians were inherently Red and they were bent on our demise. They were cruel and deceitful Socialists and we were benevolent and strong Capitalists. Joseph McCarthy helped the cause a bit, revealing in a 1950 speech entitled “Enemies from Within”, the one where he presented an irrefutable list of the names of 200 Communist subversives lurking within the American government, that, “the real, basic difference, however, lies in the religion of immoralism . . . invented by Marx, preached feverishly by Lenin, and carried to unimaginable extremes by Stalin. This religion of immoralism, if the Red half of the world triumphs, will more deeply wound and damage mankind than any conceivable economic or political system.” This is the story that is implanted into young American minds, very often with no healthy or possible alternative.</p>
<p>So how could jolly Mikhail not know hunger? What’s his story?</p>
<p>While there have been occasions in Soviet history when bread lines were a very dismal reality, a beautiful rejection of the single story allows for a different story. People don’t know – I didn’t know – that life in Soviet Russia wasn’t necessarily the seventh level of hell. From the years 1988 to 1991, for example, Mikhail had little to complain about: “In Soviet times, my fridge was always full. Now, not so much.” Here’s how it worked: people were given sheets of paper divided into coupon-like squares. Each square had some kind of rationed product that was good for one person for one month. Everyone received 1.5 kg of meat, 0.5 kg of butter, 1.5 kg of sausage, 2 kg of flour, 100 grams of tea, 1 bottle of vodka OR 2 bottles of wine, and 10 packs of cigarettes. Everything else could be bought in stores for next to nothing. A liter of milk and a kilogram of sugar were 22 kopecks, the modern-day equivalent of one-cent. Mikhail’s salary was twelve dollars a month back then, and he and his wife lived comfortably.</p>
<p>I had never heard that story before.</p>
<p>Mikhail also recalled less agreeable Soviet experiences, all the while preserving his infectious bubbly persona. When the USSR collapsed in 1991, the Bush administration sent emergency aid to Russia in the form of chicken legs. They quickly became known as “Bush’s legs”. Mikhail stood in line for four hours to get what was due to him – enough legs to feed him and his family. He finally received his lot, and he and his comrades were stunned. It was disillusionment at its finest: “We see images of American chicken – large pieces, juicy, crispy! Capitalism gives big chicken legs! But we received tiny, tiny legs. We were in shock,” as he demonstrated with his pointer finger and thumb how tiny his Bush’s legs were. It’s easy for Americans to assume that all Russians regarded us as capitalist pigs (somehow they were simultaneously considered to be victims of a ruthless regime and opposed to that regime’s ideological opposite). But there were just as many Russians who admired American economic traditions and who wished they had our chicken.</p>
<p>American history curriculums haven’t changed, and the fact remains that modern-day Russia is seldom a topic of discussion in classrooms. This implies a kind of interminable one-dimensional story where the Reds are eternally cooking up something disastrous for American liberty. But Mikhail said that the Soviet Union couldn’t exist again. People too easily become adjusted to improvement. There is no going back: “Now, if there’s a line with five people ahead of me, I won’t stand there. Too many people!” The hell with Gorbachev <i>and </i>his mile-long lines.</p>
<p>Not every product of the Soviet Union would recollect the times as fondly as Mikhail had. An old Russian professor of mine now travels the world and has exotic eccentricities like collecting Cuban voodoo sculptures and Mexican paintings of the Guanajuato countryside simply because of her restricted Soviet upbringing, full of oppressive censorship and propaganda and strict uniformity. She didn’t feel free then, and now, in America, she does. She certainly wouldn’t paint the optimistic pictures of Mikhail’s full fridges and no problems. I remember her looking back on the USSR in disgust, recalling how little she could openly read and watch. And so there were drawbacks.</p>
<p>And that’s the point. There are billions of directions the Soviet story can go, as with all stories. Single stories are not real. Single stories do not allow gray areas in a world where black and white do not exist, either. Where does that leave us? It leaves us in a world where little girls wish they were American for no good reason. It leaves us in a world where kids have to think twice before they wear a hoodie down any urban street, and anyone wearing a turban is considered to be nursing explosives in their shoes.</p>
<p>Adichie’s speech also made two things abundantly, painfully clear: Firstly, I’ve also read into single stories. I was ashamed that I was surprised by Mikhail’s lovely recount of Soviet life. I felt stupid for not knowing better (Adichie herself, with all her wisdom, eloquence, and experience, fell victim to the single story when she realized not all Mexicans are scheming criminals trying to hop the border). Secondly, these deeply engrained perceptions are difficult to shake. My entire family is from Poland, so I heard stories of the Soviet Union more complex than the average American would be exposed to. I travel the world. I constantly meet different people, all with unique stories and views and paths and callings. I know very well that facades are meaningless. I regularly read international news sources and stay up-to-date with publications such as National Geographic, Time, and Foreign Policy. I’m an inquisitive, thoughtful, and world-oriented human being. I thought these could be vaccines against single-storydom. And yet, Mikhail’s optimistic reminiscing of Soviet times sounded off to me, as if I had heard a fact that was doubtful to be true. Because without even realizing it, I bought into the single story of Soviet Russia where everything was miserable and  backwards and the average day in the life of a comrade was huddling around a fiery trash can and street fighting with chicken in mind.</p>
<p>The shrewd viciousness of the single story is that no one is absolved of society-prescribed judgment and one-dimensionality. I never considered that people have their own single stories about me, stereotypes that, in their minds, I’m not supposed to exceed. Because I’m young and blonde and female, I’m not supposed to be taken seriously. I don’t deserve to be taken seriously. I have nothing worthwhile to say.  Because I’m Polish, all I ever do is complain about how cruel the world has been to the Poles and how much we’ve suffered, how much we’re owed. Because Poland’s single story is the repetitive victimization and obliteration by armies who proved stronger. Contrarily, I have important things to say just like anyone else and, no, I’m not eternally embittered by the actions of Poland’s neighbors. I personally haven’t suffered at the hands of Russians or Germans. No one owes me anything. Most of the Polish people I know share this sentiment. And yet this is what follows me around; people are surprised to hear that I study Russian and that I think Germany is a pleasant country.</p>
<p>We compartmentalize the world in a way our primitive brains can understand: from the lens of our narrow experience. It is difficult to outright reject every single story we know because we unconsciously harbor assumptions about places and people without active thought or acknowledgment. These narratives are intertwined with ignorance, and ignorance is inextricable from the human condition.</p>
<p>While we can’t know every story, we are capable of appreciating this innate deficiency of information and perspective. Maybe simply recognizing that is enough. Maybe that’s the best anyone can do.</p>
<p>“When we reject the single story, when we realize that there is never a single story about any place, we regain a kind of paradise,” Adichie brilliantly concludes. Abandoning the single story of any place or person is an effort that takes introspective thinking, empathy, and constant recognition that we are more than what we seem. We’re more than what we know. The whole story will never be revealed to us. And eventually, I assume, the world will become a place of three-dimensionality and rich story plots. Because that’s what happens if you choose to banish the single story by labeling it irrelevant and fictional. Your world will become a place where former impossibilities are suddenly possible, great expectations from people can be met, a surprise like hearing someone was happy and satiated under Communist rule is no longer a surprise, and people are regarded and respected with the courteous assumption of complexity. It’s become that way for me, at least. I walk down a Russian street and instead of noticing the grayness, I notice all the flowers the women are carrying, the bright purple limited-edition Nikes of that Russian hipster (or scarlet red boots), and the gold-toothed smiles of those Russian babushkas as they laugh at a joke they heard the other day.</p>
<p>Paradise.</p>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4245/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/4245/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=4245&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://thesqueakyrobot.com/2012/12/03/a-single-story-of-soviet-russia/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>28</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/6209eb0b06996ae6e2f8f0d4f582752e?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">squeakyrobot</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://thesqueakyrobot.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/dsc_08451.jpg?w=678" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">DSC_0845</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Monday #15: Time Travel</title>
		<link>http://darhosta.wordpress.com/2012/12/03/monday-15-time-travel/</link>
		<comments>http://darhosta.wordpress.com/2012/12/03/monday-15-time-travel/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2012 15:20:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Dar Hosta</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[The Mondays]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dar hosta]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dar hosta james]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nostalgia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Philip Zimbardo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[time]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://darhosta.wordpress.com/?p=1473</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A few months ago I ran across Philips Zimbardo&#8217;s talk on time perspective. It&#8217;s one of many quirky RSA animations that use videos of drawings to illustrate a lecture with great effect. Zimbardo&#8217;s time perspective lecture focused on the difference between past, present and future oriented time perspectives, how they evolve out of specific places and cultures [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1473&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://darhosta.wordpress.com/2012/12/03/monday-15-time-travel/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://1.gravatar.com/avatar/41a69d96da6bb99b0944cbc22a13e241?s=96&#38;d=http%3A%2F%2Fs0.wp.com%2Fi%2Fmu.gif&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">darhosta</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://darhosta.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/hourglass2.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">hourglass2</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://darhosta.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/old-apt.jpeg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">old apt</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://darhosta.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/nina.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Nina</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://darhosta.files.wordpress.com/2012/12/bogos.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Bogos</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>To Lori Anne</title>
		<link>http://twdittmer.wordpress.com/2012/12/03/to-lori-anne/</link>
		<comments>http://twdittmer.wordpress.com/2012/12/03/to-lori-anne/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2012 18:48:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>T. W. Dittmer</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Personal Stuff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lyrics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nostalgia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[personal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Poetry]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://twdittmer.wordpress.com/?p=679</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I have a battered old soft-sided briefcase that was made in Hong Kong before most of you were born. I bought it to carry my Army stuff in, hauled it around the globe while I did my time with Uncle Sam. There&#8217;s no army stuff in there any more. That all got replaced with other [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=679&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I have a battered old soft-sided briefcase that was made in Hong Kong before most of you were born. I bought it to carry my Army stuff in, hauled it around the globe while I did my time with Uncle Sam.</p>
<p>There&#8217;s no army stuff in there any more. That all got replaced with other stuff over time.</p>
<p>Now that briefcase is filled with music and poetry and copyright certificates. Demo tapes from when I was going to be a famous musician. Guitar sonatinas and interludes. Doodlings and drawings. Clumsy attempts at art by a naive young man that would turn into a naive <em>old</em> man as the years rolled by.</p>
<p>A pile of raggedy old memories that sits in its hiding place, high up on a closet shelf.</p>
<p>I put those memories aside to do other things, but lately that briefcase has been calling to me, demanding that I remember. The demands got louder and louder, until I finally gave in to the urge, dragged that old briefcase down and started digging through it.</p>
<p>One piece in particular was trying hard to get my attention, a little ditty I wrote so long ago I couldn&#8217;t remember all the words. I pulled it out, looked it over, and everything came back to me.</p>
<p>I remembered.</p>
<h1 style="text-align:center;">*****</h1>
<h1 style="text-align:center;">To Lori Anne</h1>
<p style="text-align:center;">You&#8217;re born for the living<br />
You live for the dying<br />
And you die for the living again<br />
That&#8217;s the way the river runs<br />
Lori Anne</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">You hold out your heart<br />
To the broken down people<br />
Hoping that they&#8217;ll understand.<br />
That&#8217;s the way the river runs<br />
Lori Anne</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">You pour out your life like a drink of cool water<br />
And it&#8217;s soaked up like rain on dry sand<br />
For the empty&#8217;s so great there&#8217;s no way you can fill it<br />
The river runs on<br />
Through a desolate land</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">Lori Anne<br />
Don&#8217;t ever lose sight of your dream<br />
Lori Anne<br />
Keep reaching<br />
Keep trying<br />
Keep your heart in the stream</p>
<p style="text-align:center;">You&#8217;re born for the living<br />
You live for the dying<br />
And you die for the living again<br />
That&#8217;s the way the river runs<br />
Lori Anne</p>
<h1 style="text-align:center;">*****</h1>
<p style="text-align:left;">Huh.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">Well, enough reminiscing.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">It&#8217;s time to put that old briefcase back in its hiding place up on the closet shelf. Those musty old memories will stay tucked away there, safe from any nosing and prying until the next time they call out to me.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">But I remember, all right.</p>
<p style="text-align:left;">I remember.</p>
<br />Filed under: <a href='http://twdittmer.wordpress.com/category/personal-stuff/'>Personal Stuff</a>  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/679/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/679/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/679/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/679/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/679/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/679/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/679/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/679/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/679/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/679/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/679/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/679/" /></a> <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/679/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/679/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=679&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://twdittmer.wordpress.com/2012/12/03/to-lori-anne/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>35</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/b520f60c15f9abd43b72555a2ec653c4?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">laikhervn</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>My Top (and Bottom) 10 Favorite Christmas Songs of All-Time</title>
		<link>http://mommabethyname.com/2012/12/03/my-top-and-bottom-10-favorite-christmas-songs-of-all-time/</link>
		<comments>http://mommabethyname.com/2012/12/03/my-top-and-bottom-10-favorite-christmas-songs-of-all-time/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2012 02:56:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Momma Be Thy Name</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Holidays]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[humor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bad Christmas songs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christmas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christmas music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Christmas Song]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elvis Presley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[good Christmas songs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Little Drummer Boy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wham]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://mommabethyname.com/?p=7412</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As I was driving this evening, quite literally, through the holiday bustle, listening to the holiday music channel on my satellite radio, I started to daydream. Don&#8217;t worry &#8211; I stayed in my lane. But I got to thinking about all the Christmas songs I love, and, conversely, the songs for which I do not [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=7412&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://mommabethyname.com/2012/12/03/my-top-and-bottom-10-favorite-christmas-songs-of-all-time/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>113</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://2.gravatar.com/avatar/8284d3d35c88cb1776384a26c7ebab47?s=96&#38;d=monsterid&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">mommabethyname</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/9/9d/Mariah-carey-all-i-want-for-christmas-is-you-1994.jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">All I Want for Christmas Is You</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://files.myopera.com/theFunnyguy1/albums/707046/Alvin%20and%20the%20chipmunks%20(christmas%20edition).jpg" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">http://files.myopera.com/theFunnyguy1/albums/707046/Alvin%20and%20the%20chipmunks%20(christmas%20edition).jpg</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>From &#8220;A Muse&#8217;s Unvarnished Perspective&#8221; by Altos Wexan</title>
		<link>http://nonexistentbooks.com/2012/11/30/from-a-muses-unvarnished-perspective-by-altos-wexan/</link>
		<comments>http://nonexistentbooks.com/2012/11/30/from-a-muses-unvarnished-perspective-by-altos-wexan/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 22:45:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>alexp01</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Excerpt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[muse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NaNoWriMo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[National Novel Writing Month]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Stephen King]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[story]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nonexistentbooks.com/?p=3164</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#8220;Another year, another novel that hasn&#8217;t quite been finished but has the requisite number of words.&#8221; My muse, a blatant appropriation of Stephen King&#8217;s concept thereof as expressed in On Writing, cracks open the fridge and retrieves a cold beer. I keep it on hand for guests, being a de facto teetotaler myself; I don&#8217;t [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3164&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;Another year, another novel that hasn&#8217;t quite been finished but has the requisite number of words.&#8221; My muse, a blatant appropriation of Stephen King&#8217;s concept thereof as expressed in <em>On Writing</em>, cracks open the fridge and retrieves a cold beer. I keep it on hand for guests, being a de facto teetotaler myself; I don&#8217;t know where he got the Cuban cigar that billows smoke all over my single-room downstairs.</p>
<p>Since my muse is an insubstantial personification of my creative drive, albeit one ever so slightly ripped off from a more successful author, I don&#8217;t suppose it really matters.</p>
<p>&#8220;It&#8217;s not just the number of words,&#8221; I say. &#8220;I&#8217;ve takes one of the stories I wanted to tell and given it a good start. It barely existed before and now it&#8217;s 300k on my hard drive.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;300 unfinished k, you mean.&#8221; My muse emerges from the fridge with beer and leftover barbecue chicken strips. &#8220;Don&#8217;t you think it&#8217;s about time you finished the others?&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;What others?&#8221; I bristle. &#8220;There&#8217;s only the project at hand, nothing else.&#8221; </p>
<p>I mean it as a metaphor, but it&#8217;s taken literally. &#8220;The story about those kids finding alternate dimensions with giant landsquid for one,&#8221; my muse says. &#8220;Don&#8217;t forget the unfinished noir detective novel about a librarian, and the comic wish-fulfillment tale of the assassin and the accountant.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;I&#8217;ll get to them in time,&#8221; I say, a little defensive. &#8220;It doesn&#8217;t matter if they&#8217;re finished. What matters is that I wrote something that didn&#8217;t exist before. It&#8217;s good even if it&#8217;s a little rough.&#8221;</p>
<p>The muse sits down heavily on my couch and fires up the Xbox. &#8220;What about the one from 2008, where you tried to stretch that 500-word short story into a tale ten times its length, and wound up so desperate for wordcount that you undid all your contractions a half-hour before midnight on the last day?&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Don&#8217;t bring that one up,&#8221; I snap. &#8220;It was an election year and I had a new job. Too many distractions!&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Whoa there, killer,&#8221; my muse says without looking up from the first-person shooter he&#8217;s working away at. &#8220;Did I touch a nerve? Don&#8217;t forget that it was a failure for me too. Or do you think part of a novel each year and a blog post a day is nothing for me?&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;I&#8217;m sorry,&#8221; I say. &#8220;It&#8217;s a stressful time even without the novel.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;But you&#8217;re glad you did it again this year?&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Yeah.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;Well then,&#8221; my muse says, wreathed in smoke and barbecue beer fumes. &#8220;That&#8217;s all that matters.&#8221;</p>
<ul>
<li><em>Like what you see? Purchase a <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Excerpts-From-Nonexistent-Books-selections/dp/1475263252/">print</a> or <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Excerpts-from-Nonexistent-Books-ebook/dp/B008B1624S/">ebook</a> version!</em></li>
</ul>
<br />  <a rel="nofollow" href="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3164/"><img alt="" border="0" src="http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/freshlypressed.wordpress.com/3164/" /></a> <img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=3164&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://nonexistentbooks.com/2012/11/30/from-a-muses-unvarnished-perspective-by-altos-wexan/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>35</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/3e88de1a5811f940d71b687eaa29f702?s=96&#38;d=identicon&#38;r=G" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">alexp01</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Behaviour of Socks</title>
		<link>http://isthatcoffee.wordpress.com/2012/11/25/the-behaviour-of-socks/</link>
		<comments>http://isthatcoffee.wordpress.com/2012/11/25/the-behaviour-of-socks/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2012 00:45:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>Blathering</dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blathering about nothing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[laundry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[missing socks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[quantum mechanics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tweets]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://isthatcoffee.wordpress.com/?p=1604</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This story begins with a missing sock. Actually, approximately 40 missing socks, give or take a few, if I estimate the ridiculous amount of un-matchable socks that seem to breed in and overflow out of my laundry basket from one week to the next. But&#8230;..hang on. Before I get any further, perhaps this story doesn&#8217;t [...]<img alt="" border="0" src="http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=freshlypressed.wordpress.com&#038;blog=256907&#038;post=1604&#038;subd=freshlypressed&#038;ref=&#038;feed=1" width="1" height="1" />]]></description>
		<wfw:commentRss>http://isthatcoffee.wordpress.com/2012/11/25/the-behaviour-of-socks/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>40</slash:comments>
	
		<media:content url="http://0.gravatar.com/avatar/f75a0c158654ad872817c4de96d42ac9?s=96&#38;d=monsterid&#38;r=PG" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">number1twerp</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://isthatcoffee.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/socks.jpeg?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Socks</media:title>
		</media:content>

		<media:content url="http://isthatcoffee.files.wordpress.com/2012/11/probability_plot.gif?w=300" medium="image">
			<media:title type="html">Probability_Plot</media:title>
		</media:content>
	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
